Rym: It's Monday, January 30th, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're talking about online ads and ad tech.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we had a. you know we always have a hiatus and GeekNights.
Rym: every year for the like 15 years We got all kinds of hiatuses.
Scott: No one's paying us to do this shit.
Scott: Yeah We hate us whenever we want.
Rym: GeekNights makes dozens of dollars a month from YouTube read mostly or whatever they call it now YouTube premium.
Scott: You know what the difference is between us and the other hiatuses.
Scott: you always come back.
Scott: so far We've come back every time yep podcast rise and fall.
Rym: We just only not us and penny arcade Just keep fucking going and the Simpsons.
Rym: They just keep going.
Scott: penny arcade doesn't hate us though I don't know.
Scott: they've missed a strip in in 20.
Rym: They were more diligent about getting guests to do strips when they like couldn't do one.
Rym: we did that a few times.
Scott: It's like they always upload Something.
Rym: I should try that again next time.
Rym: we have to go to hate us.
Rym: I we should or I should arrange like we did those few times to get guests to the show because the formats really is
Scott: it's But they they make their livelihood off it in which you know yeah
Rym: I mean we if we
Scott: lived off this then yeah, I would make sure there was always something uploaded.
Scott: No, cuz if cuz think about it if somebody was like actually paying money for this like let's say it was we were taking.
Rym: Oh, if this was our job there would be ever ads.
Scott: not putting up episodes means reducing our inventory.
Scott: No money comes in wait.
Rym: you just called it inventory meaning you definitely were reading up on ad tech And I read the whole Google thing.
Scott: that's gonna be our news in two seconds.
Scott: And then you know if we were getting paid by patrons right that and it wasn't this.
Scott: you know some bullshit patron But a real one that I told people to pay for.
Scott: yeah, it's like we'd have we'd have an obligation to them Which we don't have right now.
Scott: They're just right now.
Scott: They're just fools paying for no guarantees of anything whatsoever.
Rym: Yeah Plus if I could do this full-time and live the life of now I definitely would like.
Rym: no question We would never miss a show You want to talk about your.
Scott: you finally skied in a superior ski And I want to point out full disclosure.
Rym: for like months leading up to the ski trip I kept
Scott: saying
Rym: off and on in real life and GeekNights all over the place like yeah It's gonna be pretty easy Pretty sure it's gonna be really easy because like East Coast snow is all like ice and bullshit and like I learned in the hardest conditions you can learn in.
Rym: so Every indication is that big mountain West Coast skiing.
Rym: It's just gonna be like so easy And I'm just gonna be doing like the craziest trails having a great time, and you know what.
Scott: sure that's exactly right.
Rym: It was exactly right.
Rym: Holy shit is skiing easy as hell on West Coast snow and The people are also.
Scott: if you went to the Alps would be the same.
Rym: probably Yeah, except the Alps have no snow.
Rym: they are also the Andes.
Scott: Andes is.
Rym: the Alps have worse conditions this year than like Hunter Mountain does In New York State, I'm sure it varies year to year, but no this is the first time in recorded history.
Rym: It's been this bad.
Rym: It's like Catastrophic point.
Scott: is the outside way better than whatever in New York has?
Rym: yeah, yeah until this year The Alps are like the West, but this year there's other places with a good skiing like Iran.
Scott: Iran has good skiing.
Rym: Yeah, actually.
Rym: so get this the pass the epic pass that we get.
Rym: that covers vale.
Rym: It covers Hunter Mountain like the mountain here that we ski like the local crappy one.
Rym: Oh, it's like one pass you can buy and you can just use it to ski everything in the epic network that veil like the Company owns which includes Vale the resort like that's the home base resort.
Rym: lift tickets for a day at Vale are 250 bucks.
Rym: a Season pass that includes 10 days at Vale plus unlimited skiing like fucking everywhere else in the East Coast is like 600 bucks.
Rym: So So the pass we already used to ski at our dumpy mountain just made Vale skiing free.
Rym: We just had to pay for the place in the lift ticket.
Rym: But uh, so I learned a few things skiing out there one.
Rym: Yeah, it's just better in every possible way Like I.
Scott: that's why.
Scott: that's why it's a cost.
Scott: You know if you want to buy a house in Vale How much does it cost if you want to buy a house in Hunter?
Scott: if you want to buy a house in Hunter Mountain?
Scott: What does it cost?
Rym: Scarily houses near Hunter Mountain.
Scott: The Hunter Mountain skiing was as good as the as the other skiing the house in Hunter Mountain.
Scott: houses in Vale are.
Rym: They're not as Expenses as you would expect because you will think about New York City pricing and it's kind of comparable.
Rym: actually.
Scott: well, but the thing is you get a Right, you're paying a lot, but you're paying for it to be close to the skiing.
Scott: But unlike New York right where you're in New York, you're paying to be in the New York.
Scott: So that evens out doesn't even out.
Scott: being in the New York is way better than me near the skiing But you get a lot.
Scott: you're gonna get a more house out there.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but not that much more because Vale is you're not gonna get some tiny apartment.
Rym: Vale is in this mountain pass where there's like a regional airport and there's one road in and out on either side of the valley And that's it.
Scott: Yeah, there's no public transportation.
Scott: other there is.
Scott: He shut all this.
Rym: the the town of Vale the actual like city.
Rym: there all public transportation is free for anyone.
Rym: They don't check anything buses just come and go it all just works.
Scott: Well, yeah, but it's not like there's a. there's a train.
Scott: It's like a major city.
Scott: It's like it's.
Scott: you know, the town is just a town that exists for skiing.
Scott: It's not like this.
Rym: Yeah The town only exists for skiing and other outdoor recreation like it's like.
Scott: it's like there's people who live in Wildwood.
Scott: There's a school there.
Scott: We see it right.
Scott: Well, it's really a beach.
Scott: No Yeah, the majority of people there are there for the beach and the people who live there are people who live there.
Rym: So one thing I learned I've never been that high long enough to have altitude sickness before and I and everyone in the group Except one of us George had altitude sickness the first day like we just yeah, that's that makes sense.
Scott: Yeah, it's real It's not a joke.
Rym: It was funny.
Rym: We land and we're walking her like we're getting our stuff and we feel fine.
Rym: We're like, all right I'm a little lightheaded but this is fine that we get to the place and it's a two-story like condo we're staying in.
Rym: we walked Up the stairs and I had to stop near the top.
Scott: I ran out of breath that first day Like I was like, yeah I mean if I even if I skied or let's say I went there to bike I guess with the snow melted Right, I would not do it for like 24 hours after getting.
Rym: that's what we did.
Rym: We fly we flew in that morning and the first day was just acclimate to the altitude.
Scott: Yep I mean, I always remember that one dude.
Scott: I forget what team he played for but he was an NFL player and they had a game against the Broncos in Denver.
Scott: And he like, you know, this wasn't a football problem.
Scott: It right.
Scott: It wasn't like someone hit him real hard like good recent situations, right?
Scott: It was just due to altitude sickness.
Scott: He had you know, there's a name for it I think or it's like it's extremely emergency.
Scott: You could dive.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: So basically and you can basically if you have whatever condition that guy has you just can't do Strand you his physical activity.
Rym: So it's like period or you'll die in that It's kind of random like fitness age all.
Scott: I think it's more rare than seasickness.
Rym: One in four people will experience acute mountain sickness, but us much smaller.
Scott: We're talking about the dying level of yeah.
Rym: So we were watching for the symptoms because the first day like we all just had a headache and felt like shit all day.
Rym: But then the next day woke up felt great.
Rym: I skied like 150 miles over the course of the week and every day I went harder.
Rym: I got 89 runs in and those runs are like six times longer than run 100 Mountain.
Rym: I skied more and they'll in those five days, but I think I skied in the last three years combined.
Scott: It was amazing And I'm sure when you come back down the mountain you're like, oh so much oxygen you get like, huh?
Rym: Yeah Oh when we got back home like right after we landed the next day I played DDR just to see because it was too cold to get brought outside.
Rym: Yeah my heart rate was just lower while I was working out like way lower.
Rym: and if you look at my Google or my Apple watch chart of resting heart rate and like average heart rate and blood o2 You see it's almost like a chart of how long have we been in vale because it's the heart rate Skyrockets and then slowly drops day by day while we're there.
Rym: But the skiing was amazing.
Rym: I was like off in these back bolt.
Rym: There's like a front side of the mountain.
Rym: That's like normal mountain like ski resort.
Rym: That's just big like giant.
Rym: behind it are these giant bowls.
Rym: Just ski in any direction like all the way down the mountain.
Rym: It just funnels you into a lot.
Scott: the lodges at the bottom and there's the lifts go like every which way.
Rym: So they'll know the lodges are at the bottom of the front side and on the top and in the middle the back side Like a multi lodge, yeah the back side of the mountain.
Rym: you go off the other back end of the mountain into a bowl.
Rym: There's nothing at the bottom except lifts like it's just in the middle of the wilderness.
Rym: or you take a lift even further out.
Rym: There's a. we got to this blue sky basin that takes like 45 minutes of ski down.
Rym: Ride a lift ski down ride a different lift ski down ride a different list to get to this other Basin way in the back.
Rym: Oh, okay, which was also I seem to remember the one.
Scott: I just remember seeing one.
Scott: I don't remember where I saw it where there was.
Scott: basically you drive up and there's like You know parking lot, right?
Scott: Yeah, and there's like one lift that just go and it's like that's it one lift.
Scott: And then the other side is a bowl.
Scott: Yeah and the lodge is at the bottom in the middle and the lifts on the.
Scott: once you're in the bowl go basically every possible direction North South East West and you can ski basically From you know on the north side on the west side and no matter where you ski You end up at the lodge at the bottom so you could go do the north side.
Rym: then this place is so big.
Scott: You'll end up and then when you want to go home You have to use the one lift that goes to the other side of the mountain where the car.
Rym: that's typical.
Rym: This place is just it's.
Rym: it's literally like the biggest in North America I think.
Rym: like it is so big that you'll be you could travel to a different area Basically just by skiing and more.
Scott: so I'd be you know, I'd be surprised if it was not good.
Scott: It's like why the hell is yeah, everyone go into that place if it's the not good place, right?
Rym: Yep, and I also I finally now I really strange like I leveled up my skiing I was doing some really fun dire stuff.
Rym: I skied down some like black diamond ridiculous bowls and Also, somehow you made it back.
Rym: cuz I'm a real fucking good skier.
Rym: and now I have confirmed this.
Scott: Absolutely Yeah, we'll see Rym goes to get next year up.
Rym: I'm going back every year.
Rym: I know I will.
Rym: I will prioritize being able to ski at a place like that every year from now on.
Rym: it is so worth it.
Scott: And then in three years from now, there's no snow.
Rym: So we were talking to all the Colorado has the most snow ever.
Rym: So at least for the short term Colorado and Utah are doing fine.
Rym: The rest of the world is F'd.
Scott: I mean this year was not the last year of snow, but Someday, it is depressing.
Rym: Oh, it is depressing to think about the fact that unless humans radically change course in a way that our governments won't let us I May live to see a day where children are like, yeah There used to be this sport called skiing that weird like white people did.
Scott: Now you can only do it in Antarctica.
Rym: Yeah But yeah, I'll post some photos later and stop.
Scott: meanwhile those kids live in Antarctica because it's so warm.
Scott: we start building Civilization down there.
Rym: I also tried the kinds of skis that don't work on the East Coast because the East Coast is all like icy Bullshit, so you need like stupid skis.
Scott: I just use regular old keys with you and then you rent.
Scott: or did you just rent?
Rym: We just rented there and we rented from a fancy place.
Rym: So they would give us skis based on our preferences and ability and we could even carry any skis there And we'd swap.
Scott: you're carrying skis though is easier than carrying bikes.
Rym: So, uh, yeah Most people bring their skis, but the skis I use on the East Coast would not work on real snow.
Rym: They're designed for shitty icy snow because 90% of the time that's what I'm skiing on out here Mm-hmm.
Rym: But now that I've tried those other kinds of skis, too They're so much more fun and I really but I couldn't.
Rym: I don't think I could use them here Like I don't think they would work.
Scott: Bikes are so much easier.
Scott: It's just like does it have two wheels?
Scott: Yeah, does it work?
Rym: Are you going downhill?
Rym: What kind of suspension does it have?
Scott: It doesn't need any of that.
Scott: You just have two wheels is go.
Scott: You're good You can ride it anywhere.
Scott: Might not be the perfect one, but it's gonna work, right?
Rym: Well, we did on that bike tour across New York Emily and I did.
Rym: in the summer.
Rym: we ended up in the last segment on an actual mountain biking trail in our track like our Hybrid bikes with heavy panniers on the back and we made it down just fine.
Rym: But I gotta say that is not comfortable without a suspension.
Rym: Good fucking God.
Scott: But just say it's like, you know, it's never see.
Scott: you said this situation where the skis won't work, right?
Rym: Yeah Down by mountain work I could just like a hybrid bike.
Rym: I could get down the mountain.
Rym: you know what I couldn't do carve.
Scott: Anyway, anyway in the new whole bunch of shit happened Thanks to the hiatus and we're gonna talk all about it today and then forget all about it next show episode.
Rym: Yeah, but briefly because this is so big that we almost can't talk about it.
Rym: But we got to talk about the fact that this is a thing that's growing pretty much the only news It's so big pretty much.
Rym: Well, the Google thing is secondary to this.
Rym: pretty much every tech company.
Rym: It has done Massive layoffs in the past.
Rym: that's big but there's not too much to say about it other than well other than that It is a such a rapid contraction of the technology world globally.
Rym: It's not even just the u.s.
Rym: Like Google laid off 12,000 people Facebook laid off 11,000 Amazon 10,000 Microsoft 10 or 11,000 Salesforce 8,000 Amazon 8,000. there so far There have been almost 300,000 layoffs just among large Technology firms almost entirely in engineering and technology disciplines.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So why is this happening?
Scott: and the and the truth of the matter is right.
Scott: if you try to figure out no company is gonna Give you tell you the truth about what the executives were saying in the meeting and what they decided, right?
Scott: But if you read experts people who used to be executives people executives other companies, right?
Scott: People who are reliable and not evil right?
Scott: The truth is why are they doing this, right?
Scott: Well, it's a time in which there's some inflation going on prices on things some things are rising and Companies want to cut costs, right?
Scott: Because you you.
Scott: it's not as it's easy to cut costs You just you could just do it.
Scott: if you're an executive You can just order your company you can just say the word and costs are cut.
Scott: you stop spending money that you have, right?
Rym: You're just still projects.
Scott: You can't say the word and bump revenues up Unless you're crooked.
Rym: we'll talk about Google in a little bit Unless you're crooked.
Scott: You can't say the word and just get revenues, right?
Scott: You actually have to do work to get revenues and succeed and make right bets and do right.
Scott: It's you might you know, it's it's not?
Scott: you can't automatically get more money.
Scott: Yeah, so when companies look to cut costs, right companies right now are cutting costs in many other areas, right?
Scott: They're trying to cut costs on technology like the actual computers.
Scott: How how can we cut our odds?
Scott: spending is like a huge conversation?
Rym: Shut down data centers, can we like Minimize service we give to customers anything.
Scott: how can we provide the same good or service that our company provides as its core business to maintain our revenues But spend less money, right?
Scott: What can we stop spending money on and still operate because we don't like the way that the markets looking.
Scott: We don't like how prices on other thing.
Scott: other people are raising their prices on us.
Scott: We can raise our prices but other people are raising their prices.
Scott: So it's like, you know, it's like that's an increased profits that just raises a bunch of number makes a bunch of numbers bigger.
Scott: yeah, so Cutting labor is an enormous cost at any company.
Rym: It's the biggest cost in most industries everywhere including technology industries Especially in a place like the US.
Scott: right when you hire an employee Let's say you hire an employee whose salary is a hundred K. that Employee probably costs the company 200 K because of the other hundred K of stuff.
Scott: They have to pay for Right all the other stuff they got to pay for for that employee It's you.
Scott: basically double the salary is what they actually cost the cup.
Scott: Yeah 401k matches all kinds of shit All right, so when you fire people right lay them off.
Scott: even when you pay Severance to everybody it's like yeah in the short term your pay your cost basically stay the same because I paid severance.
Scott: It doesn't cost you more, right?
Scott: And then after that six months or whatever of severance and you stop paying all those people.
Scott: Now your profits go up even though your revenues are the same.
Scott: Yeah, and the thing is companies right now For a long period of time, you know the past many years Companies weren't concerned with profits really especially not in the tech sector.
Scott: They were concerned with numbers, right?
Scott: How many you know?
Scott: user accounts did you get signed up?
Scott: Are you growing Sun, right?
Scott: It's like they're.
Rym: how many views you got how many they wanted competitive advantage?
Rym: So if you have a competitor and they're hiring like crazy, what are you gonna do?
Rym: You're also gonna hire like crazy.
Scott: how many subscribers he got Netflix, right?
Scott: And but what's happened recently?
Scott: is you know the reality that should have been there all along which is investors stopped asking how many subscribers he got and you know started asking how much profit are you making?
Scott: and the?
Scott: We're not profitable.
Scott: We never have been.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But also consumer spending.
Rym: irrespective of inflation going up consumer spending is dropping in the u.s For a number of reasons
Scott: partly someone like me who can afford to pay for things I've been just going through and looking at what I spend money on and Canceling things, you know I stop when I see high
Rym: prices.
Scott: It's like could I afford to buy $10 cream cheese?
Scott: I could.
Scott: I am that fortunate that I could but it's like I'm not paying fucking $10 for cream cheese.
Scott: I'm gonna get the cream cheese.
Rym: I like less for $4, you know, I paid because it was the only option.
Rym: I thought I paid over a dollar an egg to buy a dozen eggs in vale so we could cook breakfast.
Scott: Oh, okay, but I'm thinking right even me I could afford to buy the $5 dozen eggs.
Scott: Yeah, usually they used to cost about $12 in vale.
Scott: Oh my god I could afford to buy $5 eggs at the overpriced New York grocery store.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: I'm probably.
Scott: I think we should go to Costco buy a whole tray of eggs and split them, right?
Rym: You know, I got the car.
Rym: be really easy to distribute that among our collective friends.
Scott: We don't need a car.
Scott: get a little wagon.
Rym: Well, what are gonna get?
Rym: you can take that wagon out to Flushing?
Scott: Yeah, people everyone can come over have a little party and everyone take egg party egg party.
Rym: Anyway, but also I like that Consuming.
Scott: I even I have been anecdotally recently past few months, right?
Scott: You know cost-conscious and companies are doing the same thing.
Rym: Yep but another thing going on is.
Rym: Americans are poorer than they've been in a long time for all the reasons you can imagine.
Rym: like a lot of people lost their jobs a lot of people are being paid less a lot of people lost a Caregiver or someone who worked in their family because kovat killed so many people.
Rym: like we're in an unprecedented time in Like the history of the American economy never mind the rest of the world world world economy, too.
Rym: But America's got like extra stupid problems on top of the general problems of the world.
Scott: Yeah, it's like we got other issues, right?
Scott: You got like the eggs We just talked about.
Scott: it's like is that because of it's good the bird the bird flu killed all the chickens.
Rym: But also right even if we didn't kill all that if there was no bird flu The eggs were only ever that cheap in the first place because of the extreme exploitation of both chickens and the humans who deal with the chickens.
Rym: indeed if we have any society in the world paid a living wage and what it cost in human misery and Dealt with the externalities of even simple stuff like eggs our entire system collapses.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So basically the way you think about it is you're playing Sim City and someone goes to the menu and like clicks on five Disasters at once.
Scott: yeah, right and the Godzilla comes in and it's like the end result of all those disasters.
Scott: when it you know It's like boils down to how it affects the tech companies is lay a bunch of people off?
Rym: Yeah, so that's a little bit.
Rym: One of them lays off the all the other ones can do the same and they get all cut.
Scott: Yes, a lot of them are not doing it due to some internal logic They have of like they've.
Scott: they calculated it wherever.
Scott: they're copycatting or you know meeting market Expectations or trying to hit estimates or you know, they're doing it just because they don't even fucking know Why.
Scott: I read a study about like, you know Our layoffs a good idea how to companies decide to do them and and do they benefit?
Scott: and you know what?
Scott: The fact is layoffs usually don't help companies.
Scott: It's it doesn't usually actually yeah You know create the positive impact that they think it does and they keep doing it.
Rym: Anyway this I don't want to belabor the point But if you look back to where things really started to go weird in America Before the mid-70s a lot of companies higher had a lot of just extra employees around who weren't doing that much.
Rym: that was important and that was that sort of provided a glue to Society because a lot of people made enough money to live.
Rym: But not everyone had to work that hard in a lot of big companies.
Rym: and then as companies realize Hey, we'll be better off if we trim the fat and just work more efficiently.
Rym: That was good for the company but it was bad for people because it turned out there weren't enough jobs that companies were willing to pay a living wage for.
Rym: and That's sort of that spiral sort of continued into today and now is continuing even further.
Scott: You know the last thing I want to say right is that one notable tech company, right?
Scott: Not to toot their horn because we can certainly criticize them has yet to lay people off.
Rym: I can say something better.
Rym: the company I work for we're hiring in fact, if you listening are a software engineer my tiny little company will hire - but We're not time.
Scott: We're talking like, you know, I don't know how many spots in the next year maybe a handful But anyway, and we're also looking for a salesy people.
Scott: But the point is the sure the big tech companies who hasn't laid people off yet Apple and you know what Apple did do.
Scott: they reduced Tim apples salary at his request.
Scott: now so I mean plenty to criticize in the Apple world.
Scott: clearly, right but Apple by doing that instead of laying people.
Rym: so there's reporting today.
Rym: numerous analysts are saying Apple is definitely going to lay people off.
Rym: It's just a matter.
Rym: Okay, not.
Scott: if well, maybe they will and in which case then yeah I'll see whatever about.
Scott: what I'm about to say is not true that As of now, it is still true.
Rym: These are.
Rym: this is speculation that I've reported on, right?
Scott: Let's just say any company that were to not lay people off when its competitors did right that were to say When its competitors were firing that company would be buying into the dip.
Scott: Yeah, right, you would be by that's buying low.
Scott: You're getting these great employees when competition for their labor is weak.
Scott: Yeah Oh price.
Scott: and then when those other companies that laid people off when you get to the next quarter and the next quarter Those companies are not going to be delivering cool Products at their keynote speeches because they didn't have any one doing they were just keeping the lights on.
Scott: they didn't have people.
Scott: They cancel all their hot projects.
Scott: So a lot of those projects were gonna miss and fail and probably were a waste of money.
Scott: Yeah, but at least one of them might have been something exciting, right?
Scott: So all those companies now not only canceled a bunch of crap good but they also canceled something that might have been a success.
Scott: and now those companies are basically Ensuring that they're gonna maintain status quo and not for the near future deliver anything new and amazing That would generate good revenues.
Rym: Yeah I found a chart along these lines does showing that the biggest drop in consumer pennant spending was people in yours and mine Demographic the richer people but not the richest people.
Rym: They are the ones who are cutting their discretionary spending Drastically, right,
Scott: but if you know a company were to not lay people off and were to hire They would I predict right basically suddenly come out and deliver right some Awesome kind of product right that would pull in the customers.
Scott: whatever customers are out there right and you know get a big boost while everyone else is asleep.
Rym: and What I was arguing at my job strongly I strongly believe in what you said now is the Apple.
Scott: if if Apple does not lay people off Right because right now they haven't yet to do so at least in this cycle here.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Then I predict that they will be the company that does exactly that right.
Scott: they will come out right whenever when Microsoft and and everyone else is asleep and like next year or the year after it's gonna be like oh shit Apple's got the hot shit and everyone else has nothing to kill it.
Rym: So we'll see what happens.
Rym: This is uh, there's a lot going on in the US economy.
Rym: This is one tiny tiny sliver the other big big news and there's so much to say here But it'll segue into the main bid.
Rym: the United States Department of Justice is Basically going as hard as hell against Google to the point that they could if this succeeds break them up over this.
Scott: yep, so just to Focus only on this suit because we're gonna.
Scott: you know, what's happening is it's an antitrust lawsuit Obviously, right similar to the Microsoft one back in the day where they're basically saying Hey, you're a company and you had Monopoly power in one area of business and you used that monopoly power to basically, you know
Rym: Kill
Scott: off competition in other areas of business right in an unfair way And an illegal way according to the laws of the United States.
Scott: Yeah, so there's already a suit against Google.
Scott: That's an antitrust suit about search advertising and that is that's an old suit That's been around for years that that's coming to court like later this year I think.
Scott: and that suit is only about search advertising the old one.
Scott: when that search advertising is obviously you do a search on Google Results come up and there's ads mixed in with the search results, right and you're not running adblock Right.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: This new suit the one that's the big big news is not about search advertising.
Scott: Not at all.
Scott: It's about display advertising because this was I'm pretty sure 99% sure.
Scott: it was news on GeekNights.
Scott: when this happened Google bought a company called double-click.
Scott: Yeah Click what double-click was a company that basically had a near monopoly.
Scott: was the the industry leader Technology ad tech for display advertising.
Scott: you are which includes.
Scott: you have a website.
Scott: You put ads on it.
Scott: other people want to buy ads right.
Scott: they go through some convoluted system we're gonna explain in the main bit and They pay money.
Scott: the ad shows up on your website.
Scott: you get money Right and the images videos, you know something that displays on your website.
Scott: That's display advertising.
Scott: Google bye-bye after buying.
Scott: when they bought double-click, right the FTC it actually mentions this right said, okay This won't said, you know, they made comments as to why it wouldn't be an antitrust problem.
Scott: Right and in the lawsuit the DOJ filed they said the FTC said this and they were wrong.
Scott: It was a problem and I could have told you that back then.
Scott: So now the smart person is me.
Rym: the cool part about this lawsuit is the.
Rym: the people Within the Department of Justice who are driving it have issued some statements and give them some clarity on Why they're pursuing it in the manner that they're pursuing it.
Rym: and the idea to summarize all these articles you can click and read the actual specific details is They are hoping to set a new precedent for novel kinds of antitrust lawsuits that have previously been ignored or been difficult to Achieve like it's been hard to win.
Rym: This is this is if this succeeds This is gonna be like the big breakup of like JP Morgan oil trust and such back in the day.
Rym: Like this would be a new era of trust busting.
Scott: because now I'm not I am NOT a lawyer, right?
Scott: But the evaluations I have seen including reading most of the actual court filing well most of the court filing is actually a Layman's plain English description of how this business works and what Google did in this business.
Rym: Better description than like some sites that explain how ad tech work, right?
Scott: Like if you just want to learn how ad tech works just read this thing.
Scott: It's like it won't take you really that long.
Scott: you can skip most of it and it's pretty much just like.
Scott: here's how ad tech Works.
Scott: this is what Google did in that part of ad tech.
Scott: This is why it's a crime.
Scott: next part I gotta say is the next part of the ad business.
Rym: reading it, right?
Rym: And we'll get into this in the main bit about why I'm about to say it breaks this law and this law Reading this law here and that law there.
Rym: from the perspective of someone who is an expert in capital markets and has been in that industry for a long time It is.
Rym: it is so egregious and Obviously right for abuse what Google was doing and honestly what all digital ad not just Google But all online ads with very few exceptions.
Rym: I go like this is shit that capital markets and like stock exchanges Regulated over a hundred years ago because it was so obviously Like it's ripe for corruption.
Scott: Well, I'm gonna go further than that, right?
Scott: I think what's happened is we have the the internet and computers, right?
Scott: Yeah have allowed people to create digital market places of any kind.
Scott: Anyone could just make a digital market right.
Scott: seam has fucking cards and money and skins going around right?
Scott: It's like just anyone with no government interference or regulation whatsoever.
Rym: Yeah If I want to make a market to sell like I got to comply with a million regulations If I remember market that sells pictures of Scott my drew, you know, there are markets that involve, you know The things that the SEC regulates at least in the US.
Scott: other countries have their own equivalents, right?
Scott: fight real financial markets.
Scott: Every if anyone else who just makes a market of any kind anywhere Right is completely unregulated until the government of the place where the market is a point of order.
Rym: But making a market is actually a technical term for something very specific.
Rym: They create.
Scott: you talk about market makers at the stock.
Rym: Yeah making markets is a thing that can happen within Markets, I'm talking building a marketplace.
Scott: like you're in civilization and you go to your city and like what do I build next?
Scott: Marketplace, I need another trade route that kind of building a market.
Scott: So, but yet any and that's we've seen it with crypto.
Scott: we've seen it with skins With advertising specifically as an example.
Rym: you are making a market about a thing where the only Evidence you can give the person buying your thing is evidence you create about the effectiveness of that thing.
Rym: You're selling Their ways anyway, yeah, I mean there are ways to try to independently verify which we'll get into in the main bit.
Rym: But you're basically selling an asset that you control In a manner that is not regulated and can be very opaque to the person buying and the people buying Kind of have a vested interest in not necessarily knowing how effective or how like well It's working because of the weird incentives of this kind of market.
Scott: So based on my personal assessment this case right.
Scott: the reason it might fail is because This has been.
Scott: this is a very difficult cut.
Scott: like Rym said it's a difficult kind of thing to do.
Scott: People don't haven't tried it since like AT&T Microsoft Times right and it's just.
Scott: it's like they're trying to go up a big hill.
Scott: However The the case that they have brought is basically the strongest conceivable case, right?
Scott: It's like if you're gonna try to go up that mountain with any company under any anti-competitive circumstance if they wanted to go after NBC Comcast or Verizon or any giant monopoly ish company that probably should be broken up, right?
Scott: Sinclair with all its broadcasting shit.
Scott: They own everywhere like that.
Scott: This one is Probably not eat the strongest case they could bring I guess.
Scott: so it's like I feel like that a real.
Scott: That's what they did.
Scott: is they looked at all the monopolies they would like to destroy.
Scott: it's hard to go after an Case we have against any of them.
Scott: is the Google ad one.
Scott: let's do that one and the case that they have brought.
Scott: if it wasn't for their a history of this being difficult to do in My non lawyer opinion.
Scott: This would be a shoo-in.
Rym: Yeah, and it's partly because it is hard to go after.
Rym: monopolies in general like the laws are not great in the US.
Rym: Yeah in the US but also even when you can prove something as a monopoly You often have to go further and prove either malfeasance or harm Directly caused by it's not.
Scott: it's not a crime to be a monopoly in the US.
Scott: It's only a crime to like engage in certain specific anti-competitive behaviors Like Microsoft.
Scott: what they got in trouble for was not have it.
Scott: You know owning Microsoft Windows which had monopoly at the time on desktop computers.
Scott: The the reason they had a trouble back then is because they tried to use their monopoly power to stifle competition for web browsers and force IE To be the standard and destroy everyone else and that was using their monopoly power for evil.
Scott: So Google used its control of Advertising and search to push other ad companies, you know out and and diminish them.
Rym: Never mind the implications that Google may have engaged in fraudulent behavior in the course of many many fraudulent.
Scott: Oh, no, I'm.
Rym: I mean I'm speaking like someone doesn't want to get sued.
Rym: That's to all hell.
Scott: I am personally confident that everything written in that case is true that I've seen much of it with my own eyeballs.
Rym: So if you wonder like what the impact of this could be I should.
Scott: Crimes the crimes Google did them.
Rym: Google makes the majority of its income from the advertising.
Rym: Nothing, Google makes makes fucking money except the ads.
Rym: the ads are it Google's not even Android phones.
Scott: I don't think those make any money.
Rym: It makes money.
Rym: That's a separate problem, but it is no worthy.
Rym: I think Google's in deep shit, too Because they have not announced any features or updates from the their ads team since November 17th last year.
Rym: They just went radio silent in public Mmm, and the ad industry like the companies that like talk about and like interact in the ad space.
Rym: They're all like really scared of this because this isn't just gonna put the scrutiny on Google and what they did.
Rym: This is putting scrutiny on the like the marketplaces of ads as a fundamental concept And I think there's a lot of graft in that industry a lot of grift.
Scott: You mean all of it?
Scott: Yeah We'll do some things of the day and we'll talk about how that industry works.
Rym: things of the day.
Rym: so Lack of Daisy was a webcomic that I saw off and on.
Rym: I didn't realize it started like.
Scott: I never read it But I knew it existed.
Rym: it started in 2006 and the art got way better over time, but it was pretty good even the beginning.
Rym: Take like black sad like that kind of setting and that kind of art but make it a little cuter and a little more animally and don't have the thing where the girl animals are Hot in one way and the guy animals are like very radically differently drawn.
Rym: like it doesn't have that problem But it's very reminiscent of black sad.
Scott: It's a little bit black sad.
Scott: It's a little bit rescuers and a little bit untouchables, right?
Rym: You know, so lack of Daisy is getting an Animated short.
Scott: and when I saw this trailer, I was like, is this a whole movie?
Scott: Where the fuck did the money come from?
Scott: Yes, and they're like it's a short and I'm like, oh, okay This trailer looks fucking great.
Rym: This would even to make a short like this because it was a 90-minute.
Scott: if this was a full-length Animated motion picture it would cost tens of millions of time.
Scott: But then it was like, oh it's a short, okay Yep.
Rym: So this trailer is my thing of the day because one I'm watching this the second it comes out and two I started reading the Webcomic, it's pretty good.
Rym: I Slept on this one webcomic that came out in 2006.
Rym: That's great.
Rym: that has cool animal people doing gangster stuff in the 20s that I didn't read.
Rym: what the fuck's wrong with me?
Rym: You're just not interneting enough, you know, no, I saw it all the time.
Rym: I just never read it cuz I'm busy and read another crap.
Rym: Maybe I read it now because I stopped reading Twitter.
Scott: Yeah, so I think I think this you know Anything that's coming from the smaller indie places is gonna get more visibility on the indie web and we're gonna see even less mainstream shit.
Rym: I look forward to this but this looks great.
Rym: The voice acting sounds great.
Rym: The animation looks great.
Rym: Everything about this is great.
Scott: Yeah, so There was a song.
Scott: Rym knows this song because it was in Dance Dance Revolution.
Scott: That was a big hit song in Japan long ago.
Scott: It's called dancing hero parentheses eat you up by Okonomo.
Scott: You know, I just danced that song yesterday Right, so that song there was a a few years back Right.
Scott: There was a group of five Korean comedian women who parodied covered that song and choreographed a ridiculous awesome High energy dance, right and the name of that group in Korea was Celeb five.
Scott: right and it's funny because they lost a member.
Scott: so it's only four people but they're still called celeb five boys for now.
Scott: Yeah So what happened after?
Scott: that is a third.
Scott: there was a person.
Scott: What's this?
Scott: What's his Japanese person's name?
Scott: I keep forgetting Because I only learned about them recently because they're the person in the thing of the day.
Rym: I can't help because the entire Hara Ihara Rica.
Scott: Ihara Rica is a Japanese person who is an actress and she was going to be in a musical production in Japan and then The COVID canceled the musical production.
Scott: So, what did she do with no job?
Scott: She made a YouTube, right?
Scott: So her YouTube is like Ihara Rica.
Scott: step and go right and she's got a cute YouTube channel, right and it's popular.
Scott: She's got a hundred and thirty four thousand subscribers.
Scott: That's a lot more than we have, right?
Scott: yeah, and one of the things she did on her YouTube channel like her top video is She used to be in her earlier days according to the internet like the captain of her high school dance team, right?
Scott: So despite being a you know, she's a Broadway actress.
Scott: She's got to have some dancing skills.
Scott: Yeah, she got together a dance crew and They performed the celeb five Cover, huh, right?
Scott: So it's a. it's a cover cover, right?
Scott: But you know being a dance crew and not just being five comedians They did a way better job.
Scott: Right, I went more all-out and extreme and that video is the thing of the day Not too shabby.
Rym: In the meta moment, we're back.
Rym: I don't foresee any GeekNights' hiatus for the immediate foreseeable future.
Rym: on Wednesday.
Rym: We're gonna review a fan-anime Ramayana And next week on Thursday, we're gonna do the Alif the Unseen book club.
Rym: I finished it on the trip.
Rym: Alif was seen not least you saw him.
Rym: Yeah, I There were a few twists.
Rym: I did not expect But I thoroughly enjoyed it.
Rym: I got to say Vikram and his sister are the two Vikram?
Rym: Yeah, they're.
Rym: they're some of the best characters in these business book.
Rym: I love pretty sure it's Vikram not Vikram.
Rym: Yeah, I I know a guy who pronounces it like.
Scott: I've no human beings who had that name.
Rym: I know a guy who pronounces it Vikram.
Rym: at work and actually back.
Rym: when I worked at two jobs ago the company I worked for there was a guy who was from Russia But he lived in the US and his name was spelled Ivan IV an but he pronounced it Yvonne.
Rym: That was just a personal thing that he did.
Scott: the Google says Vikram.
Rym: Mm-hmm anyway, those two characters are Great, and the best part of the book is a moment when they're in a. I'm trying not to spoil things.
Rym: They're in a weird place Interacting with a weird entity and they're like we don't have any of your weird money.
Rym: How do we pay you and what he pays that entity with for his services is?
Rym: That and the little illustrations in the last pages of the book are fantastic.
Rym: All right for it with the iPod.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So yeah, I'll leave.
Rym: the unseen has been seen and then I get to announce the cut and choose.
Rym: I'm gonna announce two books and it's gotta left.
Rym: pick them.
Rym: pick one of the two to read Uh, we'll see what really cute.
Rym: I don't know what you'll pick.
Rym: I really don't.
Rym: Anyway, one of the long though that might influence you.
Scott: All right, so let's talk about.
Scott: we talked about in the news Google's being sued for their monopoly on display advertising, right?
Scott: How does display advertising on the internet the thing that we all block?
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: Hopefully how does it work when you don't block it?
Scott: Right?
Scott: There's three main pieces Right, there is the publisher side, which is also the sell side.
Rym: I believe right up the people who have.
Rym: they publish content and they have space for ads.
Scott: You have a website and you want to put ads on it to make money, right?
Scott: There is the exchange and then there is the buy side.
Scott: you are a Person who has a good or service and you would like to buy ads So that people click on them and come to your website instead of the website They're on and then buy your shit.
Rym: now you might notice buy side and sell side are also terms used in capital markets and just Keep that in the back of your mind for later in this main bit because I got there are some things that are stuck in my craw about ad tech.
Rym: They've been stuck in there for like a decade and they're irrelevant.
Rym: But One thing you have to really disabuse yourself of is the idea that ads are like manually or statically placed anymore.
Rym: That is rare.
Rym: That is like a very different kind.
Scott: It does happen.
Rym: Yep, but it's rare.
Rym: It's rare.
Rym: It's a different kind of advertising.
Rym: It's usually a lot more expensive.
Rym: it usually involves one-off like direct contracts between Individuals or groups or like it's.
Rym: it's a very different world from most online advertising, right?
Scott: It usually only takes place with very very big websites.
Rym: They would do that even back when they're like early ad exchanges were forming penny arcades website.
Rym: when there was an ad there They had a direct agreement with like a game publisher to do a custom ad on their site for them.
Scott: one-off Yep, or you'd be like, okay, you know someone we are you know, we are such-and-such newspaper and you know Such-and-such person is like gonna be our you know ad partner our official sponsor or whatever, right?
Scott: So we have to run their ads.
Scott: we can't just be we're not.
Scott: just.
Scott: you know If you're just got a blog and you want to make some money, it's like you're just running whatever ads, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: you're not, you know making individual deals like, you know, it's like when you go.
Scott: why on YouTube These aren't display ads on YouTube their sponsorships.
Scott: But and you see like all these people running ads for Nord VPN Not all those people didn't like go to Nord VPN and make signed contracts with them.
Scott: Nord VPN has like a thing on their website You could just sign up for yeah, right and just start running.
Scott: just start promoting them and then they send you money like the affiliate Deals, right?
Scott: It's like it's all automated.
Scott: There's no yeah caught, you know hand-to-hand shake things going on.
Rym: And when there is a hand hand a handshake situation That is like the organic ad read in the middle of the podcast.
Rym: you listen to it the YouTube video you watch.
Rym: Obviously there isn't an automated exchange that's inserting a natural ad read into a podcast usually.
Scott: But let's say somebody does buy ads specifically like on a website.
Scott: in that case the Ad the technology behind how the ads work is still the same except the exchange part is bypassed.
Scott: Yeah, you basically skip the exchange.
Scott: There's still the buy side in the sell side running the same software But they just talk to each other directly, right?
Scott: It's like, you know.
Scott: So here's how it works, right?
Scott: Somebody it all begins when you without your ad blocker like a fool Visit a website with an ad on it, right.
Scott: and now what happens is that website goes?
Scott: Oh shit I'm running some JavaScript.
Scott: I want to.
Scott: I want to put an ad here and make some fucking money.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: and they run a piece of software and that piece of software used to be called and is sometimes still called double click for publishers And is the new name of it is Google Ad Manager.
Scott: and this application right has a Monopoly.
Scott: right you can choose to use another piece of software other than this to a to host your ads on your website.
Rym: Probably a bad idea.
Scott: if you do so if you choose to use something else besides Google Ad Manager Then the only ads that will be bidding right in the auction to be the to be the ad that's gonna show up right are going to be ads from other exchanges and other weird places that aren't Google which means All of the people who are buying ads on the other side, right if people are buying ads with Google Adsense Right, you know Google products, right?
Scott: Basically those people are.
Scott: it's like you're running an auction house, right and a lot of people just won't show up to your auction.
Scott: Yeah, they're Google people.
Rym: if you want Google people to show up at your auction Then you have to use the Google product and because they own basically the entire industry if you're if they don't show up to your auction You're gonna get the lowest bidders.
Rym: It's gonna be all penis pills.
Scott: So what does this software look like?
Scott: Well, it's pretty straightforward, right?
Scott: It's you're like you go into it.
Scott: You're like new ad, you know on my home page, right?
Scott: It's this big.
Scott: I want it to be images videos, you know.
Scott: It's that you can figure what the ads gonna look like.
Scott: It gives you the embed codes right.
Scott: you copy and paste the embed codes into your website And you can figure like how much you know, what's how much are you willing to sell the ad for right?
Scott: It's like well if no one's willing, you know 50 cents minimum.
Scott: if no one pays 50 cents I'm not showing anything right or I'll take whatever I can get.
Scott: I don't care right you can figure all that Everything that you need to configure.
Rym: a lot of people a minimum bid.
Rym: they'll show their own Internal advertising or like their own content instead.
Scott: Yep, or you might configure things like, you know, these are the kinds of ads I'm willing to show.
Scott: these are the kinds of ads.
Scott: I'm not willing to show you might configure Hey, so-and-so company bought, you know a sponsorship deal, you know show these ads Specifically from this person.
Scott: right this many times because I made a deal with them Etc all these things you need to configure.
Scott: about ads showing up on a website.
Rym: You can figure in there and there's a bunch of authentication Mechanisms to make sure that like the sources of the ads themselves are on the list of ones You've approved.
Rym: if you do that sign a process.
Rym: There's a lot of it's very.
Scott: it's a very complex.
Scott: There's so much configuration that goes on which is also why it's kind of hard to compete because you would have to you know Even if there wasn't a monopoly situation your new product would have to have all the features of this.
Rym: Yeah It's got it.
Rym: If nothing else.
Rym: It's got to be perform and think about that.
Rym: So it goes to a web page and in the time the web page itself is loading you have to complete an auction That get content from a third party and embed it into your website Like this has to be performant as hell if the ad usually right
Scott: my way ads make your website slow.
Rym: But even that like advertiser people buying ad inventory like wanting to put ads on your website They really want the ad to show up as fast as possible.
Rym: They'll be mad if it doesn't.
Scott: it also needs to do other things like.
Scott: it needs to track and sort of count like okay Who saw the ad?
Scott: how long did they see it?
Scott: who clicked on it?
Scott: We know who right?
Scott: Did they move their mouse over it?
Scott: It's like how long did they watch?
Scott: did they scroll past it?
Scott: You know, it's um, it's an ad that's below the scroll.
Scott: Did they scroll down?
Scott: It's you know, and then it's got to report that information, right?
Scott: Here's how many ads you showed Right, and it's got to report that information back to the people who bought the ads, too Right.
Scott: It's like your ad was seen on this site this many times.
Scott: It was clicked on this many times Right, all these things are encompassed in this one this one product.
Scott: Yep So it's time to show the ad.
Scott: it's decided that it doesn't know what ad to show.
Scott: It's got to go find someone on the internet who's an ad buyer and get to sell them this ad right.
Scott: So it collects as much information as possible about the person Looking at the website, right?
Scott: You can't just go and be like, hey, we've got a you know A square shape ad on front row crew comm right?
Rym: It worked that way in like the late 90s.
Rym: It doesn't work anymore.
Scott: who wants to buy an ad there?
Scott: and nobody's gonna want that right?
Scott: You have to be like.
Scott: look the person who's visiting this web page Without adblock who has clicked on they're using an iPhone.
Scott: they just five seconds ago They were on Amazon and they were looking at skis, right and they're.
Scott: they're on my website now and Right.
Scott: So you get as much information as you possibly can with all the third-party cookies and trackers and all the shit that you're blocking.
Scott: Cuz you're smart, right and you put that out there Right, and then you send that to one of the ad exchanges the Google ad exchange And that's where the bidding goes on.
Scott: people see that and they're like, okay, how much is that worth, right?
Scott: Will I bid on that and how much will I bid to have my ad show up there now?
Rym: You might be wondering What if my website just lies about who's looking at it?
Rym: That's part of what this technology Putting a big asterisk here solves Because in the end.
Rym: the person buying the ads has to trust the analytics data They get through these platforms or if they're really big They might have other platforms trying to independently monitor how the ad performance appears.
Scott: That's part of what the exchange does right.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: that is.
Scott: your Google ad exchange will like look at the information that the publishing side sends them and If they have more information about that ad, you know viewer Yeah, they will add it in to the information.
Rym: This is the problem.
Rym: This is why I remember the thing about capital markets I said before You can't.
Rym: you can't have a buy side and a sell side and an exchange in the same fucking company In capital markets.
Rym: the entire world agreed over a hundred years ago that that is a terrible idea Because everyone can lie to you and you have no recourse.
Rym: So even though these are ostensibly separate platforms.
Rym: I use Google to put up my spaces where people could buy ads and the person buying ads uses Google to put ads in those places and they also Use Google to tell them how well those ads did.
Scott: Yep, so in this exchange all that's happening is auctions, right?
Scott: It's like it's getting things to sell right, you know, imagine an actual auction house, right?
Scott: These are these antiquities and antiques are coming from the web, you know.
Scott: Everyone looking at websites is an antique, right?
Scott: And the ad exchange lines up all the antiques and gets as much information about each antique as they can And then brings out the gavel, right?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So who's who's buying?
Scott: who's coming to the auction?
Rym: Hey, we got a sucker.
Rym: Just spent a ton of money on a ski trip to Vail.
Rym: doesn't have ad block running for some reason.
Rym: He spends all day on Twitter.
Rym: He's looking at Twitter right now.
Rym: who wants to get in front of his fucking eyeballs?
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: So this is the buy side software.
Scott: There's two kinds of buy side software, right?
Scott: Well, this is really only one kind but in the Google world Google has created, you know Artificially two worlds in terms of buy side.
Scott: Yeah, the one world that they've created is basically like the the automatic like Google ad.
Scott: I forget what the actual name of it is But it's basically like if you just go to google.com and you try to buy ads using like Adsense or whatever the hell it is Called now, right?
Scott: It's like basically that is like this very You know diminished and opaque and not very powerful system.
Scott: It gives you very limited options.
Rym: I've used it professionally at my last company because I was in charge of marketing and I gotta say Opaque is a very diplomatic way of putting it.
Rym: It doesn't tell you fuck it Is it just thing?
Scott: is it just called Google ads?
Scott: I forget what it's called them.
Rym: Like it not all the worst thing is using it.
Rym: It would keep making recommendations on how to do things better, but those recommendations always just meant spending more money for some reason.
Scott: Yeah, no basically that Oh Google it's just called Google ads, you know advertise, right.
Scott: So yeah, the thing that's just called Google ads now I don't know what it used to be called which has 80% market share by the way, right?
Scott: It's basically you go in and you put in here's my ads right and you can figure Where you would like your ads to be seen.
Scott: I want them to be seen by nerds and people who are searching for this.
Scott: Even if it wasn't, you know, even though they're not search ads, that's still information that they might know, right?
Scott: Someone was recently searching.
Scott: someone who was recently looking at you know, this website or that website?
Scott: someone in this demographic Someone on these.
Scott: I want to advertise on these websites and this is how much I'm willing to pay at most For all of these different kinds of ads.
Scott: if it's a you know a YouTube ad, you know and it's for on a nerdy GeekNights video, I'm willing to pay a dollar.
Scott: if it's on a Nazi video no money.
Scott: Well all that all this configuration goes on there.
Scott: and But the Google ads product which is what most people have to use right because they're not fancy rich giant companies Right, you just have to use that one because that's like the only thing you can reasonably use Being just a small-time deal right?
Scott: all those like Instagram ads you see from like small companies are all using this thing, right?
Scott: That's like you don't have a lot of configuration options right there.
Scott: it's like you could imagine a lot more and once you set it up, it just goes and it goes to the auction house and It bids for you, right?
Scott: You can't possibly Conceivably sit there and review all the bids.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it's way too fast for that.
Scott: There's too many websites.
Rym: You go to some dodgy pirate site to watch a hockey game and there's a thousand ads on that website.
Rym: How do you know your ad isn't showing up one of those fucking things, right?
Scott: So but the point is it's like you get reports back of like where your ad showed up and how much money you got back And all that sort of thing, right?
Scott: But you know, it's like you don't really have Real complete control over and you don't know what's happening, right?
Scott: So what's happening here is that you've got an auction house, right?
Scott: You got multiple auction houses, but the biggest one is the Google one, right?
Scott: You're using this product, right?
Scott: And You know if people want to show your ads Right because 80% of people are using this product.
Scott: They have to use the Google Exchange, right?
Scott: It's not gonna make bids out anywhere else because it's the Google one.
Scott: so you have an auction house being run.
Scott: the person holding the gavel is Google and Everyone bidding is also Google.
Scott: They're all bidding on behalf of someone else who isn't Google, but all the seats are filled by Google.
Rym: Literally everything we've described is regulated out of existence in capital markets Even in very dubiously regulated countries like this is babies.
Scott: first Only thing you know about how your money that you put in like, okay Here's a hundred dollars go buy ads.
Scott: the only way like the only thing you know about how that hundred dollars got spent is basically it's like What Google decided to do is like
Rym: give a kid a hundred bucks and say hey go tell people in town about my product And the kid comes back and he spent the hundred dollars is gone and he tells you yeah I told a million people and they all thought it was great.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, so That's the right.
Scott: So there's a second part of the buy side and this is also a Google product right called Google display and video 360, right which Has like 40% market share, right so it's not as dominant.
Scott: but This is what you use if you're a big deal, right.
Scott: if you're like a big fortune 500 company And you've got a marketing department buying internet display ads They're not using Google ads like every other little, you know, tiny company out there, right?
Scott: They're using this thing and this thing actually lets you configure Frickin everything right like, you know buying ads directly from someone betting on bidding on other exchanges.
Scott: It's basically like the professional the pro version of the Google ads, right?
Scott: But it's still run by Google and it still does evil stuff that you didn't realize.
Rym: I mean in the end you're still reliant on the person you bought the ad space from to tell you how well it went.
Scott: Well, the only the way you can tell is that if someone's not blocking ads, yeah, right then what's happening with display ads At least in the simplest cases Let's say a JPEG is that the JPEG is hosted on your domain, right?
Scott: So at the very least you can verify that an HTTP request is made to that JPEG From the browser that also requested the website because the JPEG isn't hosted by the person who's hosting the website It's hosted by you the advertiser.
Rym: now I might have a scam website that redirects that request through another proxy.
Rym: I may have an ad block that loads the ad but doesn't show it to me Sure, but I mean regard.
Scott: while those kinds of frauds do exist and there's a battle around it It's like there's a lot of people with phones out there who don't block any ads.
Scott: Yeah, we're seeing everything and that's you know, it's still a large number of ads being seen.
Scott: Why are they effective?
Scott: we could discuss.
Scott: we've discussed that in the past.
Scott: Yeah, are they worth what you're paying for them?
Scott: Who knows right, but that's how this works, right?
Scott: So This this auction happens right.
Scott: the auction used to be back in the day.
Scott: a Second price wins auction.
Scott: So basically what happens is everyone bids or how much they're willing to pay for the ad.
Scott: Whoever bids the most obviously their ad is the one that's gonna get shown right?
Scott: I'm gonna pay $100.
Scott: No one else is gonna pay even $1.
Scott: Mm-hmm, right?
Scott: But the price you actually pay isn't the number you bid.
Scott: I bid a million dollars.
Scott: I want my ad to be shown.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well Rym bid the second highest.
Scott: he bid a dollar.
Scott: So you bid a million but we're only gonna charge you a dollar and one cent you pay this.
Scott: is that higher?
Rym: This is a sensibly more fair because it's an opaque market in that you can set sort of your maximum price.
Rym: But if you're the only game if like you're the only one in town, they're not just gonna milk all that money out of you.
Scott: Theoretically Nope, so yeah, so it used to be a second price bid deal, right?
Scott: Whereas now they've somewhat recently switched it to just first place.
Scott: wins, right?
Scott: And when it was second price wins, they were doing shenanigans putting in Extra higher bids.
Rym: right because I remember when I was running this for my old company We kept getting credits from Google where they'd be like, hey, here's 500 extra bucks just to spend on advertising.
Rym: So, of course if I put extra money in Google basically paid me to put in added ad buys.
Rym: That would raise the bid price Right.
Scott: So what?
Scott: yeah, so the other thing that happens is like, okay So let's say I put out, you know, I go make some bids, right?
Scott: let's say an ad cut someone visits a website right and That person trying to sell the space tries to sell it on the Google ad exchange and They also try to sell it on some other exchange.
Scott: that isn't the Google ad exchange Mmm, and I'm trying to buy ads and I'm not using the Google ads I'm using the something real.
Scott: and I'm looking at multiple exchanges to try to buy ads and I see The same ad spot show up on two different auction houses, right which can happen, right?
Scott: It's not like an antique that can only be in one auction house at a time.
Scott: It's like you got Sotheby's and you got Christie's and they're both auctioning the same Van Gogh.
Scott: Yeah at the same time, right and you're looking at the prices coming in from both and the people in the two auction houses don't realize they're competing with each other unless the people in both auction houses are Google because one auction house is run by Google and The person bidding for you in the Google auction house is Google.
Scott: You see how this could person bidding Person bidding in the non Google auction house.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, Google isn't running the other auction house But they're bidding in the other auction house.
Scott: So what happens is Google was putting in an Extra bid.
Scott: the same ad was in two different auction houses.
Scott: Google would put an extra bid in that was high in their auction house, right?
Scott: Making it right.
Scott: So now what happens is the Google auction house?
Scott: Ends up being the place where the winning bid is all the time, right?
Scott: So it's like oh, I'm selling I'm trying to sell my stuff and all these auction houses But the Google auction house always has the highest bids and keeps winning all the time.
Scott: That's where the big big bidders are, right?
Scott: And so I have to sell there if I'm an ad space seller Right and they're using that monopoly power to increment.
Rym: So Now this is sort of the the thing that I. this is pure speculation, but I wonder very strongly What's going to happen?
Rym: Let's say Google gets broken up and like they actually separate all these different like Stages of the ad world into different companies that can't collude with each other.
Rym: It is possible the money exchanged in advertising will drop like a rock because it's possible that it's all inflated by Google's shenanigans Mm-hmm.
Rym: It is also pie.
Rym: It's possible that Advertising as a bubble might collapse as a result of this.
Rym: It's possible that Google literally can't make money with anything It does accept the advertising.
Scott: Well, there's a few things that will happen.
Scott: First of all, right Google and every step all three steps.
Scott: Google is extracting fees Right.
Scott: So if there is no longer if there's a competitive marketplace There will be competitive pressure for the provider of each of the three services with the lowest fees.
Rym: Yeah, just like capital markets.
Rym: There's a concept of best execution.
Rym: You cannot just charge someone more to trade a stock if they could have gotten it cheaper elsewhere.
Rym: like you can get in trouble if if I take orders from Scott and Scott's paying me a fee for me to trade and then I trade them on My friend Joey Jojo's exchange instead of the nicey because Joey Jojo will give me a better commission rate.
Rym: That's illegal.
Rym: That is like literally illegal.
Scott: I realized something.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: I did not press record.
Rym: I have the backup.
Rym: It just means that the audio on this episode of GeekNights It's going to be what Scott sounds like through the discord and not Scott's real voice.
Rym: I pushed record just now My voice may suddenly change, you know, it's Monday so this is a good opportunity, uh, you know, normally this you'd hear the ad read was like speaking of.
Rym: This is why you have redundant fucking systems and backups.
Rym: kids Like I have so many backups of Scott's voice in case something like that happens.
Rym: That's why GeekNights.
Rym: So rarely fucks up anyway.
Scott: We didn't do I guess cuz of the hiatus we didn't actually say oh, let's push record.
Rym: I did say let's push record.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: Anyway, I didn't listen for your hack.
Rym: That's the other problem.
Scott: Anyway, I pushed it now.
Scott: So The last bit.
Scott: All right, so the people who were selling ad space, right?
Scott: Have somewhat recently the past few years is what I mean by recently, right tried to do this thing called a header bidding, right?
Scott: So what header bidding is is basically been them trying to get out from under Google's thumb, right?
Scott: Basically, they're putting they're trying to run the auction right in the header of the website technologically speaking.
Scott: hmm, so Basically, you know trying to get this auction done quickly before the rest of the website loads super fast and getting prices from a Lot bids from a lot of sources, right?
Scott: You know instead of where before what they used to do is they would do a waterfall kind of situation where they would say Hey you what's your bid?
Scott: and then they would go if they didn't like that.
Scott: if the bid was good enough They'd go with it.
Scott: and then you go to the second person and they say what's your bid?
Scott: Right until they found a bid they liked and at the very bottom was Google, right?
Scott: And if they it's like, okay we couldn't find anyone else who is buying this ad and We didn't sell the ad directly to someone.
Scott: So at the last case we're gonna ask Google, right?
Scott: And because they had this waterfall system Google knew how this waterfall system worked.
Scott: They manipulated it and even though they were at the bottom they could still get you to the bottom a lot Right and win.
Scott: So the header bidding is basically trying to get Simultaneous bids from everybody, right?
Scott: It's like instead of going from one to the next to the next until you find a number you like It's just hey everybody.
Scott: What will you pay?
Scott: all the numbers come back and then in the header of the website?
Scott: It's like which ad was gonna pay the most run that one And then you know you can.
Scott: we can't sit here to explain it all but Google tried to stop that - Google's was like man, this is gonna ruin us.
Scott: and they tried to put an end to it.
Scott: And it's like on the one hand.
Scott: It's like yeah, that was anti-competitive and bad But on the other hand they were fucking over people who were doing ads so I don't have that much sympathy.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the whole thing is like all this stuff.
Scott: Right when you read about what Google did and it's like you imagine yourself in the shoes of like the ad buyer getting ripped off Or the ad seller getting ripped off, but I hate.
Rym: I hate the ad buyers.
Rym: I hate the ad buyers with a passion already.
Rym: I hate.
Scott: I hate all three of these people.
Rym: It's like ad buyers are subsidizing all the technology that people use adblock run, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: so it's like oh, so it's like I don't really care if all these people who get fucked over This is just like a popcorn situation here, right?
Scott: That's what you got to remember.
Scott: But you know if you think ad buying and selling is okay Well, then yeah the ad people.
Scott: they got done dirty By how all this works and they had to do and that's why ads Technologically keep ruining websites because they have to keep doing more and more shenanigans Like the header bidding to get the websites to you know to get the money, right?
Scott: They if they just but if they so.
Scott: it was to make a website with like nice behaving ads right like just a JPEG that loads it doesn't track you and You know doesn't do anything shady and doesn't make the website load slow
Rym: Like if I got a hundred dollars for my jpeg to show up on his page Every time anyone loads it for a month like that is very simple and straightforward
Scott: Right, if you try to do ads like that the good way you won't make any freaking money.
Scott: There's no auctions happening.
Scott: You're gonna know not know get the right prices.
Scott: They're not gonna right.
Scott: It's like if you want to get more money You have to double this tracking and that way when you put your thing in the auction house It looks really good and the right buyer can find it and bid highly for it.
Scott: right?
Scott: and you have to make your website load a little bit slower so you can take a few extra milliseconds to get bids from More places and you have to show video ads because someone will pay more for those and so on and so on and so forth.
Rym: So what do you do?
Rym: Cuz we've gone on long.
Rym: this happens.
Scott: I like all ads everywhere always.
Scott: I've always run ad block block all ads no matter what because Just in computers and talking about in your entire life Anywhere, there are ads in your life anywhere billboards.
Scott: It's like there's only so much you can do.
Scott: but do what you can do find a way to You know blot them out of your life as much as possible, right and to.
Rym: if you try to read about what we talked about you're gonna see a lot of really really Jargony nonsense because the ad tech world uses its own language to describe everything We just described like DSPs and SSPs and all these different set.
Scott: here is the link to the justice.
Scott: the US Justice Department Just read that.
Rym: it explains everything.
Scott: It's on our website for our crew calm which has no ads on it.
Scott: I even remove Google Analytics from it.
Scott: Yeah, right if you scroll to the bottom of the page, I linked right on the page You're gonna see a diagram that shows what we explained.
Scott: but at the bottom It'll say attachments download complaint, right if you click download complaint, you're gonna get this PDF.
Scott: that is How long is this thing?
Scott: It's pretty long.
Rym: Yeah, but the way I describe it is this kind of document remember 155 page PDF, but it is very plain English very comprehensive.
Rym: I think this is a legal document.
Rym: So basically this has to convince like a judge and a bunch of people For a jury a jury trial, right?
Scott: So a jury is gonna read this and have to decide, you know, whether Google is guilty or not.
Scott: It's some day.
Scott: Hopefully right if there's not some sort of settlement or who knows what they're gonna do, right?
Rym: but your innovation is that the DOJ will not accept a settle.
Rym: they issued a statement to the effect of Promises of better future behavior and fines rarely achieve the desired results.
Rym: We are seeking a full breakup as the sole remedy.
Scott: Well here we can be at the very bottom in section 9. request for relief to remedy these illegal acts.
Scott: plaintiffs request that the court a judge and decree that Google has violated this law.
Scott: a judge and decree Google is violated.
Scott: attempted to mob monopolize in violation of the Sherman Act.
Scott: a Judge sure that they have broken other part of the Sherman Act Award damages order.
Scott: the divestiture of at minimum the Google ad manager suite Including both Google's publisher ad server and Google's ad exchange along with any additional structural relief as needed I'll share a head of harm and join Google from continuing to engage in the anti-competitive practices described here in Enter any other relief necessary to restore competitive conditions in the markets of ad buying and selling.
Scott: I'm paraphrasing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I think this is Or finds dropper and Award the plaintiffs as applicable an amount equal to cost attorneys fees and the the plaintiffs.
Scott: I isn't just the US Department of Justice.
Scott: It's also several states including California where Google is, yeah, New York, Connecticut, New Jersey, Tennessee, etc, etc.
Scott: So it's like you could see.
Scott: that's like anyone can understand that if you're literate in the English language, right?
Scott: Yeah, the whole big it the table of contents is just like how ad tech tools work how ad tech intermediaries get paid how publishers and advertisers select ad tech tools.
Scott: Google's scheme to dominate the ad tech stock.
Scott: and it's like Google in here They allege in my opinion correctly Google was actually making less money than it could have made in order to squelch competition.
Scott: Right if Google had done, I guess the right thing which is I guess the second best right thing The best thing being not having ads that the second best thing of running running these networks legitimately.
Scott: They would have made more money.
Scott: Right, they were giving up revenues in order to destroy competitors for the long-term play, which is the illegal part.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: Holy crap We are back from our hiatus and the patrons on patreon for GeekNights for this episode as we resume our regularly scheduled podcast Our Alan Joyce link eg dread Lily Tenebrae case care makes music.
Rym: Chris a dot Clinton Walton Dex Finn Joel Hayes penny Reimer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin Von Harl and stop all the downloading as well as many many people who either don't want me to say their names or are giving Just like a dollar because that's totally fine.
Rym: So yeah, we're back Regularly scheduled.
Rym: We're gonna do the Ramayama anime on Wednesday.
Rym: We're gonna do a leaf the unseen next Thursday We played a lot of video games.
Rym: I think Tuesday will be pretty easy.
Rym: We're pretty much back in the swing of things.
Rym: So for now, I just leave you with.