Rym: It's Wednesday, February 1st, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym. I'm Scott. and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about Ramayana the legend of Prince Rama the anime from.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh the last I'll say about that veil ski trip is uh, like.
Rym: I got some money.
Rym: Like I'm not rich like but I got I got money.
Rym: Yeah, I'm doing okay I can still forward to go ski in Colorado.
Rym: It's something a lot of you very fortunate.
Rym: So we stayed.
Rym: there's two main gondolas that go up that mountain.
Rym: There's the gondola one that goes like to the big central part of the mountain.
Rym: Everyone wants to get to.
Scott: so this isn't a ski Lift this is a gondola like like the Roosevelt Island sky.
Rym: Yeah, these things are huge.
Rym: Yeah And they they don't even take you all the way up They just take you like about halfway to three quarters way up the mountain and then there's lifts all over the mountain.
Rym: Yeah, so there's the main gondola that takes you to the better more central part up in the mountains and there's a newer gondola That's in this like side village.
Rym: That's like a 20-minute walk away on the other side of Vale and there's a gondola in that town, too But it goes up to like the edge of the mountain.
Rym: So To go up that gondola you take like you see down to once ride a lift up ski down again And then you're in the place that the other gondola takes you in one straight shot And it's a place you kind of want to get to.
Rym: so it's like the less convenient gondola and that side of town has fewer condos and fewer restaurants and Costs.
Scott: so basically the better spot.
Rym: Yeah, so the cheaper spot like the the less good spot cost a third.
Rym: What like any room would cost near the main gondola?
Rym: So we stayed in the cheaper side of town and the cheaper side of town had resort style.
Rym: Expensive food like it cost as much as eating in New York, but it was about as good as eating in Philadelphia.
Rym: So scojo loved it.
Rym: he thought the food was great I will tell you and it was like four out of ten on the Mexican food scale a Mexican food.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, the the fan that's not the kind of food I expected to be there.
Rym: Well, there's also like a bunch of bars and grills and they were five out of ten and six out of ten respectively.
Rym: those two.
Rym: We went to a fancy place on the other side of town one night and our friend Scott.
Rym: It was too fancy weed store for him.
Rym: He was not into the food But anyway, so we stayed in the cheaper side of town like Significantly cheaper and Unlike the third night.
Rym: We're done skiing and we just walk over to the other side of town.
Rym: There's that little bus and you can walk and we want to see.
Rym: uh, and I saw That the people who stay on that side of vale are a different class of having money from the class of having money that I'm in.
Rym: It is like starkly different between the two sides of town what they're like and this is epitomized by.
Rym: when we walked in and walked around town within four minutes of getting to that side of vale we Stopped because I saw through this through the window of a shop an item for sale and that item
Scott: was was it a ski Shop,
Rym: it was I'll give you a
Scott: shop.
Rym: was it was not a ski shop?
Rym: It was basically.
Scott: I thought it was a ski shop.
Scott: you
Rym: think that it was a gift shop
Scott: and it had a touristy shit Like, you know snow globes and
Rym: yeah stuff like
Scott: glasses Postcards things
Rym: the kind of person who's visiting vale and staying on that side might buy to bring like back home to their family from the trip.
Scott: This thing like I love veil t-shirt.
Rym: So I want to give you one guess how much this thing costs and I want to give you three guesses on what this thing was.
Scott: Okay, well how much?
Scott: probably tens of thousands of dollars?
Rym: All right, it was Seventeen thousand eight hundred dollars.
Rym: So you're actually in the ballpark.
Rym: I'd say that you got that one.
Rym: three guesses What the fuck it was and I'll be probably some high fashion brand Bag coat fashion item that it was not there were.
Rym: I saw Gucci skis.
Rym: I saw four and five thousand dollars like jackets and bags, but not a seventeen thousand eight hundred dollar thing.
Scott: All right, what would they sell in a ski place?
Scott: but it's not a ski shop it's a gift shop Yeah, but it caught.
Rym: it wasn't and it wasn't like a bag or a coat or anything like that.
Rym: Like.
Rym: it wasn't an item of fashion.
Rym: I'll keep this category real broad for your sake.
Rym: I mean, it could be anything could be anything but it was seventeen thousand eight hundred dollars.
Rym: The price is right.
Scott: What cause?
Scott: it's not.
Scott: It's not some kind of ski equipment.
Rym: It is not.
Rym: I'll give you that one for free because I said it's not a ski shop.
Rym: Yeah Can't do a Bob Barker voice.
Rym: what could cost seventeen thousand eight hundred dollars at?
Scott: It doesn't sound like it was food.
Scott: It was not food and it wouldn't be some sort of durable good because it's like.
Scott: that would only be useful for someone who lives There.
Scott: yeah, which is not a tourist item I'm just trying to think of like what you see in like New York touristy shops, right?
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: seventeen thousand eight hundred dollars You know.
Scott: in New York touristy shops are.
Rym: I guess, you know, I Mean it could I like a car dealership.
Rym: There are seventeen thousand dollar cars.
Rym: You can see through the window of a car dealership, but that's a durable good.
Scott: It's not gonna be a durable good.
Scott: Yeah, it'd be something in the Souvenir class.
Rym: Yeah, and you would you would never guess we.
Scott: we stood around like it like a watch would be obvious for 17,000 but it's probably not.
Rym: we stood around that window as a group for a while Marveling at that.
Scott: was it an artwork like an art gallery that it is adjacent to that.
Rym: Oh, so you know what it was.
Rym: Mmm, it was a dinosaur bone a full tibia a real one.
Rym: What a gigantic real.
Scott: that even legal.
Rym: I don't know But to multiple of us tried to make the.
Rym: that belongs in a museum reference Simultaneously and we stood around ridiculing it.
Rym: It was part of a set.
Rym: you could buy a bigger skeleton with multiple pieces for like to get there I don't know for like 80 or 90 thousand dollars.
Rym: or you could buy just the tibia for $17,800 and it just do with it and it just put it in your house and I don't know hit someone with it Donate it to the.
Rym: I mean, I imagine you know people say they want a conversation piece in their house.
Rym: I feel like if you had if you had this in your house Literally everyone who ever visited your house would immediately ask what the fuck is that?
Scott: You know, it's a much better conversation piece a plaster replica of a dinosaur bone $1,800.
Scott: people ask about.
Scott: and then you being you know, that cool old uncle grandpa type character are like Yeah dinosaur bone like grandpa on it grandpa killed Exactly here, right and you know, you don't need the real dinosaur bone to do that.
Rym: So in the news, uh You may remember I think we had to have done a gig nights episode on whispers of the heart and the cat returns.
Scott: I just assume I'm sure we did.
Rym: Yep, so I didn't even know.
Rym: this is apparently already coming out And somehow this just went off my radar.
Scott: I think we might have knew it existed, but I just wasn't interested at all.
Rym: I think we might have mentioned it on GeekNights when it was first announced and just never thought of it again.
Rym: But it's finally coming to theaters in LA and New York so we could see it.
Rym: if we wanted the live action Sequel to whispers of the heart, which is not episodes that either one Rym must have deleted them before.
Rym: Oh, that's that's much easy.
Scott: Wednesdays God, I remember like I'd have to rewatch cat returns.
Scott: I've seen whisper the heart enough times.
Scott: I don't need to rewatch funny I'm the opposite.
Rym: I've seen cat returns a bunch of times But I would need to rewatch whispers of the heart to make sure I didn't miss anything poignant to talk about Because that movies got a lot of subtle character interactions going on.
Scott: That's all it is.
Rym: Yeah, that movie is just hey, you want to watch a bunch of really subtle character growth over the course of an hour and change.
Rym: Okay, so it's airing.
Rym: you can see it in theaters You live in a real city, but it's not the cat returns which is sort of a sequel to whispers of the heart.
Rym: It is just a sequel to whispers of the heart itself directly where it's not a remake of whisper of the heart.
Rym: No, it is set ten years after whisper of the heart.
Scott: and is Shizuku maybe say now my?
Rym: in my my complete non-interest just changed to some interest and I watched the trailer and you know what it really is.
Rym: it is just a typical Japanese live-action like love story where what between like a musician and a struggling novelist and It has only a tenuous link as far as I can tell to the original whispers of the heart anime.
Scott: It's just my characters again returned to nothing.
Scott: Yes ten years into the future Yeah, you have you gave me some interest and you dashed it away.
Rym: Yep I was more interested until I watched the trailer and it just it.
Rym: it did not look compelling to People like you and me in terms of the type of media.
Rym: We would want to watch in the year 2023 is the way I would put it not saying it's bad.
Rym: I don't think it's for us Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, what do you got?
Scott: Well in speaking of trailers that are compelling, right?
Scott: There was a movie that came out several years ago called Shin Godzilla Which was you know made directed by Anno the guy right and it was Maybe the best Godzilla movie.
Scott: It's way up there, right?
Scott: It's like it's.
Scott: you know, and you know, he even brought in his little, you know Evangelion Tiffany's going on there right.
Scott: if you haven't seen Shin Godzilla like what the fuck?
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: but that in We all know that Anno is a huge fan of Ultraman.
Scott: That's like his favorite thing in the universe, right?
Scott: But he did not direct Shin Ultraman.
Scott: He produced it and had someone else direct Shin Ultraman And the idea was obviously that much in the way that you know.
Scott: Shin Godzilla Per you know made a new standalone Godzilla movie with a different sort of lens right filter on it.
Scott: Shin Ultraman would do the same thing.
Scott: make an Ultraman movie, you know.
Scott: a stat assumes that you know This.
Scott: it's the only thing in the Ultraman universe, right?
Scott: Yeah, but clearly sticks to the cannon and you know has lots of fan service for Ultraman fans just like the Godzilla one did and You know, but has that sort of aesthetic to it, right.
Scott: and so this movie came out last year 20 summer 2022 Maybe I want to say took a long time to make apparently Yeah And I waited patiently for it to come out in the US legally and sure enough While Rym was I guess just about to go away.
Scott: I think It played in the theater with subtitles in in the US.
Rym: I was like I was gonna go see it.
Rym: I was in Germany at the time or like about to leave for Germany.
Scott: Anyway, I was wait.
Scott: I was really hyped up to see it because the trailer was Right.
Scott: such a good trail.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It may even though I don't really know that much about Ultraman I just know the basics right and I don't have like emotional nostalgic attachment to it.
Scott: Yeah, I thought he always looked kind of weird and didn't look cool.
Scott: You know, I was excited to see this cuz Shin Godzilla was so good.
Scott: So I go to see it.
Scott: and first of all, it's one of those fathom events right, which is fine.
Scott: and Secondly before the movie the movie was supposed to start at like 730.
Scott: I think right now and They start doing that.
Scott: They're promoting for some reason this like current Ultraman TV series.
Scott: That's gonna.
Scott: that's happening right now.
Scott: that has like 500 different Ultraman in it you know and It's like I'm sitting there thinking like they're promoting this Ultraman show to the US audience.
Scott: I'm like, how many fans of this are there in the US.
Rym: they make you watch something about all 500 Ultraman.
Rym: Is that what happened?
Scott: Somebody's paying to dub this right and bring it out here.
Scott: I'm like how many people care about this, right?
Scott: And so they do this trivia right for it and It's not true.
Scott: It's like it's not it's trivia.
Scott: We're like you would have to be an Ultraman super nerd to know.
Rym: No, it's like when we tried to run a version of challenger on fire at Katsucon and all the guests got the first one Wrong.
Rym: and we're like, okay.
Scott: Oh Yeah And Like it's multiple choices four choices But all of them was like was it Ultraman Taiga or Ultraman Zeeborb or whatever?
Scott: It's like the fuck do I know?
Scott: right?
Scott: and so it.
Scott: finally, you know Everyone's getting pretty impatient because it's really slow trivia.
Scott: They get to the tenth question and we're like everyone's like.
Scott: this has to be the last one right?
Scott: ten ten questions make sense.
Scott: after the tenth question, there was an eleventh question and the entire theater groaned like So there were no Ultraman.
Scott: so I'm like.
Scott: the fact that everyone groaned simultaneously Really made me confirm like who is the audience for bringing?
Scott: You know, we're there to see shin Ultraman.
Scott: None of us care about actual Ultraman.
Scott: So the movie itself right in some ways was quite good right.
Scott: the the action scenes Were you know?
Scott: Had some of the corniness of the tokusatsu right to keep it authentic.
Scott: But also like some pretty amazing like oh shit like he just did that kind of stuff going on Right, like, you know the kind of shit you see and say a studio trigger kind of anime, right?
Scott: Punching the earth kind of stuff.
Scott: And also it's like Ultraman is an alien, right?
Scott: That's his deal.
Scott: He's not a robot, right?
Scott: He's an alien.
Scott: and they did quite a good job of like making him seem alien and getting across that theme of like Ultraman being the person who sort of the go-between between humanity and Extraterrestrials right like he can understand both sides Right, but he the way he acts and moves is like, you know slightly inhuman, right?
Scott: Uncanny Valley.
Scott: and I think that really worked well because all like I said the estate what Ultraman looks like is kind of goofy right, but by making that goofiness and Keeping it and making it instead of goofiness be like alien this right it made it make sense Because
Rym: I'm always a fan of Non-human characters like feeling viscerally inhuman and weird when you interact.
Scott: Yeah, so those are the good parts of the movie.
Scott: The rest of the movie was not bad, but somewhat disappointing.
Scott: Sure, okay.
Scott: So the movie?
Scott: basically it feels like a bunch of Ultraman episodes like stuck together like end to end.
Scott: and it's like it Like it's like each thing he fights.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like they took a TV episode.
Scott: We're like they an alien a bad alien appears.
Scott: the humans figure out what to do about it Right, and then eventually there's an encounter right and they fight and Ultraman wins or loses and they then they do it again Repeatedly like four or five times.
Scott: I'd say I forget exactly how many and you know as it goes on the bad guys are getting stronger and more powerful and More serious and each one is sort of different in the way that they have to deal with it.
Scott: But it's like some stuff is super rushed some stuff is you know drawn out It's you know, it wasn't that well Put together and I think a lot of it was.
Scott: you know does have that problem where if you weren't already an Ultraman Superfan who knew a lot of things about Ultraman a lot of things just happen that have no meaning for you whatsoever Right now.
Rym: that's something that better Movies of IPs that have that kind of fan who exists.
Rym: do where like.
Rym: yeah, you'll get it and enjoy it without knowing that context.
Rym: But you'll enjoy more if you have that context, but it's not required to have that context.
Rym: It's a fine art.
Scott: I don't think it was required but it would.
Scott: it would have helped quite a bit, right?
Scott: It's like there's a lot of things that just like didn't have any Emotional and I think it felt like the movie they were supposed to.
Scott: yeah you know, the other thing is the What's it called like Godzilla right?
Scott: First of all, Godzilla doesn't have that much lower Right and what it does have has never really been like, you know Can't like this, you know, Godzilla movies even old ones before shin Godzilla are all over the place.
Scott: Yeah, right It's like they're not all right, but Ultraman has a more Consistent lore between all the Ultramans.
Scott: I don't know if it's a hundred percent.
Rym: I imagine the fans care a lot about that lore the ones that they.
Scott: Because there was because Godzilla didn't have as much lures The shin Godzilla didn't have as much.
Scott: but because Ultraman did shin Ultraman had more going on there, right?
Scott: it's like at one point like some other characters show up and it's like out of nowhere and I imagine if I had watched a bunch of Ultraman, I would have been like, oh shit That's who that is.
Scott: All right, but it's like I didn't know who that was.
Scott: Yeah But Anyway things of the day.
Rym: so I don't really like.
Rym: there's those YouTube shorts and There's not a lot of content in the YouTube shorts Like they.
Rym: there's like.
Scott: there's that one person in the YouTube shorts who does like the little comedy skits in like always in some kind of costume In the human body or a Noah's Ark or in history somewhere.
Rym: There's also the deadpan guy who has the little clips of like I pretended to be the city of LA on Facebook.
Scott: No, but I'm telling the costume person They had they are churning out short videos like a machine like they have so many.
Rym: so I scrolled down on the HTPC last night and We're gonna look for a YouTube video and I accidentally hit the shorts and they kind of just start auto playing.
Rym: But the one that auto played was actually really good and really funny and it is my thing of the day.
Scott: Yeah, I had seen this one previously.
Rym: Yeah, but it starts with the for the listener.
Rym: It starts with one of those tick-tock trends where someone like asks a question or gives you a prompt and you're supposed to put that at the front of your video and then you put your answer to the prompt.
Rym: as the rest of the video and the prompt was the biggest lie.
Rym: an adult told you that you later found out the truth and The response is a like 40 second song Where you see where it's going and it it's funny where it goes but the delivery of the reveal Pushes it up to about an 8 out of 10.
Rym: Like I was laughing out loud Mm-hmm.
Rym: I'm not gonna spoil anything.
Rym: It's a. it's a 59 second video.
Rym: So I Don't know much more.
Rym: I can say you should all watch this video.
Scott: The person with the costumes by the way is Adrian bliss.
Scott: Right and boy do they have a lot of short videos on here.
Rym: Alright, so what do you got?
Scott: Oh thing of the day wise?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What did I have?
Rym: Let me remember Brad Williams is the guy I was told not Brad Williams different Brad.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So in the 70s, there was this artist.
Scott: their name was.
Scott: the webpage is loading.
Scott: I forget their name The concrete guy.
Scott: Yeah, basically this dispersions art Wolf Vostell, right?
Scott: I think they were Swiss They were an artist and their shtick was one of their sticks was encasing things in concrete, right?
Scott: you know one of their famous works was concrete traffic where they took like an old car and they encased the car in concrete.
Scott: and The car is in Chicago in a parking garage and you can see a picture of it in this in this article here.
Scott: one of their other artworks was they took a book and encased it in concrete.
Scott: and that book is Right is in the Chicago University Library as a book, but if you just take it, it's just a slab of concrete.
Scott: You don't know.
Scott: and the question is is there a book in there?
Scott: Right, or is this just a rectangle like the car?
Scott: It's like you.
Scott: the car is in there.
Scott: You can see the wheels sticking out like.
Scott: they know the car is in there.
Scott: But the book could just be a rectangle of concrete and it's like, you know.
Scott: And if if it is a book that's in there, is it the book that they said was in there?
Scott: Or is it a piece of paper?
Scott: No, it's in there.
Rym: You know, what's in there?
Rym: the Baron?
Scott: Yeah, so in this article they discuss right briefly What they are trying to do and what they have tried to do to determine if There's a book in there.
Scott: What's in there?
Scott: What does it look like?
Scott: What is it right without?
Scott: Breaking it open?
Scott: Right because you don't want to ruin this somewhat famous and important artwork, right?
Rym: It looks like they found a rebar in there, which makes sense.
Rym: You can't just make a piece of concrete like that without a breaking.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So I think that's pretty pretty interesting.
Rym: Yeah in the meta moment the GeekNights book club book was a leaf the unseen.
Rym: It has been seen to the end next week on Thursday.
Rym: We'll be doing a show on that.
Rym: Also GeekNights will be live at PAX East 2023 on Thursday March 23rd at 2 30 p.m in the bumblebee theater with a panel that actually we've only ever done once and only like 100 people at magfest ever saw it.
Rym: and we're probably gonna rewrite the whole thing because I was looking at the slides and I got A lot of thoughts already.
Rym: can competitive and casual coexist in the same game Mm-hmm?
Rym: So yeah, that'll be fun.
Scott: It might be possible, but it's rarely accomplished.
Rym: and yeah I feel like it might actually be impossible without there being a wall between the games that make them different.
Rym: games Could be but we'll see.
Rym: do we know the answer to that question?
Rym: No, we still have to finish writing the panel.
Rym: So Otherwise, uh join the GeekNights forum.
Rym: You might have noticed stop you stopped using Twitter quite some time ago, but bit by bit I see you appearing in my Mastodon, which is actually just a republish of my microblog.
Scott: I'm working on creating a new Internet life system and you know We're gonna take our time with it and make sure we get it right because I want to make something that will last The rest of my days so I don't have to put up with this ever again
Rym: And I'm
Scott: at least last the rest of my days as long as HTTP lasts the rest of my days Which I presume it will and
Rym: I'm keeping an eye on Scott does because my solution is yeah.
Scott: I mean whatever I make will be you could use it.
Rym: Yeah, and I imagine you and I have very similar Desires about how to engage with the internet in most ways.
Rym: So I feel like whatever you build will end up being better than what I'm doing Which is I didn't want to write any code.
Rym: I was lazy.
Rym: So I basically bought some hosting and cobbled three or four services together to me.
Scott: I don't think it'll be like the only way that what I make will be better than what you know is.
Scott: if you know It becomes like a company and a bunch of people work on it, which is there's no way You know, it's like that.
Scott: I can make something that is all those features Right of like an actual other product.
Rym: I have two superpowers.
Rym: I am a Legit professional product manager and I am really good at convincing people to do things that might not be in their best interest.
Rym: We could probably get some people to start working on it.
Scott: If you had the cord on we can't even finish our own website Which is what I'm doing first.
Rym: Should I should I evenly try to convince people?
Rym: It'd be really cool to work on the website with you.
Scott: The main thing really the only hard yell right the actual import of our day, right?
Scott: We've.
Scott: I've already imported the news I'm working on importing the book clubs and then I got to import the actual episodes and then that's most of it.
Scott: But then there's a bunch of tidying up and then there's the real nerd That is that stands for extract Transform and load.
Scott: it is not even that much data on our cart website.
Scott: It's only like, you know a few thousand records.
Rym: Yeah but it's the the sheer amount of pain in the ass it actually takes compared to the pain in the ass that a naive person who is not a software person expects it to take.
Rym: When you have a bunch of data in something and all you want to do is move that data into something else That isn't the same thing.
Rym: You might think that like you might expect that to be a certain amount of pain.
Rym: It is such a pain in the ass that there are Hundreds and hundreds of companies whose sole job is to do this for you for extremely large amounts of money And those companies make tons of money.
Scott: It might honestly be faster with only a thousand something episodes to like, you know Do a really crappy ETL then clean it up by hand.
Rym: I was actually gonna possibly suggest that kind of like how it's sometimes cheaper to just fill a UPS truck with Hard drives that it is to send data over a pipe.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I'm writing a whole thing to get like the episode numbers, you know, the forum links, correct, right?
Scott: It's like what if you just sat there and like went to each episode and found the forum post and pasted the link.
Scott: Yeah So because this only has to be done once like I'm writing code To do a thing that only that code will run once and be thrown out.
Rym: Yep It's not like we're making a pipeline to be able to regularly and repeatably Take a GeekNights podcast websites and import them into our new website.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It's writing all this code to do a thing one time.
Scott: It's like Where's all the other code that's much easier to write is code that will run every single time.
Scott: So it visits the website every single time.
Scott: Rym makes a new episode.
Scott: That's much more important.
Rym: Yep All right.
Rym: So main bid we ended up going because our friend cat Reminded us this was happening and got all of us tickets.
Rym: We went to see Ramayana the Legend of Prince Rama which has been described by people who don't pay that much attention as the Ghibli Ramayana, which is a tangentially Somewhat true in that a number of animators who went on to form and work in Studio Ghibli worked on this movie.
Rym: But it is not a Ghibli movie.
Scott: No, the Ghibli Totoro does not appear at the beginning of this film.
Scott: So the deal I didn't know this existed before he went to see it and I did some minor research.
Rym: if I if I knew it Existed I feel like Mike tool told me it existed and I just forgot.
Scott: Well, it's it's on it.
Scott: You can watch it all on YouTube in low resolution.
Rym: I mean, this is this anime is in the genre of anime.
Rym: Mike tool will tell you about.
Scott: Yeah, if you look for it on YouTube, it's there and low res.
Scott: maybe Rym could link to that.
Scott: in the episode We saw a 4k digital rescan remaster of the movie Which had the same audio track as the YouTube one, but that was not the original audio track.
Scott: It's a.
Rym: it's an English dub Yep, and it was only screened once and apparently there is no legal way to show it anywhere in the United States.
Scott: it was screened twice once before and then once when we saw it.
Rym: All right, so Screening they can do in the modern era I guess right.
Scott: the the original one could be seen all over the place I guess at certain times, right?
Scott: Yeah before k1 in the US has not been fully licensed distributed, etc.
Scott: But in other places it may have already been and you know Depending on where you are in the world.
Scott: You might be able to see the 4k version we saw in who knows what language.
Rym: Anyway, yep, and it was what the hell is available in parts of India at some points and not at other points and never in Some other parts of India.
Rym: There's a. there's a. it is one of those movies Where if you go to the Wikipedia page just to give you context you'll get a brief one paragraph explaining it a list of the Cast one paragraph about the production and then an entire section titled controversies.
Scott: So what I know about it is you know, the the brief research I did yeah I was like reading a couple things is that they you know There was one of those cultural partnership things right that like every country loves to do except the United States because the United States You know as very has the superiority complex.
Scott: so they think other countries are other countries, right?
Scott: whereas other countries Think of themselves as equals to other countries or at least that's the way it appears to me.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: and so you'll have partnerships like oh so and so cultural exchange between European country and African country.
Scott: and they do it the thing and make an artwork and have an Event.
Scott: and you know, so Japan does these a lot And what they like, you know, we talked about flying go ship on GeekNights.
Scott: that was a Japan Russian deal.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if it's a cultural exchange deal, but it was an international, you know thing.
Scott: We've seen a lot of Japan France action going on.
Rym: Oh, yeah Countries love it that love the comic book and love the animation.
Scott: Yep, but This is Japan India to celebrate their many years of you know, friendship, right?
Scott: Someone got a bunch of money from some where who knows.
Rym: so there's I. I know more of this story.
Rym: So the guy who put this all together Was you go Sacco?
Rym: This was the guy and he was in.
Rym: he went to India and he was making a documentary in India for the Japanese audience about the Archaeological excavation of some place that's relevant to the real Ramayana.
Rym: Like that's what was going on.
Rym: All right According to Wikipedia and some other.
Rym: I found some other articles that all just say the same thing But I couldn't find a ton of reporting on this.
Rym: So I'm going on.
Rym: I'm going on like four sources that are all kind of circular in the 80s While this was going on Nationalist newspaper in India Sort of mischaracterized the work he was doing and said, oh, he's not making a documentary He's making of an animated version of the Ramayana like that.
Rym: you can't do that.
Rym: and the Nationalist got really mad about it and It seems like his response was well, I'm not making that but that's a good idea.
Rym: So he got people together and got some money and they went to the Indian government and the Indian government actually was very on board until it suddenly wasn't because the Nationalist got extremely mad about this.
Rym: and Eventually the Indian or agency the Indian government agency that was working with this studio and Japan backed out and said yeah We're not gonna help anymore.
Rym: But the studio continued over a decade to finish the movie and they had.
Scott: I took them a decade.
Scott: They worked on this in the early 80s like and it took them to like a decade to finish this.
Rym: Yeah, but they did employ a large number of Indian animators who wanted to work on the project Despite the Indian government not wanting it to proceed.
Rym: and it seems like this was all sort of Extra complicated because there was an incident that I don't know a lot about.
Scott: You just read about it in Wikipedia.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: Well, I remember Someone typing in whatever the IOG a dispute which I remember hearing about at RIT actually in a politics class and That was the only time I'd ever heard of it because it's a relatively recent dispute.
Rym: It's very similar to his disputes around Jerusalem and while that dispute was ongoing the Indian government basically was like, yeah We're not gonna say shit about Ramayana at any point in any capacity in public because we're gonna piss somebody off no matter what and we really want this problem To die down.
Rym: so there are big cultural controversies around the creation and existence of this movie and those seem to be a big part of why it.
Rym: There aren't really rights to screen it in most places.
Scott: Well, somebody put the effort into 4k remaster it when they did a great job visually
Rym: yeah, and it looks like the intent is to release it again and have screenings of it because the Interesting thing is from everything I can gather There was an era in India where it was just shown in theaters and kids who saw it in theaters They fucking remember it.
Rym: That's like all the Ramayana movie.
Rym: We all saw that like.
Rym: a lot of people know about it and it is very well known outside of the US.
Scott: Hmm so what the hell is this movie like?
Scott: well You can sort of tell when you're watching it that it was made over the course of ten years because the early parts of the Film I mean, I know they don't usually animate films like from beginning to end.
Scott: Oh, but this one seems like they really animated it from beginning to end really feels like in order.
Rym: They animated the park as the beginning.
Rym: like every scene in the beginning It's really long by the way is like, you know those Christian animations Or like Patriotic animations they make in America that kids something that Ned Flanders would show his kids exactly Where it's like a minimum effort.
Rym: like all the characters from the important historical thing are on screen And they all say the right things that up.
Rym: that canonically happened.
Rym: and the narrative And then Jesus went to Nazareth it narrator.
Rym: it's like strictly adhering to the most common reading of the Ramayana that would be known in India like very strictly and it's just this scene happens.
Rym: then this scene happens then this scene happens and Then it kind of goes off the rails About a third.
Scott: So first of all, right, so the the Animation quality right in the early parts of the movie is not awful, right?
Scott: Yeah, but it's also not like amazing.
Rym: or the characters stay Remarkably on model from don't think But they don't move around a lot in the first third of the movie.
Rym: They kind of just stand there.
Scott: Yeah, so and you can tell like it feels like that's the part they must have animated in the 80s or maybe it right.
Scott: I feel
Rym: like the turning point between the Indian government's on board and the Indian government is not on board
Scott: Probably
Rym: coincides with this is a strict retelling - now there's not there's jets
Scott: Right, so then towards the end of the movie there's a battle right like a giant war.
Scott: and it's like, you know in that part You can sort of absolutely tell that it was animated by people with Studio Ghibli experience.
Scott: Yeah, you know cuz clearly you're see that just the style the way things move the you know the it's like.
Scott: you can just tell right away the like.
Rym: if someone animated a Really long level in dynasty warriors with Studio Ghibli level skills like that is where in style that is what it feels like.
Scott: Yeah, like it's you it's immediately apparent that the Studio Ghibli and just it's the animation towards the end there Especially in the 4k.
Scott: like it doesn't come across on YouTube at all But it's like in the 4k one.
Scott: It was actually quite unbelievable the the cell animation going on towards the end of this movie.
Rym: Yep And if you're not story the Ramayana It's.
Rym: it is very I'd say it's analogous to the the story of the Trojan War If you're someone who would know about one and not the other.
Scott: hmm But you know, it's a. it's not that exciting a story.
Scott: It's a rescue the princess kind of deal.
Rym: Yep, right Yeah, it's.
Rym: I mean the.
Rym: the vague gist of the Ramayana Which is there are like radically different versions of it out there and even different versions in different countries near India But the one as portrayed in this anime it seems that lines up with the one that I know Best ish from like a middle school and it's basically you've got a really good King and there's a neighboring kingdom That is run by demons and demon people But that someone in the good Kings court Convinces one of his wives to do a really shady thing for no reason and forces the king to Basically exile his best smartest most perfect son to the
Scott: wood.
Rym: everyone love everyone loves Rama his perfect son.
Scott: Also everyone in the good kingdom is good and smart except for that one person who convinced the king.
Rym: The king is like everyone like.
Rym: I don't want to do this, but I'm standing by my word.
Rym: Rama is like look I know you don't want to do it but I'm gonna do exactly what the law says because I am also perfect and good and the whole kingdom is weeping and everyone everyone Agrees, everyone's perfect and good.
Rym: everyone agrees this sucks, but we got to do it yep, and then a demon steals his wife from the woods and then the Trojan War starts and the entire rest of the story is the war to What do they call it at the end of the movie?
Rym: Thus was the tale of the avoidable war.
Scott: Yeah, very avoidable war.
Scott: but the thing is the hero of the movie is supposed to be Rama the guy whose name is in The title.
Scott: Yeah, and he is to some extent.
Scott: but the real hero is He on his way to the war.
Scott: his army is not an army of people from his country.
Scott: The army is the monkey kingdom.
Rym: Yeah, Hanuman is doing all the fucking work here.
Scott: one of the monkeys is magical and can grow giant and That's the real hero.
Scott: He's due each carrying the whole load, right?
Scott: It's like, you know Rama just like steps in.
Scott: at the end.
Scott: It's like the the giant monkey did all the real.
Scott: Okay But yeah, so that's that the story is not that compelling right.
Scott: the Audio track that we heard which is the one you'll hear on YouTube is a really bad Not the worst but pretty bad.
Rym: English English charitable, you know what it sounds like.
Rym: it Reminds me of the music they put in the dub of Dominion tank police instead of the original music Like it's very synthy and very simple like it kind of sounds like it was made on a Casio keyboard.
Rym: Like the act the acting is bad, you know, yeah You know who's acting was good though the evil king that that character's voice Was actually pretty a plus a bet better than the other character.
Rym: Yeah, he was.
Rym: he would have been fine and cowboy bebop as an English dub actor.
Scott: right, but the music what happens is in the movie there are a few scenes where there is songs and During those song parts you can sort what I'm guessing because that's the way it sounds.
Scott: It sounds like they cut away from the English dub and played the original, you know is a Hindi language.
Scott: I'm assuming right track and that sounds.
Scott: you know The audio quality is low because it's some old audio track from the 80s or 90s, right?
Scott: But it still sounds incredible compared to the English dub You were just listening to.
Scott: right and I would really love to watch the whole thing with that audio track and subtitles.
Scott: I think that would be very nice.
Rym: But what is the rest of this movie like like basically.
Rym: after that very relatively short initial setup the war starts and it's basically Just Rama and his army fight a dangerous entity then they fight the even more dangerous guy Then they fight the mini-boss then they fight the boss then they fight the square boss then there's jet fighters then it's over.
Scott: The jet fighter is the the square bosses first.
Rym: Yeah, the square boss ends up having multiple forms one of which is a fighter jet.
Scott: right, but yeah, it's like During these battles, right?
Scott: It's like amazing Like shit happens.
Scott: that is like very audience pleased and everyone's very different.
Rym: almost to the point It feels like a different Animator was in charge of like each fight scene because every one of them has a very distinctive style and they're all pretty different.
Scott: Right like the it sort of begins.
Scott: actually they're the demon kingdom is on an island and they have to get to the island.
Scott: So like the first thing that's amazing is like they build a stone bridge to get to the the island.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: and it's like that scene is just like a super well animated scene and you could tell like Ghibli's throwing in a lot of Environmental stuff in there, you know, it's like it's real good.
Scott: You know, there's just.
Scott: they're not even talking They're just animating these monkeys building a bridge Out of magical floating stones and it's awesome, right.
Scott: then they get there, you know They have a regular fight with you know, some dudes right, you know, just and then it really happens.
Scott: is you know?
Scott: There's some injuries that happen.
Scott: So they need healing.
Scott: but the healing herbs on the demon land don't work.
Scott: So They find out somehow I forget that they have to get healing herbs from the Himalayas.
Rym: So Hanuman just flies there and brings the Himalayas the giant.
Scott: the giant monkey can also fly.
Scott: Well the shape the size-changing monkey can also fly.
Rym: you get the scene where they unlock his power.
Rym: They're like look we your powers were locked away cuz we didn't want you to fuck around.
Rym: so you can have all your power now.
Rym: Don't go too nuts.
Scott: Yeah, he flies to the Himalayas.
Scott: He finds the herbs right and he's like how am I gonna get all these herbs back to the the battlefield and the demon?
Scott: Island?
Scott: he picks up the whole mountain And carries it.
Scott: it's um, it's incredible.
Scott: it's like oh shit he picked up the whole Right and it basically carries on like that.
Scott: It's like what he brings the whole mountain there.
Scott: They actually show him bring you back at the end of the movie out to put it back where it belongs.
Scott: It's like, you know, they does.
Scott: he has to fight another giant.
Scott: They have to.
Scott: there's like these giant monkey war machines at one point only in that one scene, but they're so good Right, and then there's like that when the final demon King comes out.
Scott: it's like his first form is like there's no Chekhov's like Lee, you know Tinting that this exists.
Scott: He just comes out in a fighter jet shooting like grenade arrows Right and electrified weeks.
Rym: a lot of the later parts of the fight scenes reek of the animators in Japan being like, you know What'd be cool?
Rym: Let's interpret this magical stuff as technology.
Rym: I'm gonna do this.
Rym: I want to animate technology.
Rym: I want to animate a month.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Yep, I want to animate a fighter jet.
Scott: Let's do it.
Scott: He comes out they fucking he gets his head just chopped off right on screen and another head starts growing.
Rym: I think they cut off and a third one starts making its way up.
Scott: Yeah, then he becomes really enormous and has a bunch of heads and then it's a fist of the North Star situation.
Scott: little guy for his Big guy, it's like it gets really off the hook in the battle and it's it's fun.
Scott: It's a lot of fun seeing this amazing animation with these ridiculous awesome scenes going on but otherwise It's really long.
Rym: Yeah, so can I long?
Rym: writing in variety in 1993 said quote the film is Relentlessly paced and has no heart.
Scott: It definitely has no heart.
Scott: That's true It's.
Scott: the only heart is the heart that those animators put in to those You know battle scenes towards the end where they were having fun with it, right?
Scott: There's no other heart anywhere else to be found.
Rym: I gotta say though if I was a kid Like cuz I went to Catholic school when I was young and they put in one of those Ned Flanders tapes and a third of The way through it turned into this.
Scott: That would be a lot more attention.
Rym: My favorite bit is the one story the one brother of the king who is I think is a brother the giant guy Who's asleep and halfway through the fighting?
Rym: They're like, oh the war is not going so well.
Rym: Should we wake up her brother?
Rym: and they're like, ah, we could but he's so close to achieving immortality.
Rym: Let him sleep longer.
Scott: So they kind of story is this this giant dude who's actually?
Scott: he's a demon?
Scott: He's on the demons side or the demon kingdom, but he's not a bad guy right and all his sons aren't bad people either.
Scott: They're just in the demon kingdom fighting for the demon kingdom, right?
Scott: You see that trope a lot, right?
Scott: It's like the guy who you know, you know is he's lives in the bad country, right?
Scott: But he's you know, is he bad?
Scott: It's a good example.
Scott: Gundam What Romborall is like?
Scott: Yeah, he fights for Zeon, right?
Scott: But he's like a good dude and Eve even when the good guys beat him.
Scott: They're sad Like the character who supports honorable guy who was on the wrong?
Rym: Or the one who ends up supporting evil but still has a sense of honor like that's a trope in a lot of media Right, so that's what is this giant and his kids?
Scott: are that right there?
Scott: the on the bad team?
Scott: They are bad But they have honor and what you get to see it like all the little giant dude is Sleeping and if he can sleep without waking up for what six or seven years, he will become Immortal, right?
Scott: So once Rama starts causing trouble the demons like try to wake him up.
Scott: They're like, oh shit We might need the giant guy to help win this fight and they blow some horns in his ear.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's like it's not working.
Scott: It's like alright, maybe we'll just let him become immortal.
Scott: Let's see if we can handle it right without him.
Scott: Yeah, they can't.
Rym: They come back like an hour later.
Scott: Yeah shit gets dire and they're like, oh crap.
Scott: We really do have to wake him up We're losing.
Rym: They like have elephants knock him over and they dump like a mountains worth of water on it.
Scott: They put it they put a bowl next to his head and I'm like, oh are they gonna put his hand to make him pee?
Scott: If he pees they'll be a flood PBF Right, but no they have a whole army of elephants.
Scott: Roll them over into into the water so that he'll wake up.
Rym: He's animated.
Rym: He's just like son of a bitch.
Rym: All right, whatever.
Rym: I'll go take care of it.
Rym: And he's like.
Scott: he's like.
Scott: I'm pissed that you woke me up and I didn't achieve immortality, but I'm up now.
Scott: So I might as well get this over with before I start sleep Yeah, and he's perfectly polite before he starts fighting with Rama's army.
Scott: Yeah It's.
Rym: uh, I don't know this.
Rym: I like it like.
Rym: I think you said it best.
Rym: I'm glad I saw it and if you have the chance to see it like remastered.
Scott: it's worth it If you just want to have a sort of a good time.
Scott: if you go to YouTube You watch the low res one.
Scott: You can just sort of skip to the the later parts and just sort of watch those awesome.
Scott: See if until the money show up.
Rym: also I got to say the man's like the regular demons.
Rym: if you find really monkeys are building really well animated like they're just funny little guys.
Scott: find where the monkeys are building the stone bridge and that's where you can start watching.
Rym: basically and Strap in cuz it's just gonna be a series of disjointed anime fights.
Rym: The only it they edged real close into heaven in a ton of circus the way this was animated.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I think he just didn't make sense to have missiles.
Scott: yeah But there was that.
Scott: there was a Chekhov's chakra.
Rym: Yeah, but soon as that in the beginning cuz Rama's like what's this?
Rym: Oh, that's the chakra.
Scott: Yeah, they give at the beginning of the movie.
Scott: They give Rama like a whole set of magical weapons like here's your magical weapon equipment And he's like one of them is just a ring.
Scott: It's like a you know throwing blade right chakra, whatever and he's like What's this one?
Scott: They're like you'll know when the time comes and it's like he's gonna beat the final boss with that.
Scott: It's like yeah, of course Yeah, it basically works.
Rym: the same way.
Rym: Sailor Moon's first attack works.
Rym: It just fuck.
Scott: Yeah, it's tiara.
Scott: whatever.
Rym: Every other attacks you had seemed way less dangerous than that one.
Scott: What's the name of that attack?
Rym: if I remember I haven't seen Sailor Moon all the way since?
Rym: 2000 moon tiara action Thursday, but every half season they name it something different.
Scott: Okay, well the internet says it's moon tiara action where she sees like I'll punish you and then she throws up.
Rym: But yeah, if you could see this it's kind of we're seeing if you have an interest in if nothing else.
Rym: It's important because the story of how it was made and the fact that it somehow was made it's a.
Scott: it's a significant and interesting work that has you know, really good value.
Scott: animation wise and You know, perhaps so historically it for some people But is not by any means some a S-tier kind of deal.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like it will Appear off and on again in late-night rooms at anime cons and Mike tool kind of panels and it's the kind of thing.
Scott: Hey, did you know this cool?
Scott: Did you know this cool thing exists?
Scott: Check out this giant demon guy.
Rym: if I were still in charge of a anime club What I would do is we would definitely screen this one night Like we'd figure out a way to scream stream it but you'd want to hype it up to make sure people know They're getting into something weird.
Rym: So you'd probably get a full house just because of the story alone how this thing was made.
Rym: Maybe this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons who wanted me to say their name for this episode of GeekNights, I'm waiting for the page to load and sort our Alan Joyce linkagey dread lily tenebrae case.
Rym: care makes music.
Rym: Chris a dog Clinton Walton Dex Finn Joel Hayes Penny rhymer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin on oral and many many people who are giving Exactly $1 because that is the minimum.
Rym: patreon lets you and while you don't have to do that GeekNights will always be free.
Rym: one of the reasons people seem to do this is because you get a Private RSS feed in patreon and if you're subscribed to other things in patreon That seems to be easier.
Rym: that will continue to work with the new GeekNights website.
Rym: But anyway, that's neither here nor there for now.
Rym: tonight I simply leave you with Tell me the biggest lie an adult has ever
Scott: told you
Rym: and when
Scott: you figured out it was a lie I was
Rym: eight and in a play where we made our own instruments and me and some kids did percussion They said we should make some shakers with cans and paper
Scott: and then
Rym: Just fill it up with something.
Rym: Well, our moms made the shakers and most filled them with beans.
Rym: But my mom said she filled mine up with fish rocks.
Rym: then the bean kids gathered round.
Rym: That's what was making my sound.
Rym: I said y'all are in for a big shock Said there's aquarium gravel in my shaker So get ready for a different kind of music.
Rym: They said we don't believe you.
Rym: I said I'll give you a preview.
Rym: So I opened up my shaker to prove it and there were beans just beans just beans.