Rym: It's Monday, March 27th, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym, and I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about archiving the internet.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, when COVID hit a few years ago, the, uh, one of the first things I did was cancel my subscription to the local rock climbing gym.
Rym: Cause like, you know, if you, if you have ever used a gym, gyms ain't cheap.
Rym: Anyway, like in most of America, gyms are already pretty expensive in New York and the way gyms make money.
Scott: We've talked about this before.
Scott: Get a lot of people to subscribe and get memberships, even though only a small portion of them show up.
Rym: If they all show up, the gym will be in trouble, but you know, it is way more expensive than just a gym in New York City, a rock climbing gym, because those are really expensive.
Scott: It's much more.
Scott: if the equipment is much, you know, you can't just buy a giant warehouse.
Rym: You need like 40, 50 foot walls.
Rym: You need a lot of more insurance, hella more insurance, more staff.
Rym: So I'll just give you an example right now.
Scott: Just let people run free in a room full of, you know, rock climbing.
Scott: The way you let them run free in a room full of treadmills, right?
Rym: Like you're not even allowed in until you prove that, you know, the basics like.
Rym: otherwise you're a risk to yourself and everyone around you in these places.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, uh, I canceled that basically instantly when COVID happened.
Rym: And uh, yeah, as of a couple of weekends ago, I have resigned up actually for a different rock climbing gym, New York City, the most convenient one.
Rym: There was one a few blocks away, like not too far away.
Rym: Like it wasn't a problem and it was kind of the better gym, but I got to tell you a 15 minute walk versus a 45 second walk is a surprisingly big difference in terms of, Oh, finish with GeekNights and you'll be ready in 20 minutes.
Rym: I'm just going to walk downstairs and climb for 10 minutes and then come home.
Rym: Like that is great.
Rym: But uh, yeah, that's $120 a month to have access to that place.
Rym: But I saved a lot of money over the last three years.
Scott: As long as you use it $120 a month, it's okay.
Scott: Right?
Scott: I mean, my, the Zwift virtual bike world, right?
Scott: Costs, let me see, I forget what it costs and I know you use the hell out of it.
Rym: I see you using it.
Scott: I use it basically whenever the weather is not good and I want to ride bike.
Scott: It costs $16 and 32 cents a month after all taxes and bullshit.
Scott: Uh, but you have to amortize obviously the cost of the equipment.
Scott: So, but you can choose your equipment, right?
Scott: I happened to choose the bike trainer.
Scott: That was many hundreds of dollars.
Scott: Maybe it was even a thousand dollars.
Rym: Which makes sense.
Rym: You know, what are we talking about on gig nights if you're into something?
Scott: and I guess, but you know, there's the cost of the bicycle also, but the bicycle is also used for outside bicycling.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Um, but that's your hobby.
Rym: Like spend the money to have the good equipment if you can afford it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But yeah, they sell this Zwift hub now, which is only $500.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So that's not bad deal.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Of course there is plenty of free ride climbing.
Scott: It's way cheaper than a gym and it's way better than basically biking in any, any gym membership I could get would not have a biking experience superior to this.
Rym: It's going to have one of those regular stationary exercise bikes and like a row of treadmills and a row of ellipticals.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So there's.
Rym: no, my building has treadmills and exercise bikes downstairs if I wanted to use them.
Scott: That's free.
Scott: I mean, yeah, my bike, my gym and our building has two bikes.
Scott: I use, I use them.
Scott: They're not actually, they're pretty, they're like pretty damn good for a stationary exercise bike.
Scott: Um, but they're not a trainer.
Rym: They're not the same kind of experience.
Rym: Plus you're not just like in your own apartment for going as long as you want.
Rym: Like you don't have to go downstairs.
Scott: There isn't, you know, a virtual bike world.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's not, you know, it's like, so I'm feeling it, but I got to say literally riding on my bicycle.
Rym: I, uh, I also did my first run of the season.
Rym: Uh, you know, finally got warm enough.
Rym: So I ran like 11 miles and I didn't lose any conditioning over the winter cause I've been working out like hell for like three and a half years because of COVID and being stuck mostly at home.
Rym: But, uh, climbing I have not done in three years and that isn't just like, Oh, my arms are weak.
Rym: That is like, it uses very specific muscles and tendons that normally don't get really worked at all in a normal person's life.
Rym: So yeah, there's a lot of pain and I have lost a lot of ability there and I'm doing like V2 on the wall on a scale of between zero and infinity.
Rym: Zero is like walking up a stairway.
Rym: Two is like normal rock climbing that people would do a bouldering I guess.
Rym: And then the scale is theoretically unlimited above that.
Rym: Never done higher than a V5 in my life and I don't plan to, but, uh, yeah, I pretty much lost every one of those muscles.
Scott: So they just make up numbers like the, I guess there's some of us criteria for what number they can give something.
Rym: It's not really scientific, but it's sort of agreed upon by the bouldering community and it's roughly, from my understanding, based on everyone agrees that some trail is a particular rating.
Scott: Did they change, did they change the V based on like what equipment you use?
Scott: Like if I make it easier for myself.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So no time, no ropes.
Rym: Just all you got is climbing shoes, chalk and your body and nothing else.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what would like, so you're saying like the infinity would be like climbing Olympus mods with just your body and nothing else.
Rym: They basically make a new rating when someone does something that no one else had ever done before.
Rym: Then they figure out was that materially harder than the least, the next lowest down.
Rym: Is there an official rock climbing association that sort of, uh, it's kind of complicated and like it's different between the U S and Europe, but, and they actually use different systems, but the ratings are actually surprisingly consistent.
Rym: Like if I go anywhere in the world and I do a V2 or whatever the local equivalent of V2 is, they're about the same level of difficulty.
Rym: Do you know what they're like?
Rym: They're a lot like the original step ratings in DDR.
Rym: Like if I tell you who is like, you're really good at DDR, you played it a lot.
Rym: This is a seven footer.
Rym: You have a very good understanding of what that's going to be like to do an eight footer.
Scott: It's hard.
Scott: If you just started playing DDR, there's no way you're going to do it.
Scott: Like if you play DDR a bunch, it's like, you know, you're gonna, you're gonna do it and be, but it's, you know, if you're one of those people who does the really ridiculous songs, it's gonna be really easy.
Rym: It's an easy, it's like a shooting star and an eight would be more like music and a nine would be like dropout.
Rym: So bouldering sign of the same way.
Rym: But uh, yeah, my hand, my wrists hurt more than they've hurt in a long time.
Scott: You'll get new wrists.
Rym: Hey, robot body.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So over the weekend I went, I just want to comment quickly, right?
Scott: I went to this affordable art fair that I heard about.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: And basically it's sort of like a gallery but not sort of not.
Scott: basically what happens is it's almost like a convention in some ways, but only a dealer's room.
Scott: Um, it was a lot like mocha fest only, you know, right.
Scott: People show up to fend, right?
Scott: And they basically, instead of your booth being like a table at a con, right?
Scott: You display your wares, the booths were like these sort of like little rooms, right?
Scott: You would get.
Scott: basically each booth in.
Scott: each hallway was like a rectangle, but what the short side of the rectangle was missing and was facing the main hallway.
Scott: And then she had this deep rectangle with white walls that are all the way up to the ceiling and you hang your arts, right?
Scott: Most of it is hung square arts.
Scott: There were some other sculpture type things, right?
Scott: And whatnot, right?
Scott: But you just hang your arts in there and you know, maybe you make a little tiny table with your business cards and you know, you're, you stand there selling your arts, right?
Scott: Some of them were artists, some of them were like gallery owners representing artists, things of that nature.
Scott: And when they say affordable art fair, right, they mean like, yes, you know, normally you would go to an art auction and pay tens or hundreds of thousands of dollars for an art, right?
Scott: Whereas here you're only paying single thousands of dollars for the arts, right?
Rym: Which is a little more reasonable in terms of the price of wanting to enjoy something.
Rym: A thing, this is again, personal opinion, not investment advice or professional opinion, but a very expensive art tends to be, it tends to reek of money laundering and asset hiding more so than people actually valuing the arts that much.
Scott: The reason that these arts cost many thousands, right, is because if you think about it, the person who made it is only an artist, right?
Scott: And it's like, if you're, let's say you're an artist who's making, you know, oil paintings.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: How long does that take?
Scott: Right.
Scott: How long does that take?
Scott: How many can you make in a year, right?
Scott: Well, let's say you can make 30 a year, right?
Scott: Well, if you sell them for $1,000 each and you're like not even accounting for materials or any other costs or anything.
Rym: That's less money than Seymour Skinner canonically makes.
Scott: That's only $30,000 a year.
Scott: That's, it's like, and how many can you make in a year?
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like, you need to either crank out a lot of them or make, you know, but if you're cranking it a lot, how good are they?
Rym: So it's like, you need a very fundamental question around how labor is allocated around value based pricing versus effort based pricing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, but just out of necessity, a lot of these arts were, you know, 2000, 4008. that, right.
Scott: But that's affordable for an actual original art, not a, you know, some of them were photographic prints, but they're still like what that photograph people do.
Scott: is they even the, the photo, the paint people also, but it's like they do limited.
Scott: They're like, I'm only going to let anyone print this photo out big, like five times.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: So like you can be guaranteed that this fucking awesome photo I took and spent a whole of a lot of time photoshopping and making awesome will only ever be printed out.
Scott: It's big enough to put on someone's wall, right?
Rym: Usually they're also framed really well in a complimentary way to what the photo is about.
Scott: You pay extra for the framing, right?
Scott: But like the one really cool one I saw there, let me see if I can get the name of them.
Scott: Uh, where's the name here?
Scott: Oh, here it is.
Scott: Dan.
Scott: I'm not, sorry, Dan, if I mispronounced your last name, Dan P H P I E C H concrete canvas.
Scott: It's vast photos.com/concrete, but this, what this person does is they walk around this Manhattan city, New York, right?
Scott: And they look at the concrete, the sidewalk, the street, et cetera, mostly the sidewalk and looking for like interesting, just naturally occurring compositions that are on the street.
Rym: Ooh, that's a good shake.
Scott: They discover them, right?
Scott: They don't make them.
Scott: They're not like splashing paint on the ground or anything.
Scott: They're just walking around, looking around with a regular old camera, right?
Scott: Looking for like an interesting composition that would look really great blown up large.
Scott: And when they find one with a regular camera, they come back right with like some ridiculous camera.
Scott: That's like ridiculous, ridiculous resolution that aims straight down and then they make right.
Scott: And you can, if you go to their website, it's like, it's like, I would hang that on my wall.
Scott: It's like, even though it's just a picture of the concrete outside and then dissolve, if you go to the website, it'll tell you like, ah, you want to print this and it shows you how many they've made, right?
Scott: It's like, it's a limited edition.
Scott: That's how they can get away with charging X thousand dollars.
Rym: It's almost like we can do that without making a fucking NFT to go with it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's not even NFT, right?
Scott: I'm sure if you went to Dan and he like he had some limited run where he'd only did five and he already did the five and you were like, listen, I really want that exact one.
Scott: He'll be like for enough money.
Scott: He'd be like, okay, I got the raw file in Photoshop over here.
Scott: You know, but no, we saw a lot of like, there were many, many arts there that, you know, no matter what your style is, you would, you would see something there that's like, damn, I want that on my wall.
Scott: And then the only thing stopping you from hanging it on your wall would be, it's still thousands of dollars, but I saw a lot of awesome biz there.
Scott: Uh, it made me wish I was a little more wealthy.
Rym: So in the news, there's a lot going on.
Rym: We're only gonna cover a few of these things, but I want to start with the big one, this whole tick tock band, which is not new.
Rym: Like this has been in the works and rumbling for a long time now, but it's coming to fruition and a lot of people started noticing it partly because there was just a big congressional hearing where American Congress people were asking the CEO of tick tock questions.
Rym: And of course, American Congress people, with the exception of like five of them, don't fucking have any idea how any technology made after 1945 works.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So basically this congressional hearing was interesting.
Scott: I usually watch all the technology related hearings, especially when there's something like this involved.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But this one was interesting in that, first of all, most of the hearings I've seen is usually Democrats versus Republicans.
Scott: They're not on the same side of the deal.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or at least, you know, if they are on the same side, they have some sort of strong divergence, like the one where they were going to point.
Rym: Republicans and Democrats both want to increase military funding.
Rym: They want to do very different things with what that military is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like I watch I think I watch an antitrust hearing against the big tech.
Scott: And the Democrats are like, you're a monopoly or anti-competitive.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You're using your search results, Google, to keep other businesses down, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: That sort of thing.
Scott: And the Republicans come in, you know, like the worst ones.
Scott: also the worst ones are at this hearing.
Scott: They happen to be on that committee.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they're coming in like, oh, you're censoring the conservative voices.
Scott: It's like they're.
Scott: they're both against the people that are testifying, but they're completely off base from each other.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whereas here.
Scott: It's like you sort of have two different things going on at this hearing that are sort of both simultaneously true, which is that the Congress people are technologically incompetent.
Scott: They're asking all sorts of stupid questions that are meaningless.
Scott: And you're sort of want to side with tick tock on that.
Scott: But secondly, they're coming at the tick tock people for like, is this a national security threat?
Scott: Are you a danger to?
Scott: are you spying for China?
Scott: It's like, is there some evidence of that?
Scott: You know, yes and no.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I guess I think there's my gut, you know, well, have information.
Rym: There's a lot.
Scott: My gut tells me that the way that I've seen people in government acting right.
Scott: People who aren't ridiculous tells me in my completely the opinion of some guy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: For whatever that counts for is that they must know something the public doesn't know.
Scott: There must be some government information.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That the some federal agency has discovered regarding tick tock that has been in briefings to Congress people or others that is not known to the public.
Scott: Well, remember, we have a good that leads them to have a good reason to believe that, yes, indeed, ByteDance is the company that owns tick tock.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That they are in some way acting on behalf of the government.
Rym: They are beholden to the government of China.
Scott: At the very least, you know that for sure.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that's just.
Scott: that's like saying Google is beholden to the United States, which is also true.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that doesn't mean much.
Scott: There's.
Scott: but what's really being beholden to a foreign government means that you shouldn't do business with a company.
Scott: That means you can't do business with any company that's not.
Rym: Well, it wouldn't matter normally.
Rym: The reason this is mattering to a lot of interest and why this is a topic of debate and discussion now is partly because the world is starting to align once again into three blocks, very similar to what happened during the Cold War.
Rym: This has been ongoing for a few years, but it's it's escalating rapidly over even the last year.
Rym: The Ukraine war, of course, pushed this.
Rym: But we're generally seeing a block consisting of effectively NATO and NATO line countries and the bulk of the United Nations, as well as most of the large powers in Asia Pacific.
Rym: That's sort of like block one, say, first world, because for the listener who might be unaware that we call the first world now, that's the golf playing world.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, so that's a different because the problem is first world, second world, third world originally meant are you in block one, block two or unaffiliated?
Rym: Like it didn't have anything to do with economic development.
Rym: And that was sort of like.
Rym: that was added later.
Rym: And people use these terms incorrectly for so long that they fucked it up.
Scott: So but now we can't use those terms.
Scott: now, there's regardless of regardless of the etymology, it doesn't matter now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I like the term the golf playing nations.
Rym: Those are the many golf playing nations who are in the second block because the second block is Russia, China.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And a number of other powers Iran is aligning with.
Rym: India is getting a little weird about this.
Scott: And so there's the.
Scott: there's the vote, the somewhat to some degree democratic golf playing nations and the somewhat to some degree autocratic nations is the rest of the world who are unaffiliated golf, the non-golf nations.
Scott: They don't have golf course.
Rym: A lot of the third block countries also have golf courses, but they don't want to be involved in a fight between two giant mega blocks of the rest of the world.
Rym: They would rather just not have to deal with that.
Scott: Anyway, the point is.
Scott: All right.
Scott: The point is this right on the topic of should you ban TikTok?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, if it is true that TikTok does pose a national security threat, we've already taken the very sane and correct measure of saying you should not have this on government owned devices that may have important data.
Scott: And I think that that's really too lenient.
Scott: It should be that these are the list of apps that should be on a government phone or device and no others, period.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like that seems just just common sense computer security.
Scott: So that's the first thing.
Scott: The second thing is if it does really pose some sort of national security threat, they're spying on Americans and, you know, doing something shady on behalf of another nation, then it's like, well, I guess we kind of have to do something about.
Scott: here's a tricky.
Scott: You can't just let them get away with that.
Scott: I'm not done with the list of things.
Scott: All right.
Rym: There's a real tricky question underlying all of this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The next question right is, well, are they is that a thing?
Scott: It could be.
Scott: It might not be right.
Scott: We don't have the full data on that.
Scott: There might be some secret data, but there is also appears to be some other motive for getting rid of tick tock in that it poses an economic threat in that ha ha.
Scott: The United States, sort of all the big tech companies that were providing major platforms were in the U.S.
Scott: up until this point.
Scott: Google, Apple, Facebook.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's not a Twitter threat.
Rym: It's not like a no pure competition because no, but it's still it's an American.
Scott: All the previous companies that were big, at least, at least, you know, big, interesting note, multiple European nations are going down the same road.
Rym: France just announced a ban on government.
Rym: Basically, France just announced all the stuff the U.S.
Rym: did a while ago recently.
Rym: And a number of European countries are similarly planning to ban tick tock.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: OK, so but, you know, is there some other motive for banning it?
Scott: because you want to protect protectionism against the U.S.
Scott: platforms?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And who knows if that's true or not, probably at least partially.
Scott: And then the final question is, well, we still have net neutrality to discuss here, which is like, hey, you know, should you really, you know, shouldn't we me a person with Internet access?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, aren't you in some way being like China if you were to block tick tock the way China blocks things?
Scott: It's like, well, you say China's bad for their great wall.
Scott: Well, if you block tick tock, isn't that hypocrisy, right?
Scott: People, average normal people should be able to access the whole of the Internet at their own choosing for better or for worse.
Rym: Yeah, but it's like a tricky question.
Rym: So, for example, the U.S.
Rym: and many countries block known malware botnets that are based in Russia.
Rym: We've done that for some time under national security.
Scott: But it also depends on what the exact implementation of the block is.
Scott: Are you actually you are demanding that all of these private ISP companies block, you know, change their routers to block all packets going to and from some set of IP addresses?
Rym: Probably not.
Scott: Are you removing DNS entries from ISPs, you know, DNS servers and that someone using a different DNS server or know who knows?
Rym: Because that gets into this question of in the U.S with the First Amendment, you may have a right to access the data, but nobody is obligated, including the government to make.
Scott: Well, they have a right to publish the data.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't mean you have a right to access it.
Scott: Arguably, it's a right to speech, not a right to listening.
Rym: Well, that actually gets a little thorny.
Rym: But another thing around the band is more likely.
Rym: what would happen is it would be forced out of all the app stores because that's easy to do.
Scott: You can.
Scott: That's something because the Commerce Clause of the Constitution, right?
Scott: The app stores are places of commerce.
Scott: Congress is pretty much unlimited.
Scott: If it has laws, at least they can regulate commerce all day, which and they can say you may not sell that.
Scott: And even though it's free, it's still.
Rym: Now, why would you do this?
Rym: This gets into thorny questions from earlier, because if it's an economic issue, sanctions, sanctioned entities like if you're an American, you can't do business or interact in commerce with a sanctioned entity.
Rym: And it's right.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So if I can't I can't open up a company.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, you know, there's a lot of French animation studios that I don't know if they still do, but they did for they would outsource animation.
Rym: Last I checked, I want to say that petered out partly because North Korea has been nuking again.
Scott: It could could be.
Scott: I don't know what the status of it is, but it was a thing at a time.
Scott: Yeah, at least I know that for sure.
Scott: But like an American, you had you at Disney could never do that as because even if they wanted to be at any point in time, at least not since the Korean War, because laws.
Rym: So here's a funny you can do pretty easily if you talk to the right people.
Rym: I could go to Cuba.
Scott: I cannot.
Scott: Well, now you can.
Rym: It was I was loosened a little bit in recent times, but you know what I cannot do because of sanctions that are still in place.
Rym: I cannot do any work while I'm there for any American company, no matter what.
Rym: It would be against the law for me to accept a phone call that might have been from a coworker while I'm there, even on my own personal device.
Scott: You can go there and lay on the beach, though I could, which I would which I would love to do.
Rym: I still think one of the greatest travesties in American history is the extent to which we fucked over Cuba solely to prevent them from succeeding as a communist state near the US.
Rym: Not to say that Cuba was perfect.
Rym: Far from it.
Rym: But the US did not make the situation particularly better or help in any way.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: That's a topic for a show with people who know more about geopolitics than me and Scott.
Scott: But so on the topic of the TikTok ban, should they do it?
Scott: Well, should they do it?
Scott: Depends a lot, at least for me, on what the it is, what technical measures will they be taking to ban it?
Rym: I bet we're going to bite down as an entity.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And to what is the evidence for the, you know, whatever bad thing that they claim.
Rym: So here's the here's where the original authority thing that I'm unpacking the heap, the stack of concerns that I could raise along the way.
Rym: So one of the arguments about TikTok being a national security threat isn't just that it spies on people because all social media like TikTok has access to all the children with the propaganda.
Rym: Yeah, it's the propaganda.
Rym: It is that.
Scott: But what propaganda is there on TikTok?
Scott: The only TikTok I look at is like a dermatologist who's an actual dermatologist because you and me and weirdos who curate our feeds do not.
Scott: Is there really Chinese propaganda on TikTok that's getting to the American children?
Rym: It's partly more around what is not on TikTok, like what is banned versus not banned.
Rym: They can shape narratives.
Rym: They don't.
Rym: There's an argument that if China, say, decides as a government to invade Taiwan at some point or economic sanctions increase or weird stuff happens, does the US as a defensive posture want a Chinese government directed app to have direct access to millions of American social media feeds in this manner?
Rym: That is one of the concerns that is actively being discussed in the actual debates because this hearing was just a public sort of showcase.
Rym: The real debates are happening in committees right now.
Rym: We're not going to see all that.
Rym: You can read a lot of transcripts.
Rym: I have not done that because as interested as I am in the deep details of geopolitics, even I could not make it through some of those transcripts of these discussions.
Scott: My personal advice is like, what should you do?
Rym: The listener, I would say, don't use TikTok.
Rym: Anyway, TikTok is bad for you, right?
Scott: I would say I should.
Scott: you should not create a TikTok account.
Scott: You should not install TikTok apps on any device you own.
Rym: I would consider I talk to be a malware app myself.
Scott: If there is a TikTok creator who is chosen, who has chosen to use TikTok and their content is not available on any other channel, then do what I do, which would be to basically go in your normal old web browser, maybe private browsing mode or something, right?
Scott: That block for sure.
Scott: It's always on, right?
Scott: Go directly to that person's TikTok channel, TikTok.com/at them and look at their content.
Scott: Don't go to any feeds or anything, right?
Scott: Just go to them specifically, right?
Scott: And look at their TikToks and then that's it.
Scott: Don't go to any other.
Scott: Don't get.
Scott: start getting influenced by, you know, who knows what TikToks wants to show you automatically.
Rym: because remember propaganda.
Scott: So if there was a GeekNights' TikTok, which there isn't and probably won't be, you would just go to TikTok.com/@geeknights and that's it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But just remember propaganda is not as obvious as a lot of people think it is.
Rym: It's not like when you drive alone, you're riding with Hitler war posters.
Scott: But if you go to a specific creator TikTok.com/@somebody, it's not like on the GeekNights, you know, page that's suddenly going to be, China is great.
Scott: Things show up, right?
Scott: It's not, that's not going to happen, right?
Scott: And if that did happen, well then, you know, just stop going there at all.
Rym: But the type of propaganda that TikTok likely engages in and will engage in is consensus generation or the appearance of consensus around a particular topic or subtly nudging the narrative by choosing what gets featured and what doesn't get featured, which is that is how modern propaganda works.
Rym: Sometimes it's by accident, like even if YouTube is not being nefarious, their algorithms are just trying to get you to stay in YouTube.
Rym: And that might mean that's why certain things get promoted over other things.
Rym: It's a whole other topic for another show.
Rym: But yeah, the real moral is don't use TikTok because it's going to be a can of worms no matter how the situation goes.
Rym: And some other news.
Rym: So Nvidia, you might remember a while ago we couldn't buy any video cards because crypto bullshit.
Rym: guys were using video cards not to buy bitcoins, but to mine even shittier coins.
Rym: So the CEO of Nvidia, I have this quote here.
Rym: No, the tech chief, not the CEO, the tech chief.
Rym: Well, Michael Kagan, the CTO was being interviewed and make some statements.
Rym: And he said, "Cryptocurrencies do not bring anything useful for society.
Rym: when asked about Nvidia's part of
Rym: crypto.".
Rym: Good.
Rym: Which is fine.
Rym: That's great.
Rym: We can buy video cards again.
Rym: That is correct.
Rym: And it's good to see.
Rym: increasingly while we all know this is true, everyone knows this is true.
Rym: Even crypto people know this is true.
Rym: They're just scamming you.
Rym: But it is important for people who are in positions of power like this or positions of notice or notoriety to say it out loud because a lot of people don't believe things like that until there's a consensus of people who they trust or who they perceive as authorities saying it out loud.
Rym: It is a moderately big deal that a big name person at a big company like this will say that out loud on purpose.
Scott: Very minor related story.
Scott: There was recently a case or many celebrities had promoted some NFT bullshit.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: They're all getting sued now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I think they all lost or so.
Rym: They're all fucked.
Rym: There's a whole...
Scott: Right.
Scott: But basically they were paid to promote the NFTs, but they did not disclose that they were paid.
Scott: And people thought their promotion was a genuine promotion on an advertisement.
Scott: And that was illegal.
Scott: And they got in trouble.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: There's also one of the big exchanges is getting sued by the SEC.
Rym: Crypto is in deep shit.
Rym: And I'm a personal strong believer in Bitcoin Zero, meaning they will be worth zero dollars while I am alive.
Rym: But the buried lead in this Nvidia story is that what you know, what's going to buy all the GPUs and make it hard for you to get video cards, these machine learning, generative models, AI machine learning.
Rym: That is where Nvidia is going to be focusing and has been focusing for a long time.
Rym: If you haven't been paying attention, video cards are the tip of the iceberg of what companies like this do and dedicated boards and chips for machine learning.
Rym: That's where a lot of the resources are going to be going for the next decade.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, that is the real.
Scott: you know, we wait since, you know, phones like 2007.
Scott: We've been waiting for like the next technological thing to happen.
Rym: This is not great.
Rym: We're not saying I like this.
Rym: machine learning stuff is all like super useful or great right now, but it has some super great uses.
Scott: It does.
Scott: But yeah, but it's for real.
Scott: It's like, you know, when people were hyping up crypto as like, oh, this is going to change everything.
Scott: It didn't change shit.
Scott: It was garbage.
Scott: This is the real deal.
Scott: This is what's going to be.
Scott: I almost feel like I actually have to go and learn it or something to make sure I keep my job or something.
Rym: We got a notification at work that we're not allowed to use external models for any work purposes, which is a prudent policy.
Scott: That's just common sense, at least for now.
Scott: But, you know, this is like, you know, I was looking at a deal.
Scott: This is going to be a thing probably for the rest of your life.
Scott: So, yeah,
Rym: I guess what I'll say is don't evaluate what crypto, what crypto, we know what crypto was going to do, what this machine, the current machine learning stuff you're seeing, all the AI stuff you're seeing is doing right now, uh, because it's moving so fast, the actual science and the actual technology that nothing that has happened up to this point even matters compared to what's, what things are going to be like five years from now.
Rym: Like we're on a, we're on one of those little vertical Sigma curves.
Rym: Like anytime the rate of change is suddenly a straight line up, you're in a transitionary state, meaning nothing you do during that straight line matters at all.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, look at, you know, you look at like the original web, right?
Scott: And like the early nineties,
Rym: if you double down
Scott: on nothing like that whatsoever, we're still in that sort of phase of, you know, where we, like if machine learning is computers, we still have Commodore 64s and what we're actually going to end up with, you know, one thing stabilized, it looks nothing like
Rym: that.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And, uh, we'll be talking about that only barely resembles it.
Rym: This is going to be a topic that's going to come up a lot in GeekNights for probably the rest of GeekNights.
Scott: Probably, or at least, you know, let's say 10, 15 years.
Rym: So the other big news, and this one is we can't cover everything that's going on here, but if you're not aware, the internet archive basically lost their court case.
Scott: that's been going on for a while.
Rym: Huge court case.
Rym: And much like what we talked about with Tik TOK, there's a lot of complexity and nuance and none of this is black and white.
Scott: It's pretty straightforward, right?
Rym: But I mean, in terms of what should be done and how should things like this be handled, what's the right way to handle this?
Rym: Not why did the lawsuit go the way it did?
Rym: Wait, usually I'm the one who's like, well, the lawsuit blah.
Scott: So here's what happened, right?
Scott: People weren't paying attention, right?
Scott: The internet archive is a great organization that, you know, is we're going to talk about it in the main bit, probably, definitely.
Scott: And it serves a very important purpose in that they're pretty much the only organization that is taking on a very large effort of archiving just lots and lots of things that, you know, regular old libraries, right, used to be their job, you know, are not getting done.
Scott: Mostly the internet, digital things.
Rym: I mean, think, imagine the internet 10 years ago.
Rym: It's so different from the internet today that it's unrecognizable and half of it's gone.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And it's like the internet archive is keeping a lot of things available and alive that would otherwise not be available or alive.
Scott: And they've moved beyond just, you know, web pages with their way back machine, but also, you know, books, movies, literally anything that they can get and archive and store, you know, and they, you know, they still have a super long way to go, but it's like, they're still, they're already way ahead of basically everything, right?
Rym: And they are the modern library of Alexandria and they're doing good work.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's a very important organization, but the people running that organization had a problem, which the problem was called hubris.
Scott: hubris was the problem.
Scott: And what they did is they, they came up with this legal idea, at least in the U S and they, there was a group of people that supported this idea and they signed on to that group.
Scott: And their idea was this.
Scott: If we get physical copies of books, right?
Scott: Let's say they get a physical copy of the book club book, uh, the satanic versus a book that is still under copyright in the U S cause it's not that old, right?
Scott: At least not old enough yet.
Scott: And they say, well, we have a physical copy of the book on hand in our library, in our vault, right?
Scott: We scan in the book to create an ebook version, right?
Scott: To preserve the book.
Scott: That's, that's totally fine.
Scott: At least legally and morally for sure.
Scott: Um, then because we have one physical copy of the book, we think that we are allowed to lend out the ebook to one person at a time.
Scott: If we can ensure that only one person has, you know, the ebook, the, the ebook copy, right?
Scott: Our ebook copy of this book.
Scott: And we have one physical copy that that is legal.
Scott: Now that is a questionable legal thing with our capital Q.
Rym: think about how many, remember that little text you see in a lot of books that says something like this work can't be transferred, reproduced, modified, whatever, questionable.
Scott: There's a questionable legal theory that to my knowledge has not been tested in court and to my guests would lose in court.
Scott: But regardless, they had that theory and they, they empty develop that system and employed that system.
Scott: And obviously book publishers, the big ones in the U S we're not happy about that at all, right?
Scott: They want you to buy your ebook from the Kindle store and, or from a bookstore and give them money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So fast forward to the COVID times, right?
Scott: And they get even more hubris at the internet archive and they say national library book emergency.
Scott: I forget what they called it.
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they removed their restriction.
Scott: And they said, you know, you could just, well, you borrow as many copies, even more, more people can have the book out.
Scott: Then we have physical, that is all caps, questionable from a theory.
Scott: They had a theory that if we do this, it's okay.
Scott: And then they just stopped doing that.
Scott: right now, unlike say crunchy roll, which started out as a company of piracy that then went legit.
Scott: The internet archive has no way to do that.
Scott: It's not a business.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, and so it's like, okay.
Scott: You know, I agree that like, this is actually personally, I think that's an okay, morally okay thing to do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I would like to see it work, but I can't deny that like legally, even someone who is not a lawyer can clearly see that that is just piracy.
Scott: That's clearly just piracy that would get you.
Scott: And you're not hiding the piracy.
Scott: Like most people do big time piracy, the kind that will actually get a lawsuit on you.
Scott: And they got the lawsuit on them and they lost the lawsuit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So from here on, they can either stay losing, in which case there will be some sort of penalty or they can appeal, which I'm going to guess they would lose again.
Scott: Um, you know, they might not, I don't see any right, like way to appeal.
Rym: Like I don't see there's no like obvious errors.
Scott: So the problem here is that like, you know, I'm on their side from the sake of, I think that they're morally right.
Scott: And I want their important work to go on for them to continue to exist because they're important organizations in a capital.
Scott: They did an illegal, most likely, or at least so far, clearly illegal thing.
Scott: And if the punishment is too steep in terms of like, it'll probably be like some financial penalty to them, right.
Scott: For losing the case, let to pay the book publishers X dollars and damages, it might ruin them.
Scott: And that's bad.
Scott: I don't want them to be ruined.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, so it's just a sad, a sad tale of hubris.
Scott: I don't know where it's going to go.
Scott: Um, there's some people who are like, you know, mad, you know, who like really love the internet archive and are mad.
Scott: that like, you know, Hey, you know, bad book publishers and it's like, yeah, the book publishers are evil and whatnot, but the law is on their side.
Rym: Well, also we're in a situation where the book publishers are to a degree looking out for the authors so they can be paid to be authors at all.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: To some degree.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, you could just go to the regular law.
Scott: I mean, how many people really were using this to, it's like, that's the real question is like, did you know if, you know, legally, yes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But how much damage was really done to authors by if the, even if the internet archive kept all this lending going on, unlimitedly, in my opinion, probably none.
Scott: No one's using it.
Scott: Who's using the archive to check out books, right.
Scott: People who are going to pirate the book themselves from somewhere else.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They were never going to.
Scott: so, um, yeah, it's just a sad tale of how, you know, the, the people running an organization's hubris can ruin their otherwise important, but also points out a fracture in that the concept of libraries was invented in an era before modern capitalism and digital works.
Rym: And we haven't really figured out how to handle that as a society.
Scott: There's a lot of places in the U S their meetings of the day.
Rym: It's just a short little three minute 47 second video, uh, about the evolution of the cantile, which is a Finnish harp, and it is very well done.
Rym: It's just the same person playing this instrument and they're playing examples of the instrument from various stages in history, but they're also performing the kinds of music that people are performing on this instrument in those periods of history and they're updating their costumes along the way.
Rym: This is a extremely entertaining video and I highly recommend everyone watch it.
Scott: I commend the great deal of research that clearly must've gone into the making of this video.
Rym: Oh, this video is great.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I subscribe to the channel too.
Scott: This video from the listener.
Scott: Thank you, listener for pointing out this great video in our forum that the other listener could join if they wanted to.
Scott: Uh, basically this is just some YouTube guy goes and interviews the COO, or at least the regional COO of an internet service provider in Connecticut.
Scott: And now this is interesting because we recently, not that recently, there was a thing of the day that was a ISP that was like one guy setting it up in his rural area somewhere.
Scott: Right.
Rym: That was a good one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is like a medium sized ISP, right?
Scott: It's not like, you know, your Verizon's and your, you know, your.
Scott: whatever is your, your call, you know, Comcast or the big ones.
Scott: It's like this medium kind where it's like they big, right?
Scott: They got trucks and all kinds of equipment and warehouses and customer, and it got everything, but they're just not some massive telco.
Scott: They're like this medium size in between place.
Scott: Um, and what's really interesting to me about this video is a, they show you everything, right?
Scott: They're not hiding anything.
Scott: Uh, B they do a lot of bragging about how, yeah, we're not the evil, you know, cable guy like the other, like our competitors, right?
Scott: You know, we help you out.
Scott: We're good.
Scott: We're on your side.
Scott: Uh, C. I looked at their website.
Scott: Their pricing is actually, if this ISP was in my area, I would switch to it from Fios just based on this alone.
Scott: They're charging 50 bucks for like 300 megabit.
Scott: Um, that's less than Fios for the same, right?
Scott: Same deal.
Scott: So, uh, but yet it basically this, the regional COO shows YouTube guy like all their technology and how it works.
Scott: And it's pretty easy to understand.
Scott: if you know how your home network works, you can understand how this works.
Scott: Um, only this fiber.
Scott: It's really awesome to see the equipment and see their warehouse and all that biz.
Scott: Um, and it looks like the fact that the regional CEO understands the technology gives you a lot of confidence in the company as a good sign, right?
Scott: The only thing that doesn't give me confidence in this company, which is called go net speed, is that I looked them up.
Scott: They used to be a publicly traded company, but some years ago they were acquired by private equity.
Scott: And what's also interesting is that I looked at the border of their coverage and obviously they don't cover here, right?
Scott: But they cover literally people one block away from my mom's house, but not my mom's house.
Scott: And I'm like, I'm like, if they just move their coverage like one block over, I could get my mom to switch and she would get better internet and save money and all.
Scott: It's like, um, but it's still fascinating to see, you know, what's really going down at the ISP.
Scott: What is their fiber optic shit like?
Scott: This is exactly here.
Scott: We'll show you the whole thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's pretty straightforward up to a point.
Scott: It's straightforward up to the whole point.
Rym: When you look at this, you get, yeah, well, I guess they, the commercial arrangements for the upstream, like that stuff gets complicated, but that stuff was not, yeah, that was not pictured.
Scott: They showed basically everything between the customer and the ISP itself.
Rym: They didn't show beyond, but also that upstream is more business problem than technology problem.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But this is big enough.
Scott: They got a handle on it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights book club book is ongoing.
Rym: The satanic versus today.
Scott: Today I went to the library, right?
Scott: Uh, and I told them I wanted that book and dual purposes.
Scott: They have currently at the Queens, not the New York public libraries are weird in New York city.
Scott: There's there's a Brooklyn library, a Queens library, Bronx library, right?
Scott: And there's New York public library, but they're all sort of the same, but they're all not the same.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the Queens public library right now, if you go and get a library card, they got a special Mets, mr and mrs met library card.
Rym: That's pretty good.
Scott: So I went there and cause I, you know, I've had a digital library card from there when I tried to get a physical one way back in the day and I just failed somehow.
Scott: I think, all right, I had, I just moved here and my driver's license did not yet say that the New York city address and I didn't have a utility bill with my address on it.
Scott: cause it, you're right.
Scott: But, um, now my driver's license has my address on it.
Scott: So I was able to get the physical library card and I told them, get me, this is a Titanic versus book, so I don't have to buy it from Amazon.
Scott: And they said, okay, we'll email you when it's here.
Scott: Cause the library nearby is very small.
Scott: It's like two rooms.
Scott: Um, yep.
Rym: It's, it's, it's, it's a big book and there's a lot of allegorical densities.
Scott: So I think it'll take a little while for us to finish it, but if you're starting, I think the library will be excellent choice because a not paying money, uh, but also B I got to finish it before I got to give it back.
Scott: That'll help us help things along here.
Rym: Not a bad strategy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Uh, also we were live at PAX East 2023, uh, likely the last mask packs or last mask convention I'm expecting can competitive and casual coexist.
Rym: We did the panel, we hung around the con.
Rym: We tried out a bunch of new tech that Scott bought and way, I think hopefully with PAX West and especially PAX Unplugged, we can get back to earlier era of GeekNights, convention content and coverage and stuff.
Scott: So maybe we could go make use of the, you know, in the summertime, once we finished the stupid website, we could go outside and use it.
Rym: Maybe we'll go do class outside recording GeekNights outside.
Rym: We could, we did some tests before with some earlier tech and uh, I think now is the time.
Rym: Last time was not quite the time.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, stay tuned for that.
Rym: I don't think, I think our next convention for GeekNights is probably going to be PAX West.
Rym: Uh, maybe I'm thinking about going to Connecticut.
Rym: We'll see what the situation is through a few panels there.
Rym: That's a very easy trip.
Rym: You don't have to come if you don't want to.
Scott: Maybe it's really, it's really, it's really about how convenient it is, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: I'm thinking about it.
Rym: Uh, I was gonna go.
Rym: So the year COVID started, I was actually planning to go back to Connecticut because now we'd resigned as like senior staff and just do some panels.
Rym: And for the first time, just experienced that con as a regular ass attendee who did some panels and not like having to run everything.
Rym: And then COVID happened.
Rym: And obviously haven't been to Connecticut since.
Rym: So I don't want to go back.
Rym: I got, I looked at a picture of that convention center and it hit me right in the nostalgia, just right there in the nostalgia bean.
Rym: So archiving the internet, uh, you know, we just talked about this in the main bit.
Rym: Uh, I mean, it's obvious how important this is.
Rym: The internet is one of the newest and most transformational things humans have invented.
Rym: Like it is a brand new kind of thing.
Rym: Uh, arguably if you add the best argument that you can make in terms of trying to expand the history and say, it's not that new is that it is the logical extension of the Telegraph, which was absolutely earth shattering and how it changed the world.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And the fact that regular old people like us can put stuff on the internet, even from some of its earliest days, when it was opened up to public, all the things that happen, humans are making so much content.
Rym: There is so much that is created and lost on the internet on like a weekly basis at this point that preserving even a fraction of it is going to be extremely important for the future of humanity.
Rym: And you think, well, how important could it be?
Rym: Think about how hard it is to research what happened a hundred years ago.
Rym: Now, when there were
Scott: books, we could end up in a situation where a hundred years from now, you know, historians know more about the 20th century than they know about the 21st century, because so much of what happened in the 21st century would not be stored and saved in any recorded form that they could still access.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the century is on papers that have been, you know, locked away somewhere, or at least on, you know, some sort of physical distance, you know, something that is saved that someone can still access and read and look at.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But also there were a lot of, like, if you look at old, even ancient history, you'll see that we see history of a relatively stable period.
Rym: And then suddenly like the potter is different and suddenly like a bunch of shit is different in the historical record, but usually data from the transition is lost.
Rym: So if the internet, which has been changing and evolving exponentially for as long as I have been alive, you know, since 1982, the internet's been changing like every year is radically different than the previous year.
Rym: If that is such a transitionary period, then that is an extremely important period that is being lost in real time.
Scott: The way I think about it is this, right?
Scott: Like, you know, back, think about history, right?
Scott: Well, there was a Bronze Age at some point, right?
Scott: And they made shit largely out of bronze, or at least somewhat out of bronze, right?
Scott: That's why it was called the Bronze Age.
Rym: You know, I just read a very long essay about urbanization and the early Bronze Age.
Scott: The point is in the Bronze Age, they learned how to bronze, right?
Scott: And they had bronze items and those bronze items have survived to the present day.
Scott: And therefore we know something about the people of the Bronze Age, right?
Scott: We know information about them.
Scott: If at some point in history, there had been a wood age, right?
Scott: An age of only wood.
Scott: Only thing we would know about the wood age would be from the bones of the dead people of the wood age, right?
Scott: Because all of their writings in wood, their houses made of wood, their everything made of wood would no longer be around, right?
Scott: Well, case in point, there could have been a wood age, for all we know, probably even, and the people of the wood are lost.
Rym: There's a lot of more recent cultures, like Babylon and Samaria, where we have a lot of writing from those eras, but we only have, like, the boring bookkeeping, like the stuff that people archive for business reasons and political reasons.
Rym: But what we didn't have is the writings of regular old people in everyday life.
Rym: We have all the receipts, but we don't have any of the novels.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So, if we continue to write things on the internet, like just some lousy GeekNights MP3s, right?
Scott: Well, let's talk about GeekNights MP3s, right?
Scott: Right now we pay a company, right, Libsyn, to post them on hard drives to where people can access them publicly for free.
Scott: We could put them on the internet archive, which would be illegal because Creative Commons, you know, I think some of them are there, and they will preserve them, and there are many other people we could pay or not pay to store these MP3s on their hard drives, their storage devices, and maybe or maybe not serve them up.
Scott: We also have local copies on hard drives that we own personally, right?
Scott: So, if we were to pass from this world, which will happen someday, all right, what will happen to those MP3s?
Rym: Best case scenario, like the best possible case for those MP3s, is that somehow we have made enough money, and the world is in a situation to where we would be comfortable spending that money on what I'm about to describe instead of other causes.
Rym: We build a trust with the intent of trying to keep that data around as long as possible.
Scott: And the people at that trust actually have to do the work that our dead selves can't hold them accountable for, right?
Rym: They got like a bust of Scott in a data center, and they're like, "Yeah, this data center is to keep that guy's mouthing
Rym: alive.".
Scott: Even if we find some young lawyer, some lawyer straight out of law school in their 20s who really believes in this kind of work, and that ends up being their legal specialty of like preserving things, you know, running trusts and preserving things and whatever, and there's a board of trustees and all that stuff, and we put it all together, and it's well funded, right?
Scott: The board of trustees will pass from this world, right?
Scott: How long will they keep that going, the trust that preserves the Geek Dice MP3s, right?
Scott: Through all the tumult of the world, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, we see already the archive.org, the internet archive, is not invulnerable, you know, the Libsyn bill has to keep getting paid, that company won't last forever, right?
Scott: Are podcasts always going to be a thing, right?
Rym: I have hard drives here, don't stop work.
Scott: It's like, I have hard drives here, they'll stop working eventually, you know, even if someone inherits them, are they going to try, you know, take care of this NAS and preserve this data?
Scott: And it's like, how dedicated will they be to that if just two of the drives crash?
Scott: That's that, the end, right?
Scott: They can't, they had to be on top of that.
Scott: And then someone else has to be on top of that after them, right?
Rym: I think we put it all on long-term like worm memory, or we put it on the kind of stuff that you put like regulated data on.
Rym: One, it's a lot of data because it's audio compressed or whatever, but even those formats degrade and they're almost worse in some ways because one of the truest things to know about digital data is that the data that gets preserved is the data that is accessed frequently.
Rym: The less frequently it is accessed, the more likely it is that bit rot will happen.
Rym: And before you say, well, bit rot is absolutely a thing and there's a lot of things that cause it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, this is the principle behind the architecture of, you know, get the source control system, right?
Scott: Is that unlike previous source control systems, when you clone a Git repository, you are actually cloning the whole thing in most cases, right?
Scott: So like if someone has an open source project out there on the GitHub and I say, I want to do some work on that project and I do get clone, I now have an entire copy of that project and its entire code history now on my computer and every single person who ever worked on that project also has a copy.
Scott: So it's like if it would take, in order for that to be lost, even if they delete the GitHub repository, anyone who's ever cared about that project enough to check out the code locally on their own computer could restore it fully or almost fully to the state ad it was in when they checked it out.
Rym: So a better way to keep GeekNights going.
Scott: Something is very popular.
Scott: It is naturally backed up many, many times.
Rym: Which in a way is a nice self-reinforcing system wherein the things that the society collectively cares more about are preserved by more people via more means.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But that also means that some data that people don't care that much about, because as you can imagine, what society in aggregate cares about doesn't always necessarily align with what a historian might care about or what a society maybe should care about.
Rym: So already that doesn't necessarily mean the most important data is preserved.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We think about like some memes.
Scott: It's like, yeah, you know, the platforms come and go and people always will repost the old memes to the new platform.
Scott: If I look on TikTok, I bet I can find all your base on there somewhere.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like it's protected.
Rym: But like a lot of those old flash guys at YouTube flash games.
Rym: All those old flash games, what a lot of people did is just play them, record themselves playing them and put them on YouTube.
Rym: And you can experience most of them that way.
Rym: Like that's also copy.
Rym: But that's a copy.
Scott: That's a separate.
Scott: that's a separate issue of where the data has been preserved.
Scott: But the technology to use the data is not been so well preserved.
Scott: But there are people there's a lot of people making like flash, you know, alternatives and emulators and things of that nature.
Rym: And we're going to skip the whole.
Rym: how do you preserve an ephemeral digital interactive space like an MMO?
Rym: We've talked about that on Tuesday GeekNights before.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's very difficult question, right?
Scott: It's like if the website changes a hundred times, you know, the wayback machine.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: What's the official version of my GeoCities site?
Scott: The first one, the wayback machine just records many versions, snapshots over time.
Scott: And you can look at the same website at different points in its history.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But a lot of websites I made are just gone.
Rym: I mean, I didn't back them up.
Rym: I was a kid.
Rym: They were they wrote them in a notepad, like literally wrote.
Scott: I did.
Scott: I have backed up pretty much everything in the 2000s.
Scott: But yeah, there's some stuff in the 90s that I didn't back up.
Scott: And it's it's gone.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I've been looking for like some of my old stuff.
Rym: And yeah, none of that is out there.
Scott: I looked on the floppy disk.
Scott: I can't look any further back than the three and a half inch floppies.
Scott: And that's it.
Rym: Searching the Internet and searching other archives for, of all things, the ICQ numbers I used has been an interesting way to actually find more data than I expected about me, because that is a primary key that was unique to me.
Rym: That is a string of numbers, a few strings of numbers, actually, that made it around the Internet.
Rym: But even then, pretty much everything I found was either a dead link or someone had just taken that data and put it in a profile about me on a site I never use.
Rym: Like the new Oticon forum has my ICQ in it because they imported my account, despite the fact that I was banned from the old account.
Rym: I can't log in.
Rym: It says I'm banned.
Scott: But but like, you know, my Geocities page is like I had one, but it was not, I guess, significant enough to be preserved by whoever did some work.
Rym: Oh, even worse.
Rym: I had one that was the one people knew about.
Rym: Then I had a network of like 20 of them that I had made because each one gave me two megabytes.
Rym: And I used that to run an NES ROM site that was active for some time.
Rym: But that is a case where I was studiously trying to make sure nobody knew about it.
Rym: Nobody preserved it.
Rym: It was like a do you know about it or not?
Rym: situation.
Rym: I like made sure there was no way to tie it back to me whatsoever under any circumstances.
Rym: So that's almost impossible to archive if the person making it actively does not want people to keep it around.
Scott: Another difficult thing is that, you know, you talked about the telegram at the beginning, right?
Scott: It's like, are all telegrams preserved?
Scott: No, it's like there was a lot of direct human to human communication.
Scott: Phone calls are preserved unless they're like the president's phone.
Rym: But imagine if a historian today could read every telegram sent and received from like the British government telegram office in eighteen forty.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So on the one hand, it's like at the you know, for direct communications between people.
Scott: There is a need for secrecy, privacy, etc.
Scott: in the immediate moment.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Snapchats that disappear.
Scott: Instagram stories.
Rym: But in the long, long term, long after everyone involved or could ever be harmed or influenced or annoyed by that conversation is long dead.
Rym: Think about how many of the things you read in school are the private letters between Thomas Jefferson and some guy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, those were on paper, so they got saved somehow.
Scott: They looked in someone's desk after they died and they took them all.
Scott: But it's like, yeah, those that even your inconsequential stuff like, you know, hey, when are you picking me up from the pizza place?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like that still once your life, you know, is that information need to be known to everyone now?
Scott: Is it a value?
Scott: Does anyone get to preserve that?
Scott: No.
Scott: But in a long time from now, it's like, ah, there was this thing called pizza back then.
Scott: People had to be picked up.
Scott: There's so much information.
Rym: We think it was used for ritualistic purposes.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Scott: It was like, you know, it was.
Scott: there's so much information, even in just that, you know, and if you could see, ah, there was lots of communications of this nature.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We can.
Scott: they could gauge how popular different things were.
Scott: It's such incredible value in worthless, worthless data.
Rym: I could go take names of food and drink from less than 100 years ago.
Rym: And if I tell you about them, you will have no idea what the fuck they are.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Historical food channels on YouTube are a big hit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: The food you eat now will be historical food in a long time.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Ask an aristocrat in America in the 17 hundreds what punch is.
Rym: And it's not what you think punch is.
Rym: Also, it is vile.
Rym: It is the vilest alcoholic garbage.
Rym: Good Lord.
Rym: Whatever opinion you have of the American founding fathers will be lessened further than it was already lessened by, you know, slavery and how America turned out.
Rym: If you read what they liked to drink.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So even if we agree, we want to preserve everything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So here is the problems.
Scott: So problem number one is the technological problem.
Scott: And basically, if you just if you could somehow magically write, you know, get all the data on the whole Internet all at once, where can you fit it?
Scott: It's like it's stored already on the hard drives and storage devices.
Rym: You made a copy of the Internet that is obsolete before you finish making the copy.
Scott: Well, forget that.
Scott: But we don't have enough storage devices to just have two of it.
Scott: Where are you going to put this other this one place where it has enough hard drives to hold the whole Internet versus the whole the rest of the Earth?
Rym: It's like now one could argue that even if you have it and even if we only look at one snapshot of it, like say the U.S.
Rym: Census every 10 years, they take a snapshot of the Internet and they store it and they somehow solve that problem, which is already like we're already at an unsolvable problem.
Scott: So everything we're talking beyond this isn't enough storage to hold the whole Internet.
Rym: But today we've got it.
Rym: The fuck do you find anything in that?
Rym: Like we can't search the actual Internet effectively anymore.
Scott: No, we can't.
Rym: So now, luckily, I do think that is an area where machine learning is going to solve that problem.
Rym: Maybe data curation and like finding data in data.
Rym: But data leaks are a concept that are very important because they're basically if I had to summarize it and not get into the tech of it, a data lake is when there's a there's information that's too much for you to process.
Rym: But you know that data might be valuable to me someday.
Rym: Like I want to do something with that data, but I don't have the resources to heavily curate that data today.
Rym: You dump it all in a data lake, meaning in the future you might dive into that lake to pull data out to do something with it.
Rym: But you're just trying to keep as much of it around as possible for the time being.
Rym: But data lakes are not archives.
Rym: Data lakes disappear shockingly quickly, if not heavily maintained.
Scott: Data lakes are mostly a corporate thing, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you don't you know, you have your database where everything is structured and there's a schema and it's right.
Scott: But the data lake is more like, OK, dump all the spreadsheets and all the PDFs and all the everything and dump all the logs from other servers there, because why not?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And we OK, it's not perfectly structured.
Scott: It's not ideal, right?
Scott: It's not the database.
Scott: But we do have technology that will allow us to search it to some extent, right?
Scott: To look at it to some extent, to query it to some extent.
Scott: It's not perfect.
Scott: It's not ideal, you know, as it would be if everything was organized perfectly.
Scott: But it still provides business value.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you can't operate one of those on the scale of the whole Internet.
Scott: That's not going to work.
Rym: Let's say we could.
Rym: Let's say we even solve that problem.
Rym: The laws of every country, the way copyright works, the way capital, all that whole giant can of worms makes it extremely difficult to archive anything without being sued or at least blocked.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You try to scrape some website, they're going to block you because you're costing them money.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, if you get the data and maybe you avoid the public, like if you archive data, but you don't like republish it or do much with it, then you can definitely get away with it.
Rym: Like they can't sue you if they don't know you did it.
Rym: But even then, if you're not sharing it, then bit rot sets in like you're not using that data.
Rym: So no one can find that data when you die.
Rym: That data is gone.
Scott: And if no one can find it, that's letting people have access to it is a way of backing it up because more people will have copies of it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, if you make a website, you know, and then you have your personal backup.
Scott: But it's like, well, there is some person out there who's weird and is taking screenshots to your website every day.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And there's some, you know, it's like, yeah, you know, I talked about all the backups of GeekNights that we make, but it's like there's a YouTube channel that we don't endorse that.
Rym: It's called just like Rym and Scott.
Rym: And it just has the audio every fucking every single fucking GeekNights episode just in a YouTube video with a really blurry like photo of one of our logos.
Rym: Someone's making that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's probably some bot.
Rym: But I don't care, but I don't care either.
Scott: But, you know, some listener out there might just be saving all the MP threes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's one more place.
Scott: So something's really popular.
Scott: It's like, you know, some actual Hollywood movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is completely safe now.
Scott: Has no worries about that because there are people with DVDs and boo rays.
Rym: Imagine a show someone makes that only thousands of people watch.
Rym: They upload it to YouTube and then they die and everyone forgets it.
Rym: Like that's going to get lost so fast.
Scott: So, so what, what can, what can we do realistically?
Rym: I think this is something that needs to be addressed by state level, like state level entities, like governments or the scale of how this kind of problem has to be solved.
Rym: And I feel like data curation and preservation for historical purposes should be a primary duty of large governments, but we're a long way from that.
Rym: I
Scott: don't know if it, you know, I don't know if it's something that like should be a duty of governments, but you know, for any other reason besides there's nothing else big enough to take on a test that, that, that arguably
Rym: that's the only reason to have a government, to handle the things that are too big for small groups of people to handle on their own.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I think really all the governments have to do is, you know, tax people, which they already do, but do it more, uh, and put the correct percentage of their budget into libraries.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Libraries, library of Alexandria.
Rym: That's how you preserve data.
Scott: And then the libraries have experts at doing exactly this.
Rym: And what are the experts going to do?
Rym: They're going to take all the questions we just raised and already have the correct answers.
Scott: They already have the answers.
Scott: You go to library school, someone out there who already went to library school is like already has all the answers to everything we asked her in this show.
Rym: Our friend Pat is trying to do this just for conventions.
Rym: And I've learned a lot just talking to him because he studied this.
Rym: And uh, yeah, generally if you let experts solve these problems, they'll solve them.
Rym: They might not be able to save everything, but you know what?
Rym: If they know we can only save 10% of the internet, they're going to do a much better job of figuring out what 10% than a government will or any random person or any tech company will.
Scott: And you know, really it's like saving anything at this point, right?
Scott: So one thing I've seen so many things disappear already.
Scott: Like there are things that I saw in my life that are, that no longer exist and can no longer be found.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, I don't think that happened a lot in, I think that happened before recorded history.
Scott: You lost everything in your whole life, right?
Scott: There was no recording of anything, but I feel like, you know, in the 20th century, it's like things that existed didn't stop existing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, there's actually very few things from the earlier part of my life.
Scott: Pre-internet are no longer around at all.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you can find them.
Scott: It's a vintage shop or an antique shop or who knows what, but like memories and documentation of those things in the eighties nineties are all around.
Scott: We, we, right.
Scott: Um, it's things from the early two thousands.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: There's a lot of photos of me up until high school.
Rym: And then there's not a lot of photos of me until good digital cameras and smart cameras appeared like things from when I was in college and sure.
Scott: And when we were in, I have like 30 total photos of us in college, like, yeah, it's like, well, things from those times are actually the hardest things for me to find record of, um, as terms of the period of my life.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When I find a photo of myself legit excited, but the digital world still wasn't advanced enough and was definitely not preserved really very well at all.
Rym: But now if I die, like one, my light room stops working as soon as that credit card bounces to Adobe, which means all those bras are gone.
Rym: And then flicker dies.
Scott: when this, I have them on, I have them on a NAS.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I got them on a NAS that'll die when like the estate doesn't know what to do with this old piece of hardware.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So one thing I've talked about this on GeekNights from back from the beginning, this is something I've considered seriously since high school.
Rym: And I'm still very serious about doing it.
Rym: Actually, I'm getting old enough where I should start to put this in motion more affirmatively.
Rym: My general plan is to form a very small trust for my death with a small amount of funding.
Rym: And basically I would like to do something to the effect of some number of years after my death, all the media I have ever created or all the media that was in my estate is public domain and released to the public.
Rym: I mean, I can make that every second after my entire hard drive, my browser history, everything.
Scott: The reason I would wait is that things that might even private things that might hurt other people who are that's exactly it.
Rym: Cause they're my, you know, they're, I'm sure there are plenty of emails people have sent me where while I have the perfectly legal right to reshare those because they were sent to me.
Rym: Uh, I could see how someone might not want every email they ever sent to me to be released to the public.
Rym: So I want to structure this.
Rym: I want to find a way to do this.
Rym: That makes sense.
Rym: I don't know what the timeframe is, but imagine if like today, someone who lived in 1945, every letter they ever wrote and every photo from their entire extended, like their entire data archive just appeared and you could just dig through it and research it, explore it.
Rym: I would love for that to exist about people from this era.
Rym: And I'm willing to put up or shut up.
Rym: I'm willing to be one of those people.
Scott: But you know, well, you know that like, you know, rich people, very fabulously wealthy people will set up like the so-and-so library, right?
Scott: Like all the presidents.
Scott: have them at least, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Cause they're also trying to set their image.
Rym: I want the raw data to go out.
Rym: I don't want the curated like.
Rym: here's what rich Rym wanted you to think of him when he died.
Scott: I wonder if we could make an organization that's just called the U the U library and people would sign up and pay money and they would come and library people individually.
Rym: And as long as there's enough people, you give it a donation and you have a sliding scale or whatever.
Scott: And the people who are currently alive are basically paying and subs, you know, paying for the everyone who came before.
Scott: And then the people who come after will pay for that.
Rym: And that's the kind of org that could figure stuff out.
Rym: Like what is the timeframe that makes sense from a legal and moral perspective before this data gets released.
Scott: But basically while you're alive, you would pay this organization.
Scott: They would come and, you know, archive everything about you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then when you, you know, pass for this world, they come and go through all your stuff and record all of it.
Scott: They don't need to take physical possession of all the objects, but at least, you know,
Rym: but like it has to be legally watertight to where this org could on your behalf long like go to Google and say, you have to give us access to this account so we can download the archive per this will and this contract.
Rym: And here's a bunch of legal theory that backs it up.
Scott: Now they already have stuff for that, like Apple, you can put like, but I am regardless of like.
Rym: if anyone else does this, this is something I'm very serious about doing before I can make a whole organization that does this.
Scott: The only problem is it's going to archive the lives and histories of wealthy Internet individuals.
Rym: archiving because that's all the history is gone.
Rym: Most of the letters we have.
Rym: I just talked about how important it is to be able to read letters people wrote.
Rym: But other than letters that soldiers wrote home after wars, most of the letters we have from history are rich white people sending letters to each other.
Scott: I think what you should do is I think you should make it this organization.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When you pay for archive yourself, you also have to pay for it to archive somebody who cannot afford it.
Scott: Oh, that's a great idea.
Scott: Some other person could be some person who doesn't even have this gets into like StoryCorps.
Rym: Like there's other ways to archive information.
Rym: Look at things like StoryCorps and all the groups that just like, hey, find old people and just talk to them and learn as much as you can from them and record it all for the future.
Rym: Like there's a lot of ways to archive data and the most important thing because we've gone on long and I'm tired and hungry.
Rym: There's got to be a lot of different approaches to this because we don't know what technology is going to look like even 10 years from now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like you said, you might get into a trouble like with the flash situation.
Scott: It's like we save all this HTML and no one has any web browsers.
Scott: It's like all the water and you can't drink, right?
Scott: You got the books and your glasses, bro.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights who pay us at least $5 a month because they want us to say their name at the end of every show are Ellen Joyce, Likkeji, Dread, Lily, Teddie Brite, Kace, Kari Makes Music, Chris, The Dog, Clinton, Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Henny Reimer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Hoh and a ton of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: So yeah, you might've noticed those YouTube shorts.
Rym: I did confirm.
Rym: So let me know if they pop up annoyingly anywhere, but they should never show up in a normal YouTube feed.
Rym: They only show up unless you have a or you scroll down into that actual YouTube shorts feed or whatever.
Rym: So try to put up like one or two a day for the foreseeable future.
Rym: We've got a lot of panels and they're real easy to make.
Rym: I've literally got like 30 of them queued up.
Rym: So yeah, for now simply leave you.