Rym: It's Wednesday, April 26th, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Wednesday.
Rym: Tonight we're talking about GeekNights Wednesday.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I did something that kind of, I guess, it's not a surprise.
Rym: Like something I even talked about on the show a little bit.
Rym: But we had a Japanese style hot water boiler in the kitchen forever.
Rym: Like as long as we've lived here.
Rym: And that thing's great.
Rym: But it was getting a little old.
Rym: It was 2.2 liters.
Rym: It was a Panasonic.
Rym: And it was starting to wear out a little bit.
Rym: Like occasionally.
Scott: Are you supposed to like, there's some maintenance you're supposed to do on it, right?
Rym: Oh no, we did all that stuff.
Scott: If it's really bad it can get like limescale or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, no, we handled all that stuff.
Rym: This is more like the control panel occasionally.
Rym: Which is to be like, oh shit, and reboot and go back to like 190 degrees.
Scott: Oh, well that's, you know, isn't that the default?
Rym: It is the default, but it would like lose power on its own for a second and then come back and go back to the default even if I left it at a different temperature.
Scott: It could probably be repaired very easily.
Rym: It probably could, but we looked around and a lot of people have that same problem only with extremely old models of this one.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean it could still repair it.
Scott: There's probably like some capacitor or something you could replace.
Rym: Oh yeah, but also I think the control panel itself has to be replaced.
Rym: Like the whole, that bit that goes on the front.
Rym: Because sometimes if you hit buttons, they'll just like give up on you halfway through.
Rym: You replace the button.
Rym: Minor electrical, yeah, but they're all the buttons in the little control panel that's glued onto this thing.
Rym: But anyway, we were still using it, but we had another problem.
Rym: It was only 2.2 liters and it was actually starting to be not quite enough, especially now that we work from home a lot more, like we're around more.
Rym: Ever since COVID, we'd run out a lot.
Rym: We'd run out when I wanted to use it and it took a while to get back up to temperature.
Scott: You could push the reboil button to make it go faster.
Rym: If you refill it, it just automatically does that.
Scott: I know that, but if you push the reboil button, it'll heat up, it'll go normal faster than if you just fill it up and close the lid.
Rym: Not according to the manual anyway.
Rym: So all that we decided, we're going to give that one away because it still works, it's pretty fine.
Rym: We wanted a bigger one, so we upgraded to the Zojirushi 3 liter.
Rym: And I guess what I'm surprised by is one, I didn't think the Zojirushi would actually be better in any material way.
Scott: Hot water is hot water, how is it better?
Rym: And it wasn't more expensive than an equivalent model from all the other brands.
Rym: They're all around the same price for that level of nice hot water boiler.
Rym: But I'm actually surprised at, in effect, how much better it is.
Rym: So despite holding a bunch more water, it's 3 liters, it gets to temperature shockingly fast.
Scott: We got the 4 liter one.
Rym: 2, it has a pump the water out as fast as possible mode and a pump the water out slowly mode, which I find I'm actually using them both pretty equally.
Rym: 3, it, unlike the Panasonic, plays a little song whenever it's done.
Scott: Of course it plays a song.
Rym: Yeah, but the Panasonic didn't, this one does, I like that.
Scott: That's a problem.
Scott: Every single appliance we have in this house sings a song.
Rym: I know, I don't like appliances that don't sing songs.
Scott: The dishwasher puts on a whole fucking symphony.
Rym: I wish ours did, our dishwasher goes beep.
Rym: But the rice cooker, all the Zojirushi's play a nice song.
Scott: The washing machine plays a song, the fridge even sings.
Rym: It actually has more precise temperature control and it has more options.
Rym: Like I can set more precise temperatures, which actually does matter for the kind of coffee that I brew.
Rym: And I think the coffee it makes is, because I can control the temperature and I can up it like 5 degrees from 190, it is just better.
Rym: But I'm going to do a little bit of a blind test with the two.
Scott: Yeah, how would you know?
Rym: Exactly, so I'm going to do a test.
Scott: It's like if it's the same water from the same sink at the same temperature.
Rym: It's 5 degrees hotter.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Which actually does matter for extraction from like roundup coffee.
Rym: But we'll see, but I just love the hell out of this thing.
Rym: So if anyone in New York City, we're going to give the perfectly fine, other than extremely minor, pretty much inconsequential problems with the control panel on the front.
Rym: We're just going to give that one away to someone because it still works fine.
Rym: But I really like this Zojirushi.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we basically had the same one.
Scott: I just don't use it very much because I don't drink hot beverages.
Scott: And it's not winter.
Scott: Hot chocolate is basically the only thing I use it for.
Rym: I use it to make miso soup pretty often.
Scott: Oh yeah, we did use it for a miso soup.
Scott: I don't eat miso soup that often.
Rym: I use it to rehydrate sun dried tomatoes and other things pretty often.
Rym: I use it to rehydrate mushrooms pretty often.
Rym: I just use the sink water.
Rym: You don't want to use hot water from the sink in food.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: That's generally ill-advised all over the world.
Rym: In fact, in the UK there's public health advisories about it.
Rym: Hot water in residential systems tends to have more minerals.
Rym: It picks up more contaminants from the pipes because of the temperature.
Rym: It's held longer.
Rym: There's lots of stuff there.
Rym: Not as much of a problem in newer buildings, but definitely a problem in old buildings.
Rym: There's a whole thing there.
Rym: I would generally, my whole life, I will not drink hot water from a tap.
Scott: You got some weird hang up about water.
Rym: We're in New York City.
Scott: This is the best water on earth.
Rym: In London, in fact.
Scott: The water is identical until it gets to this building.
Rym: Yes, and in the building the hot water follows a different path.
Scott: Yes, in the building the hot water goes to a heated place where the same H2O molecules and all the other molecules are excited.
Scott: And then they travel through identical types of pipes.
Scott: Just one of them is insulated.
Scott: And then it gets to the sink.
Rym: And the difference in temperature does mean more things depending on exactly what kind of pipes it is.
Rym: We'll leach out of it.
Scott: Yeah, I am not concerned.
Rym: But in London they actually...
Scott: They're not lead pipes.
Rym: From the US government, the Environmental Protection Agency, only use cold water from taps for cooking and drinking.
Rym: Never cook with or drink water from the hot tap.
Rym: Full stop.
Rym: That is the official US government advice.
Rym: Hot water dissolves more lead and other materials quickly than water.
Scott: It can't dissolve lead if you don't have lead pipes.
Scott: There's no lead to dissolve.
Rym: What kind of solder is in those pipes?
Scott: What the fuck do I know, but it's not lead.
Scott: They didn't use lead in a building.
Scott: that's this new.
Rym: There's also other things that can come out of different types of plastic pipes.
Scott: I mean, if it was an old building... Basically the way I see it is this.
Scott: If the building is old, I'm not drinking any of the water, cold or hot.
Scott: And if the building's new, and the water can be trusted, how much difference is it the hot water making?
Scott: Especially... It's not like I'm taking hot water from the sink and drinking it, right?
Scott: It's like, you know.
Rym: Well, I'm just saying.
Rym: Not all the US federal government and every state government now that I'm googling around actually makes the same warning as does the government of the United Kingdom.
Scott: Like I don't drink hot water from the sink, right?
Rym: I'll occasionally just drink hot water, but even then I get it from my nice water heater.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like.
Scott: the only time I would use a hot water in a cooking is, like you said, dehydrate a mushroom.
Scott: In which case, how much water, or rehydrate a mushroom.
Scott: Like how much of that water is getting into my body.
Rym: Even modern copper piping, according to the EPA, often uses tin-lead solder.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It's on the outside.
Rym: Not 100%.
Rym: I don't think you know how soldering works with pipes anyway.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So in some news, somehow the Venture Brothers movie, which is the end of the Venture Brothers because Capitol basically gave up on those two beautiful people who are just crazy enough to keep making this weird show.
Rym: They basically said, "Alright, you can make this movie and then we're done with you.
Rym: You can't keep making this
Rym: show.".
Rym: Because you know the history of this show, which I think it's one of the better animated shows ever made in America.
Rym: It's a fantastic show.
Rym: Shockingly good compared to what the first season was.
Rym: Anyone who watched the first season of this would probably not expect it to be a show that would make you cry.
Rym: But this is one of my top 20 animated TV series ever, including anime.
Rym: At least top 50.
Rym: It's a good show.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: But the people who make it are kind of crazy about it.
Rym: It's not like, "Oh, they make a season and then it takes a year to make the next
Rym: season.".
Rym: This is like, they'll make a season and then it takes them like four years to make another season.
Rym: And then it takes them like another four years to make another season.
Scott: When was the first season?
Rym: The first season was, now I gotta go all the way back, I was working at a different company.
Rym: What does Wikipedia say?
Rym: I'm pulling that up right now.
Rym: Because I didn't even start watching it when it first came out.
Scott: It started in... There are 81 episodes, 7 seasons, and the first season was...
Rym: Wikipedia says 2003?
Scott: Original release, August 2004.
Rym: It says picture format 2003 to 2006 NTSC.
Rym: That's telling you that the picture format from when it was in production was used was NTSC, yes.
Scott: But it says original release 2004.
Scott: That's when it was released.
Scott: I'm sure they worked on it in 2003 for it to be released in 2004.
Rym: So they've made 81 episodes of this show in 20 years.
Scott: So in 19 years, they made 7 seasons, so that's about 1 season every 2 and a half to 3 years.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And 81 episodes because the seasons are not all the same length.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: In fact, the more recent seasons were just like 8 episodes.
Scott: The reason it said 2003, there was a pilot in 2003.
Rym: Ah, that explains it.
Rym: I just hit the same bit of the Wikipedia skimming around.
Scott: So yeah.
Scott: The first sentence.
Rym: This show is great.
Rym: If you never watched it, I'd say it's worth watching.
Rym: Though you could skip the first couple seasons and dive right in and maybe go back to that later.
Scott: I find it interesting that there's two trends that are strange to me.
Scott: The first trend is that there's a lot of things where they don't have an ending and they would normally get cancelled.
Scott: But instead, someone's going through the effort to make these ending movies for things.
Scott: Where it used to be an intentional thing.
Scott: That there would be like, we're going to intentionally end with a movie for a big splash.
Scott: Whereas now, it's like, you can't have another season, but we didn't do our ending.
Scott: Okay, you can make a one-shot movie for your ending.
Scott: It feels like that, as opposed to the...
Rym: Oh, it's definitely that.
Rym: This was basically...
Scott: As opposed to end on a movie on purpose.
Scott: Boom!
Rym: It's very clear from interviews and from everything I can find about these two that they would just keep making this show forever.
Rym: If anyone would let them.
Rym: And they had planned to make a whole 'nother?
Rym: season.
Rym: And they were finally told, look, you're making one movie and that's it.
Rym: So wrap up whatever you're going to wrap up so the fans don't freak out.
Rym: And that is the end of this train.
Rym: Unless someone else is willing to give you enough money to keep doing this.
Scott: Now the second trend that I've noticed that's interesting is that, you know, there's... It seems like, you know, you got the cheap shows that are so cheap but popular enough that they just never end.
Scott: They just keep making more, right?
Scott: You got the big, fancy, ultra-popular shows, right?
Scott: That will either go, go, go, but still end soon-ish, right?
Scott: Because they need to have so much audience to keep going, right?
Scott: It's like Game of Thrones ain't still going, is it?
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: Not only is it not still going, but the final season flopped.
Scott: Okay, but the point is, right?
Rym: Wait, you don't know what happened with that show.
Rym: That is a separate topic we should talk about later.
Rym: The shit show.
Scott: I don't care about any Thrones or games.
Rym: The best summary I can give you is the show was popular because of the subject matter.
Rym: And the first season was actually, like, really well put together.
Rym: Basically, the people who were in charge of running the show didn't have much experience and didn't fucking know what they were doing.
Rym: And just kind of failed to make it good.
Scott: Well, didn't they also run out of book because the guy still hasn't put out of it, right?
Rym: Yeah, but that was not actually the problem.
Rym: This is like a big story in entertainment of how badly it failed.
Scott: But anyway, the point is that the trend I'm seeing is that there's these mid-shows, right?
Scott: Like your Venture Brothers, where they're not mega-hits.
Rym: The Owl House, same thing happened.
Scott: Good example.
Scott: Perfect example.
Scott: There's these mid-shows.
Scott: They're not mega-popular, earth-shattering, everyone in the world knows them.
Scott: They're not super cheap garbage shows like reality shows or cop shows or laws and orders or whatever, right?
Scott: But they're in this mid-tier of popularity where, like, you know, nerds know them.
Scott: And somehow those shows, it's like they're not as cheap as the ultra-cheap shows.
Scott: But they hang around for what seems like longer than their popularity would warrant, right?
Scott: Just based on feeling, not based on numbers, because you don't have all the numbers.
Scott: But based on feeling, it's like, how popular does Venture Brothers feel?
Scott: Moderately popular.
Scott: How long has it been going?
Scott: 19 years and 7 seasons.
Scott: Feels like that feeling of 19 years, 17 seasons.
Scott: So as one of the people.
Scott: Feels bigger than the popularity level feels.
Rym: As one of those nerds, like I can say.
Scott: And there are several shows in that range.
Rym: Because the way they announced that the movie's actually happening is they just released a clip from it, like, out of nowhere.
Rym: Like, just, it hit YouTube.
Rym: Like, here it is.
Rym: And so many people who I know are also fans of this, like, DM'd me on Discord.
Rym: Or, like, pinged me like, "Yo, did you see the
Rym: clip?".
Scott: Maybe that's it.
Scott: Maybe that's the mid-tier thing.
Rym: I think the mid-tier thing.
Scott: Extreme fans, even if you don't have many fans.
Rym: I would say it's not even necessarily extreme.
Rym: It's more like, because we've talked about this in broader creator circles.
Rym: If you've got a critical mass of followers who believe in your content and like what you do.
Rym: Below a certain tier, that is enough people to sustain you creating what that group wants.
Scott: That's enough to sustain you if you're a webcomic.
Scott: If once you're a TV show, you need to have a certain number.
Scott: Because there's a production cost.
Rym: So I think there is a similar phenomenon for.
Scott: If you're just a band making merch, the number is low.
Scott: If you're on actual television, the number is high.
Rym: So I suspect there is a similar but distinct phenomenon for shows like Owl House and Venture Brothers.
Rym: Where it's not quite that scenario.
Rym: That audience clearly isn't sustainable to make enough money.
Rym: Or, it might be a capitalism situation, it might be.
Rym: It breaks even, maybe it makes money, but it's risky to keep making it.
Rym: Because, alright, hang these two idiots another two million dollars and wait four years.
Rym: And then they release eight more episodes of something.
Scott: It's two point seven.
Scott: five years you'll wait, not four.
Rym: Well it depends on, they did every season, like the last season, they just made eight episodes.
Scott: I mean, how many do they need to make?
Scott: One, they make just as much money if they make four or twenty six.
Scott: Why make twenty six?
Rym: I also wouldn't be shocked because they write it based on what the plot is.
Rym: They just tell their story.
Scott: I know, I'm just saying.
Scott: It's not like more episodes makes more money.
Rym: True, exactly.
Scott: You just need to maintain enough interest because the money comes from other things.
Scott: You just need to maintain the interest level.
Rym: Owl House had a totally different side story where it was partly Disney.
Rym: You know, the whole executives shuffle around and the brand doesn't want that to be part of their offering.
Rym: And it was more one of those situations.
Rym: There's a lot of situations like that that happen.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, you got any news?
Scott: Uh, what was my news?
Rym: The Pokemon thing?
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: So if you go on the Internet and you will go to popular Pokemon fan sites, you know, Bulbapedia being the number one.
Scott: But there's several others.
Scott: And you look at pictures of old Pokemon.
Scott: Especially the original two hundred and fifty one Pokemon.
Scott: The real Pokemon.
Scott: There's going to be like these JPEGs of them.
Scott: You know, drawings of Pokemon and the official drawings that you're going to see.
Scott: And you're going to see the same ones like on every website.
Scott: Because like one person way back in the day had like, I don't know, a Nintendo Power magazine or some art book or something in the late 90s, early 2000s.
Scott: And they scanned in all the Pokemon pics right as JPEGs.
Rym: And I feel like those same JPEGs have just been passed around the Internet since then.
Scott: One person scanned in the JPEGs and then every other person Google search found those JPEGs.
Scott: And there was no reason for them to scan the JPEG.
Scott: So the same JPEGs have just been going around the Internet on every Pokemon fan site.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Since who knows what year.
Scott: And all of these, like the original official Pokemon drawings of the original 251 by Ken Sugimori, who's the original artist for those Pokemon.
Scott: And it turns out somewhat obviously that whoever scanned those in wasn't like some, you know, great artist to scanner X imaging expert.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they just slap their book on the scanner.
Scott: Pressed it down and push scan and then cropped it.
Scott: Done.
Scott: Pushed auto scan.
Scott: And as a result, those JPEGs actually don't look great.
Scott: Like they're.
Scott: even if you got the originals that were first uploaded, the colors are wrong.
Rym: The colors are like way wrong.
Rym: Like there's a reason why you keep seeing this blue Bulbasaur everywhere.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like they're way wrong.
Scott: The books, you know, it's like if you want to really scan a book, you got to tear the pages out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can't have the book bent in the edge.
Scott: Because then it warps the image.
Scott: Basically, they're all wrong.
Scott: So some extreme nerds.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The good kind of extreme nerd who are super Pokemon fans.
Scott: They went out and they're like, hey, I'm tired of looking at these images that are wrong.
Scott: I got the art book here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I got the real images.
Scott: I'm rescanning this shit properly.
Scott: And they, you know, with modern scanning equipment, too.
Scott: That's also part of it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: 20 years of advances in technology.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: This ain't the Kano scan.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, you could buy a new Kano scan.
Scott: That's really good.
Rym: From what I've so total aside, I was looking to get the new scanner.
Rym: from all the reviews I read.
Rym: Everyone said that the new Kano scans aren't better than like the ancient ones.
Scott: I mean, really, the only reason to get a scanner today is like documents you get.
Scott: And if you want documents, you can just get the shittiest.
Rym: Oh, you know what?
Rym: The Kano scan we use, our Kano scan takes a USB A on one end and a USB B on the other hand.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There is no reason to get a high res fancy scanner if you're just doing documents, because you want to not.
Scott: you want to have PDFs and get rid of everything and recycle everything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Shred it.
Scott: But if you want a fancy scan, the only reason would be photos.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You got negatives, hopefully, or you've got prints and you want to scan those and get them to be high res.
Scott: Then you can enter the world of real scanners and I have an Epson that's still very good.
Scott: They make, you know, some high end ones.
Scott: Anyway, the point is someone scanned in the images properly and they're.
Scott: they're going through this big effort of not just scanning them and uploading them, you know, to the to the major fan sites that, of course, are totally on board with this and happy about it.
Scott: But also like going around to other trying to like spread the word to get other people to update their images on their websites to, you know, the correct.
Rym: So scrolling through this Twitter thread, the person who is posting has a note about how a bunch of insane nerds were screaming at them for erasing history by trying to replace the original images they know and love with these.
Scott: I'm sure I'm sure some, you know, because these images of these bad images have probably been on the Internet longer than some people have been a lot like how there's a lot of people who have weird nostalgia for like the terrible dub of an old anime.
Rym: that isn't even right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I'm sure somebody is out there and has seen like the poorly scanned, you know, and they're like, no, I don't care.
Rym: That's what Diglett really looks like.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like they've seen that poorly scanned Dragonite their whole life and they're used to it and they're like, don't change it.
Scott: And it's like, well, too bad.
Scott: And then it's like erasing the fact these old images from the Internet.
Scott: It's like, I actually agree with that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Preserve.
Scott: You know, it's like it's still a notable thing to be preserved as an example.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Sort of like how we have the dirty tile on the ceiling in Grand Central, but they're not erasing the old ones.
Scott: They'll still be out there.
Scott: There's no way to get rid of the.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's it would probably be difficult to get rid of all the old bad scans.
Rym: So so this is this is cool.
Rym: Like this is really cool.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: One last little news.
Rym: If you haven't had a chance to see Makoto Shinkai's latest movie, Suzume, it's still in theaters, at least in like.
Scott: Oh, it is.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Until like at least next Tuesday.
Rym: It looks like there's even more screenings later.
Rym: Like it's just fully in theaters.
Rym: It's in a ton of theaters.
Rym: But Scott saw it.
Rym: Emily are going to see it.
Scott: So I saw it at the premiere.
Scott: Makoto Shinkai was there.
Scott: Well, the U.S.
Scott: for me.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Seems like it looks from what people are saying.
Rym: It's a Makoto Shinkai movie and I look forward to it is a Makoto Shinkai movie.
Scott: There's no question about that.
Rym: It'll be easy to do a a traditional GeekNights Wednesday review of this.
Scott: We could have done a Wednesday show on it.
Scott: But today, if you had only seen it, I was too busy.
Rym: I literally our household was actually too busy to see it on any of the screening dates until like later this week or maybe like Monday or Tuesday.
Rym: We might have to go see it.
Rym: It's got stuff going on.
Rym: But there's a minor.
Rym: Well, there's a controversy around the movie and you've seen some talk about it, especially in some LGBT forums.
Rym: I'll link to a couple of articles about it.
Rym: But basically, there's talk from Shinkai in at least one interview.
Rym: And I see text.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: I've seen two different versions of this text and I'm not sure if they are just people summarizing translations differently or if it is.
Scott: Also, when we were at the premiere and he was there, he was asked similar related questions and he did not mention or at least the trend through the translator.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He did not mention any of this at that time.
Scott: So this was from some other interview.
Rym: And it's making some waves like several people we know actually don't want to see the movie now because of this news, like it's there's a lot of chatter about it.
Rym: But the talk is that the original movie was going to be pretty much the same movie, except one of the main characters, the ostensible love interest.
Rym: But not really.
Rym: Don't don't worry about the details.
Rym: Not really was originally intended to be a girl.
Rym: And depending on these translations, it was either, quote, a sisterhood type of romantic story.
Rym: I saw another translation of an interview that said a sapphic story, one that said a sorority girl romance or and one of them just says like a sorority fraternity, like coming of age friendship.
Rym: I've seen all these different translations and they all have Makoto Shinkai basically responding, saying something to the effect of I wanted this character to be a girl.
Rym: I didn't really want to have a lot of romance in the movie.
Rym: I was basically told by the producers I had to make it a boy meets girl romance because that's the brand.
Rym: And that's what.
Rym: that's what the movie became.
Scott: What he what he said, at least what the translator said when I was there and he was in the same room that I was right, is that he was tired of doing his usual clouds and romance deal.
Rym: Well, not even clouds and romance.
Rym: It's clouds.
Rym: and will this?
Rym: these two titular characters meet each other?
Scott: That's but I'm not.
Scott: I'm telling you what he said, not what you describe his genre as he said.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The translator said he wanted to get away from his clouds and romance, usual shtick.
Scott: And that his bosses at the studio were like, you know, but that's what sells.
Scott: We're making money here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You still have to include that to some extent.
Scott: And so in a movie that is the least that of any Shinkai movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You sort of get the feeling from watching this movie that like it's it's not about.
Scott: that's like, is there a romance and clouds and skies in the movie?
Scott: Yes, there is.
Scott: There is enough.
Scott: there is that you go, ah, this is a Shinkai movie.
Scott: Look at those clouds and romance.
Scott: They are there.
Scott: I see them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it is not about that.
Scott: It's just sort of like they're.
Scott: they're like they're a part of the setting, I guess.
Scott: And, you know, he put them there because that's, you know, what they told him to do.
Scott: You know, he also said some other interesting things, but we could save them for a show, you know, about the movie.
Scott: But regardless, he didn't say anything about any of that other stuff.
Scott: So the translator didn't say anything.
Rym: So what is translated in this interview is hit.
Rym: Makoto Shinkai's words are quote.
Rym: At first, I wanted to turn this story into a movie about Suzume and another girl journeying.
Rym: Why I even wanted to go in that direction in the first place is because I personally felt a little bit tired of telling the very traditional romance story.
Scott: I felt that I did say he was tired of telling the traditional story.
Rym: I felt that in your name, I did everything that I possibly could in terms of boy meets girl or will they, won't they, will they meet?
Rym: That element of romance is very relatable to the masses, which is why it was subject matter that resonated with the target audience.
Rym: In order, he.
Rym: basically then, there's a bunch of text here I got to skip over.
Rym: He said that he characterized the pitch as quote.
Rym: This is a movie about a sisterhood style type of romantic story.
Rym: And the producer persuaded me to make another your name style.
Rym: boy meets girl romance because of audience expectations.
Rym: And then the kicker quote, in order to not make too much of a romance, I decided to make the primary interest a chair period.
Rym: So I'm going to see, once I see the movie, I'm sure there'll be more commentary on this because these interviews that I'm quoting from were posted only in the last week.
Rym: And we'll review the movie and probably have a lot more to say.
Rym: Scott seems to have a lot to say.
Rym: I expect I will too.
Scott: I mean, the thing is, it's like, you know, if there's a, if there's a meta reason that he went with the chair story, right.
Scott: Then, I mean, there is,
Rym: I think I trust that,
Scott: but at the same time, you know, it's like, you know, you see the chair thing seems ridiculous, but in the, it's like you could actually, if he didn't say anything about it, you could totally believe that like the chair was the first idea.
Rym: Well, meta reason, there's robots in Evangelion for a bunch of meta reasons around selling a show, but yet what's it actually about?
Rym: and do the robots work?
Rym: Eska Flonay, meta reasons.
Rym: Oh, it's a mecha show.
Rym: Actually, no.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, yeah, you could, you could have told me that like you started with the chair thing and everything else came afterwards, which is obviously not the case because we know additional meta information, but the chair works.
Scott: Like, even if it was, even if the genders of the characters were all mixed up, it's like, I feel like the movie would just wouldn't have worked if the person didn't turn into a chair.
Rym: You know, that's relevant because in this interview, he said one final thing.
Rym: I think, quoting him again, through a translator, of course, I think it would also work had Susan May been a boy or had she been non-binary.
Rym: It's not necessarily the context of male, female.
Rym: It's about a human overcoming something in my future films as well.
Rym: I want to focus on that human story as opposed to too much romance or commentary on gender or sex.
Scott: Yes, they're really, yeah, it really doesn't, the genders of the characters, except for, I think, you know, gender only comes into it like maybe with like some side characters, right?
Scott: It's like, they're just, it's, it's really about, you know, it's, it's, it's not about the, the romance, like there's, I don't even think there's any fucking kissing in this movie.
Scott: If I remember, not, oh, there sort of is, actually.
Scott: Time.
Scott: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: I just bumped into this.
Rym: YouTube Music recommended it to me because I listen to a lot of DJs and a lot of remixes and sample type stuff on YouTube Music.
Rym: It's just like, that's the kind of music I listen to lately.
Rym: And what it recommended was a video.
Rym: And it was just called "60s, 70s Japanese Instrumental Cinema Funk Breaks and Beats" from an account called Tripmaster.
Rym: And the title in the thumbnail was "Knocksteady Zencast Volume
Rym: 2.".
Rym: And this is my fucking jam.
Rym: That's all I got to say.
Rym: Listen, this is 45 minutes of some fantastic funky beats that'll make you want to get your Zatoichi or your Samurai nonsense going in a big way.
Scott: So, I mean, that seems to be like everyone's, right?
Scott: I mean, you know, if it wasn't for, you know, Samurai Champloo, right?
Scott: It's like, would we have lo-fi beats to study too?
Scott: Probably not.
Scott: I don't think we would.
Rym: And the DJ who put this together is very, like, point to the stands.
Rym: This is all killer, no filler.
Scott: I like all killers.
Scott: That's how everything should be.
Scott: Alright, so, there's, you know, there's the original Matt Cross TV series, which is as old as we are.
Scott: And then there's the compilation movie "Do You Remember Love," which, you know, fans fucking love the shit out of that movie.
Scott: Even though for me, it's like, yeah, it's good, but it's still, I'd rather watch a TV show because it's still a compilation movie.
Scott: Even though it's animated nicely and whatever, it has an extra song and whatnot.
Scott: But anyway, they, you know, a while ago, for the 30th anniversary of Matt Cross, right?
Scott: Which I think was maybe 10 years ago, I think.
Scott: You know, because it should be 40 years old now, I think.
Scott: Oh no, but the movie is newer, so it's less than 10 years.
Scott: I forget exactly when.
Scott: Anyway, for the 30th anniversary of the movie, there was a Blu-ray Super HD remaster deal, right?
Scott: And they made a documentary to promote the Blu-ray.
Scott: that was an hour-long TV special.
Scott: They also put a documentary on the Blu-ray, but the documentary on the Blu-ray was different, slightly at least, from the documentary that was on TV just once.
Scott: But of course, some nerd recorded the one-hour documentary that was on TV just once.
Scott: And put it on YouTube with subtitles that give you the vibe of VHS subtitles from the 90s.
Rym: I mean, right in the beginning, immediately, it's got a warning, "For private use only, unofficial fan
Rym: sub.".
Scott: So you might want to use your, you know, this is on YouTube, it's been there for seven months, it hasn't been taken down, but it only has 872 views.
Scott: You might want to use your YouTube downloaders to download this, you know, thing, just in case.
Scott: But yeah, if you want to watch a documentary about, you know, the people who made Macross, some of whom I think may have passed away since this documentary was made, if I'm, maybe?
Scott: I have to remember exactly when, the timing of things.
Scott: But, you know, I didn't watch it yet, but it's like, do I even need to, to know that this is Thing of the Day?
Scott: No, no I don't.
Rym: Definitely this is top tier stuff right here.
Scott: Right.
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book, which will very likely- I finished reading a while ago already.
Rym: I'm steamrolling through it, and I think next week on Thursday we could very likely do the show.
Rym: The odds are low that we won't do this show next Thursday, but if we don't do it next Thursday, then the following Thursday, sometime before then we'll have recorded it, because it's a pretty good book.
Scott: You gotta start going to the library.
Scott: like me, you'd get it done in a month no matter what.
Rym: I was just busy.
Rym: I got stuff going on.
Rym: Got projects, got things.
Scott: Doesn't matter how busy you are, if you gotta return the library book, you gotta read it.
Rym: I probably would have just extended it.
Scott: I don't know how many extensions they let you have, I think if there's someone waiting you don't get an extension.
Scott: I don't know how it works at all actually.
Rym: I have no idea, I bought it.
Scott: I'm completely guessing.
Rym: But otherwise, we got no conventions coming up for a while.
Rym: Me and Emily are gonna be at a Star Trek Con hanging out in Philly sometime soon.
Rym: D&I Con, but otherwise, that's not a GeekNights con, that's just us.
Rym: Diversity and inclusion.
Scott: Okay, but what does that have to do with Star Trek though?
Rym: Because it's a super LGBT and POC friendly Star Trek convention.
Scott: But there's no Star Trek-ness in the name of the convention?
Rym: I think there's more name to it than just that.
Rym: I don't know the whole story.
Rym: I think it's a new con.
Scott: I'm not coordinating.
Scott: That could be any con, right?
Rym: When I first heard the name of it, I thought, do not interact con?
Rym: What happens there?
Rym: That's like the opposite of the pleasure dome.
Scott: But the next GeekNights- It's Galactic Diversity and Inclusion convention.
Rym: Ah, I didn't even know the G was on there because in the Discord- It's not.
Scott: If you look at the top left of the website, it just says D&I Con.
Scott: But if you look in the middle of the website, in giant text, it says Galactic Diversity and Inclusion convention.
Rym: All I'm going to say about this con is if you like GeekNights, go to PAXes and MAGFests and cons like that, and you're used to conventions where the websites tell you things, it's easy to forget what most fan conventions are like outside of these very rare gems.
Scott: No, it's not because we see most fan conventions reflected in the media, like Simpsons episodes.
Rym: I'm talking about in terms of like, I look at that website and I'm not sure exactly how it's going to go down, and we'll see what it's like.
Scott: There will be a vendor hall, there might be an artist alley.
Rym: No, there's like events you have to pay extra for to go to, but there's no information on like- Those are usually like autographed meet famous people.
Rym: They are, but there's no information in the schedule on like what time they occur, and some of them don't even say what day they're on.
Rym: It's one of those, a lot of cons, the websites just don't have all the info, and we'll see.
Scott: It looks like a pretty fancy website, it's better than our current website.
Rym: Oh yeah, well because you're working on that.
Rym: Our website very much looks like web 2.0.1, like early days of web 2.0.
Scott: But the first GeekNights- It's still pretty busted, but the new website can be seen at beta.frontrowcrew.com, and it has a search that's, you know, fast.
Scott: But obviously it won't be searching newer content than when I loaded content into it.
Scott: So you might, you're not going to get, like this episode won't be on there.
Rym: But our next GeekNights panel convention will very likely be PEX West.
Rym: I expect to return to MagFest, of course we'll be at PEX Unplugged, unless something- We'll see what happens at MagFest.
Rym: Terrible happens, I'm definitely going to MagFest this coming year.
Rym: The only reason I didn't go last year is because of the masking and the boo-bans, and the year before because of the boo-bans, and the year before because of the boo-bans.
Rym: I don't think it's going to happen that year.
Scott: I'm just saying, we'll see what happens to MagFest.
Rym: Seems like it's going to happen for TBD.
Rym: Otherwise, let's get right into it, because this is sort of a semi-meta episode, in that we realized something profound.
Scott: It's a completely meta episode, not semi.
Rym: Now we did news.
Scott: It's also a completely cod-filed episode, because you got no ideas.
Rym: We did news.
Scott: But that's also part of the meta.
Rym: And things of the day, and all that other shit, but basically, we realized something, because we skipped a bunch of Wednesday episodes, just kind of recently, the last several months.
Rym: Partly just randomly, a random thing would happen on a Wednesday and we couldn't do a show.
Rym: It wasn't just Wednesdays we would skip.
Scott: It was also the hardest day to have show ideas for, by far.
Rym: But we started to think about, why is it the hardest day, and I realized something.
Scott: Because we go through seasons of not watching anything, or we don't watch the same stuff.
Scott: And we can't do an episode if we don't watch or read the same thing.
Rym: But there's more to it than that, because there's even a more fundamental level.
Rym: Mondays, science and technology, like Scott and I are computer and technology professionals, so there's a lot of, even though we struggle to come up with Monday shows too, at least we have like a, we can try to teach you something, we can talk about a topic where we have some nominal amount of professional expertise.
Scott: We are experts, we do, whatever Monday is about is a thing that we do.
Scott: We're actively involved in technology, and I think perhaps that shows, and that the Monday episodes are super popular compared to the other ones, even though we mostly go to PAX, we don't go to tech conferences, but yet the Monday show is more popular.
Scott: Because our technical expertise is, you know, the highest, because that's what we actually do for work.
Rym: We did get a suggestion in the live stream for what to turn Wednesday into, and they said, Wednesday should be, every other week, a tech news roundup.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Well, perhaps
Scott: that listener is evidence of what I just said, and that they'd like the Monday more, because that's a better, our quality might be, I don't think our quality is high on any day, but the listener might believe that our quality is higher on Monday, because our knowledge is higher on Monday.
Rym: The other suggestion we got was make Wednesday food.
Rym: Just food.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But anyway.
Scott: We're not experts on that.
Rym: So Monday, we are professionals, like our day.
Rym: jobs are that, our hobbies are also that.
Scott: I have a degree in that.
Rym: Yep, we both have professional degrees from a real university in that.
Rym: Tuesdays, we are at the bottom tier of professionals in that technically we get comped on badges and compensated in tiny ways.
Rym: Like, we are like the bottom tier of professionals.
Scott: Right, but we've never published a game ever.
Rym: I am attached in a tangential way to two game studios in a formal investment capacity.
Rym: But we give talks, people seem to respect our opinions in this industry more so than we ever expected they would.
Scott: And also- We put effort into studying just of our own will.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Like on purpose, right?
Scott: We're studying and learning, so it's like I don't have a degree, but I'm on purpose for pure enjoyment, right?
Scott: Learning and studying both by playing and reading and watching and et cetera.
Rym: And we have been doing this, not even just playing games, like then.
Rym: that goes back to like when I was three, sitting in front of the Atari.
Rym: But we were like reading about game theory and like getting sweaty and trying hard to understand mechanics of the first urban board games we played for more than 20 years.
Rym: Like we've been seriously pursuing this as a hobby.
Rym: So if Mondays we are legit professionals, Tuesdays we're prosumer.
Rym: We are prosumer game industry people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We have a significant above base level knowledge, right?
Scott: If you're just the average person who enjoys playing games, we have knowledges and things to say that they probably have not heard and might be interested to hear through all of our learning that we have done.
Rym: Another common thread between Mondays and Tuesdays is a lot of what we talk about are active pursuits of things or interactive things as opposed to the pure consumption of one way media.
Rym: We'll get to that.
Rym: Skip Wednesday, talk about Thursday.
Rym: Thursday is the anything show.
Rym: It's whatever doesn't fit in any other category and we talk about a ton of different stuff.
Scott: But the point is, you know, we're starved for Thursday ideas as well.
Scott: But if we do come up with a Thursday idea, it's the fact that we came up with.
Scott: it means it was something that was on our minds.
Scott: It's something we have something to say about.
Scott: And so the content should be good, I guess.
Scott: But is it really good?
Scott: Because I don't know how Thursday is listening.
Rym: We'll say it's good in terms of.
Rym: there are people listening, like there's eight people watching the live stream right now, gaga, and there's actually a lot of chatter in this.
Rym: People are invested in the concept of we're going to retool Wednesday, I guess.
Scott: So Thursday is also... I mean, someone who cares about GeekNights enough to watch a GeekNights live stream, the listener is going to have something to say about itself more than about anything.
Rym: But I guess what I'll say is like from a making a podcast that makes a tiny amount of money and technically is thus a professional podcast and also having made a terrifyingly long running podcast that blurt like.
Rym: it's a hobby and we do it primarily because we like it, but it's done it for a long fucking time.
Rym: We put a lot of effort into this.
Rym: Thursday is a vehicle just to get us talking.
Rym: Like it doesn't really matter what the topic is.
Rym: It just has to be something where we both have more words to say than we can fit into the episode.
Rym: And then it's just an easy show to do.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And the book club, which is also on Thursday, is less about.
Scott: can we make a good podcast?
Scott: What it's more about is A, I can get myself to read.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whereas, you know, sometimes you can sort of forget about books.
Scott: Because it's like if someone comes and asks you what my hobbies are, it's like, oh, you know, biking and photography and baking and computers, obviously.
Scott: And games, tabletop games, board games, video games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like books that don't even enter it.
Scott: But it's like, no, actually, I fucking love books.
Scott: Any time I read a book, I usually say good one.
Rym: I'm also excited to talk about books with other people who have read those books.
Rym: so we can just talk about.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's about, you know, remember to read.
Scott: Enjoy reading.
Scott: Enjoy talking about reading.
Scott: And then get the listener to read.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because I feel like, you know, that's often a thing where it's like if I meet a random, a completely random stranger.
Scott: If you tell me just one fact about that person, like whether or not they read books of any kind for pleasure.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Obviously, it is prejudice for me to judge them based on that one piece of information.
Rym: Judge them.
Rym: You do judge them.
Scott: I do.
Scott: And usually that judgment as very high accuracy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: People who read it's, you know, it just out.
Scott: people who read for pleasure are usually kind of people that I like.
Rym: I'll go further.
Scott: Be around.
Scott: Want to talk to.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And people who don't read books for pleasure are usually the kind of person that, you know, either is a unfortunate and illiterate, which is just sad or be right.
Scott: A person I don't respect wouldn't want to hang.
Scott: I'll go further.
Scott: My kind of person.
Rym: I have known people in my life who did not read for pleasure, who started to read for pleasure at some point in their lives.
Rym: And I will say that every one of those people, I can think of four.
Rym: Five, four or five.
Rym: They became better people in my eyes over time.
Scott: That's why we want the listener to read books.
Scott: That's the whole point.
Rym: So Thursday, again, still it's participatory.
Rym: It's interactive.
Rym: So let's go back to Wednesdays.
Scott: I can actually I can go further than that.
Scott: And I can say during the times in my life when I am reading more books.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I feel like a different, better person than in the times of my life when there is a book draft.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know if that is a causal relationship.
Scott: I'm either direction.
Scott: It could be when I'm feeling good.
Scott: I read books.
Scott: Yeah, it's hard to say.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: But I you know, there is I feel based purely on feeling and no evidence that there is a correlation there.
Rym: I feel the same thing because in the first couple of years of COVID, because I wasn't traveling at all, I was kind of stuck inside.
Rym: I was doing a lot of other things because I was home and I ended up not reading a lot.
Rym: And I just felt better when I picked up another book.
Rym: Then I started reading again, like about a year and a half into COVID, like suddenly my brain was just like, yeah, that's what you needed, buddy.
Rym: Right there.
Scott: That words, words.
Rym: So Wednesdays now, early GeekNights, we had it where there is one minor area where we have some expertise.
Rym: And that area was how to successfully run an anime club in the environment of the 2000s.
Scott: Like we had some expertise.
Scott: We did it.
Rym: We did it well.
Rym: We learned lessons.
Rym: We could talk about it.
Rym: And also we were heavy consumers of anime, animation, manga and comics.
Scott: Like in a time when most people had not seen or read most mangas and animes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, yes, by the time we started to GeekNights, the bookstores are full of manga.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: There was anime on TV by that time.
Scott: Anime was just on DVDs by that time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it was just digital pirated fansubs by that time.
Scott: But the majority of people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was only it was still even then, you know, only hitting the nerds who cared about this stuff, of which there were many.
Scott: But people did not have, you know, the consumption level that we had at the time was way higher than other people.
Rym: We would literally have to like stop and be like, all right, of the five fucking shows we've watched in the last week, which one do we review?
Scott: And not only that, but it was we had because we had started early in the 90s.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We had built up a large arsenal of of anime that we had seen.
Scott: And even people who were big time fans, if they had started becoming fans at the boom time, when the Tokyo pop hit the bookstores, when the ADV hit the conventions.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If they had started, then we were way ahead of them in terms of things we had seen in red.
Scott: And so we could talk about anime, you know, all fucking day.
Scott: There's even more about it than some other people.
Rym: I think what you just said, we knew more about it than some other people.
Rym: That sort of.
Rym: there was some low hanging fruit there that made Wednesday feel equal and gravitas to say Tuesday in that anime, manga, comics were equal in our lives to gaming.
Rym: And we cared about them a lot.
Rym: But at the time, because knowledge of anime beyond just watching it was rare, like even among people who were so nerdy, they went to a nerdy university and joined the anime club and came every week to watch anime.
Rym: They didn't like they couldn't name more than like two anime directors.
Rym: They didn't know anything.
Rym: And because we knew a little bit more, if you look at early anime panels we did at anime cons, our panels were things like, hey, here's the names of 10 directors of anime you've heard of.
Scott: We did that panel a lot.
Rym: We'd be like, hey, did you know the history of like this genre, like really low hanging fruit, like low key read Wikipedia at people basically.
Rym: And that was really low hanging fruit content.
Rym: But look at now, look at the average GeekNights gaming panel.
Rym: We don't make new ones that often because we really want to like research and like know what we're talking about enough to get out of stage and like not be wrong about things.
Rym: And our expertise has grown, but we're not making anime.
Rym: We're not making animation.
Scott: We're not making.
Rym: I can't even draw and can't draw right at all, but also busy and we don't live together anymore.
Rym: So one, neither one of us watch nearly as much stuff as we used to not even just anime, but like anything.
Rym: We do less passive entertainment in general.
Rym: I watch a lot more than Scott, but I watch a lot less than most people we know.
Rym: And Scott watches like nothing.
Scott: At least not.
Scott: I don't watch television, at least, but also I watch.
Scott: I've seen all the movies, though I've seen how many movies I'm seeing right.
Scott: Like this is big time movie season.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: We just did the show where we probably see more movies in the past like month or two than I've seen like in the past several years.
Rym: There's five and I might and I might go right.
Scott: I might go see two more movies.
Scott: I could even just go see one after this show.
Scott: I can go see that.
Scott: I got to see the Mario movie.
Scott: Got to see that you could do a Wednesday show.
Rym: I'm going to go see the movie.
Rym: I'm not going to go see that.
Scott: I might want to see even though I think it's going to be, you know, not necessarily the greatest movie ever or anything like that.
Scott: But I just want to go see the one with the Finnish guy killing.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Rym: I think you mean.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: You mean I could spend.
Scott: I could spend two hours on that whatever.
Rym: But.
Rym: We also we watch a lot less and we're often watching different things just because our lives are different.
Rym: So like Scott Sousa may I'm going to see it like in a week, but like I watched all the houses out except the final movie.
Rym: I don't think you've watched.
Rym: I've watched Zero Owl House.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: It's done.
Scott: I've seen clips of Owl House on YouTube and I've seen many JPEGs and GIFs of Owl House.
Rym: What I will say is it's done.
Scott: I know an Owl House when I see it, but I've never seen it.
Rym: And so all this is sort of coming toward the fact that Wednesdays are unique in that they're.
Rym: they're not genre bound, but they're.
Rym: they're bound to the passive consumption of a narrow spectrum of media.
Rym: And all the other days of GeekNights have a lot of other avenues for shows or professionalism or expertise.
Rym: But Wednesdays are just like, hey, we're going to talk about a show we watched or a comic we read.
Scott: Well, it's not just that.
Scott: It's also that, you know, we already said, you know, our knowledge of this area is admittedly and has become apparent over time.
Scott: Not any more than anyone else's.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if you're also an anime watcher, it's like we, you know, in the year 2023, at least we don't know anything you don't know.
Rym: You might come to us to like find out what we think of a show, but you're not going to come to us to find out a show exists.
Scott: In fact, it's probably one of the only I think more so than any other day.
Scott: It's where the listener comes and tells and has more knowledge than we do.
Scott: And they do.
Scott: There's no denying it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like.
Scott: but I thought, you know, at least I didn't actually think too hard about it.
Scott: But it's just like, you know, it didn't.
Scott: it was like, yes, I don't know.
Scott: You know, I was basically never lying to myself, act in thinking that I knew more than people.
Scott: once I realized.
Rym: I think it's the bar got raised among anime fandom across the board.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, the bar was already high.
Scott: There were already people who knew more.
Scott: But now there's more people who know more.
Scott: It's not just like there was experts.
Scott: And then, you know, I guess we might have previously been in the superfan category, whereas now like anime fans know more than we do because we're just not animating that much.
Scott: We're nerds who watch some anime sometimes.
Rym: Yeah, but we backed off, whereas other people we knew and we see double down on anime and animation the same way we double down on gaming to a degree.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like I have.
Scott: I have halved or maybe even more than halved, you know.
Rym: But also, you know, there was a long, slow decline.
Rym: We got bolstered a little bit because My Little Pony fit into Wednesday because it was anime animation.
Rym: And we were into that for a hot minute.
Rym: But we also stopped going to anime conventions for a couple of for a bunch of reasons.
Rym: We're not going to believe it.
Rym: We talked about that to death.
Rym: But if, say, we were invited to go to, I don't know, Anime Boston, still a great anime convention, and we were invited to PAX at the same time.
Rym: If someone if someone said if PAX came to us and said, hey, we need a new panel that literally happened.
Rym: Yeah, but if PAX came to me right to us right now and said we need a new panel on gaming that's legit and we need it in two weeks for a brand new PAX, we could crank that out.
Rym: We could do something.
Rym: If Anime Boston has to do that for anime, I got fucking nothing that I would be comfortable.
Scott: We could do something, but it just wouldn't be that good.
Rym: It would be Woo Game.
Rym: It would be low tier.
Rym: It would be low.
Rym: It wouldn't be any different from the anime content we did a decade ago.
Scott: It would be weak.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So it would be weak enough.
Rym: I wouldn't want to do it.
Rym: I would decline the invitation.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: So it's like, all right, so we're in this situation.
Scott: We know, like, what do we have to offer?
Scott: manga anime knowledge wise, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: the only thing we really have to offer is, like Rym said, our personal take on a thing that we happen to have both watched or read, which is not that many things.
Scott: It's definitely not a new thing every other week.
Scott: I think the only thing we got, there's no, we don't have knowledge that we can offer beyond reading the same Wikipedia anime news.
Rym: There's one bit of knowledge we've got, but we've shared it fully.
Rym: And I think there's no more to share.
Rym: And that is we know a lot about American anime fandom from a very narrow time period.
Scott: That's I think, yes, to younger people, we can offer knowledge of the older days.
Rym: Our last Anime Con panel, if we ever go back to them, we'll be sitting on one of those old guys panels talking about what it was like.
Scott: We could already sit on the old guy's panel.
Rym: We could sit on the old guy's panel a while ago at this point.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that's not enough for a podcast every two weeks to just lean on that one thing.
Scott: And, you know, not being experts, not being creators, you know, what do we need?
Scott: Do we even, we just can't, we just go cut back?
Scott: Like, GeekNights is now Monday, Tuesday, Thursday.
Scott: Forget Wednesday.
Scott: Or, you know, clearly we just, you know, we could do anything the fuck we want, right?
Scott: We've never actually promised or we actually promised that we wouldn't commit fully to any format.
Scott: We just fell into a format and stuck with it through pure momentum and inertia.
Rym: Well, also because the format worked and we actually, like, we really- Well, it worked production-wise and I guess nobody complained about it listener-wise.
Rym: We also spent a lot of time developing it and we did try other bits in those early, early days.
Scott: We did try some other bits, like once each maybe.
Rym: Yeah, but we settled into this because it works.
Scott: We didn't really try as much as we could have tried other bits.
Rym: But I still- Because I not that long ago listened to a bunch of our beta episodes because they're just on the Patreon if anyone wants to listen to them for free.
Rym: And I did commentary on them.
Rym: That's a whole old thing.
Rym: But I also found all the other sound effects and bumpers that we just haven't used in at least 15 years.
Rym: So, if you came here expecting we're going to announce what GeekNights Wednesday turned into.
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: We're still trying to figure that out.
Rym: So, got a lot of ideas.
Rym: One thing I was thinking is we could turn Wednesday into the review day and that's the only day we review passive media of any kind.
Rym: And Thursday is the open day.
Rym: But that'll hurt us because right now we can lean on talking about a movie we watched on Thursday.
Rym: If we move that to Wednesday, Thursday gets hard again.
Scott: We haven't done too many Thursday movie episodes.
Rym: Not in a while, but that might work.
Rym: There's a lot of ways we could take Wednesday.
Scott: I mean, we could also just forget it.
Scott: Not talking about changing the format of the episode itself, but it's like the schedule.
Scott: We could just only do a Wednesday when we see something.
Scott: And otherwise, we just don't do Wednesdays that often.
Rym: And I'm not opposed to that either.
Scott: There's so many options.
Scott: We could basically do whatever we want.
Scott: We could change everything.
Scott: We could change Monday, Tuesday, Thursday also.
Scott: We could just be like, "You know what?
Scott: GeekNights is now a quarterly
Scott: show.".
Scott: Who says?
Rym: We could make a Friday special that comes out once a month.
Scott: But the point is that Wednesday is the thing.
Scott: that is a problem that needs fixing.
Scott: Even if there's improvements to be made, the other three days aren't perfect.
Scott: But they are not in such a dire strait as Wednesday is.
Rym: And I think what drove me to suggest we do this episode wasn't just.
Rym: we didn't have a good Wednesday show to do.
Rym: Though that was a big part of it.
Rym: I'm not going to pretend it wasn't.
Rym: But another part of it was when we realized that there was something fundamentally different about the topic itself on Wednesday compared to the other days.
Rym: Wednesday just doesn't fit into our lives the way we originally envisioned it anymore.
Scott: Well, I mean, because Monday and Tuesday, like you said, are not passive, right?
Scott: Gaming is, at least even if there is passive games out there, you're playing, right?
Scott: There's still instructions, at least, somehow.
Scott: You know, GeekNights, some of our earliest episodes are How to Not Suck, right?
Scott: We are perhaps egotistically telling people what to do and how to live their lives.
Scott: Giving advice, unwarranted, mansplaining to people how they should go about their business.
Scott: Anyone listening to us can leave this room any time.
Scott: And it's like on Monday we can tell you how you should be using your computer, right?
Scott: How you should be securing it, giving you tech tips and techniques.
Scott: Tuesday we can tell you how to win at games, better ways to design games, other techniques.
Scott: On Thursday, I guess anything.
Scott: But on Wednesday, the only thing we can tell you on Wednesday is which media to choose to consume.
Scott: There's no other instructions besides that.
Scott: And the answer is almost always yes, so why do you even listen to the episode?
Scott: Just see what we've listed in the title and you know it's gonna be yes.
Rym: If you listen to our reviews of anime movies, you're gonna find that in every single episode we've ever done about an anime movie, we tell you watch every fucking anime movie.
Rym: that's in a theater.
Rym: that isn't a sequel.
Rym: Just like always, just watch them all.
Scott: Yeah, but there's not that many of them, even if they're not the best.
Scott: You're not wasting your time.
Rym: But also we've constrained it down to where we can't even just review passive media.
Rym: We can only review passive media that is an animation or a comic of some kind.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: The other thing we're workshopping is...
Scott: I think the other problem is that even if you said, "Okay, Wednesday is all passively consumed
Scott: media."
Scott: Still not gonna work because we don't consume the same media.
Scott: Right, it's like I don't watch basically almost any television whatsoever, right?
Rym: We already do movie reviews, like we got a place for that when we have a movie we're talking about.
Rym: But also we started, we didn't do this intentionally, but we realized we were doing it like over a decade ago.
Rym: We used to review things even if they were really bad or we didn't like them in the early days.
Scott: We used to spend time in our lives watching and reading bad things.
Rym: Yep, partly so we could talk about them.
Rym: But honestly we kind of moved to a model where I only review things that I either want you to watch or I have a really good reason to warn you about.
Rym: Like if something's just meh, I feel like it's not even worth talking about, I don't want to waste your time or my time.
Rym: Nor do I want to give a negative review to something I don't care that much about because the creators might see that.
Rym: That could cause some bad feelings.
Rym: Why add that negativity to the world unless I have a good reason to bring it up?
Rym: So as a result, even movies, we only talk about a movie on GeekNights if we both are really feeling that movie.
Scott: Yeah, well that's I think above all else, that's the biggest thing is that even if it's a gaming topic or whatever, it's like I might not care.
Scott: But usually there's some caring, there is some thought I have in my brain and I have some urge to put that thought into the world in some form.
Scott: Like I have something and I want to tell it to someone.
Scott: It's that same feeling.
Scott: I'm not saying it's a good feeling because it's that same feeling of that guy at the con who's been playing some game and he just really wants to tell someone about his D&D character.
Scott: Right?
Scott: That feeling like you've got some idea, something happened to you, some story you want to tell and you just need an ear to hear it, right?
Scott: And so, you know, podcast is a way where when I have some of those ideas I can, you know, save them up and then I can save them and get that out of my system, right?
Scott: But I think, at least I believe, perhaps wrongly, that when I do that, it's like if I talk about a thing that I have at least some feeling, perhaps a strong feeling about, right?
Scott: That that is a good entertaining content because there's some enthusiasm and excitement and something behind it, right?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if I watch an anime, if I don't, even if it was good and I enjoyed myself, I might not have a particularly strong feeling about it.
Scott: I don't always, like I just watched, we talked about this show a long time ago, we didn't finish watching it, but like I guess a month or two ago I finished watching Tatami Galaxy the whole time.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And it's like, I saw it, I could, if someone wanted to discuss it with me, I could, right?
Scott: I enjoyed it, I would encourage other people to watch it.
Scott: But like when I was done, I had no urge whatsoever to like, I didn't like get a bunch of ideas about the show that I felt like I had to say to like, you know, so even if we did like a final thoughts on it, it's like there would be no excitement there.
Scott: I would have no built up idea, right?
Scott: Of like.
Scott: a thing I really want to say about that show.
Scott: It got me, got me going.
Scott: And so I don't think the show would be that good.
Rym: And there's a lot of early anime episodes where we review an anime that's just like a C-tier anime and we have fucking nothing to say.
Rym: We kind of just summarize the plot and we're like, yeah, probably not worth watching.
Rym: And that's the show.
Rym: Like we just, we wasted your time.
Rym: You could have just watched that, watched an episode and come to the same conclusion.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whereas like you look at the opposite, like say a lot of the panels that we do at PAX and a lot of those, it's like, I've got something grinding my gears.
Scott: I've got something stuck in my craw.
Scott: I got something stuck in my craw, right?
Scott: That is, I really want it.
Scott: I got this idea or I got something and I really want to say it so I can, I can easily just boom.
Scott: I make this whole panel about it and go on a huge, right?
Scott: Just because I, you know.
Rym: We're thinking of new panels, like one of those are proposing an idea occasionally, and usually we know we got a hit when suddenly we just start talking about the idea like a lot.
Rym: Then we know, all right, this is stuck in our craws.
Rym: We're going to do something with this.
Rym: This is a topic.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I don't have anything.
Scott: I got like my anime, manga, comics, craw is basically emptied, right?
Scott: All the things that I had to complain about, like either were said a long time ago are no longer relevant or just, you know, and I think, you know, another thing, looking at comics and forget about the anime and the manga, you know, when we started in the, in the, I guess when I was young, right, I go to the comic book store and had no money.
Scott: So I was only reading like X-Men and Spider-Man 2099.
Scott: That's the money I had at the end.
Scott: And then when I got to RIT, right, I guess, well, the comic book stores went away after middle school.
Scott: So high school, I couldn't get any comics even though I had some money and I spent it on computers anyway.
Scott: So it's fine.
Scott: In college, I had some money and I was able to buy some comics again at a comic book store.
Scott: And then when I got out of college and had a job and at a comic book store in the city, that's when I started to combine and there were podcasts, you know, about comics.
Scott: So then I could learn about comics that I couldn't learn before.
Rym: The cup overflowed at that point.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So then I was just overloading on comics.
Scott: I was just, I got, you know, built up huge shelves, read all the big comics, right.
Scott: You know, trade paperbacks, going back decades, right.
Scott: I just loaded up on all the comics.
Scott: And then what's happened, it took a long time, but I'd say over the past five-ish years, right, it's like a lot of the comics that I was reading regularly ended or went away or whatever.
Scott: New ones did not really come and take their place in my regular reading schedule.
Scott: Some of them I got tired of, like, you know, even the great One Punch Man.
Scott: It's like I got kind of tired of it.
Scott: Things like Chainsaw Man had a part one that ended, you know, Saga went on hiatus and came back.
Scott: I still read that.
Scott: There's no getting away from that one.
Scott: But it's like, but it's like I was putting in reliably for since I think 2006 an order form of comics to buy every month.
Scott: Right.
Scott: No matter what.
Scott: I ordered at least like some comics, sometimes a huge pile of them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: From 2006 up until like, I think last year was the first year where there were months that I ordered nothing.
Scott: Like that went through the whole comic order form.
Scott: And I was like, I'm like, there's nothing on here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like there probably were several comics that were like terrific, fantastic or whatever they might enjoy.
Scott: But I'm not going to buy.
Scott: You know, I'm like, I'm only.
Scott: you know, I was looking at how much money I'm spending on the comics versus how much I'm reading.
Scott: And I'm like, look, I'm only going to buy the ones that I'm going to open the box and read immediately.
Rym: Same strategy with Steam.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It's like if I order a new saga volume and it comes, I hope I'm reading it that night.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or the next day at the latest.
Scott: It's happening immediately.
Scott: But there's a lot of comics that I've bought over time that I buy.
Scott: When I ordered them, I was feeling good about them.
Scott: And they're still sitting here unread.
Scott: And it's like, why did I order that?
Scott: So now the line for what I'm going to order has raised significantly.
Scott: And I'm just not reading that many comics.
Scott: Although I might I still might say that I enjoy comedy, you know, the the the graphic, you know, fiction art form above, like all other forms.
Scott: Probably I just had.
Scott: you know, I already have so much.
Scott: I'm not even reading all of it.
Scott: And it's like I've had my fill and I've already gone through like all the old.
Scott: There was so much old stuff I had to catch up on and I've caught up.
Scott: You know, there might.
Scott: I'm sure I haven't caught up on everything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's just.
Scott: that's not possible.
Scott: But it's like the major significant ultra popular comics.
Scott: I've either read them or I know enough about them.
Scott: So what I have to read now is much less.
Rym: So we'll see what happens with Wednesdays.
Rym: We don't have a strong plan yet.
Rym: We're thinking about this.
Rym: We're thinking about some other things in the show, like maybe adding a new bit to the end.
Rym: But we'll save that for a different.
Scott: You know, we can mix up, you know, and anything is on the table.
Scott: The format of the show, the schedule of the show.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I guess the only thing is I guess we'll agree we'll keep doing it.
Scott: We could cancel the show.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Just say no more GeekNights.
Scott: No.
Rym: I still like consistently somehow in the year two thousand twenty three.
Rym: I still look forward to doing GeekNights most nights.
Rym: Not 100 percent of night.
Rym: Sometimes I'm tired.
Rym: You know, nobody nobody does likes doing the thing they do 100 percent of the time, especially if there's a schedule.
Rym: But I generally like doing this show and I would like to keep doing it.
Rym: And Wednesday is really the only thing I definitely know.
Scott: I don't think I've ever had.
Scott: You know, there have definitely I think I'd say the majority of the time.
Scott: I can't say that like I'm like, oh, yeah, let's do a GeekNights.
Scott: Although that happens.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I don't think I've ever even one time, not once in 15, 16, whatever years.
Scott: I think I have zero memory of ever saying, oh, I don't want to do a GeekNights.
Scott: I don't think that's happened ever.
Scott: Never.
Scott: Not not even one time.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Because if we're like good reasons, like one of us is sick, then it's not, oh, I don't want to do GeekNights.
Rym: It's I can't do GeekNights for canceling the show.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There have been times where it's like there's a thing I'd rather do than GeekNights, like a hockey game or go bike or something.
Rym: It's nice to see a concert like that.
Rym: Definitely skip, skip making your podcast to go to a concert.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But I never once when going to sit to record GeekNights, been like, oh, I don't want to do this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Never.
Scott: So why?
Scott: So that, you know, if I had that feeling, then I think we should cancel the show.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or that's when we would like radically reimagine the show.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Or do something else entirely.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Something completely different.
Rym: Just turn it into a let's play.
Scott: Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Wednesday needs help.
Scott: You know, there's the obvious ideas, right?
Scott: Because, you know, there's been so many formats of audio shows throughout history, right?
Scott: You got your interviews, you got your roundtables, you got your storytelling, your dramas, right?
Scott: You got, you know, speeches, I guess, oration.
Scott: You know, there's only so many formats of spoken content, right?
Scott: To choose from, you know, call in show.
Scott: So we haven't, you know, got.
Scott: we haven't experimented with all the existing formats.
Scott: So clearly we can go to those.
Scott: They're all tried and true.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or we can try to be ultra creative and come up with something new or a mix or who knows.
Rym: So this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patreons for this meta episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Link Iggi, Dred Lilly, Tenebrae, Kace, Kare, MatesMusic, Chris, Hadad, Clinton, Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Haze, Penny Rymer, Rebecca Thun, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl and several people whose names I'm not going to say at their specific request based on the tier or a comment or a flag that they have set in Patreon.
Rym: Tonight, I just leave you with... You're listening to Knacksteady.
Rym: Knacksteady.
Rym: Your channel is confirmed.