Rym: It's Monday, August 28th, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we're talking about blocking on things like platforms and social media.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So this weekend, because of a combination of wildfires, getting a sinus infection, having to travel for other stuff, Emily and I had not actually been to Sandy Hook Beach at any point, even though we usually go like two or three times a year.
Scott: I went one time last Monday by myself.
Rym: Yep, Monday, with your special Mondays.
Scott: It's not my fault.
Scott: Negotiate harder.
Rym: I'm working on that.
Rym: So we went to Sandy Hook, had a great time.
Rym: It was a perfect beach day.
Rym: The water was at its absolute peak temperature for the year, which is always...
Scott: The water when I was there was very nice.
Rym: And of course, it was the last weekend because next weekend is Labor Day weekend.
Rym: And even though with climate change, the beach is still pretty warm and the water is still nice.
Rym: Well into toward the end of September and even into October around New York.
Scott: But the problem is, is that, you know, in places where it's always warm, there are people who are just professional lifeguards, professional beach employees, professional resort employees, right?
Scott: They do that all year.
Rym: Those kids got to go back to school.
Rym: So the beach is closed.
Scott: Right, in New York, in northern places that have seasons, that's a seasonal job, right?
Scott: And schools start Labor Day.
Scott: And a lot of those people are younger.
Scott: College people, high school people even sometimes, right?
Scott: Because that's, you know, a seasonal summer job.
Scott: That's the kind of person that would, you know, or even if it's an adult, it'll be a teacher, right?
Scott: Who's going to work only in the summer?
Scott: Someone who works, not the summer.
Scott: Who is that?
Scott: Someone in academia.
Scott: And as soon as summer is over, they have to go back to the other, their more lucrative job.
Scott: And no matter, even if it remains 90 degrees, it's like we have nobody up here to work because it's not a full-time year-round job here.
Scott: And I think even if, you know, the summer extends to September, October, it's like we still can't quite make it a full-time job because it's like in February, nobody's going to, right?
Scott: It's like the person's not going to work, right?
Rym: It's not worth it to deal with like a couple more months.
Scott: Yeah, you can't have it be a full-time year-round job unless it's really tropical.
Scott: every single month, you know, or at least 11 out of 12 months or something like that.
Scott: So we're in this situation where we need pools and beaches open because it's still warm for, you know, everybody.
Scott: But we got nobody to work there, so we had to close them and it's still hot out.
Rym: Yup, because, you know, climate change is going to radically disturb every aspect of human society in ways that people are not even thinking about.
Rym: Like this tiny thing is going to get worse and worse and worse.
Rym: Ten years from now, it's probably going to be like 90 degrees in November and none of the pools are going to be open in New York City and people are going to die.
Rym: So at least hanging out at the beach, perfect beach day, a few observations.
Rym: So Sandy Hook has been getting more and more popular as we know, like more and more people hang out at that beach.
Rym: That ferry is like really bumping.
Rym: And when we used to go to Sandy Hook, the only food options, unless you biked like all the way over to Highlands, like over that bridge where there's a bunch of good seafood, were basically three food trucks of varying levels of sadness.
Rym: Now, not only are there more food trucks, but there are two full-on, normal restaurants on Sandy Hook.
Rym: That is a new development.
Scott: I only saw the one that was there last year, which is the like, you know...
Rym: I already forget the names, there's the one near the lighthouse.
Rym: Yeah, the one near the lighthouse is kind of small.
Rym: There's another one right next to the ferry dock.
Scott: Oh, okay, I didn't see it.
Rym: It's huge and we thought, like we ate dinner somewhere else because we wanted the good seafood over at Highland, like we biked over there.
Rym: But we went to check this place out.
Rym: There were easily like a hundred plus people in the main dining area of this.
Scott: So you were there on a weekend.
Rym: Yeah, but it was rocking, it was completely full.
Rym: There was like a line out the door.
Scott: Maybe that's why I didn't see it.
Scott: Maybe it wasn't open on a weekday.
Rym: Yeah, I imagine it's only open on weekends.
Rym: I didn't see any hours or anything.
Rym: But also, some minor updates, more of those houses are available for rentals.
Scott: I saw one that had a sign that said "for rent" with some kind of URL.
Scott: I didn't look at.
Rym: Yep, I went to that URL and I saw there's a bunch you can rent and there's also some on Airbnb.
Rym: Also, the campsite that used to, as best I can tell, was always for group camping.
Rym: You had to organize like in advance and it wasn't like a straightforward process.
Rym: Now it just has a bunch of individual tent camping sites you can just reserve on a website just like a hotel for a nominal fee.
Rym: And they even have a process, which was the thing that always kept me away from trying to rent one of the places on this island.
Rym: In the past, if you wanted to go there with your friends and you wanted to use that ferry, the ferry is very strict.
Rym: You can only book one day round trip tickets or like you'll get tackled like that crazy lady that one time.
Rym: So now, there's a thing on the Seastreak website.
Rym: If you are staying on the island or on the peninsula for multiple days because you're camping and you use the express ferry, you can call them and arrange a special multi-day trip where you can come on one day and leave on another day and not get tackled by the park service.
Rym: So we're thinking about camping on Sandy Hook in October and checking it out and seeing what that's like.
Rym: You can always come.
Rym: You just gotta get your own tent.
Rym: I only have one tent.
Scott: I have a tent, but it seems cold.
Rym: Cold?
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: In October?
Rym: It's gonna be perfectly comfortable to camp.
Rym: And in fact, camping in a tent is nicer in like late September or October because you got the nice warm sleeping bag.
Rym: It's not that comfortable usually to camp in a place like that in the dead of summer when it doesn't get under like 75 at night.
Rym: Anyway, Sandy Hook adventures.
Rym: Lots of tech news, not a tech news roundup.
Rym: We're saving that for the future.
Rym: But I'm sure you've seen.
Scott: If you go long enough, you can refill your quota.
Scott: You could do two tech news roundups in a row.
Scott: I could.
Rym: The listener is always asking for the tech news roundup.
Scott: There's like 10,000 podcasts and websites that are nothing but tech news roundups.
Rym: Yeah, and I get the impression either they're all bad.
Scott: Shouldn't we do something different?
Scott: If you want tech news roundup, why don't you just go to one of the people who do it every single day?
Rym: There's a thousand Spidermans all over the place, but why are we talking a lot about Spider-Verse?
Rym: That's the good one.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: So in some news, and this is a technology news because this is an area where technology was employed and had problems and needs to be employed better.
Rym: And it fits into a common theme of GeekNights.
Rym: One aspect of the extreme wildfires and the devastation in Hawaii and Maui during the wildfires not too long ago was that there are warning sirens on the island.
Scott: We talked about this already.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: The warning sirens were not used.
Scott: Yes, because they thought people would hear them and run up away from the water.
Rym: So the technology problem that is now in the news being talked about is how do you inform people in a place like Maui about different kinds of disasters?
Scott: Right.
Scott: We've been relying on our text message alerts, but guess what?
Scott: That shit was down.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Put a tweet out.
Rym: Well, Twitter doesn't even work anymore, let alone people don't have internet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The cell towers were on fire, right?
Scott: It's like, yeah, the radio, you know, you could have a radio tower.
Scott: that, you know, but people don't turn on radios.
Rym: Nor do most people even have radios anymore.
Scott: Or broadcast television.
Rym: The only radio in our apartment, I was thinking about this, the only one is gone.
Rym: Because the last radio we had was the same alarm clock radio that I had since middle school.
Rym: that could theoretically get AM and FM if I wanted it to.
Rym: And we got rid of that thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, I have radios.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I don't have any because what would I ever use one for?
Scott: I mean, I have an emergency radio and I also have a little Sony radio.
Rym: But this gets into an even bigger problem because even if, like, how do we solve this problem?
Rym: Does the government need to start giving people emergency radios coupled with instructions on when and how to use them?
Scott: No.
Scott: I think by law, they should, you know, put AM/FM radios in all smartphones.
Scott: Otherwise, you can't sell them in the US.
Scott: Tough shit.
Rym: That would actually require some more expensive chips and I don't think people would use them anyway.
Scott: There have been cell phones in the past.
Scott: In Japan, flip phones could pick up broadcast television, right?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: My old cell phone could do that.
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: It required physical headphones plugged into it to act as the antenna.
Rym: You can't have an antenna.
Rym: You need a bigger antenna or that doesn't work.
Rym: All those phones required wired headphones plugged in.
Rym: Guess what iPhones don't have?
Scott: A point I'm pretty sure.
Rym: You need to be through an adapter because you need a direct connection for that type of antenna.
Scott: I think there'd be a way to accomplish this.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: This doesn't seem impossible to me.
Rym: Yeah, put the headphone jack back on or give people an antenna that has to be plugged into their device.
Scott: I think that, you know, this is a solvable problem.
Rym: But also, even if you did that, one, most people are not going to have an up-to-date cell phone.
Rym: Like, most people either don't have a smartphone or have an old one.
Rym: And two, even if you do this, I don't think people would even think or know to activate that feature or even be aware that it existed.
Scott: That's okay because you can have the emergency broadcast system broadcast a signal and that signal would then automatically activate the radio in the phone.
Scott: You wouldn't have to, like, go through it on purpose.
Rym: That is more infeasible because they're not always listening.
Rym: And making them always listen would drain the batteries.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: I'm saying there are significant technical challenges to that.
Scott: Broadcasting drains the batteries.
Scott: Receiving...
Rym: So you should look up the difference between AM and FM and why you can have unpowered radios of certain kinds, but not unpowered radios of other kinds.
Scott: Well, we're not using this spectrum for, you know, people aren't listening to actual radio anymore, so we use the unpowered kind.
Rym: Except we haven't shut all that existing stuff down yet.
Scott: Shut that shit off.
Scott: We ain't using it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I guess the technology problem here is pretty interesting because in New York City, the way, like, all commercial buildings work is there's one kind of sound that means fire GTFO.
Rym: And there's another...
Scott: Well, I mean, a lot of modern buildings, the alarm systems actually say words.
Rym: Well, that's what I was about to say.
Rym: They still require...
Scott: Or carbon monoxide.
Rym: Yes, that's type two.
Rym: Terrorist.
Rym: Is a different tone.
Rym: that, as far as I can tell, by law is a different tone.
Rym: And that tone means listen for further instructions.
Rym: And those are the only two tones because we have more than two tones.
Rym: Who the hell... What human, average human of average intelligence and average knowledge will know the difference between three or four or five different tones, especially when different states are going to do it differently.
Rym: So New York has got two tones.
Rym: One of them is fire.
Rym: Get the fuck out.
Rym: And the other one is listen for instructions.
Rym: Don't do anything.
Rym: Listen for instructions.
Rym: We'll tell you what to do with words.
Rym: And I feel like that type of system of there are no more than two different kinds of signals.
Rym: And one of them should be the... If you hear this signal, do the specific thing that we have been teaching you your entire lives to do.
Rym: Like in Hawaii, the thing you are told if that siren goes off is head up mountain.
Rym: Just get that.
Rym: There's tsunami coming.
Rym: Head up mountain.
Rym: So the second tone should be activate whatever emergency device the government gave you or turn on your cell phone and hit the emergency button or whatever.
Rym: Like wait for instructions.
Scott: I also feel like these low population areas with specific disaster concerns...
Rym: You can do what Costa Rica does and what a lot of countries do and this is super effective.
Rym: A truck with a megaphone and people on bikes with megaphones just fan out from the emergency center telling people what to do actively.
Scott: We definitely do not employ that method enough in the United States anywhere.
Scott: It's like in Japan.
Scott: you see them doing it for like political campaigning.
Scott: And remember the great northeast power outage?
Scott: I'm not saying we should use it for political campaigning or advertising but it's like that method is not used enough here.
Scott: It is effective and good in high population areas.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Case in point.
Rym: If there's a riot because some live streamer caused a problem in Manhattan, a bunch of people immediately show up to handle the situation.
Rym: You'd think disaster response would be a similar high value thing for society but capital is angered by this idea.
Rym: Anyway, got any news?
Scott: We do have a news.
Scott: There's been a lot of hoo-ha around Dolby Vision, Dolby Atmos, Dolby everything lately.
Rym: I don't even have them all straight in my head.
Rym: I gotta look it up every time.
Scott: I watched some YouTube videos so now I know.
Scott: But basically Dolby, they make these technologies which are good/bad that allow basically creators of mostly movies but also television shows and other television productions to sort of distribute and master their audio and video in a certain way using Dolby technologies in order to try to guarantee to the extent feasible that when you watch, because they're mastering some movie doing color grading on like a monitor, a special studio monitor, that's like a reference thing that costs $40,000.
Scott: So there's no way that you with your $800 TV from Costco are going to be seeing the same color that they see.
Scott: So they want to try to guarantee that you see the color they see as much as you could.
Scott: or you don't have the sound system that they have in their recording studio but they want to make sure that you hear as much as close to the fancy movie theater as you possibly can with what you have in your home.
Rym: You want to know how movie theaters and stadiums actually set that up?
Rym: They'll send tones of different frequencies out all the speakers and they put sensors and people all over the facility and they use that to autotune.
Scott: The ones that care can set it up.
Scott: but the thing is the vast majority of theaters and home theaters especially but also real theaters do not go through the effort of setting everything up properly.
Scott: Imagine
Rym: the average person who has a TV and some stuff and then you tell them yes get this extra $100 device and put it in the middle of your living room and then hit a button and it's going to screech for an hour and let it do its thing.
Scott: There are those audiophile nerdy types but there are also those other types who aren't believing in audiophile nonsense but they just really want their home theater to be perfect.
Scott: so they'll pay someone to come calibrate their TV and pay someone to calibrate their stereo.
Scott: So Dolby has a thing called Atmos.
Scott: you probably heard of it and what Atmos is is basically just even more surround sound.
Scott: It's like you know.
Scott: see if we had we're used to like you know 5.1 said whatever right it's like Atmos will go the even further.
Scott: not just rear front center channels right but actually sounds going up and you know over your head right and things bouncing sounds off the ceiling and shit like that to make it sound like things are coming from anywhere.
Rym: Is that 14.1?
Scott: I have.
Scott: no I know it it's.
Scott: there's no set number for it because it depends what your equipment is.
Scott: but you know generally you know you're going to have like some rear speakers with some like upward firing drivers right that and shit like that.
Scott: And like your center channel would be like some soundbar with like who knows how many tiny drivers is.
Rym: a true audio file will want a 3D printed fully anatomically correct set of human heads arranged in their TV so that any characters dialogue is recreated with actual biological vocal cords in real time.
Scott: That'd be good.
Scott: so the thing with Dolby Atmos is that you know it works.
Scott: but you have to get like you know Dolby Atmos equipment and set it up specifically.
Scott: position the speakers right and you know a lot of people have different rooms right.
Scott: for example the room I have is not ideal because the you know it's not huge so the couch is up against the wall.
Scott: you can't really put speakers behind you right so you can't read.
Scott: the rear channels aren't very rear are they.
Scott: Or you know things of that nature and you know you get a lot of people.
Scott: you know not too many people have like wireless systems right.
Scott: that's you know.
Scott: there's also various companies for example Samsung.
Scott: I forget what they call it.
Scott: they have like a special Samsung only thing where you won't actually turn off the speakers in your television.
Scott: it'll incorporate them in to whatever sound system you already have.
Scott: Shit like that.
Scott: so Dolby actually announced the thing today.
Scott: it's called Dolby Atmos flex connect right.
Scott: so hypothetically the way this would work is that.
Scott: Just like Rym said oh with the professional calibration they put microphones and sensors all around and play sounds out of all the speakers.
Scott: and then right it basically sort of does that in your home.
Scott: so your TV would play sounds out of all its speakers.
Scott: however many the fuck you've got with your sound bars and your wireless rear speakers or who knows what you got and then the you have microphones in the flex connect television.
Scott: Right and then that would figure out what to do.
Scott: and there you go.
Scott: now you've got a Dolby app.
Scott: you're going to get the as much at most as you can get with what you got.
Scott: so this is actually strange because.
Scott: Usually this Dolby shit is all about making money for TV manufacturers and for Dolby.
Scott: right because it's like number one.
Scott: if you want to have a TV with Dolby shit in it you have to pay a licensing fee to Dolby.
Scott: So for example some TV manufacturers you know just have HDR something something which is like open right and open license protocol whatever and they don't have Dolby vision because they would have to pay Dolby to have Dolby vision certification on their TVs.
Scott: And it's like alright you know is the HDR 10 whatever?
Scott: just as good probably.
Scott: but you know the thing is some people will only buy a TV if it has Dolby vision because they really want to make sure that if they get some booray that was Dolby vision that it's the colors are exactly right even though they probably couldn't tell if it was the HDR.
Rym: I mean that's why you know even doing like color like design work.
Rym: I have some Dell ultra sharps and they're pretty good on color but they're not like pro good and it's fine but they're definitely better than like random LG.
Scott: Right.
Scott: so there's a two levels of making money you pay the manufacturer pays Dolby for a license and then the manufacturer hopes to get increased sales because they can slap a Dolby logo on their product.
Scott: this the Dolby flex connect seems to satisfy both those things but also maybe not because.
Scott: Yes the you know the Dolby would make money from the licensing and the manufacturer of a television would make money from selling their flex connect television but they might actually lose money on selling sound systems.
Scott: Because hypothetically with flex connect you could just connect whatever the fuck speakers you've got not some Dolby vision you know or Dolby at most certified sound bar system which is probably what people would buy anyway.
Scott: but like you could theoretically make a TV.
Scott: That just has Bluetooth in it and you connect as many Bluetooth speakers as you can find and you throw them all over your room and you don't care where that where they are or what direction they're facing or what kind they are.
Scott: mix all the brands together like as many as you can pair right without Bluetooth failing.
Scott: And this will play sounds out of all of them and do as much Dolby at most as it can do with the speakers that you provided that were you know cheap Bluetooth speakers you bought off of.
Scott: you know discount.
Rym: You know what is that that idea scratches is something that every nerd was obsessed with back before computers you know had the idea of things like more than one core or more than one processor.
Rym: everybody wanted to make a Beowulf cluster of something.
Scott: Yep so this could also theoretically obviate the need for like the Samsung thing I talked about where it uses the TV where it incorporates the TV speaker because a flex connect TV would obviously just.
Scott: Play sound out of its speaker as part of the and always incorporate it right it would just every speaker it can find and make noise out of will be incorporated into the at most so.
Scott: Yeah I think maybe this is like a good sign like hey you know when if you need a new TV wait for flex connect to actually come out and get a flex connect TV and then you know that'll be good because like you know forward in time.
Scott: Whatever speakers you happen to own or whatever you know will always kind of work.
Rym: right now that my my my conundrum is one.
Rym: I'm looking at buying a TV now and I may wait because of this because the current TV has not died yet it's it's having some troubles but it has not died yet.
Rym: But I am vacillating on the audio side between a kind of a different problem or a different question.
Rym: do I want long term.
Rym: Hyper accurate audio to what the media intended or do I want to go the opposite direction like I used to do like listening to music in high school and.
Rym: Just fuck it all up and mix it to my own personal enjoyment regardless of what the creators intended.
Rym: for example maybe I just start boosting the mid range vocals and put compressors in my chains to compress everything down to make it more convenient to listen to and watch movies in my actual real life.
Scott: Yeah but I mean it depends.
Scott: right because certain you know different movies are going to that's you know we're going to need that.
Scott: some aren't right and also it's.
Scott: it's not so much about the how the the sound right the equalization or whatever you're going to do in that department but just the positioning.
Scott: Yeah right it's like you know.
Scott: do you want to hear a star destroyer actually fly over your head or are you OK with just.
Scott: Right because you're home and you're not at the movie theater?
Scott: who cares what?
Rym: it reminds me a total side thing.
Rym: I saw an article and I got to find it again because I want to see how much more there is.
Rym: an argument from a doctor that the current debate of.
Rym: Movies are mixed wrong and no one can hear the audio anymore has a complication.
Rym: People have damaged their hearing more it but we want the error we are in since when this complaint started to arise it happens to line up with a bunch of industry trends but the complaints are broad even in places where Hollywood has not penetrated in the same way.
Rym: So this doctor's argument was that what's actually happening?
Rym: this is the first generation that got old and lost their fucking hearing like everyone has for all of time and was online enough to complain about it.
Rym: That and is what this doctor's arguing.
Rym: And anyway.
Rym: I think it's time for things of the day.
Rym: so I'm back on my neutrino kick and cork kick and I'm increasingly watching ever increasingly mathematical videos about quantum physics and quantum theory.
Rym: but the video I want to link to is.
Rym: Just fantastic.
Rym: it's not long it's like 15 minutes long and what it does is it explains as simply as possible.
Rym: To the best of our current knowledge like 2023 what's the best we know about what the hell quantum theory means and what it is.
Rym: And it's just really well done.
Rym: it has this great diagram that kind of shows that everything we think of as a particle it's basically just like a field and each one of these fields is like one dimension of a wave in space and we're pretty sure that's what reality is.
Rym: Really good video.
Rym: it's not three blue one brown where it's gonna feel like you understand and then it shows an equation that you can't parse and then it's all down here from there and never gets to the point of showing you an equation that you will not understand.
Scott: Okay so you ever go to restaurant.
Scott: usually it's going to be like a Chinese restaurant jab you know East Asian restaurant but not always.
Scott: and there is you know food that is not edible is plastic food that is on display to show you what the meal looks like but it is made of plastic.
Scott: right but it looks like you know like that's what the food looks like.
Scott: Or pretty close to it other than maybe like a hint of shininess that lets you know it's plastic and not edible.
Scott: yeah I've seen those around quite a bit in my life and the question is where do those come from?
Scott: is there just like you know did someone make the food and then like cast it in wax?
Scott: did somebody?
Scott: is there a catalog of like fake food you can buy?
Scott: and right.
Scott: And the answer is there's people like this guy in this video who have been making fake plastic food for like fifty years.
Scott: he's like a craftsman an artisan and he makes fake food.
Scott: and in this video he makes fake food and he just he just comes right out of the gate.
Scott: he makes a lettuce like out of nothing.
Scott: it's like what.
Scott: It's like a wizard of making fake food.
Scott: if only making real food was so easy.
Scott: well I mean it's not easy.
Scott: the guys you know a highly talented skilled you know legend of the craft but you know this is this is just fascinating.
Scott: this video right it's like he just makes it with like this.
Scott: he's got some sort of chemical some sort of plastic thing where you put it in water.
Scott: And it starts to solidify.
Scott: but he can sort of you know mix it up and reshape it and mix the colors of it before that happens.
Scott: I wonder what that material is but it's pretty just you know even if I had the material I couldn't work with it like this guy right.
Scott: Just gets it perfect immediately.
Scott: right you can make any kind of food make you know ice creams or whatever.
Rym: this feels like the kind of thing where this person has one or more apprentices and people learn it by learning from someone who is good at it and not from an institution.
Rym: In the meta moment the GeekNights book club book the murderbot diaries I have read 1.4 of the murderbot diaries and I expect to have read a lot of them by the time we get back from PAX because I have two six hour flights.
Scott: I've read.
Scott: I've read like four murderbot diaries for I think four maybe five I'm not sure.
Rym: I feel like around the first or second week of October.
Scott: I only have two left and I'm gonna get other.
Scott: I'm gonna get them from the library soon.
Rym: Which implies we're probably gonna have read all the murderbot diaries by the time we do this.
Scott: There's one that's coming out in November that so we're not if we haven't read all of them.
Rym: All the murderbot diaries that exist as of August 28, 2023.
Scott: You know what we could do since they're so easy to read and so fast.
Scott: we could just wait till the one comes out in November right read it and then do the episode in November.
Rym: We could do that.
Rym: target November.
Scott: Yeah and since it's so many books that gives people time because I think one of them is not a short one.
Scott: I think one of them is like an actual novel.
Rym: Well our friend Luke in the forum was complaining that starting with the fifth book they get really long.
Scott: That must be the fifth one that I'm about to read.
Scott: So let's do it.
Scott: let's just go to November and then we can have all of them read including the brand new one and we'll have a relevant book club episode.
Rym: Yeah so start reading the murderbot diaries.
Rym: So far I have enjoyed them.
Rym: There's a lot going on.
Rym: They're not the best books I've ever read and they're not exactly going to be mind-blowing if you are well versed in science fiction.
Scott: Spoiler it's one of those books where it's most.
Scott: it's not entirely about what happens.
Scott: It's mostly about what happens and it's it does have something to say but it's mostly what happens right.
Scott: But it's fun and the characters are likable and that's why.
Scott: I really like murderbot.
Rym: I just imagine murderbot as being this this in its in its own mind this gremlin like a gremlin like entity whose sole goal is to fuck around not have to do work watch TV play video games and the world keeps intruding.
Rym: and it's just like I guess.
Rym: but it actually does kind of care a little but it's shy.
Rym: Anyway I've read 1.4 of these books.
Rym: we'll see if it.
Rym: murderbot has increasing troubles as time goes on.
Scott: Also yes it yes it does.
Rym: We will not be doing a show on Thursday because we will be flying to Seattle for PAX West 2023.
Rym: We're doing an all new panel games you can't play on Sunday at 3 30 p.m.
Rym: in the blue morpho theater.
Scott: Otherwise the GeekNights website is actually you're not gonna believe this it is like nearing completion not completion but like the point at which it does everything the current website does and it's better than the current website.
Scott: Therefore we can launch it and they continue to work on it which will be easier to do than working on the old website because it's actually using modern technologies and not ancient versions of everything.
Rym: I think the most important indicator that this is coming along.
Rym: we're at the point where I have to actually start doing my short task list of things that only I can do or that I can do it.
Scott: So what we're gonna do is we're gonna pick a day maybe in a couple weeks and we're gonna launch it on some server.
Scott: you can't get to listener right and then we're gonna hack away at it until it's correct and then we'll move the DNS entry and then it'll be live.
Rym: And so means I gotta do my full elevated adobe marker test to make sure that adobe didn't break anything.
Scott: if it that really is for me that the markers don't work they don't work right.
Scott: to work on that later it's not a necessary feature.
Scott: Also you know once it goes live I'm gonna make the.
Scott: there is a. you know the git repository open source.
Scott: so if you want to then for once it's live.
Scott: you can then help work on the website if you so desire.
Scott: there's a list of things that are not done that could be done like for example it doesn't currently automatically like post a new episode to discord right that's a feature that pretty easy to add.
Scott: It might take like a you know a couple hours of work but I haven't done it.
Scott: so you could.
Scott: you could do that so I don't have to if you want.
Scott: Send a full request and I may or may not reject it.
Rym: Not all help we need or would ask for or would be happy to receive is programming.
Rym: for example a while ago we crowd sourced our terms of service and community guidelines and there is stuff like that that you could help us with on the website as well.
Rym: So don't think that if you're not a programmer you can't help.
Rym: not that the programming is hard for this kind of thing but there's a lot of like text and like categorization and helping us with labels and things that you could actually for real help with.
Scott: Yeah we're going to start.
Scott: also you know another feature that's planned is to help clear out the 404s and dead links on news is things of the day etc.
Rym: Oh man I just randomly the other day I found an old episode of GeekNights and I saw the name of the thing of the day and I was like what the fuck is that?
Rym: and of course it goes nowhere like it's dead.
Scott: You could listen to the episode and find out.
Rym: I could and we'll see.
Scott: That's what the listener would do.
Scott: is they would go and you know.
Rym: Yeah anyway let's get into the main bit.
Rym: so this was partly predicated by a news which we'll talk about as part of this but also.
Scott: Let's talk about that news first.
Rym: But this is a broader topic.
Rym: so Twitter which was kind of one of the more important social networks in history for a lot of reasons.
Rym: Notable and again this is a I'm not saying this is good I'm saying this is what happened situation.
Rym: Twitter of course has shat the bed and somehow has continued to shit the bed in increasing ways.
Rym: But this latest one isn't just annoying it is dangerous to a degree to the people still using Twitter.
Rym: Twitter is removing the ability to block other users.
Rym: Just full stop now there we could.
Rym: we don't need to address why they're doing it which comes down to the right wing.
Rym: People on Twitter who are angry at being blocked which is one of the main things driving Twitter.
Rym: Also advertisers and influencers who are obsessed with having their opinions are supposed to be seen.
Rym: A lot of bad people don't want you to be able to block people and blocking is a fundamental safety feature of any interactive platform in the world.
Rym: full stop.
Scott: So they are keeping muting right.
Scott: so let's talk about how it's implemented specifically on Twitter right.
Scott: And I'm not saying it's entirely right to get rid of blocking but it's not entirely wrong either because.
Rym: I do disagree with what you're about to say pretty strongly because you didn't use Twitter the way most people use it.
Scott: That's fine but blocking on Twitter right doesn't actually never even when it was there did not actually block anyone right.
Scott: If your account was unprotected meaning that your default tweets were completely public or if you had a protected account blocking is meaningless because no one can interact with you unless you allow them right so that that doesn't account.
Scott: So if you had an unprotected account someone who was blocked right they would not.
Scott: if they tried they couldn't follow you right.
Scott: And if they you know if you tweeted they wouldn't see your tweets.
Rym: They also couldn't search for you.
Rym: they could.
Rym: basically as long as they were logged in they could not see.
Rym: it was like you didn't exist anymore.
Scott: But they could log out and then see you.
Scott: so there's no point.
Scott: There is no reason to hide something that is public from someone right.
Scott: It's like yeah there's some Nazi right and it's like you know.
Scott: if they're they're harassing me right.
Scott: it's like okay if I want to prevent them from seeing my tweets but my tweets are still public and they can log out and see them.
Scott: why prevent them from seeing them when they're logged in.
Rym: Because as most people who were harassed especially minorities and targeted groups the main reason they use this is because yes it's not perfect but it introduced significant friction to harassers.
Rym: In that someone who wants to harass has it.
Rym: it's not as like an impulsive person a Nazi who just sees someone they don't like and wants to harass them and spout slurs at them or whatever.
Rym: You block them now they don't see you anymore.
Rym: they probably don't think about you much anymore.
Rym: they don't see your content.
Rym: you don't pop into their feeds especially because these communities were sharing block lists.
Scott: But if they wanted to harass you right it's like sure they can't tweet at you but they could write a tweet that's like the letter A the letter T space Rym like hey my followers everyone tweet AT space RYM.
Scott: he's a person we want to harass.
Scott: It didn't actually protect you.
Rym: It did to a meaningful degree that friction really cut down on the amount of harassment.
Scott: What they should have done is implemented actual blocking right which is you know like there's no way it right.
Rym: I do disagree because that's infeasible and the blocking feature was extremely effective for marginalized groups.
Rym: You're really underestimating how powerful the blocking as it was was especially before muting.
Scott: the muting that they still have right effectively accomplishes the same.
Rym: No it absolutely does not.
Scott: Not how is it not?
Rym: because one the biggest preventing any tweet that that person makes you won't know because almost no one blocked people to not see the harassment coming at them.
Rym: The main reason targeted groups use the blocking feature was also to make sure that their tweets generally didn't penetrate as far into those bad spaces because these groups were sharing block lists.
Rym: And if someone's a harasser usually everyone who follows them was also on the same block list and that introduced a huge amount of very real and material friction to that community of shitheads even noticing that their targets were still active.
Rym: It materially reduced the harassment that they received not because they didn't see the messages but because you couldn't even just retweet.
Rym: if you want to retweet to direct hated someone.
Rym: You had to log out make a burner account.
Rym: you had to do all these extra steps that only you know.
Scott: you could just tweet on your account and just don't put the at symbol in front of the person's name and then tell all your followers hey everyone you know.
Rym: Most of those followers are usually also on the same block list because of the shared block list.
Scott: You could have a mute list and now you don't see any of the harassment.
Rym: No but the followers still see it and the harassers can still organize around doxing you pointing people at you so they come to your website and other things.
Rym: The blocking being too way was very effective.
Scott: They could do that even if they can't see your tweets.
Scott: Yes they could but they didn't.
Scott: It doesn't actually protect you from anything.
Rym: Scott go talk to any of the communities who use these features.
Rym: they will tell you they were very effective.
Rym: So I do not agree even remotely that muting and blocking are comparable in any way in terms of how people actually use Twitter.
Scott: I think the whole point right.
Scott: the fundamental issue here is that this argument we're having right highlights the core problem not just Twitter right.
Scott: But basically the whole internet the battle that we've been fighting on the internet one of the core battles of the internet since its inception or maybe even pre internet right which is that you are a person as a consumer of information right.
Scott: Everyone everyone in the whole world wears both hats right.
Scott: But as the consumer of information you only want to see what you want to see and you don't want to see anything that you don't want to see right.
Scott: It's like here are the things that I want to see.
Scott: I want to see tech news.
Scott: I want to listen to GeekNights.
Scott: I want to know how the Mets are doing and I don't want to know anything else that I didn't ask for.
Scott: I don't want it right.
Scott: Harassers I don't want to see anything harassers are saying.
Scott: Ellen Musk don't want to see anything he's saying advertising some companies.
Scott: I don't want to see that right.
Scott: And then the other hat right which is I am a producer of information right or art or whatever right a journalist anyone.
Scott: I've created information.
Scott: I wrote something right I had.
Scott: I just had an idea.
Scott: randomly I farted.
Scott: I wanted to share my fart.
Rym: Now that person wants people to see on.
Rym: ethically that person may want to force people to see exactly.
Scott: you share the thing that you want to share with the world.
Scott: you put it out there right.
Scott: And the question is well there are people who are going to ask to see the thing that I shared.
Scott: the listener of GeekNights right is like they are explicitly subscribing to GeekNights.
Scott: they want GeekNights so if I put out a GeekNights they can see it.
Scott: But should someone who is not subscribed to GeekNights should GeekNights ever show up on their screen right now?
Scott: should there?
Scott: should it even be possible for that to happen?
Scott: right.
Scott: And it's like well if it's not then how would anyone ever find GeekNights you if the only things that they would have to know about it already?
Rym: now that zooms out to an even bigger problem discoverability of why is finding GeekNights.
Rym: GeekNights is the example that we're not making an argument about us here the listener already found us but GeekNights.
Rym: Why would GeekNights be so desperate to get people to see it?
Rym: mostly because capitalism capitalism.
Rym: most people who are making content and making things and having ideas and aggressively promoting on the internet are themselves hustling because they need people to see that or they will starve.
Scott: Right there are some people who are doing it for the money some for the fame some for both right right and it's like people just want to be seen.
Scott: right.
Scott: and it's like if you're blocking ads but then you're like also trying to get someone to see even if it's not an ad for a product or something you'll make money from.
Scott: but like you just really want your tweet to be seen by a lot of people.
Scott: you told a funny joke and you want a lot of people to laugh people who aren't following you right.
Scott: It's like well then you're that's.
Rym: you're still pushing information on people who didn't ask for it which right like I think most billboards should be banned like I think non-consensual information sharing is should be strictly regulated.
Scott: the ideal the ideal system is one in which you don't have blocking because everything is blocked.
Scott: Absolutely everything by default is equivalently blocked.
Scott: you only see what you ask to see.
Scott: so if you tweet into the wind or whatever you do activity pub into the wind right and a bunch of harassers see it and they you know pass it all around.
Scott: all the Nazis pass Scott's tweet around that says Nazis suck right and they're all sharing it amongst each other and hating on me.
Scott: I won't see that.
Scott: I won't even know what happened.
Rym: right you can be dangerous and there are instances of this where I mean it's no different than like writing in your journalist.
Scott: you write an article in the newspaper.
Scott: you have no idea who reads it or who's discussing it in the.
Scott: at the got it pinned up on the wall at the clan house.
Scott: you don't know.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's no different than that.
Scott: it's like you put information in the world and you do not know who is reading it what anyone's doing with it.
Scott: At all right you just tossed it out there and you don't know how many clicks it got.
Scott: you know how many views it got.
Scott: you don't know how many how famous you are.
Scott: you don't know how much money you made.
Scott: you don't know nothing.
Scott: you just putting it out.
Rym: And I think this is there are two.
Rym: I think the blocking to prevent someone else from interacting with your information is a separate but adjacent conversation.
Rym: to blocking to not see someone's content because exactly they are both.
Scott: The same word.
Scott: the same word is used for both things but they are completely different.
Scott: and around.
Rym: back out of the Twitter thing our disagreement just now.
Rym: Twitter achieved both with a moderate amount of success but some significant limitations and Twitter also was a very widely used platform.
Rym: so now we're in a situation where both sides of that equation just got gutted on what was one of the biggest social networks in the world.
Scott: No the only one side was gutted which is the.
Scott: you try to make it harder for people to see your stuff.
Scott: the you only see what you want to see.
Scott: stuff is still the same.
Rym: So according to this article mutes seem to not interface correct like you will still see things you didn't subscribe to.
Scott: That is a separate problem because Twitter right and all these newer social networks.
Rym: also there's a limit on how many accounts you can mute.
Scott: Well that's also my block list.
Rym: before Twitter shut down the API had more than 400,000 accounts on it.
Scott: Yeah that's a. that's a problem for sure right it should be infinity in fact right.
Scott: but anyway the all of these things have their sort of algorithmic feeds YouTube's recommendations Twitter's.
Scott: you know the all any right all those sort of feeds you know.
Scott: All that shit right.
Scott: that is not just the reverse.
Scott: chronological order list of things you follow is fundamentally you are seeing things that someone else wants you to see and not something you asked for and that is the core problem.
Scott: anything like that should just get the fuck out.
Rym: YouTube go to youtube.com.
Scott: such a thing because Twitter has such a thing.
Scott: that is why mute fails.
Scott: right?
Scott: if they didn't have that mute would be perfect because that were a secondary experience.
Rym: if the default experience was here's what you subscribe to and like Twitter used to be.
Scott: And if there is some other feed of other things that I'm not following I at least have to click on it which means I have asked to see the things that I don't follow.
Scott: it should never be the default screen because then I am seeing things I do not follow without asking for it.
Scott: You can have all those things as long as they're a click away or a command away or somewhere else other than a pay a place.
Scott: you cannot avoid looking like the default homepage.
Scott: that can't be changed.
Scott: They're perfectly fine to exist but it should never be unavoidable.
Scott: it should always be.
Scott: I asked to see this.
Rym: What do you propose?
Rym: this angers capital because it does remember and I know we talk about this a lot but you really really have to understand that this is like the fundamental crisis of the entire Internet.
Rym: the whole fucking thing is propped up on advertising.
Rym: even if we ignore the fact that most of American society is propped up on advertising the Internet is like more propped up on advertising.
Rym: no fucking webs.
Rym: if there were no ads tomorrow the Internet would go back to what it was like.
Rym: Before it was commercialized there's a few hundred websites and wealthy white people have made all of them with whatever they wanted.
Rym: GeekNights would keep going.
Rym: there wouldn't be any other podcast.
Scott: Yep I mean it's like if you put up some e-commerce right on an Internet where people only saw what they asked to see.
Scott: The only way anyone to find your e-commerce is if they already knew you somehow right.
Scott: they found your business in the real world or something or you know.
Scott: it's like how right it's.
Rym: How do you and I as a case study want to find out about things we wouldn't otherwise know about?
Rym: one?
Rym: I read a bunch.
Rym: I go to specific websites that aggregate and curate news and areas I care about.
Rym: that's Paul I'm choosing.
Rym: I read The Verge because I want to know about some of the kinds of things The Verge has.
Rym: it's not perfect.
Rym: I would like a more curated feed but it's not that bad.
Rym: I used to follow a bunch of people on Twitter partly because they were the people who would tell me about things I wouldn't have thought to look for and I trust their opinion.
Rym: but again I chose.
Rym: I want to hear what Mike tool has to say because he'll tell me about an anime would have otherwise not found out about.
Scott: I listen to somebody else already follow.
Scott: For explicitly right some other source of information you do know and there is some path through that to the thing that you don't follow.
Rym: and for products you know what I do.
Rym: I don't look for products to buy unless I've decided I need to buy something to solve X problem.
Rym: and then I do research.
Scott: Yeah but the research is using a search engine and the search engine is you know.
Scott: yes you're in some sense asking but in the other sense the SEO is determining what you see and what you don't see.
Rym: Let's see I'm going to type something to YouTube right now because I'm extra annoyed about this.
Rym: let's see I'm going to type.
Rym: I don't know minotaur.
Rym: I just picked a random word.
Scott: Wikipedia page for minotaur.
Rym: So what does YouTube return?
Scott: D&D monster page for minotaur.
Rym: So YouTube returns a random curated set of videos that include the word minotaur in the title and then after one two three four five six seven eight nine ten results.
Rym: Now it says people also watched in the tiniest font and it if you scroll by it looks like it's more search results.
Rym: but it's not.
Rym: it's showing me what other people who watch some of the videos from the search.
Rym: Themselves watched not things that matched that search and then it shows me a bunch of shorts and the more I scroll down it's just a chum bucket of garbage until eventually I hit for you and you know what that's showing me?
Rym: Literally a bunch of videos I've already watched.
Rym: Fantastic.
Rym: Thank you Google for being a terrible search.
Scott: So yeah there's.
Scott: the war is again.
Scott: you only want to see what.
Scott: you want to see people what you also as a producer want people to see your shit even if they didn't ask for it.
Scott: and then vice versa you don't want to see shit people trying to push on you and alright.
Rym: So on YouTube why can't I block an account if I see an account and a video is recommended to me.
Scott: And why?
Scott: no that's not the question.
Scott: the question is why did not every single account start blocked?
Scott: everything should be blocked by default and instead you should be turning things on right not turning things off and by default.
Scott: you see the world right.
Scott: Twitter originally the original Twitter was effectively an IRC chat room.
Scott: right effectively or you could only put short messages but it IRC chat room but everyone was.
Scott: you go in the chat room and you see all the names but everyone is muted.
Scott: by default.
Scott: you don't see any chats.
Rym: And you pick the set of people you want to see and everyone picks a different set.
Scott: You unmute people right and then you see only the things they're saying and everyone else is shut the fuck up.
Rym: That was the only good thing Twitter ever did.
Rym: the first thing.
Scott: Right that was the original Twitter and that's that is the model.
Scott: that's the correct model.
Scott: the whole internet should be like that.
Scott: you only see what you want to see right.
Scott: When you go to Google you start googling and it should be like you don't see anything and then you pick domains that you want to search right.
Scott: Like.
Scott: I only want to.
Scott: you know.
Scott: right now you can do it with like the site command right like imagine if you use Google and you only had certain domains that you trusted and liked and newer bullshit and only search those domains and every other domain you never saw results from.
Scott: It's like you block.
Scott: you shouldn't be block having to block because block should be the default in terms of what you see now in terms of what you send out into the world.
Scott: right.
Scott: Me and Rym have a difference of opinion but I believe right.
Scott: if you're.
Scott: if you're choosing to send something to a private group or individual that's private messaging.
Scott: that's already right.
Scott: But if you are sending something out into the world publicly you have to just accept the fact that you have made that information public.
Scott: and it is this trying to prevent some people in the world from seeing it but having most of the world see it.
Rym: Well that's the thing.
Rym: it doesn't actually prevent people from seeing it.
Rym: it introduces friction within that platform.
Rym: and that's the value that if there is a widely used platform then introducing friction to bad actors who would try to engage with you.
Scott: I mean the bad actors shouldn't be there in the first place.
Rym: Yes but they're there and the tool was effective.
Scott: Secondly if the bad actors can't message you then you know because the other patch is correct.
Rym: It's not just that they can't message you.
Rym: I'll give you an example.
Rym: there was that the series of studies showing that individual entities on a platform like Twitter or YouTube will always randomly be selected to be extremely popular.
Rym: If you make a fake Twitter with a bunch of pseudo ML mechanisms that all randomly retweet things over time certain random messages and random accounts just become the most widely followed and widely used like that.
Rym: That happens as a consequence of the ability to be able to share and reshare content just in general.
Scott: So just don't do that.
Scott: but if everyone's blocked by default will that happen?
Rym: But if everyone's blocked by default then I can still subscribe to anyone and retweet to my people.
Rym: Reshare to my people.
Scott: Talking about retweet I think it's a design failure.
Scott: it shouldn't be so simple to retweet.
Rym: But at the same time that was the feature I used on Twitter the most.
Scott: Regardless that's a separate topic but the point is.
Rym: But I'm saying if you have a platform the friction of making it.
Rym: if I block you on a platform then it introduces friction of you not just interacting with me.
Rym: But also resharing and like interacting with my content within that platform.
Rym: meaning if you are a bad actor who wants to take the extra step to harass beyond the block.
Rym: Now you have to do things outside of what the platform directly supports which introduces the ability to have you to easily block or ban you or bring legal consequences to you or prove.
Scott: I mean they could just log out see your tweet copy it paste.
Rym: yes they can push.
Scott: that's a.
Rym: that's a far cry for most people to go through that much effort.
Rym: that's why that feature was right effective.
Scott: And I think that it's not.
Scott: I don't think that the block is the right answer.
Scott: I think the right answer is there shouldn't be such a low friction to retweet in the first place.
Scott: It should.
Scott: everyone who wants to retweet should have to explicitly when you're putting things out into the world right that the whole world is going to see.
Rym: I want everyone who follows me to see everything I say if they want which includes retweets.
Scott: If they want that's that's fine right.
Scott: but the point is is that if you are going to publish or republish something right on any platform.
Scott: That is you know and knowing that the whole world will see a public thing right.
Scott: that should never be.
Scott: it's a bad design to have that be a low friction action.
Scott: It should because you're you're doing something serious.
Scott: right you are publishing right.
Scott: publishing should always be a big action like post.
Scott: And therefore that shouldn't be so simple.
Scott: with like one click to completely take a huge thing or someone else's post and completely repost it you should have to copy it paste it look at it see where I disagree.
Rym: there is that.
Rym: Society has shown that low friction is what people want and that is what built a lot of very positive spaces and positive communities as well.
Scott: It can build.
Scott: it can go both ways.
Scott: right you know a fast road gets you where you're going faster and it also kills people right.
Rym: that's why I'm saying.
Scott: I think we would all be better off.
Scott: in general though with a slow road right you get where you're going still and less people die even though we don't have the fast trips.
Rym: But that's where I'm saying.
Rym: in a world where the reality is almost all people want the ability to have rapidly reshare and that's not going to go away.
Scott: Do they want or do they not want?
Scott: right it's like it's one of those things where it's like when people have this.
Rym: I think they want it partly because Twitter and platforms like it.
Rym: this was not a primary feature and retweets didn't even work that well and they rapidly became the most used thing without being pushed.
Scott: They were they were very used but that was first of all.
Scott: they want the people designing the system designed it to make people use that on purpose right.
Scott: And it was so.
Scott: it's like when it's there right it's like yes people ate it.
Scott: it's like yes when I put the mouse in the box with the cheese the mouse ate the cheese.
Scott: Take any group of nerds.
Rym: put them in a room with a computer and nine times out of ten they all have five YouTube videos they each want to show to everyone else there.
Rym: And there's the big fight about who puts on which video.
Rym: like every nerd group always has this exact same dynamic.
Scott: Yes people have a desire to share things.
Scott: that is without a doubt right.
Scott: Ivan I have that desire right.
Scott: what are we doing?
Scott: things of the day on here?
Scott: for no reason right.
Scott: Come on everyone has things.
Scott: when they see a cool thing you want to tell your friends about the.
Rym: I'm saying I don't think the friction is a problem.
Rym: I think that there's other societal problem but I make the lack of friction on resharing.
Scott: I think we would be better off if the re sharing action right.
Scott: if you're you know everyone everyone has a lot of sees cool things all the time that they want to share with everyone right.
Scott: If everyone just shared everything then it's like you know it's just wait it's too much it's too noisy and a lot of low quality stuff gets through.
Scott: if we added a little friction to that process on all platforms right to where it's like oh you want to share that cool YouTube video with everyone.
Scott: Then that would raise the bar a little bit raise the quality a little.
Rym: I have an alternative but complimentary argument.
Rym: that the only reason.
Rym: The bar is so low and what you call qualitatively low quality content is indeed qualitatively yes I am also similarly ice.
Rym: I have the same quality judgment.
Rym: is you like?
Rym: don't think that I'm okay.
Scott: Okay I'm just saying I'm just.
Rym: I'm noting that there's someone out there who earnestly likes that bottom tier content like there's.
Scott: yeah I mean it wouldn't be you know but that person is going to be following people.
Scott: Right who are more like them and with the higher bar are going to see more of that stuff we think is bottom tier that they love a little bit.
Scott: I'm saying the only reason.
Rym: Almost any of that low tier content exists in the first place is because of the extreme pressures of capitalism in the at all.
Scott: Could be depends on depends on which content exactly you're talking about.
Rym: All of it there are exceptions.
Rym: one exception I can think of is fascist indoctrination.
Rym: that is not directly profit motive that is evil motive.
Scott: It's true yes without the profit motive, a lot of people out there who are making content, you know, a lot of variety, the people who say like and subscribe would not be making it right unlike the GeekNights.
Scott: that makes it even if there's one listener doesn't put ads right.
Rym: I'm saying on a given week, instead of 400,000 Minecraft videos that I have a high production value and let's just say qualitatively to low quality content, there would be an order of magnitude fewer.
Rym: And if you look at the old internet before anyone even realized the internet could be commercialized every website was just kind of great and just had the content you wanted.
Scott: That is the thing is I think that without the ability to make people see your thing and to chase view counts or anything I think that is a motivator for a lot of people to post and create in the first place.
Scott: I think the primary motivator.
Scott: It is the primary motivator for that kind of person.
Rym: But I think that is only the primary motivator for so many people because that is capitalism.
Rym: like everyone's got their hustle.
Scott: Capitalism is a part of it but there are some people who just want to be famous regardless of the money.
Scott: If we took that away a lot of people would simply stop creating, stop sharing.
Scott: The only people who would create and share were the people who are doing it like we are because for other reasons.
Scott: And I think that would be a better internet but it would be a quieter internet but it would be a safer internet I think.
Rym: It absolutely would and we have to solve this real quick as a society and culture because large language models are going to generate a literal infinite sea of garbage content.
Rym: And that is why you will never be able to find anything good again in that sea.
Rym: It is going to be like the cork foam that I just learned about from one of those Arvin Ash videos.
Scott: So we agree that blocking what's coming in, you should only see what you want to see.
Scott: And we disagree what's going out.
Scott: I think if you're willing to send something out that there should be a little bit of friction ideally because it's not a small action that you're taking.
Scott: It's a serious action, you should think about it for at least a second.
Scott: And also that you have to accept the fact that you're putting it out into the whole world, Nazis are going to see it.
Scott: Even though if we at least get the first part right you won't ever hear the Nazis coming back to you and you disagree.
Rym: Here's an idea there, a specific one.
Rym: Let's say we solve the depredations of capitalism problem so now it's more Nazis versus literally everyone else in terms of posting.
Rym: Which wouldn't be that far off from that when we get to that point.
Rym: So say we're in that environment, then arguably blocking features within platforms for the publishing if the barrier to resharing is low.
Rym: And the barrier to resharing being low would likely plausibly be a benefit to society because we've removed all this low tier content that was being generated by capitalism.
Rym: Then, now already I realize I have so many caveats that this is such a narrow point.
Rym: Then the blocking features are a very specific ratchet style tool.
Rym: They, in aggregate, decrease the friction of people interacting with my content by default, but increase the friction of people I don't want to interact with my content.
Rym: But it's not necessarily blocking more, it's almost like limiting, it's not muting either.
Rym: It basically means everyone can reshare my content, but specific motherfuckers who have crossed me in some way have more friction to do the same.
Rym: And in a large long term system, that would lead to, over time, what I see as bad or what society sees as bad actors being more limited.
Rym: But, to your point, that isn't really blocking as it is used today by most people.
Scott: If we get the first part right, where you only see what you want to see, then it's like, no matter how much Nazis reshare amongst themselves my anti-Nazi screed, I'll never hear from them, you'll never hear from them, we'll never know that that's going on, and they will be cut off from society because no one will see their Nazi conversation other than themselves.
Scott: They'll be in their own little bubble, which is effectively what they are anyway.
Rym: So do we just have another episode of GeekNights where the moral of how to solve a problem is we have to destroy capitalism?
Scott: I mean, we already know that, but the point is, we disagree on the "block what you post" part, we agree on the "block what you're reading" part, and I'm, you know, working on building exactly something, right?
Scott: I'm basically being an activity pub server that follows the philosophy that I've just espoused, right, where when you post something, it's out to the world to deal with it, but the only things you ever see are the things you ask to see and nothing else, the end.
Scott: And we'll see if that actually works or not.
Rym: And in the interim, like, if you're using Twitter and these block features go away...
Scott: Twitter is done, I think.
Rym: But if you're still using it, be ready for the fact that if blocking goes away, because that platform is designed the way it is, it could become specifically more dangerous to you, especially if you are a group, like, typically targeted.
Scott: Well, I think because the information I didn't know of the mute being limited, right?
Scott: You could eventually, you could basically run into a situation where, you know, you've muted all the bad people and then there's more mad people and you can't mute them, and now the bad people can tweet at you and you're gonna see it, you're gonna see something you didn't ask to see, and now it's unsafe.
Rym: So funnily enough, before I got rid of my Twitter account...
Scott: It's unusable.
Rym: You know what terms I had muted?
Rym: Patreon.
Rym: That's it, that's the only term I had muted.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the GeekNights Patreon patrons for this episode are... I assume to get access to that sweet Patreon-exclusive RSS feed.
Rym: That is the same as our feed, but it works within Patreon.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: See you at PAX.
Rym: Definitely not do another show this week.
Rym: We'll probably do one show next week.
Rym: And I leave you tonight only with...
Media: The Soviet Union.
Media: I thought you guys broke up.
Media: Yes, that's what we wanted you to think.
Media: [Laughing].
Media: [Singing] Must crush capitalism!
Media: [Growling].