Rym: It's Wednesday, November 8th, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Emily: I'm Emily.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are going to review Star Trek Lower Decks.
Rym: So yeah, a bunch of things kind of came together in terms of Emily and I both just really diving into Star Trek or back into Star Trek as it were.
Emily: Yeah, it was basically kind of a pandemic thing for us and I forget kind of how it started.
Emily: I mean, you were watching Netflix.
Rym: Netflix had all the old Star Treks and I rewatched some choice TNG episodes.
Emily: You were watching Voyager.
Emily: I remember because that was like we.
Emily: we were cooped up inside during the pandemic.
Emily: We have an exercise bike.
Emily: So it's like we.
Emily: we talk about our bike shows, which are typically shows we don't pay a lot of attention to.
Emily: We've maybe seen before or they're like kind of low concentration type of shows.
Emily: And we watch them while we're on the exercise bike.
Emily: And I want to say you were watching through Voyager and I'd come out tapa tapa tapa to watch like choice episodes with you.
Emily: But I didn't like super.
Emily: follow it.
Emily: But it was around when you were watching DS9.
Emily: You're like.
Emily: you started watching DS9 and then I was like, I want to watch DS9 too.
Rym: Because DS9 was the one that I had not seen all of it.
Rym: now that we watched it all.
Rym: And this isn't about DS9.
Rym: It's the animation day.
Rym: But I had only actually seen episodes from like the last couple of seasons of DS9 before.
Rym: So I hadn't seen most of that beginning stuff.
Emily: You were like, I remember that it's the Star Trek that came on after TNG.
Emily: And I was always sleepy during it.
Emily: So I'd fall asleep.
Emily: But I remember that there was a war.
Emily: And it was like the war of Star Trek.
Rym: And there were a bunch of Cardassians, but I couldn't quite tell them all apart.
Rym: And there was flaky people with problems.
Emily: The flaky guy, flaky Odo.
Rym: But even then, Weyoun was an absolute treasure.
Emily: Well, by treasure, you mean squish this like a bug.
Rym: Squish that like a bug.
Rym: Among all that backdrop, like Paramount happened and everything.
Rym: And Star Trek got its discovery reboot a while back that at least the first time I tried to watch that, I bounced off of.
Rym: But when Lower Decks came out in 2020, so in the pandemic when we were home with a lot of free time.
Rym: I feel like it wasn't just us, but a lot of people either got into Star Trek for the first time because of Lower Decks.
Rym: Or got back into Star Trek because of Lower Decks.
Rym: Because it was kind of like this breath of fresh air on what I like about Star Trek.
Emily: So it's kind of funny because I want to say Lower Decks really kicked off that pandemic Star Trek revisiting.
Emily: Because we watched both the new Trek and like the whole thing with Discovery and everything.
Emily: But we really started to more do the 90s Trek and that was because of Lower Decks.
Emily: And the great thing about Lower Decks is I started to watch it when I was way less familiar with a lot of the references it made.
Emily: It's very dense with inside jokes.
Emily: But fortunately it's also fine to show somebody who's kind of new to Star Trek.
Emily: Because you don't really need to get these references in order to like enjoy what it has to say in terms of like the plot of the episode.
Rym: They're almost more like Easter eggs like if you know.
Emily: If you know you know.
Emily: But that's the thing it's like.
Emily: so watching the first season and the second season.
Emily: Before I really got caught up before I watched all of DS9.
Emily: And you know I'd watched a lot of TOS and a bunch of episodes of The Next Generation.
Emily: But I hadn't seen any of Voyager or DS9.
Emily: So it's like there were a lot of things that kind of flew over my head.
Emily: And then coming back and watching some of those episodes is really really funny.
Emily: Because you get all these like just little asides that you never get before.
Emily: So it is incredibly good for fanboys and girls.
Emily: But it's also you don't have to be a superfan in order to get what it's doing.
Rym: Yup and I guess unlike because I like TNG it was a good show.
Rym: But first couple of seasons were pretty rocky and the episodes are pretty hit or miss.
Rym: But also because of the old style of TV a lot of old Star Treks are a little bit plodding.
Rym: Like they're kind of slow.
Rym: The writing is very 90s.
Rym: Interesting plot threads or ideas kind of get dropped.
Rym: You know Star Trek just was a product of its time.
Rym: And Lower Decks is very much a modern television show and a modern cartoon.
Emily: I would definitely say that it.
Emily: you know this might almost be a criticism of it.
Emily: But it definitely has that animation pacing.
Emily: Where it has incredibly fast dialogue.
Emily: It's very rapid fire.
Emily: There's like things are jumping around pretty pretty quickly.
Emily: There you know with animation often you're not going to.
Emily: you know on the script stage.
Emily: When you're editing the scripts you're not going to want to keep in extraneous material.
Emily: Because it costs so much per minute per second of animation.
Emily: That you're kind of like.
Emily: okay how can we really condense this to be very tight.
Emily: And like you know what was the thing with Conan O'Brien was writing for the Simpsons.
Emily: Yeah they had like a metric per minute about gags per minute.
Emily: And like how you know and because this really is a comedy.
Emily: Although it does have the occasional poignant moment.
Emily: It's definitely you know comedy animation.
Emily: So it's very dense with those like hitting them with the laughs kind of moments.
Emily: And so it's it's kind of frenetic.
Emily: I showed it to my parents and they really liked it.
Emily: But like my mom said wow everybody talks really fast.
Rym: Well compare that to like TNG where not only did it have a lot of just atmospheric shots.
Rym: And like long panning shots of nothing with just like light music in the background.
Rym: But it was partly because they were padding out for TV and ads and that long time slot that it would be in.
Emily: Yeah definitely this does not have that kind of buffer.
Emily: It's just a 23 minute kind of regular TV animation length.
Emily: They even kind of lampshade the whole.
Emily: you know they talk really fast and everybody is really high energy.
Emily: And there's a crossover episode in the recent season where it was Strange New Worlds.
Rym: That episode is one of the better episodes of Star Trek as a whole that is out there.
Emily: And it's very funny because it's like you look at the voice actors during interviews and stuff.
Emily: And by the way the voice acting is great.
Emily: Tawny Newsome I think is her name the one who who is the voice for Mariner.
Emily: But she's really really funny.
Emily: But they don't really look like their characters.
Emily: But they look like their characters enough to be believable.
Emily: Like if you put them in the costume and they really when they're in live action.
Emily: You know the two of them kind of sell that they are the live action version of their animated characters.
Rym: That fast paced level of.
Rym: I am a cartoon band.
Emily: Yes so they're very like expressive and like I just remember the one where Boimler is walking down the hall.
Emily: And he's just like really awkward and he does this really funny wobbly kind of walk.
Emily: And it was just like hysterical because it was such the same kind of movement that his animated version would be doing.
Emily: So I think that was an interesting thing to see how that kind of style of delivery.
Emily: And those kind of characters and the voice actors themselves translated over into the live action Star Trek universe.
Rym: Yeah it also comes around the same time where we've got Strange New Worlds and we've got Lower Decks.
Rym: And they both are very much a little bit of a breath of fresh air into making Star Trek.
Rym: I don't want to say like fun or more fun than it used to be.
Rym: But more like the Star Trek universe has expanded to cover a lot of different styles and a lot of different types of stories.
Rym: But it moved back to this very episodic closed story which was the opposite of what DS9 edged into and then Discovery just embraced wholly.
Emily: Yeah but the nice thing is it keeps the Star Trek thing even though it's episodic.
Emily: it does have seasonal arcs.
Emily: And it does have character development which is important I think in that like it's not everything resets every episode.
Emily: There are aspects of the characters where they're kind of learning from their mistakes and maturing.
Emily: Because it's interesting because they're all like what in their 20s.
Emily: They're definitely post college even though it feels more like especially in the early seasons.
Rym: They're relatively fresh out of the academy.
Rym: They're incense now.
Rym: They've got their first assignments.
Rym: What was the pitch to make the show.
Rym: when McMahon first proposed it was, I'm quoting here, "The people who put the yellow cartridge in the food replicator so a banana can come out of the other
Rym: end.".
Rym: I want a show about that.
Emily: And that's something that I always wanted more from.
Emily: like science fiction and superhero shows and like all the fantastical kind of stuff that happens.
Emily: The interesting thing is at its core like Star Trek is kind of a naval story as well as like you know exploration and daring do especially like the early shows.
Emily: But there is a military aspect of it even though it's like peaceful military usually.
Rym: Well there's always that divide of Star Trek.
Rym: either has the ships are out there doing exploration but they run into dangerous situations.
Rym: They have to be able to deal with them but separately.
Rym: the universe is dangerous and occasionally like the Klingons try to kill them and the Dominion War happens.
Emily: And there's a lot of diplomatic stuff that's happening.
Emily: but really it's kind of like watching the grunts on a navy ship or something like that.
Emily: But a very nice navy ship where like you know extrapolated into the future where it's not as like you know dehumanizing and stuff like that.
Emily: So it's basically like lower deckers.
Emily: They're kind of like in a college dorm situation where everybody's got bunk beds and they're all trying to figure out when their shifts are.
Rym: And the senior officers never tell them anything about what the hell's going on.
Emily: They're always like since they're their lower ranks they're always kind of left in the dark or about the higher level logistics of various conflicts and stuff like that.
Emily: So I really like that vibe.
Emily: I'm very much a fan of like you know college stories or you know also it brings in a little like I said a little bit of military story where you've got like a band of people in the same unit who are like trying to make things work.
Rym: That has also been a hallmark of most Star Treks.
Rym: Like think about both Next Generation and DS9.
Rym: All you know the Star Trek plot is happening in the background or whatever nonsense is going on.
Rym: But a lot of the screen time in both of those shows except when they're in the middle of a two-parter or like an arc is like Diana Troy's got some personal business going on.
Rym: Or like Worf and Geordi are beefing about something and it's more about the people and their relationships in the context of a science fiction future than it is about the story itself.
Emily: Honestly Star Trek.
Emily: you know the technical science part of it is often just like made up word salad.
Rym: Something something metreon particles.
Rym: Emily's submitting metreon particles.
Rym: Watch out.
Emily: But it's definitely like you know they've got this techno babble.
Emily: But really when it starts Star Trek at its best is about culture clashes.
Emily: It's about like diplomatic relations between various various planets and various cultures.
Emily: And it's about human and humanoid relationships like you know a Vulcan and a human coming from very different viewpoints but managing to make it work.
Emily: And those kind of you know.
Emily: it takes the relationship between humans and then adds another dimension because they're not all humans.
Emily: And I think that you know that's part of what the multiculturalism of Star Trek is when it's at its best.
Rym: Hey we had a quote here.
Rym: so Mike McMahon one of the executive producers who developed the show had said that they were inspired specifically by the next generation.
Rym: And Kurtzman there's this whole interview you can read where they basically said a story in a typical Star Trek episode would take place in the background of a Lower Decks episode.
Rym: So quote huge crazy crazy shit is going on in the background and that's super peripheral to the story you're actually focusing on.
Emily: I mean often they will intersect like there will be something that you know puts the ship in danger.
Emily: But then the main characters of Lower Decks have to be like oh I'm stuck in a Jefferies tube trying to figure out this engineering thing.
Emily: It's not like oh if I fail then everything is lost.
Emily: It's more like we all have a part to play and we all have to work together otherwise we'll be in danger.
Emily: And so it's kind of like it's not just the decisions of the captain that affect the outcomes of these perilous adventures that Star Trek ships go on.
Rym: Now what's cool too is the show echoes.
Rym: it brings a bunch of things from the old Star Trek animated series which probably isn't worth watching.
Rym: But they basically because it's animated they bring in a lot of the non-human characters that were hard to do with costumes or had never been done with costumes before because it would be too annoying.
Emily: Or Dr.
Emily: Miglimo.
Emily: So like you can get these anthropomorphic characters which would be a pretty big I mean in modern Trek they do have a lot of good prosthetics.
Emily: They have really a lot more they can do with computer animation.
Emily: but it's like okay it costs a lot to do live-action tracking of like you know an alien face.
Emily: Whereas in Lower Decks you've got like a cat person who fully emotes and like is jumping off the walls and like using the big security officer as like a climbing post and stuff like that.
Emily: Oh man it's so funny because she's so angry horny all the time.
Emily: She's like this really badass surgeon who's like very very foul-mouthed but like you know they put a lot of like cat mannerisms.
Rym: I mean having sexy crime play with the safeties off in the holodeck.
Rym: She's like I want to go rob a bank in the holodeck.
Emily: That's my idea of a hot date.
Rym: But also this is the first Star Trek I think I'd ever seen where it acted like the rest of Star Trek had happened.
Rym: Like the thing that always bothered me about later episodes of TNG and a lot of Deep Space Nine is like crazy stuff would happen.
Rym: And either people wouldn't acknowledge how significant those ramifications are and they'd just be forgotten in the next episode and never brought up again.
Rym: Or like oh a mirror universe and no one can figure it out.
Rym: Lower Decks is the show where like the mirror universe is literally in their training because they know it exists.
Emily: Oh this is obviously a mirror universe simulation.
Emily: so I'm gonna pretend to be super evil and horny.
Emily: And that's the interesting thing too.
Rym: The mirror universe canonically is stupid, evil, and horny.
Emily: It's like why like bisexuality should not be confined to this like the evil universe.
Rym: My theory is that the mirror universe is not a universe.
Rym: It is just.
Rym: in any given place there is like this mirror echo of the worst possible outcomes and the horniest, angriest nonsense everywhere.
Rym: It's like everyone's base urges but it's not a parallel dimension.
Rym: that's always happening.
Rym: Because every Star Trek that portrays it, it's always weird.
Rym: You know it's a TV show.
Rym: so of course we know why it's this way but it's always weirdly on the nose.
Rym: Like how come in the mirror universe?
Rym: literally every person who is on Deep Space Nine is the same as the people who are on Deep Space Nine in the non-mirror universe.
Rym: Even though there was a... You'd think in the horny angry universe at least one of them would have gotten shot.
Emily: Well cause there's like hundreds of years of lead up to that same evil empire.
Emily: Anyway the mirror universe is inconsistent and it's foolish.
Rym: Or it's hyper consistent.
Rym: It's just angry and horny and stupid.
Emily: I like your idea that it's like dark echoes of people like everyone will see kind of like the mirror in the snow queen where it shows humanity.
Emily: Like it reflects back like the worst stuff of humanity and like if you look in the mirror you just see your ugliness.
Emily: And that's kind of like the whole thing with the snow queen.
Emily: It's like I like the idea that it is a dark mirror and that's all it is and it will just reflect back whatever is going on at any given point in time.
Rym: Really it's just that the show like all this like in a TNG episode something crazy would happen and someone gets turned into the equivalent of a doll and that's like the whole plot.
Rym: That just happens in the background of episodes of Lower Dice.
Emily: I am not a puppet.
Emily: Do not play with me.
Emily: Or like.
Emily: I forget the name of his culture but the guy who always speaks in metaphors is like Shaco in the Wall.
Emily: So I think when I say the show is very meta yes it's got a lot of inside jokes but a big part of it is the characters are aware of Star Trek stuff.
Emily: You know like they're not aware that they're in a TV show.
Emily: It's not that kind of meta where they're like breaking the fourth wall.
Emily: But they are very vers- it's almost like they've read Memory Alpha and they're like okay I know the deal with this.
Emily: But think about it.
Rym: Wouldn't that make sense?
Rym: Like if you were in Starfleet- You read Wikipedia about what's been going on.
Rym: Boimler is kind of a fanboy about the Borg in the same way that in the real world.
Rym: Like I read a lot about NATO military equipment because I just find it interesting.
Emily: Oh yeah I know this weird esoteric cold war history stuff and it's like that's how people are when they join Starfleet.
Emily: And it would make a lot more sense where it's not just like.
Emily: I have never heard of this or I've heard of this only in like whispers kind of way.
Emily: It's definitely like everybody acts like not only do the plot points happen, they also bring in characters.
Emily: And so you have a lot of chance for little like Quark.
Emily: I think still my favorite favorite episode was the DS9 episode.
Rym: Having Cura and Quark's real voice actors play the characters.
Rym: And also you know we had just watched DS9 and a lot of deep nostalgia for that show again.
Emily: But there was like the Voyager episode where they go on to Voyager and they're like preparing it for like a museum piece and stuff like that.
Emily: And so there's a lot of times where having that knowledge will kind of help make it funny.
Rym: But I mean in that episode a Tuvix situation happens.
Rym: If you haven't seen Voyager like don't worry about it.
Rym: But a thing happens and there's a meme you can find if you look up Tuvix.
Rym: What would Janeway do?
Rym: Murder Tuvix.
Emily: And Rym says this.
Rym: So in this episode a Tuvix situation happens and they send the person it happened to to their room while they sort it out.
Rym: And they're like we should figure out.
Rym: Janeway dealt with the situation.
Rym: And I say out loud Janeway would fucking kill him.
Rym: Not even think about it.
Rym: And then it cuts to a character.
Emily: The character says pretty much that verbatim.
Rym: Janeway fucking killed him.
Rym: Because it's like in this in the Federation wiki like anyone can look it up and everyone on the ship looks it up right away.
Emily: That's the other thing I like about the script of this.
Emily: It is interesting because when it first came out like four years ago ish people were kind of ripping on it that it was a ripoff of Rick and Morty.
Emily: And that same as final space.
Emily: it's like final space and Rick and Morty and Lower Decks.
Emily: They're all like oh they're part of that same kind of adult animation and they're all trying to capitalize on the popularity of Rick and Morty.
Emily: But I definitely think that Lower Decks even though it might come visually from a little bit of that same.
Rym: Well and Mike McBahn is like he was the head writer for Rick and Morty when they brought him on board.
Rym: But from the beginning he everyone is very clear.
Rym: this is not Rick and Morty in a world of Star Trek.
Rym: This is its own show about Star Trek.
Rym: There's some interview where he's like.
Rym: you know writers can write different kinds of things guys.
Emily: And I think a big thing even though it has a lot.
Emily: You know it's definitely more foul mouth than your typical Star Trek which is very interesting because they bleep it out.
Emily: But like for example the cat doctor she's very like.
Emily: you know fuck this fuck that just swearing constantly.
Emily: But it's like bleepity.
Emily: bleep bleep bleep bleep.
Emily: Where's my fucking tricorder?
Rym: Reicher would have said a lot of swear words.
Rym: It wasn't 90s American television that his character was portrayed.
Emily: Yes, and it it feels a lot of times like the characters they take what?
Emily: the character should be saying in an average next-generation episode and they like Say it how a millennial will say.
Emily: Yeah, very, you know, just be like, oh my this guy sucks Don't listen to him, you know, it was just very like.
Emily: I don't know.
Emily: it's.
Emily: it's not as It's stylized in a different way because it's silly 90s stuff.
Rym: It's not our Trek.
Rym: Yeah, but it's a different era of story.
Rym: I mean every Star Trek set in a different time for a reason Yeah, and thus this one is set like later in the Star Trek timeline.
Rym: So all the other Star Trek's except parts of discovery already happened.
Emily: Yeah, and I think you know, I like new Trek.
Emily: I didn't really enjoy stranger worlds I enjoyed discovery.
Rym: discovery grew on me after they got past the bad Klingons.
Emily: Yeah The.
Emily: the first season I just was not into.
Emily: I had a lot of thoughts about Klingons and I know that's what the bad fanboys say.
Emily: so I felt really guilty being like.
Emily: I hate what they did to the Klingons, but like Yeah, I like Klingons when they're kind of more like funny stabby dwarf guys you know, like they're they're singing and they're drinking their blood wine and there's stabby like.
Emily: they're very like barbar bar bar bar Whereas like I don't want to watch Klingons for court intrigue unless it's the same kind of court entry that quark got involved in.
Rym: Then it's cool The Gauran Martok era.
Rym: Yeah.
Emily: Yeah.
Emily: Yeah, like I like that kind of Klingon drama like the 90s Klingon drama.
Emily: I'm like all here for but like I don't know.
Emily: Anyway, one of the things that new Trek I wasn't Sold on until strange new worlds is I didn't find it as funny because TOS is really if you ever watch original Star Trek, it is often just Intentionally really funny.
Rym: Yeah, and TNG was only occasionally funny Like it often got a little caught up in Picard is acting.
Emily: Yeah, I I found that's the other thing about DS9 was really funny could be incredibly cheesy.
Emily: It could be very overwrought like sometimes there were episodes that were incredibly cringe-inducing Quark just being a little shit all the time.
Emily: I love the little gremlins.
Emily: Some of my friends just hate the little gremlins, but I I cannot deny I love the little gremlins.
Rym: Curator is yelling Clark's name in the particular way She would do it which she did when she voice acted in Laura Dax playing her own character.
Rym: That is let lives rent-free in my head quark.
Emily: The best part of that though is not just her yelling at him, but quark scream His little girly scream like it's not it's not a deep space 9 Ferengi including episode without a little like a feminist scream of pain or surprise Anger or whatever.
Rym: quark is currently expressing um a thing that the show is doing that lower decks is doing.
Rym: that I think is very cool that other Star Trek's have always Shied away from.
Rym: it's actually sneaking in a lot of low-key world-building around just the Star Trek universe Yeah And exploring things that haven't been explored too much in other ones.
Rym: because you got to remember even though it's a cartoon Lord X is you know not to get into the hole.
Rym: It is canonical like the Cerritos is as Quote real in the Star Trek universe as the Enterprise.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And it is just still nuts to me to think that this is Expanding the Star Trek universe because I think it's doing a really good job.
Emily: Yeah Well, it's not done anything.
Emily: that super is upsetting and breaks Canon in like a really hard way to write Orion's pretty compelling instead of just green tit.
Emily: ladies I I really like The way they're doing the stuff with the Orion's cuz that you know That was another part of that ds9 episode was tendy Being from an Orion crime family.
Emily: She's kind of ashamed of it and she's very much like the Person who?
Emily: emigrates and then is really trying to downplay their heritage because they're kind of embarrassed about the stereotypes that other people hold about Orion's and So she's basically like oh, yeah space pirates.
Emily: Oh wouldn't know anything about that.
Emily: But then it when it comes up It's actually really really cool because it's like she knows her stuff and as the show goes on she becomes more comfortable With her, you know kind of using those two aspects of herself.
Emily: well, we'll see there's.
Emily: there's been a big plot about what's going on with tendy, but I think Like I was gonna say I think one of the main things to recommend the show is its humor.
Rym: Another thing is it's is its references Yeah, and it it makes light of some Star Trek tropes But it never.
Rym: it never makes fun of them in a way that it's not cynical.
Rym: It's not like a Star Trek used the same cave set over and over again.
Rym: It isn't that stupid.
Rym: it's not a cinema sins type of situation, but there is an episode where they're stuck in a cave and Because Star Trek is the way it is Things happen in caves all the time like the same cave is used.
Rym: in how many ds9 episodes?
Rym: Yes, and they said one of the episodes Lord X in that same fucking cave.
Emily: I think I think that's a really good way to put it though Is it you don't feel like if you're a Star Trek fan at least I don't feel like It's making fun of Star Trek fandom, but it's like poking fun at it in the way.
Emily: Somebody who likes something pokes fun at you know Like somebody who likes anime but makes a joke about anime that people who really enjoy anime will definitely like mmm, they'll relate to it's.
Emily: it's more that it's.
Emily: It's something that you're like, oh so true as opposed to oh, man They're.
Emily: they're saying it's cheesy and bad and that we should be ashamed of liking it kind of thing.
Emily: So I definitely think also just the way it treats its characters like it does often put them through the ringer in ways that you know be like We're going to test their their metal by you know providing conflict.
Emily: but it's also you never feel like the bad stuff that happens to the characters is gratuitous.
Rym: or I mean I got invested in their careers like more so than I have with other Star Treks because every other Star Trek It's all captains and senior officers.
Emily: Like it's the typical movie TV type thing and this is just some ensigns Yeah, but like you see them Like I said, there was a gradual maturing like Boimler used to be a lot more afraid of things and he's been more capable of taking command in later seasons.
Emily: and bold Boimler You've got a Mariner dealing with some of her PTSD from the Dominion war.
Rym: Yeah, I called that because they'd call that the show as soon as it was clear that she knew Worf and said like she'd met Worf on DS9.
Rym: Yeah like the show for being an animated cartoon.
Rym: that's kind of making fun of Star Trek.
Rym: it also it Weaves itself very very tightly into the Star Trek Cannon.
Rym: like if a date is dropped or some piece of information is revealed It will line up directly to the previous scripts of other Star Treks.
Rym: So it based on what Mariner said you can know for a fact She must have been on DS9 during the Dominion war and that is the plot of season 4 is what happened to her And why is she the way she is?
Emily: also, we've got you know, a Canonical pansexual character outside of the mirror universe Even though her last relationship with the with the preppy At least wrote that relationship.
Rym: But it wasn't intended to continue but the fans liked it so much and it fit so they wrote it in.
Rym: she had a short relationship that was.
Emily: that was good because it was kind of like The kind of thing that they did to throw the shippers a bone because they were like, oh, yeah, that would be fine.
Emily: but then when they broke up a lot of my Friends who like sapphic characters they got really sad about it.
Emily: It was like I was like, I warned you that they said in an interview.
Emily: It's probably not gonna be a long-term thing so it's That that was hard on some people because they really really shipped it.
Emily: but then you know.
Rym: So it goes now a cool thing if you did if you like.
Rym: if you've never seen any Star Trek I feel like this show like the first episode of the show would actually be a good first Star Trek to watch.
Rym: That are the first episode of strange new worlds.
Rym: I think those are the two worlds.
Rym: Probably I might recommend more because it has strange new worlds is a hell of a first episode.
Emily: Well, it's more about the idea of first contact and it brings in a lot of like I was saying the the culture clash or the idea of alien civilizations talking to each other and the meaning of that.
Rym: whereas course the first episode of lower decks is literally called second contact and it introduces like hey Star Trek though prime directive like making contact.
Rym: Well, we're the ship that shows up like the next day.
Emily: So all the actual stuff watch strange new worlds first episode and then you can watch.
Emily: And so now you know what Prime prime directive and first contact means and then you watch what happens with second contact.
Emily: It's basically the follow-through and the cleaning up of messes
Rym: and if you want to see Where this show really came from like the core inspiration for it If you didn't know there is an episode of the next generation called lower decks That was low-key the inspiration for lower decks as a show.
Rym: Yeah It was one of those high concept episodes where it wasn't about Picard and Worf and Geordi and all those characters.
Rym: It was basically just about these ensigns Very similar to what lower decks is as a show and you see everything from their perspective.
Rym: and it was.
Rym: it's widely regarded as one Of the best written and best performed episodes of TNG.
Rym: It's season 7 episode 15.
Rym: It's just called lower decks and the latest episode of lower decks Directly calls back to this and another TNG episode in a really really fun way that I did not expect.
Emily: Yeah, but you know, it isn't a comedy episode.
Emily: It's actually pretty Sad, you know in it, but it's also acknowledging that it's not just about the captains.
Emily: There are real people who are involved in all of these various dramatic Conflicts that happen over the course of Picard's tenure as captain of the Enterprise.
Rym: So but a minor thing.
Rym: I like that this show does is you see there's a lot of background.
Rym: I guess species culture development like the Gorn are one example.
Rym: But there's others where there are antagonistic fucked-up aliens and a bunch of Star Trek's that don't get explored too much in later Star Trek's or are kind of just left as largely faceless problematic villains and like lower decks has definitely Encouraged this idea that if you fast-forward into the future Every alien race the Federation has run into no matter how much of a problem they were Start to calm down and become like slowly become relatively Like.
Rym: okay with the Federation like you've got a Gorn just running his little chicken stand mister.
Emily: What was it?
Emily: Mr.
Emily: Krabby legs not Krabby legs, but it was it wasn't.
Emily: that was an inside joke, too.
Emily: It's like mr.
Emily: Krabby legger.
Emily: And anyway, I don't know how you get from the strange new world Gorn to Gorn wedding.
Emily: Like how does the Gorn wedding?
Emily: Yeah, how does how does that evolution come?
Emily: That will be a really interesting cuz they're both.
Rym: So someone read it pointed out It's it's been about a hundred and twenty years between the Gorn of TOS strange new world and and I haven't having a little little street food stand on Servant.
Rym: so I explained my mother bird wasn't eaten alive with eggs pushed into his body and instead was just nibbled a bit and somehow escape.
Emily: Well, he was a wedding crasher.
Emily: So, you know if somebody comes down in the spaceship and crashes your wedding you're you're perfectly within your rights to bite them.
Emily: So it's very funny.
Emily: It has a lot of cameos.
Emily: Um, I keep saying it's funny But obviously it's a comedy animation.
Emily: What do you think about the art of it?
Emily: So that's the last like.
Rym: Unlike a lot of other like, you know, if we talk about that style of like primetime American 23-minute animation it has really detailed backgrounds really good action sequences like the the.
Rym: the setting and this like the backgrounds and the sound design of the spaces is Very Star Trek, but they're using the animation.
Rym: I like that a lot.
Rym: the characters also are a little cartoony and smeary in a really fun way.
Emily: So my take on it is it's really grown on me.
Emily: for starters I did not care for the character designs when I first saw it because I thought they were really generic like.
Emily: it's definitely American animation looking and I tend to like, you know, either the voice acting is what brings these characters to life.
Emily: But really I think you know, once you get a moving when they're just standing still It's kind of like a super generic, but they manage because they have a fairly high budget to have pretty funny Expressive Just movement and like the facial acting and stuff is pretty good.
Emily: I still think that scene where in the first episode it's like the first scene of the first episode where Mariner
Rym: actually
Emily: Yes, she accidentally chops boiler in the leg with a bat less and he's severely injured and has to go to the med
Rym: That scene at any frame it is hilarious funny
Emily: because it's
Rym: like you
Emily: see
Rym: Mariner
Emily: her face goes through all these evolutions and smears and It's definitely like the animators knew what they were doing in terms of even though it goes really fast she's just like moving in this really Exaggerated way and I think that's something even though sometimes, you know They'll skimp a little in certain scenes and it will be more like talking heads limited animation.
Emily: There are scenes where they really?
Emily: Use the animation to our cartoony satisfying effect.
Emily: so Yeah, I guess That's something that You can also show It is fairly violent, you know.
Emily: It's not violent to the point where I think people would get too freaked out by it.
Emily: and like most the time when there's violence It's violence like somebody gets chopped in the leg and you see you like gristle and bone and stuff.
Emily: But you know, they're just gonna go immediately and get healed.
Emily: So it's not like, you know, it's like you're not gonna die of what was it?
Emily: You're not gonna die of a spear wound on a starship.
Rym: And that's kind of.
Emily: most of the violence falls under that, you know.
Emily: But I'm curious to see where it goes.
Emily: There are sometimes there's.
Emily: there are more Serious business high-intensity plots and well like starting to like Star Trek.
Rym: all there's old Star Trek.
Rym: It just stays episodic to a point in terms of the plot even though the characters keep evolving which all the old Star Treks did.
Rym: but it'll occasionally do what TNG would do at the end of a season what ds9 would do during critical moments of Previously on Star Trek lower decks a double episode and now the conclusion.
Emily: Yep, they do double episodes and like I said, they they will have running Plot points, but you could really pick up any episode and as long as you've seen Star Trek and you have a general idea of like like.
Emily: they transport, you know, they have transporters They have phasers, you know, they.
Emily: they do this and do that.
Emily: if you have those basics down you won't be confused You'll just be like, okay.
Emily: This is what's happening.
Emily: Yeah, you know so cool, um, I Really recommend the show.
Emily: I'm curious to see it where it goes I think as a final thoughts like I said it being kind of like a military college dorm kind of show at least to begin with.
Emily: I Think the best thing about it is they don't try to pair everybody up.
Rym: It's basically like oh, yeah characters May not be romantically involved, but they're like, there's just a lot of friends who are not going to fuck each other in this show.
Emily: Yeah and I think one of the even if they did end up like hooking up or something you'd feel like.
Emily: the Aspect of the relationship that is important to the show is friendship.
Emily: It's all about like these ties where platonic friend relationships are Incredibly important life relationships and can change people and help them grow.
Rym: I'd say there's one that's really affirming one very specific thing.
Rym: This has sort of now canonized in Star Trek is If you look at old Star Trek's.
Rym: you've got the captain's like Kirk and Picard.
Rym: who?
Rym: Break the rules and ignore the admiral's order to do a thing and that scene is very like roguish and like that's part of the Plots of Star Trek's.
Rym: like those are the interesting things.
Rym: the captain who broke the rule TNG Didn't really explore that much further and ds9 had its own thing going on.
Rym: Lower Decks has really brought back the idea that that happens all the time and that Unlike say the US Navy or a modern Navy where it is purely top-down It really implies the Federation does go both ways because captains in Lower Decks also violate the rules all the time.
Rym: people disobey orders when they have a good reason to constantly and if it all works out It seems like the Federation sort of recalibrates around that and like that's an expected part of that kind of organization in the future.
Emily: well Just the leeway to make your decisions and a lot of times captains are put in these positions where they may have to You know disobey a rule or an order or something like that.
Rym: But strange new worlds though at the same time also canonize this idea by bringing in like Old characters Kirk that was the maverick Or like I used to see you're stealing a starship.
Rym: I'll help.
Emily: yeah, it feels very like.
Emily: this is part of why the Federation works is because It's not authoritarian to the point where captains can't Make informed choices.
Emily: Yes And sometimes those choices are bad and they have to deal with the consequence.
Emily: I I gotta say Picard was hit or miss.
Emily: for me.
Emily: There were a lot of times in Picard where who was the cranky captain?
Emily: where he was just like fuck.
Emily: No Oh Shaw Exactly where he just calls them on their bullshit.
Emily: He's just like.
Emily: so I already called Starfleet.
Emily: What are you doing?
Rym: So you're not actually an admiral right now.
Rym: You're retired and you're trying to come on my ship and give me an order.
Rym: Yeah Let me just phone home and see what the other admirals have to say about what you're just told.
Emily: Yeah, so like I I think generally I Put lower decks on the exact same footing as every other Star Trek.
Emily: I think it's fully canonical and they've said as much and I really enjoy it.
Emily: I think if you're at all a fan You should definitely check it out.
Emily: And if you are just wanting to get into Star Trek I think that and maybe Strange New Worlds is a good entry.
Rym: Episode 1 of Lower Decks, Episode 1 of Strange New Worlds.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening theme.
Rym: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowclue.com for show notes discussion links and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays gaming and games.
Rym: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Rym: Thursdays are arbitrary and indiscriminate.
Rym: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 4.0 International license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Ellen Joyce, Linki G, Dread Lily, Tenebrae, Case Care, Makes Music, Chris, Dodd Christopher Orr, Clinton Walton, M. Defmec, Finn, Joel Haze, Penny Rymer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Van Harl, and a bunch of people giving like zero or one dollar or a pound or euro or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, we're big into Star Trek again lately, and I'm just gonna leave you tonight with.
Media: I don't want a lot of Christmas.
Media: There is just one thing that I need.
Media: I don't care about the presents underneath the Christmas tree.
Media: I just want to boldly go more than you could ever know.
Media: Make my wish come true.
Media: All I want for Christmas is Captain Long.
Media: It's almost Christmas and there is just one thing I need.
Media: I don't care about the presents underneath the Christmas tree.
Media: I don't want to hang my stocking there above the fireplace.
Media: Number one won't make me happy with the toy on the Christmas day.
Media: I just want to make it so more than you could ever know.
Media: Make my wish come true.
Media: All I want for Christmas is a cute baby.