Rym: It's Tuesday, August 8th, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We are reviewing a game from 1995, Pitch Car.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I realized today is 0808.
Rym: And uh...
Scott: 808. 808.
Rym: It came up when we were talking about all the anime that have the word "city" in their name kind of randomly.
Scott: Demon City.
Scott: City Hunter.
Rym: Demon City.
Rym: Wicked City.
Scott: Demon City.
Scott: If there's an anime with "city" in the name, you know you're getting into something.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: It was the kind of thing we used to do.
Rym: Like, GeekNights in the earliest days was like equal parts gaming cons, anime cons, other stuff.
Rym: Like, we went to way more anime cons than we did gaming cons.
Rym: Partly because we didn't go to PAXes, mostly because we were too stupid to prioritize them sooner.
Scott: They were expensive and far away.
Scott: We were poor.
Rym: We were.
Rym: But if we had like stopped going to all those anime cons, we could have gone to just a PAX instead.
Rym: Eh.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: But uh... We used to go to a lot of anime cons and when we were having that anime with the "city" in the title, that is the exact kind of panel that in the era where I cared about anime cons, that would be the panel I would be like, let's do a panel about all the anime with "city" in the title.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Let's do it.
Rym: And uh, I don't know.
Rym: Like, I haven't seen any of those shows in more than a decade.
Rym: Two of them are movies.
Rym: Most of them are movies, actually.
Rym: And I also don't think I have the energy to do a panel like that in the year 2023.
Rym: We've definitely skewed heavily toward gaming and technology as time has gone on.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Things change.
Rym: But uh, there's a lot of news.
Rym: We keep skipping shows off and on because life has come back full swing in the wind down from the hell era of COVID.
Scott: And uh... To the second hell era.
Scott: Hell 2.
Rym: I hope there is not a third hell era of that.
Scott: Oh no, it's just gonna be... Listen, from now until the day you leave this earth, whenever that is, it will just be a descent into further hells.
Scott: There is no changing of that.
Rym: The only thing I hope for now is I try to figure out for all the different threads of hell world.
Rym: Because we've got climate change hell world, we've got the repeated cyclical rise of fascism in various forms hell world.
Rym: We've got the internet is turning into nothing but one ad hell world.
Rym: All the different hell worlds.
Rym: I'm just trying to hope that some of them hit their nators and at least bounce off of a local minimus.
Scott: But there are other hells.
Scott: You don't even, you know.
Rym: Yeah, there's so many we're not even thinking about right now because we're focused on the ones that are like actively affecting us.
Rym: Like, "Oh, COVID is winding down.
Rym: I can finally stop wearing masks
Rym: indoors.".
Rym: And then the monkeys pause like, "Motherfucker, you're gonna have to wear a mask outdoors
Rym: now.".
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So speaking of hell world, there's a live streamer.
Rym: I guess this guy does video game streams.
Rym: I've never heard of him.
Scott: I've never heard of him before either, but apparently he's like one of the most popular streamers.
Rym: So here's my recollected, absorbed understanding of who Kai Sinat is as a streamer.
Rym: This is just what I collected from interfacing with the world.
Rym: What I know about him is he was a streamer who did some video games.
Rym: He set the record for the biggest stream ever on Twitch like kinda recently.
Rym: Like he's that big.
Scott: Basically this dude is the biggest deal on Twitch.
Rym: He also got banned from Twitch relatively recently for violating at least one term of service at one point.
Rym: I guess he got reinstated at some point.
Scott: If you make a lot of money for them, you can get reinstated.
Rym: And I'm pretty confident he's not a great person just based on multiple factors that I learned.
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: I know very little about the person.
Scott: I don't know any positive things about him.
Rym: So here's a data point that is definitely not a red flag for this person's character.
Rym: Kai Sinat apparently recently, like this just happened a few days ago, told his streamers, all his fans, he was gonna go to Union Square in New York City and give away like 500 PS5s.
Rym: Now there are so many fucking things wrong with saying those words out loud that I cannot even enumerate them all.
Rym: But let's go through the important points.
Rym: One, he did not tell New York City he was doing this.
Scott: No.
Rym: And two, he did not put forth even a minimal, like, barest effort to in any way plan how this was going to go down.
Rym: So one of the most popular live streamers in the world tells millions and millions and millions and millions of the kinds of people who are fans of one of the biggest streamers in the world that he's gonna give away PS5s in Union Square.
Rym: What do you think happened?
Rym: A fucking riot.
Rym: Now, I was not at home when this happened, and I saw the news, and the news was like, "Live streamer caused this riot in Union
Rym: Square.".
Rym: And all I could think was, "There's no way it's as bad as the news is acting like it
Rym: is.".
Rym: And then I get home and I look at the news, and it was so much worse than I thought it was.
Scott: I mean, it was, you know, it wasn't good, but it wasn't like a riot with, like, looting, smashing all the windows, setting all the buildings on fire.
Rym: It was a riot of cars being smashed and vandalized and people throwing rebar at each other.
Scott: On a scale of, like, you know, zero being peaceful protest walk, you know, and ten being...
Rym: January 6th at the White House trying to literally overthrow the government directly and actively.
Scott: I think ten would have to be actually overthrowing a government.
Scott: True.
Rym: Nine!
Scott: Nine!
Rym: January 6th was a nine because the ten would have been if they actually hung Mike Pence.
Scott: Ten has to be, like, terrorism, murders, bombs, right?
Scott: Like, full, you know, hell, right?
Rym: Well, I would say this only hit a four or, like, a four-ish because...
Scott: On that scale, this was like a three, four, five area.
Rym: Well, because New York City... Now, again, I am not saying that everything about this process is good.
Rym: Far from it.
Rym: But to borrow a phrase that's getting a lot of mileage in my life from a YouTube video about why pet monkeys are banned in Sweden.
Rym: I'm not saying this is good.
Rym: I'm just saying this is how it is or this is what happened.
Rym: So, New York City already has a rapid response force that is not just police but is also crowd control and, like, paramedics and firetruck and IMT.
Rym: There is a whole rapid response force in New York whose sole job is to detect if a crowd has formed somewhere that is too big and make sure people don't get crushed to death by it.
Rym: Like, this isn't even just designed for riots.
Rym: They have a whole other, like, above and beyond process for there's a riot and we need to tear gas people.
Rym: This is like...
Scott: Yeah, those tear gas people did not show up to this.
Scott: That shows you the level of the riot was not at a level...
Rym: So, I did see video.
Rym: Tear gas was deployed but not the, like, artillery tear gas that we're all thinking of.
Scott: You didn't see any pictures of, like, a whole phalanx of people with plastic shields.
Rym: You did, actually.
Rym: I'm gonna link to a two-hour livestream.
Scott: I didn't see that one.
Rym: The police actually did have to forcibly remove this crowd.
Rym: because this crowd, to be clear, nobody involved in this crowd thought they were getting a PlayStation.
Rym: They showed up with fireworks and they robbed a construction site with Rebar and they just started fighting with people and they refused to leave.
Rym: But the reason New York has this is because crowds on this scale have appeared in New York for such things as some store is giving away free food or nothing.
Scott: It's a thing that when you have a lot of people in a small place relative to the number of people, at least, and this can happen.
Scott: It's not gonna happen in your small town because there's not enough people there.
Rym: If literally every human within 50 miles of that town shows up, that's less people than ride the 6 train.
Scott: Yeah, it's not dangerous.
Rym: But remember in Halloween last year, that horrific tragedy where all those people died in South Korea during Halloween?
Rym: Crowds of humans that are uncontrolled in a small space are like natural disasters.
Rym: They are so dangerous.
Rym: They are deadly and they are not obviously dangerous to people who don't know these facts.
Rym: So that's why New York has this response team.
Scott: Thankfully they are mostly only dangerous to the people participating and the only innocent bystanders.
Scott: But if you're far enough away, can't hurt you.
Rym: So this was an absolute shit show.
Scott: And far enough away isn't really that far away.
Scott: You could be like a block away and be fine.
Rym: So, uh, New York City does not fuck around.
Rym: Within 4 hours they had shut this shit down.
Rym: They arrested like 70 people because a lot of these kids refused to leave even when ordered to.
Rym: The live streamer fucking bailed.
Rym: He gave one last treatment on social media that was like, "Yo dawg, it's a riot out there.
Rym: You're all on your
Rym: own.".
Rym: And he tried to escape.
Rym: There's video.
Rym: His fans found his car, surrounded it, and like jumped on top of it.
Rym: And were like hanging to it as he tried to drive away.
Scott: Yeah, I think the thing is, because of the riotous nature, right?
Scott: All of the curiosities, like all the questions you have, really don't get answered.
Scott: Like, did he actually have the PS5s?
Scott: What was his plan?
Rym: I mean the car he was in was not big enough to have that many PS5s in it.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: The people who came, did they actually think they were gonna get a PS5?
Scott: What were they mad about?
Scott: Were they mad that the PS5s didn't happen?
Rym: So it seems like they weren't mad based on digging around and watching some of the live streams.
Rym: The people there seemed like they mostly showed up because they knew a bunch of people were gonna show up and some shit was gonna go down.
Rym: And they all were trying to live stream it themselves.
Rym: But we're gonna find out the details of how it went down because he was arrested and charged with inciting a riot, among other charges, by New York City.
Rym: And I think that was rightly done.
Scott: That's gonna happen.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So this is a hell of a story and we're gonna find out a lot about exactly what happened.
Scott: And within the next morning, I was biking past their summer streets and farmer's market, right?
Scott: So it's like, you know, while this story is entirely a true story, I want to still counter the narrative that a lot of people who don't live here think that New York City is somehow some violent, dangerous place.
Rym: If you were one block away from this, you wouldn't even know what was happening.
Scott: You would be sitting at like a table outside a cafe, sipping a coffee, reading a book, right?
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Like if you went to Union Square four hours after it happened, other than the destroyed construction site, which was unfortunate, there was no evidence that there was even a riot.
Scott: The construction site has insurance, that'll be fine.
Rym: Oh yeah, but it was like fucking destroyed.
Scott: The real estate person who owns the building, they're rich, they'll be fine.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So speaking of absolute shit shows of crowds, Gen Con, the convention we don't attend for a laundry list of reasons, had its own gigantic, dangerous crowd because of Disney's Lorkana.
Scott: So we've talked about Gen Con in the past, but it's basically, it's like, does Gen Con have positive aspects?
Scott: It's like, it's still, even though Pax Unplugged exists, it's the tabletop con for the industry, for releasing new games, for, you know, at least in the US, right?
Scott: You know, it brings together the RPGs and the card games and the board games and all the tabletop everything, right?
Scott: There's a lot of stuff there, but it's run poorly.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Very poorly.
Scott: And one of the ways that it was run poorly is that there's basically no line management or policy or consideration given whatsoever.
Scott: It's basically just like, yeah, have at it, whatever.
Rym: Like imagine a line at Pax, if you've been to a Pax with the enforcers and like the pods and all that, imagine the literal, intentional opposite of that.
Rym: Imagine if Pax was like, everybody, fuck you, defend for yourselves, expo hall opens at 10, it's over there, go nuts.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's what Gen Con does.
Scott: So what happened is that Ravensburger has this new game, the Disney CCG Lorkana, which looks like it's at least going to be short term successful because there's already like, you know, demand for rare cards and all that kind of bullshit happening.
Scott: The game's barely or not even out yet.
Rym: Well, remember this is the game that Upper Deck is suing Ravensburger saying that Ravensburger stole this game idea from them.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But anyway, but I think what we're going to end up doing is just buying like a one starter enough for two people to play and just to review the game.
Scott: and that's it.
Scott: But anyway, so this game is obviously hot, right?
Scott: People really want it.
Scott: And they had it at Gen Con because it's Gen Con.
Scott: And so people really wanted it.
Scott: And they're like, okay, fine.
Scott: You can line up starting at, you know, 3
Scott: a.m.,
Scott: right?
Scott: First come, first serve.
Scott: You know, if you leave line, you know, no cuts, no whatever.
Scott: But who was actually enforcing?
Scott: Someone, I guess, stated those rules, but I don't know who was enforcing them.
Rym: So from what I've read, random people in the crowd attempted to enforce these rules themselves on the crowd.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then basically, as soon as the con opened, you get a, you know, Black Friday, you know, discount at the mall situation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, which hurt basically other attendees who didn't care about this.
Scott: The vendors, vendors who had booths that happened to be nearby the Lorkana booth were extremely negatively impacted.
Rym: Even worse, this made up line that the fans made.
Rym: when the con opened the next day, Gen Con staff ignored it, broke it up, and like opened a different entrance.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I've heard all kinds of things.
Scott: I'm reading from the Polygon article right now.
Scott: I wasn't there, so I didn't even know.
Scott: But the point is, people rushed the booth to buy this thing.
Scott: The booth, I guess, itself didn't, like I haven't heard anything from them, whether they cared or not.
Scott: Like they sold their copies.
Scott: I also heard, I don't know if this is true or not, that even after the rush was done, they still had plenty left over, like they had made enough.
Scott: So there didn't even need to be a rush.
Scott: I guess.
Rym: I mean, we don't need to belabor the point around how all the people who are destroying themselves and engaging in this behavior should probably think about their priorities.
Rym: And there's a lot going on here.
Scott: Well, you know, I've also blamed the corporations for creating this sort of, you know, limited edition product Fuhrer, right?
Scott: They should be held responsible for that.
Scott: And I also blame the convention.
Scott: It's like in this day and age where even people who can't afford a smartphone have a crappy phone that can receive texts or even if no one has a phone, right?
Scott: It's like I can go to the grocery store and to get deli meats, they have a ticket system with like numbers.
Rym: And that shit worked when I was a kid in the eighties.
Rym: You know what now also worked in the eighteen eighties.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like there is no excuse to have people physically line up and wait for anything in this world, at least on the part of the world that has technology.
Rym: Unless you are evil, you are beholden to capitalism and the existence of the line and the Fuhrer and the nonsense is part of your marketing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like you want you want that to happen.
Rym: Like think about it like this still happens.
Scott: You should be held responsible because you're hurting people for your own profit.
Rym: But I do also blame the people for falling for this shit every time they want these people in line thinks they're going to buy one of these things and flip it for money later.
Rym: The same scam in every industry all around this IP.
Scott: If also I'm waiting for the day, I don't know why this hasn't happened yet, at least in the United States, for a person with a disability to sue because that might happen.
Rym: So there's a. there's a story here about someone's wheelchair being pushed over in the right.
Scott: But not not that for that reason, but for the reason of like I have a disability, I want I should have equal access to the thing.
Scott: But I am not physically capable of sitting and waiting in a line in one place for that many hours.
Scott: You should not be.
Scott: the ADA in.
Scott: my non lawyer argument basically makes lines of that nature illegal.
Rym: So quoting the article, during all of this, at one point, quote, Ravensburger announced accommodations for those with disabilities, end quote.
Rym: So someone made an appropriate complaint, I suspect.
Scott: But the thing is, yeah, but it's like you made an accommodation, which means you recognize that everyone else isn't accommodated.
Scott: Why don't you just fucking do a digital cue of some kind?
Rym: But also a lottery or anything.
Rym: I blame Gen Con.
Scott: Or why don't you count how many people are in line, count what your supply is, and then just tell the people, listen, we counted a thousand people in line.
Scott: We got twenty thousand.
Scott: You're good.
Scott: You don't have to wait.
Rym: And this is why ultimately, while the Ravensburger owns this problem, Gen Con is equally at fault because at PAX, PAX requires companies who are doing shit like this to run it by them and coordinate it with them.
Rym: PAX doesn't let you pull this kind of shit.
Rym: If Ravensburger did this out of PAX, I think they would have been kicked out.
Scott: But I'm saying the law of the world, the country or the state or wherever you are, the laws should punish people for doing this.
Scott: If you have any sort of limited good that you are going to distribute, you should be legally required to distribute it in a safe and equitable manner.
Scott: No waiting in line overnight.
Scott: First come, first serve.
Scott: This isn't 1970 Star Wars tickets.
Scott: It's like we have technology now.
Scott: Mandate.
Scott: It must be used.
Scott: You cannot do these unsafe lines anymore, anywhere, for any reason, for anything.
Rym: I agree.
Scott: Even if you want to do first come, you can still choose first come, first serve as your system for distribution.
Scott: That's what you've decided on instead of a lottery, but you can't make people physically wait.
Scott: There has to be some other, like at the deli counter or click on something at the right moment or something like that.
Rym: But beyond the law, because we know how America is and how we can't pass laws right now, I would also say this is a profound indictment of every aspect of Gen Con sucks because of this kind of thing.
Rym: This is like, this is the epitome of the culture of the people who run Gen Con that they allow this kind of situation to even exist.
Rym: And this is exactly how Gen Con has always been.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the point I guess I'm trying to make is that even though the current laws of Indianapolis in the United States don't make these behaviors illegal necessarily, right, is that I view these actions as, you know, bankrupt as I view criminal actions.
Rym: I see Ravensburger and Gen Con equally bankrupt in this regard.
Scott: Yes, what they are doing I view as criminal activity, right, harming people.
Rym: So speaking of shit shows at Gen Con, also, some guys, and I'll link to it because there's just photos of them, like it's a convention center.
Scott: I don't know what these nerds- I've thought about doing this in the past.
Scott: I won't lie.
Rym: Yeah, but the one thing I know, because you and I have been behind the scenes of many conventions, convention centers have cameras everywhere.
Scott: There is not one inch of a convention, of a major US convention center that is not on cameras.
Scott: The bathroom is about where you can hide.
Rym: And the perpetrators of this incident, like I'm looking at photos of them right now, they are distinctive enough to where I am confident they are all going to be caught and someone's going to stitch on them.
Scott: These dudes just walked in to where the pallets with like stuff for the expo- Right, the convention people are loading the convention, right, and when a convention loads, there's trucks and vans coming to the loading dock.
Scott: The union people, I don't know if Indianapolis is union, but the employees take stuff, unload the vehicles, and put them on the big giant empty show floor, and they just dump the pallets in the right spot.
Scott: And then you're an exhibitor, you come to where your booth is, and there's all these pallets with all your stuff on them, and then you have to build, you have to tear them down yourself and build your booth.
Scott: Maybe you also have to have some union help depending on what you're doing, right, to hang things from the ceiling or the rigging, who knows, right?
Scott: But the point is, until you've unloaded your pallets, right, it's basically anyone who has access to the show floor has access to all the stuff on the show floor.
Scott: And who knows who goes with what stuff, it's just a madhouse of, you know, staff and everywhere, right?
Rym: And it's chaotic, like, we've been behind the scenes of a PAX expo hall or another convention's expo hall, or even setting up ConnectiCon back when we ran that whole floor, like, it's chaos, and there's a lot going on.
Rym: But these dudes just grabbed a pallet with around $300,000 worth of some sort of collectible card game boxes.
Scott: I'm gonna guess it was from, like, a card vendor who had a booth, and they had all their inventory and a pallet, and then, you
Rym: know,
Scott: they just used a pallet jack and they didn't even have a forklift, they just used a pallet jack and they wheeled it away.
Rym: Yep, and there are copious photos of these dudes wheeling it away, like, they just wheeled it out, like, they're even in the carpeted part of the convention center, which is also amazing because, at least, never been to GenCon, but every other convention I've been to, you can't bring pallets into the carpeted areas, like, you have to use the loading docks, and if I tried to bring a pallet, like, in ConnectiCon, if I rolled a pallet and it even touched a centimeter of the public carpeted space...
Scott: The convention center staff would be like, "What the hell is this doing here?
Scott: What are you
Scott: doing?".
Rym: So, again, GenCon, what the fuck?
Rym: How, it's one thing, if they did it entirely within the show floor, how did these dudes even get into this space?
Rym: They don't look like they were vendors, they look like they're just attendees.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, my strategy, like, if I, first of all, like, it's like, Wall-A takes some guts to steal a whole pallet going for the big haul, right?
Scott: It's like, it's so big, it's so difficult to get away with that, it's so big and conspicuous, right?
Rym: It's not worth the squeeze, even if you get away with it 100%.
Rym: What the fuck are you gonna do with these?
Rym: Fencing them is gonna cost you so much in terms of time and effort that you're not gonna...
Scott: The real strategy would be, you have some plastic storage tubs in your own booth, and you go to other booths where there's no one there, and you take, like, one box of Magic cards that are sealed, and you hide it in your own booth storage, and no one knows, you know, it's like, if they don't notice it's missing, amongst their hundred boxes of Magic cards, they're not counting their inventory until the end of the show or the end of the day or whatever, right?
Scott: And they'll be like, "Ah, shit, we lost a box," right?
Scott: It's like, are they really gonna, you know, it's like...
Rym: Well, this, actually, the reason I wanted to bring up this story, even though we already had a lot of news to talk about, is that all of the stories we talked about today have a theme.
Scott: Yeah, you notice this theme.
Rym: Now, the broader theme, if I zoom out all the way, is capitalism is a fucking problem, but if we zoom in a little bit...
Scott: Just think about it.
Scott: These cards were just worth their cardboard.
Scott: They're not actually worth anything.
Scott: It's because of the evil collectible bullshit.
Rym: There is zero scarcity on these things.
Rym: There isn't even scarcity on PlayStations.
Scott: It's like he stole $300,000 worth of cards.
Scott: It's like, no, he stole, like, $1,000 of cardboard.
Scott: It's, like, that people prescribe more value to.
Scott: If they just... They could just decide to print.
Scott: Nothing is actually physically... I mean, I think people said there was some kind of agreement or something, but, like, nothing legally that I'm aware of will stop Wizards of the Coast.
Scott: They could print a million black lotuses if they wanted to.
Scott: And they could print them in such a way that they would be indistinguishable from the old beta ones, right?
Scott: They could use the same ink and the same paper, right?
Scott: And they could get them out into the market and no one would know.
Scott: Nothing's stopping them from doing that.
Scott: This artificial value scarcity nonsense is hurting real people, right?
Rym: And the two mentalities, because the problem is, this is a feedback loop.
Rym: On one hand, I blame the companies because they are...
Scott: The most.
Rym: Because even in capitalism, companies could act a lot more ethically and still be fine, but they choose extreme profits over literally everything else on Earth.
Scott: I think that in some of these cases, they're choosing lower profits.
Rym: Well, I mean, I do too, but I think that's an adjacent conversation.
Scott: Yes, we've talked about that before.
Rym: I think the companies could do things to make a lot more money and at the same time also be more ethical and make a very different ecosystem in gaming, but that's a bigger topic that deserves maybe a future show or panel or something.
Rym: But it's a feedback loop too because the fans, the people, are also causing this and I think it's the live streamer mentality feedback loop intersecting, which is a fame economy, intersecting with the collector mentality.
Scott: The hustler.
Scott: All these people have in common is that they're hustling, right?
Scott: They're not playing games purely for the joy of playing games.
Rym: Nobody in that line wanted a PlayStation.
Rym: Nobody in that line wanted Larkana to play it.
Rym: They're all hustling either to live stream it or fence it.
Scott: Yeah, even if they did want to play it or even if they did, it's like there is also the hustler mixed in with that.
Scott: There is the purity of simply wanting to enjoy the entertainment was not there.
Scott: It was mixed in with attempting to profit.
Rym: And in a way, capitalism on all angles, in a way, I respect the dudes who just fucking stole the cards more than the people who stood in that Larkana line because they were dumb.
Scott: They were dumb, but I respect that because they're not there.
Rym: They are not lying or pretending.
Rym: They were like, I'm fucking stealing magic cards to sell for money.
Rym: I'll steal whatever or whatever.
Scott: Who knows what they might have been?
Scott: Pokemon cards are a mix.
Rym: I am stealing these because people think they're valuable.
Rym: I'm not going to even pretend to engage with the game itself.
Rym: Now, the pro move would be if the people who stole them stole them because they have 100 friends and they're just going to play magic or whatever.
Scott: I think someone said they were magic commander decks.
Scott: It's like they're just going to play commander from now until the end of time.
Rym: If that's true, that edges into anti-capitalist action.
Rym: I think it's funny.
Scott: That's awesome.
Scott: They just really wanted to play commander, but they couldn't afford it.
Scott: And now they can play commander till they're blue in the face.
Rym: So anyway, in the meta moment, we will be at PAX West.
Rym: Look for us.
Scott: We'll hang out.
Scott: Hopefully.
Scott: I know.
Scott: I'm going to guarantee you there won't be any dangerous lines.
Scott: There might be long lines, but you don't need to wait in any of them.
Scott: They'll be well managed.
Rym: So PAX, to talk about why PAX is the literal inverse of Gen Con and every point that matters.
Rym: We're panelists, so we're guests of the con.
Rym: One of the things they ask us every year is, "Hey, do you want to do a fan meetup of any kind or any sort of gathering of any
Rym: kind?".
Rym: Because if you do, one, we want to help.
Rym: And two, you have to fucking tell us because if you do it without asking, it's going to be trouble.
Rym: We don't want a Gen Con situation, basically.
Rym: So maybe we'll do a little GeekNights speed up for anyone who wants to see us.
Scott: All but one person will come.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: Also, we've got four days in Seattle.
Rym: I'm sure we'll find some time to hang out with some people.
Rym: Look for our panel.
Rym: We'll post the schedule.
Rym: We'll post all that stuff.
Rym: We're back at PAX's, baby.
Rym: I'm excited.
Rym: We've got an all new panel.
Rym: I started sketching stuff out.
Rym: I've got a good, clever angle here.
Rym: But the problem is, we submitted this panel.
Scott: Did you just skip from over things of the day and went to meta moment?
Rym: Oh yeah, I went straight to meta moment.
Rym: I got too excited about this.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So my thing of the day.
Rym: You ever see a war movie and there's people on a navy ship and there's like one guy who has a gigantic helmet?
Rym: Like everyone else has normal helmets and there's one guy with like this gigantic helmet, usually in the background.
Rym: And like, you wonder if it's a thing, but it's like not acknowledged and no one says anything about it.
Rym: Like it's not part of the plot.
Rym: It almost looks like one guy is wearing a prop that just doesn't fit.
Rym: Well this video, in three minutes, will explain what the deal is with those big helmets.
Rym: And they're actually very clever, very important, and very cool, and they're a real thing.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So speaking of games and hustling, we all know that crane games are just slot machines.
Scott: Right?
Scott: You can, when you have a crane game, if you open the back of a standard crane machine, you configure, you tell the crane machine, "My merchandise is worth this much money.
Scott: This is how much money per play.
Scott: I want you to make this much profit
Scott: margin.".
Scott: And the claw will only grab with full strength and with a frequency.
Scott: that is, you know, gonna get you the profit margins you desire.
Scott: Right?
Scott: You could configure it to pay out every time.
Scott: In which case, you don't have a claw machine, you have a fun vending machine.
Scott: But that's how claws work.
Scott: Claw machines are gambling or anything similar to a claw machine is still gambling.
Scott: Don't play those.
Scott: They're bad.
Scott: However, in Japan, obviously they're a big deal.
Scott: Right?
Scott: UFO catchers and claws and whatever.
Scott: And there's a whole culture of people who go and play claw, you know, and associated games at game centers.
Scott: And most of those people are losing money gambling.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: However, a claw machine does differ from a slot machine in one regard.
Scott: And that is, it is still beholden to the laws of physics.
Scott: Ahhh.
Scott: If you can somehow get the prize to fall down the hole by some means without opening it and stealing, right, crime, you win that prize, even though the slot, the crane machine may still be not closing its claw with full strength.
Scott: So it's like, can you get it to drop the prize when the claw is basically not, you know, closing fully, right?
Scott: And deciding to give you the prize.
Scott: And in Japan, many, many claw machines apparently are poorly configured or the prize is inside or set up in an interesting way.
Scott: And if you have a lot of skills and practice and 100 yen coins to spare, and you really want to get, I don't know, 30 anime figures, or a pile of plushies, right, there are ways that you can get and profit from claw machines with incredible levels of skill.
Scott: Do not play the claw machines.
Scott: You will not profit.
Scott: But this YouTube channel, run by someone, a Japanese person named Yuya, I guess that's their internet name, is the claw master.
Scott: And I can't deny, they are really good at the crane game.
Scott: They know all the secrets of the crane game, various different kinds of crane games.
Scott: They can spot ones that are poorly configured or weak or have vulnerabilities.
Scott: In one video, they won three PS4s with a few dollars.
Scott: In another video, they're swinging the claw around without making it descend, and there's a display in the back of the crane with a bunch of tiny plushies, and they spin the claw around, it grabs it and knocks it over, and all the plushies come falling down.
Rym: Oh, that video appeared in my feed before you made this the thing of the day.
Rym: I saw that video.
Scott: Yeah, so this person, watch them, but do not try to replicate them because you will fail, right?
Scott: But enjoy that they are beating the system, right?
Scott: And they're like getting these, some of these anime figures are worth at least 20 bucks, and they're knocking some of them down into the hole with like three or four pokes.
Scott: That's a $15 profit, right?
Scott: And this person, also I appreciate, they know that crane games are a slot machine, right?
Scott: And they're straight up telling you like, "Hey, if I miss this, I'm gonna lose money," right?
Scott: And like, "I need to get this in so many pokes in order for it to pay out," et cetera, et cetera, right?
Scott: They're not, they're not, you know, they're telling the truth about the situation, right?
Scott: They're not deluding themselves into thinking that like they're skilled at, you know, I mean, they are skilled at the crane, but you know, they know the reality.
Rym: But yeah, they have the gnosis of the nature of the claw itself.
Scott: They're like, they're like, "The claw is not going to grab strongly.
Scott: I need to do something different and unintended to get the prizes to come
Scott: out.".
Rym: There is some clever shit in here, like getting the claw to hook around a little loop in a plushie that you're not even supposed to be able to get out of there.
Scott: Yeah, whenever a plushie has a tag on it, they're like, "Oh, let's grab that
Scott: tag.".
Scott: In one video, he even has a claw at home, and he's like, "Look at the structure of the claw.
Scott: Some of the people, the clerks at the, at the claw places don't put the tip of the claw on properly, and you can snag something on the back of the
Scott: claw.".
Scott: And he's like, "See right
Scott: here?".
Scott: He's like, you know, so this is, this is truly a fascinating situation.
Scott: There's not that many videos.
Scott: You can just watch the whole channel, pretty much.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: I enjoyed it.
Rym: So, to continue the second half of my over-enthusiastic meta moment, got too excited about PAX, because it's, you know, in the pre-COVID times, starting in August, it's the good summertime, but it's also the time when I start thinking, "Pax is coming.
Rym: PAX is
Rym: coming."
Rym: And I always get a little jazzed up about it, but we did the Book Club book, This is How You Lose the Time War, we read it, we did the show.
Rym: The next one will be some amount of the Murderbot Diaries.
Rym: We are planning to do the next Book Club show, I haven't made the post yet, probably toward the end of September, and our goal is we're gonna cover as much of the Murderbot Diaries as we've read by then, so just start reading.
Scott: Yeah, so, right, we didn't realize that it was another short one, and I was like, "But there's seven books,
Scott: right?".
Scott: So, I think what we're gonna do is we're gonna have a little fun.
Scott: It's like, how many of these little volumes can we read, you know, by, you know, we can't just say read 'em all, that's too much, right?
Scott: And we can't, you know, picking a number of them is also difficult.
Scott: So let's have fun.
Scott: Let's say we'll do the episode in like a couple months-ish, right?
Scott: How many will we read by then, right?
Scott: You know, we might say, "Ah, these suck, I don't wanna read anymore," and stop, right?
Scott: We might get so excited and read all of them, even though I think that's too much, right?
Rym: A dark horse factor is the Rym factor of, "Well, I read one of the Wheel of Times, I guess I'm in it to the
Rym: end.".
Scott: Yeah, but it's not, you might be in it to the end, but will you get to the end by the time we do the episode?
Rym: That is true.
Scott: So, the book club selection is some number, unknown, you can have fun guessing, right?
Scott: How many volumes, or predicting, how many volumes of the Murderbot Diaries we will get through, at least one, guaranteed, no matter what.
Rym: You know what this means?
Rym: Every meta moment, we can interrogate each other about the status of bots and murders.
Scott: Yeah, you'll get every GeekNights episode, there'll be a status update about how many Murderbot Diaries you're gonna have to get through, and when the episode is gonna be.
Scott: That way, we can sort of balance the "get a substantial amount of book" in there, because one volume is tiny.
Scott: For the people watching, look how tiny this thing is.
Scott: From the library.
Rym: And the Time War was also a pretty thin, that was like a three hour read.
Scott: This is Time War sized, right?
Scott: So, you know, that's that.
Rym: Alright, so, I have played Pitchcar, I want to say seven or eight times in my life, at various points?
Scott: Some single digit number of times, but for real, of various degrees, right?
Scott: Because sometimes you play a little Pitchcar, and sometimes you play a big Pitchcar.
Rym: At a gathering relatively recently, thanks to our good friend Matt, we were able to play what I would call- Matt owns every single Pitchcar expansion.
Scott: I'd say we played a fully realized Pitchcar, like- Yeah, so I don't think it gets bigger or better than that.
Scott: Your wildest dreams.
Scott: You could buy multiple sets and make it even bigger, but it's like, what's the point then, right?
Scott: This was the ideal sized Pitchcar.
Rym: So, Pitchcar is one of those relatively rare games, there's more now, but it kind of comes and goes in the tabletop gaming world.
Rym: Dexterity games come and go in terms of popularity, but a very specific subset of dexterity games are the flicking games.
Scott: I want to make a comment about flicking games in general, while we're here, because why not?
Scott: And this happened, and I didn't comment on it at the time, because who really cares, right?
Scott: It's not that serious a game.
Scott: But whenever I play flicking games, even as far back as middle school times, a lot of people don't flick properly, as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: I had a note in my notes that I wanted to bring that up and another related topic up before we got into Pitchcar itself.
Scott: As far as I'm concerned, a valid flick means that you use your thumb and you pick one of your other four fingers.
Scott: It doesn't matter which one, I don't really care, right?
Rym: Middle finger's the best one, but we could disagree there.
Scott: You pick one of your other fingers and you press the nail of the finger against your thumb as hard as you want, right?
Scott: But your finger doesn't actually move forward because your thumb is holding it back.
Scott: And then you release your thumb, and all that pressure that you are applying to your thumb with your finger is released in one instant.
Scott: And your finger that is released hits the object that you are flicking for a mere instant, and then it transfers power and momentum into it, and then that object then moves.
Scott: And that is a flick.
Scott: I've seen people do shit like put their thumb on top of an object and try to release it.
Scott: That's not a valid flick, right?
Scott: I've seen people just push it, like tap it with the back of their finger.
Scott: Yeah, none of those are valid flicks, and if I was holding a serious competition... No one's playing Pitchcar seriously, we weren't.
Scott: But if I was having any serious competition at a flicking game, if someone did an invalid flick, as in not what I just described, and they were physically capable of doing a valid flick... I would just say, "Listen, that was your one warning.
Scott: If you ever do a non-valid flick again in the tournament, you're just disqualified for the whole tournament.
Scott: You must do a valid, true flick.
Scott: Anything else is not a flick.
Scott: Get out of
Scott: here.".
Rym: So the second point around that that's in my notes, I guess I'll get this out of the way first before we review Pitchcar as a flicking game.
Rym: Because this also is not about Pitchcar, this is about all flicking games.
Rym: I have found in my personal experience across all flicking games that the people who do not flick properly either do not want any instruction or assistance flicking.
Rym: Like, they will actively resist being given advice or help, and two, even if given advice and help, will never flick properly.
Rym: Like, they just never change what they're doing no matter what.
Rym: But what this leads to is my sort of final flicking game conundrum.
Rym: And if you want to play Pitchcar or games like it with your friends, this is a warning.
Rym: Just like there are games where they can be played fast, but a certain kind of person will bog it down, Pitchcar and all flicking games, I have found, cause a significant percentage of the people who play them to get really, really frustrated, angry, heated, yelling, quitting the game,
Scott: even in a non-serious who cares game,
Rym: like even when everyone in the group is supportive, and everyone's laughing and having a good time and no one cares who wins, I see people, and the same thing happens in mini golf, I see people lose their fucking shit in these games and like have to walk away or start yelling or get actually angry.
Rym: And I have seen this in every tabletop flicking game I have ever played, like without exception.
Rym: Not all dexterity games have this problem.
Rym: Flicking games, if you have a friend who gets a little over frustrated if they're not doing well in a game, I advise you to not play flicking related games with them.
Scott: Or, you know, sports in general.
Rym: But flicking games are a place where there's a lot of people who have that problem who might avoid sports, but don't quite internalize that a flicking game is also a sport, and thus they start playing it, they don't do well, and rather than just shrugging it off like they might in a regular tabletop game, they get like unreasonably angry.
Scott: Okay, so Pitch Car is a flicking game where it's really straightforward, is you build a racetrack, like Hot Wheels, but only wider, right?
Scott: And you have discs, just wooden discs basically, and you take turns, you have a disc that's your car, and on your turn you flick it, and your goal is to get around the racetrack first, it's a race, right?
Scott: But everyone gets an equal number of flicks because you take turns in rotation, right?
Scott: So, that's all there is to it, really.
Scott: If you go off the track, however, which happens often, basically what happens is you have to put your disc back where it started, and then wait for, you know, your next turn, you basically just didn't progress that turn, which, that's the thing that bogs the game down.
Scott: However, you could say, "Well, why don't you just, you know, put the disc where it left the track, but the person then loses their next
Scott: turn?".
Scott: And it's like, you could do that, but actually, that would encourage people to just hit the thing really hard and leave the track somewhere really far away, so that, that would actually give them more progress, right?
Scott: Actually having to progress safely through all the parts of the track is what makes the game meaningful.
Scott: If you could just, otherwise it would just become, flick the hardest the game, and the track itself would lose all meaning and purpose.
Scott: So that's why you can't have that rule adjustment.
Rym: Now the other little bit is that the car, the little cars have a car logo on the top and nothing on the bottom, because you also, your car needs to land face up.
Scott: Correct.
Scott: Now you could, it could flip over, as long as it lands face up, you're all good.
Rym: Now one thing I did find, digging through some online chatter and the board game forum is that most people who, I feel like there are people who play Pitch Car once or twice at a convention, and people who are Pitch Car people, and I have found reliably, people who are into Pitch Car will do something that, I think it's a flaw in the game, that the game does not have the, like, extremely precise rules to handle all the potential edge cases of a flick and gone awry.
Rym: I agree, yes.
Rym: Correct.
Rym: But the way to deal with that, if you play Pitch Car, this is one of those games where you should, regardless of exactly what the rules say, define up front, out loud, with the group you're playing with, exactly how the game will proceed in detail, and pre-make the calls you expect to be able to have to make based on the track and the people.
Rym: Even if those are not in the rules, this is the one case where I say, you need to do that up front, not only to avoid the weird frustration problem, but also to avoid the debate mid-game of whether or not a flick was okay.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, the components in this game are honestly pretty A+.
Rym: They, you're gonna make a pretty good course, and it's pretty obvious what makes a good obstacle or not.
Rym: Like, I'm really impressed with the physicality of this game.
Rym: It's the kind of game if I had a house, I would definitely own, and because I have a New York apartment, I will definitely never own.
Scott: The thing is, you know, you have to have, to build a good course, you either need to A) not have enough pieces that you can make something that won't work, in which case anyone can build the course, or B) if you have lots and lots of pieces for lots and lots of fun, you need adult considered restraint to not make an impossible course.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right?
Scott: But, like, don't put, like, the jumps in front of the loop, it's impossible, right?
Scott: It's like there should just be a straightaway for the loop, right?
Scott: Because otherwise, no one's ever gonna be able to do the loop, and it'll just be a frustrating, you know, mess, and no one will win.
Scott: You know, it's like, you could build the bridge, it's like, make the area around the bridge kinda easy, 'cause actually getting over the bridge isn't as easy as it looks, you know?
Scott: But if you show the restraint, any of the obstacles individually, or at least in the correct orientations, are conquerable, right?
Scott: With some amount of flicks.
Scott: You know, we did, what, a two lap race, and we finished, right?
Scott: So, you know.
Rym: And I guess, that is where, this is a game too, where that curation you described is very important.
Rym: Designing the track, not only is it super important, and, like, that's gonna determine if the game is fun or not, but, designing the track is itself fun.
Rym: Like, I think half the fun of owning Pitchcar, or playing Pitchcar, is, you're sometimes the one who sets up the track for everyone to play.
Rym: Like, it would be fun, if you own this game, to take turns, who makes the track?
Rym: People who have different styles.
Rym: And there's a lot of debate among Pitchcar people, around what makes a good track, what makes a poor track, How are you gonna handle situations with a track like splits, or deviates, or does something crazy?
Rym: But I think a real key there, is you wanna design a track that has relatively easy, straightforward areas, that are connecting what you would consider to be relatively discreet challenges.
Rym: Kinda like how good Mario Kart tracks are, or good actual real world race tracks are.
Rym: Like, a race track has a long straightaway, a long straightaway, in and of itself, is not hard in a race car.
Scott: It is, somewhat.
Scott: I mean, the difficulty of, you're trying to, you know, there is some challenge to it, right?
Scott: You're putting on the maximum speed, you're flooring it, but you have to hit the brakes at some point, 'cause the straightaway will end, and it's like, how long do you floor it, when do you stop?
Scott: That's the challenge of a straightaway.
Scott: But it's not the same as the straightaway as the challenge of a complicated chicane with three turns that suddenly goes downhill.
Scott: That's, right.
Rym: And arguably, much of the challenge of the straightaway is defined by the chicane that's right after it.
Rym: Or the corner that's right after it.
Rym: And the components of this game do a really good job of giving you the tools you need to make an interesting and compelling course for the flicking.
Rym: Like, it's a fun game to play, I really enjoy it, I would play it again, pretty much any time.
Rym: My only real complaint, other than, you know, it takes a long time to set up, long time to tear down, the components are a little fragile, and you might not have the space or the people who will not freak out to play it, is just that it's the kind of game, if you want to enjoy it, I feel like you want to play it regularly, in the same way that mini golf is the kind of game that's more fun if you play it regularly as opposed to just once a year.
Scott: I think it's one of those things, I think mini golf can be fun if you play it regularly, but you would need more than one mini golf course, right?
Scott: If you're playing it the same mini golf, like if you owned a mini golf or worked at one, if you played that course every day and then you got really good at it, then it would have.
Scott: no, right, with pitchcar, you can keep remixing the track, right, all the time, and that's what can keep it fresh, as you play it repeatedly and build your skills.
Scott: But yeah, mini golf, you would need to go traveling around to different mini golfs, right?
Scott: Even regular golf, you have to go to different golf courses, playing the same regular golf course over and over, some people do that, but it's like, you know.
Rym: I mean, those are the same people who play Counter-Strike, Dust2 only.
Scott: Exactly, right.
Scott: Another thing about pitchcar is that, you know, if you make a long straightaway, you have to consider that if people are flicking properly, right, they're gonna try to get as much power as they can, and the disc is wood, it's like you can hurt your fingers playing pitchcar just on your own, flicking your own disc.
Rym: Because pitchcar is a dexterity game, and thus it is a sport, just like Jungle Speed, where you can break your finger.
Scott: Right, it's like, if there's a long straightaway or the loop, it's like, the way to conquer those is indeed with power, like as much power as you can get is only gonna help you get through those obstacles.
Scott: I
Rym: gotta say, the finger hurting problem, I think partly a factor there is that we're all around 40 now, because when I was in middle school and high school, and I played a lot of flicking games, like we'd play a lot of games that involved flicking, like just various, like I don't have names for them, the games you'd play at a lunch table.
Rym: We'd flick each other, we'd play a flicking equivalent of punch for punch.
Rym: Flicking did not hurt me at any point in my life until I was 40, and now flicking...
Scott: I think it's because when I was flicking at the lunch table, it was like a cardboard trying, it was a piece of paper folded into a triangle of marbles.
Scott: I'm just saying, but I got the piece of wood, and you're trying to flick it as hard as you can, right?
Scott: A marble, you're never trying to flick it as hard as you can, you're trying to flick it straight, right?
Rym: Sometimes with a brake marble, you're flicking hard.
Scott: Some power, but not necessarily as hard as, you know.
Rym: The thing is, marbles you're supposed to flick with the thumb up, and there's a different technique, but we're not talking about marbles, we could do a show on marbles.
Scott: I think it would be cool, I think it wouldn't be feasible, but it would be cool if someone could make a pitchcar where the things you flicked, right, were somehow softer on the finger, but there was less friction, you know, they were a little slidey like air hockey pucks.
Rym: I think you could open up pitchcar itself to a broader audience, which would help the people we've encountered who get frustrated because they can't flick, if the game had devices that basically would hit the cars, kind of like you have your pallet of golf clubs.
Rym: when you're playing golf, you have your pallet.
Scott: Like a little tiny thing, like hot wheels, right, is?
Scott: you put the car on that little gun, and you, you know, you rev it up, you pull the string, and then you push.
Rym: So what if instead, you know, you have all your woods and irons in golf, if there were four devices with different powers and configurations, and every turn in pitchcar, you pick a device and use it instead of flicking.
Rym: That would be a way to introduce a little bit of an ego shield and reduce the surprising barrier to entry that knowing how to flick seems to be.
Scott: Yeah, removes the necessary, you know, necessity of learning a technique, right?
Scott: You have a device that does the flicking for you.
Scott: All you have to do is hold the device near the car, aim it, set its power, and push a button, right?
Scott: But I mean, you could also achieve that by playing pitchcar on like TTS or something, where it's like.
Scott: basically, you know, you just, as a physics engine, you have a disc object in the 3D world, and you just apply a force at an angle and push the flick button, and it will flick the object, and the physics engine will guide it, and not the real world physics, so it's not exactly the same.
Scott: But, you know, you could, it's probably most of the fun, I imagine.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: so pitchcar, I would say, in terms of any, wrapping up the review, if you're the kind of person who hosts gaming events, or shows up to gaming events as "the one who brought the game," and you're like curating pitchcar experiences for other people, or want to do
Scott: that.
Scott: If there's a lot of people, if it's a, you know, a big atmosphere, a kid's birthday party who likes cars or games.
Rym: If you got kids, if I had pitchcar as a kid, this would have been one of my favorite toys.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, it's a big event sort of showcase kind of deal, right?
Scott: A convention or something like that, where you can set up the pitchcar and organize it, right?
Scott: It takes effort to make it happen, but it's, you know, it's worth it if you're going to do that.
Scott: But it's like, just having a pitchcar on the shelf with all your other board games, it's like, maybe if you don't have any expansions, just a little one, it's like, maybe, but is it really going to get pulled out?
Scott: It's like, I don't really see that happening, right?
Scott: Which I would say- Just because the people waiting for you to set up the track, it's like, you know.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Meanwhile, when we were at our thing, our friend Matt, we just like, I went off somewhere and I come back and the pool table is covered in like an F1 quality pitchcar track.
Rym: And I'm like, what's going on here?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like, well, I guess that's going to happen now because someone went through the effort to make it happen.
Scott: If not for that person, it doesn't, you know, that would have just sat on the shelf there.
Scott: At no point would someone have said, let's set up the pitchcar, right?
Scott: But someone independently set up the pitchcar.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: And they said, I have prepared for you the pitchcar.
Scott: It is here now.
Scott: Let us play at the appointed time, right?
Scott: And so it was.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patreons for this episode of GeekNights.
Rym: Alan Joyce, Link E. G, Dreadily, The Tenderbread, Casey Care, Makes Music, Chris, Don, Clinton, Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Sherman Von Hurl, and tons of people who do not want me to say their names or are giving a tiny appropriate amount like a dollar or a pound or a euro per month.
Rym: Just probably, I assume, so you can get access to that pretty good RSS feed that's in there.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, GeekNights is back, PAX is back, I got nothing new, Emily's been out of town for the last week, so I've been playing a lot of Overwatch and also working on some secret projects.
Rym: But anyway, right now, I got nothing, I'm real hungry, and I'm gonna go out to eat because I am lazy and in goblin mode, so I leave you only with... .
Media: Google doesn't work anymore  .
Media: I've tried to search for what I need  .
Media: I'm still looking for.
Media:  .
Media: Yes, I know about the quotes  .
Media: I know about the dash and or  .
Media: It's all ass.
Media:  .
Media: Google doesn't work anymore  .
Media: I am from the future  .
Media: I can't bring a message for your time   That Google would become the thing it sought to destroy.
Media:   Yahoo.
Media:   Yahoo  .
Media: They passed on buying them twice.
Media:   Sold their souls to the advertisers.
Media:   Uncompassing as Trudad.
Media:   Google doesn't work anymore .