Rym: It's Monday, May 8th, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we're talking about the noise that comes out of technology like computers.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, this past weekend, you know what I did?
Rym: Went to a Star Trek convention, which is not something, you know, I like Star Trek a lot.
Rym: And I like conventions a lot.
Scott: But anyone who's listened to GeekNights- I like one of those things.
Rym: Anyone who's listened to GeekNights for more than, like, a few minutes knows that when I- when me or Scott say we like conventions, what we're actually saying is we like PAXes, Megfests, and a handful of other specific named conventions.
Rym: Uh, most conventions that are not PAXes and Megfests and things like that, and, like, a lot of anime cons, have bad weird formats, they make you pay for events, like, there's all sorts of nonsense going on.
Scott: Yeah, the majority of conventions out there, especially smaller ones, are pretty much, like, just a room full of, you know, tables, right?
Scott: Which is perfectly fine.
Scott: if your event is, say, the Mocha Festival, where it's, like, that's all you, you know- Or if your event is that thing in Wildwood where it's just a hyped-up garage sale.
Scott: Well, but that's not a good event.
Scott: That's exactly a bad convention.
Rym: Well, yeah, I guess it's, you know, it sucks because that type of event- That's more like a collectible show than a convention.
Rym: Well, like, Philly Wizard World is very good for the kind of person who wants to go to Philly Wizard World.
Scott: Right, but a lot of conventions out there, if they have panels, they're real weak sauce, right?
Scott: There's no content beyond shopping or whatnot, right?
Scott: So, you know, and the thing is, you know, the Star Trek con is pretty much- That's, like, I don't know if the first- I don't think the first con was a Star Trek con, right?
Rym: Star Trek cons were, like, some of the first cons that we would recognize.
Scott: But I do credit the Star Trek fandom with making nerd cons into a thing, right?
Scott: You know, when nerd cons entered into the consciousness of, you know, nerd or the rest of, you know, the culture, right?
Scott: It was the Star Trek cons that were the ones that were, you know, making the biggest waves in that regard.
Rym: Like, you can probably thank Star Trek cons for, like, panels.
Rym: Like, those cons don't have panels even today.
Rym: That's a weird thing to most people.
Scott: No, but, you know, it was Star Trek cons that were the ones that were parodied on television and, you know, on sitcoms.
Scott: They would always be a Star Trek con episode or something like that, right?
Scott: Or a comic con, maybe, sometimes.
Scott: But usually a Star Trek one.
Scott: And, you know, the cosplaying.
Scott: I guess, you know, there were cosplays before Star Trek, right?
Scott: But those people really went in on it with their, you know, their Starfleet uniforms and the little badges that go beep-beep and whatnot.
Scott: So, their Spock ears, right?
Scott: So, you know, credit where credit is due.
Scott: But a Star Trek con is, you know, even if I like Star Trek, right?
Scott: Which I don't.
Scott: But if I did, a Star Trek con would still not be appealing to me.
Rym: Yeah, well, we had a good time.
Scott: I'm not gonna spend-- Because those are historically the not good kind of convention.
Rym: But we had a good time.
Rym: But I'm not gonna-- I won't belabor, like, a big review of the con or anything, but I want to get a point out is that they had a panel format for when they had a panel with some guests on it that I had never seen before.
Rym: And I think this could be used at other cons.
Rym: Like, if we were still running panel, like, that entire content floor--.
Scott: So, what was the format?
Rym: So, at Kinetic Con, I would probably implement this.
Rym: The format was, instead of just having all the guests on stage, and then they answer questions or tell anecdotes or whatever, they would introduce all the guests, but the panel room is broken up into, like, six circles of chairs.
Rym: And each guest would go to one of those circles and just have a conversation with that smaller group of people for ten minutes, and then all the guests would rotate which circle they were in.
Rym: So, you got, like, just have a conversation among a relatively small group of people, like, small enough to where you can actually kind of have a conversation.
Scott: But only a ten-minute conversation.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But as a result-- So, if there's a horrible nerd, they get to escape them within ten minutes.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But also, obviously, I would modify this format a little bit.
Rym: Like, I'd have, of course, a staffer, like, standing in each one to mitigate the nerd if they're there.
Rym: You know, that kind of thing.
Rym: But what was interesting is that what ended up happening, like, by observation, is that-- Did you go to any of these circles?
Rym: Oh, yeah, I sat in one of the circles and met, like, a bunch of Star Trek people.
Scott: With what famous person?
Scott: that I don't know?
Rym: The guy who played Gowron in Star Trek.
Rym: The guy who is-- Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The guy we-- The eyeball guy?
Rym: Yeah, and in fact, the first question a nerd asks while we're hanging out, 'cause one, this guy's really funny, and he was like, "So, uh, why did you do the eyes like that?
Rym: Like, what's the real story behind the
Rym: eyes?".
Rym: He's like, "Oh, it's actually better than you think.
Rym: You want to hear the story about the
Rym: eyes?".
Rym: And he told the story about the fucking eyes, and it was really good.
Scott: He probably tells that story, like, a hundred times.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But, uh, we met the guy who played Martok, another one of the Klingon Chancellors.
Rym: The guy who played the Doctor in Deep Space Nine.
Scott: Don't know that one.
Rym: The woman who played Jadzia Dagg-- You're not gonna know any of these people.
Scott: No.
Scott: I knew the Gauran guy.
Rym: Yeah, you know the Gauran guy.
Rym: You can see him right now, most likely.
Scott: There's also the anti-Semitic Jewish bartender guy.
Scott: I know that guy.
Rym: Armand Shimmerman, Quark.
Scott: Reading Rainbow eyeball guy.
Rym: Uh, Geordi, that's from TNG.
Scott: Obviously, I know, you know, the two-- The coolest one was not a visitor.
Rym: She played the major on DS9, but the thing that was really interesting-- If you say the major, I only think about-- I know you do.
Rym: They're, in some ways, similar characters who kick similar amounts of ass.
Scott: The cyborg guy.
Rym: But what happened was that you get a little more back and forth, and you have conversations, which I think is better because, frankly, pure anecdotes from nerd celebrities are all documented in detail by nerds on the internet.
Rym: Like, the nature of the kind of person will ask that question at a con.
Rym: That person has seen the ten times that guest gave that answer already before they even got to them.
Scott: That person has just never read the internet.
Rym: Ah, depends.
Rym: It is shocking how few people read the internet, but people at this con seem to mostly have read the internet.
Rym: But also, these guests were way more willing to get more personal in this smaller setting and, like, answer more personal questions in a pretty good way.
Rym: And it was just, it was interesting that as an ostensible expert in, like, the running of nerd conventions, I had never seen this format before, and having seen it run, it is a pretty good format that I would institute if I was ever in this position again.
Scott: I mean, I've used that, I've used and participated in that format, but not when it came to celebrities at any level, right?
Scott: I've used it for, like, you know, alright, you know, educational settings, or teamwork-y settings, or...
Rym: And that's, that's it.
Scott: That's the secret.
Scott: Conference-y settings where everyone is mostly on the same level, or there might be, like, one leader at each station or something like that, but never was it for celebrity purposes.
Rym: Yup, so, I guess what I'll end on here, and then we'll get into the actual news, the benefits of this were twofold, and one of them's primarily for the guests themselves.
Rym: I think these guests had a way better time doing this than doing regular panels.
Scott: Like, they seemed- Well, it's less prep- you don't have to prepare anything.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But also, they got, like, some of them just, like, asked us questions the whole time, which was actually really kind of funny.
Rym: Like, what were they interested in?
Rym: They're like, "Why are you into Star Trek?
Rym: Like, what's your
Rym: deal?".
Rym: And it was actually weirdly interesting.
Rym: So, I think it's better for the guests, especially the kind of guest who, like, goes to a million cons and maybe is sick of going to cons.
Scott: The thing about that, the thing about that, right, is, like, uh, you know, if this, you know, when the celebrity's asking you stuff, it's like, that's good because you're getting away from them telling those same stories over and over again.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right?
Rym: The danger is you get to hear the worst guy in that circle just tell-.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: It's more enjoyable for the celebrity, right?
Scott: 'Cause they're hearing something new, right?
Scott: They're asking, presumably, 'cause they genuinely want to ask and then, you know, or they just want to not have to be the one who talks, right?
Scott: It's a way for them to, right?
Scott: It's a tool for them.
Scott: And also, I definitely would want to be asked, right?
Scott: It's like, if someone I cared about, you know, comes and asks me, like, you know, that would be the greatest.
Scott: Like, if, I don't know, Urasawa's like, "Hey, why do you like my
Scott: manga?".
Scott: I'd be like, "Oh, let me tell
Scott: you.".
Rym: It's like, alright, you're- I'd have to preface that by saying, "So I'm just gonna keep talking until you cut me off.
Rym: Feel free to cut me off,
Rym: buddy.".
Rym: Right.
Scott: But, if there's another Scott and Urasawa asked that other Scott that question, that is the worst for me.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Listen, I don't give a shit about some stranger and why they like the same celebrity I do.
Scott: That's awful.
Rym: They ended up asking questions that had relatively short answers, but nobody went on too long.
Rym: And I think, I suspect, the people who are the most damaging and dangerous in traditional panel Q&A are terrified of speaking up and trying to ask a question in a small group setting where there isn't a microphone that says, "You are the one who gets to ask a
Rym: question.".
Rym: Like, there were no "that guy" questions that I observed, and I cannot believe that was true.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: I need more data!
Rym: I have a datum!
Rym: I have one convention where I saw this format, but the fact that 0% of the questions at a fucking Star Trek con were "that guy" in this format is a piece of data that needs to be looked into a little bit further.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: It takes less, you know, a shy person, right, would, you know, could be empowered and sort of, you know, the sea of faces, right, it's easy to talk into a microphone and it's like, you know, but it's like if you're in a small, intimate setting, then if you're that kind of person, it may be much more difficult to say anything.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: 'Cause it's no longer a sea of faces, like it's individual people that you're seeing, right?
Rym: So, jumping into some news, this is fine, looks like it's finally for real, you can do it now, like it was announced a while ago, but it's here.
Rym: You can now use passkeys to sign into your Google account.
Scott: Yup, so, I think we did a multi-factor authentication episode last year, or 2021, somewhat recently.
Rym: I'll find it and link to it.
Scott: But yeah, passkeys are a thing, they're just, you know, there's a sea of acronyms that are, you know, involved with FIDO and, you know, TOTP.
Rym: Yeah, and I'll get, you know, as a technology professional, where part of that is my job, for real, even right now, I don't even know all those acronyms, like it's like-.
Scott: Oh, well, I can explain passkey to you very simply, right?
Scott: Here's how passkey works, it's really a great, it's a great idea, it's not perfect, but it's pretty, it's gonna make things a lot better.
Scott: It's better than typing a password.
Scott: It's a lot better than passwords for everybody, right?
Scott: So, the way it works is, you have some sort of private key, right?
Scott: And the private key is generated, right?
Scott: Presumably, uniquely, right?
Scott: It could be uniquely or not, but it doesn't matter, but for the websites that you're gonna log into, right?
Scott: Things you're gonna log into.
Scott: And, basically, they send you, you know, you got a public key, and you give the public key over to, you know, whoever it is that you're gonna log into, right?
Scott: And then, now that they have your public key, you can prove to them that you have the private key that goes with that public key, right?
Scott: So, Google says, "Hey, Scott, yeah, give me a public key.
Scott: Here, here, here's one.
Scott: Alright, now, here's some data that's random.
Scott: Encrypt it with your private key.
Scott: Okay, I'll encrypt it.
Scott: Here you go.
Scott: Here's the encrypted
Scott: data.".
Scott: And then, they, you know, check it with the public key, and they go, "Yup, it's mathematically impossible for the person, right, who encrypted that data, right, to not have the private key that went with the public key.
Scott: Therefore, we know that that person who gave us the public key is the same person who encrypted this data, right?
Scott: 100% mathematically proven.
Scott: Therefore, you go to a website, and it says, "Hey, register with our website.
Scott: Tell us your username, and, you know, do your Apple Touch ID, or do your Windows Hello, or do your YubiKey, or do your whatever.
Scott: Do your thing that your device does that has a private key in it, right?
Scott: And that will, behind the scenes, prove to us, right, that there, you know, there's a, we'll get, we'll receive a public key, and we'll know that you go with it.
Scott: And then, from that point forward, right, the next time, the first time, you could send anything.
Scott: It's like, you could use whatever, right, because it's the first time you're registering.
Scott: But after that, they call it a ceremony, after you perform the registration ceremony, right?
Rym: This is how a thousand years from now, we're just wizards, and technology is just magic.
Scott: After you perform the registration ceremony, they've got your public key, and they've associated it with your account.
Scott: And so, you come back three days later, and they're like, "Hey, you want to log into the Scott
Scott: account?".
Scott: And you're like,
Scott: "Yeah.".
Scott: They're like, "All right.
Scott: We already have Scott's public key.
Scott: Prove it.
Scott: Prove that you have Scott's private
Scott: key.".
Scott: I proved it.
Scott: I did my Windows Hello, or my Apple Touch ID, or my Apple Face ID, or my whatever the fuck it is that your device does.
Scott: And they go, "Ah, you have proved it.
Scott: You are the same person who registered for this website five days
Scott: ago.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: "You're logged in.
Scott: No password necessary.
Scott: No, not, you know, you hit the Yuba key.
Scott: That was the same Yuba key that was used when you registered.
Scott: You're good to
Scott: go.".
Scott: And this is hugely, hugely beneficial.
Scott: Is it perfect?
Scott: No.
Scott: But is it better than passwords?
Scott: A thousand times, yes.
Rym: Let's say you did it without any further, like there's no other passkey or biometric or anything.
Rym: You just use that and no password.
Rym: It's still better than just a password.
Rym: Like, if you're going to have one factor, passkey is objectively superior to a password.
Scott: In a lot of ways, it might even be better than two-factor, right?
Scott: Consider this, right?
Scott: So, first of all, "Oh no, the website's database is
Scott: hacked.".
Scott: Okay, they got a bunch of public keys.
Scott: Useless, right?
Scott: No way they can decrypt, you know, do rainbow tables and find passwords or anything.
Rym: Completely useless.
Rym: Rainbow table?
Rym: No one younger than 40 knows what a rainbow table is.
Scott: I'm just saying, it's completely useless.
Scott: You hacked the database.
Scott: You can never get anyone's password.
Scott: "Oh, someone's using the same password on a bunch of different
Scott: websites.".
Scott: No, they're not, right?
Scott: They're using different keys, right?
Scott: It's all different encryption everywhere, right?
Scott: Behind the scenes, the user doesn't even know that it's happening, right?
Scott: So, none of that's happening.
Scott: "Oh, someone's using a weak
Scott: password.".
Scott: No, everyone's using a really strong private key because they don't have to remember anything.
Scott: So, it's super strong no matter where you go.
Scott: Good luck breaking anybody's anything, right?
Scott: It's like the only way, you know, to basically bust into someone's stuff, you know, "Oh, someone made a fake website to try to phish
Scott: you.".
Scott: What's to phish?
Scott: You can't phish it.
Scott: It's unphishable, right?
Scott: Because you can't, you know, in order for the Windows Hello or whatever to send you, you know, what you would need to impersonate bank.com, it won't do it.
Scott: You'd have to be bank.com.
Scott: It can't be done, right?
Scott: It's like, so phishing, not a problem anymore.
Scott: Basically, all these, you know, people don't remember passwords.
Scott: Well, nothing to remember.
Scott: So, the only problem is, hey, someone gets your phone, right?
Rym: And you didn't listen to our advice in that other episode.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they unlock it and you help them with your face ID.
Scott: Well, now they can log into Apple.
Rym: Or worse, like the most common Discord scan when people say they get hacked is actually just someone's fucking with you.
Rym: And then they just convince you to scan a barcode in your Discord app that logs them in.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: So that can still happen.
Scott: But yeah, it's like we, you know, implementing passkeys everywhere will be a great boon to user security everywhere.
Scott: I plan to implement it.
Rym: Absolutely.
Rym: And I'm excited, honestly, because now we're getting critical mass of big companies with widely deployed infrastructure using this stuff, getting people used to it, and also standardizing in a way to where, like, it's easy for people who might listen to, say, GeekNights to set up a YubiKey or set up like traditional TOTP.
Rym: But moving to passkey like this will, for most people who can't achieve that, just work.
Rym: And then things like 1Password can mostly just disappear.
Rym: Like, we don't need to remember passwords anymore.
Scott: So the major downside, while 1Password might be able to help you, if you use it for your passkeys across platforms, right, because this is the one major tricky part that I think is gonna be a problem, is that, I think it's really gonna be the biggest problem, is that there are roaming authenticators, like YubiKey or 1Password.
Scott: You can use those on a bunch of different devices, right?
Scott: The same YubiKey on your phone, the same YubiKey on your computer, right?
Scott: The same YubiKey on another phone or a tablet or a laptop.
Scott: You just got one YubiKey, use it everywhere, right?
Scott: But if you got, say, if you don't have a YubiKey, let's say you're using your phone, right?
Scott: Well, you might have some system, right, where you could, like, use your phone like it's a YubiKey to unlock on other devices, maybe, if, you know, Apple might help you out with that or something.
Scott: But for the most part, that's not a roaming authenticator.
Scott: That's a platform authenticator, right?
Scott: So if you log in to, say, Google with Windows Hello, and then you try to go and you're on your iPhone, it's like, well, you can't get your Windows Hello on your iPhone.
Rym: But if you're a nerd and you have, like, a YubiKey or something like that, then you can use that kind of thing to facilitate passkeys anywhere.
Scott: Or, like, Apple is using iCloud to synchronize.
Scott: So, like, if you log in with, you know, Face ID on your phone and then you go to your Mac, it's like it'll be synced over.
Scott: But it's like if you're not syncing, let's say some Linux user logs in with their Android phone and then they go to their Linux computer.
Scott: It's like, well, that platform authenticator on their Android phone is not on their Linux computer.
Rym: I've started calling that person.
Scott: And they can't move the private key over.
Scott: It's in a secure whatever.
Scott: So we got to figure something else out, right?
Rym: So I've started calling that person Linux Gjorg in the same way that...
Scott: What's Gjorg?
Rym: So there's an old meme.
Rym: I guess you just never encountered it or you might remember it when I tell it.
Rym: But very briefly, there's the statistic, you know, the fake one that, you know, the average human eats six spiders at night in their lifetime.
Rym: And that's not really true.
Rym: What actually happens is the average person eats zero spiders while they're asleep.
Rym: And then there's this one dude living in Serbia named Spiders Gjorg who eats thousands of spiders every day on purpose.
Scott: OK.
Rym: So it's like the weird outlier.
Scott: Send Spiders Gjorg a Nokia N-Gage, though.
Rym: So two hours Gjorg was what two of our friends call the person who makes an otherwise short game take way too long.
Rym: that normally doesn't happen.
Rym: And Linux Gjorg is the person who has the kind of problem you described.
Scott: OK.
Scott: Well, anyway, pass keys are good.
Scott: I recommend using them.
Rym: The end.
Rym: And I did a poll.
Rym: of the people watching the stream.
Rym: Of the people who responded to the poll, only one of them had any idea what the hell a rainbow table was.
Rym: OK.
Rym: The other four had no idea and Googled it.
Scott: Well, the other four.
Scott: Good.
Scott: You Googled it.
Scott: That's all you need to know.
Scott: How to Google.
Scott: Congrats.
Rym: They haven't been a thing for like 15, 16 years or more.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, it's it's super old, but it's still, you know.
Rym: So let's see.
Rym: And some other news.
Rym: Not going to get too deep into it, but I think you should read this article, especially if you're involved in software architecture or like infrastructure or anything that's sort of deployed at scale.
Rym: If you use Amazon, but anything beyond just having easy to instances, because one, this article is really good and there's a lot to think about.
Rym: But also, it is very easy to skim this article or to just read the extremely click bait headline and come away with the exact wrong conclusion.
Rym: So what I'm going to say is either read this article all the way through or don't read it at all, because if you just skim it, you might you might think some really wrong things.
Scott: Yeah, I think the headline was a bit too simplistic.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And people people read the headline only and the article got widespread, even though it was just another one of those, you know, here's the story of the technology we did.
Scott: Yeah, deals.
Rym: Amazon Prime video team throws AWS serverless under a bus.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: that's not what happened.
Scott: So the broad the summary is that, you know, the serverless architectures that you can use and Amazon Web Services offers a lot of things that count as serverless things like Oz Lambda is really the big.
Rym: That's the one I've used.
Rym: The only one I've used actually.
Scott: They've got like, you know, and there's other things that are somewhat serverless.
Scott: You know, your DynamoDBs and things like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, your SQSQs.
Scott: And basically the idea is that, you know, you architect your software in terms of like what the processes are.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you don't need to worry about like how many CPUs, how much RAM, how much storage, you know, upgrading software, any of that.
Rym: What fucking EC2 instance am I running this on and do I need a bigger one?
Rym: and what Python library is installed in there?
Scott: You don't need to worry about any of that bullshit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if you use other, you know, an example of not serverless would be something like Amazon RDS, where you use, you know, you get a database server.
Scott: It is easy.
Scott: You just one click, they spin up a database server for you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Let's say you get a Postgres on RDS, but you still have to worry about how much storage it has, how much CPU it has, what scale to set it at.
Scott: Do you need more of them?
Scott: Do you have to configure you to configure them?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like the serverless stuff is like you barely you don't really configure it much at all.
Scott: And you're just paid by usage.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like you get some lambdas, you just put your code.
Scott: All you need is the code you want to run and lambdas run your code.
Rym: The end.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So a really trivial example, server website, I click on your link and you've got Apache running in an EC2 instance that responds to that click.
Rym: It does a bunch of stuff on a regular server or you click that link.
Rym: And in a Lambda instance, like one little Lambda is spun up to execute a piece of code that will do something that will serve that website.
Rym: If a million people click on that link, a million Lambdas spin up to handle them all.
Scott: Well, maybe not a million.
Rym: I mean, you might obviously do something more clever.
Rym: They get reused.
Scott: But the point is it's invisible.
Scott: The point is it's invisible to the developer.
Scott: The developer doesn't have to configure a Web server.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the reason this is beneficial is because if you're just starting making a brand new application.
Scott: And you just want to think, you know, is this application even going to succeed?
Scott: Is anyone going to use it?
Scott: You don't know enough about it yet.
Scott: It's a brand new idea or it's you're.
Rym: just you might change it radically halfway through the project.
Scott: It's a lot of work, you know, for the Ignites website.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was a lot of.
Scott: most of the work was like deploying an architecture stuff.
Scott: You can just avoid all that work.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, and you don't have to worry about scaling or anything because it automatically scales.
Scott: If suddenly a million people visit, well, a million Lambdas will happen.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like it's on demand usage.
Scott: So you'll never run out of hard drive space.
Scott: You'll never run out of RAM.
Scott: You never run out of seat.
Scott: You never run anything.
Rym: Instead you pay like 0.00 something cents per action.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You might run out of money, though, if usage gets out of control.
Scott: Because it's you could put limits on it.
Scott: But it's the point is you could, you know, so and it might not always be the fastest, best solution.
Scott: So what you want to do is after you get your application up and running serverless wise, you might notice like, hey, that particular process doesn't get run very often.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's really rare.
Scott: So keeping that on something like a Lambda serverless is a great idea because it spins up for that fraction of a second.
Scott: You need it.
Scott: And the rest of the time you're not paying.
Rym: because if you didn't do it that way, you either have a weak server running that service.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And then if you get overwhelmed, you have some weak, tiny server that's always on that barely gets used and you're losing money on it, even though it's a tiny.
Rym: Or if you want to scale it, you've got a big honking server running that isn't fucking doing anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the problem is, is the opposite.
Scott: Let's say one of your processes is like getting used all the time.
Scott: It is mega intensive.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, well, actually, for that case, you would save money by configuring a server that's always on and can handle all the right things coming in instead of using a serverless thing.
Scott: And that's what happened with the Amazon.
Scott: Think about the difference between parts of our prime video service are like, you know, we could save money, save resources, do a better job by doing the effort to set up some servers for those parts.
Scott: And it'll be faster, cheaper, better, stronger, because really they're both.
Rym: they're they're both solving the same kind of problem, which is usually an orchestration problem, which might be worth a episode.
Scott: I think I think we did some.
Rym: we might have because that's actually a big part of my job right now is orchestrated architect, like how we do orchestration at scale.
Rym: But I guess if you have only ever worked at one company or only ever worked below a certain scale or just haven't like you haven't been in the industry long enough or an industry long enough, you might think that there's this divide between monolithic architecture versus microservice architecture.
Rym: And the reality is any sufficiently complex project or architecture will be a mix of both and figuring out what to architect, how in a broader orchestrated workflow.
Rym: that is the job that pays the most money, because that is a hard problem to solve.
Scott: But the point of this news, you know, people are spreading this news as if it was Amazon saying, oh, all that server stuff is bad.
Scott: Go back to EC2 and setting up servers the old way.
Scott: That's better.
Rym: That's not even what this team did.
Scott: No, not at all.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The news is basically like, hey, you know, sometimes doing it the old way for some services is better and sometimes is not.
Scott: Especially like common sense.
Scott: They were just telling you a specific case, right, in detail of what happened.
Rym: And the case is actually a super common case, the case where you might have a bunch of microservices or a monolith, but you're doing a thing where the data set you have to take action on is big.
Rym: So if you set it up, if you architected the wrong way, you're going to take a big blob of data and pass it around between things a bunch of times.
Rym: And that generally is a bad idea.
Rym: And in my job, we have some things that do it that way because that gives you a lot of power and a lot of flexibility.
Rym: But it costs you a lot of overhead.
Rym: And we have other processes where the orchestration is happening somewhere else.
Rym: But the data blob is sitting somewhere and getting basically fucked with destructively.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You could just have, you know, one machine that holds the data blob in RAM all the time.
Scott: And it's like, woo.
Rym: And especially remember, the problem in this article is QAing live streaming high definition video, like frame by frame.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I think that's enough news.
Rym: So let's get right into things of the day.
Rym: So this is going to be the last time I talk about anything even remotely related to fast Fourier transform for a while.
Rym: But my thing of the day is a video that's kind of old, but I just encountered it.
Rym: But it explains it.
Rym: It connects two dots that I didn't know could be connected.
Rym: And it kind of fucked me up.
Rym: So, you know, the Heisenberg uncertainty principle that we can't know the momentum and like we can't know the location and the momentum of a thing.
Rym: We can either approximately know both or exactly know one and have no fucking idea about the other or some combination.
Rym: But we cannot know both.
Rym: Absolutely.
Rym: That is a as best we can tell, hard fact to the universe.
Rym: And it's also the only reason quantum entanglement and like atoms can exist.
Scott: Do you know where I am or do you know when I am?
Rym: I know approximately where and when you are, but I don't know the specifics because I can't see your whole body right now.
Scott: Maybe I've got like a genie legs.
Rym: Just a wisp.
Rym: Or just a snake down there.
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: Let me action.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So my thing of the day is a video titled The More General Uncertainty Principle.
Rym: And this is what fucked me up.
Rym: Turns out Fourier transformations and the theory of why that works has the same constraints as the Heisenberg uncertainty principle.
Rym: Because the Heisenberg uncertainty principle is basically just a single case of this more fundamental mathematical uncertainty principle.
Rym: And that fucked me up.
Rym: And you got to watch this video.
Rym: You got to be as fucked up as I am about it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It's real good.
Scott: So my thing of the day.
Scott: So you might know Russia not doing great right now.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Bad times there.
Rym: Russia's speedrunning the world of a hundred years ago by invading Europe from the east with genocidal ambitions.
Scott: Anyway, the people who live in Russia are not all bad.
Scott: Some of them are bad, but some of them are not bad.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, imagine.
Rym: Let's say you're the best person in the world and you live in Russia.
Rym: What the fuck are you going to do that doesn't just get you executed or sent to jail?
Rym: Like, you're really stuck.
Scott: Somehow flee, but you got to flee without getting executed.
Rym: And guess what happened?
Rym: So many people have fled Russia that it has actually severely hampered their entire economy.
Scott: OK.
Scott: Well, anyway, the point is, is that there are people in Russia who do not have access to or not easy access to truthful news.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, that's true, I guess everywhere in the world.
Scott: But in Russia, particularly with regarding news of the war that they are that they started.
Scott: The people in Russia, many of them are misinformed, underinformed regarding what's going on.
Rym: And like in the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: there's fake information and fake news and some people choose to read fake news.
Rym: But we're talking here about the people in Russia who see the fake news that their government puts out.
Rym: But they want to know the real truth about what's happening in the world.
Rym: They want.
Scott: So how do you.
Scott: So if there's people in Russia who want to read real news about the war that their country started and they want to know what's really going on.
Scott: I mean, there are plenty of people from other countries who are happy to report it to them.
Scott: I mean, there's people from Russia who are happy to report it to them, but they'll get stopped.
Scott: So but so other countries want to report it to them.
Scott: But how do you get that news to someone who is in Russia?
Scott: Well, you can't like just mail them a newspaper.
Scott: That's not going to work.
Scott: It's like the Russians are going to read the mail and it's going to go right to the house of the person who's going to get in trouble for getting that in the mail.
Scott: So can they just go to CNN dot com?
Scott: No, that shit is blocked on their Internet.
Scott: And I guess they could do fancy Internet tricks to try to get around that.
Scott: But, yeah, can't really just go to a news Web site.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You got to go do some Internet that is not sent censored, not surveilled, et cetera.
Scott: Now, there's a lot of ways you could do this if you were trying to do it on purpose.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But what if you were the news organization?
Scott: You're not the reader.
Scott: You're the publisher.
Scott: You want to get that news in front of eyeballs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Who may not be seeking it out and may not be trying to hide on the Internet.
Scott: You have to find some other way to get those bits of news to Russian people living in Russia.
Scott: And what?
Scott: this news is a Finnish newspaper, I think Finland's main newspaper.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What they did.
Scott: So genius.
Scott: Counter-Strike is popular in Russia.
Rym: It's one of the most popular online video games in Russia.
Scott: In the world.
Scott: But in Russia.
Scott: Yeah, it's really popular there.
Scott: They made a Counter-Strike level.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like Counter-Strike maps aren't censored people in Russia.
Scott: And in the Counter-Strike level, they made a secret room.
Scott: And in the secret room, there's just newspapers to read and they have real news on them.
Scott: So if you play this Counter-Strike map and you go to the secret room, which, of course, everyone wants to hear the secret room.
Scott: They want to go there real bad.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But I want to point out right now, there are very likely many, many more things now just like this that are not getting a bunch of news reporting, because when news report news reports on this stuff, eventually someone figures that out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the point is, as long as you can, you know, the fundamental truth that we've always known is that if you can communicate with another person.
Scott: Then you can communicate with them any information you want without any chance of surveillance, et cetera, if you go through the effort.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's that's just true because encryption is a thing, et cetera.
Scott: But, you know, if all the, you know, if communication can be blocked, well, it doesn't matter.
Rym: This is arguably a highly evolved form of modern steganography.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm saying is that if you just, you know, are they going to block Counter-Strike maps?
Scott: It's like, good luck with that.
Scott: Are they going to surveil all Counter-Strike maps?
Scott: It's like, OK, we can just move on to something else, a steganography of some other form.
Scott: It's like, are you going to block all YouTube videos?
Scott: It's like, you know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What if someone makes a Skyrim mod?
Scott: They probably do block all YouTube.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And in the Skyrim mod, there is a place you can go where there's an arrangement of pots on the ground.
Rym: And if you fly up in the air, the pots tell you a Russian URL that will tell you news.
Rym: Like, how do you even detect stuff like that without active surveillance?
Rym: I guess the key here is this kind of thing cannot be discovered.
Rym: Now, it can be dealt with once it's known or once it's discovered, but it cannot be discovered by the intelligence apparatus of a hostile actor without active surveillance.
Rym: Someone has to find it.
Rym: There's no firewall filter that looks for an arrangement of pots in a Counter-Strike map.
Rym: This is really good stuff.
Rym: And I encourage any of you out there, if you are a nerd and you know how to do stuff like this and you feel bad about what's happening in Ukraine and you want to help, one thing you could do is try to smuggle real news into Russia via Counter-Strike maps.
Scott: Or by any other kind of mechanism.
Rym: Cheeky breeky.
Rym: In the meta moment, Geek Knights Book Club book, The Satanic Versus.
Rym: We didn't do the show on Thursday because I had a work thing.
Rym: Fun fact, the work thing ended up being at The Uncommons downtown.
Rym: Also, fun fact, maybe 20% of the people invited to this thing were nerds with high power levels.
Rym: And everyone else were just like senior people, older than me, my age, who don't really know what the hell's going on.
Scott: How did people fit in the time?
Scott: Isn't it still tiny?
Rym: We rented the whole place out.
Scott: Yeah, but it's a tiny place though, even with the whole thing.
Rym: So they've got that room on the side on the left?
Scott: Yeah, they've always had that room on the side.
Rym: And we were packed in pretty tight.
Scott: Okay, I haven't been there in many years.
Rym: We had also spilled out to the outside.
Scott: It didn't look bigger.
Rym: That place is still hopping too because all night people kept trying to come in, but it was rented out all night by us.
Scott: Yeah, the fact that they're still in business in a Manhattan location tells me that yes, it is a popular business.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I kickstarted them.
Scott: That's how long ago I was done.
Scott: When they didn't exist.
Rym: So next week, Thursday, we will have the show on The Book Club Book.
Rym: So if you haven't started reading it yet, it's not that long a read.
Scott: It's a pretty straightforward, allegorical- I read it in a month because that's how long they.
Scott: let me have the library book.
Rym: Yeah, Magical Reels and Fantasy Book.
Scott: I only had to read like 30 pages a day or something.
Scott: When I started reading it- Maybe not less than 30.
Rym: So when I started reading it, because I remember and it ended up being pretty accurate, my Kindle said, "It'll take you about nine hours to read this book to the
Rym: end.".
Rym: Total.
Rym: Like, total reading time.
Rym: So in the rest of the meta moment, you might have noticed a bunch of old GeekNights YouTube videos have new thumbnails, which has caused them to pop up in people's feeds again because it seems to be how the algorithm works.
Rym: But because I remembered that old GeekNights panels existed, and I looked, and some of those videos predated when I even had the ability to upload a thumbnail.
Rym: Some of them had terrible thumbnails because I was just bad at Photoshop back then.
Scott: Some of them are just pictures of us.
Rym: Yep, some of them are just the automatically generated thumbnail that is just a random picture of us from the panel, possibly blurry.
Rym: So I went back and I started just making nice thumbnails for everything.
Rym: And I'll link to the YouTube thread where they are because I want to get your comments, your thoughts.
Rym: I'm just going to make a thumbnail for every video we got out there.
Rym: And I'm probably going to start making thumbnails for regular old episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: because if you use Adobe Creative Cloud and you don't know this, there is something we've been using for a while, but now we're using it more, Adobe Express.
Scott: I don't even think you need a Creative Cloud to use Adobe Express.
Scott: You don't.
Rym: If you have a Creative Cloud account, you can do more.
Scott: I think it's just free.
Rym: It has a lot of capabilities that are locked unless you pay.
Rym: You might not need those.
Rym: I ended up needing those because I'm doing a little more with this thing than you might.
Rym: But basically, if you have even like a one percent level of basic understanding of the kind of graphic design you like, you don't even have to be good at it.
Rym: If you have the vaguest awareness of what you want something to look like, if you kind of just flail and click in Adobe Express, it'll make something that'll look better than anything you could have made using a regular old application.
Rym: It'll kind of just look good.
Scott: Not only does it provide all these automatic design templates, but it also lets you do lots and lots of very simple but extremely common media operations, like resize an image, convert a video to a different format, crop a video, trim a video.
Rym: Do you want some of your text to be at an angle?
Scott: Turn something into a PDF.
Scott: All this stuff that you commonly do, that if you're not a skilled pro, it lets you do all those simple operations in a couple clicks.
Rym: And you don't have all the tools and all the precision.
Rym: You can't even set all the angles exactly.
Rym: You can't make everything exactly the way you want it.
Rym: But if you know exactly what you want, don't fucking use Adobe Express.
Rym: Go use real applications.
Rym: But if you want to make a professional looking thing in two minutes, it's way good at that.
Rym: I'm just cranking these things out.
Scott: If you have no skills to make a professional looking thing, it's like, you know, if you have no skills, you get real Photoshop, you won't make a professional looking thing in 10 hours, right?
Scott: So that's what Adobe Express is for.
Scott: The new GeekNights website is like, there's still a long list of things to do, but the list of things that are needed to do before launching is now suddenly short, real short.
Scott: So we really just need to sort of take the fine tooth comb and go over the front end bits and then do some polishing.
Scott: And then we could launch it, and then Rym could start making thumbnails and images for everything ever.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Funny, funny.
Rym: Why did Rym suddenly make a pipeline to rapidly crank out GeekNights thumbnails?
Rym: It's almost like everything's aligning.
Scott: But yeah, so that'll, you know, you can go to beta.frontrowcrew.com to see the kind of broken, but current version of it, you know.
Rym: Which actually gives me a vague idea.
Rym: I'm just curious, I'm going to put this out there.
Rym: I'll make a post in the forum and everywhere else too.
Rym: I kind of want to throw a no host party just in Queens, like at a beer garden or something.
Rym: once we launch the site.
Rym: And if anyone shows up, they show up.
Rym: And if no one shows up, I'll just be there with like a few friends.
Rym: Like an open invite party.
Rym: Whenever we do this, whenever the launch happens or sometime thereabouts.
Rym: One other little thing.
Rym: So this is new.
Rym: I have joined a team officially, and I'm going to be competing and running in the New York Marathon on November 5th at the end of this year.
Scott: Rym, don't run marathons, they're not good for you.
Scott: Also Rym runs marathons.
Rym: I'm going to run one marathon because I like running half marathons.
Rym: That's like the perfect distance of Alright, this is recorded.
Scott: So when Rym runs in the 2024 marathon.
Rym: The thing about marathons, they're just too long.
Rym: Two hours of running is about what I like to do.
Rym: Kind of like biking.
Rym: I like biking 70 to 80 miles.
Rym: I can bike 100 to 110 miles, but 70 miles is like the sweet spot of low effort, minimum effort, maximum reward.
Rym: So similarly, a half marathon for me is like the minimum effort, maximum reward.
Rym: But I'm going to run in this once, and I'm doing it for charity because that's one of the only ways to get in.
Rym: So what I'm going to say is I'm going to have a thing.
Rym: I will fund this.
Rym: I don't need people to give money to this thing.
Rym: The money all goes to cancer research at Sloan Kettering.
Rym: And I will match dollar for dollar up to the first $5,000.
Rym: Anything, any of you, donate to this thing once it's up.
Scott: There's a lot of bike rides I want to do that are charity only rides, but I don't want to do any fundraising because the minimum fundraising is always thousands of dollars.
Rym: Oh yeah, I got to raise a ton of money for this, but I'm pretty confident I can.
Scott: What if you fail to raise the money?
Rym: Then I have to make up the difference in my own checkbook.
Scott: What if you just decide not to run?
Scott: Can you just return all the money?
Rym: Then I get kicked out of the race and all the money I raise still goes, but I would get kicked out of the New York Marathon.
Scott: Yeah, right?
Scott: It's not easy.
Rym: Well, I think I can raise $3,500 because I raised a lot of money.
Scott: That's lower than some of the bike ones I've seen.
Scott: I think it's because the bike ones are usually multi-day things that have hotels and have support groups and bike equipment.
Rym: I do work for a very big company that is covering most of what we need to raise.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: The company is covering most of it.
Rym: And is also matching on top of this.
Rym: So basically, this is a way for you out there to amplify your giving, because if you give here, it's going to get matched twice, but I'm going to personally match dollar for dollar up to the first $5,000.
Scott: But couldn't people just donate to something better?
Rym: I mean, cancer research at Sloan Kettering is not the worst thing.
Scott: No, I didn't say it is.
Rym: I mean, granted, you know where that money should be coming from, taxes.
Scott: Yeah, they could donate to Scott's Beach Fund or whatever.
Scott: You know, just think about what you want to do with your money.
Scott: Would you enjoy the world more if you helped cancer get solved and also helped Rym not be on the hook for spending?
Scott: It's like, think about it this way.
Scott: If you don't donate, Rym is going to pay for it entirely out of his own wallet.
Rym: I'm going to make up the difference to $3,500.
Rym: But if you all donate $5,000, I got to put in another $5,000, because I'm matching you.
Scott: So basically, your donation only matters if you collectively donate over $3,500 divided by two, because otherwise Rym is just going to pay that out of his own wallet.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: That is absolutely true.
Rym: I mean, really, this fits within.
Scott: So either donate nothing, so Rym loses a lot of money, or donate a lot.
Rym: And then I'm out a bunch of money that I wouldn't otherwise be out.
Rym: So that's the strategy.
Scott: Whatever you don't want to do is donate exactly $1,750.
Scott: That is the worst possible result.
Rym: I'll tell you what.
Rym: If we hit that number exactly, I'll just put five grand in, like on top.
Scott: Okay, that cancels out any bad scenarios.
Rym: It cancels out the absolute worst case scenario in the middle.
Scott: You want to collectively organize yourselves to donate exactly $1,750.
Rym: So yeah, I'm going to run a marathon.
Rym: This should be fun.
Rym: But the hard mode is, so I signed up to join the team.
Rym: The next day, literally, literally, the next day at work, I learned that I will be in Singapore and Asia for like the two weeks before this.
Rym: So I'm going to speak at a conference, the next morning fly from Singapore to New York, and then the following day after that, run a marathon.
Scott: It's too bad.
Scott: I can't bike the marathon at the same time people are running.
Rym: You can bike it before, but not during.
Scott: Yeah, I've done that several times, but it's like if someone actually knows who's running, it's like I can bike next to them like Lil Mac.
Scott: That's what I want to do.
Rym: I am going to post, at least for the duration of the marathon, I'm going to share my Google location publicly on the internet so everyone can see where I am.
Scott: You can see you take a subway or a taxi like all the other marathon runners.
Rym: Oh, rimran the marathon in an hour and 45 minutes, huh?
Scott: Wait a minute, Scott's still biking and Rym's already at the finish line?
Rym: All right, we should get to the main bit because we've been going on long here.
Scott: You haven't done a show in a while, that's what happens.
Rym: Yeah, actually we've already gone long enough where that could have been a whole show.
Scott: Well, there's not too much to say, but noise.
Rym: Noise from technology almost entirely in the modern era comes from the fans.
Rym: that cool that technology.
Scott: If you're talking about computers.
Rym: Yeah, I'd say most technology.
Rym: Maybe because we don't have a lot of time we restrict this to computer noise.
Scott: I guess so.
Rym: I think that makes sense.
Rym: So computers, in the old days computers made more noise partly because fans were worse.
Scott: Oh no, computers in the olden days made so many fucking noises from all their moving parts, right?
Rym: Oh, you want to go all the way back.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of computers had relays.
Scott: They had hard drives.
Scott: You know how loud a five and a quarter floppy drive is?
Scott: Modems going dee dee dee dee dee dee dee.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's fucking, Jesus Christ, computers were loud AF, right?
Scott: And what saved us from all the loud noises was better motors, better moving parts, right?
Scott: You know, but mostly solid state technology to where we didn't need anything that moves, right?
Scott: We finally replaced the magnetic hard drives.
Scott: At least we still have them for some reasons.
Rym: But magnetic hard drives, like nowadays.
Rym: I have a gigantic NAS like right there.
Rym: And that thing makes a little bit of noise.
Rym: Most of that noise is fans.
Scott: The drives will- I'm upset that the hard drives I bought that were mega discount, they're noisier than the ones I had in there before.
Scott: My NAS used to not bother me, now it bothers me.
Rym: Yeah, I bought really expensive drives and they are, you can only hear them if, frankly, all the computers in the room are off and you listen real hard.
Scott: Yeah, I think, you know.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Or every Friday for about an hour when it's syncing up to Amazon Glacier, it makes a little bit of noise when it's going full steam.
Scott: I don't mind if it's making noise when it's doing something, right?
Scott: These drives, these Seagate Ironwolves, the Western Digitals I had in there before, which were much smaller, they only made noise when there was activity.
Scott: These new ones, they make this clicking noise all the time, even when it's idle.
Scott: Yeah, mine does not- mine doesn't even- And I go online and there's a million threads about it and no one has any answers.
Rym: Yeah, my drives make zero noise when they're not spun up.
Scott: And there are some people who have, you know, threads with answers, but their noise is not my noise.
Rym: In fact, my NAS, most of the times, unless I'm, like, doing a big project or I'm backing stuff up or a script is running, my NAS is idle and the drives are spun down.
Scott: My NAS, I would like it to go to sleep, I tried to enable the sleeping mode, and it just keeps waking the fuck up.
Scott: and I tried to go- Synology has a whole website that's like, here's all the things to check to make sure your NAS doesn't wake up on its own when it doesn't need to.
Scott: It just- I did every single thing on the list, it just keeps waking the fuck up.
Rym: This is like back in RIT when my computer kept fucking waking up because I couldn't disable Wake on LAN and there was a lot of Wake on LAN- I had Wake on LAN disabled and it still wakes up, so that's not it.
Scott: It's something else.
Scott: So- It's something else that's waking it up, I don't know.
Rym: But the thing now, like, nowadays, modern computer, unless you're doing something crazy, you probably don't even need any magnetic disks.
Rym: Or maybe you have, like, one or two giant magnet disks, like, if you don't have external storage, like, that's fine.
Rym: But pretty much the only thing that makes noise in a modern computer, and even then, only if it's a computer that's either crappy or really good, is the cooling.
Rym: Like, the cooling is what makes noise in computers now.
Rym: That era of computers making all those beeps and bloops and clicks and clacks is just gone.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And, frankly, what it comes down to, honestly, if you want your computer to be quiet, you actually care about your computer being quiet.
Rym: You either have to make a relatively low-powered computer, so you can make it passively cooled, like, just no fans, which is totally doable.
Scott: Or your iPhone, iPad.
Rym: Yeah, just give up on a computer altogether and just have tablets, you know, something like that.
Scott: And there are laptops that are, like, this MacBook Air, actually, is passively cooled, but, you know, you get something bigger, MacBook Pro, I'm pretty sure those have some kind of fan.
Rym: And even the Switch has a little fan in it that spins up if it gets too hot.
Scott: Yep, I mean, you know, there's a lot of computers.
Scott: They got a tiny fan, or they got some clever, like, the Mac Mini and the Mac Studio have, like, clever fans that are, you know.
Rym: But, in a computer, if a computer is powerful, like, you're listening to GeekNights, you probably are the kind of person who wants to own a workstation for some reason, then it comes down to buy the better fans, and I think that's it.
Scott: Bigger fans, better fans.
Scott: If there's any situation in which you can get rid of fans and use, say, water or some other, you know, liquid cooling of some kind, right, then that's going to be quieter, right?
Scott: But if you have fans, what you want to do is you want to get bigger fans, right?
Scott: If the fan is bigger, right, that, you know, millimeter-wise, like, larger blades, then that means with less RPMs, it can push more cubic centimeters, feet, whatever you measure volume, right, of air per unit time, right?
Scott: So, with less spins, you can push the same amount of air as a smaller fan with more spins, and spins are what makes the noise.
Scott: A slow, a giant, giant, imagine a giant fan, right, like the size of your whole house that spins real slow, like a windmill, right?
Scott: It's like, that pushes so much air, but the blades are moving so slow, you don't hear anything.
Scott: A tiny little fan to push that much air would have to spin like a jet engine, like, weeee, right?
Scott: And that so much spinning makes a lot of noise, so get bigger fans.
Rym: Yup, that's why my computer now has a 200 millimeter fan in the top, pulling air out.
Rym: That thing makes zero noise.
Rym: I cannot hear it make noise under any circumstances.
Scott: Yeah, also by higher quality fans that have better bearings, you know.
Rym: Which, honestly, right now is Noctua, like...
Scott: Yes, Noctua has been on the top of the fan game brand-wise for quite a while.
Rym: I would not even consider another brand right now unless, like, multiple authorities told me otherwise.
Scott: I mean, if I buy a case, and the case has fans in it already, I'm not gonna replace them unless they're noisy.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So, my case, when I bought it, one of the fans, the smallest fan that was in the back, it's only a 120 millimeter, it was actually noisy enough to where I replaced it with a Noctua.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But it's like, if there are spots in the computer case for extra fans, and there aren't fans there already, or if a fan is noisy and I'm gonna replace it, I'll just buy a Noctua.
Scott: And that's not to say that, like, yeah, maybe I could buy another brand of fan, like a Cooler Master or something, and it's probably just fine.
Scott: But it's like, I know the Noctua is good, so why would I fuck around?
Rym: They're so quiet, but too...
Scott: I have them on my HDPC, I know they're good, there's no reason for me to mess around trying to experiment with other brands when I already found one that's good enough.
Rym: But a second reason to buy a Noctua, and Noctua does not pay us, this is... No.
Rym: No one pays us.
Rym: Does not take sponsorships.
Rym: Though, if anyone wants to send us free stuff, by all means, as long as it's good and expensive.
Scott: Noctua, send me free fans.
Rym: Yeah, I take 'em.
Scott: I'm a big fan.
Rym: The second thing you can do, because the other source of noise from a fan is not just the spinning and the moving of the air, but it's the vibration noise.
Rym: And vibration noise from computers is currently the hardest noise to deal with, because one, it'll transfer along your floor, along your desk, it'll resonate around your room in surprising and difficult to track down ways.
Rym: And two, it is almost impossible to get rid of without making physical changes to your environment.
Rym: The best way to prevent vibration noise from a computer is, one, your computer should be on rubberized feet of some kind.
Rym: Like dampeners of some kind.
Scott: And also where the fan attaches to the computer, a lot of times they'll be like little rubber bits.
Scott: The Noctua's are rubbery in the corners.
Rym: They're rubbery in the corner and they come with screws if you want to screw it in, but they also come with these clever little like long thin rubber bits that actually replace the screw.
Rym: And if you put that in, that dampens the vibration and almost eliminates it as far as I can tell.
Rym: Like I can't measure or hear the vibration noise from any rubber mounted fan.
Scott: Alright, so let's talk about some other parts of a modern computer that still make noise, right?
Scott: We're not going to talk about the speakers, right?
Scott: But we will talk about the beeper, right?
Scott: A lot of computers back in the day, the only audio they had was a beeper unless you bought a sound card.
Rym: The PC speaker is what it's officially called.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Even today, right?
Scott: Even the newest computers, the motherboard still has a little four pin spot.
Scott: You know, even though maybe not all the pins are used, where you can connect a speaker that's like the simplest electronic speaker that can basically only go beep boop.
Rym: It's a spec from 1981.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like it's still.
Scott: that standard is still there today.
Scott: And the only thing it's used for really on a modern computer is to beep when the computer turns on.
Scott: So it's like it's like the single beep, like it confirms the motherboard is working.
Rym: So my current computer did not have one on the motherboard and I did not install one and my computer cannot make noise.
Scott: Really?
Scott: I've never seen a motherboard that didn't have the connector.
Scott: What?
Rym: That's the connector.
Rym: I just don't have a PC speaker.
Scott: Oh, well, yeah, you have to get your own.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't get one.
Rym: I didn't plug it in.
Scott: You also, it can beep sometimes error codes if there's problems with the motherboard, right?
Scott: Because it's like, you know, the computer only has so many outputs, right?
Scott: And they're not expecting you to like connect a serial, you know, terminal to your computer in the year 2023.
Scott: So if the display isn't working, then it needs a way to communicate with you that there's a problem.
Scott: And some motherboards these days, at least fancy good ones, have like a little tiny LCD, like, you know, like seven, you know, sector, whatever you call it.
Rym: Yeah, they can show you.
Rym: they can show you a code that you can type into Google and find someone else looking at your motherboard instruction manual.
Scott: But the beep is the is usually the signal, right?
Scott: If you turn your computer on and it goes beep, beep, beep, it's like, you know, you got a problem.
Scott: You know, as long as it goes beep, then you know, it's good.
Scott: Any other beep bad, right?
Scott: But if there were if you didn't have the speaker, you would miss out on that.
Scott: beep, beep, beep.
Scott: And you might be like, why is my computer not turning on?
Scott: Uh oh.
Scott: And you need to find a PC speaker to figure that out.
Rym: Thankfully, that really unless you buy dodgy brands or get really unlucky, that is not much of a thing anymore with computers.
Scott: It's pretty rare, but it's still a thing, you know, and it's only matters like when you first put together your computer.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And that's something really weird happens, like a hardware failure at some point down the road.
Rym: And fun fact, PC speakers, all they can do is produce a two level square wave.
Scott: Yep, that's it.
Rym: That's all they can do.
Scott: The final part of computers that makes noise, at least in the present day, is keyboards and sometimes mice.
Scott: Those are moving parts.
Scott: And some people like Rym get one that's intentionally clicky, clicky, clicky.
Rym: And I got one that's a little bit clicky, clicky, but not as much as I have one that's less clicky at work and one that's full clicky at home for typing pleasantly.
Scott: Now, on the one hand, the clickiness right is can be very annoying to other people.
Rym: And I will admit straight away, if I could get the exact feel of a Cherry MX Blue, but it was silent, I would pay a lot of money for that.
Scott: I mean, there are ones that are the same feel, but closer.
Rym: They're not if it was silent, but it felt the same.
Scott: Anyway, the point is, is that, you know, it might be annoying to other people, especially like misophonia people and whatnot.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But for the person using the computer, the typing person, you know, I don't know if this is true or not.
Scott: But I feel like, you know, the click is a is, you know, positive feedback.
Scott: I don't get annoyed if I'm typing on a clicky keyboard.
Scott: I get annoyed if someone else is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, you like iPhones.
Scott: They even have virtual clicking noises, you know, for the keyboard that you can disable if you want, because it sort of gives you some feedback like audibly.
Scott: that like, you know, you've pressed it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which I guess is even more helpful on the iPhone keyboard.
Scott: You can't really feel it, though they do have some haptic features as well.
Scott: And mice also click when you click the buttons or make noises when you scroll the wheel.
Scott: Thankfully, the ball is gone.
Scott: That doesn't make noise.
Scott: But those noises, how useful are they?
Scott: They're pretty quiet.
Scott: No, I don't.
Scott: You know, but they're still there.
Scott: There's still some sort of positive feedback noise that wouldn't be the same, really.
Scott: If like, you know, you like imagine if your keyboard was silent, like in your headphones, it was like the iPhone where it was like simulating keyboard noises.
Rym: I guess there is one last worthwhile thing to talk about.
Rym: If it is possible to make computers like even extremely powerful computers effectively nearly silent, why are server rooms so loud?
Rym: And the answer is one, noise is not like other than that weird edge case of magnetic drives actually do perform worse when it is loud around them.
Rym: Like that's a thing.
Rym: But magnetic drives are increasingly not used in data centers, or at least if they are, they're used in separate areas where the disks are.
Rym: because data centers have evolved a lot since the last time any of us talked about them.
Rym: But two, because other than that, like no one cares about the noise.
Rym: So you want what you care about is power usage, form factor.
Rym: The fact that they're so loud is kind of is part of just the trade off of all the other things that are way more important in a data center.
Rym: But it mostly comes down to noise.
Scott: The noise is only a problem if there are humans there to hear it and be bothered by it.
Scott: Now, there could be other problems with the noise.
Scott: Maybe you've put your computer in some animal habitat.
Scott: It's bothering the animals or I mean, I used to work in the vibrations from the noise or disturbing a fault and causing earthquakes.
Rym: I had to wear ear protection when I went into the data center and you literally could not talk to a human being in there.
Rym: It was impossible even next to someone to have a conversation without screaming at each other.
Rym: So that did present a challenging work environment.
Rym: Like if we're in there and something like we're failing to solve a problem, we might have to leave the data center and go to a quiet room to discuss what we're going to do and then go back into the data center and try to execute on what we discussed.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, but that's not.
Scott: how often is that happening, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, when computers are not operating near people to be annoyed by them, the noise doesn't matter.
Scott: And that goes back to me complaining about my NAS, right?
Scott: Making noise now with these different hard drives in it.
Scott: A lot of the threads, people are just like, who cares?
Scott: Shove your NAS in a closet.
Scott: It won't matter.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Then you can't hear it.
Scott: That is the solution.
Scott: I really wish I could.
Scott: I wish I could.
Scott: Right?
Scott: The layout of my tiny apartment and where the network cables are.
Scott: I can't do that.
Rym: So yeah, if I could get away with it, I'd love to mount my computer in its own cool environment or something, but I ain't got time for that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like if I had a house, I just put the NAS in the basement.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But the other reason they're like this is very simple.
Rym: A lot of servers are one or two.
Rym: you like they're small, they're compact.
Rym: So they have to move a terrifying volume of air through themselves for cooling.
Rym: So they have like, if you've ever opened a 1U server that has fans in it, they have these little like one inch diameter fans.
Rym: And sometimes you have like five of them in a row, like in serial.
Rym: They whine like a demon being murdered.
Scott: If you go on Google image search and just type like 1U server inside, you can see like the two, there'll be like some tiny fans in the back.
Scott: And a lot of times like they'll stack the fans up on top of each other.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Like in a row or in series.
Rym: So my advice to you, because when I was young, I got a 1U server once from work and I actually ended up scrapping it.
Rym: A lot of nerds think it'd be really cool to have like a rack in your basement, like a quarter rack to stick your switch in.
Rym: If you get an old server to run some services, my advice to you is never do it.
Rym: Because if you live in a house, even a big house that has a basement and you put it in a basement.
Rym: Rack mounted servers, because of the kinds of fans they use, they don't make the lower pitch noise that you think computers make.
Rym: They make very high pitch noises.
Rym: And I will tell you now, you could be on the second story of your house and you have a nerd rack in a closet in your basement.
Rym: And you will hear that fucking rack on the second story of your house.
Rym: You will not be able to unhear it.
Rym: There is no way to dampen that noise in a house that is reasonable, feasible, and plausible to execute on.
Scott: I'm looking at a picture.
Scott: This is the most impressive one so far.
Scott: The Dell PowerEdge R620.
Scott: It's 8x2.5" single processor 1U server, right?
Scott: And the fans are basically the front of the server, right?
Scott: With all the, you know, the front where you can insert all the drive.
Scott: Oh, look at those little fans!
Scott: Right, and then there are seven sets of fans.
Scott: Each set has two fans, one in front of the other, right?
Scott: And they're basically separating the front of the case from the back of the case.
Scott: They're blowing straight across their, I guess, parallel with the RAM sticks.
Scott: So basically all the, you know, the RAM sticks like fins.
Rym: Also I love that this server, look at how many fucking DIMMs there are there.
Scott: Right, it's like a shit ton of RAM sticks and all these fans just lined up and like they're double fans, one in front of the other.
Scott: The front fan is actually like a big thick one and then a thinner one.
Scott: And then they're all blowing straight across.
Scott: It's like that thing is loud.
Scott: You can just tell looking at it how loud that is.
Rym: I can hear it just looking at it.
Rym: Not only are the fans loud, the noise of the air itself moving will be loud because it's moving through such a complex and constricted space.
Rym: And then you've got a rack, you've got like 20 of these things stacked end over end.
Rym: So 20 times 7 times 2 screaming fans in one rack, not counting the power supplies at the top or the switches and the routers that are even louder.
Rym: Yeah, if you've never worked in a data center, don't.
Scott: And you know, if noises don't bother you, that's great.
Scott: And if they do bother you, make your computer quieter or put it somewhere else.
Rym: I put quiet above performance very pointedly my entire life and I will continue to do so.
Scott: I mean, like I said before, I can tolerate noise as long as the noise is accompanying a purpose.
Scott: Like if I start playing a game.
Rym: Oh yeah, if I spin up like Overwatch or something and then like my video card starts going like that's fine.
Scott: If I start working my computer and the GPU goes whoosh, then it's like, ah, OK, that's fine.
Scott: But if it's doing that all the time, that's not fine.
Rym: Got an HDPC that's well, there is one problem.
Rym: HDPC totally quiet when you're not using it.
Rym: You watch a 4K movie and all the fans spin up and it makes noise.
Rym: That's no bueno.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Link Iggi, Jirad Lilly, Tenebrae Case, Karen Makes Music, Chris Adad, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Penny Rymer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horrell and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names because they were giving an appropriate amount of money, which is like a dollar.
Rym: But yeah, remember the Patreon is mostly here, at least for the immediate future, as a nice backup to GeekNights because it is free.
Rym: I still make all the posts free.
Rym: But stay tuned for some Patreon specific content that will be appearing in the near future.
Rym: But we'll talk about that when it actually happens because we got to get the website live first.
Rym: But for now, tonight, I simply leave you.