Scott: It's Wednesday, April 23rd.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we, I guess theoretically, primarily talk about Maurice the Jojo.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, we totally blew off last night's show.
Scott: Well, you know how, you know, the stuff that, you know, at work, there are some things, you know, you're just working on them.
Scott: And there are some other things where it's like, okay, you're just working on them, but there's a deadline.
Scott: And there's some other things.
Scott: you could work on it or not.
Scott: And then occasionally something will happen and you have to work on it right now.
Scott: Those things never happen unless you're about to leave.
Scott: They never happen as soon as you walk in in the morning.
Rym: For three days in a row, I'll say this, I've barely escaped, but every day I leave work pretty much at four to catch the 4.10 train.
Rym: It's so perfect.
Rym: But every day for the last three days, I'll be sitting there and it's like, all right, it's 3.58.
Rym: Putting my laptop away, getting ready to say, all right, guys, I'll see you tomorrow.
Rym: 3.59, someone walks over.
Rym: Hey, Rym, can you look at this real quick?
Rym: This doesn't look right.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: Type, type, type, type, type, type.
Rym: Look good, look good, fine.
Rym: Bye.
Rym: Run out the door.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: There needs to be sort of like a time, like if you come after, you could come to me after 3.30.
Scott: No, it doesn't matter what it is.
Scott: It could be the end of the company.
Scott: I'm not, forget about it.
Rym: You know what's scary?
Rym: I'll say this.
Scott: It needs to be like a handoff period.
Rym: I actually like my company enough to where I would probably, if it was an emergency, stick around.
Scott: Well, my policy in my work is if it's something that is the cause of me, I will stay there and fix it.
Scott: If it's really important and you know we're losing money or whatever.
Rym: I would also stay if I can fix it without, like if I wouldn't be able to do any better than anyone else at fixing it, then I probably wouldn't stay.
Rym: But if it's something I could do or I know or I don't think anyone else could do it quickly, I would just do it.
Scott: Yeah, it really depends on the thing, but I make a judgment call.
Scott: If I feel responsible for it, I'll stay and do it.
Scott: And if I don't, then I'll be like, all right, you take care of it.
Scott: Bye.
Rym: Yeah, at least with my work, we have this overlap.
Rym: Like I work seven to four and this other guy works like 9.30 to 6.30.
Rym: So we kind of overlap there.
Rym: So if there's a big problem, he can usually cover it at the end of the day.
Rym: And kind of the payback for that is that I got to be there in the morning when other things go wrong.
Scott: See, we don't have things go wrong in the morning.
Rym: It's more that I got to show up every morning at the crack as dawn and make sure everything's going to be OK.
Rym: I turn on the lights.
Rym: I pick up the mail.
Rym: I do all that stuff, too.
Rym: It's fun.
Scott: My computers give it here tomorrow.
Scott: I'm actually most of it's here now, except for the case, the CPU and the hard drives.
Scott: Sort of important parts.
Rym: But actually, the reason we didn't do a show last night was Scott had one of those.
Rym: All right, look at this.
Rym: Fix it things.
Rym: But he text messaged me while I'm on the train.
Rym: It's like, I'm going to be late.
Rym: But he didn't say how late.
Rym: So I had a choice to make.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Do I query him to find out how late he will be and make plans accordingly to do the show?
Rym: Or do I assume he's not coming home, totally go out to dinner with Emily and then hang out?
Rym: So Scott finally did get home.
Scott: You knew that if I'm late, it's going to be at least one train, which is already enough time to eat dinner and still do a show.
Rym: Yeah, but if it was that, you probably wouldn't have even told me.
Rym: Oh, I was looking for an excuse to not do the show because it's been.
Scott: You're always like every day you're looking for an excuse to not do the show.
Rym: Not today.
Scott: It's only because you feel bad about not doing the show yesterday.
Scott: You had a choice of being here and doing the show.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or going outside and going, ah, would you sit here, do the show?
Scott: Would you go outside?
Rym: See, the thing is, I do have a choice.
Scott: You do.
Scott: And I'm here.
Scott: No, but you feel obligated despite it.
Scott: You know, they're not actually being a real obligation.
Scott: Yeah, you have it created for yourself a duty.
Rym: I think you forget that I get home like an hour before you.
Rym: So I got home and then I went for this crazy long run and then I did all this other stuff outside.
Rym: So I'm kind of sated right now.
Scott: Even still.
Rym: Plus, I got the window open right there despite all the noise going on out there.
Scott: Anyway, what else we got going on?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Normally we talk about anime news or comic news, but is there any anime news or comic news that we care about?
Scott: Well, I mean, there was this huge New York comic convention.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Whole weekend.
Scott: And there's a lot of news from it.
Scott: But really, I don't think any of it is news worthy.
Scott: It's mostly we license this, we announce that, and it's all just kind of bled.
Scott: There's nothing like, oh man, something to discuss or something awesome.
Scott: It's mostly just...
Rym: What could possibly... It'd have to be something crazy like, oh, by the way, they're making another Ghost in the Shell movie.
Rym: Or like, oh, by the way, I don't know, something crazy.
Scott: I mean, they could announce things that are actual news.
Scott: Something interesting.
Rym: Well, what's your line, though?
Rym: I mean, there was interesting news.
Rym: It's just it's not news that, while it may be interesting, there's not much for us to comment on.
Scott: And it's not interesting if there's nothing for us to comment on.
Rym: Yeah, there is.
Rym: Because it's partly that we're not the first line of news.
Rym: If you want to just find out what happened, like just the objective facts, just go read the Anime News Network.
Rym: They'll tell you everything that got licensed and everything.
Scott: At least anime wise.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And comic wise, you can find all that news.
Rym: So we're not going to just say news that happens unless we have something personal to say about it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And none of the news that happened.
Scott: It was all just announcements of new things and boring shit like that.
Scott: So there's no thing to discuss except for what happened.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, like I'm saying, that news wasn't interesting.
Scott: Hence, it's not interesting news.
Rym: Well, not to us personally.
Rym: A lot of those shows people really cared about.
Scott: I say if there's nothing to discuss...
Rym: Alright, can you name one piece of these newses?
Rym: Because I think you're just saying.
Scott: There's that Stanley Manga thingy.
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That wasn't announced at the Comic Con.
Rym: That was announced a long time ago.
Scott: No, but it's like, you know, they show off stuff.
Rym: But there was no news about it.
Rym: It was just, hey, just in case you forgot that thing's still coming.
Rym: Had they announced it at the New York Comic Con?
Scott: It was effectively like the, you know, they had said, you know, they basically said Stanley Ultimo.
Scott: And then at the convention, like, okay, here it is.
Scott: Here's the pictures.
Scott: Here's all the more information, you know.
Rym: But a lot of that information was already available.
Scott: Oh, not really.
Scott: And then, you know, it's like there were new trailers for TV shows and movies.
Scott: And there's all sorts of news about new comics coming out from all the comic companies.
Scott: We're making this.
Scott: We're making that.
Scott: We're making more graphic novels.
Scott: We're making more Spidermans.
Scott: You know, all that kind of bullshit.
Rym: But had they actually announced the Ultimo thing, I would have had something to say.
Rym: Again, I still have something to say because we never covered it.
Rym: I'll say this about Ultimo.
Rym: They're not selling or marketing or promoting Ultimo in any way.
Rym: They are promoting, marketing, and selling Stan Lee's Ultimo.
Rym: You look at this poster they had up and it was like, Stan Lee and the biggest letters they could fit.
Rym: And a big picture of his face.
Rym: And then much smaller than that, Ultimo coming soon.
Rym: And then a picture of something from Ultimo.
Rym: Obviously, this is gonna be some generic comic that is being sold primarily on the name Stan Lee.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: I predict not so good.
Scott: What do you predict?
Rym: I think it's gonna be average.
Rym: I don't think it'll be bad.
Rym: I don't think it'll be good.
Rym: I think it'll be an average comic.
Scott: Well, I'm not buying it.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: We gotta review it.
Scott: No, we don't.
Rym: Yeah, we do.
Scott: Well, then you can go buy it.
Rym: I'll acquire it somehow.
Scott: Well, go to the comic book store next to the train station and buy it.
Rym: No, someone will send it to me, I'm sure.
Scott: I'm sure.
Scott: Stan Lee's gonna send it to you?
Rym: Not Stan Lee, but someone else will.
Scott: Alright, we'll see about that.
Rym: I mean, I've gotten so many crappy comics in the mail.
Rym: I figure someday someone other than Vertical is gonna send us something good.
Scott: Yeah, well, I'm not buying it.
Rym: Actually, it's scary.
Rym: I mean, instead of doing news, we can talk a little bit about the New York Comic-Con.
Rym: Unlike other conventions, we're not gonna dedicate an entire show to the New York Comic-Con.
Rym: Because there's not nearly as much to say about it as I would have to say after going to say Otakon or Katsu-Con.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But basically, New York Comic-Con, better than the pre- it's the third year, I think, yes.
Scott: Yes, the third year of this con.
Scott: And it was superior to the previous years.
Scott: Unlike the first year, you could get in.
Scott: Unlike the second year, there was more than one entrance.
Scott: And there were wider aisles.
Scott: So, it's actually, you know, the con is pretty much just one big room.
Scott: And it's got, you know, dealing in one corner.
Scott: It's got exhibitors in most of the space.
Scott: It's got a big-ass artist alley in the other corner.
Scott: And then there's a little stage with a bunch of chairs.
Scott: And they sort of do random shit.
Scott: that's just fucked up.
Rym: I have things to say about that.
Scott: And then behind the stage, hidden in the corner, is like a little podcast area.
Scott: And it's just this giant, you know, it's like, I say, two-thirds of the main Javits room, right?
Scott: And the aisles were even on, you know, we didn't go Saturday.
Scott: But even on crowded Friday, you could sort of, at least as long as you weren't in the artist's alley, there was room to walk around.
Scott: Sunday was nice and light, just kind of ahhh.
Scott: And just like the year before, you go there, you walk around the big room, you see what there is to see, and there's no reason to hang around.
Scott: Because most of the panels are pretty boring, except there was one panel that was Doug Rushkoff and Scott McCloud, but it was really early on Friday when I was not able to go at like 1 o'clock p.m There
Rym: was also ICV2, which I didn't, if I'd taken the day off work, which I kind of wanted to because you get cocktails and stuff, and it looks like it's a pretty fun thing for a press person, but I wasn't going to take Thursday off of work for that.
Scott: No, no, I wasn't.
Rym: But pretty much, I do want to point out one thing.
Rym: We had several listeners point out that this was like their first convention, and they seem to have a good time, but I do want to say that the New York Comic-Con is very typical of any sort of comic convention, but pretty much almost not in any way similar to an average anime convention.
Scott: Well, see, I'm actually starting to realize, right?
Scott: It doesn't have much to do with the subject matter of the convention.
Scott: It has to do with whether it's fan-run or for-profit.
Scott: There are for-profit anime cons besides the New York Anime Festival, and they're mostly just like a big, boring dealer's room.
Rym: But not really to the extent of this because it seems like comic conventions in general, commercial or I don't know how many fan-run ones there are.
Rym: I'm sure there's some.
Rym: But they're so focused on the buying and the selling and that sort of thing that the biggest complaint...
Scott: It is true that fan-run comic conventions are more focused on the buying, are more like for-profit other conventions.
Rym: But the biggest complaint, the only main complaint I had about the New York Comic-Con was that everywhere I walked, unlike any other conventions I go to, and I remember this happened at Philly Wizard World too, people kept ramming into me.
Rym: Now, there's crowds at anime conventions.
Scott: There were bigger aisles this year, despite there being, you know, they had a lot more stuff, but they had a lot more space, and the aisles were adequately wide.
Rym: Yeah, but what I'm saying is that, you know, I was walking around this convention, like, I mean, Otakon has gigantic crowds and crazy crowds, and you can't walk anywhere, and Katsuokon's like that, but at all those anime conventions, I don't really get bumped into a lot.
Rym: You just, like, everyone is kind of close together, but everyone's walking and nice orderly and da-da-da-da-da, and people are sitting in the sides, but at this convention and at Philly Wizard World and at the previous New York Comic Convention, I was rammed into by people, like, kind of hard a lot, constantly.
Scott: No one rammed me that hard.
Scott: If someone did ram me that hard, I'd probably push them over.
Rym: Well, no, you're really missing the point, not like ram you, like, to the point that they would knock you over, it would hurt, but running into me at a speed that was well above what is acceptable, and people were, like, swinging bags into me and onto other people, and I saw other people, the same thing.
Rym: It's like everyone was kind of bumping into each other and bumping into tables and knocking stuff over.
Scott: Well, I mean, you have a giant room, right, and despite wide enough aisles, you've got a shit ton of people in this room.
Scott: Yeah, but what I'm trying to point out is that there are things in every possible direction grabbing people's attention.
Rym: What I'm trying to point out is that this doesn't happen at the dealer's rooms at anime cons I go to that are just as crowded, if not more so.
Scott: Well, the dealer's room at an anime con isn't the whole con.
Scott: It's one small part of the con, and it has smaller aisles, but it doesn't matter that it has smaller aisles because a smaller percentage of the con is in there at any one time, and there's also a lot less, like, attention-grabbing in different directions.
Scott: It's straight aisles.
Scott: Did you say that at all?
Rym: It was straight aisles here, too, and there's the same thing.
Scott: Not really.
Rym: Yeah, they were straight aisles.
Scott: The layout of the room wasn't a perfect grid, you know, like...
Rym: There were a couple of minor variations.
Rym: It's pretty much exactly the same as an anime con dealer's room.
Scott: Eh, not really.
Rym: The only difference, I think, because the dealer's room at Otakon is actually a lot more crowded than this place at any given moment.
Rym: I think the difference is that anime cons, because they have these other places that aren't dealer's rooms, a lot of times at an anime con, you see people walking around who, they've already looked at stuff, and now they're just kind of chilling, and they're either looking for somewhere to sit down and chill, or they're kind of walking slowly off somewhere to chill in a nice, quiet area and hang out, and they're not just doing anything in particular, but at comic cons, there really aren't places to chill so much.
Scott: The lobby?
Rym: The lobby is it, and that's pretty far away from everything else.
Rym: You gotta walk all the way out.
Scott: Well, they had the beanbag area, and they had all the chairs by the stage.
Rym: Yeah, those couple of areas on the far ends, but it seems like most people who were walking around weren't even looking at anything.
Rym: They were just kind of walking slow, chilling, but because it's all just one big dealer's room, they were just kind of walking, chilling, in the middle of where everyone else was walking, trying to go somewhere.
Rym: But even then, I don't understand why so many people bumped into me.
Scott: Yeah, I don't get it.
Rym: Like, it was really, really apparent that people were bumping into me a lot more than any other public place I've ever been.
Scott: Alright, well, I mean, there was some bumping going on, but I guess I didn't notice it as much as you did.
Rym: It was just, well, you were ramming into me, too.
Scott: Yeah, well, to the convention's credit, actually, they did have a whole area that we were able to find, even though it was far away from everything else, that had a whole bunch of panels, like 200-plus panels.
Scott: The thing was, is except for a very small handful of the panels, I was completely not interested in any of them.
Rym: Well, that's just, Scott, I was actually interested in quite a few of the panels.
Scott: Well, I think most of the panels, though, were just so-and-so company, so-and-so other company.
Scott: Not a lot of it was like, "Ooh, something actually
Scott: interesting.".
Rym: Like what?
Rym: What would be interesting?
Scott: Well, like that one panel I couldn't get to on Friday at one.
Rym: Okay, so what else would be interesting?
Rym: You were real vague there.
Scott: People actually discussing something, as opposed to just advertising.
Rym: A lot of those panels didn't look like they were just advertising.
Rym: I mean, a lot of them did.
Scott: I think the vast majority of them were just some company advertising their new thing.
Rym: Okay, well, that's your opinion.
Scott: Go look at the list of panels.
Scott: You'll see.
Rym: Yeah, and there were a bunch I wanted to go to.
Rym: Actually, I was really interested in checking out that black panel, but Scott really didn't want to go, so we left.
Scott: Yeah, I wasn't.
Scott: What would I want to go to the black panel for?
Rym: I wanted to see what they had to say.
Rym: There was a lot of people lined up.
Rym: It looked interesting.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't look too interesting to me.
Rym: Okay, well, nothing ever looks interesting to you.
Scott: But even so, okay, so that's two panels out of 200-plus.
Rym: Actually, I really wanted to go to the Avatar panel, too.
Scott: That's a company selling something panel.
Rym: Well, it was something that I really want, and they were showing things that hadn't been seen before.
Rym: I failed to get an interview with those people, partly because everyone failed to get interviews with those people, because as far as I could tell, pretty much every single member of the press wanted an interview with anyone associated with Avatar, and as a result, no one really got interviews.
Rym: In fact, the two creators, from what I hear, actually said, "Ah, never mind," and just kind of flew out early.
Scott: Even so, right, that's three out of 200-plus.
Scott: That's pretty sad.
Rym: Well, I'm saying, of the time I was there, I can think of a couple more.
Rym: They were all told maybe five or six panels that I probably would have wanted to go to, which is-- Out of 200 is really sad.
Scott: Not necessarily.
Scott: I mean, at an anime convention.
Scott: Besides, not every anime convention.
Rym: Not interesting to you or maybe to me, but there were panels where people-- If you're into these comics, there were people who have a lot to do with these comics.
Scott: I guess that is true, is that-- That is true.
Rym: I don't understand why you're so down on these panels.
Scott: Because every time I went down there to look at the panel schedules, there's absolutely nothing I wanted to go to.
Rym: Oh, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Rym: Every time.
Rym: You went down there once for like five minutes.
Scott: I went down there three times.
Rym: You went down there once for like five minutes with me.
Rym: You walked past every time.
Rym: Literally, you walked in, you're like, "Well, that sucks, that sucks, that sucks, let's
Rym: leave.".
Scott: But it wasn't just the panel that was currently in there that sucked.
Scott: I looked at the entire schedule for the day, and I said, "Nothing in this room at all.
Scott: Nothing in this room at
Scott: all.".
Rym: Yeah, and meanwhile, I actually wanted to stay for some, but Scott was getting impatient.
Scott: What did you want to stay for?
Rym: The Black Panel, among other things.
Rym: And some of the ones I was walking by.
Rym: There were pretty big crowds, and they were doing Q&A.
Rym: Someone might ask an interesting question.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Like in what, the DC panel?
Rym: The DC panel that you refused to stay at for more than two minutes, so we only got to hear one question.
Scott: It was just fan--.
Scott: I heard like three questions that were all fanboys.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They were all fanboys asking stupid shit about like, "Oh, why didn't Superman do this?
Scott: Why didn't Green Lantern do
Scott: that?".
Rym: There wasn't a single question like that.
Scott: Yeah, there were.
Rym: Actually, no.
Rym: The only question we saw was, someone asked one question about like when a comic's coming out, and then the next question was the moderator actually asking the audience if any of them had like stopped reading comics, and then something got them to read comics again.
Rym: And they were all telling like, "Well, I stopped reading when blah, like this
Rym: year.".
Rym: Or like, "When these superheroes got all weird, I didn't understand them anymore, and I never started reading
Rym: again.".
Rym: Or, "I started reading again because they reset
Rym: this.".
Rym: Or, you know, "I just randomly picked up a comic, and actually it was kind of interesting, but Scott was like, "Eh, let's go, let's
Rym: go.".
Scott: It wasn't interesting because they were all talking about DC Universe BS, not comics as a whole BS.
Rym: So it's not interesting to you?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What if you like DC?
Scott: No, I don't like any of that shit.
Rym: I like how you want to be.
Rym: so, before the con, you're like, "Man, we got to be so objective with press.
Rym: We got to be like, we got to cover things and be objective and serious
Rym: business.".
Rym: And all you did was walk around the con loudly proclaiming that everything sucked.
Scott: Yeah, well, it's kind of hard.
Scott: I realized I sort of had to have a press hat and a fan hat.
Rym: But you never put on a press hat.
Rym: Even when you were trying to film stuff.
Rym: There's these Star Wars people that were fighting on stage.
Rym: Scott was loudly saying, pretty much everyone in earshot would hear him going, "Wow, this is lame.
Rym: Wow, these guys suck.
Rym: Wow, this is so
Rym: stupid.".
Rym: Everyone was kind of turning around and looking at him like, "Seriously, what's your
Rym: problem?".
Scott: It was pretty lame though, you got to admit.
Rym: While it was pretty lame, I thought you wanted to be objective press.
Scott: I was wearing my fan hat at the time.
Rym: I don't think you own a press hat.
Scott: I got to get one.
Scott: I don't think you own one.
Scott: It's very easy.
Scott: It's one thing to know what to do.
Scott: It's much harder to actually do what you know what to do.
Scott: Technically, I academically can get a book that says, "Aha, this is how to draw a beautiful
Scott: picture."
Scott: And it's another thing to actually draw a beautiful picture.
Rym: But in regards to the Star Wars thing, while I don't quite have the venom that I guess Scott had for these people.
Scott: I don't have venom.
Scott: I just think it's really lame and it's kind of sad watching these people sort of act like they're legitimate and cool and worthy of respect.
Scott: When they're just a bunch of like really sad adults acting like little children.
Rym: But once, Scott, they were like teenagers, all of them.
Scott: No, that guy was like 20-something for sure.
Rym: No, he definitely wasn't.
Scott: No, definitely was.
Rym: And most of the people on stage were clearly in high school.
Scott: No, that's how it looked like to me.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Why don't we go find out exactly how old those people were.
Scott: They were definitely most of them in their 20s.
Scott: If not 30-some of them.
Rym: I disagree with you pretty much 100%.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You've got your film.
Rym: Go pull the film out and put it on YouTube or something.
Scott: It's a really bad film because I suck at the camera.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I have the same problem with the video camera that I have with the photo camera in that I carry it and I want to video things but I just, I don't.
Rym: Well, I kept telling you two and you kept putting the camera away.
Rym: I'd be like, "Scott, film
Rym: this.".
Rym: You put the camera away.
Rym: By the time he fumbles it out, the thing's over.
Rym: And then he immediately puts the camera back away.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I had, well, because carrying it, first of all, is very annoying.
Rym: Dude, I had the Marantz and the microphone and all that business.
Scott: That's easier to carry.
Scott: Not really.
Scott: Because you don't, yeah it is.
Rym: It's actually heavier than that camera.
Scott: It's not about the weight.
Rym: The microphone itself is heavier than the camera.
Rym: I had that big XLR cable.
Rym: Thing was jangling around, hit me in the thigh.
Rym: I had to keep fiddling with the radio and I was-.
Scott: The point is that if I'm using the camera, I have to like have my hand in front of my face and I can't like do anything else.
Scott: I can't like talk or look around or anything.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Like you can interview someone and look around and walk.
Rym: Not really.
Rym: I pretty much have to stare constantly at the meters and keep adjusting the levels.
Scott: Nah, it's not necessary.
Rym: Actually it's very necessary.
Rym: I've gotten a lot better at that.
Rym: That's why the short interview clip I have with the International Office of French Publishers, I think, publications.
Rym: I forget exactly.
Rym: It sounds really good, but all the interviews I did at every con before sounds awful.
Scott: Anyway, this isn't helping people, but basically if you like comics at all, right, and you're near New York, if you're far away, but if you're near enough to New York, it's probably worth your time to go to the New York Comic Con one of the days.
Scott: I suggest either Friday night or Sunday.
Scott: Saturday's probably not worth it.
Scott: And just go around, look at all the stuff, and then go home.
Scott: And that's worth it.
Scott: But otherwise, it's really not so much worth it.
Rym: I can say one thing.
Rym: On Friday I saw probably the best Avatar cosplayers I've ever seen.
Rym: It was one of those groups of people where obviously they got all their friends who kind of already look like characters.
Rym: We have a friend who looks exactly like a character from Bleach.
Rym: So if she cosplays as that character, it looks like this crazy amazing cosplay.
Rym: But all of these kids looked exactly like the people in Avatar.
Rym: Furthermore, they dressed up in Fire Nation, which is kind of like what they're wearing in the third season, and it was totally awesome.
Rym: I talked to them briefly.
Rym: I didn't give them a flyer because I didn't want to reach into my bag, but if you guys somehow find GeekNights, you guys were totally awesome.
Rym: Especially whoever it was who was in that gigantic Appa costume.
Scott: I bet you if you hadn't suddenly become like an Avatar fanboy, you wouldn't even notice them.
Rym: Suddenly become.
Rym: I've wanted, pretty much as long as I've known about Avatar, I've known it was good.
Rym: And now that I've actually watched it, I just confirmed that it was as good as I thought it was.
Rym: In fact, a little better than I expected.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, I don't know what it is, why you hate Avatar.
Scott: I don't hate Avatar.
Scott: It's just from what I've seen, it's.
Rym: Which is nothing.
Scott: I've seen enough.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It really seems like a kid's show that a lot of people like.
Scott: And while I'm not going to pass a judgment on it until actually seeing it.
Rym: But what have you seen?
Rym: You walked past the TV.
Scott: I have no expectation for it.
Scott: And I have a lot of things above it in the queue.
Scott: And I have no reason to have a high expectation of it.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Despite the fact, you see, because you poo-pooed like this book you're reading now.
Rym: I didn't poo-poo it.
Scott: No, you very clearly poo-pooed it.
Scott: I didn't poo-poo.
Scott: I passed no judgment.
Scott: And I said, I'll get to it eventually.
Scott: And eventually, I got to it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So can I, all right.
Rym: Well, I guess you hated the comic convention at least.
Scott: I didn't hate it.
Rym: You hated all the panels and everything on stage.
Scott: No, it was --.
Rym: Well, you already said you didn't like all the panels.
Rym: No, the panels -- And everything on that stage.
Scott: The handful of panels that I wanted to go to, I couldn't go to.
Scott: For having 200 panels, a very small percentage of them were non-advertising panels.
Scott: But no matter what, if you're interested in something geeky, there probably were, you know, like five panels there for you at least, because they were just such a quantity.
Scott: You'll be interested in at least a handful of them.
Scott: But when is that handful going to be scheduled?
Scott: You know, you'd have to figure out, you know, look at the schedule ahead of time and go at that, you know, when they were going to be.
Scott: And usually, they probably wouldn't be grouped up.
Scott: So like, you know, if out of the 200 panels, there were five you were interested in, you know, good luck actually getting to more than one of them, because that would require going all three days, which is way too long to spend at this thing.
Rym: Well, I can at least say one thing that Scott probably won't argue with like everything else, and those kids were totally in high school.
Rym: But anyway, I'm glad we didn't bother getting a table at this time.
Rym: And I think other than Otakon, where we're doing something kind of awesome with the front row crew and Katsucon, where we pretty much set like set up like the entire front of the video game room.
Rym: I don't think I'm going to bother getting tables at conventions ever again.
Rym: Like, it seems like, yeah, completely not worth it unless we're selling swag.
Scott: I see no reason to get a table at the convention.
Rym: But even then, I'm not really going to sit at the table.
Rym: I'll hire someone to sell the swag.
Scott: No, yeah.
Scott: You know, but I'd be at the table maybe like for scheduled times, you know, and that's actually something else.
Scott: The artist's alley was really big.
Scott: And last year the artist's alley was small and too crowded.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it was much better.
Scott: And last year, the artist's alley at this convention was basically all like A-list people, like holy shit people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which has also contributed to its crowdedness.
Scott: This year, there were still some holy shit people in the artist's alley, but not as many.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there were plenty of, you know, B-list awesome people.
Scott: They were still awesome.
Scott: They just weren't, you know, A-list famous people in there.
Scott: But other than like the peak hours, I'd say like up to 40 percent of the artist's alley, just no one was at their tables and there were empty tables all over the place.
Scott: Like on Sunday, a lot of the tables are empty, you know, so it was either too crowded.
Scott: You can't really look at anything or it's not crowded now.
Scott: Oh, there's like people missing.
Scott: I can't see their shit.
Scott: So like there was awesome stuff in the artist's alley, but I barely even got to see anyone in the artist's alley because they either weren't there when I was there or it was too crowded.
Scott: I couldn't get through and it wasn't worth it.
Rym: But there was one absolutely awesome thing at the con.
Rym: On Saturday night, TM Revolution had his concert, which went crazily well.
Scott: Except we weren't there.
Rym: Well, because we ended up having to skip Saturday.
Rym: You had to miss anyway because your family stuff.
Scott: Yeah, they put the.
Scott: they put the convention on Passover, which is, you know, you know, I'm an atheist Jew, so it's not the biggest deal.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I wasn't like, oh, no, I'm going to Jew hell, which doesn't exist.
Scott: But, you know, my family was eating dinner.
Scott: It's like, huh, free dinner with family convention.
Scott: I'm spending a whole bunch of time for free anyway.
Scott: TMR who I've already seen.
Scott: OK, I'll go get the free awesome.
Rym: But anyway, the main event for us, like because we weren't even going to go to the New York Comic Con, but we were kind of roped into it.
Rym: But the reason for all that was that on Sunday TM Revolution talking to our Nishikawa himself came to the Kinokuniya on because, you know, we set up this thing because we talked about this way back, but we're friends with the people here who'd work for like Tokyo FM.
Scott: And they were like, Brian, I think the company's GIO.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But they worked like they do stuff for Tokyo FM.
Rym: You know, the radio station in Tokyo.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And Brian Nishi is a host of this awesome baseball show.
Rym: If I if I was a baseball fan and I understood Japanese, this would be the show to listen to.
Rym: Yeah, seriously.
Rym: This here in this energy, especially because, you know, the Japanese baseball is big to them.
Scott: Yeah, pretty big.
Scott: They don't have, you know, some of the other sports.
Scott: They don't have ice hockey, really.
Rym: Like baseball in Japan is the way hockey is.
Scott: They don't have basketball.
Rym: Baseball in Japan is as big as hockey is to me personally.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: But so this was set up to where basically TMR came to the Kinokuniya for this big event.
Rym: And by the way, the upstairs was completely filled to capacity with fans.
Rym: It was kind of shelves.
Rym: It was kind of crazy.
Scott: Smart fans would have sat in the Zaya.
Rym: Well, the thing is, it was tough to get in there because people had already had this idea and parked themselves in the Zaya well before this event.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not sure, though, how many people in the Zaya were parked for the event and how many just happened to be in there.
Rym: Well, I think next time what the Kinokuniya should probably do is try to work out a deal where the Zaya closes that part and doesn't sell.
Rym: But instead, they like sell snacks to people throughout the whole store for that one time or something.
Scott: Yeah, they need to make a deal with them because then you could actually put the, you know, like the people in the Zaya or something like that or have seating in there or something, you know, something.
Rym: But basically he came and there was an interview where he was the guest and he was interviewed by Brian Nishi and also interviewed by us.
Rym: We were brought up as like the big anime fans from America with the award winning, amazing anime podcast.
Rym: And we were brought up there and we got to ask him three questions.
Rym: And I got to say a couple of things.
Rym: One, this guy Takanori Nishikawa, like the per pound energy in this band is like off the charts.
Scott: Well, either, right?
Scott: First of all, they had a booth at the Comic-Con for TMR, right?
Scott: And they had some of his clothes there, like on mannequins.
Rym: Now we'd seen him in concert.
Scott: But we were far away.
Rym: And also he looked really tall and really big because, you know, when you're on stage and you're kind of like out in front of everyone else, like in front of the backup people and there's the lights, you look larger than life.
Scott: Especially when someone is so far away.
Rym: But even up close, you look like this kind of epic figure.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: In reality, TMR is a very, very, very small man.
Scott: He is incredibly small.
Scott: Like, holy shit, is he small.
Rym: He is very pretty.
Rym: And in fact, multiple of the questions that were asked to him by people in the audience were related to, so how do you get your hair to look that way and how do you look so good and stuff like that.
Rym: Of course, I think I like this guy a lot because unlike the majority of interviews with Japanese stars I've heard, he gave some pretty funny answers.
Scott: Yeah, either.
Scott: He's like just really good, like a really great actor.
Scott: And he knew like awesome answers to say.
Scott: You know, it's always tough to tell when a famous person is genuine.
Scott: You always have to have some skepticism.
Scott: You know, like, are they just really good at pretending they love all their fans?
Scott: Or do they actually love all their fans and are awesome?
Scott: And, you know, it doesn't really matter because you never know the person in real life.
Scott: So it doesn't matter if they're genuine or not.
Scott: What matters is they're awesome and providing the entertainment that you're looking for because they're an entertainer.
Rym: The thing is, though, I think he's genuine because actually one of the questions we asked, because it turns out that a long time ago he used to do a radio show.
Rym: It was like Takador Nishikawa's.
Rym: All Night Nippon.
Scott: All Night Nippon.
Rym: It was funny because we printed it out.
Scott: And it was question mark, are you Night Nippon?
Rym: Well, it was Naito, too.
Rym: So I was like, what is this?
Rym: It was in Romaji.
Rym: It was like, all right, what is this?
Rym: Why did Google cut off this character?
Rym: What was it?
Scott: Is it like Iru Naito Nippon?
Rym: Because, you know, we're dumb.
Rym: And we show it to people who speak Japanese.
Rym: They're like, no, all night.
Rym: Oh, you know, all night.
Scott: We're like, ah, oh, nice on the phone.
Rym: But apparently, like he did this radio show and he loved doing it.
Rym: And he only stopped because he kind of got so famous that he had no time to keep doing it.
Rym: And I think it's if nothing else, the energy that guy has is definitely genuine.
Scott: Yeah, definitely.
Scott: Definitely.
Scott: He seems to enjoy what he's doing.
Rym: The coolest thing is we asked him, like, you know, because he actually voice acted in Gundam Seed and Gundam Seed Destiny.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like he played minor like Gundam pilots.
Rym: And he answered the question around by way where he basically said, you know, if you'd gone to me when I was a kid and told me that I would have effectively had my very own Gundam, I probably would have peed myself.
Rym: And then he proceeds to make a motion of.
Scott: he does like a hand gesture showing like, you know, he's like, yeah, peed all over the place.
Rym: Like the pea would have just gone everywhere.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, yeah, he definitely is a funny guy.
Scott: He's pretty cool.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Whether you like his music or not, because, you know, not everyone likes that kind of music.
Scott: Whether you like Gundam or not, it doesn't matter either.
Scott: He is a pretty awesome person.
Rym: Not just Gundam, he's done music for other shows.
Scott: He's done music for plenty of things.
Rym: And actually, Walt TMR is like this very specific kind of music.
Rym: He's also involved in this other project called the Abingdon Boys School, which if you if that name sounds familiar, think Radiohead.
Scott: Yeah, basically, he started another band.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And he named called it Abingdon Boys School, which is the school that Radiohead, you know, started in.
Scott: So it's like an all boys school in, you know, England, Albion somewhere.
Scott: So he must.
Rym: What the hell is England?
Scott: He must be a Radiohead fan of some sort.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That would be like if I made a band and I called it Strawberry Fields.
Rym: I really wanted to ask him about it, but because of time limitations, we only were able to ask him like three questions.
Scott: Basically, we submitted a bunch of questions, you know, and we decided, OK, well, it doesn't matter what questions we submit.
Scott: You know, if they have a high probability of actually getting making the cut or a low probability, doesn't matter.
Scott: You know, that way we can stick to our principle of ask hard questions, but then someone else decides which questions we're actually going to be able to ask.
Rym: The thing is though, what hard question can you ask him?
Rym: It's like, all right, so you're a musician.
Scott: I would go online and I'd research and find like his harshest critic and then like, you know, say, what do you think of, you know, this critic saying such and such about you?
Scott: The worst thing I can say.
Scott: I could have asked, you know, hey, your music is only popular because you attach it to popular anime.
Scott: Do you think that your music would be popular if you didn't attach it to any anime?
Rym: Yeah, except the answer based on Japan is already yes, very much.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Rym: But I'm just you can ask that kind of question.
Rym: One thing I find very interesting about TMR is that it's popular in America.
Rym: It seems like half of the people who know about TMR in America know about him because of Gundam seed.
Rym: But the other half of these people are.
Rym: there's a lot of people, especially in New York City, who are fans of Japanese music, like particularly J-Rock or J-Pop.
Rym: Oh, yeah, metal.
Rym: And they are fans of him.
Rym: They don't even know he was in Gundam.
Rym: They don't care.
Scott: Well, they know he was in Gundam.
Rym: But they're not.
Rym: Some of them I don't think did.
Scott: Well, maybe a few didn't, but even so.
Rym: You can tell the J-Rockers in the audience as opposed to the anime fans.
Scott: You could definitely.
Rym: It was like this 40/40 mix.
Rym: And then the other 20% were actually, I don't know the deal, but it seemed like a bunch of people in Japan won this contest or something where they came with him to America to see the concert.
Rym: And there were all these Japanese schoolgirls like lined up outside the glass, like watching and yelling.
Rym: It was pretty funny.
Scott: How long have we gone?
Rym: We should wrap this up.
Rym: The one last thing I got to say, and Scott will probably think this is lame, but I can't believe that.
Rym: I mean, I shook hands with TMR.
Rym: I was up there on stage with him.
Rym: It was pretty cool.
Rym: And he even like said, I give it like a 75% chance that he was serious, that he will listen to or at least check out what GeekNights is.
Rym: But beyond that, he high fived us again on his way out.
Rym: And then I got to kind of give the second hand five five to all the people behind me.
Rym: And I think that was pretty cool.
Rym: Are you like, yeah, it's just a person unlike you who is jaded about everything in the world and everything is met.
Scott: Unlike me, unlike you, who is not a teenage 13 year old girl who thinks that touching someone is like somehow magical and then touching somebody to touch someone is like magic rubbing off.
Rym: It pretty much is.
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: Concentrated magic that came off his hand and as cool a guy as he is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And as fun as he was and as awesome as the event was, he's just a dude, a really small dude, but a cool small dude.
Scott: And he's not magical.
Scott: And high fiving him is not special.
Scott: Yes, it is.
Rym: And you suck.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: You're just mad about everything.
Scott: I'm not a 13 year old girl.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: I think it was awesome.
Rym: But I can at least tell you all this is it won't be terribly useful.
Rym: I'm going to see if we can get permission to get the audio of this thing.
Rym: But if nothing else, if you really want to hear us asking TM Revolution some questions, it will be aired on Tokyo FM in the Tokyo, like, you know, metropolitan area at midnight, Eastern Daylight Time on Saturday.
Scott: That's terrific.
Scott: So maybe our friend Altimo Spalpin recorded someone driving late at night, you know, from down Mount Akina will turn on the radio and they'll hear GeekNights.
Rym: And the second time we've been on the radio in Japan.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Do you want to do the thing or go on the things of the day anyway?
Rym: Despite the fact that Scott doesn't understand the magic things of the day.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: OK.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: You're not excited about things.
Scott: We better call Randy.
Scott: then if it's the magic rubbed off on you, we can go get a million dollars.
Scott: Then you can go fly to Japan and high five again is in the bag.
Rym: Anyway, so this has been going around the Internet.
Rym: I'm sure a lot of you've seen it, but there's this video of a guy who was stuck in an elevator for 41 hours.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: That now that really sucks.
Scott: And it's basically the guys going nuts.
Scott: And I would also go nuts.
Rym: I particularly like how he cracked open the door and peed down the shaft because that's pretty much the only thing you can do.
Scott: Pretty much.
Scott: I'm surprised he didn't poop.
Scott: Did he not eat?
Scott: Well, I wonder what was up with that.
Rym: I can go a couple days without poop.
Rym: And if I have to.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But I mean, if I had to poop like it would, you know, it could cause some problems.
Rym: Well, if I had to poop, I would also see hydration starts to become a serious problem.
Scott: He probably would have been better off drinking his pee now.
Rym: Forty one hours is not so long.
Rym: And you're going to get that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But how long?
Scott: He didn't know it was only forty one hours.
Rym: Now he did because he got stuck.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: I don't want to dwell on this.
Rym: We've already gone on long.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: We got to keep.
Scott: this video was everywhere.
Rym: And a lot of people were saying it was fake or it was staged or it was some sort of like.
Rym: that's cool, but you couldn't be stuck there for 41 hours.
Rym: If you did a little bit of research, this happened once, like in like 1990 something, this is old, but to.
Rym: what happened was he was working late on Friday, went for a smoke break, came back up and got stuck.
Rym: No one came back to the building until Monday.
Scott: Well, number one deserves it.
Scott: Smoker.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Number two, where was the cell phone?
Rym: He left it upstairs because he just went down for a smoke.
Scott: See, I keep my cell phone on me at all times.
Rym: See, I often don't know.
Scott: It's about you're getting stuck in an elevator.
Rym: Number three, I have been stuck in an elevator before.
Rym: I was stuck in an elevator for over an hour once.
Rym: Number three, IBM with one of my co-workers.
Rym: We're in an elevator ride and it's going down and we're going.
Scott: You want to hurry this up?
Rym: It was going.
Rym: The elevator is going down and it stops and we look at each other.
Rym: We're like, no fucking way.
Scott: So you push the emergency button?
Rym: No.
Rym: And then it goes again.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Rym: And then we get off and then I get back in the elevator with the car to go back up by myself and it stops.
Rym: And I go, ha ha.
Rym: And then it doesn't go.
Scott: And you push the emergency button and it didn't do anything.
Scott: So that's the problem.
Scott: Those buttons are supposed to do so.
Rym: A lot of them just make a bell ring.
Rym: But if no one's around to hear the bell, then you're fucked.
Scott: So that's those buttons are supposed to, like, call the fire department.
Rym: Most of them don't.
Scott: That's bullshit.
Rym: But most of them don't.
Scott: Well, we need to make some.
Rym: a lot of the older ones.
Rym: They ring a bell outside the building that says, hey, someone stuck in an elevator in this building.
Scott: But that's a little better.
Rym: But most no one knows what that bell is.
Rym: If I'm walking in Manhattan and I hear a bell ringing, I know I'm just going to walk past the building.
Scott: But even so, it's like that button should call the, you know, help.
Rym: Well, it does call help, but they didn't expect anyone to be.
Scott: I mean, really, what they could do nowadays is the elevators have a cell phone and you push the button.
Scott: It calls, you know, not on one.
Rym: Anyway, for all the people who are saying he should have sued the place, the building settled for an undisclosed amount that he accepted.
Rym: So I'm sure he was paid.
Rym: Anyway, this video is pretty cool.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So Will Eisner.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We we've yet to talk about Will Eisner, mostly because the first Will Eisner book that we must read is at my grandma's house.
Scott: Good to get it back to my grandma.
Scott: There'll be plenty of Will Eisner action, which is it's kind of sad that it hasn't been Will Eisner action, seeing as he's the greatest comic creator to ever live with only Tezuka coming close with a tie or a second place.
Scott: It's hard to tell.
Scott: Anyway, Will Eisner, when he joined the military in the World War Two times.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And he mostly did comics for the military.
Scott: And afterwards, when he had his own comics company after leaving the military, talking, you know, from the early 50s to the 60s and such, he was still, you know, had the military was one of his clients.
Scott: And he made a magazine called Preventative Maintenance Monthly.
Scott: And here on this blog are many images and scans of Preventative Maintenance Monthly.
Scott: And it is quite awesome.
Scott: And you can see the the epic comic power that is.
Scott: Will Eisner and his amazingness even doing, you know, a lame military comic telling you to change the oil in your Humvee or whatever and not let Greece get on rubber because it'll ruin it.
Scott: He still manages to make some of the greatest comics there ever were.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So so anyway, before we get on to the main bid, Scott announced this contest intermittently for a while and then he kind of kept forgetting to mention it again.
Scott: Yeah, I have been lax.
Scott: I think maybe that's why we get so few entries for contests and we're so unsuccessful with them is because despite, you know, saying we're going to do contests right, everyone else, you know, fucks them up.
Scott: We never do them right.
Rym: So well, you never do them right.
Rym: I'm smart and just don't do them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I think the other thing is that so we either we either don't do them or do them poorly.
Rym: I think it's more that we asked a lot.
Rym: I mean, most of the entries we got patently didn't follow the rules.
Rym: So screw them.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, I have about.
Scott: basically we had a contest.
Scott: The contest was for the three volumes of the Goon Saga manga, which is a side story to the actual Goon Saga published by Vertical in English.
Scott: It's the entire thing.
Scott: It's only three volumes.
Scott: We have all of them.
Scott: And the contest was to write an essay saying why we should give them to you and, you know, to not screw up that essay.
Scott: And basically, no matter how good your reasons were, if you screwed up the essay, we didn't count it.
Scott: And, you know, I didn't get that many submissions, but there were a handful of valid ones and I've been lazy, but I finally evaluated all of them.
Scott: And the winner is Mr.
Scott: Roboto, who is from Costa Rica, mostly because his essay was valid and he lives in Costa Rica.
Scott: Therefore, it's probably best that someone in Costa Rica gets this manga because they probably can't buy it easily.
Scott: And he also has a U.S.
Scott: address, which is very nice because I can send it with normal shipping and then he'll get it somehow.
Scott: I don't know how that works, but maybe I should get a Japan address and then I could buy Japanese video games and such and they would be sent to me.
Scott: I want to figure out how that works.
Scott: I'm pretty interested now.
Scott: But yeah, Mr.
Scott: Roboto, you should email me your address and then I will send you mangas for free.
Rym: You should probably also follow up with him via email.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Scott: I could do that, too, if he doesn't listen to the show.
Rym: But anyway, on to actually reviewing some anime here on gig nights, Wednesdays, the quote unquote award winning anime podcast that doesn't talk about anime enough.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Part of that's because Scott doesn't watch any.
Scott: I've been reading books.
Rym: I didn't say anything other than that.
Rym: You don't watch so much anime, do you?
Scott: It's video game and book season.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: OK, so you don't watch so much anime.
Scott: Not lately.
Scott: Lately I've been watching more because it's starting a new anime season.
Rym: But anyway, tonight we're going to talk about something pretty quickly because it's a fairly short kind of one off thing.
Rym: And I highly recommend it, but not for the reasons you might expect.
Rym: We talk about Marius the Chojo.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Not show, Joe, but Joe Joe.
Rym: It's kind of like if a show Joe means girl, Joe Joe means Supergirl.
Rym: This was actually released originally by CPM as the Supergirl or the Super Gal, and they were kind of sued because of Supergirl and were forced to rerelease it under a different name.
Scott: But anyway, the deal is Rumiko Takahashi of Ranma slash Uruze Yatsura slash etcetera fame.
Scott: Right.
Scott: She made a short story, a very short manga story about Marius the Jojo.
Scott: And Emily said she read that manga and owns it.
Rym: But it's like 10 pages long.
Rym: It's like this happy little.
Rym: Yeah, let's go.
Rym: The end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We haven't read it, though, but we know it exists.
Rym: And she said, oh, that thing that's like this 10 page funny comic.
Rym: We should watch it.
Rym: It'll be short.
Rym: There's not much to it.
Scott: Well, is it an OAV or a TV movie?
Rym: It's OAV, I think.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So it's basically a one shot OAV, one episode.
Scott: So it's sort of like a short movie.
Scott: Was it like 40 minutes, something like that?
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: It was late and I didn't.
Rym: I wasn't sure how long it was going to be.
Scott: Wasn't as long as the movie.
Rym: But I'll say this, much like a lot of other anime from that era of when I'm watching anime, it wasn't that long.
Rym: It was, in fact, only 45 minutes.
Rym: But it felt interminable.
Rym: It felt pretty long to steal a term from Dave and Joe.
Rym: Kind of like how you watch Vampire Hunter D. And it's not that long, but it feels like it's super long.
Scott: I think what it is, a lot of the scenes sort of drag.
Scott: It's like there'll be a scene and there's not much plot.
Scott: I mean, they only had 10 pages of manga to go on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But to fill up 45 minutes, like they would get to outer space and then they'd like a big scene.
Scott: Like when they're in the desert.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're in the desert on some planet.
Scott: And it was just like a really 10 minutes of walking in the desert.
Scott: And I was like, come on.
Rym: Except it was actually only like a minute or two, but it felt like.
Scott: it felt like they were all going to the desert forever.
Scott: And there's the beach scene, which is the scene.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: It's just awesome.
Scott: You're awesome.
Scott: It felt like it was five minutes long.
Scott: Just watching crazy shit on the beach.
Rym: But first, this was actually directed by, of all people, Kazuyoshi Katayama, who, among other things, went on to direct the Big O. Big O. It's Showtime.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: And he was actually I didn't realize this.
Rym: He was the assistant director for Nausicaa Valley of the Wind.
Scott: All right.
Rym: And a bunch of other stuff.
Scott: But it's a pretty important anime person that not many people have heard of.
Rym: Maurice the Chojo is about.
Rym: it's about a girl who's from a planet that was blowed up.
Rym: And everyone on that planet has seven times the strength of a normal human.
Scott: I imagine it's probably one of those things where the planet had seven times the gravity.
Scott: So everyone is super strong there.
Rym: I don't know if it would even be addressed.
Scott: The thing is, she's super strong in outer space also, which, yeah, it was not one of those things where they explain it, where, you know, a science fiction nerd would be satisfied.
Rym: But because she's super strong, she wears these restraints most of the time, because otherwise she busts stuff up and gets in trouble.
Scott: Like if she just walks around without restraints, like she'll just her step will smash the floor, which is not too good in a spaceship.
Scott: It could mean a certain doom.
Rym: So what problems does she face?
Rym: Well, one, she's poor and that's pretty much it.
Scott: That's pretty much.
Rym: And she wants to not be poor anymore.
Scott: That's pretty much typical anime fare.
Scott: I mean, in outer space, no money.
Scott: Can we bebop anyone?
Scott: I mean, how many times have we seen this?
Rym: Now she has her kind of copilot and friend is this little kitsune who is hilarious.
Scott: He's pretty funny.
Rym: And the plot is basically she's.
Scott: I don't know why he hangs out with her, though.
Scott: He should.
Rym: But he comes out constantly complains.
Rym: Why do I hang out with you?
Rym: But he doesn't go away now.
Rym: But the plot is that it starts out and there's this kind of action scene where she beats up a bunch of people.
Rym: And I was worried about what kind of show this was because she beats up everyone.
Rym: But there's one guy who's wearing like a power suit and he's like, oh, like, I'm awesome and I will defeat you.
Rym: But then we put Scott's like, is that?
Rym: did he pee himself?
Rym: No, it can't be.
Rym: And we're watching.
Rym: It's like, no, that's just like some waters.
Scott: I can't.
Scott: I completely forgot about this.
Rym: And then it cuts to her and she's like, wow, he's so afraid.
Rym: He's so afraid, despite all appearances.
Rym: And we're like, was that actually intended to be P?
Rym: to convey that?
Rym: And not only is that indeed P, not only did he pee all over himself, but the P is there like in inordinate amount.
Rym: Like you see it so much in every like it's highlighted.
Rym: It's there.
Rym: The guy peed himself.
Scott: This is this is pretty much a wacky show.
Scott: It's just as very simple, sort of dragon half cut.
Scott: If you want to drag and have only a little crazy, you want an analogous show.
Rym: It is Project Aco.
Scott: Project Aco is also very analogous.
Rym: The deal is eventually she gets a job to save some guy who was kidnapped and the guy is super pretty.
Rym: So she decides any super sounds like dragon have to be all right.
Rym: I'll save him and then he'll marry me.
Rym: And I don't care what he's like because I'll be I won't be poor anymore.
Scott: And plus, she's got a family who has the same problem she does, that they're super strong.
Scott: But her dad's drunk and her mom's stupid, I guess.
Rym: And she goes to save him.
Rym: But it turns out that he's being protected by this evil guy who's just char.
Rym: And then this other girl who's basically Biko and she is three times the strength of a normal human.
Rym: But it turns out they were both wrestlers and it just goes crazy from there.
Rym: And what this really is, is a vehicle for a million cameos and side jokes.
Scott: The beach scene.
Scott: It's never more evident than in the beach scene and in the the the the cantina scene.
Rym: Basically, yeah, the Darth, the Mos Eisley.
Rym: So basically, Darth Vader's huff and paint.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So first, I'll discuss the beach scene.
Scott: They there's one part in which they they taxi someone to the beach as a ploy to get money.
Rym: So say it, Emily, this is like one page and that's it.
Rym: But instead, they drag it out into this almost music video montage of all these scenes of the beach.
Rym: And it's actually really funny.
Scott: Yes, it's basically, you know, they get to the beach and then they just this camera.
Scott: They show you all these just scenes happening on the beach while this music plays.
Scott: And you see such things as other Rumiko Takahashi characters hanging out on the beach, under the water, et cetera.
Rym: All of them, like you see Ten and Lum and Ataru and all these people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You see a battleship under the sea shooting.
Rym: You see, there is a strange undertone where it's obvious like you watch this and it's like, wow, this giant war is just starting.
Scott: You see an alien invasion of mechanical space alligators.
Rym: The Dinobots are marching out of the ocean and right next to them, everyone's just hanging out on the beach, totally ignoring them.
Scott: It's really weird because this giant like it's like there's an alien invasion of bat of old and new battleships in space and undersea.
Scott: And, you know, cyborgs and robots and aliens and God knows what.
Scott: But all the people on the beach are hanging out.
Scott: It's like if you took an anime about a horrible alien invasion and took an anime about hanging out on the beach, being happy, and you just put the cells one on top of the other and didn't.
Scott: And the two things, the two worlds didn't actually collide.
Rym: The best part is the guy who's scuba diving.
Scott: No, definitely.
Rym: Because he kind of there's this big blue thing and spoilers, I guess.
Rym: And he's like, he's swimming toward it and he kind of pokes his head in the hole, is looking around and suddenly clamps around him and it eats him.
Rym: Well, it's like it clamps around him and you wait.
Rym: And I'm like, ha ha.
Rym: And then it goes like, oh, now he's totally inside.
Scott: So he just got eaten by a creature on the bottom of this.
Rym: Now, that's funny in and of itself.
Rym: But then a second later, like with perfect comedic timing, his bones pop out, it burps and these bones pop out.
Rym: And it's just hilarious.
Scott: Not only is it funny that the bones pop out with comedic timing and a little burping noise.
Scott: The actual the way the bones are drawn is really funny.
Scott: I like bones, but they're really cute.
Rym: There's a similarly long scene with the desert, but I guess what I would say about the desert.
Scott: So at one point they crash on the desert and it's the girl and the and Maurice and the fox walking around the desert.
Rym: By the way, while it kind of works, the kitchen is a total jackass asshole.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So in that one, two characters crash spaceship walking around the desert.
Scott: And I'm like, Star Wars.
Scott: I even said Star Wars out loud.
Scott: Right.
Scott: While we were watching it, they arrive at sort of a shady ghost town.
Scott: I'm like, most easily I say it out loud.
Rym: And then we immediately see Darth Vader huffing paint.
Scott: There's Darth Vader huffing paint and there's an R2D2 in the background.
Scott: And I'm like, I fucking called it.
Scott: How more obvious could they be?
Rym: But if I was going to say anything about this show, it wouldn't.
Rym: it's not necessarily a great show in and of itself.
Rym: No, not really what it is.
Rym: And it really gave me the same vibe I got when I was in fourth grade, when I was like eight or nine years old and I was seeing my first anime and I would watch any anime I could get and shows from that era.
Rym: Like shows like that where there's these long kind of dragged out musical number scenes and there's this goonie kind of humor that that the style of goonie humor in modern anime is a lot different from the style of goonie humor from this older anime.
Rym: And I don't know, this is the best show to show to a whole bunch of people at once.
Scott: As the best show to hold a bunch of people in that genre.
Scott: It's a great show to show to a whole bunch of people.
Rym: I think it's up there with Elf Princess Rain.
Scott: It is definitely right up there with Elf Princess Rain.
Scott: It's just Dragon Half, Echo, all those sort of wacky sort of semi one shot adventure thingies to have a fun time with.
Rym: But these are wacky in the older school way as opposed to like Excel Saga and all those kinds of things which are wacky in this kind of completely different way.
Rym: Not saying one is better or worse, but it's a different kind of wacky.
Scott: Yeah, it's the old school wacky and I liked it, but I don't know if I'd watch it again.
Rym: But the real vibe I got and Emily got the same vibe and Scott even did to a degree was watch this show if you're in the same frame of mind to watch like Space Ghost Coast to Coast.
Scott: Yeah, definitely the late night quiet kind of weird action enhances it in a different way than the large crowd does.
Rym: Yes, but I think both are good.
Rym: I mean, if you run an anime club show this, it'll go over really well.
Scott: I got people yelling and screaming and oh my God, they can get over the fact that it looks old, which I never actually heard any.
Scott: You know, I hear old school anime fans complain, hey, kids don't look at stuff because it looks old.
Scott: And I've never actually heard anyone say I'm not watching this because it looks old.
Rym: The only people I've ever heard say something like that were people who aren't anime fans.
Rym: They're Naruto only fans or they're Bleach only fans.
Rym: People who are like just getting into anime, they've only seen like the Dragon Ball.
Rym: That's all they like.
Rym: Yeah, but anyone who watches anime, no, I've never heard Dragon Ball looks old.
Rym: Yeah, Dragon Ball does look old now.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't realize how old it looked till I saw some the other day.
Scott: It's also really poorly drawn that Mario's the Jojo is better looking than Dragon Ball.
Rym: Mario's the Jojo.
Rym: If you have an anime club, show it and talk it up as this old school event and people will yell and scream and they'll stop.
Rym: They'll be kind of bored during the desert scene.
Rym: They'll be like, what's going on?
Rym: Where is this going?
Scott: And the desert scene, it actually starts to get serious for a little bit.
Scott: And like a few times it sort of tries to be serious, kind of.
Rym: But it does it in that old school like Slayers where it's like, we're going to be serious.
Scott: Just kidding.
Rym: Yeah, but all that desert scene is, is just set up.
Rym: If you have a crowd for when they see Darth Vader, even if it's not that funny in and of itself, if you've got a crowd of anime fans in a room having been set up with this desert scene and suddenly they see Darth Vader, they're going to go,
Scott: ah!
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That was a little bit of a long show, but I guess it makes up for no show yesterday, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And we'll probably do a show tomorrow.
Rym: There's a tiny chance we might do a special or something quick because I'm actually going to Rochester for Toricon, which might be the last.
Scott: Aren't you going Friday?
Rym: Yeah, but I got to pack and get ready Thursday and sleep.
Scott: I'm going to have a new computer tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So basically what I had to put together and what I'm trying to warn all of you is that I might want to go to bed early and hang out.
Rym: And much like when I got my new computer and suddenly there were a couple of non-GeekNights because, oh, Rym's got to do something.
Rym: Maybe I think Scott's feeling the desire to build his computer.
Scott: Maybe we could do something like special.
Scott: I'm thinking maybe.
Rym: I think we should do a special.
Rym: The Thursday specials are always fun.
Rym: People seem to enjoy them almost more so than a normal Thursday.
Scott: I'm kind of thinking, right?
Scott: This might be spur of the moment.
Scott: I don't know if we want to say it on the show, right?
Scott: I don't know if you haven't discussed this with you beforehand, but maybe we could do something crazy like we Skype a listener and talk for 15 minutes and that's it.
Rym: That might be interesting.
Rym: Depends on the listener.
Rym: I know I kind of want to listen to that.
Scott: I know we're like, sure, Betts.
Rym: I kind of want to Skype like Daryl Surratt.
Rym: I mean, like, hey, Daryl, let's talk about something that isn't anime or video games.
Scott: Well, you could do like a 15 minute geek profile or, you know, something like that.
Scott: So I guess people are probably going to comment on that saying, pick me, pick me in the forums, right?
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure they will.
Scott: I'm sure they will.
Scott: Well, maybe we'll do it.
Scott: Maybe not.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: But anyway, the New York Comic Con was OK.
Scott: TM Revolution was the fucking bomb and hopefully explosive, hopefully a very small bomb with a very large explosion.
Rym: He's like a neutron bomb.
Scott: He's really small.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: He's so energetic, so small.
Rym: Normally with someone who's famous, you expect at some point that grin to turn into the slightly forced grin.
Rym: I mean, as like game face as I am at conventions, because people see me at cons.
Rym: I'm up there like, yeah, and then I get to the room and it's like my face goes from the smile to like the frown before I fall asleep and snore and like die.
Rym: But every now and then my visage cracks and visage and famous people, it cracks because they have even more pressure.
Rym: But I didn't see a single crack in this guy.
Rym: Maybe he might be a robot, a very small robot.
Rym: He might be a robot.
Scott: He's a very small robot.
Scott: During the show, the show's got to be over now.
Scott: It's done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.