Rym: It's Thursday, March 27th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We tried we wanted to talk about Monty Python, but other things came up.
Rym: Let's do this so normally I'd avoid talking about politics whenever Scott is here because he never seems to care.
Rym: but This story needs to be talked about a little bit Partly because it is my opinion that this marks the pretty much the end of Hillary Clinton's viability as a Democratic candidate for president this time around.
Scott: I don't know if it's not something that's gonna be in a history book 50 years from now.
Scott: I don't think it's worth talking about.
Rym: Okay, a lot of this is gonna be in history books much like.
Rym: I mean do we defeats Truman?
Scott: Yeah, that's yes.
Scott: So that's the only thing that's in the history book though.
Scott: three words Not these details and such.
Rym: only if you went to a crappy school and had crappy history books.
Scott: I mean think about it.
Scott: right.
Scott: teapot dome like one paragraph.
Scott: my history book one paragraph.
Rym: We had like a whole unit on that thing.
Scott: Yeah, like what fair.
Rym: and then we had a whole separate unit on economics.
Rym: and why teapot dome mattered?
Scott: Yeah, is this teapot dome level?
Rym: This is in current events.
Rym: This is I'm convinced that what happened here has Basically told us that Obama is going to be the Democratic nominee.
Rym: I think that this absolutely clinches it.
Rym: you have to read between the lines a little bit The story here.
Scott: basically It's Rym likes to grasp at straws.
Rym: Not really.
Rym: This is pretty.
Rym: you'll see what I mean.
Rym: So Hillary Clinton as you know is behind in the popular vote and she's behind in terms of pledged delegates and she's behind Total in terms of all delegates even if you include the super delegates who split more for her than for Obama Despite the fact that he has actually gained several super delegates recently.
Rym: He gained one most notably when spitzer Had to step down due to various things loops, but Clinton has had a lot of trouble lately.
Rym: I mean a little while ago.
Rym: She was caught fiving about Landing in Bosnia under sniper fire and then it turned out that there was actually news video of her landing and it completely Contradicted her entire story.
Scott: Yeah How come when like the people who are in charge like that happens to them on a daily show like every other day and no One makes a big deal about it.
Rym: Uh No one makes a big deal about anything because no one knows anything or cares or even understand what's going on.
Rym: Yeah, I care about this a little now.
Rym: I posted this in the forums.
Rym: I got to say the fact that Hillary lied about this and got caught.
Rym: I don't think it says anything about her character because her fib Was pretty much par for the course when it comes to American politics.
Rym: Like I don't even worry about that.
Rym: the fact that she exaggerated a bit and fibbed a bit doesn't even register for me.
Rym: I would never consider saying well, that's it for Hillary.
Rym: She lied.
Scott: I mean the.
Scott: I said this in the forum, but basically the political climate in the u.s.
Scott: Nobody's a perfect human being.
Scott: nobody everyone has something, you know that they did wrong except Barack Obama.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure or a mistake they made at some point or you know something right?
Rym: What about FDR?
Scott: He couldn't walk.
Rym: I don't think that was his.
Scott: Okay That was anyway, he's got too soon.
Scott: No, that was me.
Scott: Yeah, right to see.
Scott: now That was me leading into.
Scott: oh, so it wasn't his fault that he couldn't walk.
Scott: So it wasn't my fault.
Scott: You bastards got sick.
Scott: Okay, end of story.
Rym: Yeah, except you were the one who went out In the first place.
Scott: Oh FDR went out and got polio.
Rym: Is that we're saying no You see the thing is I don't think FDR spent the the previous many years of his life going around telling people how immune to polio he is.
Rym: I don't think that's what he was doing.
Rym: Wow, you can tell it's Thursday, we're done All right.
Scott: So the way the way the media works in the US if you're a politician, especially one running for office Especially one running for federal office, especially one running for president Especially one would have a good chance of winning at president.
Scott: winning at president like it's a game the president game.
Scott: I want to win at it.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Um You pretty much.
Scott: you either have to be perfect as a human being your entire life from when you were born Or you have to lie and not get caught
Rym: because sadly which
Scott: are both pretty much impossible things to do in the current world when everyone is looking at you all the time and Going over every word you say making sure you didn't lie.
Rym: But at the same time that I like the environment is creating because it's gonna get to the point where people can't hide what they've Done anymore.
Rym: and once people realize that and the new governor of New York State Actually is kind of on the forefront of this because after all the scandal he stepped up and pretty much immediately It came out that he had an affair in the past and his response was yep
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: and it's that whenever anyone accuses you of something a bit embarrassing whatever as long as you're not gonna go to Jail over it.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into you know, well don't confess to crimes because if you committed a crime that was bad You probably should confess.
Rym: But anyway, well fifth amendment, you know, you know, but I'm just saying if Someone is like I heard you were an anime if I got to think of something horrible that isn't horrible enough to warrant jail.
Scott: You watch the worst hentai all the time.
Rym: I heard that you were into Harry Potter doji and cheese where everybody's gay Totally having sex and if you're a person like that would get a lot of votes.
Rym: But if your response to that is yep, you want to see some That takes all that talk about taking the thunder out of someone's argument.
Scott: It's like, uh, no Well, it takes them out of one argument and brings it to another one.
Scott: And basically what you're doing there is you're avoiding the.
Scott: you know you're bad because you're lying battle and instead you have.
Scott: you're deciding that you're going to have the Gay Harry Potter doujin is good battle And if you don't think you can win that battle You should probably lie and try to get away with it.
Scott: But if you can win the second battle though Then by all means you should always cuz like the governor the new governor.
Scott: he came out.
Scott: They said you had an affair and he said yup and he cuz.
Scott: he knew he could win the.
Scott: plenty of people have affairs.
Scott: We sorted it out.
Scott: We're better than most people in those terms.
Scott: He could win that battle.
Scott: So he decided to go fight it, but he couldn't win the.
Rym: I didn't have an affair cuz.
Rym: that's when the YouTube videos come.
Rym: yeah, but What Hillary did is she lied about something that was minor but yet was trivially trivially proven wrong.
Rym: and the fact that Obama has not made a similar misstep and Just the nature of exactly what Hillary lied about it doesn't say that she's a liar.
Rym: All politicians are liars except like crazy beings except except crazy politicians.
Rym: They often don't lie, but they're crazy So it's not okay, so I guess that's me.
Rym: I don't lie, but I'm crazy Like Mike Gravelle and Ron Paul, they don't pretend like well, I'm for this one really there for this They're really for this.
Rym: This is just crazy and stupid.
Scott: Well, Mike Gravelle is only he's great except for like one one you who won it one or two issues.
Scott: He's just stupidly crazy.
Scott: So crazy that he's unvoteable.
Rym: Yeah, I Got news about him, but I'll say imagine if someone agreed with you on everything.
Scott: But they also thought that the earth was a cube a hollow cube.
Rym: Yeah, not even like a flat.
Rym: We're talking like a cube that's rotating on the top of a turtle.
Rym: That's purple.
Scott: Yeah, it's like whoa, dude All right, you agree about everything else, but now I can't respect you or vote for you or anything.
Rym: But does your earth cube?
Rym: the fact that Hillary fibbed about something like this?
Rym: Speaks to the fact that she doesn't get the modern world.
Rym: She is definitely an artifact of old world politics And Obama whatever you feel about it.
Rym: He has not made any modern misstep.
Rym: He has made missteps in the classic political sense, but he has not made a modern mistake.
Rym: He is.
Rym: he has not run afoul of issues that are new in politics.
Scott: I really the one thing I got to say that I do kind of care about politics now Right is it's gonna be super interesting.
Scott: Let's say let's pretend Obama wins and he's the president and you know, so it's it's February or March 2009 right?
Scott: How's?
Scott: the Daily Show is gonna have to make fun of them?
Scott: What are they gonna say?
Scott: I really want to see what those jokes are gonna be.
Rym: They'll be like well Obama's really Smiley today and Loki.
Rym: Wow, you fixed the economy.
Rym: I was just great, wasn't it?
Scott: I don't think that I'm not too sure about that Anyway, but what happened here is Hillary.
Rym: I think in addition to that is kind of grasping at straws here these short stories that she her campaign threatened.
Rym: Nancy Pelosi The house speaker who is Nancy Pelosi is a very interesting politician and I really really respect her.
Rym: She is one of the few people who is had.
Rym: she's like.
Rym: she represents kind of this interesting Element that's starting to grow in the Democratic Party.
Scott: What state is she from?
Rym: You know, I don't even know where.
Scott: what's her?
Rym: You know, I only know district.
Rym: I only know about her like national political house issues.
Rym: I don't know anything about her local.
Scott: I'm gonna go look at a button.
Rym: She is kind of on the forefront of this movement that if it comes to fruition It's kind of like for the long time.
Rym: The Democratic Party has had this Reputation in America as being the party.
Rym: that isn't the Republican Party and that was mostly what made them.
Scott: They were Nancy Pelosi is.
Scott: she represents the 8th District of California.
Rym: Oh, that's very close to my favorite district.
Scott: You know my district, you know what the 8th District of California is, huh?
Scott: It's 4/5 of San Francisco.
Rym: Well, there we go.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: Like her and Howard Dean and there are a bunch of people who are kind of pushing the Democratic Party Toward being a party that has solid issues and stands up for what it believes in as opposed to the wishy-washy Democrats we've had for a long long time Except Jimmy Carter who was only portrayed to be wishy-washy, but it wasn't so much.
Rym: But anyway, I don't want to get into a crazy political thing here.
Rym: So basically her campaign realized found out that Pelosi had basically said super delegates should probably vote for the candidate who has the most pledged delegates and go with.
Rym: you know what the people in the Democratic Party want.
Rym: and The Clinton campaign said hey don't say that You should take into account other factors.
Rym: You know factors other than the popular vote or the electoral vote factors like something that has nothing to do with votes at all Like who might win against McCain or who did better in, Ohio?
Rym: Uh-huh, and she backed this up.
Rym: It wasn't just a threat like hey stop that.
Rym: Basically they threatened her with a whole bunch of people who typically donate a lot of money to the Democratic Party Saying that they'll pull all their support from Pelosi and the people who are with her if she doesn't back down on this.
Rym: hmm, and the thing is Nancy Pelosi is in a position to kind of decide who wins because a lot of people who are super Delegates will do whatever she says Mm-hmm, and she has not publicly supported someone but she supported the candidate with the most votes which cannot be anyone.
Rym: But Obama like almost nothing could happen to make Obama not have the majority of everything at the end of all this.
Rym: So Nancy Pelosi's campaign.
Rym: Well not campaign.
Rym: I keep saying campaign because you know the campaigns are going on.
Rym: There was a response and the response is exactly what I would expect from someone cool like this.
Rym: This is not actually from.
Rym: they're not Nancy's words.
Rym: They are the words of someone who speaks for Pelosi.
Rym: Speaker Pelosi is confident that super delegates will choose between senators.
Rym: Clinton or Obama are two strong candidates Before the convention in August.
Rym: that choice will be based on many considerations including Respecting the decisions of millions of Americans who have voted in primaries and participated in caucuses.
Rym: the speaker believes that it would do great harm to the Democratic Party if super delegates are perceived to Overturn the will of the voters.
Rym: This has been her position throughout the primary season Regardless of who was ahead at any particular point in delegates or votes.
Rym: now Notice how if you translate what she said into layman's terms Vote for Obama is what she said.
Scott: So I think really a lot of what this stuff is is that?
Scott: It's really not the people.
Scott: It's not Hillary Clinton doing it's not.
Scott: you know Obama It's all these people under them and it really shows you it's not real.
Scott: It's the people under them to sort of control all this stuff that goes on.
Rym: Well, it's more that I mean.
Rym: Hillary does direct the campaign and she chooses who she wants running the campaign.
Scott: And yeah But it really it seems like those people are a lot more of the decision-making and then the candidate just sort of like does.
Rym: Well, no, I'm not.
Rym: I'm even talking about like.
Rym: oh the threat blah I'm not.
Rym: I'm talking about the game of politics.
Rym: What this says is that her campaign the experts running her campaign have realized that unless they do something drastic She cannot win.
Rym: Resorting to something like this is an incredibly risky gambit Because if it doesn't go well and so far it has not gone Well, it can do nothing but harm her and remove the last chance she has to win which is winning the rest of the super delegates.
Rym: and The fact that they have resorted to something like this means that they think she cannot win and this is their life.
Rym: this was like the great white hope and Now there's almost nothing she can do.
Rym: I think that this is this is kind of like the bellwether of Hillary's campaign and I think that as of this response from Nancy Pelosi the race is over And the rest of it's just mopping up.
Rym: I may be proven wrong But that is what I believe.
Rym: and come the Democratic National Convention I will stand up for what I think was going to happen.
Scott: when That convention.
Rym: I wish I could go.
Scott: I said I didn't say go why would you want to go?
Scott: that'd be amazing.
Rym: I'd love to be at that convention.
Scott: What are you gonna do there?
Scott: You're gonna stand it's gonna be crowded It's gonna be loud.
Scott: You're not gonna.
Scott: you don't do anything.
Scott: You're not a delegate.
Scott: You just stand there.
Rym: you realize that unless Hillary drops out technically it won't be decided Until the convention and that convention is gonna be mighty interesting.
Rym: It's also a nice way to hub nub, you know rub shoulders with.
Rym: a lot of people are really into politics.
Rym: I think it would be fun.
Scott: They're just a bunch of kooky old people usually or delegates.
Rym: now this time around There's a good chance that a lot of Scott Johnson II and Remy type people are gonna be there and not a lot of Scott Rubins, I don't care about politics.
Scott: Well, it's got Ruben.
Scott: I don't care about politics.
Scott: It doesn't go anytime.
Rym: Anyway, Scott, the Democratic National Convention is going to take place after all of the primaries and caucuses.
Rym: I think you can figure out when that is now.
Rym: What do you got in the news?
Scott: I don't know when it is.
Scott: I take a look at a calendar.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: I honestly believe that this was it.
Rym: This was the.
Rym: this is like.
Rym: this is the bellwether.
Rym: There's that's the perfect word.
Rym: I don't need another word.
Scott: Whatever Alright, so here's the news.
Scott: That's actually important Raises a lot of questions to have an actual discussion, but did this affect you directly?
Scott: It doesn't.
Rym: it affects me in that I can now use it as a step, okay Okay, I'm just pointing out that usually your argument against talking about politics is that it doesn't directly affect you right now It doesn't.
Scott: but While this the actual story here does not affect me I can use this story as a weapon further in my life.
Scott: I know it's sort of sad to use such a sad story as a weapon But well, you know what?
Scott: I'm of the mind that I'm using it as a weapon for good.
Scott: think of it as like a Sword of justice.
Rym: what I was about to say is I know what Scott what's new Scott's about to talk about?
Rym: now?
Rym: I'll warn you all right now that this is not a the typical funny happy or Angry but in a funny Rym and Scott way news.
Rym: and this is like, you know when Penn Jillette talks about some things on like the bullshit show and he's all funny and like Blah-blah-blah funny joke funny joke, and then there's a couple of times where he stops like this isn't funny what we're gonna talk about?
Rym: I'm not kidding this isn't funny and that's what we're gonna talk about.
Rym: but I would look at using this as a weapon or as a tool as more of kind of making the death mean something mmm, so There's a terrible news.
Scott: There are some people.
Scott: they lived out in Wisconsin right.
Scott: so that already tells you something.
Scott: And they had a family that tell you Wisconsin is the Midwest.
Rym: It's not that bad.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, well, it's West in Wisconsin.
Rym: I don't know where that is.
Rym: I'll look it up.
Scott: Yeah, you anyway anyway, you lived in Wisconsin and they had a. but they're just a family with a bunch of kids and one of the kids was 11 year old girl and She had diabetes Kito acidosis keto acidosis.
Rym: That's what happens when you go on Adkins for too long in an improper way.
Scott: Yeah, basically she had diabetes diabetes, whatever and They she never went to a doctor from the time.
Scott: She was three to the time.
Scott: She was 11.
Rym: now I point out that untreated diabetes Completely untreated is almost invariably fatal and causes Horrible numerous medical problems pretty much continuously.
Scott: We now know that the diabetes well, it's undiagnosed diabetes because they never went to a doctor.
Scott: But we know it was entirely treatable entirely.
Scott: if they would have gone to a doctor the girl would have been just fine.
Rym: She would have lived the same life that millions of people worldwide who have diabetes like that live.
Scott: She would have taken some insulin shots and whatnot.
Rym: This isn't like some rare exotic disease.
Rym: This was this is something that was solved a long time ago.
Scott: Yep, but on Sunday She died because she didn't have enough insulin because they never went to a doctor and got insulin shots or anything.
Rym: now Did they not go to the doctor because they were too far poor?
Rym: Was there a reason they didn't go?
Scott: even if you're poor you could have at least run to the emergency room when she was really Sick, right and she was really sick for like, you know the keto acidosis Which is you know, sort of like, you know, sort of like the AIDS is to the HIV.
Rym: Well that what a way keto acidosis is when you're starving to death and your body is breaking down Fats and whatever whatever it can even muscle in order to get you the energy you need to continue to live.
Scott: Yeah, but without insulin it's not gonna help very much Because there was no insulin.
Rym: that's why it was happening.
Rym: Yes Anyway, the medical bit here that the point I want to drive home before because this isn't the news really.
Rym: This is just the kind of the precursor of the story.
Rym: But there was nothing preventing this family from getting medical help for their daughter?
Scott: No, nothing at all.
Scott: They they could have gone to the doctor at any time and even they could have even gone to the emergency Room, she was you know, very ill and here here he is.
Scott: These the exact thing.
Scott: She had been ill for about a month.
Scott: So even though she had diabetes for a long time for about a month She was suffering symptoms such as nausea vomiting excessive thirst loss of appetite and weakness.
Scott: So they had a month to go to the emergency room for free and they didn't.
Scott: why?
Scott: Well, they didn't.
Scott: it says here that they have nothing against doctors, right?
Scott: They did not belong to an organized religion or faith.
Scott: They're not fanatics But they believe in the Bible and they believe that healing comes from God and they opted to pray To God or to a God they believe in rather than go to the doctor.
Rym: now You said that they have other children.
Scott: They do.
Rym: I Don't think there's really any debate about the fact that those children should not be left in their care.
Scott: No, I don't think there's any debate about that other.
Rym: Otherwise, I think the only debate here honestly is whether or not they should be imprisoned or whether they should be committed.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's a tough call though because it's like You know, if you have a child, you know, you're you're sort of you're responsible for taking care of it.
Rym: Yes Both morally and legally until the child is 18 years old unless they're emancipated.
Rym: in the United States The parents are responsible for taking for the care of the children.
Scott: Yeah, and if you don't do that responsibility There's uh, there's laws about that like neglect and whatnot.
Scott: And it does say that there are police investigating the family But I don't really see What you know.
Scott: the investigation would take me like five minutes because pretty much the family like admits it and There was an aunt of the family.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: My sister-in-law is very religious.
Scott: She believes in faith instead of doctors.
Scott: She called my mother-in-law today and she explained to us that she believes.
Scott: her daughter's in a coma right now and she's relying on faith.
Scott: Yeah This is the kind of thing, you know.
Scott: people come and they're like, oh you're so mean You know, we we might believe in crazy things.
Scott: we you know, we do good and we help people.
Scott: and the thing is If you didn't have the faith in the first place the faith introduces the possibility of this sort of thing happening.
Scott: If you didn't have faith, this would be not possible.
Scott: There'd be no chance of this kind of crazy thing happening where you know, and the thing is right.
Scott: they prayed their daughter died So what do they do?
Scott: They remain strong for their children.
Scott: only our faith in God is giving us strength.
Rym: at this time I don't even want you still I don't even want to get into the argument of you know Well that that means technically that God killed your daughter.
Rym: Why do you still trust him?
Rym: or?
Rym: but then the argument against that is well God had a reason for killing the daughter But what kind of God is that?
Rym: yeah, it's like but that's not even the argument I want to have because Arguing Oh religion blah.
Rym: There's much more the issue of what do we do in this situation in society?
Rym: People who make decisions like this.
Rym: I mean, it's one thing if someone makes a decision that harms only them and If I and the pride like fake medicine is example.
Rym: There are a lot of people who get cancer or something and they rely on Alternative medicine and as a result they die of something that might have been treatable or they get.
Scott: usually.
Scott: what happens though to those people is They get that, you know Their symptoms worsen and worsen and worsen and then when they're really sick They finally go to the real doctor and they end up worse off than they would have been but they don't.
Scott: they don't die often But they die or a lot.
Rym: Well, it happens a lot of times is a cancer or something that would have been treatable progresses to an untreatable states Before they go and seek medical help.
Rym: Yep, but again, there's there's kind of the argument that the only reason the seed of even believing in Fake medicine or something like that is there is because a lot of our society it legitimizes these things.
Rym: Letting people sell that airborne product or an herbal medicine that is clearly fake or homeopathic remedies in stores Creates this sort of legitimacy in people's minds Even if it's just very subtle that well that sort of thing is possible.
Rym: Keep an open mind or yeah Well, there's a lot we don't know.
Rym: So maybe acupuncture works and I don't want it's not it.
Rym: I don't want to make a slippery slope argument But keeping that door open makes it very easy for people to fall further and further down the line Until things that are less and less plausible seem more and more plausible.
Rym: But at least if someone does that it only hurts them.
Rym: So I don't What about this situation where it didn't just hurt it killed a little girl.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much I mean look at like, you know people.
Scott: there are plenty of people out there.
Scott: take for example I keep forgetting the guy's name the guy who's like the famous, you know human genome project guy.
Scott: But he says it's okay to believe in God or whatever, right?
Scott: So while he's all science and I'm sure he would take his children to a doctor being a you know, world-famous Biologist who's like, you know, I did he win Nobel Prize.
Scott: I'm mad of you know, super famous super smart, right?
Scott: You know the faith that he has is probably not going to result in anyone being hurt.
Scott: but he wrote a book, you know defending that.
Scott: and You know if he writes a book that says it's okay to believe in something without evidence Then you have other people where it's okay to believe in other things that evidence.
Scott: and thus You have these people believing in something without evidence and they kill somebody.
Scott: I don't want to say that that guy is responsible for killing someone I'm not I'm not going that far but we really you shouldn't be you know Emphasizing that kind of thinking.
Scott: you shouldn't validate it You shouldn't respect it because it's that kind of thinking even if you know this person who thinks it is not doing any harm And that person who does think it is, you know, you might say Oh, well the people who aren't doing any harm are doing the harm.
Scott: The people are are.
Scott: Well, the problem is is if you didn't have that kind of thinking this kind of harm would never happen.
Scott: It only happens because that kind of thinking is legitimized and respected.
Rym: now Don't get us wrong.
Rym: I mean I believe in freedom above all else as people are free to speak their beliefs and Say whatever they want whenever they want.
Rym: as far as I'm concerned and there's nothing wrong with writing books about these things saying that you believe in these things believing in these things, but at the same time that is why people who believe in these things even if they do otherwise great things or otherwise respected or otherwise intelligent I Cannot respect them as human beings because I feel as though their legitimization of these ideas Indirectly leads to what just happened where this little girl died over something so ludicrous that I Don't even know what should be done with these parents.
Scott: Yeah, I mean these parents aren't.
Scott: well They're not outwardly dangerous people like usually the argument for prison is like, you know You put this person because if you let this person roam around they're going to you know hurt people.
Scott: They're gonna shoot people and stab and go crazy.
Rym: So you put them in a prison where they can't hurt anybody but they are dangerous to those under their care Those for whom they have power.
Rym: Oh, so as a result in the very least there is pretty much no argument That could sway me to believe that any child should be left in their care for the rest of their lives.
Scott: No, I don't think that.
Scott: here's the other thing though, right?
Scott: You can take away their children But what if they make more?
Scott: now we have to take them away and now that means these people are free To create more children there.
Rym: They're basically they have the right to create a burden on society, but at the same time Neither one of us can make the argument that forced sterilization or and something along those lines is even.
Rym: I mean It's a laughable idea and I don't know what to do.
Rym: I don't think they should go to prison because that doesn't solve anything.
Rym: All it does is remove two people who are somewhat.
Scott: they're moderately productive in society I'm sure they have jobs and do work and whatnot, you know, and they're probably not see.
Scott: this is the really hard part of this and what makes it so hard.
Scott: and Why atheists, you know get it like a bad rap when they you know Yell at these kind of people is because these people are good intentioned, you know, they they meant well.
Scott: and it's like You know when you yell it when someone means well and they have good in their hearts and you go and you say you're a Terrible person, you know, it's like it makes you look like a bad person.
Scott: But really if you mean well and let's say I'm trying to like help someone and I think that you know Jumping up and down is gonna help them.
Scott: So I jump up and down but jumping up and down is actually hurting them.
Scott: But I just think it's helping them because I don't know any better that it's like I think I'm helping.
Scott: I'm a good person I'm trying to help.
Scott: I'm you know, my heart is in it but I don't have the knowledge to actually help and I cause harm because of that.
Scott: and then some mean guy comes along and tells me I'm Eviling crazy and I'm doing harm and I'm bad and I shouldn't be doing that.
Rym: So in this case now, what do we do?
Rym: I mean my in my opinion the the first cause maybe not the but like the first thing that the justice system or a Justice system.
Rym: what justice is should do is to as best as can be done Undo or mitigate the harm that was done, but the harm can't be undone the girls dead.
Rym: So moving on the next thing that a justice system should do is within reasonable bounds and at reasonable cost prevent Foreseeable future harm and that can be done by taking away the children.
Scott: taking away their other children is is obvious.
Scott: There's no question about that one.
Scott: But what about?
Scott: you know, they can.
Scott: there's still the they're allowed to make more children.
Scott: No one can stop them from doing that and that will create a burden on society and cause harm because we can't let them keep Their new children.
Scott: we have to take them away.
Rym: and then we you know, it creates a burden on you know Orphanages or whatever, you know There's the foster homes and such the third notion the third order away from this which is almost a subset which is prevent future harm directly and That could be.
Rym: there are a number of ways to do that But most of them involve limiting these people's freedom and effectively removing them from society.
Rym: It also starts to tread into the cruel and unusual terror not even that it goes into the fourth order, which is punishment, which is really.
Rym: there's a fine line between deterrence and revenge and I'm of the mind that deterrence is a very valid idea and I think that it's something that should always be a part.
Scott: Well, is there something that we could do to punish these people?
Scott: that would deter other Crazy religious people from keeping their kids away from the doctor so that you know We would do?
Scott: we would somehow make an example of these parents and then other Similar people would then see that and bring their kids to the doctor.
Scott: now the problem is what could we do that would make?
Scott: That happen.
Rym: I don't think there's anything we could do because anyone who believes something like this I if anything they would see these parents as martyrs if they were punished in any way.
Rym: and thus that leaves us with the final order, which is revenge and Revenge, I think while it is a very ingrained part of human society Revenge for the sake of revenge as opposed to quote unquote revenge for a deterrent effect.
Rym: That is measurable.
Rym: it's kind of like the difference between I'm a general and I'm in an army and I in a country invades my country so I March into their capital burn it to the ground and utterly destroy all of their armies.
Rym: I go far above and beyond and At least that's a deterrent effect in that.
Rym: Alright the horrible thing I have done is done, but it will prevent a future horrible thing from happening.
Rym: But a lot of people say they're doing something like that but what they're actually doing what is truly in their hearts is nothing more than revenge and The deterrent effect is little or nothing.
Rym: I point to many instances of the death penalty being enacted in the United States.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I don't like even if I was the king of the world Right, like.
Scott: I don't feel like a desire for revenge on these people.
Scott: I just feel a need to set these people straight, but then you know you get in Anti freedom there, you know some, you know reeducation 19 1984 style.
Rym: punishment should only exist to change Future behavior for the better or to help.
Rym: it should never be solely to harm.
Rym: But we've already shown that there's really no punishment.
Rym: I think that could have any effect on anyone else committing a crime like this and There's very little we can do against these people.
Rym: So the only option is to I don't know commit them.
Rym: But we don't have the in the asylum infrastructure in this country that we need.
Scott: well because we had Asylums and they were terrible.
Scott: The thing is instead of reforming them to make them not terrible We just got rid of them.
Scott: and now all the people who normally would be in asylum are either in prison I'm on the street prison or they're homeless.
Scott: or they're these people.
Rym: and Also if we if we agree that the only option is to commit them because they are a danger to themselves and others But they mean no harm and prison is no option because the deterrent effect will.
Rym: there is no deterrent effect.
Rym: it won't deter anyone else from doing things like this.
Rym: all it will do is punish.
Rym: so a reasonable asylum something that barely exists in this country is the only option.
Rym: but that brings up my final point.
Rym: if People who do have had these beliefs are committed to an asylum for having these beliefs and for acting on them.
Rym: I honestly contend that the beliefs of Christianity Islam and religious Judaism are no less crazy and make no less sense.
Rym: The only difference is that those people either act out fewer of their beliefs or believe in fewer of these things.
Scott: Or they you know, they say they believe but they don't really which is a lot of people.
Scott: I mean, I really think that the vast majority of people are good intentioned even the crazy Suicide bombers, you know, they they have good intentions.
Scott: Like they think that what they are doing is good No one thinks I'm evil.
Scott: I'm going to take over the world.
Scott: Mwahahaha.
Scott: They think that what they are going to do is going to make the world a better place Because they believe that if they do this then this will happen and then something else will happen and then there'll be some sort Of you know paradise on earth when everyone believes in Muhammad and whatnot.
Scott: now the thing it's everyone has good intentions.
Scott: They just because they don't believe in things.
Rym: Christian saying that the road to hell is paved with good intentions.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, they The things that they believe are about the real world are not true.
Scott: Therefore when they try to make decisions about how to affect the real world Their decisions do not get the results that they desire because they are but those decisions are based on false information.
Scott: So only people who believe in just what's real or what's you know?
Scott: Very probable are you know going to almost always make the best decisions that are possible?
Scott: Given the resources and knowledge available to the human race at this time, so I respect philosophy.
Rym: I Deeply respect spirituality.
Rym: Actually my thing of the day will be very relevant to that.
Scott: Are you gonna use that one?
Rym: I have to.
Rym: it's too relevant.
Rym: All right spirituality and philosophy and thought experiments and possibilities and optimism and hope are very important things.
Rym: and There's a lot out there in this universe and we haven't seen even a fraction of it.
Rym: So Saying that there's nothing out there that we could that we couldn't comprehend or nothing out there.
Rym: That's special and nothing out there That's crazy or nothing out there.
Rym: That's amazing or nothing.
Rym: even saying that out there somewhere There couldn't be beings that are like gods or like aliens anything like that None of that.
Rym: It's it's not even an issue because it could be out there.
Rym: The possibility is there.
Rym: and a lot of people misrepresent atheism as not say they say they think that atheism means that there is no chance of spirituality that There is that there is a belief that there is absolutely no chance.
Scott: Yeah, you'll see a lot of people say I'm not atheist of agnostic blood when really no you're you're atheist.
Scott: You just you don't.
Scott: you don't like the word atheism or you know, you don't understand.
Rym: atheism does not mean that I believe earnestly and truly that there is nothing in this world outside of what I observed.
Rym: it means that I only Accept as true in my life things that have been observed and everything else.
Scott: And because it's I mean it could be.
Scott: but if I made my decisions based on things that could be Then how would I make a decision based on anything?
Scott: I mean, you know a lightning could strike randomly.
Scott: Maybe I shouldn't step forward one space, you know, maybe I should walk backwards instead?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: so.
Rym: at the same time there are a lot of closely held beliefs and a lot of hosts closely held philosophies and things people feel in their hearts.
Rym: and that's one thing and This is the other problem that a lot of times the arguments of atheists are conflated with general arguments against believing in anything.
Rym: and That is why I really have to say that I can't say if you believe something That I agree or disagree with it until I've thought about it and there are an infinite number of possible things that you could believe or hope for.
Rym: but what I can say is that if it presented with a specific belief I can evaluate it and That is why regardless of my beliefs and feelings and philosophies and regardless of all the possible things out there that anyone could conceive of.
Rym: I can say very strongly that I believe I Cannot respect a person who honestly believes in Christianity Islam or Judaism or anything else but I do ism.
Rym: Well, I just I don't want to get into the.
Rym: you know There's a million things.
Rym: there's shades and a lot of religious ideas edged toward philosophy and then they're not religion anymore.
Rym: And you can't just say don't believe in anything.
Rym: You can say don't believe in things.
Rym: I haven't seen or you can say I Evaluate statements and beliefs based when they are brought forth.
Rym: You can't argue generally.
Rym: you have to argue specifically.
Rym: So just to clarify it's there I. there are specific things that I don't believe and that atheists in general don't believe Because there is no evidence for and in all of human history There is evidence against.
Rym: we have very clear evidence of the secular origins of Christianity Islam and Judaism.
Rym: We know historically where they came from.
Rym: we can see a lot of where these beliefs evolved.
Rym: We can see about when parts of the Bible were written and which parts were excised and what was changed.
Rym: We know a lot about people who were like Jesus.
Rym: a lot of people claim to be the Jewish Messiah back in the days of Rome so to believe in these things where there is no evidence for and Some evidence against is ludicrous and I really can't Fathom or respect people who actually believe in these specific three things.
Scott: and when I do see people who are like that Because I have good intentions and because I make decisions based on you know What I see and what you know is is real the colloquial real, you know I just I have to try my best to you know, help the people, you know The the people who believe in Jesus and stuff.
Scott: They're always trying to help people because they think that if they convince people to believe in Jesus They'll help them.
Scott: and you know, everyone's like, oh, they're they're pushy.
Scott: We don't like people pushing stuff.
Scott: But you know, I might you know, there's something to say about trying to you know, push things and other people.
Scott: But if I would have successfully pushed, you know atheism on this family, I would have saved someone's life whereas, you know pushing Jesus would have not helped.
Scott: because So, you know while it may look like we're arrogant and pushy and trying to you know You say oh, we're no better than Jehovah's Witnesses trying to convert people blood.
Rym: I just want to clarify.
Rym: when Scott says we I don't think he means myself and him specific.
Scott: No, I mean the colloquial.
Scott: we yes atheist the total we Not.
Scott: we mean someone else Me we and everybody.
Rym: but I think it's a very important distinction here.
Scott: Yes Alright, let's go on to things of the day and fun again.
Rym: So moving on to things of the day.
Rym: Here is the thing of the day that I referred to earlier And this let me do mine first.
Rym: Okay, you can do yours first.
Scott: Okay, this is real simple.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: I'm gonna read to you the paragraph.
Scott: This is totally gonna be like the tangent in the middle of the show to lighten it up.
Scott: ready breathe engage your five senses Close your eyes and inhale deeply.
Scott: Be in the present moment.
Scott: Notice the color of the chocolate the glossy shine.
Scott: rub your thumb over the chocolate bar to a release the aromas of Smoked applewood bacon flirting with deep milk chocolate.
Scott: Snap off just a tiny piece and place it in your mouth.
Scott: Let the lust of salt and sweet coat your tongue.
Scott: Moe's bacon bar.
Scott: Applewood smoked bacon plus alderwood smoked salt plus deep milk chocolate.
Scott: 41% cocoa consumed within eight weeks.
Scott: seven dollars and fifty cents.
Rym: that Sounds like one of the most wonderful things that has ever graced this earth.
Scott: I got one more Flying chocolate pig more bacon and chocolate exclamation part solid milk chocolate flying pigs.
Scott: twelve dollars.
Rym: You know, I think I'm wrong.
Rym: There is a God there must be All right.
Rym: So my thing of the day this is kind of shared because Scott and I both wanted to bring this up and this is one Of those things where neither one of us can claim credit like oh, I found this.
Rym: someone posted it in the forum But there's a man whose name was Alan Watts.
Rym: He died a long time ago.
Scott: Not that long ago.
Scott: Just a few decades 1973 this man was born.
Rym: World War one.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, Alan why I'm not gonna talk about Alan Watts?
Scott: I feel like I should do a separate show But we'd have to learn more about Alan Watts because we sort of just discovered him and now everyone's all the smarter people than us Are going.
Scott: oh you morons.
Scott: I can't believe you didn't know who that was.
Scott: But
Rym: what has been posted in our forum is a video that you all should watch because this is a video that kind of Expresses better than I would have been more eloquently and more concisely what I meant by spirituality because you see Scott and I and pretty much everyone in the front row crew and pretty much everyone I Associate with and talk to and know in my life is an atheist and A lot of us are very spiritual and anyone who thinks that's a contradiction needs to watch this video to understand Why I don't think that's the case.
Rym: Mm-hmm this is kind of a a mishmash of things that Alan Watts has said and overlaid with.
Rym: this is some animation and It it's so concisely and perfectly expresses these ideas that there's very little I can say about it other than that the sound that people make when they went when the earth is peopling is Exactly the sound that people make when the earth is people.
Scott: it basically the deal with this video is that?
Scott: The South Park guys took a few things.
Scott: Alan Watts said, you know, they took audio of him speaking.
Scott: You know some sound bites and then they created animations to go with those sound bites and the one you know all of it is fantastic, but of course the part where the apple tree produces apples as compared to the earth producing people is the greatest part and That you know sound effect of the people going Is Awesome,
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I particularly like the line.
Rym: So where there's rocks watch out watch out.
Rym: actually though ugly Fred in the forum was the last person to post in the thread I'm looking at it right now Pointed out that probably the most poignant part and I have to agree Definitely have to agree was the last bit because I see so many people make this mistake in their lives.
Rym: I see people in my current life in the process of making this mistake But I'm not gonna really explain it.
Rym: but here's kind of a quote from the third bit.
Rym: Well, it was a hoax a dreadful hoax because life is music and you were supposed to be singing.
Rym: It's the myth of the real world that we're all supposed to reach some magical fabled day of attainment.
Rym: Well, fuck that it's the biggest lie I was ever told.
Rym: life is real right now and never let anyone railroad your life choices because it's what you're supposed to do.
Rym: that is that's somewhat quoted from ugly Fred in the forum and When you see the third bit, you'll get what I you'll.
Rym: you'll understand the significance of that.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So going to talk about Monty pythons flying circus It's But We took too long.
Rym: Yeah, I don't want to waste Monty Python on either doing a two-hour long show Oh my god, because I want to make some dinner or on, you know, five minutes of talking about Monty Python.
Rym: Also, I don't know if you're all in the mood to hear about Monty Python when effectively we just did in defense of atheism You know, what can we do with the you know, horrible news like that, you know How could I not do that news?
Scott: and then how could we not say everything we said about that news?
Rym: Yeah, there was really and I could have gone on more.
Rym: We kind of actually tried to push ourselves to stop.
Rym: but it's If you ever wondered why we're atheists and why I really don't respect someone who believes that Noah's Ark was literal or that a man named Jesus really ascended into heaven or that there's a god who's going To send me to hell or that a lot.
Scott: I mean think about what that family is probably thinking right now.
Scott: They're probably thinking you know, oh our daughters in heaven.
Scott: Isn't it?
Scott: So great that you know, they're thinking it's great.
Rym: They're probably when They're saying it's great that their daughter has reached the day of attainment that life wasn't a hoax a dreadful hoax It wasn't music and you weren't supposed to be singing.
Scott: Yeah So you want to live in a society where you respect people who believe that it's okay to just not Take your kids to the doctor.
Rym: And then uh, oh, yeah Yeah, I don't know we don't have much else to say.
Rym: we there's no Thursday.
Rym: I look through the calendar that really fits after what we just talked about.
Scott: No, this is unplanned Really?
Scott: We sort of destroyed the.
Scott: the Monty Python shall be pushed to next week.
Rym: Yeah, at least I can say this the Monty Python show will happen next week.
Scott: Yes, and we're probably gonna prepare lots of Bites for it and such.
Rym: Oh well, so I Guess we'll just stop here.
Scott: Do you just want to stop here?
Rym: Yeah, it's been about as long as a normal show.
Rym: unless you have some other I mean I could reiterate my points again.
Scott: Yeah, I guess we could.
Scott: there's really.
Rym: no I mean it's gotten to the point where I don't even have the will to argue much about Religion anymore.
Scott: Yeah, I sort of like I just.
Scott: it seems like when you're trying to get this through to a lot of people It's like they just don't think in The right, you know, they don't think properly they don't and it's it's pretty much impossible to get through to them.
Scott: And it's actually here.
Scott: I got one more thing to say, you know the science-based medicine blog Which is like the best blog in the universe, you know, I'm gonna keep probably bring it up all the time.
Scott: now.
Scott: There's a great article About when impressive science fails to impress patients, right.
Scott: and it says, you know doctors You know the way they think right is?
Scott: they look at like You know a whole bunch of little tiny people's and like a big You know bowl and then they're not at the level of the people's they're way up high.
Scott: There was little people's in a bowl, you know.
Scott: And some of the people are exercising and some of the people are not exercising and they see that after an amount of time You know the not exercising people are you know dying off a lot faster than the exercising people, right?
Scott: So they're like hi exercise is good But down on the level of the people right the people just looking to their left and to their right.
Scott: the people are exercising and not Exercising right.
Scott: one of the not exercising people looks to the right and they see an exercising person like break their hip You know exercising.
Scott: they see another exercising person pull a muscle.
Scott: They see another exercising person like die from overexerting themselves or you know, you know hurting themselves.
Scott: Well, you know mountain climbing or something like that.
Scott: and they go.
Scott: Oh hell.
Scott: no and it scares them away, you know and they don't think in the same way and I don't know.
Scott: It's it's like is there?
Scott: I Really been questioning?
Scott: if someone doesn't think in the wet in the right way Is it possible?
Scott: You know just later in life to get them to think the right way?
Scott: or you know People didn't think the right way originally didn't realize it.
Rym: Well, I don't think we I mean instead of saying the right way I'll just say to having a illogical and rationally skeptical outlook on life or just Rationally evaluating the the evidence that has been presented to you in the world and making decisions based upon it.
Rym: I mean, I've noticed that whenever I argue with someone about religion Almost never in my life has anyone made to me in an argument about religion a rational argument.
Rym: I've never heard one in our forums.
Scott: No one has even come close and they always just you know appeal to emotions or They.
Rym: the worst thing is when I may like whenever there's an argument you see this all the time and even like one-to-one forget the forums.
Rym: in my own life It seems like no one has ever answered any concern I have brought up.
Rym: they simply bring up another one of their prone points and if I refute it, they just ignore that I refuted it and bring up another one of their points and They just that there's always something there's no end.
Rym: There's no argument that would convince them.
Rym: There's no argument that we even get through to them or that they would even address.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if I have a giant wall made of bricks.
Scott: Right, and I see that they don't have a wall made of they don't have any bricks at all.
Scott: They've got nothing.
Scott: So I say hey, you've got nothing.
Scott: they say.
Scott: Oh, but watch this.
Scott: I'm gonna poke one of your bricks out.
Scott: I win I see you.
Scott: So I'm like, I've still got all these other bricks here.
Scott: They'd be like, ah, there's a hole in your brick wall.
Scott: I'd like.
Scott: you don't have anything.
Scott: It's someone with nothing no leg to stand on, you know versus my mountain of bricks that maybe they can poke a whole few holes in.
Scott: but then I patched them right up and They act like they've won.
Scott: when they poked a tiny hole when they've got nothing I mean it just it's still.
Rym: it harkens back to me to the day when I was in high school.
Rym: I might have told this on the show before but it's so relevant.
Rym: I was.
Rym: I was sitting in an 11th grade or 12th grade.
Rym: I forget what grade it was, but it was.
Rym: it was a class about world government and we're learning about the you know beliefs in sacred cows and The.
Rym: a student raises their hand and you know ask like where does belief come from?
Rym: We start talking all about it and the secular origins of this belief which are actually clearly known through like it's.
Rym: it's.
Rym: it's ludicrously clear Like what pressures on society cause these beliefs to come into play.
Rym: We know exactly.
Rym: So she asks like after we learn all this you raises her hand again after a moment thought and asks Well, why doesn't someone just tell them that that's where their belief came from?
Rym: and I point out that this girl was in fact a very Devoured Christian mmm, and I remember the teacher looked at her and he was a man I respected and he couldn't really get into the argument because there's
Scott: a tea is a public school teacher and he get in trouble.
Rym: But it was you could at that moment.
Rym: You could look around the room and five or six people looked around the room and we all kind of met eyes with and there was this revelation of Well, we all understand the irony of this and the teacher met all of our eyes and he understood the irony of this and no one else in the room did.
Rym: and That girl never.
Rym: I don't want to get into all the stories of high school things since then but that girl never Changed or learns.
Rym: Yeah, she was she.
Rym: I don't think she had the capacity to understand the irony of what she had just asked.
Scott: Yeah, and what do you do in a world where you know, ethically and morally we have we've sort of you know All people are equal or should be treated equally.
Rym: yet All people should be true in that or any bill.
Rym: in terms of speech in terms of beliefs in terms of ideas Anyone is free to make whatever assertions they so desire.
Rym: but at the same time as a human being they must be willing to deal with the fact that other human beings may make counter-assertions and that You do you're respected.
Rym: everyone who is alive gets respect as a living being.
Rym: they get respect as a human but that does not mean that they get respect as an intelligent human.
Rym: and If someone believes in something crazy I still respect their rights and I respect that they exist and they can do whatever they want as long as they don't harm others But at the same time I cannot respect them.
Rym: I cannot let things that they say that I disagree with or that I can prove wrong stand.
Rym: I can't just look.
Rym: it's like if you're in a restaurant and someone just stands up and starts yelling and screaming about how The steak that they're eating is actually full of cockroaches.
Rym: and I look and it's a perfectly fine steak.
Rym: and they keep yelling That is full of cockroaches.
Rym: So I bite a piece.
Rym: I take a piece and I eat it and I say look it's steak I'm eating it.
Rym: It tastes like steak.
Rym: I get ten other people to bite it.
Rym: a scientist come in and says it's steak.
Rym: I can't just let them continue to say without someone refuting it that it's actually cockroaches.
Rym: that's such a Crime against logic for me to stand idly by when someone makes an unfounded and irrational assertion.
Scott: I think the thing that bothers me most and has gotten me so, you know basically reinforce the idea in me that maybe some people are beyond helping is that You keep going back to the Flying Spaghetti Monster and Nobody ever.
Scott: you just say Flying Spaghetti Monster Hello, and then no one ever says anything back to it at all.
Scott: They just run it.
Scott: They just do something else.
Scott: They don't no one ever.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: that's the end of the argument.
Scott: I mean the Flying Spaghetti Monster.
Scott: it there's no evidence for it.
Rym: or by any of that arguments farms.
Rym: I mean You're the classic argument that a lot of people have made to Christians that well, do you believe in Odin?
Rym: No, I do not.
Rym: So you do not believe that Odin exists.
Rym: Nah, how about Thor?
Rym: How about Zeus?
Rym: How about Quetzalcoatl?
Scott: How about wait, I do believe in Quetzalcoatl, but how about this?
Rym: How about that?
Rym: So so what do you believe in?
Rym: and they'll say God?
Scott: How is that any different?
Rym: Well that that's because the classic line is always.
Rym: well It seems to me that we're both atheists.
Rym: I just believe in one less God than you.
Scott: Yeah, and no one ever.
Scott: no one has anything to say to that.
Scott: I mean honestly, I want to have an argument where pretty much the other person is forced to reply to that.
Scott: I mean as opposed to going off on some other tangent about BS reply to that argument and that argument only.
Rym: I've never in my life read or heard and I've sought them out an answer that even begins to address that.
Scott: Yeah, I mean what.
Scott: how is you know, the Christian God more likely than Zeus.
Scott: Well, a lot of people believe in the Christian God.
Scott: Well, a lot of people believed in Zeus.
Scott: a lot of people believe in a lot.
Scott: Yeah, that's an argument.
Scott: I'm ad populum next of course.
Scott: I know there's a Bible.
Scott: There are a lot of books about Zeus and they're a lot older than the Bible next.
Rym: It's a funny thing is I especially when I was reading a lot of Plutarch and I forget the exact passage.
Rym: I've been reading a lot of kind of first-hand historical text and there's nothing more fascinating to me than Reading a history book from ancient Rome about ancient Greece.
Rym: That there's something special about that and the fact that like the ancient Greeks would study the ruins in Egypt and try to figure out what they were and it all.
Rym: it's fascinating but there was a lot of talk about how the ancient Greeks were superstitious and the early Romans were superstitious and they believed in these silly things that we now know are silly and he talked Mentioned many times and there's a lot of evidence actually that a lot of the things that you know people say yes the Romans believed in Jupiter and Mars and all these things.
Rym: but there's a lot of evidence that the state religions of well, I guess the overarching state religion and by the way, Rome was actually a Surprisingly and I say probably surprisingly.
Rym: I mean one of the most tolerant ever Societies in terms of tolerating religion separate Christians to the lions and such.
Rym: but a lot of that didn't happen.
Rym: And also, I mean it's even more complicated than that the only reason the Jewish people were persecuted was that they resisted a kind of a false belief in that.
Rym: Generally from what I've read the Roman state religion was not a religion in that Very few Romans if any truly and actually believed like well Jupiter's up there and he's gonna kick my ass Yeah, they're all they were all.
Rym: you know, hail Caesar they weren't hail Jupiter Mars like Swearing the oath to the religion or swearing the fealty or any of those things Was not so much an exercise in believing in the Roman God.
Rym: They couldn't care less.
Rym: It was an exercise in Acknowledging Roman culture and acknowledging that you are now a part of this large overarching Centralized world.
Scott: it was more of a symbolic thing.
Scott: Jupiter wasn't treated the same way that say, you know The Christian God or Jesus is treated and I was treated more the same way.
Rym: We treat like the statue of justice at the courthouse and I read time and time or like Paul Bunyan Yeah, or Johnny Appleseed Yep but I read time and time again that the Romans were more.
Rym: they were puzzled that.
Rym: why do these people not accept this simple gesture?
Rym: they actually believe in this other weird thing and It also didn't help that the Jews were revolting.
Rym: Yeah, it's pretty much There's a classic joke and you didn't jump on it.
Scott: Well, I know that but what are they up to now?
Rym: Yeah It's a classic joke.
Scott: Yeah, I know and I'm not a fan.
Scott: I never thought that joke was funny.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I find it funny only if it's done in a silly voice.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, it's like they were mostly Persecuted.
Scott: not because we don't like you you believe some crazy thing.
Scott: It was mostly.
Scott: you're revolting and causing trouble.
Scott: So stop causing trouble.
Scott: yeah, and it just like you know, these parents cause trouble and Crusades cause trouble and fake medicine causes trouble.
Rym: Ah the Crusades.
Scott: Yeah, are we done?
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: I think once we get to the Crusades, that's like our Godwin.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.