Rym: It's Monday March 24th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight the IT help desk.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: God when we get a real studio am I gonna have to save that stupid blue chair for you?
Scott: What what about the blue chair?
Rym: What are you gonna sit in when we record gig nights in the studio?
Scott: my freedom chair?
Rym: You're so reclined.
Rym: Yeah, you're reclined to an extreme amount.
Scott: if you're in a reclining chair, and there's no one behind you and no one in front of you Why ever would you not at least partially recline?
Scott: I mean you might not want to fully recline because then you sort of had to pick your head up.
Scott: if you want to look at something like a TV, but Always at least partially recline at least do the leg rest thing.
Scott: Hey, why wouldn't you anyway?
Rym: I just really don't want to ever have to like.
Rym: I kind of want to leave that chair here when we move out Cheers not so good.
Rym: You know hard.
Rym: It was to get it up those stairs.
Rym: the bottom kept falling out.
Scott: Yeah, I think if we move we're gonna need to get like.
Scott: you know we're actually into pay some dump to take away shit.
Rym: Yeah, Craigslist, man.
Scott: Yeah that too All right, so remember.
Scott: I don't know when it was but recently We talked about how we went to that haircut place in the train station.
Rym: that was really convenient But sort of expensive and you needed that haircut to match your purse right and those shoes.
Scott: people are going like oh $30 for a haircut.
Scott: you're crazy.
Rym: Meanwhile because I happen to have long hair even though I'm a guy I had to pay 60-something dollars.
Scott: All right, so I want a haircut this morning, and so I went in there and the first thing I realized Is that the first time I went there all right?
Scott: Which is the only.
Scott: I've only been there twice is the second time.
Scott: the first time I went there I had apparently gotten there really early.
Scott: like before most of the people who work there got there So it was like the only I was.
Scott: I must have been the first one there that morning.
Scott: So like the only like girl there washed my hair and like the only guy there cut my hair, right?
Scott: But today I got there a little later and like all the working be all the people were there all the barbers and such and The whole other side of that place is like a barbershop, but not just you know.
Scott: It's like a real barbershop, and I was like aha yeah, I gotta go to that side where the men go.
Rym: It depends on what you're getting done.
Rym: I mean I get the nice head massage and that you know the wash.
Scott: They wash your hair, and they cut your hair and whatever.
Scott: Some um you know I like I'm.
Scott: it's kind of shabby because I didn't even shower this morning and whatever you know because if someone Else is gonna wash my hair.
Scott: Why should I wash my hair?
Scott: Right it's like dentist the morning.
Scott: I go to the dentist.
Scott: You don't brush your teeth.
Rym: Yes, you do.
Scott: You brush your teeth the night before maybe but oh good.
Rym: God you brush your teeth in the morning.
Rym: There's nothing dentists hate more because remember they're not brushing your teeth.
Rym: It's not what they do there.
Rym: No, they're getting rid of the plaque.
Rym: if all it does is make your stay much longer and more uncomfortable I'm told the dentist my uncle.
Rym: I'm gonna torture him Brush your teeth before you go to the dentist.
Rym: for the love of God.
Scott: No don't don't?
Scott: what are you paying for?
Rym: I'm paying to remove plaque and make sure I don't have Gingivitis.
Scott: so the plaque should be removed when you brush.
Scott: it would be tartar that you would scrape off.
Rym: I believe no plaque is what you're having a scrape.
Rym: anyway tartar can be removed.
Rym: I believe plaque cannot.
Rym: do we have to look up Wikipedia?
Scott: Why don't we call a dentist?
Scott: because neither of us are dentists.
Rym: we have any dentist listeners.
Rym: I know we have a lot of lawyers.
Scott: That would be a very.
Scott: we do have a lot on.
Scott: well We have a. I think it is.
Scott: is that the lawyer?
Scott: Here's my thinking.
Rym: oh because I wonder if you have the same thinking I do.
Scott: is that lawyers the kind of people who are lawyers are much more likely to be like Participants because they're you know that they like to talk back.
Rym: Oh wow I was gonna say it much more bluntly.
Rym: I think lawyers are more argumentative.
Rym: Yeah, and because of the somewhat adversarial style of our show It's very easy to decide that maybe an argument should happen.
Scott: Anyway, so I went to that place this morning.
Scott: I went to the barber side some old guy.
Scott: I was like hey come on.
Scott: I'm like all right, and I'm like he's like do you want to shave?
Scott: and I'm like Why not yeah?
Scott: I'll get a shave.
Scott: what the hell?
Rym: Did you get one of those nice straight razor shaves?
Scott: Yeah, except it wasn't so nice really.
Scott: yeah come look at my face.
Scott: It's not too.
Scott: Good.
Scott: It looks good from far away.
Scott: Ah, but it was.
Scott: I could have shaved myself better.
Scott: It's actually under.
Scott: my chin is unshaven spots, and it was all scraping.
Rym: did he actually use a straight razor?
Rym: Yeah, you probably just sucked.
Scott: I think you just sucked.
Rym: see the thing is it's I mean people like.
Rym: a lot of people accused us When we first started using these you know old-time razors.
Rym: is that you're just doing it cuz it's cool?
Rym: Now if we were doing it because it's cool We'd be using straight razors, but let me tell you a straight razor is no better than a safety razor.
Rym: in fact He's worse is too less Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's not gonna.
Rym: Give you a better shave, and you're.
Rym: the chance of dying is increased dramatically every morning.
Rym: Yep, I don't want my chance of dabbing.
Rym: I already have to worry about falling over and dying in the shower.
Scott: I don't want to worry about cutting my throat open all right, so I'm like oh well I got at least I'm shaving.
Scott: I mean it wasn't great, but I'm shaving whatever right like I cut my hair.
Scott: He cuts my hair just fine.
Scott: You know washes my hair which is nice because that's what I needed cuz they didn't wash it this morning.
Scott: Yeah, and then you know I leave you know how much that was how much it's $50 $20 for a bad shave.
Rym: I'll shave you for less than what he charged.
Scott: yeah for $20 I could have bought in 20 razor blades more than 20 remember I know I could buy like four four packs.
Rym: So and that's the platinum coated nice ones.
Rym: if you're willing to get the cheap ones god They're like five cents each.
Scott: I know right, so it's like wow okay.
Scott: I'm not getting a shave here again.
Scott: Maybe oh, maybe I don't even know if it's worth it for the $30 haircut.
Scott: cuz while the $30 haircut You know it was a fine haircut.
Scott: You know and I got my hair washed, which is you know what I wanted.
Scott: Still I mean like it wasn't that it wasn't twice as good as a $14 haircut, so yeah Alright, but anyway.
Rym: It is tech day It is you know science and technology and all that and a lot of tech news happened in the last week And we're gonna have to skip most of it because we don't want the show to just be one of those tech news round up.
Scott: Yeah, you can listen to it or something.
Scott: It's not we're not to it.
Scott: We refer to them often because they're like you know sort of hard not to refer to when you're a podcast about technology And they're the biggest podcast about technology.
Rym: Yeah, plus you know we have special episodes.
Rym: Tech news roundup is code for we totally didn't feel like doing a show and it happens to be Monday and now that we have our alternating IT CS Mondays, that's not gonna be a problem.
Rym: Yeah, so what should I talk about?
Rym: I could talk about Pakistan breaking the internet or I could talk to old news isn't it?
Rym: It's not that old all right plus the five mean it was like a week and a half ago plus the follow-up stories have been Going up until today.
Scott: Oh, I didn't know their follow-up stories.
Rym: Oh there were a lot of follow-up store.
Rym: But now what I'm gonna talk about is something that oh, I know you're talking about.
Rym: so here's the deal.
Rym: Google unveiled something amazing and awesome, and you they've had this functionality before but they've kind of taken it to the next level.
Rym: It's kind of a search within a search.
Rym: So I search for like Best Buy and I end up on Best Buy.
Rym: so now I can search In Best Buy or in the search results that I just had or more stuff.
Scott: Yeah, but let me explain that.
Scott: So you go to Google.
Rym: I was about to but you go ahead you go to google.com.
Scott: right okay?
Scott: I'm going to google.com.
Scott: I type in Wikipedia right.
Scott: it takes It doesn't take you directly to Wikipedia unless you push the I'm feeling lucky button right.
Scott: so if you push the search button Or you press enter it takes you to a list of search results because that's what Google does.
Scott: the top result of course is Wikipedia.
Scott: But under that result before the second result which is the main page of Wikipedia English It's a. there's a little text box that says and then a button and the button says search Wikipedia org.
Scott: so I could actually go in that search Wikipedia org and type in farts and click on it and now It'll actually you know search with site colon Wikipedia org.
Rym: so see that this isn't new functionality.
Rym: You could search with site colon a site forever.
Scott: Yeah, that's always existed.
Scott: in fact It's very useful because you ever have a site with a really shitty search engine.
Scott: Okay, every website right if it it's much easier to search those websites with Google than it is with their shitty search engine.
Scott: So you do is you want to search and gadget?
Scott: don't go to engage it and use the engagement search box Go to Google and if you want to search and gadget for I don't know phones type phones space site si te colon and gadget comm and press enter and you will get Google search results But you will only get search pages results that are at in gadget comm.
Rym: It's super useful pretty much to make this easier like if you search for a retailer or something big like Best Buy or whatever.
Rym: it'll do that thing Scott said and it'll make it really easy for people who don't know about all the kind of syntax because you Can put a lot of interesting syntax and arguments into a Google search if you know how to do it Mm-hmm, but they're making it really easy.
Rym: now A lot of people are spreading some thought about this and more importantly a lot of people are really Really really angry about this and I I think those people can die in a fire But I also think they can go ahead and fire.
Rym: I think I need to explain a little bit about exactly why this is a concern and what the deal is.
Rym: Alright, so in the old days I'd have to go to Best Buy and use their crappy search and I could find stuff on the Best Buy website Marginally and I was it.
Rym: and even if Best Buy had a great search it could only find stuff on Best Buy.
Rym: now Let's say I use the Google thing.
Rym: alright, I'm searching on Best Buy site with Google and it's a much better search already.
Rym: and Because I'm searching on Google technically I just happen to be searching Best Buy's content.
Rym: I See all the ads the Google ads like I would if I was searching on Google.
Rym: now Let's say I search for a certain brand of cell phone that I know Best Buy sells.
Rym: Well, I'll see the Best Buy link in the Best Buy price.
Rym: I'll also see ads for all the competitors who are also selling that cell phone.
Scott: Yeah, like the Google ads basically did.
Scott: the difference here the things that the website operators are complaining about is now people who want to search for things on Where they normally would have gone to Best Buy calm and done a search.
Scott: that means they would have loaded multiple Best Buy pages.
Scott: Now the person is going to be loading a bunch of Google pages and maybe one Best Buy page if they end up going to a Best Buy page at all.
Rym: Now consider the following quote.
Rym: this pretty much sums up the jackasses.
Rym: who are against this?
Rym: Google is showing a level of aggressiveness with this that's just not needed said one quote internet consultant.
Rym: Take for instance a test where users of Google searched the Washington Post and were given a secondary search box.
Rym: Those who type two jobs into that second box saw related results from the post employment pages, but the results were bombarded by Advertisements for competing employment sites like Career Builder or Monster.com.
Rym: So even though the user began the process by stating their intention to reach the post Google's ad steered them to some of their competitors.
Rym: now It seems to me that the only argument anyone has against this functionality is That now it is easier for people to compete with you.
Rym: Capitalism I think this is great.
Rym: if I search on Best Buy and I want to buy I don't know some CDRs And I see a Google ad that says hey those exact CDRs that Best Buy is charging 10 bucks for We'll give them to you for five.
Rym: Well, what's wrong with that?
Rym: That's gonna put a lot of pressure on P. It's gonna make prices come down.
Rym: It's good for everyone But people who can't actually compete in a free market and rely on the fact that consumers are generally ignorant or Rely on the fact that while all the information is technically available.
Rym: It's difficult to get all that information together.
Rym: Google more and more.
Rym: But the beauty of Google is not so much that they allow you to find information It's that they allow you to find the same like stratum of information across different sources.
Rym: and by bringing that information together Consumers can be so much more informed and no one can get away with having high prices ever.
Scott: yeah, Google is uh Pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, but and I you know if you read the article You'll see that pretty much everyone complaining against this just either really doesn't understand it or understands it all too.
Scott: Well Yeah, they're crazy SEO bastards.
Rym: Yeah, but seriously I I Mean I could see a lawsuit or something coming out of this But I imagine Google would win and I have yet to see any legitimate argument against Google doing well.
Scott: They never complained before.
Scott: now They're only complaining because suddenly there's a text box and a button making a feature that's existed for a long time easier to do.
Scott: If it wasn't a problem to do it before why is it suddenly?
Scott: it shouldn't be a problem to make it easier?
Rym: Well, remember these retailers have always had a history of this sort of thing.
Rym: I mean if you ever want to see an example of this go to like a Best Buy or Circuit City or whatever with a big old notebook and Walk-around writing down prices of things.
Rym: There's a good chance.
Rym: You'll be kicked out within a few minutes.
Rym: Mm-hmm because retailers that I don't even get into that suffice to say I said it.
Rym: I said it.
Rym: You didn't want me to say it, but I said it Google's doing nothing but good here, and I don't think I can beat that horse further.
Rym: No, so what do you got for me?
Scott: So I remember all that satellite radio.
Scott: I mean satellite radio feels to me like it was really big Few years ago, and it's sort of gotten a little.
Scott: they like.
Scott: they said they were gonna merge Or maybe there was gonna be a merger and then it was quiet, and it seems like you know satellite radio sort of been Since then.
Rym: satellite radio would have been great if I didn't have podcasts iPod and my own music collection.
Scott: Yeah, but basically they they you know.
Scott: the question was are we gonna let these guys merge?
Scott: and the answer is yes.
Scott: And they basically said the obvious Statement of the Department of Justice antitrust division is decision blah blah blah.
Scott: Basically evidence does not establish.
Scott: the combination of radio providers substantially reduce competition.
Scott: Basically the summary it up.
Scott: They said there were too many other options, so Combining all the satellite radios isn't a big deal because there's other there's am/fm radios and there's internet radios and whatnot.
Scott: so it's not A big deal huh.
Rym: that's like the opposite of what happened with dr.
Rym: Pepper back in the when coca-cola tried to buy them out.
Scott: yeah, but yeah Radio is sort of a weird thing because it's sort of cool in that you can it's you really high-quality radio Right if you can have live stuff on it.
Scott: Just like broadcast radio, but there's.
Scott: no it's a lot easier to get reception.
Scott: You can get a lot more channels you.
Scott: the audio quality.
Scott: I think is better.
Scott: It must be right.
Scott: There's a lot less commercials if if there's any commercials at all.
Scott: I don't know that much about it.
Scott: I never actually listen to it.
Scott: And there's a lot more selection of stuff And you can actually get some pretty niche weird kind of stuff on there.
Scott: like.
Scott: I know There's a lot of podcasts that just they play on their podcasts on the internet And then they play on satellite radio also.
Scott: just you know the satellite radio provider takes the podcast and puts it on the satellite radio.
Scott: It's actually looks a jewel time.
Rym: I actually really looked into doing that for GeekNights and the only reason we haven't done it is that it's kind of a Gigantic pain in the ass.
Scott: yeah Your show has to be like exactly like to the second a certain length And you have to put little noises in your show so they know.
Scott: so the automatic Satellite radio system can insert your audio and pretty much I'm nothing.
Rym: we're never gonna be syndicated like that unless we get to the point where we have paid staff to deal with all that Crap for me.
Scott: yeah pretty much.
Scott: Yeah, I think this is pretty interesting.
Scott: I mean this is either going to result in You know both the satellite radio going.
Scott: uh this is tote the whole.
Scott: I mean you have an entire industry embodied in one company right so it's a lot easier than other industries.
Scott: you go How's the industry doing?
Scott: is a lot of companies and some are doing good and some are doing bad?
Scott: You're like the whole industry's in one company.
Scott: So we know if satellite radio is a good idea or not based on the success of this.
Scott: now one company.
Scott: but The question will be is it is it gonna succeed or is it is it blend?
Scott: Yeah?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I Satellite radio, there's some things.
Scott: I like about it, but really I'm not.
Scott: you don't see me buying it.
Rym: I think that the main reason why I would never consider satellite radio is that it's still push rather than pull I mean, it's not like well.
Rym: I mean
Scott: you have a lot more choices, so it's a little bit of pull I mean, but
Rym: not really it has the same pull that cable TV
Scott: Exactly got
Rym: a thousand channels, but if I want to listen to like whatever and whatever's on at eight o'clock I'm pretty much screwed unless it's eight o'clock, or I have some sort of TiVo for my radio.
Scott: see like cable television.
Scott: I think that satellite radio would do well to move to some sort of on-demand type Programming.
Rym: yeah, but the infrastructure really isn't fully in place for that especially because every time anyone tries to do something like that Especially with radio it seems like everyone in the industry jumps down their throat and starts screaming about copyright.
Rym: And you see there is.
Scott: there was some sort of on-demand radio.
Scott: That would be.
Scott: that's it for podcast you know because that's really.
Scott: that's the one reason I want to have a moat like the iPod.
Scott: if you want to get podcasts on the iPod you have to plug it in to a Computer and sync it with iTunes.
Scott: if the iPod could just get podcasts on its own Right had iTunes or podcatcher built into it or any other mp3 playing device.
Scott: That's the same thing as on-demand radio because you could just browse the web find any podcast Get the episode no matter where you are as long as you have Wi-Fi, and then it's on-demand radio.
Scott: And that is what we really need.
Scott: and satellite radio could beat the podcast mobile device to it if they moved.
Scott: But I don't see them moving well.
Rym: There are a lot of limitations.
Rym: I mean remember satellite radio is Not exactly to weigh.
Scott: Yeah, I think another problem with satellite radio is that they all all the devices seem to be like these car devices.
Scott: You know where's the carry in my pocket satellite radio.
Scott: Do they make one of those?
Rym: see what I would have done if I was setting up satellite radios.
Rym: I would have sold.
Rym: you could buy like base stations for anything once for cars once for RVs once for in your house once for Outside.
Scott: I think they have house ones that you can hook up to your like receiver.
Rym: Oh, yeah But I would have made like all those things.
Rym: and then the simple way is you what you get for your subscription is like a Little key a little dongle little thing and whatever satellite radio thing you plug it into you get your service Regardless.
Rym: so I can bring my service with me go to my friend's house.
Rym: He has satellite radio course.
Rym: theoretically He should have a dongle, but if you had some sort of subscription model Or you know semi on demand or maybe you pick likes you know all that There are a lot of better ways.
Rym: It could have been handled than it was handled.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like they competed in a market that was on the verge of becoming a different mark.
Rym: well They created the market and then no they were competing in the market of listening to audio when I am not home.
Rym: Yeah, and the problem is they they jumped in with the right technology.
Rym: The problem is they should have jumped in a few years earlier Or they should have jumped in a little bit later, but they would have jumped in like pre iPod.
Scott: I think that like a couple years before the iPod came out I seriously believe the satellite radio would be like the default in cars.
Rym: Am/fm might have died if they'd been around when I was in high school because remember I didn't even have a CD player For a long time and then in my car I had my CD player, and I would make mix CDs.
Rym: I would have paid a lot to have had even an mp3 player, and if there had been satellite radio.
Scott: Oh, man Yep, oh well.
Scott: Well.
Scott: We'll see what comes to this.
Scott: I I'm gonna give it six months or so before we can make a verdict.
Scott: I think they'll definitely last at least that long.
Rym: so I got one more little news partly because a lot of people are probably Somewhat in the dark as to exactly what the deal was with this.
Rym: But I'm sure you've all heard the stories that Pakistan broke YouTube or Pakistan broke the internet something.
Scott: Oh, it's an old story.
Rym: It's not that old a few weeks old, but anyway The fullness of this was that Pakistan ordered all of its ISPs to block access to YouTube because YouTube contains quote blasphemous web content slash movies.
Rym: Now there's some arguments that that might have just been a cover story Because it kind of coincides with a lot of political unrest in Pakistan And there were a lot of videos kind of pointing out certain things about the government in Pakistan at the time.
Rym: But nominally this was partly because of the whole Muhammad cartoons OMG thing.
Rym: well Basically what happened here was that Pakistan said all right YouTube is no longer cool in Pakistan, but what they did is Instead of enforcing it legally they enforced it technologically by advertising false routing information To YouTube's websites these false routes because of the way the internet works partly because people trusted Pakistan Which I don't think anyone wouldn't.
Scott: they just tell all Pakistani ISPs to block traffic to the YouTube IP addresses.
Rym: Well what they did is that's difficult to do yeah, but what they did is they firewall it out.
Scott: I don't know they.
Rym: There's arguments that they did this maliciously uh-huh in order to pretty much censor this as far and wide as they could but no one we can't know for sure because we Don't have access to it really feels.
Scott: it feels to me like an incompetent IT Situation.
Scott: it feels to me like there might have been minor malicious intent But at the same time the people who got poisoned by the bad data.
Scott: it feels like that they that shouldn't happen.
Rym: You're supposed to be able to trust the routing information you get and Regardless of whether or not people did trust it the fact remains that Pakistan was advertising false routes Yep, which is bullshit.
Scott: It is like.
Rym: that is.
Rym: one of the fundamental things that makes the internet Go is that people don't lie about the basic low-level stuff of the internet.
Rym: That's why every now and then when there's a big internet problem It's because one of the high-level providers has had some sort of peering dispute with another high-level provider And that is one of the biggest reasons why we need some more network network neutrality legislation.
Rym: but I digress.
Rym: so Pakistan advertised these false routes and these routes got propagated around the world and that is why There was a period where YouTube was very difficult to access from many parts of the world and a lot of internet traffic was being Routed all over the place in bad ways.
Scott: See the thing is that the thing with that right shouldn't that?
Scott: shouldn't the people?
Scott: I mean if you are in?
Scott: Pakistan obviously the false route will screw you right but Someone if you're somewhere else and you know somehow they advertise this false route Shouldn't you like there should be some sort of?
Scott: there's a hierarchy of authority right?
Scott: I mean the Pakistani ISP Don't you know?
Scott: My big router in the sky isn't gonna listen to them.
Scott: when it comes to where the question of where is you?
Rym: well when it?
Rym: Comes to BGP routes and that I mean routes are summarized in very broad brushes on the internet because broad brush routes take a lot less processing power to deal with and they're less difficult to maintain.
Rym: and basically what happened was there's this kind of implicit trust among high-level ISPs worldwide.
Rym: and My take on all this is that Pakistan then as a nation at least as far as their technology and government is concerned Has violated that trust and I note how it was rather rapid the response of the world in Containing and removing these routes.
Rym: I don't think anyone is ever going to trust routing information that comes out of Pakistan ever again.
Scott: Mmm, and yeah, I there really needs to be like.
Scott: You know some sort of web of trust like.
Scott: I trust these people more than these people more than you know.
Rym: So the problem is something like that requires updates to routing protocols updates to routers.
Rym: It's not easy.
Scott: You can't just like type some things in your Cisco and make it happen.
Rym: Not really Every road routing protocol has its pros and cons and this is usually BGP type stuff.
Rym: I I'll do a show on routing protocol someday in the future.
Rym: I'll warn you.
Scott: It's not interesting Because I the way I you know, cuz I don't know much about the routing prop.
Scott: You know propagation of routes, but I know about like, you know The propagation of DNS and DNS poisoning and it really DNS poisoning is very hard to do.
Scott: But yes, I feel like shouldn't the routing poisoning be?
Rym: Routing is a lot more complicated than DNS.
Scott: All right, tell you what and sometime soon I'll do a show on like routing protocols for dummies like how the internet works like how Like if I set up a DNS server and I my DNS server says Google's up your butt it's not gonna work.
Scott: No one's gonna end up up your butt when they were looking for Google Except maybe the people.
Rym: that's a very I don't know what but that's a very Dave Riley kind of phrase right there.
Scott: No one's gonna end up at up your butt.
Rym: I can actually answer this very broadly and very succinctly.
Rym: The reason DNS is so much more robust against that sort of attack is because DNS is a hierarchy That is a straight-up tree.
Rym: There is a root of DNS a top.
Rym: Yeah, that is the absolute top That is 100% trusted.
Rym: Yeah, and then like there's this hierarchy going down and it's extremely strict hierarchy Mm-hmm.
Rym: The internet is not a hierarchy.
Rym: It's a gigantic messy web.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean I trust sprint more than I trust Pakistan.
Rym: All right, you trust sprint But where do you get your routes from and you have connections all over the world and everyone?
Rym: It's so hard to manage all those routes that a lot of I'll talk about on the show.
Rym: Yeah, but suffice to say Number two, you gotta think of a different phrase instead.
Scott: Someone think of an alternate phrase.
Rym: be that as it may that doesn't quite fit though.
Rym: I like that though, but it means something different.
Scott: I know whatever.
Rym: I could just say something completely random.
Rym: So fizzle bottom your mom your mom.
Rym: Okay Pakistan's mom apparently, uh I had a bunch of other stories that are all related to this because recently a film that was being made about the Prophet Muhammad that may or may not have been casting him in a bad light was taken down by the ISP hosting it on the grounds that was blasphemous.
Rym: and there seems to be more and more a lot of problems in regards to the internet and portrayals of Muhammad.
Rym: and I don't want to get into a religious argument because I don't think this is a religious argument.
Rym: I don't think this has anything to do with religion at all.
Rym: freedom of speech wins Regardless.
Scott: Yeah, it's the same amendment asshole.
Rym: Well in the cut in the u.s.
Rym: See the problem is that there are nations like Pakistan who decide to lie on the internet in order to prevent us from seeing pictures of Muhammad or possibly to prevent us from seeing well prevent Pakistanis from seeing what's actually going on in the government, but fizzle bottom I'm very much getting to the point where I'm sick of this and I'm done with it and I don't know.
Rym: I feel like the bodies that govern the internet and the United Nations should have some sort of universal code of freedom of speech over communication means Yeah, something like that.
Rym: Yeah, but that's a show for another time.
Rym: All right things of the day.
Rym: So you ever get an email from someone where it's from like sprint comm but in the reply to address They don't want you to respond.
Rym: They give you some crap like Blah blah blah at do not reply calm or they make up some address so you can't email them back because they don't want to Get deluged with people who can't read who just hit reply and then just you know, shoot their mouth off.
Rym: I guess that was a rhetorical question.
Rym: I'll continue.
Scott: Yeah, I guess.
Scott: So I was actually reading something.
Rym: This is a very very bad idea and it's something that happens a lot if you spoof the reply headers in An email.
Rym: that is against pretty much every code of conduct and ethics and even some laws on the internet.
Scott: if you do that then pretty much every Email server administrator will be like up blacklist.
Scott: We're done with you.
Scott: Go away.
Scott: We don't want any emails coming from you.
Scott: We don't want to send any emails to you.
Rym: Fuck you, but even beyond that it's also just.
Rym: it's bad practice.
Rym: but it happens a lot too just because people When they follow instructions to set things up with technology a lot of people Don't really read the instructions or don't really understand what they're doing and a lot of people configure routers and switches and things Very badly.
Scott: Well, I think specifically when it comes to email email servers are very hard to set up.
Scott: It's probably the hardest thing to set up there is.
Rym: that's why we use Gmail.
Scott: But anyway, it's like we like Google.
Scott: take care of it.
Rym: Yeah, squirrel mail didn't work.
Rym: So well, no squirrel.
Scott: Well, that's so good.
Rym: but a lot of people will set up even like big companies will set up routers and switches and things to send information or broadcast routes or do things to domains or for domains that they do not actually control.
Rym: and What happens if someone owns one of those domains because there is a gentleman someone who gets my thumbs up of the day For owning the domain.
Scott: do not reply calm and see I wanted to own them domain test calm But I don't know who had food at bar.
Rym: calm would be pretty good to listen to.
Scott: that's a good one.
Scott: There's a lot of.
Scott: there's a whole lot of domains That would be really interesting to get.
Scott: just because the a lot of email is sent to those domains You know by people testing shit out.
Rym: but the the person who runs do not reply.
Scott: comm is brilliant because instead of using this for blackmail or Nefarious purpose I would use if I had test calm I'll use it for nefarious purposes Logging into all sorts of people's test development servers and stealing all their code.
Scott: That's what I would do.
Rym: but a lot of scary things get sent to do not reply.
Rym: comm.
Rym: government documents.
Rym: There's.
Rym: people are saying that actually some of the WikiLeaks things actually come out from this side.
Rym: No, what this guy is like that?
Scott: if that guy, you know, it seems like he's a smart guy I would not be.
Scott: it would be very likely that if he finds interesting things He would send them to WikiLeaks.
Rym: quote from slashdot Apparently everyone from major US banks to the TSA to contractors in Iraq.
Rym: Use some variation of this address in there from fields for all the emails sent out and all the bounced emails go to this, dude Mm-hmm.
Rym: So he pretty much stopped trying to tell people that happens and now he just posts the interesting ones Mm-hmm.
Rym: So this is my thing of the day.
Rym: My head is off to you, sir And if the government ever shuts you down, it'll be a sad day.
Scott: He's not doing anything illegal.
Scott: I don't think he's doing anything legal at all.
Scott: I don't think someone sent him an email to his domain Even if that was by accident.
Scott: if someone sends me something in the mail with my name on it Even if they you know wrote it wrong, you know, maybe they put the wrong thing in the wrong envelope.
Scott: It's mine tough shit.
Scott: That's yeah, that's the way the law is.
Rym: That's the law with physical mail and if it isn't it should be that way with email.
Rym: I believe it is.
Scott: I'm not a lawyer, you know I know but lawyers are always trying to apply the physical world rules to the to the internet and it usually doesn't work.
Scott: This case it works perfectly.
Rym: you ever get an email where at the end someone has this long boilerplate Like if this message was not intended for you, you must delete it.
Rym: You're not allowed to forward this message to anyone.
Rym: That's all.
Scott: that's complete bullshit Cuz.
Scott: I didn't agree.
Scott: I didn't sign anything to agree to that contract and there's no law backing that up
Rym: because it's the same thing that happens with cease and desist orders where someone will Send a cease and desist and in the cease and desist They'll didn't say that it's illegal for you to post or in any way show anyone the cease and desist.
Scott: Yeah, it's like stuff if you get a piece of paper.
Scott: It's like it says top secret eyes only on it.
Scott: Yeah, that means it's not illegal for you to look at it.
Scott: It's just illegal if you you know, like Complicated.
Rym: Yeah, we're not lawyers.
Rym: I'll say this if anyone ever threatens you with something like that call a lawyer.
Rym: The lawyer will probably be able to point out that you don't have to do half of what they're.
Scott: well I wouldn't call a lawyer right away cuz that costs money.
Scott: What I would do is I would first call the bluff.
Scott: then if they you know, well first blood, you know You're not bluffing but you know be like All right Make me.
Scott: and then if they try to make you then called lawyer because odds are if you just put the slightest bit of resistance They'll just go away and won't come back.
Rym: But uh, yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I got a thing of the day here.
Scott: Oh, do you?
Scott: yeah Well, you know when you're web browsing, I mean, I know personally at work, right?
Scott: Multiple virtual desktops, right and I got a lot of windows open and I basically have a Firefox window But I'm like every window.
Scott: cuz I'm developing web applications.
Scott: I'm making websites I'm visiting websites to read things but some websites like good my gmail and stuff.
Scott: I just have open all the time and You know, it's sort of annoying because I sort of use my gmail because I mean it is an application like a web application but since it's also a website I Have it open in Firefox like a website and it sort of doesn't mix in with it's like, you know You have the tabs within Firefox to switch sites But then I also have the virtual desktops and the taskbar in my operating system to switch applications.
Scott: So having some of my applications because they happen to be websites in Firefox It's sort of like this dual task switching system that you know, like I'm used to it and it's fine, but it's not.
Scott: It's not correct in a Semantic sort of way if I guess that's the best word I have.
Scott: So Mozilla if you go to their lab site, they're actually working on this thing.
Scott: That looks really cool called Mozilla prism Mozilla prism and Mozilla prism.
Scott: basically what it does is you can take any web Site that is an application and turn it into an application.
Scott: So for example, I could take mail.google.com, which is Gmail and say hey, yeah Mozilla prism see mail.google.com.
Scott: turn that into an application called Gmail.
Scott: It'll make a desktop icon called Gmail with an icon.
Scott: I can click on it.
Scott: It'll open up Gmail in its own window as if it were a standalone application.
Scott: I can switch to that application using my standard operating system switching stuff But it doesn't have back or forward or location buttons or anything.
Scott: It's just there like, you know an application is and you know, well, I don't think this is like, you know Something you're gonna be replacing your Firefox with because you still need your Firefox for going to the web sites For web applications, especially ones that you keep open a lot.
Scott: I think this is pretty cool.
Scott: I definitely think there's there's something to this here.
Scott: I mean because really it's like, you know, Gmail is an email application.
Scott: Why should it be treated in the GUI in the interface any different from you say outlook?
Scott: You know just because it happens to be a web application and this sort of breaks that barrier and turns web applications into real Applications in your user interface.
Scott: I think that's the way to go and you can actually download this and try this out Which I if you this sounds like something you like go for it.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: Yeah, I like it.
Rym: but anyway to get on to our main bit here as you know Scott and I are kind of Alternating between his field of expertise in my field of expertise, you know IT and CS and it's my turn this week.
Rym: I had a kind of long rambling.
Rym: I was tired.
Rym: I wanted to eat overview of what IT was and We realized pretty much right away that in order to actually talk about IT I have to break it down into all these tiny little pieces and talk about them.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I sort of realized after last my last week's episode just kind of Blair You know, it's like on the one hand I want to break stuff up in the way that I know it But on the other hand if I break it up that way a lot of the episodes are gonna be uninteresting or Boring or unhelpful.
Scott: So as we start out to find a balance between talking about something that people want to know and want to hear and entertaining but also the you know, the Foundation information that sort of we feel needs to be known even if people don't want to know it and it's tough.
Rym: So I'm gonna start tonight by talking about one very important piece of IT and luckily It's something that you can probably all relate to because pretty much that the part the IT that the majority of human beings will ever directly interact with is the help desk
Scott: The
Rym: help desk.
Rym: now there are a lot of ways to define help desk But I'm gonna use a somewhat broad definition that I think serves my purposes very well.
Rym: helpdesk is the interface between IT professionals and IT services and End users.
Rym: now end user does not mean non-technical user.
Rym: I mean Here's two examples of a helpdesk.
Rym: one you work at your job and you use the computer and you print to a printer and the Printer stops working.
Rym: you call the helpdesk and say hey the printers broken and someone comes and fix it.
Rym: so or let's say you work for a major ISP and One of your ds3 circuits goes down.
Rym: So you call the helpdesk at Verizon or XO or whoever and say hey My ds3 is down fix it you assholes Mm-hmm.
Scott: So, you know, what if?
Scott: How about?
Scott: the ones were like I buy a Dell and the Dell doesn't work and I got is that a help desk?
Scott: Does that count or is that like the customer service line?
Scott: is that there's a tech support different than out desk?
Rym: It's tricky actually that the customer support and help desk are interrelated in a lot of companies But they don't necessarily have to be interrelated.
Rym: So I'm gonna take a kind of I'm gonna make up an example company that happens to provide Every possible kind of service in the world and talk about all the different aspects of their help desk and/or customer support.
Rym: All right, that's pretty much the easiest way to go about it.
Rym: I want to preface this by saying that this does not represent any Particular company that I may or may not have worked at in any way as you see here.
Rym: Actually, it really doesn't.
Scott: I'm just I'm saying as you see.
Rym: Yes, I do.
Rym: I don't have to say that just because of the.
Rym: There's also a bunch of other organizations.
Rym: Oh God you know.
Rym: Actually, I'm gonna try to get permission from my company to do a show on how the stupid financial stock markets and everything work.
Rym: It's actually really fascinating, but I gotta actually ask permission before I could talk about it in any depth.
Scott: It's a lot like the grocery market only with a lot more money and a lot less food.
Rym: But anyway.
Rym: So you got a company and you've got employees who do the business to the core business.
Rym: because remember every every company Every profitable company at least I'm not gonna ignore cases like I don't know SEO where there was no core business.
Rym: But in most companies, there's a core business.
Rym: the thing the company does the thing.
Rym: the company makes its money with Selling snake oil.
Rym: the reason the company exists like IBM has a lot of them but like Joey Jojo's tomato stand his core business is Tomatoes.
Rym: he makes his money selling tomatoes.
Rym: Everything else in his business is nothing more than supporting the business of selling tomatoes.
Scott: Yeah, he has a cash register, but that's really just there to help him sell tomatoes.
Scott: He has a truck but that's really just there to help him move tomatoes.
Rym: He has his data center and his Oracle database and his 4ds threes and that's just to help him count how many tomatoes he sold.
Rym: You do you or do you not deny that this shit be banging.
Scott: this should be banging.
Rym: But you really have to understand like in any company, what is the core business?
Rym: And this is something that a lot of computer professionals and technology professionals kind of lose sight of especially in smaller companies.
Rym: It's very easy when you're the tech guy in a company to feel like you are the company and know in the end The core business is the company and you exist solely to make sure that its core business keeps going.
Rym: So different aspects of a helpdesk, let's start on the very broadest level What Scott was talking about.
Rym: there is of course customer support which may or may not be IT and may or may not be help desk.
Rym: Let's call this the tier one of help desk or tier one of support.
Rym: These are typically be completely non technical people who deal with core business problems.
Rym: a customer has a problem.
Rym: They are calling your core business because they have a problem and you need to resolve it.
Rym: So they will continue to send you money in return for goods and services.
Rym: So usually what you have are people who are either Minimum wage grunts or if your company is actually high class or high scale or for whatever reason You might actually have like public relations or consumer relations professionals But regardless there is some sort of interface between the customer and the company.
Scott: So that should be so.
Scott: really someone calling Dell with a problem with their computer Isn't really sort of an IT help desk situation?
Scott: It's the same as if they were calling Joe's tomato stand with a problem about tomatoes.
Rym: Yes, but it can become an IT or a help desk situation because of something a concept called Escalation.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Now, so let's say we've got this tier one, you know Someone?
Rym: I'm Joey Jojo's tomato stand and a customer calls and they've got a problem.
Rym: I don't know what their problem is.
Rym: So I have a generic number.
Rym: any customer can call and the customer says I tried to buy Tomatoes and I was unable to do so.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: Well, how did you try to buy them?
Scott: They collect information and once they collect I put some money in Joe's pocket, but he didn't give me any tomatoes.
Rym: that asshole I screamed at my computer and tomatoes didn't come out.
Scott: You have to wait for them to show up in the mail.
Scott: that man You're not responsible for mushiness.
Rym: So this customer support person will follow up some rules.
Rym: is there some sort of way they have to determine Where the problem is and they may solve the problem on their own.
Rym: They might say oh, well, do you have an account?
Rym: Blah blah blah, but the problem might be a technological problem.
Rym: And if it is then it gets referred to the help desk.
Rym: Now the help desk or IT is still a very multifaceted thing.
Rym: But the way most help desks would be set up is that now if it's an IT problem They would escalate it to either IT, but we'll just call it tier two.
Rym: We're gonna ignore everything that isn't an IT problem.
Rym: So say the problem was the customer Couldn't make the order because they could like.
Rym: the website wouldn't work for them.
Rym: The customer support person isn't going to know anything about that.
Rym: So they escalate it to the tier two.
Rym: support the lowest level of IT support.
Rym: now If a company has a core business that is technology.
Rym: That level is usually the first level you reach.
Rym: like if you call Comcast my cables out you pretty much reach this level immediately.
Scott: Well, the the the first level if you call Comcast would usually be there's a problem with your bill.
Rym: There's a problem, you know, usually the first level is press one if you have a billing problem.
Rym: Well, yes to to report a service.
Rym: Yeah, it would be the tier one support.
Rym: You can automate tier one support in most cases.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but we're gonna skip over that.
Rym: I could do a Thursday show on that business Mm-hmm.
Rym: so these people are kind of like the lowest level of support for external customers and they will try to get enough information to Determine if one is a problem they can solve or two if they need to escalate it either further up the chain or sideways into different components or aspects of your IT help desk infrastructure or Organization depending on how complex you are.
Rym: So say you call and he says can't get to the website.
Rym: So they escalate to tier two the IT help desk and they say that you type in the URL and the guy says yeah What'd you type in?
Rym: I typed in this.
Rym: All right, looks like it's working.
Rym: Yeah, I get some SSL error SSL error you say and then you're looking.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: No one's been able to get to our website for a while.
Rym: So then you escalate to the tier three or the developers or the support, you know some sort of specialized or higher-level group.
Rym: Because like we got a friend who works a help desk and there's different levels and different jobs.
Rym: So if I'm a mot like an early entry-level Lowly paid like I just got my foot in the door.
Rym: I answer the calls from stupid people and or I answer the calls that are simple and if it's a problem that's complex I forward it up to the higher paid people who are more specialized.
Rym: because you if you have someone who is being paid a lot their time is worth X dollars per hour.
Rym: if They have to answer every call that gets sent into a help desk no matter how easy It'll probably answer a lot of them really quickly and really easily and really awesomely.
Rym: But at the same time it's not worth the money it costs to keep them around.
Rym: They should be doing better things for your business.
Scott: Yeah, I mean a person with those skills could be doing other things that make mad monies.
Scott: They're not.
Scott: you know, your business isn't that much better because they answered a bunch of phone calls.
Rym: So theoretically you hire people who can do the blood just what is required at the lower levels and pay them less Because someone who's paid $20 an hour spending four hours working on a problem is a lot cheaper than making the person who's paid $120 an hour even read that email.
Rym: Yep Now don't read from this that low-level tech people are stupid because actually Most low-level tech people that you call are fully qualified to do a lot more.
Rym: They just for various reasons are because of the IT industry are working at that lower level And they just don't have access to the actual decision-making thing.
Rym: That's a whole other.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that said that's a completely separate issue.
Scott: I mean look at all the people with like college degrees working you like Home Depot.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: that's that issue.
Rym: I think yeah, but theoretically in a nutshell.
Rym: now What you do is an IT helpdesk.
Rym: goal is to get a customer who has a problem Figure out at what level that problem needs to be solved Direct it to the level where it can be solved that person solves it and then direct the solution back to the customer.
Rym: Now that's for external customers.
Rym: But why would it be any different for an internal customer?
Rym: It's not if I and it isn't if I've got a prod work for Joey Jojo's shack and I Manage the database server that keeps track of all of his multinational tomato orders.
Rym: So if I have a problem with my PC, all right, I'm a tech professional I work with the database server, but my job is the database server.
Rym: I'm being paid eight thousand dollars a minute to make that database server go.
Rym: if my computer blue screens one day And I can't make it boot?
Rym: What's more worthwhile for me to spend my eight thousand dollar a minute time going to Microsoft's website and?
Scott: Reinstalling windows, I mean cuz.
Scott: he knows how to do that.
Scott: He said, you know, he knows so much about computers.
Scott: He's a database manager.
Scott: He could fix his own computer, but that's not his job.
Rym: like Scott Scott could fix his own computer at his company.
Scott: Sometimes I do Sometimes I don't.
Scott: sometimes I say you fix it It's your job.
Rym: now the scale and scope of these operations really depends on how big your company is.
Rym: If you only have four employees like us now, then people can fix their own stuff.
Rym: or maybe you have one IT guy.
Rym: But if you've got a hundred employees It's probably worth your while to have some sort of dedicated help desk staff to deal with all these problems.
Rym: now even though Help desk is a cost center in that halt the help desk will never make money.
Rym: In fact help desk can only cost money.
Rym: it can never make money.
Rym: But what it can do is reduce operating costs and give you a net Like benefit as in it technically cost you twenty thousand dollars a year to maintain this help desk But in the end it saved you $40,000 worth of people who are more important time resolving simple issues.
Scott: Yeah, cuz think about this fixing up a broken computer a broken Windows computer pretty easy.
Scott: Someone who's not that awesome can probably take care of it.
Scott: They can be awesome, but they don't to be that awesome.
Scott: Okay, so let's say you have a hundred awesome Programmers.
Scott: one of their computers breaks.
Scott: Do you want them to fix the computer or do you want the not?
Scott: Not as awesome guy to fix the computer you just have one spare computer.
Scott: They programmers can all be programming all the time and one guy goes around making sure all the computers work all the time.
Scott: You get a lot more programming done now.
Rym: I've already gone on a little long.
Rym: Yep Cuz I don't want to go into a lot more detail.
Rym: cuz I think you've got the gist of it now.
Rym: What a help desk is what it should do But I want to give you a little bit of nuts and bolts as to how help desk should be set up.
Rym: now I could.
Rym: I'm gonna do whole shows in the future on How to actually set up a help desk and the differences like network operations and production support.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: If you ever go and you see like, you know tech people calling up because they have a problem They always say give me the knock Operation Center, that's what they're all grumpy.
Scott: Give me the knock.
Scott: I don't want to talk to you morons.
Rym: Yeah And those are like the places that have the big screen with like the picture of the network and it's all green and red And then alerts are coming in and all the cool stuff.
Scott: They really exist those places.
Rym: Yes I have.
Rym: actually every company I've worked for has had one and in fact now I kind of sit in one Mmm, and actually IBM's was the coolest.
Rym: but it was the coolest because it was so old school Looked like some Apollo action.
Rym: No, it looked like I don't know.
Rym: It looked like a cold war scene.
Rym: It felt like I could launch nuclear missiles from that place.
Rym: war games.
Rym: It was also fortified.
Rym: I don't think I could express to you how cool it was to be in the knock at.
Scott: IBM should take a picture.
Rym: I got some pictures, but I can't legally show them to anyone.
Scott: That's not cool.
Scott: If I was IBM, I'd want to show it off like check out our cool cold war.
Rym: not know because you'd all go Wow, that's cool.
Rym: But IT people would go Wow Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, I don't want to make fun of IBM too much but My advice to anyone who is managing a help desk or is at a company where there is a help desk or anything even a small company pretty much you want to formalize the processes of a help desk as Early as possible and in fact in general you want to err on the side of overkill because the more informal your processes Are the more completely fucked you are if your organization ever gets bigger or if anyone ever gets fired or leaves or retires?
Rym: It might seem onerous to have like this formal ticketing system where like say at GeekNights Like Scott has a problem with an episode.
Rym: that sounds funny.
Rym: so he goes to the thing and he makes a ticket with a number and he assigns it to me and I open that ticket and I resolve it and I log my solution and then maybe I can't fix it because it's a Libsyn problem.
Rym: So I escalated to Libsyn and I give them a ticket number and they come back to me with that ticket number once they've solved It and then I de-escalate back down to Scott and he approves my solution.
Rym: That might seem like a lot of red tape But you know what if you don't set up at least basic structures like that early on?
Rym: You're so screwed if you ever get bigger like.
Rym: I can't even express to you how many IT companies that are very large have Inadequate business structures for their help disk and as a result spend so much money trying to rectify that.
Rym: I could do a whole show about it and I probably will.
Scott: Yeah It's easy to set up a system when there's only a few people and that's usually why no one sets up a system because you only have a few people.
Scott: what do You need a system for?
Scott: you can just talk and that it works with only a few people.
Scott: But it's easy to set up a system with a few people.
Scott: It's hard to set up a system with a lot of people and if you have a lot of people you need a system.
Scott: so the only way to make things work is either to spend a lot of money and have a pain in the ass or Set up a system when you're small then get big and keep the system and then you won't have to spend a lot of money Or have a pain in the ass
Rym: in the future.
Rym: I'll go into a lot of detail about all of that.
Rym: I got a bunch of episodes planned about like knocks and network operations and all those sorts of things But I think that's enough for tonight.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.