Rym: It's Tuesday January I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talked about some of the two most important things in the world spice and Treachery.
Scott: being a jerk and being a jerk three things.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know what's great about doing a Tuesday show it's Sunday.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's probably the best part you see right now.
Rym: Right now at this moment while you were listening to GeekNights We actually recorded a little bit ahead something we don't do often something we say we'll do all the time.
Rym: Well any weekends I've come home.
Rym: We're like, alright, let's watch like a ton of crappy anime Do like four anime shows and then nothing happens.
Rym: Once we were a whole week ahead on the show and that lasted about one week and then we blew all those extra episodes like Right away.
Scott: Well, you know between now and katsu kana in February Something We're gonna have a bunch of free weekend something that is not happening quite a long time.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: So next week, I'm going skiing the weekend after that.
Rym: We're playing burning wheel.
Rym: Ah Great, we might go to that other con but that's in March.
Scott: So I don't know that.
Scott: but the point is is that we actually we're gonna have some free weekends now whereas before we had none and We're gonna be more productive during these free.
Rym: What did we do this weekend?
Scott: clean the house?
Rym: I failed to buy a ski jacket.
Scott: I read some comics.
Rym: I did buy an algae.
Rym: No, I'm cool.
Scott: I Reshelved my books.
Scott: I cleaned my room and some other cleaning.
Rym: Yeah, we pretty much just cleaned up.
Rym: after the visigoths We made this show.
Rym: We're still making it.
Rym: We didn't make it yet.
Scott: It did some other stuff.
Rym: Yeah, we went off the road and decided we'll never have to go up the road again.
Scott: Maybe bought some paper.
Rym: Yeah, I have discovered that there's now Nothing in the world left that will cause me to go to a mall.
Scott: Yeah, what do I need?
Scott: I don't need to go to anywhere.
Scott: pretty much everything I can buy online or elsewhere.
Scott: I don't need to go to retail stores anymore at all.
Rym: I mean god I just went to a retail store tried on a ski jacket decided I liked it came home went online Found the same ski jacket for 40 bucks less.
Rym: Nice, I'm proud of that.
Rym: Yep But uh, yeah, the reason we're recorded ahead here this kind of a mantis occasion is that right now?
Rym: We are interviewing someone kind of awesome.
Rym: Oh, right.
Rym: I forgot all about that.
Rym: Yeah, do you think we should tell him what we're doing or just wait till next week?
Rym: They'll find out.
Scott: Uh, I think the cuz cuz we're interviewing right.
Scott: cuz the Tuesday where you're listening to this right now.
Scott: You recorded this on Sunday because we have to play this on Tuesday.
Scott: cuz on Tuesday We're interviewing someone for the following Tuesday, and you'll find out who that is Next Tuesday.
Rym: Oh, so you don't want to tell him not really.
Scott: I mean, I Only they'll listen no matter what.
Scott: and if we tell them see is the thing right.
Scott: if we tell them who it is And they're excited about it.
Scott: They will listen.
Scott: if I tell them who it is and they're not excited about it They might skip that one All right, but if we tell them we're interviewing someone awesome or someone we think is awesome, then they're gonna listen Even if you know we tell them who it is, you know, we'll get more listeners if we're vague about it.
Scott: That's what I'm thinking.
Rym: Well, I gave some hints last week.
Rym: I'm sure they all forgot.
Rym: I'll give one more hint tonight.
Scott: No, no hints are necessary because then a hint is basically either doesn't help them figure out at all.
Rym: No, it might tantalize what.
Scott: what hint could tantalize without giving it away or being too mysterious.
Rym: doors perhaps?
Rym: Okay, they're their doors involved.
Rym: Whatever there are yeah You know, I don't think you understand how excited I am about doors.
Scott: I think you're too excited about doors.
Rym: It's the best part is having doors.
Rym: Okay, nothing's better than having a door.
Scott: You want to do a news, right?
Rym: So this is on slash John.
Rym: a lot of people are talking about it But there was an interesting correlation in the Iowa caucuses by the way if you weren't paying attention my man Barack Obama won and I give him a 51% chance of getting the Democratic nomination for the race for the president in the u.s
Scott: Sounds about right
Rym: and I think after Monday that chance is either gonna go up to a good 80% or go way down
Scott: New Hampshire's tomorrow.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Everything's super weird and early this year because it's all messed up.
Scott: I know I cut the news almost completely ignored that fact like all that weird stuff that happened.
Rym: No, they didn't.
Rym: the news talked about it constantly.
Rym: You just don't watch the news I don't like.
Scott: Google News didn't say anything.
Rym: Yes, they did.
Rym: It was in all the newspapers.
Rym: I didn't see any mostly last year because this has been fomenting for quite some time.
Scott: Well, it seems to have gone off without any actual problems.
Rym: Michigan effectively removed itself from the primary process.
Rym: way to go I try.
Rym: they tried to become more important and as a result now they don't matter at all.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: Luckily, I vote in New York where it kind of matters Kind of the primary it definitely does Because one person has a distinct advantage and the other person is the one I'm voting for.
Scott: Aha, I guess that might make a small difference.
Scott: I think my vote counts considering how few people vote in primaries and it maybe maybe it does.
Rym: Yeah, that I'd better count.
Rym: I've high registered for the stupid Democratic Party just so I could vote in their stupid primary.
Scott: I stuck with my undeclared Declaration.
Rym: I'm going back to Golisano's party right after this business.
Scott: Oh, you're actually gonna register for the Independence Party.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: Oh, no before I was the libertarian but as much as I like the ideals of libertarianism Libertarianism not so great.
Scott: I think they call themselves the Independence Party just so people would accidentally register with them Trying to declare being independent.
Rym: a friend of mine Aaron Arty was in a band Tell this story in our high school.
Rym: I know one special and and the band was called nobody's special because you know Our clubs work for crap little bands is when you walk in you pay the cover charge.
Rym: They ask you who you're here to see and if you say whatever name of a band that's playing then they get.
Rym: that increases their Percentage of whatever amount of money they get paid for bringing people to the car.
Scott: At least it helps that band out.
Scott: it increases the likelihood that they'll bring that band back to the club again.
Rym: But this particular club they paid out based on how many people said they came to see you.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, of course they named their van nobody's special to try and game that.
Rym: so I remember.
Rym: I showed up and I was gonna see Their van for the first time and they said who you're here to see.
Rym: and I said nobody in particular.
Rym: Yeah, just to be a jerk.
Rym: Of course that was the same night where I was mistaken by two individual people for a drug dealer.
Rym: Nice, if two people came up to me and they're like, hey and they tried to buy drugs from me and the first one I'm like, uh, I think you have me mistaken for someone else and the second time I was like, ha ha ha.
Rym: Yes, I'll sell you drugs.
Rym: Ha ha ha.
Rym: then like no, I don't have any drugs.
Rym: I Was like, yeah, I only got cocaine.
Scott: What exactly they say to you.
Rym: They were the first one was like, hey I heard you had some merbs.
Scott: Yeah, I got some parsley out back.
Scott: Oh Maybe some pencil shavings Shavings in a bag.
Rym: I think the problem was I was dressed in all black and a trench coat and I wasn't up for That wasn't my kind of club scene.
Rym: So I was kind of standing in the back of the room not dancing just watching the band.
Rym: Yeah myself.
Scott: Yeah Yeah way to do a drug dealer impersonation exit.
Scott: Okay news time.
Rym: So in the Iowa caucuses someone noticed that.
Scott: are you doing this news on Tuesday?
Rym: This is kind of relevant here.
Rym: okay, so in the caucus if someone noticed that there is a strong correlation between Candidates stances on video games.
Rym: Aha the Tuesday ness and how well they did in the caucus.
Rym: now I'm not gonna explain how a caucus works other than that.
Rym: It is different from a primary.
Rym: Scott didn't know any.
Scott: I knew enough.
Scott: No, you didn't I did.
Scott: You just thought I didn't know.
Rym: you didn't know Jack.
Scott: I know enough.
Rym: Anyway, so I want to point out I want to talk about this very much that you know.
Rym: People are making kind of a big deal about this.
Rym: No, maybe video games matter now, and that's totally not true.
Rym: What happened here is very simple Politicians who don't care about video games Obviously are smart enough to realize more so than other people what positions matter and what positions don't or For whatever reasons.
Rym: like they recognize that video games is not something that should be even talked about by politicians.
Rym: It shouldn't.
Rym: it shouldn't come up ever.
Rym: There's no reason.
Scott: Yeah, how do you feel about?
Scott: Television?
Scott: how do you feel about movies?
Scott: How do you feel about radio?
Scott: Yeah, that's not a big deal.
Scott: You know for the president of the United States he has to worry about war war But video games real war.
Scott: which one's more important?
Rym: I don't know one obviously video games young people people our age and younger voted in well, I guess voted doesn't really work but showed up in record numbers for this caucus and Young people if there's a caucus in your area, it's fun.
Scott: You should go even if you don't care cuz it's fun.
Rym: I think I was the only state that has caucuses.
Scott: I think so, but it's still.
Scott: they could be a caucus for something else besides, you know, choose, you know.
Rym: They're only fun if you care a lot about politics It's four hours of people trying to convince you to stand in one corner of the room or the other corner.
Rym: But it's catered.
Rym: not always now.
Scott: Fuck it.
Rym: Sometimes I've seen I've heard tell of caucuses from old political professors professors at RIT back in the day that were Shall we say full of?
Rym: Beverages that may not have been conducive to the democratic process.
Scott: There's a most excellent variety of caucus.
Rym: But what happened here was that I think there is no correlation between Video games the correlation.
Rym: Well, there's no causation.
Scott: exact a video game stands and being voted Going to a particular the corner of the room based upon video games.
Scott: unless someone had like a DS in one corner of the Room, then they might have gotten someone over there.
Rym: But if I had a caucus there would be the awesome snacks and a Wii and a button a ps3 and an Xbox in the one Corner, they're not.
Rym: Yeah, I just some rickety chairs and an angry dog in the other corner With the DS is in the Rym corner.
Scott: Is that sort of cheating?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Okay, you can do whatever you want.
Rym: Caucuses are crazy.
Scott: Can you really do whatever you want?
Rym: pretty much?
Scott: Can I just like give a dollar to everyone who agrees to stand in my corner?
Rym: You could probably get away with it.
Rym: really, you know Theoretically a lot of people who aren't legally able to vote deal in the caucuses because there's no way to know your 14 year old Son could be there.
Rym: Yeah Legally, they're not allowed to talk they can only observe.
Rym: but yeah that happens.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: Anyway, there is no real causation here.
Rym: What happened was in my opinion, though?
Rym: I think this is pretty solid.
Rym: Candidates who don't care about video games are probably also more in line with the kind of more not so much radical But just what the younger crowd cares about.
Rym: the more hip Politicians the ones who don't care about the old man fuddy-duddy business and young people voted a lot.
Rym: So there's probably strong correlation between people who appeal to young voters and people who independently of that don't care about video games.
Scott: I mean do care no don't care.
Rym: You know, no one says yeah video games Politicians either don't say cuz they don't give a shit or they act like video games of the devil.
Rym: No, okay If you don't care about video games You're probably a better more hip politician and you probably.
Rym: your stance is probably aligned more with the younger generations.
Rym: Okay, as a result B-rock is doing mighty fine among video game fans.
Rym: I like how one of the tags on slashed out for the story is stupid.
Rym: post-hoc.
Scott: Yeah Great.
Rym: So what do you got for me?
Scott: Okay, now Rym gave a little Thursday news that he turned into a Tuesday news.
Scott: I'm gonna give you a little Monday news like a turn into Tuesday news right for this.
Scott: Okay, so we know Software patents, they're stupid.
Scott: They shouldn't be there.
Scott: It's like that parrot.
Scott: It shouldn't be.
Rym: yeah The best thing is we we have a friend now who works.
Rym: probably shouldn't be.
Rym: we've had this friend for a long time But this person works it with patents and we have heard straight from the horse's mouth that software patents are bullshit.
Rym: Yes from someone who knows something from my patent examiner Maybe maybe possibly possible who may or may not know more about patents than us.
Scott: Maybe maybe someone?
Scott: okay Basically, there was a news story in 2004. my a guy named Sheldon Goldberg sounds like a Jew, but I'm Jewish It's not.
Scott: I'm not saying that racist Lee.
Scott: I'm saying it actually sounds like a Jew.
Scott: and There's a. there's a place called as a website called the troll tracker Which is a which is a tracker.
Scott: the tracks patent trolls and well this guy way back when he had like some patents or Solitaire like computer solitaire.
Scott: This guy was yelling in 2004 that his patents covered solitaire.
Rym: Yeah, and we might have even talked about this.
Scott: I don't know me my I don't know.
Scott: We didn't make a show in 2004 I didn't say on the show.
Rym: I said we might have talked about it.
Rym: Okay, I'm sure we talked about.
Scott: he also has some patents for a network gaming system and Another patent for a method for playing games on a network.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I've got a patent for your mom.
Scott: Yeah So this guy is a lot of crapo patents, right?
Scott: Well this guy finally bust it out.
Scott: He's suing among others doing everyone dig Google AOL Yahoo Maybe Microsoft.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't see Microsoft on the list, but they might be there and he's suing.
Scott: I know.
Scott: I don't know why you sue and dig.
Scott: that's sort of out of nowhere.
Scott: But you know what?
Rym: I think he's a lot like remember in Futurama the one about Lila and her past and all that.
Rym: and There were the story of the mole people who because they were blind and they couldn't see well They couldn't see very well and they were at war with someone and they just basically fired missiles in every direction.
Scott: He's suing New York Times Washington Post CNET tribune interactive and e-bombs world.
Scott: You know e-bombs world deserves it, but everyone else he's suing all these people with these lame lame patents.
Scott: So if you're some video gaming person right the software patents affect you to.
Scott: video games are Software people are gonna be.
Scott: if these software patent things that you probably don't care about only caring about games Happen and go through and this bullshit happens.
Scott: People are gonna start patenting video games.
Scott: I mean, it's already bad enough that like EA is the only person only company allowed to make a football game.
Scott: Imagine if you know, uh, I don't know Activision was the only company allowed to make an RTS because they patented that shit.
Scott: It's bad news.
Scott: Imagine if this guy wins and suddenly he's the only one in the world allowed to make networked games or networked gaming systems.
Rym: luckily Also what we've learned from our friends that may or may not exist at the patent examination office.
Rym: Is that perhaps?
Rym: Everyone there is smart and knows the deal and are doing their best to fix every.
Scott: well some of the people there The thing is none of them have really enough power because there's their view into this.
Scott: myth is thousands of thousands of patent examiners.
Scott: Yeah, well, I maybe not a thousand but there's a lot of them.
Scott: There's a whole bunch It's like seven now and each one of them, you know views patents from such a small Topic area and there are so many patents.
Scott: So it's like if you're a patent examiner You might be looking at something so ludicrously specific like some topic that is just so small.
Scott: That's the only thing you really have the power over, you know.
Scott: So yeah Yeah, if you're some gamer and you're not caring about the tech issues Look the tech issues affect you.
Scott: your games run.
Scott: video games run on technology.
Scott: things that affect technology affect your games.
Scott: You need to pay attention.
Scott: Intellectual property patents all this bullshit affects you too And if you don't watch out for it soon games can be fucked up.
Rym: Like if this guy wins bad news luckily He's not gonna win.
Scott: There's no way this guy is gonna win.
Scott: The Google alone has enough money to just put him out of his misery and a straight legal battle without any You know doesn't matter what his lawyers say.
Rym: I'm pretty sure they'll just money them out of business.
Rym: I'm pretty sure I could win in a patent battle against this dude.
Scott: probably probably but yeah patent trolls are out there and They're starting to spread into other areas besides just you know Hindering the open source type peoples.
Rym: So I got one more news I want to talk about briefly might do a show or something in the future about this, but I think it's kind of cool.
Rym: Straight from slash shot.
Rym: a New Zealand physicist has written a paper recently saying that scientists should seriously explore the possibility of The of the universe being a giant virtual reality simulation.
Scott: in other words He wants to make sure where it's not the matrix or that it is.
Scott: now
Rym: The thing is this is really interesting because if you look at quantum theory and what happens at low levels There's kind of this idea that things don't seem to exist until we observe them and it's kind of scary How that happens when you look at hot like quantum particle interactions and things aren't there but then they're there or they interact with things that aren't there anymore and all this weird stuff.
Rym: and one way that this could be explained is that the universe is being generated by some sort of system that is Quantizing an unquantized thing kind of like when you have the RAM deck, you know, I'm recording my voice It's all digital for you But when I record it, it's analog and hits a box that basically breaks it up into a bunch of discrete bits.
Rym: And of course not all the information of my voice could possibly be done because there's an infinite amount of data there theoretically.
Rym: But at the same time I can get pretty damn close and it's possible that the universe is the same way.
Rym: now It's not necessarily that an intelligent thing is simulating the universe or that it's a game or anything like that.
Rym: It could be a natural phenomenon or something.
Rym: It's an idea that he's saying we should look into.
Scott: I say we should look into every idea all the time.
Scott: That's what you know, you have hypothesis.
Scott: test them all.
Scott: they haven't been tested yet.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Sure It makes as much sense as any other crazy string theory things, you know I guess.
Scott: the other interesting thing is you look it's you know Like.
Scott: it makes a lot of sense when you start to think about how we make software like if I make a video game right like say Mario right well in the game of Mario I need to have all the data for what all the maps look like and all the bad guys are right and But only a small part of that is actually on the screen at a given time, you know The part you're looking at right now.
Scott: So to make the game go faster I mean I could have you know The game process the entire world map all the time kind of like how what dwarf fortress does that?
Scott: Yeah, look at you play half-life.
Scott: right in half-life You can have the whole game map in the memory all the time.
Scott: But instead of doing that Every once in a while it says loading and it unloads the map behind you and loads the map in front of you Because it would be too slow even I think a more apt example like in quake 2 back in the day.
Rym: There was a whole system setup where it would only render or bother rendering things that it knew you could see and it Everything else in the map didn't exist Except as abstract data until you viewed it and then suddenly it got rendered.
Scott: Yep cuz I mean why if it's you could have the computer render things that you are not currently on screen and it would just Slow the game down.
Scott: so it might be that the universe works in this way where things are only Things only come into existence and matter when they're being observed or doing something.
Rym: plus I mean look at a game like half-life.
Rym: It has a physics engine.
Rym: The engine is not infinitely granular it only gets down to a certain point and it suffices real well And it's pretty damn realistic.
Rym: and we can simulate all sorts of things on the macro level Because things that events on the micro level are so insignificant that they're effectively meaningless for most of what we would do.
Rym: And theoretically the real world could be the same way.
Rym: now I find it interesting that he even has an idea of how to test this hypothesis.
Scott: How does he think we're gonna test this hypothesis?
Scott: This is like a hypothetical hypothesis, but theoretically you mean like every hypothesis.
Rym: well Theoretically if we wanted to test this if we could ever find a task that information processing Itself like the idea of information processing cannot handle and yet we can do it in the real world Then as far as our knowledge of information processing is gone.
Rym: I've gone.
Rym: we have disproven it.
Rym: That's as good as he seems to be able to come up with right now.
Scott: It's a little weak.
Rym: see the thing is I always found it fast.
Rym: there is that theory I think I've talked about this before that theoretically if we could perfectly model the physics of our world like we could make a computer simulation that Perfectly modeled to the point that it was exactly as the real world any so all our physics.
Rym: then.
Rym: theoretically the odds are that we exist inside of a simulation because of all the infinite possibilities and all that.
Rym: and That can only be disproven by the also possible idea that information processing Requires energy.
Rym: and it's possible that sure you can simulate physics But to simulate the entirety of physics requires the energy output of the entirety of physics.
Rym: Yep, we'll find out eventually Hopefully things of the day, so I'm sure you all remember and love the Super Mario Brothers Super Show.
Scott: Super Mario Brothers Super Show.
Rym: We're the Mario bro, okay, it's enough of that but Everyone remembers that most kids, you know, we watched the Mario show we tolerated.
Scott: Oh, you're gonna use this horrible thing for your thing today.
Rym: Oh God what we cared about was the the Legend of Zelda cartoon that only played on Friday and That show when I was a kid was great.
Scott: when I was a kid It was great and I look forward to it cuz it was hot.
Scott: It was like this thing that was on so rarely.
Scott: it seemed like because you know, the only way you could watch something was if it was on TV and TV dictated and what you could and couldn't watch and VHS tapes, you know You might have had a VCR but you didn't own too many tapes.
Scott: You couldn't own a whole lot.
Scott: So when something wasn't on TV often it was like a special treat.
Scott: That was like Saturday morning.
Scott: cartoons are so great cuz like x-men cartoon.
Scott: when that was on The only way to see it was Saturday morning.
Scott: That was it.
Scott: once a week.
Rym: was all you got?
Rym: unless you just were smart and programmed your VCR.
Scott: You needed blank tapes then, you know how many blank tapes we had.
Scott: we didn't have so many.
Rym: Hundreds and hundreds and hundreds.
Scott: We recorded and usually my parents would use them to record something like a movie or something that was on long and then They would never record over it again.
Rym: See we did.
Rym: and also we made the the day killers.
Rym: We recorded every episode of every show we watched and then without commercials.
Rym: Yeah, remember those things.
Rym: any time we wanted to kill an entire day at RIT just put in a tape.
Rym: That's like 30 episodes of The Simpsons with no commercial breaks openers or closers.
Rym: It's just one long string of Simpsons.
Scott: You put that thing in and nobody will move or they'll just be a gibbering mess.
Rym: Now one thing about this show.
Rym: is that it these shows actually did one thing really well that I'm surprised.
Rym: more Kids shows that are about video games that sort of thing do is that most shows about video games don't actually have anything to do With the video game at all and the kids watching.
Rym: I remember as a kid.
Rym: I'd see shows like Captain N. I'd go wait a minute.
Rym: That's not how it was in the game.
Rym: This is bullshit.
Scott: That's what I said.
Rym:  but this show and the Super Mario Show and that one Sonic show that I liked I like the other Sonic show.
Rym: you suck.
Rym: I like Sonic Underground - you can go to hell.
Rym: He's a Sonic Underground is awesome.
Scott: You never even watched a single episode of Sonic.
Rym: You know what the idea of it is so awesome?
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: It is.
Scott: It's Sonic the Hedgehog Sonic.
Scott: That's the good one.
Rym: I'm all about Sonic Lura bell.
Rym: no so the show as I know being older is not that good because the one thing is if the 90s were like the early 90s mid 90s were epitomized by the Zack Morris cool kid and the Zack Morris Ideology.
Rym: the 80s were defined by the link from the Legend of Zelda ideology.
Rym: 90s kids were cool and caused trouble but not real harmful trouble.
Rym: They didn't kill anyone or anything.
Rym: They just you know, there were those troublemakers that showed up late to class and were snarky like Bueller.
Rym: Bueller Even though he was 80s, but he was ahead of his time.
Scott: He was ahead of us.
Scott: That was why he's so great.
Rym: Yeah, but uh, he said that he said the model 80s things.
Rym: everyone was a brat bastard not most of them.
Rym: most like characters and shows were just self-entitled whiny little bitches.
Rym: and while the Super Mario Show and the Zelda show were so close to the games and just to the point that that was actually a Detriment in the long run, but like all the items were the same the sound effects were the same And I think that's the reason most kids like these shows and have such nostalgia for them is that it was the game.
Rym: I played the game.
Scott: Let's see the Mario live-action movie.
Scott: The reason it was so bad is because it wasn't anything like the video game.
Scott: I like the video game and they just took the words from the video game and plastered them on something else.
Rym: In fact, if the Super Mario movie with John Leguizamo had been Not a Mario movie, but it just been that movie without Mario.
Rym: I think I would have liked it a lot more more Complete hate.
Rym: Yes, it had a Funny moments and it it did do one thing, right?
Rym: That is one of the few pieces of media ever that has treated the Bob-omb with the proper level of respect.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: But other than that, no nothing the movies almost worth watching for that one scene.
Scott: Just watch the one scene on YouTube if you can find it.
Rym: Oh, yeah I'm sure you can find it and I don't know what the deal was with Big Bertha in that movie.
Scott: Yeah, but these are the only cartoons that actually respected the source material and were truthful to it.
Rym: However, um, you might remember that Everyone was a bratty little bitch and link was often found to say, you know, his catchphrase happened like in every episode.
Rym: Well, excuse me Princess.
Scott: Yeah watching this show now Rym seems to still like this show.
Rym: I like it only to watch in a group of people because it's hilarious watching it.
Rym: It's not hilarious.
Scott: It's just painful.
Scott: It's like watching he-man.
Scott: It's bad.
Rym: watching it in a group is really fun.
Rym: No, I don't know why Scott's so humdrum about it.
Rym: Every time I've had a bunch of friends over and we have watched the Zelda show Scott goes The whole time and everyone else is laughing their goddamn asses off.
Scott: It's terrible.
Rym: So this is a video of Every single time.
Rym: the link says well Excuse me princess in the show and I want to point out one thing frightening.
Rym: There were only 13 episodes of this show and this is kind of a long video.
Rym: He averages and excuse me princess about every six and a half minutes sound like that.
Scott: He says it a lot.
Rym: Good God.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Also, I always remember the early 90s in the 80s.
Scott: They're all about catchphrases.
Scott: I mean don't have a cow man.
Rym: You buy.
Scott: sure I caramba eat my shorts.
Scott: Those are all from the same show, but that doesn't matter.
Rym: No, it's chocolate.
Rym: The only thing I remember watching the show again is it link sword was really kind of stubby.
Rym: I guess I didn't notice that as a kid, but now as an adult is true to the video game It's kind of an act in.
Rym: uh, it's kind of disappointing.
Rym: I think Lionel's sword is much more impressive Lionel.
Scott: Yeah, Lionel is a train.
Rym: now if you took a sword and put it on a train sword train.
Rym: It's our train Right next to the soul train right next to the night train.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: All right.
Scott: I got another Monday thing I'm gonna turn into a Tuesday thing.
Scott: Here is the video.
Scott: in this video.
Scott: You will see an IBM model 5150 PC.
Scott: This is the first PC the first like personal computer could have your house like an 8080 processor.
Scott: It's an 8086 like you know how you know.
Scott: We talked about the 386 the 286 the 386 and the 486 right and then the 586 And then every chip that you're using today is a 686. pretty much all these Intel chips in the max all these AMD chips They're all.
Scott: 686 is unless you have one of those power PC max in which case it's a power PC.
Rym: Well in which case you went down there.
Rym: if you bought a newer one, you kind of went down the wrong path.
Scott: But yeah, anyway, it's a 686 in your computer.
Scott: Now.
Scott: This is an 8080. that's a 080 after the 8080.
Scott: I don't know I don't remember if it was 80 81 80 82, but it was 80 86. then there was 186 286 386 46 and etc.
Scott: This is the first one.
Scott: This is the oldest PC the oldest one.
Scott: Anyway, it's really slow and shitty.
Scott: It's got 640k of RAM a 10 megabyte hard drive that's less than 10 floppy disks worth to five and a quarter inch floppy drives 4.7 so less than 5 megahertz and CGA graphics, right.
Scott: Some guy wrote a program for this computer and he got this computer to play 30 frames per second of CGA Full-color motion video.
Rym: I am sure there's some pot pallet swapping going on in here.
Scott: There's all sorts of clever programming techniques going on, you know on the lowest levels of the machines.
Scott: You know depths of scary assembly languageness to get it to do this, but there's this huge scene.
Scott: I don't know if the scene is shrunk in recent years But it's called the demo scene and the demo scene or all these people.
Scott: they make demos But not demos in the sense of.
Scott: you know I'm gonna make the first level of the video game free and the rest of the video game you have to pay for.
Scott: We're talking demos as in a program that demonstrates the full capabilities of a piece of hardware, right?
Scott: They get a computer and they writes they optimize and optimize and optimize some assembly language program that pushes The CPU and the GPU and whatever other chips are in the computer to do the most they can possibly do.
Scott: and well This is a lot easier to do for older computers, which are have much simpler chips in them.
Scott: But when they do it you you'd be amazed at the things that really simple computers can do.
Scott: I mean go look at some like Apple to demos or some like 286 demos.
Scott: Those computers can do some crazy-ass shit when the programs are actually optimized.
Scott: So this video shows you you know, it's a pretty good demo of a Ludicrously slow processor.
Scott: five megahertz is playing a video of a dude breakdancing.
Scott: It's pretty fantastic.
Scott: So imagine if someone you know the games you're playing now you play Bioshock or whatever, you know Supreme Commander you look at those system requirements, right and they're ludicrous.
Scott: It's like you need ludicrous stuff to play even get this game to play Barely at all.
Scott: right.
Scott: If that game was actually Optimized and some people actually took a year to the reason they can't optimize it because the game is so complex that to optimize it Yeah, you realize that I don't think Object orientation is gonna be happening so much.
Scott: We have.
Scott: the way people program things now is we make it a lot easier for the programmers to program them And that is what allows us to actually create complex programs without having to think really hard.
Rym: It gets to the point where the amount of time it would take or the effort or they just what you would have to Do to make low-level things do these high-level things is almost and probably is now beyond what humans can do.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean if you spent like a few years we're talking years and years of actually trying to make say Half-life right and optimize it fully, you know on the for pro that for the programmers It'd be the hardest work probably you can imagine.
Scott: but the result you could probably get like something is good As counter-strike to work at like a hundred FPS on a 386.
Scott: It's probably possible.
Scott: It's just ludicrously difficult to optimize that program to that level.
Scott: but here's a demonstration to show you that that sort of thing is indeed possible.
Scott: and basically, you have to spend a whole lot of money on lots of crazy hardware in your computer because Programmers are lazy and not as smart and not that smart.
Scott: And in fact, no one is that smart not a single person No one can do it.
Scott: It's that hard, but it could be done.
Rym: So a long time ago in the in the year of 1979 a great year for the world.
Scott: I was not alive yet.
Rym: Neither was I. I was z- negative 3 but in that door There was a company named Avalon Hill and this company put forth a game a game called Dune based on the science fiction books by Frank Herbert.
Scott: Yes, Frank Herbert's Dune the books that I tried to read once and did not like but that was a long time ago.
Rym: You only tried to read the first one.
Scott: I tried to read the first one in like middle school.
Scott: They didn't like it.
Scott: I don't remember anything of it.
Scott: That's all I'm gonna say.
Rym: Well, I remember way back when we were Scott and I were living up here before, you know more people moved into the geek houses sphere of influence and we were so bored and crazy and just wanted to play games that we went to this local gaming club a. As a result, we met two really cool people from a local college who?
Rym: Like they took us over and they played board games with us.
Rym: We played.
Rym: uh, what do we play?
Rym: played Starfarers of Catan?
Scott: No, I like the mechanic of Starfarers and Catan with the question thing.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is once you know the answers.
Rym: Yeah, if anyone to memorize the answers has an advantage, but I think anyone who doesn't memorize the answers is stupid.
Rym: Yep, and we played other games with them.
Rym: But I remember one time we were at one of their apartments and we're gonna play a game.
Rym: We're gonna play that King Arthur game and then suddenly we start talking about this Dune game and he brings down He shows it to us and he's like, yeah, this game is super old and super out of print But it's super awesome and he explains it to us.
Scott: And basically the way he explains us the game is he doesn't actually tell us how the game works.
Scott: He's just goes through the six different races that you're allowed to be and he tells us what their superpowers are.
Scott: now You know you play a game like Starcraft.
Scott: It's like the Zerg.
Scott: They can make a lot of guys in rush Oh, man, the protoss they can make a few guys that are really powerful but expensive like oh man, right?
Scott: Well in Dune, do you want to go through the list right now?
Scott: We can do it that you can give people the same experience that we got.
Rym: I think we should because I remember we were talking about asymmetric games that are good and how rare they are And he was like.
Rym: Dune is probably the best asymmetric game ever.
Scott: What do we mean by an asymmetric game?
Scott: right is a symmetric game is a game where every player is the same a monopoly.
Scott: Everyone gets the same everyone has the same starting money.
Scott: Everyone starts in the same position.
Scott: It's pretty much everyone is equal in the game.
Rym: It's more like an asymmetric game.
Rym: would be like say you play chess But one side gets four Knights and the other side gets four bishops.
Scott: Yep, that not everyone is the same, you know be like Starcraft protoss for a Zerg you don't?
Scott: you're not doing the exact same.
Rym: or like a Fortress America where there's three players with one common goal and then one player plays a completely different Players America.
Scott: and but that's more of a versus game.
Scott: But it's still a symmetric one person's America and plays by these rules as opposed to a non versus game.
Scott: Yep, such as Co-op game like Arkham horror.
Rym: I think most games are versus games.
Scott: I know I'm just saying saying what.
Rym: okay So the way he described this game is you basically just told us the powers of all the factions.
Rym: So the Harkonnen See in this game the one the best thing about it is that you look at the board.
Rym: It's so epitomizes the world of Frank Herbert's dude.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: I don't really know anything about Frank Herbert's dune But I can tell from look playing this game and looking at this game from what other people's reactions to this game That all the rules of this game Mirror the world of dune so flawlessly Like if you like dune.
Scott: this game is dune in the same way that the Mario Super Show Actually mirrors the Mario game.
Rym: I mean the first time we played it With a full group of people The way the factions kind of ended up allied with each other was very much like what happens in the books.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, so the Harkonnen they oh, yeah, I forgot what I was gonna say here.
Rym: I gotta get back to that.
Rym: You look at the board.
Rym: There's two piles of cards spice and Treachery and that's pretty much it.
Rym: That's the whole game spice and treachery.
Rym: Yep so the Harkonnen start with two treachery cards instead of one and Every time they buy one they get another one free and they can hold twice as many in their hand as any other player.
Rym: and There's traders.
Rym: you see everyone has these like generals these leaders that whenever you're in a battle you have to send one of them to lead the battle and before you play the game everyone shuffles up all their leaders and everyone picks for and draws them and you look at them and you pick one of your enemy leaders and decide that they are in your pay.
Rym: and Any time you're in a battle involving them you can if you wish but you don't have to Call out treachery and automatically win the battle and kill their other.
Rym: all this business happens and you win and it's super fun and awesome.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: So, uh the Harkonnen they get as traders every single person that they see in that stage of the game.
Scott: So everyone else has at most one trader.
Scott: the Harkonnen could have as many as four people under their pay.
Rym: Everybody was gaga.
Scott: So think about that power, right?
Scott: That's an insanely strong power almost cheating.
Scott: You don't even know how the game works, but you can tell twice as many treachery cards as everyone else Being able to hold more of them and get free ones Having four times as many traders in your pay as anyone else.
Scott: That's ludicrous and that is why this game is amazing is because everyone plays by as different powers that let them break the rules and Everyone's power is ludicrous.
Scott: Every single player's power is ludicrous.
Rym: So the guild right now in this game when you want to ship troops from your reserves onto the board You have to pay to ship them there and it costs more or less depending on where you ship them.
Rym: You don't pay the bank.
Rym: You don't pay some sort of abstract bullshit.
Scott: Well, you do usually.
Rym: no Well, if you're shipping troops you pay the guild.
Rym: the guild is a player.
Rym: So if Scott's the guild and I want to ship people onto the board I pay Scott.
Rym: Yep, everyone pays Scott.
Scott: keep in mind that most players start with the mass majority of their people not on the board and they have to pay to Ship them on.
Rym: and also when people die and go to the tanks You have to buy them back and then you have to ship them back again.
Rym: Oh Yeah, the guild also unfair that is also.
Rym: they can take their turn at any point during the turn if they want.
Scott: I thought that was an optional.
Rym: it is but most people play with all those rules.
Rym: Okay, and if no one wins the game at the F after 15 turns they win by default.
Scott: Oh My god, think about how crazy that is, but the Harkonnen was equally crazy.
Rym: So the Fremen?
Rym: now this is with the optional rules But everyone plays with those.
Rym: in addition to their normal troops three of their troops are elite.
Rym: They move faster They're not destroyed by other business on the board and they're mostly immune to the storm and they can predict where the storms going And that sort of thing
Scott: great
Rym: if no one's won at the end of the game and certain conditions But you're not that hard to make.
Rym: come to pass come to pass.
Scott: They just win and if they don't win then the guild wins.
Rym: and They like if the worm comes up they can ride the worm somewhere and they don't have to pay to ship their guys onto the board.
Scott: Ultimate enemies of the guild.
Rym: so the Emperor has five of these elite units that he can deal with and you know those treachery cards you bid on him every round and Oftentimes you pay a lot for those treachery cards.
Rym: You don't pay the bank you pay the Emperor.
Scott: Ah People are buying treachery cards all the time.
Rym: Yeah, you pretty much have infinite money throughout the entire game if you're the Emperor.
Rym: So the old ladies the Bene Gesserit they can see anytime two factions are on a space on the board.
Rym: They have to fight to the death.
Rym: the Bene Gesserit can if they choose Coexist with other people's units and not cause a fight.
Rym: also Whenever they're fighting they can tell you what card they want you or do not want you to play during the combat.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You have to do what they say.
Scott: Yeah, you're fighting me right now.
Scott: Yeah, don't use any weapons in this fight?
Scott: No, seriously, you can't use any weapons.
Rym: because I said so cuz I'm an old lady and if anyone ships anyone to the board They get to take one unit and put it in the middle of the board for free every time.
Scott: So like if you know It doesn't matter who ships if if I put five guys on the board the old ladies put one guy in the middle.
Scott: if Rym puts three guys on the board the old ladies put one guy in the middle and After all the factions are picked and before the game starts the Bene?
Rym: Gesserit secretly determine one player and one turn.
Rym: if that Player or an alliance including that player wins on that turn.
Rym: They don't win the Bene?
Rym: Gesserit win instead.
Scott: Ah, so if let's say the the old ladies say they secretly they write down Scott's gonna win On turn three and Scott wins on turn three.
Scott: Scott doesn't really win on turn three.
Scott: The old ladies win on turn three.
Scott: So a viable strategy for the old ladies is help someone else win on the turn that you predict.
Rym: Yeah, there are a lot of fun ways to do that too.
Rym: Now.
Rym: How's the tradies?
Rym: They when you know when you bid on treachery cards, you don't get to see what they are You bring it's not like a treatise and then you bid on them.
Rym: So, uh, they get to look at every card before it gets bid on.
Rym: Now now now there's another fun rule in this game that makes this power so much more interesting.
Rym: you see and this is what really Sold me on the game, you know most games like Shogun or risk or whatever You can make deals with people but there's no kind of in-game mechanic for it.
Rym: It's just alright I'll ally with you, but there's nothing to enforce it.
Rym: You can just break them all the time and the alliances really never play a big part in the game because you can't trust anyone As Pete learned so famously the first two times we played Shogun
Scott: Yep,
Rym: but there's other games like settlers where you can trade very specific things in the game with very specific set of rules And it's very much like guided by the game.
Rym: Mm-hmm in Dune.
Rym: You can trade without as long as you do not violate the rules of the game and do not trade leaders or treachery cards Or powers those the only things you can't trade.
Rym: you can make any deal you want with anyone.
Rym: And the thing is you can make deals secretly, but then they're not part of this rule.
Rym: They're just part of a normal game.
Rym: You can do it or not do it.
Rym: No one has to follow through.
Rym: if you decide to make a real deal like say Scott and I agree All
Scott: right When you're bargaining like when you're bargaining like I can bargain with Rym off to the side Quietly, I can just beg whisper whisper whisper whispers, right
Rym: and we could even make a deal quietly, but it's not bound by these rules
Scott: Right, so we make a deal quietly then I if I break that deal, whatever it doesn't matter.
Scott: It was we were just talking quietly that it doesn't mean anything.
Rym: But if we decide alright, let's do this we can come back out and say alright If Scott attacks Scott Johnson next round with 17 men blah and blah and blah and then we and we ally on And we agree not to break our alliance up on the next Nexus then I will give him 25 spice right now.
Rym: Mmm now I give him the 25 spice.
Rym: It's not like there's a penalty if he doesn't follow through.
Rym: he must.
Scott: It's the rule.
Scott: if you make a deal out in the open and you shake on it and it's it's a it's a locked in Deal, it is now the rules of the game.
Scott: You must do it.
Rym: You must so with the house.
Rym: I can see all the cards.
Rym: I could say sell people the privilege of knowing what the card is before the bidding or say I'm fighting it real hard with the Harkonnen next to me and The Harkonnen just bought a bunch of cards.
Rym: I could be like I'll pay you five spice if you tell me and no one else what cards he just got Or anything like that.
Rym: you can do all sorts of stuff.
Rym: you also get to see ahead of time where the spice is going to be.
Rym: Now think about that.
Rym: every faction in this game has a crazy fucking power And if you look at any one you think well, they're gonna win no matter what but everyone.
Rym: you say that about everyone And I think that is what makes this game great.
Scott: Yes, like hey, there are six races.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Each one is different.
Scott: Okay, this one can basically cheat.
Scott: how do they lose?
Scott: well that one can cheat too.
Scott: In fact, they can all cheat just in a different way And I think that's one of the things that makes this game really fun.
Scott: is you know whenever you play any sort of game Right.
Scott: The game is all about restrictions and if you learn anything from counter-strike.
Scott: Sometimes breaking the rules in a game can be fun because if you play a game and you have to obey all the rules and The rules are really, you know Constrictive and and restrictive and they don't let you do everything you want to do then it can be unfun.
Scott: and occasionally You know if someone gives you the ability to break those rules even once it's like yes Yes, I can break those rules god damn it.
Scott: Yes I'm gonna kick ass now and everyone gets to kick ass in a different way all the time.
Scott: So it's like yes I'm kicking ass and everyone's kicking ass all the time and everyone kicks each other's asses all the time.
Rym: now the other thing I Didn't mention yet because I think I said something about oh well Alliance this game handles alliances in perhaps the most awesome way any game ever has.
Rym: you see whenever a worm comes up from the spice deck a nexus occurs and basically the game stops until All the alliances are settled and any number of players can form an alliance and you can only be in one Alliance.
Rym: You don't have to be an alliance You can break them whatever you want But until the Nexus ends everyone can form alliances as they please with whatever conditions they want.
Rym: yep, and if I see to win the game there are what five strongholds on do on Arrakis.
Rym: if any one player or any alliance of players has at least one token on Three or more of these fortresses at the end of a turn at the end of any turn The game is immediately over and they win.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So let's say I have two fortresses and Scott has two fortresses.
Rym: Everyone else has buckets.
Rym: Maybe the Fremen have like one fortune.
Rym: the worm shows up the worm shows up.
Scott: We just decide that we're gonna win and we do so.
Rym: Scott and I say all right We ally great.
Rym: if we still have at least three fortresses at the end of that turn we win.
Scott: Yep, unless the old ladies predicted that one of us would win on that turn.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Now this rule I Mean, I wondered how it would work out But the first time we played it with a full group of people the worm came up like right away And I was the Harkonnen.
Rym: so I had a fortress already and I had a bunch of guys already on the board and I look around look at Alex.
Rym: It's like alright we both have a ton of money and a ton of guys and two fortresses between us want to just fucking win and We look around and yeah, we allied then we won and there's pretty much nothing anyone could have done about it.
Rym: Nope, and the thing is theoretical.
Rym: you could make an alliance of five players and just fuck Whoever was the sixth player and win.
Rym: Yeah, and that seems really out of the spirit of the game.
Scott: But at the same time I have no problem with it.
Rym: I have no problem because I don't feel like that'll happen a lot because think about this This is the game is much like it.
Rym: It seduces you much like the power of spice.
Rym: and why dune was the way it was in the story.
Rym: Alright, I could just be nice and share my victory with all of you But what if I act like I'm gonna be all nice and then when the next Nexus comes up before the game's over I fuck everybody and win on my own?
Rym: that's so much more awesome than sharing my victory with these posers.
Rym: or what if?
Rym: Why should I ally with four of you when I can just ally with Scott and then our victory is so much more meaningful?
Rym: You suckers.
Scott: Yeah, you want it.
Scott: basically, you know, if you are actually someone who cares about winning which you should be.
Scott: if you're playing a game Otherwise you're playing it wrong then you're gonna sort of naturally want to win with as few people as possible.
Scott: Why would you you know, I mean you could technically always win like worm.
Scott: everyone allies game over, but that's lame.
Scott: You want to do something awesome and the motivation you have and playing the game is gonna cause the game to always be awesome.
Rym: And I remember when the first Nexus came up It's like pretty much everyone formed these gigantic alliances right away And then everyone kind of sat there for a minute and then pretty much all the alliances Collapsed as everyone started arguing and fighting and for like 20 minutes we argued about it and it was great.
Rym: Yep, people like well I'll agree to do this and I'll smash this and I don't know that and that that alone made this game worth the price of Purchase that that moment when that first worm came up was so great.
Scott: I think this game is most similar to diplomacy and that you know There's some rules of stuff that goes on in the board and you sort of have to master and understand those things or else you're Gonna be a really weak position.
Scott: But as soon as you master those things, right and it's not too hard to master them.
Scott: Just play the game a few times.
Scott: Eventually the game becomes all the wheeling and dealing is the stuff that really matters and all the other stuff is sort of a given because it's unlike a lot of other games like you play a game like I don't know Vinci right and Who wins and who loses pretty much comes down to the final turn, you know, it's like it's a close race.
Scott: It's a close race to close races.
Scott: the final turn.
Scott: who got the most points of the final turn?
Scott: It was Scott.
Scott: Yeah in this game.
Scott: There are five spaces on the board You need three to win.
Rym: a lot of people start with one already.
Scott: Yeah, so it's not too hard to get three.
Scott: pretty much every turn is like the last turn.
Scott: someone can win at any moment.
Scott: so every turn you play it like it's the last turn and You're pretty much on the edge of your seat fighting for the game every single turn and that is crazy.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: that like every single turn could be the last turn.
Rym: now a guy Whose name is a gnarly thotep Aha, you know gnarly GN Adam Prince, okay on board game key Posted a review.
Scott: that I think sums up everything I want to say about yeah I know I saw this review there when I was doing the pre show Research like five minutes ago ten minutes ago and um, this guy doesn't target for a half hour.
Rym: It was well.
Scott: his review is so much better than our review.
Scott: I feel like our show is worthless in the in the face of his review.
Rym: now Basically, I'm going to read the first few paragraphs of his review brief And I think this will tell you more so than anything.
Rym: we have said what makes doing great.
Rym: and if you ever played diplomacy You'll know this feeling because Dune if nothing else is the kind of game Where if you're not close friends with someone or you have trouble not taking things personally you will lose Friendships.
Rym: if you play this game much like if you play diplomacy, maybe all right.
Rym: There are a few reviews out there.
Rym: I'll skip that paragraph.
Rym: Dune gives you and the other players the absolute Unrestricted and utterly unbeatable chance to be a jerk.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: Dune allows you to be a huge jerk and all in the name of fun.
Rym: and really what's more fun than being a jerk?
Rym: Nothing being a jerk to plenty of people at once jackpot This game.
Rym: let me tell you right away like in the first game I was like I went over to Scott Johnson kind on the slime like alright We're next to each other and we both have ornithopters.
Rym: Let's just agree to Ally and then win as soon as we can.
Rym: and that didn't happen.
Rym: I totally stabbed him in the back immediately, but at the same time So many of the things I did in this game were such asshole moves.
Rym: like alright It doesn't really cost me much to send some guys over there to attack so-and-so, but you know what I got spice to kill.
Rym: I'm just gonna ruin their chances of winning this round just because it doesn't cost me much.
Scott: Yeah, I would basically like I when I was the Emperor I didn't have.
Scott: it's hard for the Emperor to actually fight because his guys all start off the board So he takes him a while to get all those guys on the board.
Scott: So just I would basically send guys out to their deaths in stupid battles.
Scott: They couldn't win just to make sure the game didn't end and I just basically suicide people.
Rym: Oh also the way combat works.
Rym: I'll basically I'm gonna roll this down real.
Rym: simply the mechanic you need to care about is that you both have a battle wheel with Numbers from 0 to 20 and you can only have 20 guys in space.
Rym: So that works out when you guys yeah, so when you fight with someone basically you play cards whatever behind your shield and a leader.
Rym: But most importantly you each dial a number from 0 up to the number of guys you have there.
Scott: So if I have 10 guys in the space fighting I can put the wheel on any number from 0 to 10.
Rym: now Then you compare numbers, which is basically the number you dialed plus the battle value of your leader plus any other effects.
Rym: But there aren't many.
Rym: whoever has the highest number wins now.
Rym: whoever had whoever lost all their guys die and they lose the space.
Rym: But the person who wins loses no matter what a number of guys equal to what they dial.
Scott: So if I have 10 guys and I dial the number 5 if I win I lose 5 guys.
Scott: If I lose I lose all 10 guys.
Scott: So I can dial 10 which should give me a much better chance of winning because I have a such a big number.
Scott: But if I win I lose all the guys and it basically it's a kamikaze attack, it's so great.
Scott: It's great, but continue reading that review there.
Rym: All right pros of the dune game Allows you to act like a complete jerk for an entire session.
Rym: All right Khan opponents tend to be jerks.
Rym: Yeah Bro, a flavorful atmospheric game with enjoyable tense gameplay.
Rym: I think tense is right on.
Rym: Khan may take a bit too long to play.
Rym: for some people.
Scott: doesn't take that long Actually is surprisingly not long.
Rym: Well, no the first game we played didn't take long.
Rym: the second game we played went on forever.
Rym: Okay Pro.
Rym: it's based on a well-loved book series Khan.
Rym: Extremely hard to locate and purchase without spending enough money to put someone's kid through a four-year college program.
Scott: Yeah, this game was made in 1979.
Scott: It is out of print.
Scott: There's.
Scott: there was a new copy on eBay.
Scott: I bid 80 bucks on.
Scott: it went for a hundred something.
Scott: Eventually, there was a used copy on eBay and with good timing I was able to get it for $40 and it's luckily an almost perfect condition.
Scott: So that was lucky.
Scott: but this is a very hard game to get.
Rym: Yeah, and don't get me started on the expansions You're not gonna find those no, but this game is almost impossible to buy isn't it?
Scott: Great that we're reviewing it so glowingly making you want to play a game that you can't get.
Rym: Yeah, luckily the rules are well known and on the internet and there's a con here.
Rym: This is probably the most important con of the game.
Rym: This may lead you to the urge to carve lacquer paint acid sketch inscribed program virtually tattoo or otherwise overdue Your own personal copy of the game.
Scott: a lot of people out there have made their own copies of Dune.
Scott: They get the rule book and they look at pictures on the internet and whatnot and they they make Their own copy of the game because you can't buy a copy of the game.
Rym: now luckily there is a computer Simulation version of this game that from what I gather is all like 99% perfect.
Rym: That's good, and I'm gonna link to it.
Rym: I highly recommend you get some friends together.
Rym: Don't play this over the internet with idiots.
Rym: Get a bunch of computers hot.
Rym: However, you need to do it and play it with all of you in the same room.
Rym: This game is so fun If you are willing to deal with the fact that this game is incredibly hardcore.
Scott: Yeah, it's a super hardcore game.
Scott: This is a nerd game from 1979 before there were internets.
Scott: before there are really nerds and geeks.
Scott: So this is when you had to program a computer with like basic if that right.
Scott: so everything was hard for geeks back then.
Scott: So this game is included in.
Scott: that is a hard game.
Scott: It is not easy, but it is a good game, and it is awesome.
Rym: And if you're ever at a con, I think I want to run this game at a convention.
Rym: whoa I think we should run into ConnectiCon.
Rym: Oh Unless they say no and I doubt they will because ConnectiCon is like my favorite little con We'll have to have people sign up for it though.
Rym: Oh, yes, but low quality like walk-ins play the rare out of print game Yeah, but I'm so about this game being run at cons by me mmm.
Rym: Good God all right, but anyway seriously If you if you have money Buy this game you can get it on eBay for a hundred something dollars or less Maybe.
Scott: yeah, you got to try really hard.
Scott: I got it for 40.
Rym: so try it on the with that program first to make sure you like it.
Rym: I think you'll like it.
Rym: or just you know Hang out with a bunch of friends for a weekend in college and make your own set.
Rym: It's not that hard.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's a map which is a circle with some lines on it.
Scott: It's a. you can even just print out a picture on the web.
Scott: you need 20 token 20 colored tokens of six colors.
Scott: you can buy those at the craft.
Rym: This is my favorite one.
Rym: someone made like this wood lacquered one.
Rym: It looks so hot is it?
Scott: yes They won't sell it to you.
Rym: We could make this yeah, but by make it.
Rym: I mean pay someone to make it.
Rym: Actually, this is we should do another show on this because the only board game anyone should ever make for themselves is crocodile Tigers and Euphrates.
Rym: Maybe see the thing is looking at these pictures is inspiring me again.
Rym: So I've had this idea for a long time that I play board games a lot like.
Rym: board games are a huge part of my life and I feel like nothing would be like.
Rym: you know you when you go to like a ping-pong competition right or A pool like you go to a pool hall and there's always that one guy Who brings his own pool cue or brings his own ping-pong paddle.
Rym: go to the bowling alley.
Rym: the guy with his own bowling ball as?
Rym: Opposed to you or rented an alley ball for a dollar.
Rym: your alley shoes alley shoes alley ball.
Scott: go play golf.
Scott: He's got his own clubs.
Scott: He didn't rent any.
Rym: you know his own golf cart when I was a kid when I was actually going golf ball mini golf.
Rym: I would bring my own Potter to the mini golf.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: I'm not good at mini golf anymore cuz I don't play it that much granted.
Scott: Who's the best at mini golf Scott?
Scott: That's right, though.
Rym: I gotta say it's got kind of close at the last Wildwood.
Rym: It got real close.
Scott: I think I lost to somebody.
Rym: you did you lost to me.
Rym: I want someone else.
Scott: I win most of the time he does but I never do poorly.
Rym: Well, you didn't do poorly but to a couple of people did better than you last time.
Scott: Yeah, by like a few strokes, but it no it came down.
Rym: I remember cuz last time we played mini golf.
Rym: Oh, we got a do show mini golf.
Rym: I was down by a lot like the first the first nine.
Rym: I was sucking I sixed out like three times.
Rym: Uh-huh, but then in the second half It was nothing but twos and I caught up.
Rym: Yeah, but this game that we're not talking about mini golf Even though Arrakis is kind of a sand trap.
Rym: Yeah sand trap for your soul Okay, but uh, yeah, I had this idea that perhaps I should make my own set of gaming accoutrement.
Scott: Well, I mean RPG.
Scott: people already have this.
Scott: they have their own dice They have their own pencils and their own clipboards for their own character.
Rym: I'm thinking like if I had a set of four tokens like silver edge like cheap silver like sterling silver With felt on the bottom.
Rym: like these are my leaders for T&E and like I make stuff for all the games that I care about A lot I make stuff for those games my own set.
Rym: These are my pawns That I will use when I play chess Yep, and for like every other game just make a set of generic tokens and pawns and things that are all kind of themed to Me.
Scott: yeah, these are my stones.
Scott: So when I play go and I think though, you know because board games It's sort of like unlike other games, you know individual sports like, you know golf or bowling where each you know Each person has their own individual equipment.
Scott: a board game is sort of like the shared piece of equipment where everyone Manipulates the same thing.
Scott: So I think it's really much better to just make a custom set of the game that's what most people do rather than have your own stuff and you put your fancy silver tokens on the plain T&E board or You just make a fancy T&E set with like, you know, the fancy board and the fancy pieces and the fancy tip.
Rym: yeah, but the thing is I always look forward.
Rym: cuz Scott and I we play games at conventions a lot and we pretty much always Win partly because we're obsessive about games and we play like playing T&E at a convention.
Rym: I've played T&E so many times in my life Yep, but imagine going to a gaming con like you're like, oh man I'm gonna play Settlers of Catan.
Rym: and then some dude sits down and pulls out his custom set of cities that are Intricately carved silver cities with gemstones in them.
Rym: and he's like, all right kid Let's play.
Scott: you have your own cities for this game.
Scott: Yeah, and your own dice.
Rym: Yeah and your own robber.
Scott: Yes, when I roll seven you'll be twice robbed.
Rym: But the one thing is you could make very generic pieces and I think it'd be a cool thing at least playing with friends.
Scott: Yeah, you could make generic pieces that are applicable to many games.
Scott: I mean like ten colored tokens that are you know You could play with those and almost the thing is if like a bunch of us have a set like that.
Rym: That's the kind of thing where say we're thinking about an idea for a board game or an expansion for a board game We own.
Rym: we have all these pieces now that make it a lot easier to kind of visualize what we're thinking.
Scott: Yeah, I think.
Scott: better though to design board games It's much better to just buy like chips and tokens and pawns in bulk than to try that.
Rym: I am kind of thinking about making a custom T&E because that is my favorite game ever.
Scott: Yeah, we'd have to count the things and it might be yeah.
Rym: Plus the thing is we could make one that's kind of customizable.
Rym: We could like it make individual tiles to lay down a theme teeny.
Rym: Ah, no, I like the theme of teeny.
Rym: That's what I like about it so much.
Rym: It feels like playing this ancient like Mesopotamian.
Scott: I know I know it's so perfect.
Scott: Are we done?
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: We're done.
Rym: The dune game is great.
Rym: The spice must flow and There's.
Rym: there are also nukes.
Rym: So great.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four Different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.