Rym: It's Thursday, March 13th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I don't know what rims gonna call this episode And I didn't know what I was gonna tell the episode.
Rym: and then I said tall instead of calm.
Rym: Let's do this Instead of what I usually do which is slip out of work and buy a beard papa to eat on the train.
Rym: I actually went and bought a holla instead And I was actually thinking of buying a bread.
Scott: when I walked by the bread stand, you know I took the late train home, but I didn't buy a bread and you know what?
Rym: I'm glad I didn't because when I got home there was a bread sitting there, you know We'd better call Randy because there must have been some sort of psychic synchronicity.
Scott: Yeah, that bread stand I walk by every day and think about brying a bread every day.
Rym: Yeah, what a coincidence that how much money can the bakeries in Grand Central make?
Rym: I mean think about this.
Scott: Well, the bakery itself is somewhere else and they just they have like locations around the city and they just bring it.
Scott: They just you know, drive bread around to the different locations.
Rym: Well, yeah central big bakery places that sell bread and they do bake some of the smaller things directly.
Rym: They're partly because it generate that.
Scott: well, you know, they heat up some frozen things things like that.
Rym: No, they also bake.
Scott: What do they bake?
Rym: I've seen them bringing in the dough in the remember.
Rym: I get there in the morning when the deliveries are still Coming in.
Rym: Yeah, they bake.
Rym: Anyway, whatever you say how much money do they have to make?
Rym: I mean think about two hundred something thousand people walk past that bread stand twice a day.
Scott: Well, it looks like they have there right about every day.
Scott: How many bagels would you think are stacked up there early in the morning?
Scott: a lot five hundred to a thousand bagels?
Rym: Well, I think there's a simpler way to look at this.
Rym: two hundred thousand people walk past that every day.
Rym: They walk past the first time When it's morning and they probably didn't eat breakfast because you know a lot of people who take the train don't eat breakfast.
Rym: So hey, I could get a bagel and cream cheese for like a dollar right there and it's on my way to work.
Rym: It won't inconvenience me at all.
Scott: That's already like a thousand dollars in the morning at least, you know.
Scott: then you add in the coffees add in the two dollar fifty cent orange juice add in all the paint like the Danishes and muffins and rolls and then the sans.
Rym: I've known.
Rym: it's weird But like when I worked at IBM, even when I worked at well I guess the house now cuz the cross one I think a long commute is.
Rym: what does it because I worked at IBM be like, all right I'm going home and I'd leave at some point between three and six just depending on what I felt like and I Would just drive home and then I'd get home and I'd do stuff and I would like for summer.
Rym: I would just wait and then I eat dinner later.
Rym: But then when I had a long commute when I drive home from the hospital or from anywhere in the Bronx I would almost invariably stop at a Starbucks and get like a cookie and a coffee Or I'd stop it like a gas station get a Red Bull and like a snacky cake.
Rym: I just I'd get something to eat.
Rym: and now every day while I don't do it every day My brain always says hey Rym You better buy some sort of melon pot or something to eat on that train because five minutes after it starts rolling You're gonna wish you had it.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much every day if I don't buy something.
Rym: I'm on the train like damn it I would pay like 10 bucks if someone would give me some food, right?
Scott: That's why as soon as I get home, I just died like eat like three snacks and drink some juice every day.
Scott: So Ram what are we doing the show on today?
Rym: Oh, well, I think we'll get to that in the minute We don't?
Rym: we got nothing.
Scott: You have no idea.
Scott: We're doing the show on.
Scott: I'm just revealing the fact that we do like the first half of the show not knowing what we're gonna talk about in the second Half of the show.
Scott: not always sometimes we do that We're gonna we're gonna get at we're gonna do the news and then we're gonna sit around thinking of what the main bits gonna be.
Rym: Yeah, you're gonna you're you know, it's a bit like talking.
Rym: They don't hear that thing that a music come in then it stops.
Rym: We're basically gonna pause and one that thing of the day.
Rym: music So you all know is not live.
Rym: that's added in after the fact by a script that figures out when we stop talking.
Scott: yeah, so So, yeah, we have no idea what they're doing the show on.
Rym: Maybe we should do the show on reveal all the secrets of GeekNights.
Rym: It's like what I'm wearing right now.
Scott: No, that's not.
Scott: let's not reveal our secrets because then someone will will copy us.
Rym: Oh Yes, because anime world are winning.
Scott: It's like giving away the secret recipe To the secret sauce.
Rym: some I don't think anime world order or fast karate or movies You should see would be made better if one they didn't plan their show ahead of time to One of them or more of them were mostly naked Mm-hmm All right, I got that's it.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: I'm done.
Rym: Yeah news or something.
Scott: Oh, I got news gonna do news.
Rym: All right, I can do my news.
Scott: Are you kidding?
Rym: is pretty hot this kid.
Rym: This is this is the kind of stuff I love.
Rym: so all right some kid.
Rym: In fact, I should say his name because I think he's cool.
Rym: His name is Michael Sheraton.
Rym: Well,
Scott: wait, he must have not done something to get him in trouble with the law because then they would say we can't release the name of a minor blah blah blah,
Rym: ah The wonder of committing something that is not actually a crime, but yet you can still be punished for.
Rym: However, it's cool.
Rym: It's all cool.
Rym: So Michael Sheridan is an eighth grader.
Rym: He was an honor student in some Connecticut middle school.
Scott: He was the vice doesn't say the name of the school?
Rym: No, all right.
Rym: He was the vice president of his class.
Rym: All right So he's like.
Rym: he's one of those like kids like he's one of those cool smart happening like in the student government Not the president but the vice presidents who probably wields all the real power.
Scott: Anyway, because this real power the student government at a middle school.
Rym: so he uh, he purchased from another student some contraband was caught and Had his title stripped from him and was then Suspended.
Scott: now what the contrary what the contraband is I can already tell.
Scott: Whatever that contraband is is the story.
Rym: now the deal is.
Rym: we have this obesity epidemic, right?
Scott: It was soda or candy or something?
Rym: Well, this obesity epidemic is brought on entirely by people's own goddamn faults if they just eat less food, but I digress.
Rym: Yep, also corn subsidies are not helping.
Scott: Not helping too much not helping at all.
Rym: Man any day.
Rym: now my Dublin.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Pepper is gonna be here.
Rym: I ordered two cases of Cane sugar original recipe.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Pepper.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: I ordered it at no small expense, too.
Rym: So you visit goths who are coming.
Rym: you're not drinking it.
Rym: if it comes tomorrow I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna hide this crap.
Scott: You're gonna have to.
Scott: well I think you should do is I think you should just give them all one bottle one bottle for all of them.
Scott: So that way it's even more cruel because they all know what they're missing But they can't get any and they get like such a small portion of one serving.
Scott: That's so mean I know of course, I mean they could always get but you you deserve to do that.
Rym: Well, yeah, I guess I do.
Rym: actually it wasn't that expensive.
Rym: The thing is it was like, oh man, it's only $10 a case.
Rym: I'm gonna order like 10 cases.
Scott: shipping is like 20 bucks.
Rym: Yeah, then I realized wait a minute freight shipping cases.
Scott: Are they glass bottles or cans or what?
Rym: Actually, I could have gotten glass bottles or cans.
Rym: I chose cans because the cost per ounce including the glass Not worth it.
Scott: No I would have gotten one case of glass bottles and the rest cans.
Scott: and that way you you know You have the glass bottles for those special times, but then you know, you have the cans for practicality.
Rym: You know, I actually what I'm thinking of doing is I'm gonna I gotta make sure cuz I'm.
Rym: I had real You know what?
Scott: What if you get it and it tastes like shit?
Rym: Well, I had real dr.
Rym: Pepper when I was a kid like real Dr.
Rym: Pepper.
Rym: cuz dr.
Rym: Pepper was hard to get up in Michigan and Relatives would bring it from down south because my mom was addicted to it and at a young age.
Rym: So was I. but Dr.
Rym: Pepper changed and now it's a different recipe uses corn syrup and all that.
Rym: but this is the real deal.
Rym: so I got to make sure that it tastes as good as I remember and Experience thing.
Rym: I think it will be because I love Mexican soda.
Rym: Mexican soda is thousand times better than anything you get in the US other than maybe the Passover coke Mmm, so, uh, I ordered the canes to make sure it's good.
Rym: if it's good I'm gonna order some of the glass and I think I'm gonna put it in the wine cabinet.
Rym: next all the wine.
Scott: Go go you.
Rym: it costs about the same.
Scott: Are you gonna mix it with the Vodak?
Rym: No, all right, dr.
Rym: Pepper and vodka would taste.
Scott: What do I know?
Scott: I don't like either.
Scott: one of those beverages that I know that people mix the alcohols and the sodas That's what I know.
Rym: You just said to me is like hey, what if you take your orange juice you mix it with pay What?
Scott: oh hey, that's doo-doo thing is to me the book.
Scott: all dr.
Scott: Pepper will.
Scott: all soda and all alcohol tastes like pee.
Rym: So it's like, you know know what you mix with dr Pepper dear Scott is rum particularly spiced rum.
Scott: Okay, cuz cuz I know.
Rym: well, you should know.
Scott: no I shouldn't cuz I don't drink rum and I don't drink dr.
Scott: Pepper.
Rym: I'm gonna give you a little hint.
Rym: Here's an easy way to tell this doesn't work for everything.
Rym: if it's a brown drink put a brown liquor in it It's not a brown drink.
Rym: You shouldn't be putting a brown liquor in it.
Rym: There are some exceptions.
Rym: There's a lot of exceptions, but that's a good rule to go by.
Scott: Uh-huh So it could we make up some sort of rhyme to go with that like if it's brown flush it down.
Rym: if it's brown Chuck it down.
Scott: It's yellow.
Rym: Let him read go to bed.
Rym: That's terrible, I don't know.
Rym: red bullets dr.
Rym: Pepper's.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of urine colored.
Rym: Well, we don't have a main bit we digress.
Scott: can I do my news?
Rym: I didn't even get to mine.
Scott: oh So, uh, that's right the kid.
Rym: So here's the quote from the superintendent super Nintendo Reginald Mayo.
Scott: Well, what is the was the contraband?
Rym: I'm getting to that.
Rym: All right, the principal He said quote.
Rym: the principal was just trying to keep students safe Okay safe from this contraband now.
Rym: he was originally suspended this kid for three days But they brought it down to one day in Light of his honor record and the fact that he was the vice president of the Student Council.
Rym: However, they did as I said impeach him and strip him of his title.
Rym: He will not be reinstated.
Rym: Uh-huh Michael said that he did not realize the item purchase was against the rules But he admitted later that he did notice that the students selling the item on February 26 Might have been acting somewhat secretive.
Rym: Mm-hmm The banned item was a bag of skittles.
Scott: Oh Man, now one got to sue the school over that one.
Rym: Yeah This this bothers me a little bit.
Scott: that courses middle school doesn't matter that much.
Rym: this New Haven School system the entire system banned candy sales in 2003 as part of a district ride wide school wellness policy.
Rym: now, I remember my high school.
Rym: Right, my high school was worried not so much about obesity, but more about just a kid's got to be healthy Whatever which I think was absolutely not true because the stuff they sold for lunches in that high school.
Rym: I don't we want to get into that.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but there was one pop machine.
Rym: I can say pop because it's referring to the past much like how we had a friend.
Rym: We'll have a friend who got a sex change and changed the name as a result And then we had a serious debate as to whether or not.
Rym: if referring to the person now we use the new name obviously, but what if we're referring to a story that happened in the past when the name and gender were different and The answer from the person in question was well if I was a dude back then then use my dude name.
Rym: And because I was a dude then if I'm not a dude in the story then use my non dude name.
Scott: It's as if someone died and was reborn and it's two different people.
Rym: Yeah, so if you ever have a sex change in friend, that's the answer.
Scott: All right, but anyway great advice from Rym.
Rym: So I can say pop because I lived in Michigan.
Rym: It was pop.
Rym: It was the pot machine in other words you.
Scott: so You agree that it's soda now.
Rym: No, it's pop.
Rym: I'm just so.
Scott: why do you have to make a disclaimer?
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I have to make a disclaimer if the default was not soda The only reason the fault was the only reason you would only have to disclaim soda.
Scott: I think you basically just done yourself.
Scott: in
Rym: the only reason I have to make a disclaimer because I point out that According to that survey at the last time I looked at it, which was a couple of years ago So it might have changed but soda and pop were pretty much neck and neck and
Scott: I think your trust that survey.
Rym: Yes as a valid scientific It's been widely cited, but I think we can all agree on one thing.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of things are widely cited.
Scott: that doesn't mean anything.
Scott: I could.
Scott: I could write You know rims-a-douche and then cite it a hundred times.
Scott: it doesn't make it any less false I think.
Rym: I think you've discovered the secret to editing Wikipedia.
Rym: Yeah Alright, but I think that us pop believers and you soda heathens can agree on one thing much Like how Muslims and Christians agree on one thing they agree that atheists suck and generally don't like them.
Rym: I think we can agree that if you say coke and you're not referring to coca-cola or at least a cola beverage you're wrong Alright.
Scott: so continue with the with the news here about the skittles.
Rym: Alright, so in my old high school The pop machine, right?
Rym: Yeah They would turn it off during school hours because there was some sort of mandate where they didn't want kids buying unhealthy things.
Rym: You couldn't buy pop during school Mmm, and all but the real reason.
Rym: and I got this straight from the vice principal's mouth And it was verified by a bunch of other people.
Rym: The real reason was the pop machine Would be used to the exclusion of all the juice machines and the school was losing revenue.
Rym: The pop machine was owned by some outside company and there were these juice machines that the school owned.
Rym: No one wanted juice from the juice machine.
Rym: wasn't even real juice.
Scott: Wow See when I was in middle school, there was just a juice machine, right?
Scott: But when I was in high school, there was a candy store.
Scott: They would sell candy in the school every day.
Scott: There was actually see.
Rym: my high school had that too.
Scott: So I don't get it for until my senior year because basically what they did is when I was a freshman We were the first class of freshmen in high school who weren't allowed to smoke.
Scott: All the people older than us could smoke on the smoking dock And when we were seniors the smoking dock was finally just an area you could go, you know It wasn't the smoking area because that now there was no smoking.
Scott: But when I was a junior the people who were sophomores when I was a freshman they were the current seniors and they they were the only ones who can go outside and smoke on the smoking dock.
Scott: and There was smoking in high school.
Scott: and now now you can't even get skittles.
Rym: God Also, we should do this show about what high school was like when we were in high school.
Rym: because think about this We got a lot of listeners.
Scott: I think we just did the whole show though I got a lot more to say.
Rym: my I used to go to the mall over lunch.
Scott: I used to just leave I think for the news that you just did.
Scott: I think the general problem there is, you know, no candy in school.
Scott: I mean when I was in middle school, you know candy sales in school.
Rym: Oh because he bought the skittles from a contraband dealer.
Scott: Okay, but basically Here's the moral.
Rym: before you get into your thing There's so we could do.
Rym: you don't have to go back to this story?
Rym: The moral is the kid who's not named who is selling the contraband Gets mad props for being awesome.
Rym: And if my school had banned the sale of pop or something you can bet your ass I would had an illegal pop dispenser in my locker.
Scott: You know back in the way back in the day when Mortal Kombat was a new game a friend of mine wrote a strategy guide for it and Sold it the copies and sold it to kids in school and got in trouble for it.
Scott: He got mad moneys that he needed for something.
Scott: I think he bought a Super Nintendo or something.
Rym: Man the school shouldn't punish that.
Rym: the school should reward him for being entrepreneur.
Scott: I know right, but yeah, basically I think the only problem with the story that you just read there was that the punishment was way too harsh.
Scott: I mean suspended and stripped of student of vice president because you bought skittles.
Scott: I mean I could understand that for say maybe like, you know cheated, you know on like a final.
Scott: or You know is giving out answer books or stole something from somebody, you know something somewhat serious.
Rym: I'm glad you said final though because I'm cheating on homework.
Rym: I Whenever I couldn't get around but buying skittles, that's one detention at most, you know You know what that.
Rym: all that should be is one Punish the seller.
Rym: that do course that I'm sure the seller got punished a lot more and I'm sure.
Rym: but that seller mad props.
Scott: The seller was probably not a high-class, you know student vice president.
Scott: He doesn't get in the news.
Rym: Yeah, it's always the sad thing in high school.
Rym: All you kids in high school remember and remember well.
Rym: as long as these teachers and administrators Believe that you are a nice kid You will get away with anything you want to get away with.
Rym: However, if they think you're a troublemaker you'll get in trouble if you didn't do anything.
Rym: That's kind of the world works.
Rym: So learn it in high school and take advantage of it.
Scott: crying wolf.
Rym: There's a reason the honors kids skip class a hell of a lot more than I don't want to say you because a lot of You are honors kids.
Rym: But there's a reason those kids skip a lot more and get away with a lot more.
Scott: if you're an honors kid You're not skipping.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: Yeah, seriously, you're obvious.
Scott: You're the nerdy type who needs to learn to cut loose.
Rym: if you're a junior in high school And you've had perfect attendance for two years you had straight A's and you've never really been in trouble and you think you're not geek That's definitely nerd territory.
Rym: No, cuz I was like that except for the perfect attendance.
Rym: I Didn't skip though until my sophomore year of high school and I said wait a minute.
Rym: I don't have to go to class.
Rym: What are they gonna do?
Rym: they're not gonna expel me.
Scott: No, all right, so you're a fan of the sub vocalization, are you not?
Scott: I Am.
Rym: oh, I know I know what your news is.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah for those.
Scott: You don't know sub vocalization is basically I mean, it's really it's sort of hard to come with an exact definition, but basically No That's a Wikipedia is sort of sort of unsure about how much I can trust Wikipedia.
Rym: Don't go by Wikipedia Talk, I'll look at the Wikipedia.
Rym: Let's see if it's accurate.
Scott: Basically, it's somewhere but you're basically talking but you're not talking.
Scott: like imagine if you talked and you went through all the motions of talking But you removed the lips tongue and mouth part and you just use the throat part.
Scott: now some people even say Oh, you don't even use the throat part.
Scott: You just sort of you know Think about some words and your body's your the nerves in your body and your throat sort of do Thing but they don't actually make any noise and that is largely true.
Rym: I mean theoretically you could make a device that would read like I Don't know nerve impulses in your neck and throat and figure out what words you were thinking about with the gym.
Scott: Did you just read my news?
Rym: Actually, I didn't read it, but I saw the headline.
Scott: yeah, basically someone's made a device that basically reads the nerves in your neck and There's a picture.
Scott: they figure out what were is a video.
Scott: they figure out what words you're sub vocalizing And then it sort of says them out loud.
Scott: so you can talk without talking so like, you know what this does.
Scott: You're like tongue gets cut out.
Scott: suddenly you can talk.
Rym: There's more to it than that.
Rym: I mean think about this Theoretically that for certain kinds of paralysis, too Yeah, you could talk again, but also beyond
Scott: thinking the
Rym: words This is also very because devices like this that don't measure the nerve impulses But you can talk very low like so low that no one could possibly hear you in your throat.
Rym: and a lot of Special forces people use these things and police forces use these things to communicate in say hostile environment Where you don't to be like counter-strike where I'm sitting there around the corner and I'm waiting for
Scott: and you gotta say you gotta tell Someone to circle around back, but if you go hey Rym circle
Rym: around
Scott: back suddenly all the terrorists go.
Rym: I heard Scott.
Scott: Let's go shoot him.
Scott: They're coming from behind they're coming from behind they're circling around back Of course, I don't say that and then circle around front and then shoot him in the back.
Rym: But then all your teammates circle around back.
Scott: I know man.
Rym: I Don't know anyone realizes the joke with a full joke of circle around back.
Scott: Well, tell it another time.
Scott: Should we let's save it?
Scott: It's a good joke.
Rym: I could you know, we'll wait until I find audio of that.
Rym: good Go that is that is I don't think anything needs to be said.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So, yeah, go go go.
Scott: so they made this device and you know, it's gonna be pretty awesome.
Scott: but the thing is right now it can only recognize about a hundred and fifty words and phrases.
Scott: and because it has to do so Much processing even with the fast processor in there This is a delay between the time you sub vocalize and the time that it says the words out loud for you.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: That doesn't matter at all because all what this is if nothing else is a proof of concept.
Rym: What we've learned from this is that yes, that's possible.
Rym: It's only a matter of time.
Scott: This is a good example of not only something that's awesome and a technology that's gonna change the world for a lot of people but I think this is something of an example of wow, that is something that is patentable.
Scott: like If we have a patent system, this is what patents are for something It's actually fucking new and actually amazing.
Scott: not for someone taking a bunch of stuff that already exists It just happening to be the first one to glue it together, which was obvious to everyone else.
Scott: They just didn't do it yet.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: after you know, there was gonna be a pause there.
Rym: But actually unlike what Scott said before there was no pause there.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: We didn't do it.
Rym: We're going on the wire.
Rym: This is live.
Rym: We don't have any plan.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me?
Rym: Think of the day Scott.
Scott: well water is poison posted this bad boy in the forums and I was so high quality And so impressive that I got to pass it on to anyone who doesn't check it out in the forums.
Scott: basically Do name Christopher Hitchens and he was in a debate with Alistair McGrath in October last year.
Rym: I point out that Alistair is one of my favorite names ever Yep, and basically it was the.
Scott: it was you know, one of those atheism versus religion debates, you know the old-school happy time, right?
Scott: And Basically what someone's done is they took Christopher Hitchens opening statements And by the way Christopher Hitchens is the atheist side of this debate, uh, you know I think we could have left everyone hanging until they listen.
Scott: yeah, they they took his opening statement basically for this debate and they made two videos on YouTube that sort of illustrate his opening statements with pictures and graphics of sorts and Not only the opening statements themselves.
Scott: Pretty much amazing and I couldn't even think of any way to fight against them Even if I wanted to be on that religious side, right the illustrations add a lot of humor and other things, you know and power to the Statement.
Scott: it's worth definitely watching these videos and there's also a link I'm basically linking to our forum for this one.
Scott: It's also Star Fox posted the link to a full video of the debate itself so you can actually watch the whole debate if you're that interested and I'm getting the feeling this is gonna be a high-quality debate because it's a high-quality opening statement.
Rym: cuz I really it's not entertaining To watch someone go there's no God and you're stupid someone else go.
Rym: There is a God and you're stupid.
Rym: Yeah Debates like this are so up my alley.
Scott: There are two people who are actually like academic and civil.
Scott: Speak intelligently in a in a fair and organized way.
Scott: You know the kind of thing that happens not on the internet.
Rym: Haha Maybe we should just go back to like ancient Athens.
Scott: You want your What's it called penis on the Parthenon?
Scott: No you think with the wine?
Rym: Oh, actually I'm still thinking about that.
Rym: I think I gotta wait till we get a house.
Rym: I kind of if I get a house with the sideways chairs with the circuit spiral pillow My thinking is actually if and when I get a house I want to for what.
Rym: I want to furnish the living room not with a big couch Like everyone has like the central black and the coffee table because that's with the sheer number of people We have over so often.
Rym: That's just so restrictive.
Rym: and what we can do and how is the hundred beanbag chairs of the major is even worse.
Rym: They take up so much space and offer so little.
Rym: they turn into flat crap.
Rym: I gotta have you gotta have the kind of more beans, but then they take up even more space.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I want though.
Rym: I want symposium chairs and then all I need is a big bowl like a big bowl to put in the middle of the room and a bunch of saucers and I Seriously want to host a symposium in the classic sense.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: you the only the only You're.
Scott: you're steam cleaning the carpet afterwards.
Rym: You see you're not.
Rym: If you get drunk at a symposium, you're doing it wrong.
Scott: I'm talking about spilling the wine.
Rym: If anyone spills the wine, there's a giant is a giant bowl and saucers.
Scott: It's gonna be spilled.
Rym: Well, it'll be a tile room.
Scott: So uh-huh.
Scott: All righty, then.
Scott: Yeah, then you got him off the floor.
Rym: I'm so about as important and if you and if you stay in the grout purple, you gotta clean that - I'm surprised You remembered that because this is something that's been in my it's.
Rym: this has been in my hopper for a long time Ever since I learned what the word symposium actually meant.
Scott: All right, we got a thing of the day.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Symposium.
Rym: Well, I do.
Rym: in fact speaking of the exact opposite of a symposium This is this is a video of us performing at an anime convention.
Scott: Oh, come on, what do you give using us as a thing of the day?
Scott: That's so shit.
Rym: We're not the thing of the day.
Rym: Here's the deal.
Rym: I There are a lot of videos of us on YouTube performing conventions and I was not aware There's not to go watch.
Rym: a lot of them are very poorly done Just because you know, it's some punk kid in the audience filming something.
Rym: But my thing of the day is not hey watch this video and I wouldn't even recommend you watch the whole thing.
Rym: But I want to point something out.
Rym: We've talked about this on Tuesdays and Wednesdays mostly Wednesdays.
Rym: But you know our Thursday listeners are a different bunch in general.
Rym: A lot of you listen to like all the rest of GeekNights or you only listen to Thursday.
Scott: It's kind of weird what goes on with the different days.
Rym: Thursday's a really different day.
Rym: It's kind of a different.
Rym: we we tend to blow Thursday off a lot more and get a lot less formal and a lot more.
Scott: I like today Today's super air.
Rym: Yeah, but it's weird.
Rym: every time we do an episode like this people like man.
Rym: that episode was great and every time we try and do like a Research episodes like wow, that was boring.
Scott: I don't get it.
Rym: Anyway, so there's a phenomenon that occurs whenever you're in their groups of fans of something and never nowhere.
Rym: Is this more clear than at an anime convention now?
Rym: I want you to watch the beginning of this video because the video quality is awful.
Rym: I apologize for that, but we're running this anime match game.
Rym: It's like a game show with we got all the.
Rym: actually the guests up there are pretty hot.
Rym: I'll say that the old-looking man is Peter Fernandez the first voice of Speed Racer.
Scott: No the English choice.
Rym: Yeah, let me tell you that dude's a cool freaking dude.
Scott: It's weird cuz like this old man hobbles in and I'm like, oh man, it's that guy I knew he was coming like.
Rym: I don't want to hurt him and then he talks.
Scott: He still has like famous old radio voice and it's like wow Like tiny old man with like this crazy voice coming out.
Scott: You're like, holy shit.
Scott: I need a voice like that so I can be all radio.
Rym: but notice what happens in the beginning of this.
Rym: I'm doing you know a match game question and this is one of our like throwaway questions that supposed to be a crowd-pleaser.
Rym: It's not because we the match game was never intended for anyone to actually win it.
Rym: It's intended to make people write funny things.
Rym: So the question is I say, you know, this is very blah blah blah.
Rym: name for me a Pokemon and I Consider the noise level of the room up until ice.
Rym: I asked the question fully and then listen to what happens because it seems like whenever you're at a fan convention Especially anime you can you could we could do an event and we do this at all our panels just to see and kind of Mess with people.
Rym: All right We're gonna talk about something and the crew there's a big crowd hundreds hundreds of people and they're sitting there and they're waiting for me to talk.
Rym: and if Scott or I just say like Final Fantasy the crowd loses their shit.
Scott: No Final Fantasy 6 Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles, oh my god, they said the name of something I like.
Scott: it's time to cheer.
Rym: I learned of this phenomenon at the RIT anime club because Luke who was kind of the leader of the club at the time whenever there was a Delay like a technical problem You got to entertain the crowd or they'll fucking kill us.
Rym: cuz that's.
Rym: the crowd was big and dangerous.
Rym: yeah, a bunch of anime fans, but If he needed to entertain a crowd on the spot with no preparation.
Rym: All he do is go to the crowd.
Rym: He'd be like yell out someone who's awesome and then someone would be like Roger Smith from Big O And then he'd be like, all right Who's more awesome than Roger Smith?
Rym: and then the crowd would just go crazy and he would just kind of whip them up into this Fury.
Rym: Until we are we were ready to go and then we hit play on whatever DVD we were watching.
Rym: Yeah, I don't understand this phenomenon but here's an example of it in case you have never seen it.
Scott: if you ever think about where rims actually saying what actually is Going on and look at the reaction people the audience has to what's going on and look how disproportionate it is It's like they react so crazily to so little.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of scary.
Rym: Wasn't one of our clever questions That wasn't one of the ones with like four sentences of witty like build-up to some amazing funny thing That was name a Pokemon.
Rym: The worst thing is people react the same way as people named Pokemon.
Scott: Yeah, okay, man, okay, man.
Scott: So can't help.
Scott: what are we doing the show on today?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: So we had to show on something.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, let's see.
Rym: We were talking.
Rym: we could talk about high school.
Rym: How high school has changed?
Scott: yeah, but what am I gonna say?
Scott: I already said what I had to say.
Rym: I got a lot more to say but that's cuz.
Rym: my high school was weird.
Rym: So like my high school wasn't locked My school wasn't locked.
Rym: high schools are locked.
Rym: Now.
Rym: You can't get in during the day.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Rym: Yeah, I can't go outside.
Scott: I think yeah Maybe that's part of the thing is that it's hard for me to say what's different about high school because I don't know about high School now very much.
Scott: I know but I've been to high school and like I I graduate in 2000.
Rym: So we're talking like a decade pretty I think the reason I know is that the whole Columbine thing happened while we were in High school and I graduated right.
Rym: but the summer after I went to college I actually went back to Michigan for that summer.
Rym: That was the last summer I spent in Michigan.
Rym: like that was the last any time I spent in Michigan really.
Rym: but I Went back and you know I knew some a lot of the administration and people at this college or God the college a high school and Went back and I wanted to talk to people and I remember one day I just went back over the high school and I tried to walk in and the doors were locked.
Rym: I was like what the fuck all the doors were locked.
Rym: So I went to the front office and they're like, who are you?
Rym: I'm like I'm an old Rym.
Rym: I was like Practically valedictorian.
Rym: I was awesome.
Rym: Don't you remember me?
Rym: And they're like, oh, yeah, we know who you are.
Rym: What the hell you doing here?
Rym: Like I don't know.
Rym: I want to say hi to mr.
Rym: Garrison.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: What's-his-name?
Rym: No, I just made up a name.
Rym: I want to say hi to mr So and so and miss so and so.
Rym: you can't go in here.
Rym: What go away.
Rym: You can't be on school grounds.
Rym: You leave immediately.
Rym: What?
Rym: You're not a student here.
Rym: You don't live here.
Rym: You have to leave.
Rym: law blah blah blah blah like.
Rym: ah.
Rym: So I went over to the one place.
Rym: I knew I could get into the school the band room.
Rym: I just ripped open the secret door that as far as I know is still broken.
Rym: you can just open it 24 to 7 and I went in and Talked to my teachers.
Rym: They're like, yeah, if they find you here, they're probably gonna call the police.
Rym: I was like what and I remember my teachers telling me how crappy this high school had gotten in like the year and a half.
Rym: So yeah high schools are different.
Scott: All right, so do you want to do the whole show on that or you think it's not else?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: All I could do now is enumerate all the things that are different and I don't want to get into that because that also be A lot of man.
Rym: high school was awesome.
Rym: All you kids can't experience what we had.
Scott: All right, so let's see what do we have on the calendar here, let's see all you open in the calendar.
Scott: I already had the calendar open.
Scott: It's a spaceship.
Scott: dogfight is scheduled for today, but I don't think we want to do that.
Rym: I look up spaceships.
Scott: Yeah, I only know a few.
Scott: Let's see if I were a superhero if I were a super villain.
Scott: Yeah, if I were a pirate Do you really build the calendar for those?
Rym: if I worse because we were hurting for Thursdays for so long and then finally Someone in the forum was like what if you were a super villain?
Scott: and we realized that was me.
Rym: Yeah, and then we I guess it was you and then we're like, wait a minute Why don't we just do?
Rym: those episodes are really popular and they're really easy to do But I don't know.
Rym: I don't feel like doing one of those that takes that's a high-energy episode.
Rym: Yeah I don't have high energy.
Scott: There's a crime and punishment where I guess we talked about like dostoevsky and what's wrong with them and that sort of thing.
Rym: Yeah, or we could talk about the book.
Scott: I've never read the book.
Scott: What it's big and long.
Rym: It's really good.
Rym: Have you read anything by him?
Scott: No, I know he is.
Scott: I know his books.
Scott: I've never read them.
Rym: Oh, it's got you got to read crime and punishment.
Scott: That's not gonna happen.
Rym: It's a good book.
Scott: All right, I'll read that and I'm just gonna let that Prince of Nothing sit there.
Rym: God read the Prince of Nothing first.
Rym: It's a better book.
Rym: Oh Man, I wanted to this Thursday about the Prince of Nothing, but you got to read it.
Scott: I'll read it something.
Rym: actually it's something all of tall.
Rym: you listeners out there I want.
Scott: you know, I would have read it sooner But you know what?
Scott: I'm almost done with Ace Attorney when I was gonna face 34 and as soon as I finished it I was maybe gonna read Prince of Nothing, but you know what?
Scott: No, Krista Chronicles DS shows up.
Rym: Oh, well I'm gonna tell you all right now everyone out there.
Rym: There's a book.
Rym: It is called the darkness that comes before the Prince of Nothing.
Rym: It's the first in a series.
Rym: it is written by our Scott backer.
Rym: I Cannot recommend this book to you highly enough.
Scott: Do you want to set the Amazon affiliate thing that we talked about?
Rym: We should set that up.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, basically like I know people out there, right?
Scott: We have always said we don't make money on the show and we don't want to make money on the show We're not gonna advertise or anything like that, right?
Scott: But apparently, you know, the Amazon affiliate program has been around for a long time.
Scott: If you don't know what it is, basically it allows you to make links to Amazon.
Scott: So and those links sort of give you money.
Scott: So for example, if I wanted to link to say this Prince of Nothing book And I put a link to the Prince of Nothing book on Amazon on our website, right?
Scott: I Could just make a link to the book on Amazon.
Scott: there's nothing stopped me from doing that.
Scott: but the affiliate program means I do a special link and what happens is if I was to Click on that link a special link and then buy the book Amazon would know hey someone bought this book and Scott sent them here.
Scott: I'm gonna give Scott like, you know, ten or twenty percent of the price of that book.
Rym: I think it's a lot less than that.
Scott: It's actually a quite a bit.
Scott: It's a significant discount.
Scott: So you could buy like books from yourself and save money on Amazon.
Scott: Cuz they'll just.
Scott: it's basically like an automatic rebate if you set up the affiliate program for yourself.
Rym: Well, anyway, I think you can also.
Scott: the real idea of it Is that like you listeners would buy books that we told you to buy or not just books but DVDs CDs Whatever and you click on the links at front recruit calm.
Scott: you then buy the product and then we get money.
Rym: Now I guess we're thinking about doing this partly because we don't have any other way to make money off a GeekNights.
Rym: And well as we've said clearly and repeatedly we will never ever advertise in GeekNights on the website anything ever.
Scott: Nope, it's not gonna happen.
Rym: So we figure basically we're warning you now because if we do this We're pretty much we don't want like unlike a lot of other people who just throw these links in willy-nilly like in foreign posts and everything To try to just get the money and
Scott: they don't tell you what they're doing.
Scott: They're just put a link there to Amazon.
Scott: You don't realize that they're making money off.
Rym: We're gonna be so upfront about this.
Scott: We're gonna be like if you click this link and buy the book we will make money.
Scott: You can click this link to buy the book and we won't get money.
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna totally be upfront with it, but we just give the option out there.
Rym: Yeah, of course We're gonna start selling.
Scott: also use it to buy stuff for a discount for ourselves.
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: I did just buy another copy of the darkness that comes before.
Scott: we have one.
Scott: What do you need to?
Rym: I bought?
Rym: The hardcover one.
Rym: I couldn't get anywhere.
Rym: so I bought it used in good condition for really little money.
Scott: I guess what needs a hardcover for hardcover suck because it's a really good book.
Scott: That doesn't mean anything.
Scott: hardcover suck.
Rym: the hardcover is gonna be my lending copy.
Scott: Why don't you an episode about why I could argue that hardcover suck?
Rym: actually You know what?
Rym: If a book is thicker than about an inch.
Rym: I really prefer a hardcover.
Scott: I never prefer a hardcover and here's why.
Scott: number one.
Scott: It's more expensive.
Scott: not if you buy it used number Yes, but the same can be said for paperback.
Scott: number two, it takes up more physical space.
Rym: It's worth it.
Rym: If you're reading a book that's more than an inch thick or if it's two inches thick Without the hardcover the thing falls apart and sucks to read and it only falls apart if the binding is shitty.
Scott: binding can be shitty On hardcovers - I've had hardcovers fall off just as much as soft.
Scott: I haven't only old ones Yeah, but if the binding is shitty does not?
Scott: you know that the binding is shitty?
Scott: It doesn't matter what kind of binding it is.
Scott: It's a shitty binding.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: I disagree with you.
Rym: I like hardcovers.
Scott: I don't like hardcovers ever.
Scott: I would always.
Scott: the only time I get a hardcover actually is I actually buy the Walking Dead in hardcover because it's so much cheaper.
Rym: Anyway, anyway our Scott backer the Prince of Nothing the darkness that comes before Serious hardcore amazing fantasy.
Rym: I I'm amazed by these books.
Rym: I think I talked about him before.
Rym: Yeah, yes But the reason I'm gonna tell you all to get these books and read them again is because I'm working on Getting an interview with the author.
Rym: No, and I've seen other interviews with him and There's no question that I had was not already asked Answered.
Rym: so if any of you have questions for the author Let us know I guess and then I'll have to read the book and then that'll push me more and more toward actually getting an Interview or trying to get an interview.
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty sure I can get one.
Rym: Also, if any of you have questions for Luke Crane the god of role-playing Then I don't think he's the god.
Scott: I think he's like the rock star of rope.
Scott: Yeah, he's definitely the rocks The rock star of tabletop role-playing.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna interview him again soon.
Rym: So send us your questions.
Rym: We'll talk about that on Tuesday, I guess.
Scott: All right, so we're not gonna talk about that.
Rym: I Guess I could talk about it.
Rym: You could just sit there.
Scott: Yeah Okay, so let's check the forum thread of show ideas.
Rym: Oh great.
Rym: This is gonna go nowhere.
Rym: Yeah, I know Let me pull it up to.
Rym: we can.
Rym: You see guys out there.
Rym: This is what happens.
Rym: This is what we do.
Rym: part of the reason we're doing This is we're just.
Rym: this is what we would be doing if We didn't have a show idea and we weren't tired and we weren't worried about getting the show done and going to bed or whatever.
Rym: I'm in brawl.
Rym: We would just have this discussion for an hour and then we do the show on whatever we decided.
Scott: Thursday series Disney animated films.
Scott: We thought of that before.
Scott: I could do a show on Dumbo probably or Aladdin But we sort of skipped out of the movie phase.
Scott: you want to go back to the movie phase a little bit.
Rym: I don't got to watch movies Scott who's never seen a strange days and How to run an online community?
Rym: that's probably Monday.
Scott: that's a Monday.
Rym: Yes, that's not a suggestion.
Rym: well Okay, you might want to do continue the series.
Rym: how to not suck at college.
Rym: Yeah, I guess we never continued that.
Scott: What?
Scott: where did we stop?
Scott: what's left to say?
Rym: we ended with part one.
Scott: did we?
Scott: really?
Rym: well He said do a part two.
Rym: Did we do a part two?
Rym: What page you on the first of the last page?
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: Oh Well to go look that one up.
Scott: Well
Rym: Anyone out there if you want to tell us to continue how to not suck at college Tell us what we talked about in the first how to not suck at college
Scott: and tell us what you want us to talk about In the second how to not suck at college.
Rym: However, tell the easiest thing.
Rym: there are three things and you can only pick two sleep fun grades.
Scott: I would like to see an episode on Tesla coils or Tesla's other great inventions.
Scott: That's sort of a Monday, but we could do a Tesla show.
Scott: Yeah, that's really cool.
Rym: Also a lot of people as is my man a lot of people however think Tesla accomplished a lot more than he actually did.
Scott: That is true is not?
Rym: he did not make magic.
Rym: There's all the conspiracy people always like.
Rym: yeah, Tesla had a blah in 19 blah.
Scott: He had a thing that you could fit in your pocket but would have make earthquakes that would shake the whole city.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: You're right and And I would like to hear more of rims 80s metal keyboard.
Rym: Are you are you serious?
Scott: I think he's me may be serious, but he's alone All right.
Rym: Do you guys want to hear more of my 80s metal keyboard?
Scott: the keyboards not even here anyone?
Rym: No, it's an Emily's apartment, but I have a laptop and a MIDI interface.
Rym: Oh, I could go over there and make you some music.
Rym: I don't know if you want me to.
Scott: yeah, someone wants to do an Akira show.
Scott: That's a Wednesday, but you still haven't read that.
Rym: Now, yeah, we could do just the movie first.
Scott: I haven't watched the movie in so long.
Scott: I didn't get the DVD.
Scott: I could get the DVDs at least actually a good DVD.
Rym: We can watch it on Netflix on demand anytime.
Rym: Is it really on there?
Rym: Yeah, it's the dub but it's.
Scott: no that doesn't count.
Rym: Tell us not that bad.
Scott: I know but especially the new dub is not that bad.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah So I probably actually the new dub is better than the old dub There's no doubt.
Scott: but I accept my style.
Scott: I have nostalgia.
Scott: I have a nostalgia for the old dub and the new dub sort of bothers me because the nostalgia Hey, you always yell at me when there's nostalgia for a dog because I at least I admit it.
Scott: Well, it depends because some dubs like the difference between saying that what though the old ones better and saying the old one isn't better But I like it better.
Rym: for There are some dubs like where the old dub or the American dub Was probably worse on a technical scale and worse on an accuracy scale.
Rym: then newer dubs of newer shows But they were just done better and with more spirit or more emotion or better acting and just more.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Sometimes the old stuff is better.
Scott: All right, let's see the Constitution.
Scott: Yeah, it takes more than a show.
Scott: We need like one show per you realize amendment and then one show per article.
Rym: You realize we've already like we're.
Rym: whenever we finally do shows on politics We probably need to do a multi-part series on federalism in and of itself.
Rym: How about the idea of democracy?
Rym: democracy itself would take us a month to cover God?
Scott: sitcoms Simpson Seinfeld, that's it.
Rym: Uh, I don't know the credit stones.
Rym: the critic was good.
Scott: Is that a sitcom?
Rym: What did?
Rym: what did what?
Rym: what constant you realize got?
Rym: sitcom means a situational comedy a comedy wherein humor can be derived from situations in which Critic is more of a character comedy than a situation comedy.
Rym: Uh, but they put the character in situations.
Scott: Seinfeld, I don't know.
Rym: Ah We should do Sean Seinfeld.
Scott: That's not a bad show.
Rym: That's a good show.
Rym: I like Seinfeld.
Rym: is you know what the funniest thing about Seinfeld is?
Rym: I really found it funny.
Rym: as a kid and my parent like all my whole family We love Seinfeld.
Rym: now that I live it like live and work in New York It's a lot funnier cuz a lot of those jokes I didn't quite get.
Rym: yeah now I get him.
Scott: Oh this guy chaos of 99 has a good list here.
Scott: Let's see Michael Moore.
Scott: He's crazy.
Scott: presidential elections Go back to the old way.
Rym: I Don't know horror movies.
Scott: They're not scary.
Scott: Importing games cost too much money.
Rym: a zombie a go-go suggests.
Scott: Yarr matey nice Road trips are traveling in general.
Scott: We've covered that collectible card games.
Scott: put that on a Tuesday already in the calendar.
Rym: Infiniti or non collectible collectible card game.
Scott: Yeah infinity in math or science It means infinity like goes on forever to stop.
Rym: No, there's.
Rym: there's a lot of different kinds of infinity like the aleph-nal infinity And yeah, I don't know that kind of kind of math.
Rym: I could do a show on that but it's not that interesting.
Rym: There's the extent of what I could do.
Rym: I could tell you all the different kinds of infinity and describe what they are to the best of my knowledge.
Scott: Utopian and dystopian futures.
Scott: that's kind of interesting.
Scott: But what are we gonna are we just gonna talk about?
Scott: Possibilities or like different books that have utopian and dystopian future talk about what's more likely or what?
Rym: Technologies could cause either to happen.
Scott: No fraternities.
Scott: I could talk about that.
Rym: You should do a show just on 1984.
Scott: Yeah, we could do that.
Scott: I haven't read it in a while.
Rym: You read it again.
Scott: It takes.
Rym: you guys need to read and review Johnny the homicidal maniac.
Rym: I have read Johnny the homicidal maniac.
Scott: I've only read the first volume of Johnny the homicidal maniac.
Scott: That was a long time ago.
Rym: I think we should read it again and then do a show on it.
Scott: We can get means we gotta get it.
Scott: We don't have it.
Scott: I'll get it.
Scott: It's not easy to get.
Rym: well, cuz I borrowed Greg's I know me too.
Scott: I read his first ball.
Rym: Anyway, uh, Jason, did we ever learn how Brandon became Rym?
Rym: I've answered that in like four separate shows.
Rym: seriously people Oh and someone right after link to me explaining it in the forum, let's see Thursday, okay Experiences in Walmart.
Scott: Walmart is a store and I didn't don't go there ever.
Scott: I will I will.
Scott: if it was the last store on earth.
Scott: I wouldn't go there.
Rym: last time I went to a Walmart.
Rym: I was in North Carolina.
Rym: It was the only place I could get Red Bull.
Rym: Oh, no, I went to one in Arizona to.
Scott: paranormal experiences Don't exist because they're not real.
Rym: Ah, I think I could do a good show along those lines though Being bored at work.
Scott: You mean?
Rym: Every day why don't see you get a job like I have?
Rym: I have not been bored at work ever.
Scott: I actually I see.
Scott: the thing is I actually have work to do at work and it's not boring but I'm just kind of man like I'll sit there and just sort of read my email and read the forum and then put my head on my desk and when I could be doing work and I kind of want to do but I just kind of go
Rym: a Stochicon episode.
Rym: we can do.
Scott: we have to do that.
Scott: that has to be done things.
Scott: I miss as a child.
Scott: I'm not a child.
Scott: So I don't miss anything.
Scott: I could miss things from childhood.
Scott: I miss having no responsibility in plenty of free time.
Scott: How about and having someone cooking clean for me?
Scott: Yeah, that was.
Scott: that was good God.
Rym: is that in terms of if I look at that part like just from that perspective When I was in high school, I had infinite resources.
Rym: as far as you know, reasonable resources were available.
Rym: I had infinite free time zero Responsibility and I could do whatever I want whenever I wanted any time and no one would say anything.
Scott: Oh God pizza and Italian food Mexican food Chinese food Japanese.
Scott: What's it?
Scott: the food people?
Rym: We've done a bunch of food.
Scott: I'm telling you someone out there.
Scott: We need some more food podcasts.
Scott: There's a demand for food podcast that is unfulfilled.
Scott: We should make like the food podcast network.
Scott: I think I could make a food network would sue us, but we should make the food podcast network I think I could make.
Rym: if I weren't doing GeekNights and I had free time I think I could make a pretty good like once every other week or once a week food.
Scott: But see I wouldn't.
Scott: actually if I made a food podcast I wouldn't say anything about food because I'm not qualified But all I would do is research culinary people not re-interview culinary people from around the world And I would ask them about their cooking and such.
Rym: why ice hockey is awesome.
Rym: Oh, no, he heard that episode.
Rym: He wants to talk about RIT hockey.
Rym: Uh Hockey I could do a show on RIT.
Scott: Hey, that's what this is.
Rym: That is hit somebody.
Scott: You gotta do you know what?
Rym: I suddenly I really miss being able to yell hit somebody And have someone out there hit somebody directly because I said it.
Rym: I don't think God we got to do a show Even at the NHL.
Scott: that won't happen.
Rym: Yeah, remember at RIT hockey if you were sitting in the corner and you yell remember you can't just yell hit somebody you have To yell it like that hit somebody.
Rym: Someone will hit someone as soon as they can usually getting interference call.
Scott: Yes for the evil refs We would you.
Rym: how the evil around?
Rym: how dare they enforce the rules against us and how dare they not call that cheap shot From the other team.
Scott: Okay Someone says we should do a Monty Python show next Thursday.
Scott: Monty Python.
Rym: Definitely.
Scott: There we go.
Rym: I learned one thing when to go lock Emily's friend to Gucci Sun was visiting from Japan.
Rym: We learned something They know about Monty Python in Japan.
Scott: They don't have anything.
Scott: Let me there's nothing we have that they want that they don't talk.
Rym: talking to this kid was fascinating.
Rym: I should talk about this on a Wednesday, but we learned a couple of things.
Rym: one as far as the average Japanese anime fan is As far as they would consider our anime tastes and collection We are old fucking men who watch old obscure weird stuff that kids they had never even heard of or don't care about.
Scott: Yes, pretty much like that.
Rym: We know more about anime than we should.
Scott: Yep And also the only thing that the Japanese people want from America that they don't have is iPhones and we don't even want iPhone.
Scott: Yes, you can have the iPhones take them.
Scott: We don't need them.
Rym: He was like, yeah Like they're like we're like all men and he's showing us like his DS games like.
Scott: oh He's got like this game by Atlas that is like this amazing like maze game that looks like Dungeon Master.
Scott: and I'm like Oh, look at that maze I want that game so bad.
Rym: and then we talked to him and we realized that there no there's.
Rym: every game that is good comes out in Japan and Possibly America.
Rym: no game that is good comes out in America not Japan except PC games.
Rym: That's because PC gaming barely exists in Japan.
Scott: Yeah, there's a barrel.
Scott: Yeah, they don't have portal but they don't know about it to want it.
Rym: god It was funny.
Rym: Emily was trying to explain to him what portal was but you know offhand You don't know the word for like wormhole in Japanese.
Rym: So it was like it's a game but instead of shooting bullets you shoot doors.
Rym: what like front doors?
Rym: No, like like holes like explosions.
Scott: No, like like the entrance to should I just showed it to him?
Rym: No, she did.
Rym: She was like fine.
Rym: Never mind here YouTube video Dawg.
Rym: Yeah, ah, yeah, yeah, I do a show about Chianti But I don't think anyone else wants to have we have we managed to talk long enough about what to do a show on that.
Scott: We've managed to kill the show yet.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I kind of want to make my french toast holla and some eggs to go with that.
Rym: So You have gotten a rare insight into the creative process of GeekNights Yeah, and a total cop-out from some lazy ass fools.
Rym: I'll tell you all something scary and you might be.
Rym: it might have sounded like we were talking to you because When we're alone we sound like this.
Rym: when when our friends are over we sound like this like it might sound weird But we noticed this way back at RIT when the way the room was set up.
Rym: We'd all be in the living room of our apartment because everyone hung out in our apartment our tiny ass little smelly Dank basement apartment.
Scott: Oh the dank mo the dank.
Rym: What about the dank?
Rym: but everyone would sit like in the living room But it's kind of had our computers like against the far wall and our desks through there.
Rym: So we'd sit in our computer chairs because you know We got to use every possible place.
Rym: someone can sit or stand or no one's gonna fit.
Rym: So we would sit kind of facing each other and like a 45 degree angle half facing each other Half facing the front row crew and extended Visigothic community the Visigoths the Ostrogoths the Vandals everyone and We would talk.
Rym: it was almost like we were different.
Rym: It was like a forum debate and everyone else was the audience and like a burning wheel duel of wits.
Rym: and it wasn't just us Other people would do this too, but it got to the point where whenever any of us talk to each other We almost always talk as though there's a third neutral party who was evaluating us and we were trying to convince them not each other.
Scott: Mm-hmm, and it's kind of weird sometimes but if you were in the room with us Party you agree that like Rym should like end this episode and we should go eat right and go to bed.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Well, yes, I do.
Rym: You know what if I weren't tired and lazy I totally should have used the mic dent button.
Rym: no don't All right, we're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.