Rym: It's Thursday, October 23rd.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: It's a Thursday.
Rym: We talk about the dorms at RIT.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So you'd think, in these troubled economic times, working for one of those Wall Street financial companies, everyone would be fully vested in interest in what is going on in the stock market and dealing with the systems and the market and all this stuff.
Scott: Well, I mean, it depends what your company does.
Scott: I mean, like, look, if you're a company...
Rym: Well, no, I'm about to tell an anecdote.
Rym: You see, I'm not making a general statement.
Rym: But you'd think that when there's work to be done, you'd be paying attention to the work, and maybe it's kind of like when you're at a boxing match, right?
Rym: More often than not, no matter how much money you paid, I'll bet that if you're watching this boxing match and suddenly two drunk guys in the audience get into a fight, everyone's going to turn and watch the drunk guys.
Scott: I was at a football game last weekend and there were.
Scott: whenever there's a fight in the stands somewhere, the heads turn that way.
Rym: That really says something.
Scott: The thing is, usually the fights happen like between plays.
Scott: You don't miss.
Scott: I didn't miss a single moment of the game despite seeing like two fights.
Rym: Well, because the people fighting obviously paid to see the football, obviously.
Rym: But when there's not football on, they got to do something.
Rym: But so, you know, we're at work and I'm typing.
Rym: It's kind of early in the morning.
Rym: Not everyone's in yet.
Rym: I'm doing stuff and other people are doing stuff and we're talking about, oh, what's the market going to do?
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Talking shop and a mouse walks by.
Rym: Little mouse just kind of walks by, walks along kind of casually, walks into a conference room and then we lose sight of him.
Scott: So it's a pretty old building.
Rym: Well, it's the Lincoln building.
Scott: So is this from the 1800s, this building?
Rym: No, I don't actually know the full history.
Rym: All I know is that the Lincoln building is pretty damn old.
Rym: It's one of the older skyscrapers in midtown.
Rym: It's like right across from Grand Central.
Scott: I guess it's.
Scott: it's not older than the Flatiron.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: But this mouse, it's like, you know, everyone's working.
Rym: And then someone says, was that a mouse?
Rym: Everyone in the entire office.
Rym: Remember, our office is all cool.
Rym: Like it's one big open space with glass walls and it's kind of neat.
Rym: Everyone stands up.
Rym: The mouse is now the most important thing in the world.
Rym: We ended up chasing it around.
Rym: We caught it in a wastebasket and we took it downstairs and we let it outside into the subway.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, think about it, right?
Scott: You're at work.
Scott: No one actually wants to work, you know.
Scott: And yeah, this excuse is totally thing that happens outside of, you know, the normal workflow.
Scott: So everyone's just looking to find any reason to escape and spend some time on something that doesn't happen at work every day.
Rym: Well, it's a phenomenon I've seen often.
Rym: I remember when I worked back at the hospital one day, this was back in the last month there where I didn't really have any work to do.
Rym: I got up and I went to go to lunch and I tried to get out.
Rym: And one of the door just like wouldn't open.
Rym: I just couldn't open it.
Rym: So I went around to the other side and I saw that the door was jammed.
Rym: So I went and told someone and like everyone in the car, there were like a hundred people talking about the door.
Rym: Everyone was like standing around like, well, how could we fix it?
Rym: I'm going to try to jam a screwdriver in there.
Rym: Oh, that didn't work.
Rym: And more people were more interested in this door than anything they'd ever been in anything they'd ever done for this company.
Scott: It's a way to escape from, you know, work and do at least something.
Rym: Of course, the hospital was different from my current job in that I don't think anyone did any work.
Scott: That's most works.
Rym: That I don't know.
Rym: That's all I have.
Rym: It was it was kind of a boring day other than the mouse.
Scott: Yeah, my day.
Scott: Not too exciting.
Scott: Starting to, you know, it's getting a little corporate up in my business now that we got bought.
Scott: You know, they quit.
Scott: I got to get another job first.
Scott: And I've.
Rym: I've never been quit shy.
Scott: I'm not quit shy.
Scott: I'm very quit trigger happy.
Scott: The only thing is I don't quit until I got a place to go already.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I guess the thing is that my new policy now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which I'm trying to figure out is a good policy to have.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: I'm going to guess never take a new job unless it is substantially better than the previous one.
Scott: Well, not just that.
Scott: I'm not going to take any job.
Scott: that isn't completely awesome.
Rym: Well, I can at least say that my my change was a little more subtle.
Scott: I basically one day said, look, because I've had a whole bunch of basically pretty good jobs, but none of them are the kind of place where I want to hang around for years and years and years and years.
Scott: I'm not going.
Scott: the next job I get, whatever it is, working for myself or someone else is going to be a job where for years and years and years and years, every single day, even like 10 years from now, I'm like, oh, man's work.
Scott: Here we go.
Rym: Rock and roll.
Scott: Otherwise, I'm not doing it.
Rym: See, my policy was pretty much I realized in the first job, you know, funny how I get like the best job ever, probably the last salary job I will ever have.
Rym: And I get it when I decide that I'm not going to separate work from real life anymore.
Rym: I'm not going to hide like, you know, resumes.
Rym: I didn't put like gig nights or anime conventions on my resume before I put, you know, I put some things on there, but I kind of left the whole podcast thing to the side and I didn't talk about kind of my.
Scott: See, I never hid that stuff, but it never mattered.
Rym: But I finally put all that stuff on my resume.
Rym: I like game theory in there and like Otakon and all this stuff.
Rym: And suddenly everyone wants to interview me and suddenly all they ask about is, oh, so you do a podcast.
Rym: Oh, you're on the radio.
Rym: Oh, you go to conventions.
Rym: You're a professional speaker.
Rym: What's all this?
Rym: Blah, blah, blah.
Rym: And I have like the best freaking job in the world.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Actually, I've applied so far for one rock star job.
Rym: It is a pretty rock star job.
Rym: Scott applied to.
Scott: I applied to work with Peter Rojas at record level or wherever they're calling it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And which is happens to be very close physically in location to my current work.
Scott: I don't know if I'm going to hear back from them.
Scott: He hasn't emailed me back yet, but he tweeted today and I saw his tweet was someone sent me a resume, but they sent me a link to a Google doc.
Scott: They get they score major points with me.
Scott: And I'm like, ah, I was thinking of doing that, but I couldn't get the formatting to be consistent because I made a Google doc of my resume and I went and I looked at it on Linux.
Scott: I looked at it on Windows and it didn't look the same.
Scott: It didn't look the same in every browser.
Rym: And like I had bullets on there and the realize I realized long ago, my resume has been PDFs for the last eight years.
Scott: Bullets are all messed up in the different Google docs.
Scott: So I chose not to send him a Google doc link resume instead said the PDF to get the guaranteed formatting treated him and said that I did.
Scott: I did tweet him and say that I said I was thinking of doing that, but I couldn't get the formatting consistent.
Scott: So I did an open office export to PDF.
Scott: But maybe next time, since I'm applying for rock star jobs with, you know, cool people, the cool people will like, you know, like the Google doc, like I don't know, you know, it's weird.
Scott: I'll do the Google doc link and the PDF attachment.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: I can't say one thing.
Rym: I used to, you know, pretty much throughout RIT, I would update my resume like every couple of weeks.
Rym: Like I'd keep my resume like this.
Rym: It's always ready to go.
Rym: And I'd have like the most current version, like with me all the time.
Rym: And I was always.
Rym: I don't even know if I have my resume anymore.
Scott: I think I've always had it lying around on a disk.
Rym: But the last time I made it, I made it from like my previous one.
Rym: You know, it was like the ten thousand.
Scott: I've just been updating the same resume from like two thousand and two or some shit like that, too.
Rym: But two thousand, maybe unless the original is on one of those, like four hard drives I'm not using.
Rym: All I have left is the PDF.
Rym: Oh, yeah, granted, I have, you know, the full Adobe thing.
Scott: I think actually open office three, I think an open PDF and edit them, I think.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The feature is something like that.
Rym: I don't know if I'll ever pretty much.
Rym: I don't think I need my resume for getting a job anymore.
Rym: I need my resume for other things, like trying to be an expert witness.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, you know, you never know when you need a resume.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But I feel like I think I'm just going to make my quote unquote, I mean, you're going to work at the same place for, you know, you might work there for five, maybe ten years, but you'll need another job after that.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I pretty much feel like you're going to work there for 30, 40 years.
Rym: No, I feel like this is my penultimate job, as in I will.
Rym: either this will be my career or I will leave it at a point when I no longer will be working for someone else.
Rym: It's going to be one of the two.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or I guess, you know, if Mad Max happens, then I'll have to get a new job.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Scott: Your new job of, I guess, leading my married man, leather wearing ne'er-do-wells, corpse, hokudono Ken master or I don't know.
Rym: I've been practicing pleather preparer.
Rym: Why do they have so much pleather, so much gasoline?
Rym: I also didn't realize there were three Mad Max movies.
Rym: I only thought there were two Mad Max, Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome.
Rym: And yeah, that's the only ones I knew about.
Rym: But I was told by multiple people there was a third one that I guess I had three even farther beyond the next three.
Scott: return to Thunderdome Mad Max three Thunderdome.
Scott: So far back there, I can't even see it.
Rym: Actually, I think Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome might have been the third one.
Rym: I don't know why.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I am DB.
Scott: I call to you.
Rym: All IMDB.
Rym: What's your news?
Scott: I got almost I got the Wikipedia coming through here.
Rym: Fine.
Rym: I'll tell you about my news.
Rym: So this is not a technology thing because it happened more or less in the real world, but it used technology.
Rym: But in, you know, computer science and information security, there's the idea of the man in the middle attack, which is that theoretically you have a secure line of communication.
Rym: But one way to violate that line of communication is to place yourself in the middle, an intermediary between the two people.
Rym: So instead of person A talking to person B, person A talks to me and person B talks to me and I read their messages and respond to both of them accordingly, thus getting everything I want out of that conversation.
Scott: They think they're talking to each other, but really, you are checking everything out they're doing.
Scott: And you can even give false replies to.
Rym: this was a huge security problem with SSH one.
Rym: That's why we use SSH two now.
Rym: But even I mean, man in the middle is ancient and there's a lot of it exists in a lot of forms.
Rym: But I thought this was clever.
Rym: Some dude, some Russian immigrants hacked the Department of Transportation website called Safer Sis dot org, which apparently has this list of like trucking companies and brokers.
Rym: And basically it's a place where you can go and arrange shipping between places for like companies.
Rym: What they would do is they would basically use this to intercept requests for shipping, take those requests, get payment, and then subcontract those requests to the original.
Rym: the people that the original people thought were the people that were contracted to do it.
Rym: And then they would keep the money and or keep the goods.
Rym: And that was the end of it.
Rym: And it was good.
Scott: They got the goods.
Rym: I think they shipped the goods most of the time.
Scott: I didn't read the subcontracting the good shipments.
Scott: How could they hook if they kept the goods?
Rym: Well, you could subcontract the good shipments, but then just show up before the subcontractor arrives and take the goods.
Rym: So I show up in the AGMI Trucking Co company truck.
Rym: I take the goods.
Rym: I leave.
Rym: The real AGMI Co truck shows up, looks for the goods, and the dude says, you already came.
Rym: I don't think they did that.
Rym: I think they just took the money and then left everyone confused.
Rym: It's kind of like the.
Scott: they're making a small profit.
Rym: They made about five hundred thousand dollars before.
Scott: You're making a small profit per thing because how much is someone going to pay?
Scott: Because you're paying the subcontracting truck company.
Scott: So you got to know they're only making the difference.
Rym: That's the brilliance.
Rym: They didn't actually pay the subcontracting truck company.
Rym: What you realize the way the business world works, if you buy something, you don't just pay, you submit a purchase order or something along those lines and then they submit an invoice.
Rym: And usually they have terms like net 30, which means the balance in full will be paid within 30 days.
Rym: You know, that sort of business.
Rym: So basically they take money from Person A, subcontract out to Person B, keep the money.
Rym: Person B delivers the goods and then never gets paid, tries to sue Person A for not paying.
Rym: Person A says, I did pay.
Rym: Here's the proof.
Rym: That money went to some third party who's already gone.
Rym: It's kind of like so that so.
Scott: but so the situation is such that the the subcontracted real trucking company doesn't send their invoice to the Russians if they were sending it to the Person A.
Rym: Yes, they manned in the middle or man in the middle.
Scott: I don't know how that seems like paperwork is messed up somewhere, but all right.
Rym: Now it's probably remember.
Rym: they had the middleman, they controlled the middleman, the trusted middleman.
Rym: It's kind of like the the famous Chinese restaurant, Frank, only with money.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I find this interesting and I don't really have anything more insightful to say about it other than scammers in the modern world are often very, very clever.
Rym: And the real failing is that the website that people trusted was untrustworthy and everyone trusted it stupidly.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much where all you know, that's it's why it's called a con man, a confidence man.
Scott: They give you confidence in something, you know, trust in something that is untrustworthy and then you are fooled.
Scott: Yeah, that is the foundation of all trickery.
Rym: It's weird, though, because I feel like I don't know if they could have gotten me because I I don't trust any website, really.
Rym: Like I don't even really trust Google.
Scott: I trust Amazon.com kind of.
Scott: Well, I trust them to send me a book and I give money.
Rym: I only really trust Amazon because Visa and MasterCard have my back.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: If if Visa and MasterCard didn't have me, I probably would.
Scott: Then you're trusting Visa and MasterCard.
Rym: Yes, but I trust them because if they became untrustworthy, it's Mad Max.
Scott: OK, so Mad Max, Mad Max, followed by two sequels, Mad Max two, a.k.a.
Scott: The Road Warrior.
Scott: And Thunderdome came out in eighty five and as of April 08, a third sequel, Mad Max for Fury Road remains in pre-production in quotes.
Rym: Oh, my.
Rym: According to Wikipedia, though, I haven't seen Mad Max be on Thunderdome since I was a kid.
Rym: I don't know if that movie will live up to my childhood, you know, it's.
Scott: you know, it's beyond Thunderdome.
Rym: Pleather and gasoline, Fury Road.
Rym: OK.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So here I got.
Scott: I got a little news, I guess a combo of two news and then some other news, right?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So here we go.
Scott: First story, these two related stories.
Scott: The real quick virtual quote, murderer jailed.
Rym: Wait, is this the Dutch thing?
Scott: No.
Rym: OK, because there was a similar story from the Dutch.
Scott: It's a Tokyo woman, right, was jailed for murdering her ex-husband.
Scott: Well, kind of.
Scott: She logged into his MapleStory account and killed his avatar.
Scott: She's not been formally charged.
Scott: If convicted, she could face up to five years in prison or find it to five thousand dollars because they're thinking of charging her with inappropriate computer access.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I was that makes sense.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But it's weird.
Scott: It's like, you know, she she killed a virtual character.
Scott: She basically twiddled some bits in the database.
Rym: You know, it's funny that every time there's a story like this, whatever book we read most recently has a lot to say about it.
Rym: All I want to say, Scott, is the sibrid.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So here we go.
Scott: Here's the Dutch thing.
Rym: Oh, so you are talking about the Dutch thing.
Scott: Teens convicted of virtual theft.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Two Dutch teenagers were convicted of virtually roughing up a classmate in RuneScape and stealing virtual goods.
Scott: The quote, virtual goods are goods under Dutch law.
Scott: So this is theft.
Scott: The court said on Tuesday.
Scott: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Rym: Was this like they killed him in a PVP server and took his stuff?
Scott: No, that's what I thought it was, because that's because if that's what it was, I would say that's way wrong.
Scott: But actually what happened was they were like at his house or some shit or in school or I don't know.
Scott: And they they literally roughed him up and coerced him, you know, to give them his like fancy helmet and fancy sword or some shit is sort of spare and magic helmet.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So basically instead, basically it's no different than beating up for lunch money.
Scott: It's just they beat him up for, you know, hey, click on that and give me that fancy item.
Scott: No, I'll do it.
Scott: Oh, here you go.
Rym: The real the real question here is, did the I mean, the Mabel story, they could just restore it.
Rym: I mean, shouldn't the first thing I mean, but shouldn't my idea of a justice system as that the first?
Rym: the first thing a justice system should always do is undo harm if possible.
Rym: So I feel like the first thing before we even think about punishing anyone is just give the person their stuff back.
Rym: There's an audit trail in both of these cases.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There is the other question, though, right?
Scott: Do you really want this seems to be sort of this this way of the world in which when you have a game and a game has rules, be it video game or sport or whatever, right, that like you don't really want the world government like coming in and modifying the rules of games, which are sort of like, you know, atomic in their nature.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, like it's OK if say something happens in a hockey game.
Scott: And there's a disputed goal.
Scott: And the NHL comes down the next day and says, all right, we've decided that that's a goal.
Scott: This team wins.
Scott: Even if it's after the game is over and they override the ref, it seems OK, like you can accept the NHL ruling itself.
Scott: if the U.S.
Scott: government comes in and some judge says, no, we decided it's not a goal, something something that's sort of at least a really bad taste in the mouth.
Rym: But at the same time, forget the game aspect.
Rym: This wasn't an.
Rym: this was one of those situations of, you know, someone in the MMO scam, someone else in the MMO in the context of the game.
Rym: This was a case of in the physical world, someone was extorted.
Rym: It's no different than I mean, by that, I would say that what if I was playing the ATM game and someone forced me to take out a bunch of money from the ATM game and give it to them?
Rym: Right.
Scott: But if you look at like like, you know, Pete Rosebud and all those baseball games and there was some crooked refs in the NBA and stuff, but they don't you know that it was how it was, you know, you don't go back and retcon that shit, you know, you let it be and you just fix it for the future.
Rym: You know, and if so, I think so, we shouldn't give the money back from the ATM game, the ATM games, different game.
Rym: Why?
Scott: Because banks, you know, because the much, much in the way you're reaching, I got it.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: I got you.
Scott: You got it much in the way that the commissioner of the NFL right is, you know, sort of the boss of all the rules of the NFL.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When it comes to banks, the House of Representatives is the boss, you know, and the Senate Banking Committee is the boss.
Scott: So so what if I have their decision in the in the rules of banking and money?
Scott: the same way you would accept the decision of the commissioner?
Rym: Fine.
Rym: I'm playing the grocery store game and someone takes all my groceries.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: From the parking lot.
Rym: Now, now who's?
Rym: who has the authority?
Scott: Well, you're on U.S.
Scott: government land.
Scott: No, I'm not physical goods and commerce.
Rym: I'm not on government land.
Rym: It's owned by.
Rym: it's owned by the supermarket.
Scott: The government is the boss of commerce.
Rym: But by that logic, the government is also the boss of any game that is in the United States.
Scott: Technically, yes.
Scott: Therefore, you realize it is a bad taste if they're infiltrating into the game and not just in the commerce level.
Scott: Like if World of Warcraft took my money, even though I canceled my account, then that's commerce that they can.
Scott: they can come in and do something about.
Scott: But if, you know, someone takes my purse, I don't know if the government should really be stepping in.
Rym: Well, I don't know.
Rym: I feel like if some of the problem here is whether or not those things have intrinsic value, I would argue, no, because the company in question can recreate them immediately and without any sort of consequences whatsoever.
Scott: Yeah, it's just.
Scott: it's a state of.
Scott: you're basically saying you're the state of a system rather than, you know, the possession of actual goods.
Scott: And it's not possession.
Scott: It's I don't know.
Rym: Well, see, that's the real interesting thing.
Rym: How do we define possession of digital goods like that?
Rym: What do what do I own that's different?
Scott: Well, I mean, theoretically, right, it's like there's all this translation on different levels of the universe between state and position.
Scott: I mean, everything possession I mean, everything is state.
Scott: It's what are the configurations of all the subatomic particles in the entire universe?
Scott: And that is everything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But then you look and it's like I possess this land.
Scott: Well, no, actually, it's just the configuration of the universe.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Rym: That has your name on it.
Scott: That happens to also say deed on it.
Rym: Wait a minute, Captain.
Rym: Absolute.
Rym: I think we need to zoom in a little bit from your overarching, pedantic and positive.
Rym: You've you've committed not the fallacy, but the I don't even have a word for this,
Scott: where
Rym: you take an argument and either draw it out to such a universal concept to where it is universally applicable and thus no longer an argument or zoom in so narrowly that you have proven something absolutely which can have no effect on anything.
Scott: I did both, in fact, by going to the subatomic particles and also the entire universe at the same time.
Rym: I feel like the difference here, though, in all honesty, in this situation versus, say, someone in the game tricking me into giving perps, I don't even know if you can give people perps.
Rym: I know there's like bonding and stuff.
Scott: And I'm sure you can give someone an item, right?
Rym: No, there's this.
Rym: you can if you pick up certain items, they're bound to you and no one else can use it really to prevent what the fuck to prevent all the sorts of things that happened in every MMO that came before.
Scott: Oh, God, even I got it, man, we should actually play.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: So we can find all the stupid shit like that and realize it's worse than we think it is.
Rym: You want to play.
Scott: while I'm looking at, you know, this we have like one hundred demo days.
Rym: Some, you know, I got one right here.
Scott: We said we were going to do it for like one day last winter.
Rym: Well, you know, I got on a vacation time.
Rym: I'll be off for like a week or two around New Year's.
Rym: Yeah, well, we'll say we want to play two solid weeks of wild.
Rym: No, I'll take two weeks off.
Scott: I'm talking like maybe two hours, two weeks.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: But anyway, I feel like the.
Rym: I don't know where exactly the line is, but there is a difference between being scammed in the context of the game and being physically coerced in the real world to giving up a password to an account from which items are then liquidated.
Scott: Normally a story with the headline, you know, teens convicted of virtual theft or virtual murder or jailed are the kind of headlines I would go, boo, what the fuck, what the fuck?
Scott: But I agree with what happened in both these situations.
Scott: I think it was, you know, it was right.
Scott: We did what was supposed to happen.
Rym: Of course, it it really depends because who owned that MapleStory account?
Rym: and if he gave her the password and they and she had ever played it, then I think she has just as much a right to delete the characters he does.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, plus, right.
Scott: Maybe, you know, he was letting her play or whatever she meant.
Scott: But, you know, plus, you know, does the intent.
Scott: intent matters in, you know, crimes and such?
Scott: What if she was intending to just play MapleStory, but she just sucked?
Scott: You know, how does how does that go?
Rym: Well, I think she deleted it.
Rym: I don't know how if you can die.
Rym: I don't know how MapleStory works.
Rym: Wasn't that the game?
Rym: that looked really good, but there was actually no gameplay.
Scott: It's like a side scrolling.
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: I forget.
Rym: Yeah, I remember playing it and then we got hooked on that other game Gunbound.
Scott: Well, Gunbound was the cannon fodder, but you pay money to win.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: That introduced one word to my vocabulary.
Rym: The only thing I remember from that game is bungeeing.
Scott: Oh, God, I forgot about that.
Scott: I had something else to talk about, but I'm going to save it.
Rym: Anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So Wyatt was a classy dude, was out for the weekend and we went hiking and stuff, but he showed us something and I'm going to inflict this upon all of you.
Rym: Someone made these people make, among other things, alternate openers to television shows.
Rym: And I want to link to two of them.
Rym: Now, the first one is frightening, horrifying and really not safe for word.
Rym: But it is kind of an alternate opener to DuckTales.
Rym: And it's a little disturbing.
Scott: I feel like I've seen it before somewhere, but I don't remember.
Rym: Where were you here when we show it, when we know, but I think is it that new?
Scott: Because I feel like I saw it a long time ago.
Rym: I have no idea now, but in case you don't want to watch that one, I have to link to a second one.
Rym: And this one's just weird and it's funny.
Rym: And it kind of reminds me of the Hasselhoff recursion for a number of reasons.
Scott: Well, it does involve the Hoff.
Rym: It does, but it involves a recursion of the Hoff as well.
Rym: But it is not the Hasselhoff recursion.
Rym: It is perhaps a Hasselhoff recursion, but Hasselhoff is played by another guy.
Rym: Well, there is only one.
Rym: This is definitely a bastardization.
Rym: It is not the true recursion in all of its glory.
Rym: But if the first one is disturbing and funny in a really dark humor, sick way, the second one is just really weird.
Rym: When the little mini Knight Riders come out and start shooting missiles at the big Knight Rider, that is itself in a pow pow power wheel, riding around in a cube that has images of the opener to Knight Rider on all faces.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Scott: Is that it?
Rym: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: What do you have?
Rym: Something more exciting.
Rym: Captain Scott on this lazy Thursday.
Scott: It's exciting if you like boobies.
Rym: The bird?
Rym: No.
Scott: OK.
Scott: The things on women.
Rym: I can tell it's going to be a classy night.
Scott: Oh, it's classy.
Scott: So Halloween's coming up pretty soon.
Scott: Halloween is all about costumes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: No.
Scott: Yes, it is.
Scott: Well, costumes and pumpkins.
Rym: Halloween is primarily about parties and dressing up for candy.
Rym: Yes, mostly parties.
Scott: So to celebrate the costumes of Halloween, right.
Scott: You know, some people, they like the scary costumes.
Scott: Some people like the funny costumes and some people like the sexy costumes.
Rym: Sexiness, sexy.
Scott: No, not all the costumes are sexy.
Scott: And anyway, sexy, sexy and frog.
Scott: OK, here are someone put together this gallery of the 50 best cosplay cleavage pics.
Scott: All right.
Rym: And should this not be saved for a Wednesday?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Some of them are video games.
Scott: Some of them are anime.
Scott: Some of them are just sort of who knows what they are.
Scott: They're just cosplay of some sort.
Rym: I still feel like it fits mostly in a Woden's Day.
Scott: Perhaps, but no matter what, normally I wouldn't link to something like this, you know, because normally it's just sort of a perverted kind of, yeah, whatever.
Scott: Fan service, cheesecake, sexist kind of thing.
Rym: You realize Steve Bennett has probably checked off one more mark on the.
Rym: I will corrupt those two boys.
Scott: But some of these are way hot.
Scott: Like, I don't know what no matter what gender you are, some of these are like unbelievably hot, like, oh, man, like, who the hell is that hot?
Scott: Like, oh, man, like you don't see things this hot on the Internet every day.
Scott: I mean, the Internet's got a lot of porn.
Scott: You know, it's got more porn than anything in the history of, you know, the universe.
Rym: But most of that porn, the statistic that more porn, more pornographic video is made in every 20, that's just any, you know, real porn industry.
Scott: More porn is made, you know, not counting like photography, porn, internet porn and, you know, all the other porns, but hentais and everything.
Scott: But, you know, there's a lot of porn on the Internet.
Scott: A lot of it is, you know, not so great.
Scott: In fact, 99 percent of it is not so great coming from you, the expert in connoisseur.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: I'm such an expert.
Scott: No, it's Sturgeon's Law.
Scott: Every 90 percent of everything is crap.
Rym: You know, one needs to tell you that, you know, you know, the phrase 90 percent of everything is crap takes on a whole new meaning when talking about pornography.
Scott: I hope 90 percent of the porn isn't crap that way, even though more than zero percent of it is, which is more than enough.
Rym: You still haven't seen that video.
Scott: Because I'm smart, just like I haven't seen all that bad porn.
Scott: But regardless, this isn't actually porn.
Scott: It's, you know, just cosplay photos.
Scott: Just, you know, they just happen to be, you know, provocative, even if there is no provocative is the word.
Scott: There's no nudity.
Scott: There's no there's nothing that would be, you know, rated X here.
Scott: So no, no, it's not only it's actually any nipples, even though it's a lot of cleavage.
Rym: Cosplayers seem to be pretty good at that.
Rym: I mean, I remember very clearly a long time ago at an anime convention, there was a girl dressed up as Ray.
Rym: What when Ray was wearing nothing but a towel and this girl was wearing nothing but a towel and foot pads because she wasn't allowed to walk around barefoot.
Rym: So she had these flesh colored pads on the bottom of her feet that technically counted as shoes and a towel.
Rym: And a wig.
Rym: And that was it.
Rym: And yet she somehow managed, as far as I could see, to avoid showing a nipple or anything less savory for the entire convention.
Rym: Yeah, now, what kind of reaction is that?
Scott: I was listening to what you were saying.
Scott: I was looking at some Internet, some Internet.
Rym: You were looking at your own website.
Scott: Actually, I closed that already.
Rym: So what were you looking at?
Scott: You know, just some random shit, whatever.
Scott: Let's get on with it.
Rym: So we're back to the crap thing, I see.
Rym: Yes, OK, we didn't have much to do.
Scott: And, you know, you can tell this is this is not going to be crab people night.
Rym: It was a crab people night indeed.
Rym: And we had a crab people from earlier in the week and all week it was, yeah, if we don't come up with a better show by Thursday, let's talk about this.
Rym: The thing we were about to talk about.
Rym: I like how we always act like we're not going to reveal until the last second.
Scott: Yeah, you're the one who acts like we're not going to reveal.
Scott: I'm just sitting here going.
Scott: whatever you always go along is real hungry.
Scott: I kind of just want to eat.
Rym: We could just stop now and do a special.
Scott: No, no, let's let's do something.
Scott: At least people, people, they spend their hard earned Internet bandwidths to download this.
Scott: And they're they're expecting something to listen to to entertain them on the way to work.
Scott: If we stop now, what do they do for the second half of their commute?
Scott: So what do they do while they're bored at work all day playing flash games?
Scott: They played every flash game.
Scott: Now, what are they going to do?
Scott: We need we can save them for the next 15 to 20 minutes.
Scott: And give them something to occupy their brains until they can finally escape and go home and do something worthwhile.
Rym: So when we were in college for one, not even a whole year, but for three quarters of our time of our freshman year of our
Rym: I.T.,
Rym: when I say quarters, I don't mean, you know, 25 percent.
Rym: I mean, quarters as in 10 weeks plus a week of finals.
Scott: So for 30 weeks, well, 33 weeks.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Thirty three weeks.
Rym: Plus all the vacations where we weren't forced to go home, which were all of them, except the Xmas one.
Rym: Right.
Rym: We lived in dorms.
Scott: Well, the RIT dorms.
Rym: Yeah, well, we lived in dorms is a correct statement.
Scott: Yeah, I guess.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Except for the few friends we had who because of RIT's money grubbing and the fact that they always have more students than dorms because half those people will fail out before the end of their freshman year and then there'll be plenty of dorms.
Rym: We had some friends who were actually staying in the hotel down the street on RIT's dime.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know, the thing that I think the reason dorm life require warrants discussion is because, you know, some people, you know, they love that dorm life.
Scott: They live in dorms like their whole college time.
Scott: They'll even live in dorms when they're out of college.
Scott: You know, maybe in the military, you know, dormitory style living or or who knows what, you know, hostels and things.
Scott: But some people dorms just don't work.
Scott: They just you know, they they fight with every roommate.
Scott: They can't deal with it.
Scott: They always get new roommates switching dorms, having troubles, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: And, you know, there's there's a lot of things that people need to know about dorm life.
Scott: If you're on your way to college, maybe you're in college, maybe you've never lived away from home before, like a lot of people scarily have.
Scott: Really, if you're going to college, you before you go to college, you should at some point live away from home for some amount of time.
Scott: You know, spend a month in a foreign country or go to summer camp at least to summer camp, not day camp or or something.
Scott: You don't want to go to college and go to the dorms.
Scott: That would be the first time you're away from mommy and daddy.
Scott: That's that's not going to be good for you.
Rym: But one thing I do want to say, this is not going to be one of those how to not suck shows.
Rym: We're not going to preach at you about how to live in dorms and how to deal with it and what to do and all the stuff we usually do in these kinds of shows.
Rym: I pretty much just want to talk about the RIT dorms because I got to say and I could say this, too, about when we lived on campus, not in the dorms, but in the on campus apartments, you know, the the original geekhouse, the basement of colony.
Rym: God, we could do a whole show about that place.
Rym: But what I miss about the dorms and I get this a little bit in New York City, but not nearly as much as I got back at RIT, was the fact that not a day would go by where something weird didn't happen.
Rym: Something weird always happened.
Rym: There's always the weird dude, the explosion, the fire, the naked guy screaming and running down the street.
Rym: The frisbeeing and frisbeeing does not involve throwing a frisbee.
Rym: I'll get to that later.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you know, when you live in a house with just a few people, right?
Scott: Think about it.
Scott: The average person has something weird happen in their life once every few weeks, once every month, you know, something like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if you get enough people together, something interesting will happen to someone every day.
Scott: And if you're living with these people, then that interesting thing happens to everyone.
Scott: And also, in addition to that, because you're living with these other people and, you know, and you interact in these ways, people will do things with other people and they'll make interesting things happen.
Scott: And, you know, because it's a lot easier to make a lot of different things happen when there's other people to make them happen, too.
Scott: If you don't have anyone else to pull a prank on, there's no prank to pull.
Rym: But at the same time, college dorms far and away from everything else have this extra bonus going for them in terms of this sort of stuff happening.
Rym: One, generally, I mean, it depends on the college, but, you know, RIT in particular, it was pretty much just nerds and geeks.
Rym: I mean, even the drunken frat boys were drunken frat boys playing FPS and counterstrut.
Scott: Or drunken frat boys writing software programs.
Rym: Or drunken frat boys constructing their own hot tubs and then lying in them in the winter.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, even, you know, because think about it at RIT, right?
Scott: Think about this, right?
Scott: At most schools, right?
Scott: It's like, OK, all the whatever majors, you know, all the normal majors, I don't even know what they are, are the normal people, the frat boys and whatnot.
Scott: And then the engineers are the nerds.
Scott: At RIT, everyone's a nerd and the engineers are the least nerdy, the jock frat types.
Rym: Yeah, it was kind of engineering.
Scott: Or maybe the School of Science also has some non nerds.
Scott: But all the other schools, right, is the what?
Scott: The computer science school and the art school.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But I guess the business school, but everyone, even the business school people, though, a lot of them were really geeky.
Rym: I mean, everyone played Counter-Strike.
Rym: Everyone did all that stuff.
Rym: Everyone did those geeky, nerdy things.
Rym: And also because RIT is kind of expensive and private and all these things, it was also at the point where, by and large, everyone there had a lot of similar interests, a lot of commonalities.
Rym: And also we were isolated.
Rym: Remember, RIT, everyone says, yeah, it's in Rochester.
Rym: Now, it's not in Rochester.
Rym: It's in Henrietta, which is next to Rochester.
Scott: Henrietta, at least from the perspective of an RIT student, basically Henrietta might as well just be called RIT town, even though people live in it.
Rym: You arrive at basically RIT is like this compound that is completely isolated from the entirety of the rest of the area.
Rym: And not many of the freshmen have cars and not many people in general in the community did not fit into anything we're going to talk about.
Rym: And you're isolated and you have nowhere to go and nothing to do.
Scott: And where can you go?
Scott: There's one road in Henrietta.
Scott: It basically has a bunch of strip malls and then one actual mall.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And you couldn't even walk there.
Rym: If you wanted to walk there, it took forever.
Rym: And also I point out it's basically the ice planet Hoth.
Rym: So you can't walk there.
Scott: Yeah, there's very limited time.
Scott: And add in one more thing to this equation.
Scott: You know, the sort of the eye of Newt, if you will.
Scott: Everyone's a college student.
Scott: They've got loads of free time to kill.
Scott: They're not people working nine to five.
Scott: These are people who are in those dorms a lot of the time.
Rym: And the way RIT tends to work is that your freshman year, with a few exceptions, there is very little difficult going on.
Rym: At least for the majority, we can.
Rym: basically the people who are going to fail out are going to fail out already.
Rym: Like the fact that you were going to fail out of RIT almost feels like it was predetermined from before you even decided to go there.
Scott: Yeah, much like in high school.
Scott: When I was in high school, my freshman year, I had like these like amazing grades and then I started to let it slide the rest of high school.
Rym: Freshman year at RIT, 4.0.
Scott: Yeah, freshman year at RIT, I was like way, I was doing, kicking out all sorts of ads.
Rym: Sophomore year, 3.8.
Rym: Then it went,
Rym: "Ding!"
Rym: I'll go by year by year.
Rym: 4.0, 3.8, 3.7, 3.41.
Scott: I don't even remember what it was, but it was pretty much right away.
Scott: It was like all A's.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: Think about that.
Rym: To drop so quickly, my senior year, with all the momentum of grades I had before that, yeah, I didn't really go to class.
Rym: I didn't really do, I skipped a final.
Scott: Strangely enough though, I made the Dean's list once at RIT ever.
Scott: And it was my final, like year, final quarter.
Scott: I don't know what that was about, but we're not talking about RIT.
Rym: We're talking about living in the dorms.
Rym: Now, one thing about living in the dorms was that for the majority of students, no one had any schoolwork to do because either you are one of the people who will not fail out of RIT, which means everything you do your freshman year is painfully easy, or you're one of the people who are going to fail out of RIT.
Rym: In which case.
Scott: You're not doing your work.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Now there were some people, you know, the bookworms, the people who have the nose to the book all the time, even though there's, I don't know what the hell they were working on.
Scott: Like it was the weirdest thing.
Scott: I would, I would be in a class.
Scott: Someone else would be in the same class, right?
Scott: I would've, I would've, you know, felt that I had no work to do for that class yet.
Scott: I would see someone else in that class with the book for that class, like in the library, spending a lot of time in there doing something, but at class, there are people in the dorms who'd be on those quiet floors and those people would just do work and they wouldn't do anything else.
Rym: We're not talking about the quiet floors because I got to say, I know very little about them.
Rym: I went to one a couple of times when I was working on a project with someone my freshman year, they were scary.
Rym: Like everyone in there was really, really scared except for like the three or four people who were stuck.
Rym: Like they didn't want to be on that floor, but either their parents forced him to be on that floor or they ended up there because no one wanted to be on that floor.
Rym: And basically those people never spend any time on that floor, but we could really only talk about our own doors because every dorm had its own character.
Scott: I know that's what it's all about.
Scott: I was just about to say the thing about floors, right?
Scott: Each dorm, each floor, each section, right?
Scott: When however the dorms are architecturally structured, you know, each unit has its own character and its own community and its own attitude.
Rym: Well, it had its own name, its own RA, and then as a group, they had their own RD.
Rym: And we really only have experience with four of the dorm, I don't know, social units of RIT.
Scott: So I have some interactions with some other units, but yes, I know I'm most familiar with it.
Rym: I know them in the way that a visitor to a foreign land for a few weeks of a year knows the foreign land.
Rym: I mean, here's what I know.
Rym: I mean, there are people who probably are nothing like the people, all the things we're going to talk about on all those other weird floors.
Rym: But let me tell you, all I know about the study, the studying floors was that I never saw any of those people outside of those floors or outside of class, maybe in the library, but I only went in the library when I needed to sleep.
Scott: I went to the library, but not as much as some people.
Rym: Actually, you know, I can say I did a lot more work in the library for my elective classes than I ever did for anything else.
Scott: I did a lot more things in the library just for fun, looking around, because it's a big library.
Scott: They got a lot of books.
Scott: There's a lot of weird stuff in there.
Rym: But I didn't get to pick my dorm and I didn't really like.
Rym: I put in some preferences, but I tried to get into computer science house.
Rym: Not going to talk about that.
Scott: No, I'm glad I didn't get in.
Scott: Me too.
Rym: But I ended up in in one of the more infamous of the places to live at RIT.
Rym: I lived in Fish B.
Scott: Well, Fish B, too, right?
Rym: Fish B, too.
Rym: Well, fish in and of itself was special because there was Fish A, which was completely separate from Fish B and C. And Fish A had the girls, but there's girls only.
Rym: In fact, Fish B was special in that I believe it housed the majority of the alcoholics at RIT at the time.
Scott: Fish, because it was all boys, wasn't it?
Rym: Fish B, I believe was all.
Rym: fish B, too, however, was unique among RIT floors because most of RIT's dorms were unisex.
Scott: You know, you mean you didn't have girls and guys in the same room, you know, unless they signed up for it specifically or because everyone just swapped rooms and like hid it from the R.A.
Rym: like.
Scott: Well, yeah, but you didn't have that.
Scott: RIT would never assign a strange guy and a strange girl to the same dorm.
Scott: You either did it on purpose or you signed up for it or something, but you would have a guy's room next to a girl's room.
Scott: You know, there wouldn't be any bathroom sharing going on.
Scott: But that's how most floors were, is that to be, you know, guys and girls on the same floor.
Scott: But Rym's dorm, Fish B, too, was guys, guys, guys in every room.
Rym: Now, the other.
Rym: there's a couple other things to note about Fish B, too.
Rym: Now, I'm not going to mention names, but we had our R.A.
Rym: I will call him Eric and leave it at that.
Rym: I will not give his full name.
Rym: The man was unique.
Rym: Eric Big Shemmy's he.
Rym: he I'll put it this way.
Rym: He didn't get in my way and I didn't get in his way because I basically I was disconnected.
Rym: The floor was around me, but I was not of the floor.
Rym: The floor attempted to bring me into it.
Rym: I had nothing to do with this floor.
Scott: I just think your roommate didn't have anything to do with your floor either.
Rym: But there's something cool.
Rym: There's almost this honor among thieves where crazy things happened on the floor.
Rym: And a lot of the things to the outside observer would appear malicious, cruel, destructive, dangerous, horrifying.
Rym: However, it was all.
Rym: I guess there's a quote from The Simpsons to us all in good fun because they only all did it to each other and they all took it with grace.
Rym: And no one dished out anything that he did not expect to receive threefold in return.
Rym: But no one ever did anything to me because I never did anything to anyone.
Rym: I simply lived within these people, observe their culture like an anthropologist and one time woke up, Dr.
Scott: Remington, I presume to eight.
Rym: I opened my dorm room door on a Sunday morning to go out and get the Sunday brunch as I off did.
Rym: Me and Greg would often go down and eat fried eggs until we were too full to eat more fried eggs.
Rym: Wait any more hungry that you are.
Rym: And I opened my dorm room door and a drunk person kind of collapses into the room.
Rym: He's been, he's sleep.
Rym: He was sleeping against my door and your door opened inwards.
Rym: My door opened inward and he collapsed into my room, still asleep.
Rym: He had written on the whiteboard on my door.
Rym: Let me in.
Scott: Is this your roommate?
Rym: No, it was the dude who lived in the room next to me.
Rym: I don't know if he was confused or bored.
Rym: I don't know if he thought let me in was somehow going to convince me to let him in.
Rym: I kind of pushed him into the hallway and locked the door behind me and I wrote no on the whiteboard.
Scott: That's a good one.
Rym: But Fishby too was connected to a building that had an elevator, but itself did not have an elevator.
Rym: So it was connected only on the third floor.
Rym: So basically there was no way in the world for a wheelchair to get to the second floor.
Rym: Yet we had a wheelchair accessible bathroom.
Scott: There was a way, just a very difficult way of lifting the wheelchair.
Rym: Now after about a week, we had a, you see there were floor meetings as I'm sure all college kids are familiar with.
Rym: But I skipped all of them when I realized right away that there were no possible repercussions.
Rym: What, they weren't going to kick me out of the dorm.
Rym: So once I realized that, I didn't go to the dorm meetings and Eric would always come and say, "Hey, you didn't go to the dorm meeting.
Rym: You know, they're
Rym: mandatory.".
Rym: And I said, "Yeah, I know.
Rym: I'll go to the next one.
Rym: I'm
Rym: sorry.".
Rym: But I didn't go to the next one and he'd say the same thing and I'd say the same thing.
Rym: And I got through the entirety of RIT's freshman year never going to these stupid floor meetings.
Rym: I heard tell of them.
Rym: There was one where we were, apparently the floor was admonished for the fact that both bathrooms had been completely filled with vomit, apparently at one point.
Rym: As in every sink was clogged with vomit and no one would fess up.
Scott: The drunkenest floor in the college.
Rym: No one would fess up and apparently the cleaning lady quit because of it.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: And they didn't know what to do and they...
Scott: Hire a new cleaning lady.
Rym: Apparently the argument from the floor was, "Well, you can either kick us all out or you can deny us the use of the bathrooms.
Rym: I don't think either will end
Rym: well.".
Scott: Yeah, we could have vomited elsewhere.
Rym: I had nothing to do with these people.
Rym: But the floor had kind of... See, I went to the secret meetings where the whole floor would get together and kind of have this rule of manly law.
Rym: And everyone got together and decided that, "Here shall be the rules of the
Rym: bathrooms.".
Rym: Because the other interesting point of Fish B2 was that there was a woman's bathroom, but there were no women.
Scott: And there was a handicapped bathroom, but no handicapped people.
Rym: So we had to decide what to do.
Rym: And one proposal was, "Leave the women's bathroom for women under the auspices that women would come to our
Rym: floor.".
Rym: Oh.
Rym: The argument put forth in counter to that was that, "Ha!
Rym: Fat
Rym: chance!".
Rym: And thus the agreement was such, "The handicapped bathroom shall be for women who visit, and people who are in need of privacy for matters that will be understood to be agreed upon by
Rym: all.".
Rym: Basically masturbation.
Scott: Or women who visit.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Or someone who needs a private place, perhaps with a woman.
Rym: So that bathroom, let me tell you, was meticulously clean and there was a chair in there.
Rym: It was rather large, actually.
Rym: Actually, it was a full quarter the size of a dorm room, but I don't want to get into that.
Rym: One guy moved into it for a little while.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Weren't you taking your showers in there?
Rym: I took my showers in there for the longest time.
Rym: But, henceforth, the bathroom signs were replaced with the... We made signs.
Rym: One said, "Pisser
Rym: Shitter.".
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: It said, "Pisser
Rym: Shower-er.".
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: And the second one said, "Pooper Vomiter," or "Shitter
Rym: Vomiter."
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: The men's bathroom was the "Pisser
Scott: Shower-er.".
Scott: So if you had to urinate or shower, you would go in there.
Scott: But there was a rule.
Scott: If you had to shit or vomit, you would go in the women's bathroom.
Rym: If you chose to poop in that bathroom, you were allowed to.
Rym: But if there was any trace, any evidence that you had pooped in there, you have committed a crime against the floor, we didn't ever decide what the punishment would be, but...
Scott: Well, obviously retaliation threefold in kind.
Rym: A retaliatory pooping?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Threefold pooping.
Rym: Despite all the antics, no one ever pooped in a way that was noticeable in that bathroom.
Scott: Yeah, because it was the "Pisser
Scott: Shower-er."
Scott: And everyone showered in that one.
Scott: Even an animal knows not to, you know, shit in its shower.
Rym: And then the other one, basically one bathroom was for nasty stuff and one was for slightly less nasty stuff.
Rym: And of course, if all the showers were full, well, people would shower in the other one.
Rym: It was basically, if you can, use the nice bathroom for nice things.
Rym: If you can't, use the un-nice bathroom for nice things.
Rym: But woe betide he who does un-nice things in the nice bathroom.
Rym: And it worked real well, because I gotta tell ya, all the stories I heard from everyone else in the dorms was that they could never take a shower because they were always full.
Rym: Because, of course, everyone's first class was at 10 AM.
Scott: Yeah, see, I actually lived on "Peterson 3," which does not fish B2.
Rym: I spent most of my time on "Peterson
Rym: 3.".
Rym: In fact, I slept in their lounge more than once.
Scott: It was an un-renovated dorm, one of the last un-renovated dorms there, which meant the rooms were bigger.
Scott: There was no communal bathroom that had many, many shower stalls.
Scott: We had one bathroom for two dorm rooms.
Scott: We had one shower in there.
Scott: I think there might actually have been two showers in there.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: There was basically a shower, a toilet, and two sinks in there.
Scott: It was pretty good.
Scott: It was almost a private bathroom.
Scott: Almost.
Scott: It was a beautiful thing to live in "Peterson
Scott: 3.".
Scott: "Peterson 3" was the "no drugs" floor.
Scott: The complete opposite of fish B2, where there was vomiting and whatnot.
Rym: It was called the "substance-free" floor.
Rym: It wasn't just like, "Yeah, we won't drink on the
Rym: floor.".
Rym: It was like, "All right, we know everyone's doing drugs and smoking pot, but don't do it in this
Scott: And not only that, but if you are drunk, and you return to the floor, that is a very bad idea, and you can actually get in serious shit.
Scott: So basically...
Rym: Well, RIT's serious shit was, "Well, you have to live somewhere else
Rym: now.".
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So it was awesome, because I lived on this floor of all these people who didn't want to be drunk, didn't want to get stupid, and actually just wanted to be cool and have a good time.
Scott: Now, the other thing is RIT is also home to the NTID, National Technical Institute for the Deaf, but half the people on the floor were deaf and half were not.
Scott: So it was actually pretty cool, you know, half the people were just like, you know, they were deaf, and they were all like, "What's
Scott: up?".
Scott: Because they were the cool deaf people, not the drunken deaf people.
Rym: Now, the thing is, the substance-free thing, whatever, I didn't care about that.
Rym: I mean, I kept wine in my room, and actually I left a very large red stain as a bottle of red wine exploded in my crappy little mini-fridge, because apparently it got set too cold and froze the thing.
Rym: And my stupid roommate, who I never interacted with, I remember I got back, and there's this giant red stain on the floor, and he says, "Yeah, I heard a noise from your fridge, and that stuff started leaking out.
Rym: I figured I'd leave it for, I didn't want to intrude upon your space or anything, so I didn't do
Rym: anything.".
Rym: I was like, "Thanks, dude.
Rym: That was
Rym: great.".
Scott: The winner is you.
Rym: I didn't have to pay.
Rym: I don't know why, but I never got billed for that.
Scott: Yeah, my roommate was similar.
Scott: He was a guy who was really interested in soccer, and I don't think he made the RIT soccer team, but he was always watching European soccer and stuff like that.
Scott: You're a geek about something.
Scott: It's all good.
Scott: We got along.
Scott: We didn't fight or anything.
Scott: We both did our thing, and I think I got him to play a geeky card game once.
Scott: I think he played guillotine once or something.
Scott: But other than that, we didn't interact too much, and it was just all good.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Mine was a little weird step beyond that.
Rym: I don't even remember the guy's name.
Rym: We introduced each other, and our parents were there, and they talked to each other like, "Oh, what a nice young boy.
Rym: Oh, what a nice young boy.
Rym: Yeah, they get along just
Rym: fine.".
Rym: And the only time we interacted... Well, we interacted three times in the entirety of the time.
Scott: The tribes do.
Rym: Well, I guess four times.
Rym: So time the one.
Rym: We moved in.
Rym: We set everything up, and we realized that the dorms were so small.
Rym: We had one of the narrow dorms.
Scott: The renovated dorms.
Scott: Yeah, the big dorm.
Scott: Pre-renovation.
Scott: Nothing was new and fancy.
Scott: It was a little scuzzy and old, but it was bigger and better.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But we realized that we could not both sit at our desks at the same time.
Rym: So we skewed everything to make sure that worked, and we had to talk while we moved the furniture around.
Rym: And then when the wine exploded, I talked to him.
Rym: When I jumped out of my bunk bed and landed on the floor and kind of hurt myself that one time, which I've told that story before, he asked me if I was alright.
Rym: And then there was the time when we moved out, and I said, "Well, see
Rym: ya.".
Rym: And then he left, and then I lived in the dorm for four more days by myself.
Rym: It was great.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The dorm, the size of the dorm I lived in, if it had been anywhere else, would have had three people in it, but it only had two.
Scott: It was wonderful.
Rym: You could fit four of the RIT narrow dorms in the living room of our house with room to spare.
Scott: Easily.
Rym: And two people lived in each of these things.
Rym: They were not large.
Scott: No, and that is why the furniture is such that, you know, the bed goes above the desk, and the closet is sort of built in there.
Rym: But it was funny, the kind of honor among, like, the expected protocols that everyone, everyone, every guy hosted their class schedule, kind of like, not like publicly like, "Here's my class schedule," but everyone always put it out so that the roommate could, with very little snooping, kind of just look at it.
Rym: And for anyone who hasn't been to college yet, this is for no purpose other than to determine the masturbatory schedule.
Scott: Yeah, there's nothing worse than, you know, getting your groove on and then- And hearing that jingle, jingle, jingle.
Scott: Yeah, hearing the jingle of keys getting ready to open the door.
Rym: However, every time you return home to your dorm room, and you're supposed to be at class, you always took some extra time jiggling the door, just, you know, just in case.
Rym: Give the person some time, because you know what they're doing, and when you walk in, they know that you know, but there's kind of this unspoken, well, it's not even kind of, it was unspoken.
Rym: No one ever made reference to it.
Scott: Nope, no one ever said anything.
Rym: But it's weird how everyone kind of just did it.
Scott: I actually had a close call once.
Rym: I had a couple close calls, because my man liked to skip class.
Scott: Who didn't like to skip class?
Rym: I skipped class a lot more than him, but somehow he always skipped, like, when I was in there masturbating.
Scott: All right.
Rym: But I hung out in Scott's dorm, and eventually, actually Peterson 3 became the hangout of the front row crew.
Scott: Well, also, because remember, every dorm has a lounge, and lounge is key, because some people are the kind of people who use the lounges, and some people are not, right?
Scott: And the lounge is sort of a first come, first serve thing.
Scott: It's like, if your group of friends is in there, everyone else has got to find somewhere else to go.
Rym: And no one ever came in and kicked people out, but it was just the people in there were made so uncomfortable.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You could come in and use the microwave if someone else was hanging out in there, but you couldn't bring your friends to hang out if someone else's friends were hanging out.
Scott: You didn't know each other, you know, unless you wanted to, you know, sort of get in on whatever their activity was, which happened, I guess, a couple times.
Rym: Yeah, that's how many people joined the front row crew.
Scott: But you don't come in and try to have your activity side by side with someone else's existing activity, and you don't come in and try to display someone's activity.
Scott: You either come in and join the existing lounge activity or you don't go in the lounge.
Rym: But it was like this force of will where whichever group had the stronger force of will just laid claim and no one ever questioned it.
Rym: There was never an argument.
Rym: No one ever said, "Hey, can we use the lounge?
Rym: Hey, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Hey, you guys are
Rym: loud.".
Rym: It was just one group remain- two groups enter, one group remains.
Rym: But Peterson 3 became the hangout primarily because there was this thing in the corner of the room.
Scott: Yeah, the lounge, you know, was old, so it was bigger, right?
Scott: It had a TV just like every other lounge, right, with a VCR and cable, you know, provided by the school.
Scott: But in the corner of the room, right, because it was like the way the building was, there was a storage closet next to the lounge.
Scott: So in the corner of the lounge, there was like this weird terraced block.
Scott: It was like three steps and then a landing.
Rym: I think there was like a pipe.
Rym: There was something under it.
Scott: There had to be something under it.
Scott: I think it might have been the storage closet or who knows what was under there, but there was just like this little terraced step in the corner of the room.
Rym: It was pretty tall, too.
Rym: It was like four and a half feet tall.
Scott: You could, you know, it was sort of like, "Hey, we could like have the DM sit up there.
Scott: It'd be
Scott: cool.".
Rym: Basically, the Dungeon Master sat up there, and it's weird, when we weren't playing D&D, no one sat there.
Rym: Like, if you or I guess if you were telling a story sometimes, you'd sit there.
Scott: If you ran out of room in the room and you're out of places to sit, some people would go up there.
Rym: But rarely.
Rym: Usually, the only time someone was there is if they had, for whatever reason, either playing D&D or telling a story or whatever, if they were kind of the master of ceremonies, they had the control of the zeitgeist of the room at the moment.
Rym: It was kind of like the speaker's podium or the soapbox.
Scott: Oftentimes, we'd put the little TV there.
Rym: Yes, we would, because the little TV, when we were using it, had control of the room.
Scott: Yeah, because remember, there was a VCR, I think, in the lounge, or wasn't there?
Rym: No, there wasn't, but I brought a VCR with me.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: I said the lounge had a VCR.
Scott: Actually, I was wrong.
Scott: It did not.
Scott: So, we would bring a VCR sometimes, but if we didn't, my roommate had brought a tiny TV with built-in VCR and we'd carry it to the lounge and watch things on this incredibly tiny television.
Rym: It was great.
Scott: Mostly anime from the Anime Club library on VHS.
Rym: Oh my God, those were good days.
Rym: We were pretty much our schedule on an average day.
Scott: That was also the last time I had cables and I lived in those dorms.
Rym: Yeah, but we'd show up, you know, we'd wake up.
Scott: I paid for that cable, half of it, every freaking quarter, but I never used it and the other guy only used it to watch Italian soccer.
Rym: We'd wake up and we'd, like, on a given day that wasn't a club night or something, we'd all go to class
Scott: and then
Rym: we'd all, like, do our thing and we might see each other for lunch or whatever, front row crew, all this business, and then, you know, a few of us worked, but most of us didn't have jobs.
Rym: We just had no money and no jobs and didn't care, and then we'd
Scott: all kind of
Rym: converge on
Scott: Gracie's around
Rym: like six o'clock, six thirty, seven, and the time would slowly shift, but the whole front row crew and, like, all the kind of attached crews, because that was kind of the peak of our crew before the front row crew kind of fully distilled out
Scott: of it.
Scott: Before we distilled and condensed.
Rym: There were a good twenty to thirty people at the absolute peak who would kind of congregate around the front row crew.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what happened to a lot of those people.
Rym: Well, it was kind of like the front row crew was the core and there was this large, like, tertiary group around it that would follow us.
Rym: Like, wherever we gathered, like, all those other people would kind of gather around us, but we were always there.
Rym: We always got wherever we were going first and left last.
Rym: It was kind of weird.
Rym: Like, we'd all go to the quad and hang out on The Thing, which was the common pastime outside when it wasn't, you know, as cold, and then that group would kind of find out we were there and converge around us and we'd all hang out, and then it'd all eventually leave, and then it'd be back to the core group again for another couple hours.
Rym: But we'd all go to Gracie's, which we could do a whole show on.
Rym: Gracie's in and of itself, I think, but...
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: It's a cafeteria.
Scott: How much is there to say?
Rym: A lot of things.
Rym: Remember when that dude stole my hat?
Scott: Alright.
Scott: The dude stole your hat.
Scott: The end.
Rym: Remember Steve Towell?
Rym: The, uh, the spectacle?
Rym: I don't know if you were there for the spectacle.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: The spectacle, if you don't remember the spectacle, you weren't there.
Rym: But, uh, we would go there, we'd all eat, and then we'd kind of wait for the people we didn't want to hang out with to give up and leave, and then we'd all go to Peterson 3, hang out until, like, 1150, and then, oh shit, the core's closing, and we'd run down to the corner store, Scott and I would buy Red Baron's Four Cheese Pizza, and everyone else had their own kind of ritualistic food.
Rym: We'd go back, we'd all microwave our various ritualistic foods.
Scott: I'm real hungry.
Rym: We'd eat them, and then we'd hang out until about 1.32, 3 in the morning, and then we'd all go to bed and skip our next, you know, day's classes.
Rym: Man, I really suddenly have all this nostalgia for hanging out in Peterson 3, but eventually, there was this whole shuffle where some of our friends like Alex and Pete had to move dorms because they were renovating dorms in the course of school.
Rym: So they eventually moved into the new dorm, the new tower, Sol 8.
Rym: And we kind of replaced Peterson 3 with Sol 8 because the lounge there, while it didn't have the thing, was a lot bigger, had a better TV, had better couches, the microwave worked a lot better, and it didn't smell funny.
Scott: Yeah, we usually did, you know, anime marathons there, because that was a renovated dorm.
Rym: Yep, but if we had to play D&D, we still went back to Peterson 3.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Actually, while we were at RIT, right, they renovated this one dorm, so actually we had people who started out living in one dorm that had to move to the one that was finished being renovated.
Rym: Those were Pete, you know, all the people we were talking about.
Scott: Yeah, they were living in Ellington, which is un-renovated.
Scott: Then, they finished renovating Sol, these people from Ellington moved to Sol, then they started renovating Ellington.
Rym: And of course, I mean, man, we used to do a lot of it.
Rym: Like, we used to, like, eventually we'd get bored and we'd get this wanderlust, and we'd like, wander into all the tunnels, because half the tunnels under the dorms at that time in RIT were abandoned.
Rym: Like, there was old stuff down there, like, the old nightclub that was closed, and the old arcade that was closed.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you went down to these dorms and there was, like, relics of, like, a college in the past.
Scott: It's the kind of thing that always gets me upset.
Scott: It's like, you see things that tell you, they let you know clearly that awesome was here, awesome is now gone.
Rym: There were nightclubs, bars, arcades, like, rooms we weren't even sure what they were for, stores that hadn't been open since, like, the 60s or 70s, tunnels that were cut off, fully functioning bathrooms in parts of the tunnels that didn't even have power.
Rym: Like, it was weird.
Scott: There was, you know, because the renovations, this tunnel system under all the dorms actually was split in half for a time, and you could only get from one area to the other, and people only really went down there to do laundry, and then that was it.
Scott: But, you know, there's the corners there.
Scott: Well, well,
Rym: and we went down there to do laundry, but in my side, at least, because I was connected, basically, there were the tunnels that actually connected to everything, and then there were kind of the bastardized tunnels that would connect to everything, but it was cut off for the renovation.
Rym: And Peterson was connected to those, but I was connected to, I guess, the real tunnels.
Rym: You could get between all the different dorms, except for the ones under renovation, and all the way to Gracie's, and all the way to the frat houses, and a large portion of the way to the academic side, without ever setting foot outdoors.
Scott: And this is key.
Scott: This is very key, because Rochester is fucking cold in the winter.
Rym: You would plot out, like, exactly how far can I get before I have to step outside, and then what is the quickest way to get back inside at the other side of the buildings, where, you know, the academic side had its own set of tunnels.
Rym: And you try to get from one tunnel to the other tunnel as quickly as possible.
Scott: The post office is also down there.
Rym: Yeah, it was, and a lot of other cool stuff.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, exploring those tunnels, man.
Scott: Well, not so much exploring.
Scott: They were really quick to explore all of them.
Rym: But we'd wander around.
Scott: Going down there and checking stuff out and seeing what was up was good times.
Rym: And, like, we'd get bored and just kind of wander around.
Rym: I remember that one time we found, they built, like, for some reason, they made a really fancy new conference room down there, like, in the middle of effectively abandoned tunnels.
Rym: And they left it open one day, and we found it.
Rym: So, we rigged one of the other doors, there were two doors to this place, so it looked like it was closed and locked, but we could still get in.
Rym: And then, for a while, we would go down there to play BattleTech.
Scott: Yeah, big conference room table, tunnels, night, no one's down there.
Scott: Whiteboards, why not play BattleTech?
Rym: It was really cool.
Rym: It was kind of like this, like, it was basically our tree fort, because we'd lock ourselves in there.
Rym: And, you know, it was quiet outside, like, there'd never be anyone in those tunnels, except every now and then the security guy.
Rym: But we were cut off from everyone in our own private hangout, no one knew we were there, and the door was locked.
Rym: No one could bother us.
Rym: Eventually, someone must have found the tape we'd put in the rigged door, because one day we couldn't get in anymore, and we never got into that room again.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But no, dorms are all about staying inside, not going outside.
Scott: You know, you've got the wicked fast internet connection, you've got plenty of people, you've got access to food without going outside.
Scott: You don't have to worry about money or anything, right?
Scott: So, it's all about just getting everything done, doing your whole life awesome, just in a building.
Scott: It's good preparation for the arcology living of the future.
Rym: But you're so isolated, and, you know, you're all together, and you're all geeks, and you're bored.
Rym: So as a result, I think that's part of the reason why the front row crew is so close and so family-like, is that we basically lived on a space station, isolated from all other people for long stretches of time, with nothing but other geeks around.
Rym: And, ugh, man, they were good times, let me tell you.
Scott: Yeah, that's sort of why I want to make, like, a geek apartment complex or building or something like that, you know, to sort of, you know, give people who are not, you know, RIT CS students the opportunity to have that kind of living.
Rym: In the deadest dead of winter, no one had Friday classes, so Friday morning, like, we'd all get up and get, you know, lunch, well, breakfast at like one o'clock or whatever, and we would all not set foot outside until Monday when we had to go to class again, and we'd all eat at Gracie's, like, you know, breakfast, lunch, and dinner for the whole weekend, and we'd, like, marathon a bunch of anime, like, we'd watch 13 episodes of a show on Saturday.
Scott: And you had not a care in the world, nothing else to do, nothing else to think about, nothing in the way, no real life, you know, you did your laundry, you did a little bit of homework, you know, to pass class, and then, what else did you have to do?
Scott: Nothing.
Rym: What I really miss is that by having no other concerns, I mean, you're a freshman too, so it's not even like the future is looming, nothing's looming, so everything I did was something I wanted to do, and I wasted a lot of time, but I wasted it purposefully.
Rym: I used to always tell people about the slacker spirit and become infused with the slacker spirit, and the slacker spirit is this.
Rym: If you are going to dick around and waste time and just enjoy yourself, do it wholeheartedly.
Rym: Don't worry about anything else in the world.
Rym: If you're gonna skip class, don't worry about class.
Rym: If you're gonna waste an entire weekend, don't even think of it as wasted, just do what you wanna do, and I would watch 20 hours of anime over the course of a weekend, as in, we'd marathon a whole show, and then like on Sunday we'd watch a bunch of other anime, and play some D&D in between all those things, and not get anything done, and at no point in those 20 hours did I ever think I could be spending this time better.
Rym: In fact, at best, I would think, "Man, are these the best days of my
Rym: life.".
Scott: Yeah, I mean, if you cut class to play Tribes 2 and the whole time you're like, "I shouldn't have skipped that
Scott: class.".
Scott: You were nervous.
Scott: You should have just gone to the class.
Scott: You wasted it.
Rym: The fact that nothing ever distracted me from what I was doing at RIT.
Rym: That is one thing that I had, and I don't have that anymore.
Rym: Maybe it's because I'm ambitious.
Rym: Like, even now, I'm at work, I'm working on work, but I'm also thinking about what I'm gonna do with GeekNights.
Rym: I'm at home, I'm doing GeekNights.
Rym: I'm thinking about what I'm gonna eat when I finish this show.
Rym: When I'm playing Natural Selection, I'm thinking about I'll look at the clock and think, "Well, in an hour, I should probably stop playing NS so that I can do
Rym: X.".
Rym: At RIT, I would skip class, I'd come home to the dorm, I'd start playing Natural Selection.
Rym: I would stop when I was done.
Rym: I didn't even think, "When's my next
Rym: class?".
Rym: I thought, "I'm playing
Rym: NS.".
Rym: At some point, I would stop NS.
Rym: I'd look at the clock and go, "Oh shit, it's 8 o'clock.
Rym: Fuck.".
Rym: And then I'd say, "Well, I already missed class, better go get
Rym: dinner.".
Scott: -I don't think we were playing NS when we were in the dorms.
Scott: It wasn't out yet.
Rym: -Might not have been, I don't remember.
Scott: -It wasn't until we were living in the apartment.
Rym: -We were, however, playing tribes.
Scott: -We were playing tribes, too.
Rym: -But I did the same thing in the apartment.
Rym: That's not a dorm-only thing.
Rym: That was a RIT thing.
Scott: -Well, I think it's an A college thing.
Rym: -Yeah, well, it depends.
Scott: -Can I eat now?
Rym: -Oh, you wanna stop doing the show?
Scott: -I'm just hungry.
Rym: -Alright, I'll tell you this, 'cause we have a lot of anecdotes about RIT in the dorms, and I just wanna hear this.
Rym: All of you out there, you GeekKnives listeners, do you want more, maybe a better-produced episode, as opposed to this kind of, "Ah, we're tired and we're kinda just winging the episode,".
Rym: but do you wanna hear more anecdotes from RIT?
Rym: Because we got a lot.
Scott: -People seem to just love anecdotes shows, but I feel like we should have more substance in it, and yet again, much like someone who, you know, "Ah, you know, is thinking about what they should've gone to class while they were skipping it," right?
Scott: I am thinking, "Ah, we should do a show with substance while we're doing a crab people
Scott: show.".
Rym: -Of course, at the same time, I'm kinda tired this week, but that's just an unrelated thing, so I'm just waiting for the show to be done, 'cause then all I have to do is FNPL tomorrow, and then, uh...
Scott: -Yeah, it's weird, Thursday is our most flexible day, yet it's the hardest day to actually come up with what to do the show on.
Scott: Maybe we should just do a lot more, maybe we should just do a lot, I'm reading a lot of books, maybe we should just turn Thursday into book day.
Scott: Maybe that'll get people to read.
Rym: -No, because no one seems to read the books.
Scott: -Maybe if we just kept doing it, people would fuckin' read.
Rym: -But I feel like, I don't know, maybe, would you guys like it if we just did a Thursday that was just, like, we'll turn into a series, we won't do it all the time, we'll do it sparingly, I don't wanna waste it, kinda like those zombie shows.
Scott: -I don't know, I think we already told most of the anecdotes we got.
Rym: -I haven't by far.
Scott: -What do you gotta talk about?
Rym: -I got a lot to say.
Rym: Chris, I've always been more of the anecdote-tician than you.
Scott: -I don't know, what anecdote do I have that I haven't already used, you know, only so many things happened that were memorable.
Scott: I mean, some of them were perhaps memorable, but there's really, you know, it's what, it's sort of those, you can't really tell a story about it, it's a "had to be there" thing, you know, it's like, "Hey, remember that time we sat there and watched Ava
Scott: straight?".
Scott: It's like, yeah, we did.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: What else is there to say about it?
Rym: -I guess you just don't have the gift of the storyteller.
Scott: -Dude, I can tell a great story, that has to be a story to tell.
Scott: It's unlike you, I don't make up stuff.
Rym: -Except I don't have to make anything up when I'm talking about RIT.
Rym: God, I have hours.
Rym: More happened in terms of just memorable events in the few years at RIT than have happened in many other periods of my life.
Scott: -Yeah, there was a lot that happened but I can't, you know, there's not that much of it that it can be a whole series of shows.
Scott: We've already used a lot of it in the early shows of GeekNights that many people haven't listened to.
Rym: -Yeah, and we could probably just tell them again, better and more experienced podcasters that we are.
Scott: -I think we could tell them again better podcast wise but less memory wise.
Rym: -I don't seem to have this problem.
Scott: -It was three years ago, the GeekNights.
Scott: -Anyway -And we talked about that shit.
Rym: -Okay, I don't know, what do you guys want?
Rym: Because I feel like what we could do is -You don't need to ask the people, the people always say yes, anecdotes.
Scott: They just want all anecdotes all the time.
Rym: -I want to hear it from them because I'm willing to put forth at least a token effort here.
Rym: Basically we said we're going to change up the Thursday format and we really haven't yet.
Scott: -No, we failed.
Rym: -But I feel like every Thursday we should just do something weird in story time or whatever.
Rym: but I feel like we could do a short series of vignettes just about you know, what it was like to be us at RIT.
Rym: Not the how to not sucks where we try to kind of tell a story about us or someone we knew and then try to use it as a parable for life.
Rym: Or not.
Rym: the kind of here is how to succeed or any of those things.
Rym: Just vignettes of what it was like very directly to be us, the front row crew, in college at RIT.
Rym: If you don't want to do it, maybe I'll do it on my own.
Scott: I feel like I can do this.
Scott: -I feel like we've already communicated that pretty thoroughly and I don't have, you know, it's definitely something that is people want to hear and some, you know, but I feel like we've done it already.
Scott: It's like it's already been done and you're proposing doing it.
Rym: -No, because part of it is that yeah, it has been done but it's diffuse throughout hundreds and hundreds of episodes of GeekNights and this would be kind of a consolidation.
Scott: -So maybe the solution is to go back collect the material and edit it together.
Rym: -No, that's a terrible idea because usually all the material is told in the context of something else and also there's no way in hell I would have the time.
Scott: -No, no, I mean just like you know, take all the episodes and just say these are the episodes to listen to.
Scott: that have, you know.
Rym: -That's also a terrible idea.
Rym: A better idea would be to take all the vignettes and retell them in kind of some sort of narrative even if it's a loose narrative and have a separate show.
Rym: You've done the pre-work and the research by telling the anecdotes diffuse throughout all these shows and you consolidate them and make a separate show.
Rym: that is Life at RIT.
Scott: -Eh, maybe.
Scott: Doesn't excite me that much.
Rym: -It excites me a lot to the point that I'll probably, I'll probably do that and have it done long before I do any of the other things I've been promising I'll do for GeekNights.
Scott: -I'm working on websites and things slowly but surely.
Rym: -Anyway, let's eat some food and go to bed.
Scott: -Oh god food.
Rym: -This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: -Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: -We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: -You can send us feedback by email to geeknights at frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: -If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: -GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share-alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.