Scott: It's Wednesday September 17th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: final thoughts on Neon Genesis Evangelion.
Scott: Let's do this So not this weekend, but next weekend in other words the weekend of September 26 27 28.
Rym: yes, we will be at once again an anime convention.
Rym: We're gonna be at the New York anime festival and a New York and a festival number two Yes in the Jacob Javits Center in New York City.
Rym: You can probably find it will link to it.
Rym: But just in case you're interested.
Rym: I know you people like to see our live shows, but on Saturday We're doing three panels comics for the manga fan Anime match game, which is always a riot, and we're doing the last.
Rym: I swear to God.
Rym: We're never doing this again.
Rym: Gecky guy the rated our version at the request of the convention.
Scott: We still have it.
Rym: I've got it Actually went through it again, and I I forgot how funny the stupid tree is.
Rym: oh my god.
Rym: Like I was reading through the tree now.
Rym: I forgot about the gods porn thing.
Scott: GPX is the other manga.
Rym: I thought I think one of them's wounded man and one of them is Basically I forgot about the porn and I remember the tree, but I forgot about the true glory of the tree That shot, that's that I would call that piece clarity clarity of vision.
Rym: oh My god, yes Gami is truly a master master of something, but yeah the basic master like Van.
Scott: Gogh.
Rym: I've mentioned this but for those who are unaware if You're going to be at the New York anime festival You should go see our gecky got panel.
Rym: for one reason and one reason alone We did the PG rated version at the last New York anime festival because it's a family-friendly con.
Rym: People heard tell of what happened at Otakon and what happened at Katsu con.
Rym: apparently our gecky got panel is Infamous.
Scott: hey, it's infamous with a small crowd But infamous nonetheless.
Rym: infamous to the point at least that the convention asked us to do the version We did at Otakon to which I said even though we did this panel already at the convention last time to which I said hell No So we're doing what we did at Katsu con.
Rym: We were doing the rated our version not the rated Gerald version
Scott: Oh Gerald
Rym: and also as a special treat because I had to be in the city anyway, I Will be doing possibly with Emily our know your creators panel on Sunday at like 245 without Scott because he didn't want to come on Sunday and
Scott: it's not worth it for me to go to the city on Sunday to Do a panel and go home.
Scott: Yes But basically I got stuff to do.
Rym: I needed a day in the city to go like by skis for the winter and all this Business and it was basically the perfect day to do it.
Rym: So I've got to be in the city.
Rym: Anyway, I'm just gonna swing by.
Rym: me and Emily are gonna do this panel and get right back on our way.
Rym: So for those of you who don't know what Emily looks like it might be your chance to see her.
Scott: Yeah, you know the panel that I came up with I'm not even doing.
Rym: yeah, that's fine.
Rym: We learned a lot from doing the panel at Otakon.
Rym: We learned that we had far too many creators.
Scott: Yeah, well, that's cuz I we tried to eat.
Scott: that came up with that great stick But to pull off the stick required too many creators.
Scott: Yes Whatever.
Rym: so, uh, what do you got?
Rym: the news being an anime show haven't done one of these in a while.
Scott: It's not really big anime news Great, but there is a video game news Involving anime.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Is it y'all?
Scott: you're all.
Rym: you're all skeptical and I am all skeptical.
Scott: What are you skeptical of?
Rym: I'm skeptical that it's really usefully related to anime manga or comics.
Scott: Oh, it's incredibly usefully related.
Scott: You see who of all the video game companies in the universe is awesome right now Capcom Capcom.
Scott: And you know Capcom.
Scott: they like to do their games of Capcom verse, you know, the fighting games have come first Marvel Comics.
Rym: I'll be.
Rym: I'll be honest.
Rym: Some people might not like me anymore.
Rym: I never liked those games.
Rym: I don't think they're good games.
Scott: I like them in a way.
Rym: No, I like part of what like.
Rym: I like what they are and what they stand for.
Rym: playing them Not so fun for me.
Scott: it depends on which one.
Rym: All right, it's fun to play them against people who suck at them, but that's about it.
Scott: Yes I know people are just too good.
Scott: Any fighting.
Rym: I know just enough to where.
Rym: if you're not good at that game I'm going to fucking destroy you.
Rym: but if you are good at that game, you will destroy me.
Scott: That's pretty much how it is with any fighting game.
Scott: What fighting game is are you not that like that?
Rym: but the level in this game like the point like yet when you get to the point and it doesn't take much to get that 1% better than normal people when you realize the game is all about those combo.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, okay I don't see how it's any different than any other fighting in.
Rym: the point is the point is People who don't know anything about Soul Calibur 2 will beat anyone.
Rym: but a god about a third of the time That doesn't happen to Marvel vs.
Rym: Capcom for example.
Scott: Anyway, they're making this one.
Scott: It's been out of news for a while.
Scott: people have known they're making Tatsunoko verse Capcom, right?
Scott: Now, I don't know if people realize what Tatsunoko is.
Scott: Do you know what Tatsunoko is?
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: You really don't know?
Scott: No.
Scott: It's very anime appropriate.
Scott: Tatsunoko is basically an anime company and they I Don't know if they're like a. they're a production company apparently Okay and they're responsible for many.
Scott: many things fall under the banner of Tatsunoko like Well Speed Racer.
Rym: So Speed Racer is gonna be fighting in this.
Rym: quite possibly That that sounds a little more lame than it does.
Rym: Awesome.
Scott: Hurricane Palomar Lots of crazy weird giant robot things.
Rym: So is this gonna be a bunch of crazy weird giant robot thing fighting game and that's it.
Scott: I think.
Scott: gotcha man will be in there.
Rym: Maybe so far.
Rym: This isn't exciting.
Scott: It's all sorts of samurai pizza cats.
Scott: Aha, take a man blade Yeah, whatever it's lots of stuff that you don't care about apparently but money.
Scott: many other anime fans out there will care about many Of these characters that will now be in a top-class fighting game.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm just.
Rym: I don't think that the game is gonna do very well in the US.
Scott: Well, I don't think it's coming out in the US.
Scott: well There it.
Scott: the news is is that the two news is that just happened about this game.
Scott: right is number one.
Scott: You know, this game was originally just gonna be like an arcade and ps3 game or whatever, right?
Scott: but now it's gonna be a Wii game and Recently people have cracked the Wii to play some backups and such.
Scott: So I can see some bootleg importing torrenting of this game going on in the US.
Rym: I foresee playing it at anime cons because I'm not gonna bother trying to get it.
Scott: I might try to do something like that, but they added a Character to the game.
Scott: at least the Wii version is gonna have characters that the other versions don't have which is sort of crazy Uh-huh.
Rym: Can I fight with my me?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: I highly doubt it's not that kind of game.
Scott: They're gonna add Hakushan Daimo Who is like this sneezing genie character from something I never heard of but when I saw him I was like wow That is freaking old-school and obscure.
Scott: This is definitely a game for the fanboys And if you are the fanboy you are you should be pretty excited.
Rym: But just in case no one has seen this I mean it was in our forum and people were talking about it.
Rym: But Emily pointed out to us a while ago that there is in fact a new anime coming and of course There's always new anime coming but it's so rare that there's a new show that I'm excited about.
Rym: I mean every season There's like one show.
Rym: I'm kind of excited about but I mean what I let's see bacchanal slayers revolution and this.
Scott: But this show looks so incredibly bad You know, it's really weird though is if you actually count the number of shows like on Japanese TV There's more than ever.
Scott: there's like 40 something show anime on Japanese TV right now or something like this.
Rym: I mean, it's not really an indictment of Japanese anime because I'm equally pessimistic about American television and there's about all entertainment in all mediums from all countries.
Rym: But anyway, the show looks incredibly awesome and I really want to make sure everyone is ready for it to come.
Rym: I expect the fan subs to be well worth it, but Michiko and Hachin has a lot of high-powered people involved.
Rym: Of course for one.
Rym: It's being produced by Watanabe aka.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Cowboy Bebop and it's basically set in like Alternate semi future Brazil and it's about this hard-ass woman and this little girl shooting people.
Rym: It looks like a buddy comedy that's really gritty and cool and I Really get the cowboy bebop samurai.
Rym: Champloo kind of vibe from it.
Rym: You know, that might be kind of obvious, but it's also man globe is involved, you know, ergo proxy and such.
Rym: so Watch this trailer and if you're not excited about this, I guess you just don't like the kind of anime I like.
Scott: I guess you don't like anime.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But yeah, it's you know the show from the trailer.
Scott: I can't really draw that much out of it.
Scott: But what I can tell is definitely this is not another moe show It's not a robot show.
Scott: It's definitely one of those anime that's not in a typical anime genre.
Scott: Therefore the chances of it being good are significantly higher.
Rym: Well one the trailer looked actually really really good and two it's coming soon.
Rym: It's actually coming in October.
Scott: Yeah, they usually you don't find out about anime that far in advance You know, they usually keep everything under wraps until the show's definitely gonna be on TV or something like that.
Scott: You know, they don't like to say anything and then have to go back on it Later, like, you know a lot of companies in the US do where they say something and they go oops No, we didn't mean that.
Scott: they just you know, keep their mouths shut and they only say any something if it's a sure deal.
Rym: So if nothing else when the show actually comes out you can bet that we will be reviewing it or at least previewing it Pretty quickly.
Scott: because isn't that sort of a weird thing though?
Scott: It's like, you know anime is a medium, you know It's animation for Japan and Japan, you know people from Japan can animate anything anything that can be animated.
Scott: they can animate it Right yet.
Scott: There are certain genres.
Scott: They happen to animate lots and lots of TV shows movies and OAVs in those genres such as magical girl, you know Giant robot etc.
Rym: than anything.
Rym: I mean in America you can film or animate or do whatever to anything you want.
Rym: But yet they just make a lot of like buddy cop shows Procedural cop shows and it was reality shows.
Scott: I know the thing is is that in Japan it seems like not in Japan, but in anime it seems like Good.
Scott: good shows are always the ones that are not in one of those default genre, you know It seems like the same way the US.
Rym: anytime a show like breaks the mold.
Rym: It's usually the great show.
Scott: So When you think about that, right?
Scott: Why would anyone?
Scott: Not well, you should just break the mold every time.
Scott: part of the reason you're not breaking the mold Why bother you got you're not doing something?
Rym: Yes It's pretty simple because a lot of shows try to break the mold and very few of them succeed.
Scott: And it's not hard to break the mold.
Scott: Don't make a magical girl.
Scott: I was trying to break the mold.
Scott: I made a magical girl show accident.
Scott: I shit.
Rym: breaking the mold is a huge risk because most shows that break the mold Fail miserably and wallow in obscurity.
Rym: and the rare one show that broke the mold and was good Does way better than a show that didn't break the mold.
Rym: but a show that doesn't break the mold is it pretty much?
Rym: Guaranteed moneymaker.
Rym: It'll make enough money to pay everyone involved and have a tidy profit.
Rym: You're not gonna make some revolutionary new art?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: look I look right now and it seems like every mold breaking show is good at least good You know and every non bold breaking show is just a not so much.
Scott: That's what I'm seeing at least in the world of anime one I disagree But to like.
Rym: if you look at American TV That's pretty much clearly the case and you can see all the different shows that are like yeah check out our show It's edgy.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: This show is not like other shows.
Rym: We're trying real hard here.
Scott: Well releasing a hundred moe shows seems to have not done the anime industry very well in America.
Rym: Hey, I'll bet those shows made enough money.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: So before we tread into these very dangerous waters we do have as always things of the day.
Rym: This might be a cop-out, but I guess now don't know because the phrase here I know what you're doing the phrase here is quoted for truth.
Rym: All right Because this has been on my mind a lot after we went to PAX.
Rym: but anime news Nina in case you haven't heard me say this enough exceeds all expectations and the anime news network gets mad points for using a somewhat edgy poignant and I guess awesome webcomic as their official webcomic.
Scott: I mean usually when you have a comic that is created to sponsor something or is in Association with your company or a mark a comic comics used for marketing purposes are typically really really really lame Every pretty much.
Scott: it's really hard to find a comic that is associated with a business or is an ad that isn't lame.
Rym: And usually it's because they can't really be witty and biting and edgy and dark And they can't really take snipes at what is the truth because then they'll get in trouble and turn people away.
Rym: But anime news Nina has consistently Bait into people who deserve biting into and it is witty and it is gray.
Scott: It's like if the newspaper was all about anime.
Rym: This would be the political cartoon anime news named Nina quoted for truth and Basically this animators Nina the second most recent one Kind of in a roundabout way encapsulates what it is I think is wrong with American anime cons in a big way.
Scott: I agree with it a hundred million percent and it doesn't even beat around the bush.
Scott: It's like there's no Bush to beat around.
Rym: It's like why?
Rym: because what what do you mean?
Rym: Why?
Rym: because we're fucked the end Pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, and the the faces on the people lined up are brilliant Mmm, anyway, that's all I have to say.
Rym: I'm not even gonna spoil The comics about so we can discuss it I know because I want to get into the dangerous waters that we are treading very rather go into dangerous waters and discuss a good Topic.
Rym: Yes, that's just the kind of man You know what?
Rym: It's the gecky guy ideal to walk forward on my own true feet to be what it is that a man is.
Scott: When I was a pack without all the rape Ram, you know, we've had lots of good ideas for you know Merch the company should make that they never made.
Rym: Ah, yes such as Metroid umbrella, you know, oh my god I would buy a metro to umbrella.
Scott: Imagine for a minute a clear umbrella clear plastic with three red balls inside and some white spikes hanging down in the middle.
Scott: That's a wicked cool umbrella right there.
Scott: that is Nintendo.
Scott: make that umbrella.
Rym: No that umbrella it two words social currency.
Rym: Yeah, that's like a thousand dollar bill.
Scott: All right, so, you know, there aren't really like Metroid merches like there should be especially not cute ones.
Scott: I mean you can get Samus action figures I guess but that's about it and I've always wanted like a little plush Metroid like a little one.
Scott: That's cute like You know or maybe like a Metroid hat sort of like those You know the head grabs.
Scott: Yeah, the head crab hats that valve makes, you know, something like that only a Metroid.
Scott: well When I was at PAX I saw someone wearing a Metroid hat Karen a Metroid plushie and This shit looked like it was official real-deal merch.
Scott: So I was gonna ask them where the hell they got it.
Rym: Did the guy just make it himself or why it was a girl?
Scott: But and I failed to ask them where they got it because they sort of you know was in a crowd I couldn't get close to him and then on the way out I was almost close to them, but then I couldn't get.
Scott: and then it was you know, forget it.
Scott: So I later on I searched for Metroid hat because I think I thought it was real merch, right?
Scott: I could find it.
Scott: It was not real merch.
Scott: They made it and in fact, there is a website Metroid hat calm.
Scott: And Metroid hat calm is that person's website and on that person's website is a Metroid plushie tutorial.
Scott: That's how come I found their website.
Rym: Are you gonna make the Metroid hat?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe I'll try to make the Metroid plushie.
Scott: I mean I made a stuffed alligator when I was in middle school.
Scott: Why couldn't I make?
Rym: I miss it was not that hard granted.
Rym: We don't have a sewing machine.
Scott: No, if I had a sewing machine to be 10,000 times easier, but I want to really cheap.
Rym: Yeah If I buy one to go to the craft store I could probably make stupid audition and auditions more expensive than a cheap sewing machine.
Scott: I could probably do it if I wanted to but I've got some programming things to do first.
Rym: Regardless, you could get one of those geeky sewing machines that you can program.
Scott: Yeah to bring it back to the anime and the manga right?
Scott: Not only does this a Metroid hat calm Of this girl from you know, Western Canada who was at PAX, right?
Scott: Not only does her website have the Metroid plushie tutorial It also has the Nintendo power Metroid Prime comic that was in Metroid Prime.
Scott: it has scans lations of the Japanese Metroid manga and it has Broken a mother 3 fan comic among some other things on here.
Scott: So if you like Metroid hats mother 3 Metroid comics anything along these lines want to make a Metroid plushie?
Rym: You had me at Metroid.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: check any of this other stuff, you know cute pictures of Metroids wearing hats that aren't Metroids.
Scott: You know, this is a website.
Scott: You should probably go to Alright.
Rym: Alright, but we really shouldn't beat around the bush anymore.
Rym: because you see we realize that of all the anime podcasters out there that we know I Believe that we have more I don't know testicular fortitude than all of them combined.
Scott: Well, I'm not sure that none of them have gone in these waters before.
Rym: they've gone in similar waters.
Rym: I will give them that because reviews of certain things are very very intimidating to do crystal triangle and They have other people like anime world order.
Rym: They've reviewed shows that I am still kind of afraid to go near.
Rym: but at the same time No one has touched this show with a.
Scott: well, I mean someone might have touched the show, but I haven't heard it.
Rym: We did once before I think we did a show that was basically you're all stupid if you don't like this show.
Scott: I. now we're doing that show again times 10.
Rym: You see a long long time ago.
Rym: We had a poll We're like, alright, it's been a while I mean we did a final thoughts episode about you know like one or two anime that we didn't do it for a long time and We did a poll and we asked people what shows they like final thoughts about and you know people voted for the obvious ones.
Rym: They wanted a lane.
Rym: They want to try gun.
Rym: They wanted Ava.
Scott: I haven't seen Lane in a million years.
Rym: Oh my god You know what?
Rym: I watch Lane in high school.
Rym: I haven't seen it since.
Scott: I saw it early at RIT way.
Scott: early I watched the DVD box set.
Scott: It was a good show.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, keep going but We were gonna do.
Rym: a final thoughts on Shinseki Evangelion one of the now This is where the shit from all you people out there begins because what I'm about to say is a somewhat controversial statement one of the best Freaking anime ever created.
Rym: Oh, no Rym.
Scott: You're wrong.
Scott: Oh, oh, it is among the greatest television shows in the history of the universe.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: when we and I say among I don't think I mean top hundred I mean like top five.
Scott: now something like that.
Rym: a month ago as recently as a month ago I would have said yeah, it's in the top 50 at least probably in the top 15, but you know Hindsight blah blah blah.
Rym: I watched the show a bunch of time was I was younger?
Scott: This is a show.
Scott: I watched this show on VHS alone.
Scott: Then I watched the movies, you know alone actually.
Scott: then I watched it on VHS and a marathon.
Scott: It's not not too long after that the same year In fact like within months and then I didn't watch the show for one two three Possibly six or seven years.
Scott: I think seven years.
Rym: meanwhile I be maybe eight years.
Rym: I was into anime when I was in high school.
Rym: I got a fan.
Scott: so the show is more than seven or eight years old of air and a pure heart for you.
Rym: the movie the Movie the aim.
Scott: Well, they're not gonna confuse you by talking about all the different.
Rym: I'll get it.
Rym: I'll explain what we're gonna talk about in a minute.
Rym: Yeah, don't worry the the AT field aka the spoiler line We're not there yet.
Rym: We're getting close, but we're not there yet.
Rym: We're not gonna spoil anything.
Rym: I saw the movie before.
Rym: I knew there was a show and all I want to say is that I showed it to a Bunch of people.
Rym: we watched it it ended.
Rym: everyone turned to me and said and I quote with one voice Rym What the fuck did you just show to us?
Scott: Seriously, dude We had to know what happened and it ended and we know it as soon you got to like that when you got to like Pure heart for you.
Scott: You thought you were gonna find out what happened.
Rym: Yes, and you know what?
Scott: How did you?
Scott: you didn't even know what happened before?
Scott: Know what the resolution would be.
Scott: even if there was a resolution I didn't know what was being resolved.
Rym: the worst part about that movie is that I found out Exactly what happened and that was worse than not knowing anyway.
Rym: Anyway, we are not talking about the Ava movies.
Rym: That is I'm not even gonna get into that.
Rym: We're Basically what we were doing here.
Rym: now, this is final thoughts Evangelion, so once we say the word Spoilers spoilers spoilers and normally a lot of people when they don't care about a show say yeah I don't care just spoil the show for me.
Rym: In fact when it came to shoujo kakamei Utena multiple people had asked me over the years to spoil the show and I refused to know.
Rym: and when Emily finally saw the show all The way through she thanked me for not spoiling it.
Rym: And all I want to say is that if you have not seen Neon Genesis Evangelion all the way through do not listen any further.
Scott: This show is so Incredibly worth your watching and if you're one of those people out there I know you exist right who has not watched the whole show seriously given watched every single episode in order with your full attention.
Scott: or Maybe you've never watched any of it and you have all the sorts of Misgivings about it.
Rym: or if you saw it while you were a teenager or a young 20-something Watch it again.
Scott: when you're older get the DVD box set.
Scott: the platinum DVD box like 30 box is stupidly cheap.
Scott: It comes with the entire TV series and four director's cut versions of episodes 21 through 24, I think right Watch the whole thing Again, so or for the first time and I don't care if you're one of those people who's like, I don't like robots Is it?
Scott: I don't give a shit.
Scott: watch it.
Rym: even if you hated Ava you listen to us you watch it again You watch it four more times and you still hate it in the end.
Rym: That's fine.
Scott: It's kind of like You're just a retard.
Rym: Yeah, but you can you can.
Rym: you can say I do not like Citizen Kane and While a lot of people will say wow, you have some bad taste in movies at the same time you they can at least say but it is your opinion as long as you admit that citizen Kane is an important movie a Well-constructed movie an amazing movie.
Scott: I mean like you might look at say I don't know the Sistine Chapel and say, you know I'm not really feeling anything.
Scott: I'm just looking at it and I got no feelings coming in, you know, that's fine.
Scott: You know, I don't like different different, you know different strokes and folks and all that business, right?
Rym: But All that made me think of was the opening scene of the stupid Ava movie.
Scott: Well, maybe think of different strokes the TV show.
Rym: Well one stroke for some folk right all over some other folk To which my mom said, why do you why don't need this business?
Scott: I keep that business out of here.
Scott: But if you look at you can't say it's this teen chapel sex.
Scott: no It's.
Scott: it's pretty much like the best ever and if you don't like it, you're you're dumb.
Rym: Yes, but basically this is final thoughts Evangelion, but I'm gonna have to clarify that because there is a lot to Evangelion.
Scott: so you could probably just sit here and talk all night and not run out of things to say.
Scott: So we're basically gonna.
Scott: it's it's the one hour of thoughts of how to even yes So it is going to be however a final thoughts.
Rym: episode Nothing is sacred spoilers all over the place, but I Want to say that this episode is almost more.
Rym: I would almost want to call it in defense of the event.
Scott: I don't think it needs defense.
Scott: Why would you need to?
Scott: it's like well who needs to defend citizen Kane?
Rym: Well, the reason it needs to be defended is because unlike citizen Kane Imagine if you went online and there were entire websites dedicated to people ranting about how much citizen Kane sucks.
Rym: I Search right now you search for that because I see that with Ava a lot of otherwise intelligent people will come up to me And try to tell me that Ava is a terrible show and yet I've never heard a well-reasoned.
Scott: The top result for hate citizen Kane right is checked.
Scott: Here's a quote from it.
Scott: despite the fact that I can respect and appreciate its significance cinematic history based solely on entertainment value I hate citizen Kane.
Rym: Oh, that is exactly what opinion you were allowed to have exactly but I Feel like the reason we don't need to defend Evangelion like Scott said is because we're like one of the lessons I've learned from both gecky guy and hockey The best defense is a strong offense.
Scott: Yes We've already begun to make fun of the people who hate Evangelion and I can tell you we will not stop doing so.
Scott: So what eventually I mean?
Scott: before my most recent viewing I might have said yeah, you know I know why people don't like the show.
Scott: It's sort of weird and tries to be existential and could be interpreted as pretentious.
Scott: People don't like the heavy metaphor action I believe when we watch big o2.
Rym: I said the words in the big o2.
Rym: final thoughts This show did the end of Ava better than Ava and you know what?
Rym: I retract that statement a hundred percent.
Rym: the final two episodes of Ava are brilliant.
Scott: Yeah, if you really and I watch Ava again, and now I say no no, no, no longer Am I gonna say I understand why people don't like the end of this?
Scott: Well, I guess I do understand Your.
Scott: your brain is broken you're wrong you're an idiot.
Scott: but basically yeah, yeah, you don't have no taste You have no tongue.
Rym: what this show is what we're going to do very specifically is Tell you everything we think even though we've already killed like a whole bunch of time not saying anything.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: Well, because this is it's.
Rym: this is one of those difficult.
Rym: We are in very dangerous waters here.
Rym: We are treading Deeper.
Scott: that's okay because we brought a whole boatload of ammo.
Rym: Oh my god Listen to him.
Rym: reason that's right or in a t-field.
Scott: No, they'll listen to reason, you know, what's great?
Rym: Oh, here's my one fanboy moment.
Rym: reason wouldn't have done shit to even Ava zero zero.
Scott: Not at all.
Rym: But what we're doing is we're talking about the show Shin Seiki Evangelion neon Genesis Evangelion episodes 1 through 26 as you would see them if you buy the platinum Collection pretty much as they were seen by people on TV.
Rym: and We're not going to talk about anything.
Rym: That is not in TV in Japan yes, and the reason I say that is because There's a lot you can say about Evangelion that is not able to be determined from the show.
Rym: You could only know these things if you saw the movies books listen to interviews with Anno and all these things really color the show.
Rym: and we're not talking about that.
Rym: we could do a whole Show on like interpretations of Ava.
Rym: We're not talking about how to interpret Ava.
Rym: We were talking about what is in Ava.
Rym: So thus at this point the spirit vlogging news is going right through that spoiler line.
Rym: once again I beseech you if you have not seen Evangelion all the way through or you don't remember what it's about or if you watched it and you kind of liked it But you haven't watched it in a long time.
Rym: Do not listen any further.
Rym: come back after you have watched Ava all the way through.
Rym: Yeah, so that said Ava is a show about the end of the world and that might sound like a very trite thing to say.
Rym: I mean, yeah, it was the show where they kill everyone at the end.
Rym: They're not kidding.
Rym: a lot of shows about the end of the world.
Scott: think about how many right anime manga especially but sci-fi Things in general, right?
Scott: Maybe they're post-apocalyptic and the world already ended and now it's the few people left over Who are still you know struggling to survive and you know make their way in a doomed land.
Scott: or maybe it's one of those shows Where okay, there's something horrible attacking and if the good guys lose it will be the end of the world.
Scott: But you know, it's just mostly a big fighting show sort of like I don't know Project blue cheeky usos.
Scott: Yeah, or something like that, right or it could be one of those shows.
Rym: Well, there's like the last question, you know science fiction that deals with these topics.
Rym: But Ava what it does it does something that has been done before.
Rym: it's not like Ava is the only work of fiction to ever do this, but the gravity of the situation and the gravity of what I mean.
Rym: It is the end of the world and the gravity is presented to you in Such stark relief in this show.
Scott: it is done handled So well, well because what most of those other shows do especially the ones that are you know have the risk of end-of-world Situation is it's basically if something happens that barely anyone knows is happening Then the world will end pretty much near instantly.
Scott: Evangelion is.
Scott: Everyone pretty much the whole world knows it's coming.
Scott: They know the chances of the world.
Scott: It's not one of those things where there's a chance the world could end.
Scott: It's like there's a chance.
Scott: it maybe could not end maybe but now it's probably gonna end.
Rym: The characters in the show the characters we are, you know experiencing this world through their eyes.
Rym: These people Masada Shinji y'all they know that the world is ending.
Rym: That's it They're.
Scott: they're all happening.
Scott: It's not happening quickly It's happening over the course of many many many days.
Scott: They have a lot of time to think about and the whole world knows it - no It's not like it is big.
Scott: Well, it's somewhat secret, but it's not super secret.
Rym: Well, it's kind of like early on in the show The world isn't 100 like they.
Rym: you know, they know something's going on and but the guy, you know the moment God sent his angels to end the world and All nerve is is kind of humanity's last ditch.
Rym: Like there's a tiny chance.
Rym: We might not all die.
Scott: It's basically big monsters are coming out of the sky trying to destroy the world and the humans see him.
Scott: It's kind of hard to hide a big giant monster and they're.
Scott: they're using all of the science of man to try to fight it off and They're barely making it now.
Rym: Of course part of what makes the show the gravity so powerful and makes the show so powerful is that Basically, they don't win.
Rym: I mean you've seen the end of Ava.
Rym: a Lot of people joke and say yeah everyone dies, but no think about that.
Rym: It's not just a kill-em-all to me.
Rym: Everyone dies everyone everything existence Everything ends.
Rym: It's over.
Rym: Nothing exists.
Rym: It's done.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Think about that.
Rym: Think about what that entails.
Scott: Well, the thing that really gets me is not so much that everyone dies at the end because there's a lot of shows where everyone Dies at the end.
Scott: It's that or at least everyone you care about that.
Scott: Yes, but it's not just that it's everyone yeah, but it's um It's that during the show, right?
Scott: The people in the world actually act as if it's the end of the world at least more so than in anything else.
Scott: I can think of any other, you know story in any medium that you know comes to mind Right.
Scott: I mean there's this town that's the one city even though it's a highly defensible city We're all the mod or all the you know, crazy monsters are attacking.
Scott: So people all move away from that city and then you know, like the the UN stop the humanity they use, right?
Scott: I mean think about this right when you're in every day-to-day life even of the real world right now, right?
Scott: You know governments around the world they make decisions about how many resources to allocate towards different things.
Scott: You play a game like civilization, right?
Scott: You decide how many resources towards science How many towards defense how many towards these different things.
Scott: right in this situation?
Scott: You actually have the entire world Expanding 100% of its resources to stop the pretty much unstoppable end of the world.
Scott: because if it's really the end and it's really horrible monsters attacking and you don't have you know, Some mystical Voltron that just comes out of nowhere for free.
Scott: You're gonna spend every single dollar every single person every single thing You've got for any chance that you can find and the world does that now.
Rym: now at this point I mean we really I want to talk about because a Concept and a plot alone are not what can make something great because as Neil Gaiman always says the idea is nothing.
Rym: Everyone has ideas.
Rym: doing it is what matters.
Scott: Yeah, because people would always write to Neil Gaiman Like I have this great idea for a story.
Scott: Do you want to write it with me?
Scott: You know and Neil Gaiman's like listen your idea isn't worth anything.
Scott: everyone has a million ideas, right?
Scott: The only thing that's worth anything is not just your ability to turn that idea into something great But actually doing it your actual labor.
Scott: You actually have to sit down do it and make it happen and making it happen and hat is what's worth something.
Rym: But Ava does all of these things incredibly well and incredibly subtly and I think it is my honest opinion That most of the people who have such an intense dislike for Evangelion Really honestly truly did not understand it and well not pay attention and don't know what it was about.
Scott: I think that a big part of the Evangelion that hurts a lot of people is that you know You really really really more so than a lot of other things I could think of it.
Scott: Let's say you have to pay attention With your conscious brain to every moment of it.
Scott: There are significant significant things where if you miss them You won't know what the hell's going on.
Scott: that will happen in like a second real quick like someone will say something like oh such-and-such or something will be in like the corner of a frame and You know the the.
Scott: that shot will be on screen for maybe five seconds.
Scott: And if you didn't see it, you're missing something major in the show and when people talk about it later You'll be like what the hell are they talking about?
Scott: You have to pay attention to every single word and every single thing you see.
Scott: and Even you know I paid really close attention and there are even some things where I had to rewind a little bit because I know I missed something.
Scott: And if you don't do that, I can understand why you wouldn't get the show or think it was so great because you didn't see it.
Rym: But even that's it.
Rym: No, no see because even then even if you don't understand all those kind of you know What was instrumentality and what exactly was happening?
Rym: That's not the point of the show.
Rym: I mean that's I think that's what really trips people up that the show was a bait-and-switch.
Rym: It started as this monster of the week show got a bunch of people watching it and bit by bit That's all stripped away like an onion and then at the end you left with nothing and the last two episodes very literally Sit you down and say look none of that bullshit mattered at all.
Rym: Here's what this show was about.
Rym: and what it was about was brilliant And I think the way it was portrayed in the end was great.
Rym: And I think a lot of people just they didn't see the forest for the trees They saw that end and they didn't think about what that meant about solipsism about identity about Psychosis about you know humanity they thought.
Rym: but what happened to the giant robots?
Scott: Yeah, because they were only understanding the show on a surface level and they were just.
Scott: you know And it's.
Scott: it's not hard to understand how you could enjoy the show on the surface level because the show is I mean You know people always talk about.
Scott: you know things being deep or things being shallow right and in reality at least according to me If you give something can only be enjoyed on the deep level But on the surface level it's crap.
Scott: or if something on the surface level is great, but has no depth to it That's both crap.
Scott: good things are good from top to bottom and Evangelion is good from top to bottom.
Scott: that surface level robot show.
Scott: that's in the beginning right.
Scott: fighting the monsters is One of the best surface level robot shows ever easily, but
Rym: at the same time I think a lot of people they get hung up on very little details about the show like they see something like they really wonder About these things and they care so much about the minute Fanboy details of the show that as a result.
Rym: They can't see the wholeness of the work.
Rym: They get so zoomed in about what.
Rym: why did the guy in the back of sale?
Rym: This the reason to the other guy who said this man what exactly was the room of golf?
Rym: and oh my god Kabbalah Kabbalah.
Scott: many shows and many books and many movies like to do a thing where they They they let you know that a secret exists.
Scott: They're like.
Scott: they'll say something you know that is sort of or they'll present an enigma of somewhere.
Scott: They'll they'll show.
Scott: they'll show you something visually But not tell you or explain what it was you just saw in any way.
Scott: They just show you something and then you're left thinking what was that?
Scott: They showed it to me.
Scott: It must be something.
Scott: what was it you know as a Chekhov's gun of some kind.
Scott: and Evangelion shows you more stuff without explaining what it is right away.
Scott: then Think about how many things it's like three or four things so far.
Scott: where I've said it does it more than anything else.
Scott: right Evangelion is harder better faster stronger than all the rest in every way But at the same show has a lot of secrets but show does something really.
Rym: Here's kind of the important part of what it is that makes Ava good.
Rym: a lot of shows that try to be deep Though it shows that people accused of being pretentious Sometimes are and the reason they are is that they don't actually have a lot to say or they can't say what they want to Say.
Rym: well, so they will hide behind layers of obscurity.
Rym: They will make things obtuse on purpose and they'll like they'll flash things on screen That just confuse you and then there was no way you could have figured them out.
Rym: But I'll say this if you watch Ava and you're reasonably intelligent and you pay attention You just and I mean pay attention to a reasonable level not even to the Scott level.
Rym: if you never rewind back You just watch the show with your attention You will get 95% of what happened and you will be able to understand the wholeness of the show.
Scott: I was incredibly surprised upon my most recent watching how many of the secrets are just Plainly said exactly what the secret is.
Scott: They just come out and say it.
Scott: There was a whole episode where they basically tell you the past of everything right where they show you.
Scott: You know all the adults and they were kids and everything.
Scott: and I'm like, I totally forgot that episode even existed.
Scott: But the episode basically tells you everything.
Scott: it just spells it out and spills the beans right there in plain English And I was left wondering like hi I wonder why people always thought that the show is so hard to figure out.
Scott: they're pretty much telling you everything.
Scott: There are even early episodes where they just come out with stuff like oh, yeah this by the way You know, I always thought the reveal of the you know, Ava's being you know Biological was in.
Scott: you know that later episode where Ava zero one goes crazy.
Scott: Episode two they reveal their biological because the armor falls off at Ava one's face and it's got like the crazy jaw in there.
Rym: All right, speaking of that.
Rym: I think we should talk a little bit.
Rym: spelled out the Specific things like why we say this.
Rym: cuz I mean we can't go into every detail.
Rym: someday I want to do a clip panel where I show these things because I went to this great lecture at Emily's school.
Rym: you know NYU.
Rym: a while ago in the the professor did a lecture about citizen Kane and What he did is he would show like he'd say, you know The show did this symbolism and then he would show you all the scenes where it was done.
Rym: then he'd say It's poignant and relevant because they use these camera angles to do this effect.
Rym: and then he'd show you the scenes and he'd say any.
Rym: Look at that.
Rym: Look how the camera is on this scene But it's focused on this character and not this character.
Rym: the focus of the lens is on this background character.
Rym: Why because of XYZ?
Rym: and then he would back up all these points.
Rym: You could do a series of lectures on Ava and I I'm going to say this I believe that Ava is so well put together that it would handily stand up to that level of I guess dissection and that level of analysis by PhDs in film.
Rym: Easily I'm not even like a Contest and I would love to see someone like that Analyze Ava that way partly because I don't think I have the time or the effort or the knowledge to pull it off.
Rym: But like what does Ava do like?
Rym: I want to talk a little bit about sound Ava's soundtrack and when I wrote no that soundtrack sound scape Is amazing.
Rym: well because it's not just the music the music is very important.
Rym: notice how the music Changes throughout the show.
Rym: there are themes in the show like the Happy misato theme the everyone's hanging out.
Rym: You know using that one Songs appear they have like characters have light motifs, and they come and go.
Rym: but yeah a lot of those light motifs Disappear.
Rym: the tone of the show Changes as it goes on and if you went through the show like there you can point out the exact moment I guess where the music died where the laughter died where you hear a song and see a scene and you could say Definitively that music is never played again.
Rym: a scene like that never happens again.
Rym: in fact There's a point at which you can say there is not a single joke Nor is there a moment of levity of any kind.
Rym: from this point forward until the end of the show.
Rym: This was the last moment you could smile.
Scott: This was the last joke early on in the show.
Scott: Right it's you know even though there's some weird stuff going on fighting aliens chance at the end of the world weird stuff right?
Scott: There's some jokes.
Scott: you've got misato getting drunk acting silly Asek and Shinji Bicker with each other and Shinji fighting with each other that episode where they do the music and they basically play DDR And that episode is directed by the guy who directed Fullmetal Alchemist by the way.
Rym: yes And that episode and you can sort of tell but that episode stands out as being amazing.
Rym: and all these things.
Rym: the show Starts out with a like you know 40% humor, and then you know 60% everything else voice.
Scott: It's not humor fun It's you know it's it.
Scott: There's sort of normal everyday anime kind of stuff going on some of the time Maybe 30 40 percent of the time even when poignant thing happened.
Rym: things happen.
Rym: There is a little bit of levity.
Rym: You know.
Rym: you know.
Rym: it's kind of the idea that The show builds up tension, and then there is release and it builds up tension And then there's release.
Rym: But the show does something clever and I could point to a thousand examples of this where In the beginning the show builds up say five tension points And then eventually you know it drops excited like opening parentheses and closing parentheses.
Rym: when you're writing code It'll open five then close to that open one more, but then it closes them all again you get release But as the show goes on it all it'll start and like episodes will end Without all the tension being released.
Rym: and then the next episode like more attention is introduced But even less is released, and there's a point at which they just stop releasing.
Rym: like seriously I mean Scott says that but no literally there's a point in the show at which There is no more release at all until the last until the last One minute and five seconds of the show give or take.
Rym: like up until that point There are like a six episodes fan where there is no release at all.
Scott: Yeah, it's like oh fight a nasty robot get freaked out.
Scott: Oh, but we're now we're in school.
Rym: all right all right Get freaked out not even be happy.
Rym: I mean remember when Shinji stops He kills karo.
Rym: you know the lad that the second to last the last angel whatever, but he feels bad about it.
Rym: He wins he kills it the next.
Rym: you know the next scene that you see is not hooray It's Shinji saying I should have died it shouldn't have been him.
Rym: I feel nothing.
Rym: the world is dead.
Scott: basically He starts.
Scott: they start carrying over The you know the craziness of the previous episodes into the next one, but like it's not just you know early on It's like okay.
Scott: They carry over episode one into episode two okay, but then as you go on it is Monster of the week and the monster is only there for the week, and then once they get rid of the monster You know it's like okay.
Scott: Whoo we beat that mod.
Scott: later in the show the monsters are Well You know Ray gets Ray gets injured she remains injured for a significant amount of time.
Scott: Shinji gets sucked into that weird other dimension.
Scott: He's fucked up for like two episodes, but it's not just that then asagum And she's fucked up.
Scott: She's fucked up for the entire rest of the show.
Scott: He's done, but here's the thing.
Rym: the show like I was gonna say it's kind of cliche.
Rym: You know the monsters remain, but no the monsters remain because they're in the heads of the characters.
Rym: But you've seen the end of the show, and I think it's safe to say the monsters are the characters.
Rym: Yeah, it's like the characters themselves are it?
Rym: and the show just like you know that scene where Shinji says I should have died not Him and there's no release of the tension.
Rym: even then what does the Misato say?
Rym: she doesn't say it's all right She doesn't comfort Shinji.
Rym: She basically says no you were right to kill him, and then he says You're cold.
Rym: You're a cold person, and then it ends There's no release at all and the show starts getting uncomfortable to watch.
Rym: and part of that uncomfortableness, I think is because as Kind of the world is stripped away and as the show becomes more and more about the characters and their motivations because there's nothing left in the show You start to get uncomfortable because you identify with the characters, and you don't want to because you hate them.
Scott: Well you have to be uncomfortable in that kind of situation because you're in the city where the giant horrible aliens that no one Understands are attacking this spot for some reason right trying to do and if they win It's the end of the world.
Scott: You're a very small group of people the only people who can possibly save the world and everyone else.
Scott: everyone You know you know which is pretty much the happy people that you know were somewhat normal at least all moved away.
Scott: There's no one there.
Scott: You're all alone in this horrible base.
Scott: You know these horrible robots and machines, and it's quiet and scary and mysterious, and you know you're just Waiting away the days until either you lose the world ends or you save it.
Scott: And then what you're fucked up from the experience.
Scott: Even then it's.
Scott: it's even worse than waiting in the mall for the zombies to eat.
Rym: everybody get back to the structure because again that Idea is not new and not special in and of itself.
Rym: But Ava just does it so well because they make you feel like the people there.
Scott: I mean if you watch Dawn of the Dead you know I don't really feel so much like the people in the mall.
Scott: You know as much as maybe I could in Ava.
Rym: well I think I feel worse than what it is is they force it on you in a very subtle way.
Rym: I mean the beginning of the show and watch.
Rym: Notice how background characters are rarely drawn in a generic style.
Rym: They're often the background characters you see in the beginning of the show are often unique Characters.
Rym: someone pointedly drew them all to be different.
Rym: to stand out is different and The show goes a long way for one to show that all of humanity is kind of working together But - it goes out of its way to show you all the side characters you see all like.
Rym: There's a scene where they're like putting together in an early episode one of the plugs to plug into an Ava for something and They show you like 60 or 70 engineers and scientists and workmen and laborers and janitors all over the place Working on this.
Rym: you see all these people Everywhere you come to the city you see cars you see people in shop.
Scott: the episode.
Rym: This is the important thing.
Rym: you overhear a lot of conversations of side characters.
Rym: people are talking speaking lines.
Rym: That totally goes away bit by bit And then you realize towards the end of the show that you haven't seen anyone at all But a very tiny subset of main characters for much of the.
Scott: yeah The episode of the power goes out right and Gendo is there with all these engineers like you know turning cranks on everything to make everything work is with all the manual backups and everything Later on.
Scott: it's basically like six people at a computer, and there's no one else around do.
Scott: they walk around this gigantic Gigantic gigantic underground base and early in the show it'd be like they'd walk around the base And there'd be other people walking around the base opening the doors up and down the escalators.
Scott: now They're always alone in the elevator whenever they're in an elevator.
Scott: if someone else comes in the elevator It's always another one of the characters.
Scott: you only ever see the characters.
Scott: everyone else is gone and even when People there are people who aren't the characters that come in you know the main characters that do come into play at that point in The show.
Scott: there's an episode where you know Oscar runs away and someone goes to and they like UN or some spy guys go and find Her.
Rym: but notice how now these care.
Scott: They don't show you that guy They're all faceless there.
Rym: if they have a voice is completely off-screen.
Scott: you see his shadow And you only see Asuka and even the guys in sele.
Scott: they become sound only and you never see them again.
Rym: that I mean.
Rym: That is one of those brilliant things.
Rym: as to what makes Ava like the subtlety that is there I mean look early on.
Rym: you know sele is not there when the sele got the old man Who by the way if you're if you're looking to read things into the show?
Rym: They're Jewish.
Rym: now seriously think about that for a minute and think about Judeo-Christian mythology, but I'll get back to that later, so But they meet via these video conferences and the way those scenes are put together amazing.
Rym: But then as Scott pointed out as all the character all the people who aren't the main characters all the excuses Every excuse the characters have to not face the monsters inside themselves to not face themselves To pretend that other people are around and therefore they can just keep living their lives.
Rym: They won't have to confront everything that they really are because there's no one left in the world.
Rym: There's at that very pointed moment where you see sele again, and there is no longer sele.
Rym: It is just big black monoliths sound only you stop seeing their faces, and that's not just allegory It's not just color It's not just this subtle shift toward alienation and toward forcing people who are alone to confront themselves.
Rym: It has very literal meaning as to what's going on at the end of the show.
Rym: Yes, they are they.
Scott: what are they doing?
Scott: Yeah, why is sele sound only?
Scott: they were holograms before.
Scott: what happened?
Scott: It's because they went somewhere where they can only have sound and there's no cameras to you know make the holograms any.
Rym: now if you pay Attention to what's going on in the show you know this is gonna be.
Scott: they just tell you straight up where they went.
Rym: yes Notice how they were creating the Ava series.
Rym: It's obvious like it's really obvious that they are all in the Ava series for whatever thing that is They're gonna do at the end of the world.
Scott: because remember you know sele is talking about how they really want to finish this.
Scott: you Know production series of Ava's you know yada yada yada And you know notice that if you ever have watched you know you're not gonna know this because you're not talking about episode the alternate App air right, but yes
Rym: because remember They
Scott: TV show They're piloting that production series.
Scott: That's where they went.
Scott: They're all inside Ava's elsewhere, and that's why there's no holograms of them.
Rym: But along with that a sense of alienation doesn't you know?
Rym: I'd mentioned the soundscape and then I left it.
Rym: But aside from the light motifs and the music and the wonderful use they use the way they use Major minor or dissonant or augmented chords as their own kind of like like there are the light motifs But within those songs these different chords really jarringly like set the mood in different ways.
Rym: But it's also the sound effects.
Scott: you know that sound of the cicadas That you hear people don't really I didn't catch this until the most recent watching right.
Scott: But there was a second impact in that you know way back when right.
Scott: the second impact was you know giant explosion in Antarctica.
Scott: most people on earth think it was a. you know they tell them the story that it was a meteor that hit Nervous.
Rym: it wasn't basically Misato's dad who did that basically yeah?
Scott: And you know Antarctica melted basically and as you know say global warming times a billion.
Scott: And it's always summer.
Scott: and the thing is when I watched it back in the day I sort of missed that fact that it was always summer.
Scott: It's not it's easy to miss that but if you're a Japanese person You know cicadas are big there in the summer.
Scott: so hearing cicadas all the time Constant reminder that it's summer constant reminder that you know there's the worst global warming.
Scott: Antarctica melted.
Scott: There was a huge like you know pre apocalypse many years ago And this is still always summer.
Rym: this is used to great effect I mean they taught.
Rym: they mentioned briefly later the room of golf which is this old like Jewish Jewish mysticism thing and there's a lot of ways to read into it.
Rym: But it's the idea that in the heavens I guess technically in like the stakes like one of the specific heavens that I don't know a lot about this stuff, but there is the idea that all souls originate from this place and The Messiah the end of the world cannot come and will not come until that room is empty until the last soul is born into the world.
Rym: and there's a separate myth part of that that the sounds of grasshoppers or the sounds of certain insects or the sounds of certain, but you know things in the environment are the sound that you hear when souls come out of this room or in this room.
Rym: and The cicadas are used in this very subtle way to allude to that.
Rym: But they're also used as a light motif because you hear them in the background in certain kinds of scenes Usually to express alienation emptiness loneliness the fact that the world is empty and dying and there's nothing left.
Rym: Yeah, and then there's more to it than that.
Rym: There are a lot of subtle little references where someone I think miss out.
Rym: Oh, you know they say there's a very there's like a 0% chance that this is going to succeed Or a very low chance that this thing will succeed.
Rym: and Masato says yeah, but there's a chance.
Rym: It'll snow tomorrow, and if you didn't Remember or realize or think that it's summer all the time that it's never going to snow again That statement just sounds like yeah, and pigs will fly.
Rym: But it's actually.
Rym: there's a lot more to it, and it's subtle and meaningful, and it's really easy to miss that stuff.
Rym: But I don't want to you know go into every detail because I don't want to spend the whole show pointing them all out.
Rym: But the show is full of references like that.
Scott: Yeah, and because you know it's not I mean it's not the real world there Aren't really giant aliens and robots and all sorts of crazy shit like that.
Scott: But it's other than that.
Scott: It's you know real human beings on earth in Japan and Tokyo number whatever right?
Scott: so you three or four right?
Scott: Cuz you know you can never get enough Tokyo's And you know the things that they talk about are plain English.
Scott: It's not like loaded with proper nouns as much as you know say the prince of nothing is.
Scott: And it's real easy for you know things they say For do you interpret them as per the real world because using real word real world words.
Scott: But really in that universe which you know they don't go and explain like all the details the universe like a lot of fantasy Kind of books will do you know.
Scott: so you'll miss out that it actually means something different in that world because of the way things Are and because of the situation they're in.
Scott: and if you didn't pay attention You don't get it, and you think they said something else that they didn't say.
Rym: But I want to go back a little bit because Scott mentioned the episode where the powers out and everyone's kind of scrapping together.
Rym: This episode has perhaps my favorite comedic moment in the entire show because you know we're talking about all the reasons.
Rym: the show was good Indeed and like how well put together it is, but the shallow parts are really well put together, too.
Rym: I mean the fight scenes are amazingly well choreographed and everything is great, but that scene where you know There's no air conditioning.
Rym: It's hot.
Rym: It's dark.
Rym: There's no power.
Rym: Everyone's in the uniforms you know doing their work and Someone remarks that yeah, we have to.
Rym: you know it's hot and this sucks But we have to pull through.
Rym: look at them.
Rym: look how cool and collected they are just cuts up to.
Rym: you see Gando and Futsuki.
Rym: Gando's sitting there with his you know that pose that he always has and he looks totally cool and collected And he's not showing any discomfort at all.
Rym: and he's standing there, and he's just like they're in charge.
Rym: They're in command and It cuts very briefly to a back shot of them And you see that both of them are in their uniforms from the waist up But they totally have their pants off and their feet are in buckets of ice water.
Scott: yeah, it's a house good stuff.
Rym: and or like when they get the the super sniper rifle to take out that early angel and Basically misato shows up at that research lab, and she's like yeah, we're here to take all your shit.
Rym: And then she says all right ray and Ray just rips the roof off the off the stupid warehouse and reaches in and they don't show you any of this.
Rym: But she says now be careful.
Rym: That's a incredibly delicate piece of machinery.
Rym: and you immediately hear nothing But like 20 seconds of crashing and horrible destruction as she rips this thing out of the building.
Rym: And I just thought that was really funny.
Scott: It is really funny and in the episode with the laser even right It's like the show is all about the gravity of everything, you know It's like we're giving you all the electricity in Japan to fire this laser Literally literally.
Scott: and you know at first, you know You can interpret that as sort of like a silly thing that happens in robot shows.
Scott: But in this show because it's not presented and you know Like it's just the animation style of it alone does a good enough job of you know Not making it seem like a messenger.
Rym: Z How much of that episode is dedicated to shots of thousands and thousands of people doing work.
Rym: they cut to all the infrastructure the amazing like you step back and think how Absolutely amazing and awe-inspiring it would be for humans to pull something like that off the sheer number of people the man-hours the effort and the fact that it barely works and it.
Rym: The show does such a good job of expressing to you the gravity of the situation and it does this time and time again And he uses amazing just like shots and sounds and techniques to like convey it in every possible way where you can't miss it.
Scott: And in the pad the power goes out.
Scott: episode again, you know, everything has a manual backup.
Scott: It's so like perfect every you know every single, you know You look around a lot of mecha design right and a lot of mecha design is lots and lots of little crazy Details all over it, you know, like little hatches and doors and things like that, right and Ava The mechanical design has some of that going on, but really actually all those little details, you know Usually you'll see like a robot have like a million things all over it.
Scott: Most of them are just decoration.
Scott: and Ava all the million things everywhere, right?
Scott: It's actually stuff that you can sort of.
Scott: you sat there you can be like, oh, that's that and that's that and you know They actually draw this stuff like it's gonna be used and it is used.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean the shifts the difference between Gundam seed and the fire the low and greens and they basically just throw in proper nouns and they make them self consistent But it doesn't really matter.
Rym: but in Ava all these details that they present to you are Self-consistent and matter on at least a shallow level.
Rym: but in many cases on a much deeper level - on a metaphorical level Not just mecha design but characters - yeah There's just there's so much there.
Rym: I mean I could spend forever talking about specific scenes.
Rym: that like really moved me Like I think the scene this scene every time I see it.
Rym: It gives me.
Rym: it gives me chills.
Rym: There are two scenes more so than anything in the show that just like I get a chill when I see them and one I really want to mention is Just remember the angel that actually gets into the command center.
Rym: Shinji doesn't want to pallet the robot it breaks down the wall.
Rym: Misato is standing there face-to-face with this angel.
Rym: It is about to kill her.
Rym: It is about to kill everyone.
Rym: the world is going to end it is over and Shinji who didn't want to fight Suddenly finds the will after that again Amazing conversation with Kaji and the watermelons and I could go on and on about Oh Kaji in his water.
Scott: Oh my god, but Kaji's like one of the best parts of the show period.
Scott: but
Rym: the scene where it breaks in and the angel this Alien thing lumbers forward and looks them in the eye and Masato looks it in the eye and especially knowing what she went through as the child and what she is and why she's the way she is and the the amount of hate that is in her heart for these angels and just that whole scene and the music and the sounds and Everything is amazing.
Rym: And I literally like I get a chill every time I see that scene.
Rym: I think it's beautiful.
Rym: Yeah You have any Eva scenes.
Scott: Eva scenes equally big.
Rym: equal chill is when the Ava goes berserk near the end of the show and everyone finds out what it is as it Eats that angel and incorporates the s2 engine into itself.
Scott: Yeah, that's a pretty difficult scene.
Rym: Yes But the partly because the sounds the Ava like the sounds the Ava makes are somewhat like they're disturbed.
Rym: They're really disturbing They really really get under your skin and they're frightening.
Rym: and they set the scene so well.
Scott: Things that always gets me is the you know, the.
Scott: there's the episode where Shinji sort of he gets sent like the What's it called like the other dimension where they fuck they call it?
Rym: Oh, oh, yes the sure Dirac space.
Scott: He gets stuck in a sea of Dirac Right and then he comes back and like you can't get out of the robot He's stuck in there and they're like, he's not in there.
Scott: Yeah, it's just his suit floating in the in.
Scott: Oh, I got to talk about.
Scott: I can't not talk about that.
Scott: What's it LHC?
Scott: What's the LCL?
Scott: LCL god damn it.
Rym: this is another example of people.
Scott: This is an example of pay the fuck attention, right?
Scott: The whole show is about LCL.
Rym: LCL is the show.
Scott: LCL is the show.
Scott: if you don't realize that LCL is the show you weren't paying attention Right.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So LCL is based on and I'm just gonna tell it to you straight in case you weren't paying attention Right.
Scott: and you've watched the show recently LCL.
Scott: when they get in the in the Ava right the suit fills up with this yellow goop Right, and then somehow they can breathe in it and it works.
Rym: It's also the reason the Ava's work, right?
Scott: LCL is basically like this chemical that is like, you know how metal conducts electricity.
Rym: Well, LCL conducts souls basically, and it's a cross between like.
Rym: I mean metaphorically and literally in the show and I mean that specific metaphorically and On the surface level it's like a cross between primordial soup and amniotic fluid.
Scott: Yep, and if you don't notice when you when they're walking around nerve and there's different doors that they open and things You'll see stuff like LCL pool fat this way LCL factory and they show you this way We're like.
Rym: miss Ritsuko was clearly working with the LCL.
Scott: She was diving in it Yeah, and you look down, you know in the.
Scott: I guess that's in the movie.
Scott: But now in terminal dogma you see this at the at the bottom bottom bottom, right?
Scott: Bottom is terminal dog.
Scott: Where Adam?
Rym: Oh, I'm sorry Lilith.
Scott: Yes crucified Adam slash Lilith is stuck on the cross with or without the lancey vlogging news, right?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Just the whole thing is just this endless sea of LCL.
Scott: That's what they make all of it.
Rym: Look at it.
Rym: All right, the.
Rym: it is crucified there LCL is coming out of it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Where do you what do you think?
Rym: they're getting?
Rym: the LCL.
Scott: and here's one more.
Scott: This is from the movie, but I can't not say it right at the end of the movie.
Scott: It's famous because of the part where everyone dies.
Scott: Everyone sort of it just explodes right like boom, but it's not just they explode not exploding.
Scott: They're basically Turning into LCL.
Scott: They're not exploding with blood everywhere again loading into yellow goo.
Rym: Literally, literally it is.
Rym: they are LCL because we are LCL.
Scott: So that's how the human instrumentality project which you know combining all human beings into one being LCL is the mechanism for that.
Scott: everyone turns into LCL and there's a giant pool of yellow goop Literally giant pool of yellow goop and everyone's soul is transmitted in the yellow goop one pool.
Scott: now We're all one soul.
Scott: We're one giant primordial ooze.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's it's literally that it's not.
Scott: that's not some metaphor.
Scott: That's what it is.
Scott: Everyone turns in the yellow goop.
Scott: That's a big pool of yellow goop.
Rym: But anyway, let's save until the very end of the show because we can give a very concise explanation.
Rym: Didn't get it?
Rym: Oh, you know what happened because I think it's pretty obvious but it warrants discussion.
Rym: But the scene you were talking about because that is a very powerful scene.
Scott: Mmm.
Scott: All right completely forgot.
Scott: Where are you stuck in the Sea of Dirac?
Scott: and then they can't get him out.
Scott: and then there's all this whole thing where it's Like, you know, yeah There was someone else that we tried to get out and it totally didn't work and that was Shinji's mom and whatnot.
Scott: And you know whatever.
Scott: and then like at the end of that episode he like Pops out and Then the episodes over and it's like ah plus it's not that the popping out that gets you It's the episode over right away.
Scott: It's a lot like that episode of Eska flown a where the robots bleeding and then over right away a new episode plus.
Rym: That scene is so I mean the show does a really good job of having characters express real raw Painful to watch.
Rym: emotion.
Rym: I mean the way Misato reacts to Shinji reappearing and the way she reacts to the fact that she thought he was gone.
Rym: That is some powerful stuff and even more powerful the scene still to this day gets to me when Misato Finds out that Kaji is dead.
Rym: Mm-hmm and the way and how and not not just That how she finds out and that she finds out and not just the last words in that answering machine because I choked up I mean when the first time I saw Eva and then
Scott: she listened the answering machine again
Rym: over and over those words, you know I'll say the words.
Rym: I should have said you wait.
Rym: I'll admit the first time I saw the show.
Scott: I cried Really hard at that scene, but there's another thing you might miss is uh, you know, the the pill that goes on there Yes, and they reference that multiple times.
Rym: But anyway, that scene is so powerful and it's not just her reaction and how visceral it is but the fact that it's also so important to the show because She you're watching the show you feel like shit.
Rym: You feel terrible.
Rym: You're incredibly incredibly You.
Rym: it's awkward and difficult to watch someone in the depths of so much anguish and despair And yet so that they're they're not even you know They're acting totally whack like a person does.
Rym: but at the same time now it cuts to Shinji and he hears this and there's that scene where he opened.
Rym: he sees he opens his door and he sees her there and he hears her and He's like you.
Rym: now you're him you identify with him Observing this and he cannot deal with it any better than you can.
Rym: and he does not go to say anything and he just he Turns away from it and he he can't even muster any Amounts of sympathy like he can't do anything for her.
Rym: He's so separate and cut off from her.
Rym: and that scene Really that scene kind of encapsulates can't place everything that Ava was really about.
Scott: Yeah I mean a lot of shows, you know more shallow shows, you know, and that's what they are is more shallow shows, right?
Scott: It's people have predictable, you know simple emotional response to things.
Scott: someone dies We all cry, you know We win we all cheer.
Rym: and some shows really manipulate Fullmetal Alchemist when they killed a certain character Really just manipulated you and milked it, but it didn't really mean that much in the in the wider scheme of the show.
Rym: No, it was just a sad scene to make you feel bad.
Scott: But the thing is in the real world with real people, you know Emotions aren't that simple.
Scott: people are fucked the fuck up and they do weird shit and they act in Completely irrational and screwed up ways.
Scott: and you know, it things are a lot more complex than that.
Scott: I just think you know having the you know, only like, you know a range of like, you know Six different distinct emotions and then each one like worried angry, you know sad.
Scott: No, the things are a lot weirder than that.
Scott: and Ava actually, you know I guess people in Ava are a little more crazy, but it's the end of the world.
Rym: What do you expect see at the same time though?
Rym: They really aren't in a lot of ways because they really kind of encapsulate the fundamental ideas and problems that all humans face.
Rym: the thing is because I mean Humans can deal with these problems much like in the show.
Rym: Notice how people the characters are dealing with these problems partly because there are a lot of other people around.
Rym: As the show goes on there aren't as many people around which means there is less.
Rym: there are less places They can go to hide from their own emotions There are less ways people can distract themselves and what's going on inside of themselves.
Scott: Yeah, no one's making you know, TV shows at the end of the world, you know I mean, I think there's a TV show that's on sort of earlier in the show.
Scott: You can see on some of the screens but later on, you know what she's got like his Walkman.
Scott: That's.
Scott: that's about it.
Rym: notice how he listens to the same couple of songs over and over and over again And they really use that.
Rym: Mckay that the these the scene the idea that he'll just keep looping the tape Over and over and over again.
Rym: It's just like one of his final refuges from himself.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: the point of all this is that The show does not just have all these amazing ideas and all these really well put together thoughts But that it expresses them in an Incredibly deep and well put together way and that the show from a technical perspective and from a kind of look at it like how does it present its message is Beautiful and amazing and I can't imagine Someone like just not getting it or not feeling it or not understanding the emotion and how well it's put together.
Scott: Yeah, and that's not even counting the fact that you know The animation quality was a million times better than anything else at the time and the animation stands up.
Scott: Things today, you know The sound quality was better than things.
Scott: everything about the production of it was better than the vast majority of anime productions Discounting only things like Satoshi kon miyazaki movies Akira, etc.
Rym: but of course The real and I don't want to talk about this forever because we've gone on for a while and partly I just I want to express You know without having to worry about spoilers how good of a show I think this is now meaningful it is.
Rym: but What was the show really about?
Rym: because remember this show very famously Starts out as a robot show those 24 episodes sits you down and says alright not gonna show you what happened Doesn't matter.
Rym: Here's what I want you and I really honestly I'll say this again I just a few hours ago watched the last two episodes of Shin Seiki Evangelion again.
Scott: I watched them a few weeks ago pre-pack, so I don't have them as quiet as clear in the mind, but they're they're clear enough.
Rym: People who say those episodes were a cop-out or who say that, you know the show it was just a total, you know Cop-out.
Rym: they could have done it better.
Rym: You're wrong.
Rym: It is my opinion that you're wrong.
Rym: those episodes I'm honestly going to say this and they're not pretentious They're brilliant.
Scott: Well, first of all, right my memory before rewatching the show was that those episodes were like, you know The show was normal and then suddenly existential and weird.
Scott: that's not true at all.
Scott: The show gradually led into that.
Scott: very very well, you know They have that whole part where it's like.
Scott: you'll see like a vertical line squiggling and someone will talk then a horizontal squiggly line and someone else will talk then like the square and someone else will talk or the Whole analogy where Shinji is free.
Rym: What is freedom?
Scott: Oh Freedom.
Scott: you go back, you know to episode, you know 15 and forward.
Scott: they do all that shtick more and more and more as the show goes on You know, there's less and less just watching what's happening and more and more that weird stuff.
Scott: And then at the end they just do full-on.
Rym: Well plus the pace of the show gets more and more frantic.
Rym: Escaflowne did this very well, too.
Rym: And then towards the end of the show like the focus narrows the focus narrows not just as a show but in the characters minds in your minds and everywhere.
Rym: and it gets up to this.
Rym: fevers pay feverish pace of.
Rym: We are fighting the Angels because we don't want the end of the world to happen.
Rym: and then at the end of the 24th episode They start, you know, they did it.
Rym: they did it.
Rym: they stopped the last angel.
Rym: it's over they won.
Rym: Now what?
Rym: and you realize that the show's focus has narrowed and everyone, you know, what's ausgas deal?
Rym: I'm nothing without Ava.
Rym: What Shinji?
Rym: I'm nothing Corollary, I'm nothing without Ava.
Rym: Every everyone in the show the only characters left.
Rym: There was nothing left for them, but Ava but fighting but fighting the angels.
Scott: Early on in the show.
Scott: they these people actually have a lot going on, you know in their lives, you know, they got school They got you know work.
Scott: They got stuff, you know, go, you know, they're going out to dinner You know all kinds of stuff later in the show.
Scott: They got nothing except saving the world.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Whatever a key see a character if they're not actively, you know fighting an angel off.
Scott: They're sitting around going.
Rym: But no the technical aspect of this the reason this works and the reason I say the end is not a cop-out But brilliant is that there was really no other way to end that show and it follows right along with the previous episodes.
Rym: it's basically the show did end in episode 24. the plot ended and the show had gotten you to the point where There was no more plot.
Rym: There was no more possibility of plot There was no more possibility of moving forward for any character in that show or for the show or for you as a viewer.
Rym: and Thus you think what now and I think the show did such a beautiful job of doing that.
Rym: I mean, I don't want to sit and you know go step by step through the last two episodes, but It's brilliant.
Rym: They just sit the characters down and ask them.
Rym: Why did you do this?
Rym: We have come this far.
Rym: you saved the world Why.
Rym: and they would say why.
Rym: and then they would ask the same question very Socratic, you know Why do you pilot Ava?
Rym: Because I want to.
Rym: why do you pilot Ava?
Rym: because I want to.
Rym: why do you pilot it?
Rym: pilot Ava?
Rym: Because because people tell me to.
Rym: why do you pilot Ava?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: and it's like all these characters being forced to To realize what they are because humans lie to themselves all the time and I've seen very little Literature movies books films anything that does such a good job of Driving that point into your head so well and so subtly and yet at the same time It's subtle, but it's not.
Rym: it's subtle and that most people watching you don't realize what it's trying to make.
Rym: you admit What is really trying to make the characters admit but at the same time it's being very blunt about it.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I know but I won't admit it.
Rym: What do you want?
Scott: the greatest part that I think is at the beginning of episode 26, I believe if I remember correctly They're like he'd be pretty much comes out and says in plain English.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Look I Wish I had the exact subtitles to just read out loud.
Scott: He's like we want to explore this idea and answer this question, right?
Scott: But we don't have time to answer this question for all the characters.
Scott: So we're just gonna look at Shinji.
Scott: It's a just says that that's what the narrator says.
Scott: that at the beginning.
Scott: episode 26 Yes, and people are confused about what the episode is about.
Scott: He just told you in plain English Oh my gosh, and then they do it and then the show is over.
Rym: and I mean really the show deals with a lot of fundamental philosophical issues and you know What what am I and you think you know, what do you what think?
Rym: ask yourself this question?
Rym: What are you and this you know, all the ideas of solipsism?
Rym: and what is the soul and what is the mind?
Rym: and what what am I and what are other people and what do I exist for?
Rym: and These are questions that a lot of people don't deal with very well.
Rym: They avoid when they think about it and the show Ava Does an incredibly good job I think of addressing these issues in an intellectual and philosophical way and also in a clever and accessible way.
Rym: Mmm, I think the show says what it says Incredibly well.
Scott: Oh here here.
Scott: I got I found the script online real quick.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: This is what the narrator says.
Scott: the beginning of episode 26 already.
Scott: if this isn't plain English and not weird I don't know what is.
Scott: it was 2016 ad.
Scott: that's not hard to understand.
Scott: the thing that people lost in other words the compensation the Complimentation of the mind has begun.
Rym: God instrumentality, right?
Scott: However, there is not enough time to describe the entire process.
Scott: We've only got like a 20-minute episode here.
Rym: We can't show you Every single soul on all of Earth combining into one pile of yellow goop now at the same time for anyone who says those Episodes are crap cop-outs because of no budget Watching those episodes again.
Rym: I want to point out that while all this is going on He shows you Masato dead shot.
Rym: She was shot and she is dead.
Rym: It shows Ritsuko shot dead and then it immediately shows Ritsuko and Masato talking to each other.
Scott: Yep Anyway, I'm not done yet.
Scott: Therefore we will examine the Complimentation right the instrumentality of the mind of a single boy named Ikari Shinji.
Scott: So what he's telling you here is it couldn't be more plain Every mind on earth combined into one which was the instrumentality project.
Scott: So that's that's six billion plus.
Scott: I don't know how many people were alive in the year 2016 when the room of golf was empty, right?
Scott: Every single soul and all of the entire earth went through an experience of combining into one right and In order to tell the complete story We would have to tell you all six or seven billion stories of every single thing that all those souls felt and went through.
Scott: But we can't do that and look 20 minute TV show and look at all the like glimpses that it gives you.
Scott: Yep So we're just gonna show you What happened to Shinji during this process and that way you'll get a better understanding of it.
Scott: because you know what if we actually Just had a camera looking at the world All you would see was a big pile of yellow group that you saw in the movies.
Scott: You don't know anything that's going on because there's no characters.
Scott: It's a big pile of yellow slime.
Rym: But I mean and look like they give you glimpses like that that amazing scene and the amazing voice acting where Masato You know, yeah the whole idea of the Hedgehog's dilemma and the AT field.
Rym: and then you know Near the end of the show when you find out what the AT field really is you know the boundary between people the reason we have the Hedgehog's dilemma the fact that Solipsistically no human being can ever share truly what they are with other human beings.
Rym: all that blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: Masato shows Masato desperately not wanting other people to see what was really in her heart and just horrified and afraid and crying and screaming because Shinji and Kenji and Fuyutsuki and Every single person in the world her father are seeing Everything that she is.
Rym: there are no secrets.
Rym: It's kind of like a god looking down on a two-dimensional world.
Rym: I mean think about that think about what instrumentality is the whole show is people unable to deal with each other people who because they cannot share the Solipsistic nature of their own heart and soul with other people are fundamentally isolated from each other By the AT field by humanity by the fact that we are individual souls The fact that everyone in the world now has no secrets and everyone is one soul and nothing is sacred Nothing is hidden.
Rym: that is frightening and horrifying and that is what people are going through in the end of Eva.
Rym: That is kind of the literal truth of what is happening.
Rym: Instrumentality succeeded.
Scott: there goes yeah, and you have these people who are so emotionally fucked up because they won't even like Talk to each other openly and honestly because they don't want anyone to know what they're really like on the inside.
Scott: So they're all putting on a show, you know, Asuka's putting on a show, you know being all strong and cool But really she's not.
Scott: she's crying about her, you know, bitch mom and whatnot.
Scott: But she acts all happy and bratty all the time and you know That the whole show is just.
Scott: all the characters act like that.
Scott: But then it's actually literal.
Rym: there's actually this field and we actually destroy all those fields and now you have to And people and you know one of the I could go on forever about like what the end of Ava means and solipsism and humanity.
Rym: But the criticism I hear most about the end of Evangelion is people will say it's pretentious It's a cop-out and it doesn't say anything that hasn't said before.
Rym: You know, what?
Rym: Very little that has ever been written or shown Says something that no one's ever said before.
Rym: You don't tell me that you're Gurren Lagann or your cowboy bebop said something unique and special.
Rym: But Ava is just saying things people said.
Scott: but yeah Well, I mean think of it.
Scott: pretty much every idea that there is to have was thought up by you know Philosophers in Greece and such a lot.
Rym: Anyway, that argument is bullshit.
Rym: Yeah, but second to that the argument the unstated argument the beg to question is that Ava does not say it.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: I'm not gonna mince words.
Rym: You're wrong.
Rym: Ava says this more eloquently than most have and more repetitively.
Rym: It says everything it says multiple times and it says it with such artistic grace and with such style.
Rym: and I got to admit I Will put the end of Ava.
Rym: and when I say the end I mean the clapping the suddenly the notice how the music in the background slowly fades in and it's you know the opening theme Cruel angels thesis.
Scott: Well, it's a piano version, right?
Rym: Yes, but it is that theme and you know the lyrics.
Scott: you've seen that opener 26 times man that you know, that song is a song I've heard a billion times in my life like a billion right and they play it all the time and anime Conventions and social nights and all sorts of things.
Scott: right and you know, it's a good song.
Scott: But I got tired of it after a while and it didn't really have anything for me.
Scott: Right when I started watching the show again, I would actually watch the opener Because you know, it's a good song, you know, you know, even though I heard it a million times.
Scott: It was getting a little old.
Scott: That song fucking pumps you the fuck up.
Scott: it's like oh shit and the thing is cruel.
Scott: angels thesis.
Rym: watch out This is a beautiful example of the show Making a point very very artistically.
Rym: I think those last few minutes of the last episode of Ava are some of the most well-constructed and subtle moments in any show I've ever seen.
Rym: and I Will say I think the end of Ava where the glass cracks and that music plays and ever, you know Amedetou, Amedetou, thank you is Right up there with the end of Cowboy Bebop.
Rym: It's it's amazing Absolutely amazing.
Rym: and think about all that's going on there Shinji.
Rym: He is brought to a head.
Rym: and the moment he's brought to a head.
Rym: He starts to talk He starts to take form, you know, all the things that you see all the imagery.
Rym: The imagery is very important and means a lot.
Rym: and then the music starts playing and the music is the opening scene.
Rym: The the music that you heard at the beginning of the show the very first thing about Ava that opening theme.
Rym: You know the lyrics at this point and now they're playing an instrumental version of the song But they're playing it in a different manner from for the instrumental version.
Rym: notice how despite the fact that the song is scary There's a lot of major chords.
Rym: It's a fairly upbeat melody.
Rym: and now you hear that.
Rym: and but when you see the opening You know the opener.
Rym: It's set with this very very disturbing imagery and the lyrics are Very very deep and not at all what you expect from this upbeat song.
Rym: But then now that you know what the show was saying You know what it's about and you hear this in the background just before that glass cracks the lyrics take out a whole different meaning and The show does that thing of.
Rym: it doesn't play the lyrics for you It doesn't beat it and show you the lyrics and make you say say what the lyrics are saying.
Rym: It plays the song quietly in the background and you yourself Think back and remember the song and you remember young ball who shines brighter than anyone else rise to become a legend and everything that that song was really about.
Rym: and Then that glass cracks.
Rym: and once again the first time I saw that I got choked up.
Scott: That is an amazing thing about just the name of the song right cruel angels Thesis.
Scott: that that's what the show is cruel angels.
Scott: and then a thesis boom.
Scott: How could you be right come on?
Rym: Well, I think I had more analysis than that.
Scott: Yeah, what you gonna do?
Scott: What you gonna do?
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I'm gonna say all my analysis.
Rym: But I Did I mean basically I'll put it this way.
Rym: I hear a lot of people talk a lot of hate about Evangelion.
Rym: I have never seen anyone put forth what I would consider an Intelligence and backed up argument.
Scott: Yeah, what is like?
Scott: what do people say?
Scott: They're like, it was right dangerous.
Scott: They don't actually have any specific arguments to back that up.
Scott: They'll just be like they'll say something vague right like Oh, it was trying to say all this stuff, but it was just confusing and weird.
Scott: Oh, it was just a crazy guy.
Scott: Oh, it was just this they don't actually specifically point out.
Scott: Well, you see this in the show was you know bad for this?
Scott: and this reason?
Scott: because if you actually looked at the show It's all good.
Scott: It's not anything bad.
Scott: You can say no.
Scott: Well, maybe this side.
Scott: It's not perfect.
Rym: No, it's not perfect, but nothing's perfect.
Rym: but I'll say this if You listen to this and it and you disagree with us and it's been a while since you've seen Ava
Scott: watch it again
Rym: watch Ava again because I Feel a lot more positively about the show having watched it again
Scott: Partly
Rym: because seeing it when you're young I guess maturity makes the show make a lot more sense.
Rym: Being older being wiser having lived longer Makes the show a lot more poignant because you've lived a lot.
Rym: You'll watch the show when you're 14, and I'm not like that but violin robots awesome when you're 25. when you're 35 you know you look back on your life while you're watching the show and you realize that While you can't identify with everything these kids.
Rym: do you can?
Rym: identify to a very very strong degree with a lot of the ideas that are presented in this show and a lot of the darkness and a lot of the feelings that the characters express and the ideas and the show is incredibly poignant and amazing.
Rym: and if you Watch Ava again, and you still think it's a bad show I defy you to argue that point at all.
Scott: Yeah, I who I who has actually tried to say I mean some people have said they don't like it or whatever They think it's.
Scott: you know way over hyped or something like that and you know what I think you're wrong.
Scott: Well the show does.
Scott: you know the show a lot of ways.
Scott: you know is there's a lot of people who are fans of it because they're fans of you know like Oscar and right hand ties biggest argument I hear against Ava is arguments against fanboys about Ava not arguments against Ava arguments against fanboys and their interpretations.
Rym: Yeah, forget interpretations.
Rym: look at cinematography look at soundtrack look at message look at artistry.
Rym: the show is so amazingly put together.
Scott: There is a whole phenomenon of people who their opinion.
Scott: They can't separate their opinion of a work of art from the opinion of that work of art of others.
Scott: So it's like they have you know cowabeebop, but now suddenly cowabeebop is popular So it's no longer cool, or there's Evangelion?
Scott: well if it was just me and Evangelion and no one else in the world I would love it, but you know what?
Scott: because there's a million perverted fanboys who want to see naked ray.
Scott: I don't like Evangelion anymore.
Scott: Well, that's that's that's.
Scott: it's a bad way to be.
Scott: cuz you're missing out.
Rym: I'm gonna state my opinion absolutely unambiguously and argue all you will.
Rym: I Feel that Shinseki Evangelion stands out among art and among works of fiction and among television shows.
Rym: It stands apart as one of the greater television shows ever made straight up without any reservation or qualifications.
Scott: Try to think of a better TV show.
Scott: it's it's.
Rym: it's gonna be rough.
Rym: you could argue cowboy bebop.
Rym: It's close, and I'm you know I'm.
Rym: we're sticking to anime examples because it's Wednesday.
Rym: We're talking about anime.
Scott: Yeah But even if I try to think of non anime TV shows that are better just in any genre in any way just overall Quality score on that
Rym: level like in terms of artistry in terms of how well it's put together I put Ava the show in the same league as like the Godfather which I think is one of the Most perfect movies ever made.
Scott: it's definitely like number one or two movies.
Scott: The is the Godfather.
Scott: number one easily.
Scott: Yeah, I can't I can't think of it so that We're deep in this LCL.
Rym: We're out here in these dangerous waters.
Rym: I Defy you Rebut us really.
Rym: I don't think you can.
Scott: yeah, and even if you hate all that shit How could you not like robots punching aliens in the face?
Rym: Now because there's the one thing that Ava does not do that big O does so much better.
Rym: If there was ever a show that exemplified robots punching robots in the face or nay Anything punching anything in any capacity?
Rym: Big O is Number one.
Rym: it is the king of the genre of something punching something.
Scott: Yeah, that that I'm not saying it isn't but I'm saying Ava has plenty of punches to satisfy the punch likers The punch band.
Rym: oh, and if you wanted to listen to this show expecting us to explain what Ava was about We could we kind of did a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean it figure goes pretty straightforward cuz I think it's all pretty obvious not good We're not going to.
Scott: all you had to do to know what Ava's about is to actually try to figure out What the characters want mostly mostly what the bigger more secretive characters want.
Rym: very simply look at the show and think What is Gendo after?
Rym: What is Sele after?
Scott: they're obviously after something.
Scott: they're not just doing all this stuff for no reason right.
Rym: what is Kaji after?
Rym: Why did Sele do what they did?
Rym: Why is Sele at odds with Gendo?
Scott: What did they do?
Rym: Why?
Rym: Yeah, why did Gendo?
Rym: Why did Gendo not want the spear to be there?
Rym: Why was he at odds with Sele and vice versa?
Rym: it's all pretty straightforward and Maybe someday we'll do a little like special like a 10-minute.
Rym: Here's exactly what happened and what Ava was about.
Rym: but the show's not about that.
Rym: the show is about why Ava is great And you know what it's great.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four Different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.