Rym: It's Wednesday January 16th.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm a Scott and this is a geeky night tonight for the first time in a long time.
Rym: We review some freaking anime.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: I get to work this morning.
Scott: do my normal work thing right?
Scott: It's Wednesday this breakfast.
Scott: I get me a bagel of course.
Scott: I was a little slow on the bagel action So I actually got like one of the last bagels.
Scott: I took this poppy seed bagel that was looking kind of haggard and the only other bagels left in there were like this salt Bagel and these sort of nobody likes the salt bagel and like these brown bagels that were.
Scott: obviously that we I don't know But I think it was like a pumpernickel bagel or something.
Rym: Oh, that sounds really good.
Scott: It was.
Scott: he was not popular.
Scott: That's just because people don't understand now, so I toast my Second-rate poppy seed bagel.
Scott: I go back.
Scott: I need a beverage.
Scott: Yeah, I just drank some orangey, but I still need something to wash the bagel down.
Scott: drink the orangey before the bagel.
Scott: So I go to get some water and now the water cooler at our work doesn't actually get water in it.
Scott: Well, it does, but you don't have to put the stupid bottle.
Scott: water cooler doesn't have water You don't have to put the stupid bottles in it.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's hooked up to the tap and has a filtered tank in it And you just put your cup under.
Scott: you push the button and you're good to go.
Scott: You put your Nalgene and you push the button and water comes out All right, and it's cold and it's from the tap and it's New York.
Scott: So doesn't matter, right?
Scott: I Go to push the button and for the first time ever Nothing comes out.
Rym: So I'm like, huh, you know, that's a really unexpected.
Rym: I mean there have been a couple of times in my life where I turn on a faucet and nothing comes out.
Rym: but the thing is usually when that happens if it's not through like if it's a normal faucet if There isn't water there instead of water you get possibly some brown sludge, but usually a horrible banging noise.
Scott: Yeah, now it just kind of word little, you know compressor in there.
Scott: I guess word a bit and nothing came out says, huh?
Scott: So I'm just like fuck it and I go sit down again and then there's an email a little while later like yeah We have no water.
Rym: That's what you get for having some like those.
Scott: There's like a broken water.
Scott: main on everything in the city is always.
Scott: it's never the building It's always something happened on some street somewhere.
Scott: It's like water main broke on X Street.
Scott: Telephone switch broke on Y Street, you know, you know.
Scott: Anyway, a water main broke on some street.
Scott: So we didn't have water.
Scott: I think the 12th floor had water and Probably maybe because we're on the second floor.
Rym: There's a tank at the top of the building.
Scott: Yeah, so we had to go like 10 floors up if you needed to pee, which you know.
Rym: There's been some scary stories about those tanks because usually no one maintains them and there's been some interesting things found floating in them.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: Yes, indeed, but I did not go to the 12th floor.
Scott: I held it in.
Rym: Not like in that movie that short.
Scott: I didn't need to go.
Scott: that bad Anyway, but my co-worker right.
Scott: so normally it sucks if electricity goes out you can go home But if water goes out you got to stay.
Rym: All right, so my co-worker then water was the only thing that ever made RIT shut down.
Scott: I know right 9/11.
Rym: We're going 12 feet of snow.
Rym: That's fine.
Scott: No water send the kids home Yep, but then my co-worker, you know, he was getting pretty pissed you know, he's gonna go out to like a restaurant to pee or something, but then His computer stops working.
Scott: Like I think his power supply died.
Scott: pretty sure that that's the current diagnosis.
Scott: I think it's obvious that he sabotaged it so he could go home and the other co-worker whose job it is to fix that Sick today, so he just went home.
Scott: No, it was actually broken.
Scott: I checked it.
Rym: Oh, no, I'm not doubting that it was broken.
Rym: I'm wondering how it came to be broken.
Scott: He didn't sabotage it.
Scott: Trust me.
Rym: There wasn't a paperclip sticking.
Scott: I checked it.
Scott: Maybe then again, maybe he let me check it so he'd have proof.
Scott: Anyway, so he goes home.
Scott: I'm sitting there and eventually after a few hours I'm like, I couldn't.
Scott: I was think I was gonna make lunch and at work.
Scott: I have peanut butter and jelly and a knife.
Scott: I couldn't clean the knife to make lunch.
Scott: Wow, so eventually I get fed up and I go over back to the water cooler thing and I put my nalgene under there.
Rym: I push the button and water comes out, you know, usually when there's a water main break You're not supposed to use the water that comes out for like 12 hours.
Scott: I know but I said fuck it.
Scott: I'm using this.
Rym: Oh, you're gonna die or whatever.
Scott: I know well, it was going through the filter in that little machine, right?
Scott: So I was okay.
Rym: Is there a filter there?
Scott: Yeah It's a machine.
Scott: that's just a filter and a compressor and a cooler and the tap water comes into it through a little hose and you Push a button and the water comes out.
Scott: That's all it is.
Scott: So I push the button the water comes out and I'm like, ah But I didn't think the water was fixed.
Scott: I just thought I got lucky and I got the last of the water or something like that Even though that doesn't make sense since previously no water was coming out at all.
Scott: I didn't care.
Scott: So then I'm like, alright and then I go back to my desk and there's you know an email that says the water is fixed.
Scott: I'm like, oh that explains it.
Scott: so I go to the sink and I clean off my knife and the sink was pretty funny because when I put the sink when I put the sink on hot water it came out normally right because the hot water, you know Must have been in a tank somewhere, you know waiting around But the cold water was
Rym: a minute.
Scott: if that means you probably could have used the hot water to wash your knife I know But the cold water was like put put put put put put put.
Scott: it was pretty funny.
Scott: I like the cold water.
Scott: He was making the sink jump up and down.
Rym: So did you have the classic problem whenever water starts up again of the infinitely flushing toilet?
Scott: Well, you why are you stealing my thunder?
Rym: because that happens.
Rym: It's a common thing.
Scott: Why you got me doing that?
Scott: I was giving you the opportunity because I was gonna bring it up in a second.
Scott: I was next.
Rym: all of you out there understand how excited Scott was about the fact that the toilet wouldn't stop flush.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: So our bathroom is notorious for that being shitty.
Scott: It's like the worst bathroom ever cuz on the second floor.
Scott: so all these UPS guys use it and shit and it sucks.
Scott: But you know after I make my lunch and whatnot.
Scott: I gotta finally pee.
Scott: I finally drank water.
Scott: So now I had to pee.
Scott: I go in there and I hear a toilet flushing And I pee and I still hear this toilet flushing.
Scott: I go over there and this toilet is flushing and it's not stopping.
Scott: It just keeps flushing and blushing.
Scott: Water keeps coming out and water keeps going down.
Scott: It's like it's permanent cyclone and I'm like, oh man We're gonna go.
Rym: Did you tell anyone?
Scott: No, I just let it go.
Rym: I should have told someone.
Rym: What do I care?
Scott: I still go and no it's not cuz I went in later wasn't going anymore.
Scott: but Yeah, it was pretty funny to watch this toilet.
Scott: Just keep going and going.
Scott: it was like a perpetual toilet.
Scott: Yeah, and they see perpetual motion machines are not possible.
Scott: explain that toilet.
Scott: It kept going.
Rym: So what today I had to listen to some guy tell me this story on how the water was out in his building And I was flushing infinitely something like that.
Scott: Yeah, it was pretty awesome.
Rym: There's you know, I was looking at the anime news, you know, it's anime day and you know ostensibly manga comic day But there's never news about manga.
Rym: There's there's never news You don't.
Scott: the manga news is.
Scott: this new manga was licensed.
Scott: This new manga is going to be so created now.
Rym: I often say ah, there's no anime news, but there's no freakin anime news today.
Rym: There's nothing I care about to talk about.
Scott: there is nada.
Rym: So, uh, I figured I should do a some sort of geek bite cuz it's been a while or a geek back.
Rym: It's gonna be a geek bite for me.
Rym: Okay, I Long time ago, you know, I read the first ghost in the shell manga.
Rym: It was it was kind of epic and awesome and I really enjoyed it.
Scott: It's something any manga fan should read.
Scott: really any comic any comic reading person should read that at some point no matter if you like Manga or not.
Scott: you really it's one of those necessities up there with like the watchman.
Scott: It's not as good as watchman But it is really good.
Scott: It's really good.
Scott: It's not watchman good, but it's this necessity to read it.
Scott: You gotta read it.
Rym: Scott had had the issues of the second manga.
Scott: That's actually funnily enough.
Scott: I Stopped buying comics and I was a kid right when the comic book store in the mall went out of business.
Scott: Right and when I was a kid, I read x-men and I read spider-man 2099, right?
Scott: I stopped reading them, you know when the comic store out of business.
Scott: I didn't read comics again until Like around 2000, you know when I was in college He went to the borders right and we go to the borders every once in a while to hang out look at stuff.
Scott: You know, they had the meager manga shelf.
Scott: Remember that manga shelf and everything on it was amazing.
Scott: Even if it was crap.
Scott: Yeah, it was great and we'd go to that manga shelf and I almost bought some manga.
Scott: sometimes I think I might have bought like initial D number one there and stuff like that.
Scott: But they had a comic rack in the borders.
Scott: It was like a bigger than usual comic rack for borders is.
Scott: and on that comic rack I at one point when I was looking at the magazines I happen to notice ghost in the shell - man-machine interface issue number one.
Scott: I said, holy shit.
Scott: Look at that It's I got it and I went back the next month and got number two.
Scott: I don't like the next month again number three.
Scott: And then eventually my friend Ian got me going to the conflict store again And now I have boxes coming every month.
Rym: No, uh, thank you Shiro.
Rym: I avoid reading that partly just because I hate issues like I. Comic books are so unpleasant to read that I just can't deal with it.
Rym: I'm gonna get some sort of compilation or trade or I'm just not gonna bother.
Rym: there is No, what if?
Scott: what if I took like all the issues right and I bound them together into a single book?
Rym: It's still that big floppy paper.
Scott: If it was quality binding maybe but now actually for ghost in the shell - I kind of like the issue.
Scott: I don't like the separation of the issues into the separate, you know things.
Scott: I like it all to be together.
Scott: But the bigger Pages really helped that manga because a lot of little things in it.
Rym: I didn't feel like I missed anything.
Scott: No, you probably didn't.
Rym: but well anyway, here's the deal.
Rym: Scott's been trying to get me to read this forever.
Rym: It's been in the pile along with.
Scott: it goes in the shell - goes in the shell.
Scott: one epic must reads.
Scott: It goes in the shell - it's got to be epic must read right now.
Rym: Scott would never say anything beyond.
Rym: Yeah, you got to read this.
Scott: Well, I would say a few things like we'd be watching say stand Solid state society and you're like, oh this is this.
Rym: is this happens in that?
Scott: well No I say wow this reminds me a lot more of goes in the shell - that it reminds me of.
Scott: goes in the shell.
Scott: one like it goes In the shell - it's a lot more hacking stuff and it's always with you know The big circles and the gates and all that stuff and the sort of they use those same visuals in some of the later Set in standalone complex second gig and in Solid state society.
Scott: So when those visuals came up I'd be like, ah, this is a lot like goes in the shell - man.
Rym: So I finally read it.
Scott: you like that tanuki.
Rym: right the two key was those was arguably the best part.
Rym: That's nuki Andy of the wolf spirit the way that was drawn.
Rym: I thought was really cool.
Scott: That's okay.
Rym: Beyond that I mean I enjoyed it, but I read it and I felt like all right.
Rym: I'm reading this.
Rym: I'm reading this I I know what's going on and I got to the end and then I thought back and I realized that I had no fucking Idea what had happened.
Scott: that entire goddamn mong explain the plot to me.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Uh, so so a bunch of pigs died, right?
Scott: What were the pigs doing?
Scott: Why were they special?
Rym: Well, uh Arguably, they're being used for some nefarious purposes.
Rym: But who by who?
Scott: well, what were they supposed to be used for?
Scott: Organs and what were they being used?
Rym: brains but not organ.
Rym: That is so not the plot.
Rym: No, but but I I don't.
Rym: There's a point at which I could have just stopped reading and I would have had the same understanding of the manga As if I'd continued reading.
Rym: I got to the end and realized that the second half of the manga.
Rym: Not only did I not know what happened, but I suddenly realized like wait a minute.
Rym: No, her name is Kusanagi not Aramaki.
Rym: Why didn't I notice that before then?
Rym: I'm like, oh, wait a minute.
Rym: Well, what the god damn it?
Rym: It's one of those things Shiro I Defy you to tell me what the fuck happened.
Scott: and ghost in the shell - I can actually sort of piece it together But you know how many times I've read it Seven more than four at least.
Rym: The thing is basically I got to the end and I'm like, wow That was really profound.
Rym: and then I realized that everything I was thinking about that was profound Was not something that I'd read in the manga but something I was thinking about because of ghost in the shell.
Scott: I think the thing about ghost in the shell - man-machine interface the manga right because well, I guess it's only a manga is that There is a plot a literal plot.
Scott: You can get it by reading extra carefully and extra slowly and extra and multiple times and extra painfully.
Scott: But that plot is not really the point and it doesn't matter.
Rym: I think I think the point of ghost in the shell - What?
Rym: well there are a lot of points.
Rym: I think basically it was Shiro just Kind of getting his mind on the paper and ghost in the shell just happened to be the way he was doing that Yeah, and it was basically just him thinking about Well, what if this and what if this?
Rym: you know kind of like speculative fiction but at the same time Shiro-tastic.
Scott: Yeah, basically each page each scene each you know action is just something to like.
Scott: work your brain and The plot suffers.
Scott: the coherency of the plot suffers as a result of extreme imagery.
Rym: Yes I mean there is a point at which I think she was in a game but maybe not and I pretty much lost track of Plot from that point on yeah, and she switches into like using like D cots.
Rym: fine with the D cots until I couldn't figure out if she was in a D cot or in the real world or Or if the D cot was in the real
Scott: and maybe the point is to get your brain to do that Or maybe it's just Shiro and he's just a crazy nut job.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: I mean or maybe both
Rym: my real idea is that one of the ideas Shiro was trying to get across is that the world that The entity that is arguably known as the major What lives in now and exists in is so utterly different and so much faster paced than the real world that like Every now and then it kind of cuts out of following the main character around and just shows you like humans Doing things and the humans are a lot like the humans are moving so slowly and doing so little compared to what she does in like two minutes.
Rym: that Beyond that.
Rym: I don't know what happened something with a tree at the end and something I don't even know who was hacking the pigs if there even were any thugs.
Scott: Yep Yep, something like that.
Rym: Okay, I don't get it.
Rym: I suggest you read it.
Rym: However, you read it again.
Rym: Maybe I think what really got me about it.
Rym: I mean I enjoyed it.
Rym: Don't get me wrong, but the fact that Shiro has footnotes and it's not like.
Rym: well Here's a footnote to explain this and here's the footnote.
Scott: There's one footnote because early in the manga there's like these two flying machines, right and he basically puts a footnote like yeah I know these flying machines are impossible because of blah.
Scott: I just drew them this way cuz it's better.
Scott: Sorry It's like what you're talking about what's possible and impossible in your made-up future.
Rym: Oh, he goes well beyond that.
Rym: I think my favorite footnote is on a random page and I Swear to you that this footnote has nothing to do with what is happening on that page or any page anywhere near it.
Rym: He just has a random footnote talking about how the u.s.
Rym: Is upgrading its military.
Rym: Now, maybe Japan should do the same.
Rym: Yeah military fanboy for sure Shiro, I gotta hand it to you man.
Rym: That was some.
Rym: that was some epic manga right there.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so when someone says shirotastic and you're not quite sure with it that mean I think ghost in the shell.
Rym: the second manga Epitomizes.
Rym: now sure.
Rym: I think it is the second most shirotastic.
Scott: if I'm to understand correctly Orion is the most shirotastic.
Rym: Well, I have never in any way engaged with Orion nor have I but I know better.
Rym: so as far as I have experienced the As far as someone who would even consider anything Shiro believes to be a valid philosophy could believe to be true.
Rym: Ah That was the most shirotastic thing I've ever witnessed.
Scott: All right, you ready?
Rym: I think we're ready.
Rym: That's that I could come up with tonight.
Scott: I was uh, I was just you know Looking around cuz.
Scott: I've been watching the galaxy Express 3 9 TV show recently because some someone's fansubbing it so nicely But their fansub me too slowly.
Rym: Well Scott has this thing.
Rym: It's like whenever he's tired Like my.
Rym: when I'm tired, I go to bed.
Rym: Maybe I masturbate or something.
Rym: I don't know but when Scott's tired He'll put on some leji Matsumoto like old melodramatic side.
Scott: lady Matsumoto's anime are Amazing all of them, but they only work When it's dark and when it's late at night and when it's quiet.
Scott: That's the only time they work and then when it when that's true, they work Amazing if you're Scott and if you're tired, they work even better.
Rym: I think you're confusing lady Matsumoto with space ghost.
Scott: Well, I think part of what it was is when I was you know young and I first discovered lady Matsumoto, right?
Scott: It was on the sci-fi channel.
Scott: It was late at night on anime week on the sci-fi channel and
Rym: you watched galaxy
Scott: Galaxy Express 3 9 movie dubbed and then the second Galaxy Express 3 9 movie the next day also dubbed late at night in the dark and the couch in my living room alone and that's sort of.
Scott: It really worked on me.
Scott: That was like more than any of the.
Scott: that was like really when I started Super animating that week of anime right because it was like Fatal Fury Fatal Fury 2 Galaxy Express Galaxy Express 2 and then something else shitty that I remember Sean or something.
Scott: I don't remember a son terror No, I think was actually only four days because then I think Godzilla started which is also awesome.
Scott: By the way, Godzilla vs.
Scott: Mothra is the best Godzilla movie.
Scott: hands down hands down.
Scott: No one can say anything else.
Scott: You're all wrong.
Rym: Well, I think it comes down to the fact that my Mothra edge like 10 to the score of any Godzilla.
Scott: Yeah, and while well, well Ghidorah is the best of all the monsters, you know in coolness and lookingness Cuz he's like a hydra with three heads Mothra is still better.
Scott: So whatever anyway.
Scott: So, you know that was that was my experience with that and that more than any other anime I watched that week was like the double awesomes.
Scott: So Every time I watch even other leiji Matsumoto things like harlocks and things like that I always try to go for the same feeling and it always works.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: it always works on me.
Scott: It's always great.
Rym: The result is whenever we have the crew over we're ready to you know, the nights winding down We're about to maybe all retire for the evening or maybe play one last game of something.
Rym: Scott always suggests that we watch some sort of not necessarily leiji Matsumoto But I think pretty much either that or a night on the galactic railroad.
Scott: It was Dying like to grow Galaxy Express.
Scott: There's a link.
Rym: Yes The problem is one of them is good one of those boring.
Scott: Well, he based the Galaxy Express off of the you know.
Scott: Well his idea to have trains in space was because of the novel of nine the Galactica.
Rym: But anyway, oh, yeah, I'm not.
Rym: I mean I just that movie is so boring.
Scott: Anyway, so watching anime again, right cuz I'm watching Galaxy Express TV show.
Scott: I realized I can watch like five plus anime episodes a day if I watch them on the train.
Scott: So I was thinking hey, I'm gonna actually go back now.
Scott: I'm gonna watch that Ava I'm gonna do it and then I'm gonna watch that eska flown.
Scott: a I'm gonna do it and we're gonna make the show, right?
Rym: I've been waiting for this day for a long time because I'm itching to talk about eska flown.
Rym: That's still to this day one of my top three.
Rym: That is one of the best anime ever made, right?
Scott: So we're gonna do those right as soon as I get her out.
Scott: Yeah, they're only 26 episodes so I could probably watch them in a week.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So anyway Realizing that I said hey, I gotta watch the cowboy bebop.
Scott: I've seen it like five times.
Scott: I get to see it seven times.
Scott: So I'm like, I wonder if I can buy it and You know, it was available first.
Scott: They made it available on the original DVDs.
Scott: Well VHS then DVDs The VHS is are mad expensive because like two episodes of tape The DVDs are mad expensive You know because there were a whole bunch of them and the box set was like a hundred something dollars.
Scott: and today if you want That original box set.
Scott: It's still a lot of money.
Scott: Then they came out with like these best sessions Which was like a little set that had like the best the quote best episodes or the most important episode.
Rym: That seems really kind of silly though, cuz you got to watch cowboy bebop all the way through it.
Scott: All right, I had like the most process everything.
Scott: It was like this little set of like a couple DVDs or one or two I'm not exactly sure but like the most important episodes.
Scott: then they were putting out cowboy bebop remix Which is six separate DVDs that had the audio remastered, you know, the 5.1 surround sound.
Scott: now They're doing anime legends cowboy bebop remix.
Scott: So it's all those remix DVDs all six of them in one box on Amazon for thirty seven dollars and forty nine cents.
Scott: Not bad be released on February 5th.
Scott: This is my news here.
Scott: Is that if you have never seen cowboy bebop if you don't own it all if you have seen it, it doesn't matter.
Scott: Now is the time to buy all of cowboy bebop for thirty seven forty nine.
Rym: Unarguably the greatest anime ever.
Scott: that is the great.
Scott: I will go farther than that.
Scott: I will say that is the greatest value you could possibly get in anime ever Ever existed.
Rym: not necessarily.
Rym: However in all of entertainment because I we paid 50 cents to see the powerpuff girls movie.
Scott: Yes, but this is the best dollar per awesome You can get in terms of purchasing anime on DVDs that has ever existed in the history of the world and probably will for quite Some time.
Scott: I mean if you let you know someone gives you something like, you know for free.
Scott: But we're talking about like a you know a deal at a store not a deal.
Rym: What not that that epic box set that we saw for sale.
Scott: So, you know this got me thinking right you look cowboy bebop.
Scott: anime is you know bandai?
Scott: I guess is bandai entertainment, right?
Scott: They're doing anime legends.
Scott: So that must be their new sort of like labeling of their awesome box sets and things like that.
Scott: You know of the?
Scott: let's take old anime re-release them on new DVDs and sell them for less money.
Scott: They're gonna call it anime legends.
Scott: So I go to write stuff and I search for anime legends and I got a whole bunch of stuff But I don't care about most of it because some of it's not.
Scott: you know.
Scott: box set some of its other things.
Scott: So I'm looking for the thin pack collection.
Scott: So I type in You know anime legends complete collection.
Scott: you ready for the list here?
Scott: These are all excellent values in anime that I recommend.
Scott: ready Agent Aika, no, I don't recommend that.
Scott: our Joe.
Scott: I know I don't recommend that either.
Scott: Here we go.
Scott: big Oh $36, oh man, but that's just season one.
Scott: It's $36 also for season two.
Rym: They're both worth it.
Rym: Big O one is one of the better giant robot shows ever.
Scott: That's not too.
Rym: is Ava done better?
Scott: That's not a very good value because you're paying as much as you are for 26 episodes of cowboy bebop for 13 episodes of big.
Scott: Oh, but big I was so good Then this is probably still the cheapest way to get it.
Scott: if you can't get the old bricks so big.
Scott: Oh Blue sub 6 complete collection not bad crest of the stars Eska flown a $45 that is well worth it.
Scott: Check this out.
Scott: This pisses me off because I bought this individually just by disc Gundam seed The first 25 episodes for $45 and then the second 25 episodes for $38.
Rym: I want to say one thing real quick about Gundam seed.
Rym: if you don't like Gundam shows.
Rym: Well one you're.
Rym: I hate you.
Rym: but if you know if you haven't seen a Gundam show before or if you just don't think you like Gundam shows or Prejudice
Scott: to get or you have misconceptions if you've never watched one and you have some sort of prejudice about what you think they're like or if you've seen one and Maybe you saw the wrong one a G Gundam and you had you know.
Scott: you think you know what they're like.
Scott: and if you haven't seen Gundam seed or You haven't watched like Zeta Gundam or the original Gundam You really don't know Gundam.
Scott: a lot of you will think they know it and don't like it or think they know it and do like It but they really don't know it.
Scott: Buy this.
Rym: Yes, seriously.
Scott: I paid a lot more for this and I'm not sad.
Scott: Gundam wing DVD collection one.
Scott: so I assume there's gonna be a -.
Rym: I'll say one thing The dub is not as good as you thought it was.
Rym: Yeah as a kid Let's see.
Scott: No, no good.
Scott: No good.
Scott: No good No good.
Scott: wolves rain, I guess.
Rym: Yeah, you know I never saw the end of that because everyone said it was Tara save or marionette J complete collection.
Rym: scrap princess complete Princess is kind of worth watching.
Scott: which hunter Robin?
Scott: complete collection.
Rym: Are you just gonna name all these?
Scott: He's gonna say I'm skipping a lot of them.
Scott: I I didn't mention.
Scott: please teacher Or please twins Oh God.
Scott: Yeah, okay There's a lot of these.
Scott: and if you're looking for good deals in anime cuz back in the day ban I entertainment pretty much licensed all the good stuff and they still resell it.
Scott: They're still publishing it and you can get it for real cheap now.
Scott: So go for it.
Rym: things of the day.
Rym: if you ever wondered how a bobbin works This is making the rounds on the internet.
Rym: Here you go.
Rym: That's all I got to say about that.
Scott: Yeah sewing machines.
Scott: It's cool Alright, so if yeah, I know this is sort of a video game thing, but whatever the anime peoples like the Phoenix, right?
Scott: You know if you've never played the Phoenix, right and you're not sure or you maybe you have a misconception about it Like you do about Gundam They've made a flash application.
Scott: Capcom has made an official flash application that it's ace.
Scott: It's ace attorney Apollo justice mock trial version.
Scott: you can go with your web browser and play a bit of Phoenix right action and You'll see what it's like and decide if you like it or not.
Scott: All right, and you can embed it in your website.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: so you might be shocked you might be amazed but we have watched some new and new ish Anime newer than Galaxy Express.
Rym: That's for sure.
Rym: We got I think two shows from the current season ish and then one somewhat older show that we watched an episode.
Rym: I think we got something to say.
Scott: Yeah, we got some good stuff to say.
Scott: Alright, so which one of these you want to go from like worst?
Scott: Well, there's one bad one and two good ones.
Scott: See, let's do the bad one.
Rym: Alright, we can get this done quick.
Rym: There's this show is called persona hyphen Trinity soul.
Scott: Yeah, so the only good thing about this show is that our favorite voice actor in the known universe.
Scott: Takehito koyasu plays one of the care of me somewhat major characters so off his game.
Scott: Yeah, he doesn't sound like when he.
Scott: when he first talked I was like.
Scott: that sounds like koyasu But I was like, but I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Scott: it sounds like a type koyasu imitator, but no, it's really him.
Scott: So he must be off his game.
Scott: now There's something not right.
Rym: shows being directed by some guy who is known for jack all great and Honestly, the show is pretty bad, but it's not bad enough to make fun of.
Rym: it's just really not entertaining.
Rym: The only thing it's got going is that basically the plot as far as you can tell from the first episode is People have souls.
Rym: those souls are also giant robots and people have psychic giant robot battles and that's it.
Scott: That's pretty much all that's going on in the show.
Scott: I mean, it's like these two siblings and like they don't have a home and they have to go back to live with their brother or Something and I think this lives kind of exemplifies everything.
Rym: that's wrong with a lot of anime that comes out these days because this show Reminds me a lot of several other shows I've watched in recent memory where the first episode like the character designs are kind of generic.
Rym: The animation is kind of sterile and boring.
Rym: They always introduce characters and give all this stuff about him, but they also introduce some central mystery And they pretty much ignore that mystery or don't tell you enough to know anything about it.
Rym: but they also want to give you enough to care about the characters and They kind of jump in the middle of something that you don't care about and they don't go anywhere with.
Scott: yeah I think the primary problem with the show is that they toss you into it, right?
Scott: They first and you know It's at the classic anime first beginning of the first episode thing where they show you Some mysterious like government or military group doing something mysterious and then a strange event occurring or something like that And then they cut and they give you the opener and then they throw you to the main characters and then you know that whatever They're get whatever is gonna happen to them is gonna relate to that mysterious thing.
Rym: They showed you 30 seconds of the beginning and apparently the plot involves of people being turned inside out by something called Reverse.
Rym: Yeah, it's just this show does not look like it has any potential to be in any way entertaining.
Scott: It's so boring, I think pretty much the major problem with the show is that there's no reason to care about anything.
Scott: It's like people are being reversed.
Rym: Okay, I still crack up.
Scott: It's not even like, you know, huh?
Scott: There's some clues and now I can start thinking about a mystery.
Scott: It's like no just people are being reversed Alright, and I'm supposed to wonder about why.
Rym: just pretty much from that alone Every conversation the character has just goes nowhere and you don't care and it they always refer.
Scott: no one.
Scott: I think it's another problem.
Scott: a lot of anime do this.
Scott: No one has any direct Conversations.
Scott: everyone just sort of thinks a lot of things but no one says anything to anyone.
Scott: people just kind of look at each Other and then walk around and they say things like offhand comments that reference things.
Scott: We don't know about like brother If only blah or that guy blah blah blah, which guy you talking about?
Scott: you're purposely saying that guy so we don't know which guy you're talking about, you know, and This just it's not where it was.
Scott: just the first episode is so painful.
Scott: I couldn't continue.
Scott: go I think the music was okay though.
Rym: Yeah, but the opener didn't really fit.
Rym: It was one of those generic openers.
Rym: It's just the show's got nothing.
Scott: No You can skip persona Trinity soul even though it's kind of sad because it's one of the few shows I've seen in recent years.
Scott: It's like the.
Scott: the percentage of moe shows to non moe shows is getting pretty off.
Scott: There's a lot more moe shows going on or at least shows with moe elements if not full-on moe moe shows.
Scott: And it's kind of sad that one of the non moe shows is shitty.
Rym: So don't even bother with this show.
Scott: It's not good Yep, skip it.
Rym: So, uh There's another show we checked out and this one has a lot of promise.
Rym: However, you have to be a certain kind of anime fan to enjoy a show like that.
Scott: You have to be in the right situation in the right mood to enjoy the show.
Scott: This show's actually from 2007 and it was ran from April to September 24 episodes so Lovely complex.
Scott: that might sound like a bad moe Show, maybe a harem show of some sort something like that, but it's actually One of those cute funny shows.
Scott: there aren't too many shows in this category.
Scott: It's sort of like karakano Sort of like koto-cha in there sort of like koto-cha sort of like Haniori Dango, it's one of those sort of shows.
Scott: It's a. it's a comedic high school shoujo thing and It's really not too bad.
Scott: I mean, it's not something I would go out and watch a whole lot of you know, like diligently But if I'm in sort of a silly mood and I need me some laughs or maybe I'm an anime club And I want to get everyone riled up.
Rym: This is the medicine, you know There hasn't been a show like this in a long time.
Rym: This show fills the koto-cha hole because if you want that kind of show You got to go to the old stuff or you can come to this show right here.
Rym: There's there's definitely there's a lot of uh, Mon's Eye going on Which I'm a big fan a big fan of that Mon's Eye action.
Rym: The plot is pretty simple.
Rym: There's a there's a girl who is really tall and there's a guy who's really short and they hate each other But they have a lot in common.
Scott: They have a hell of a lot in common but and they're sort of like.
Scott: they're sort of like friends and enemies at the same time like to hang out with each other and You know, they team up but also they hate each other.
Scott: and so like Right, and you can tell that they that you know, they're supposed to end up together But it's like something they wouldn't even think of.
Scott: you know, it's it's it's one of those kind of situations.
Scott: It's sort of a cliche situation and it's a little obvious.
Scott: Right and and what's gonna happen in the episodes is always sort of obvious because the shallow High school comedic romance plot more heavy on the comedy than on the romance, you know That's not the point.
Scott: the point is that the jokes that are actually go on during the show are actually kind of funny and endearing and it's like oh but then it's like lol's epic lol's and They actually kind of act like normal people and they make real-world kind of jokes and it's just silly and fun.
Scott: And then occasionally, you know, there's crazy slapstick stuff to like people getting hit over the head.
Rym: Yeah, definitely a child's toy kind of vibe going on there.
Rym: Also the main character kind of reminds me of waka ba.
Rym: Yeah, kinda only much more Gruff and maybe a little consign.
Scott: Yeah, maybe a little bit.
Rym: Oh, I didn't even realize this is directed by a konosuke Uda.
Scott: Who's that?
Rym: He also directed Galaxy Express 999 internal fantasy.
Scott: That's yeah, that's not.
Rym: and the Sailor Moon super s movie clearly the best of the Sailor Moon movies my best I mean worst.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the show has some other stuff going on in it, too.
Scott: You know, there's there's like, you know some school stuff.
Scott: They actually pay attention to what's going on in school a little bit.
Scott: you know.
Rym: what really makes the show stand out is kind of it's the opposite of persona Trinity soul and that The character designs have character and just the way they talk and interact and the way everything's done.
Rym: There's There's enough going on.
Rym: that gives the show charm that just some of these other newer kind of sterile shows just don't have.
Scott: yes Definitely it is the exact opposite of persona Trinity soul in a way because it doesn't really have much of a plot.
Scott: to speak of The episode we watched, you know a couple episodes we watched the what was gonna happen was so contrived cliche and obvious.
Scott: It might as well nothing might as well have happened But you know it the characters you care about them.
Scott: Each character is really characterized.
Scott: Yeah, you know you and they interact with each other and interesting or you know At least funny ways quite often.
Scott: that's pretty much the whole show.
Rym: and the show is really.
Rym: it's stylized.
Rym: The way it's drawn and the way everything is put together is it stands out from all the other anime coming out lately.
Scott: Yeah, well at least there's a lot of bright colors so we can kind of hurt your eyes sometimes.
Scott: But other than that, you know, it's not those moe colors though.
Rym: It's actual bright colors Yep, not those like faded moe girl hair color, whatever.
Scott: No, no, it's actually bright colors Like, you know super gals kinda that kind of color.
Rym: now.
Rym: last and certainly not least a lot of people have been talking about this show and I Was a little leery.
Scott: but I was also a little bit leery.
Rym: I heard enough good buzz and especially once I heard what the plot nominally was I actually I kind of am excited about seeing more of this show maybe.
Scott: so the show is called Spice and wolf right and at first I was like, uh-oh This is gonna be a not a furry show for furries, right?
Scott: because the picture you see when you look for this show is like a girl with ears and a tail and You think there's gonna be big-time moe furry action, that's what I expected to see but we watch it anyway.
Rym: Yeah, I mean basically I expected it to be Uto are they do mono - And he wasn't.
Rym: well the thing is.
Rym: then I was told the plot and it seems like it's it's definitely said in a European Middle Ages kind of you know monotheism is kind of making its rounds and the old gods are being forgotten.
Scott: and this this will is the plot of the the final.
Scott: well the Final finished chapter of Phoenix the same plot something like that.
Rym: Yeah, but basically this wolf goddess is Her time has passed.
Rym: She the people no longer need her.
Rym: so she is going to leave and travel to the lands in the north and she needs help.
Rym: so she kind of Shanghai's this poor merchant who's just passing through town into taking her north.
Rym: Yep, and I'm not sure exactly where they're gonna go with this.
Rym: I've only seen one episode but this show if they go in any of the directions that I think it might go in and there's two or three directions it could Go in where I would be pleased.
Rym: The show is actually got a lot of potential.
Scott: Yeah, definitely.
Scott: The only thing this I don't like the show 100% I mean, I really that merchant main character guy I really kind of don't like him so much like he seems kind of glad.
Scott: I wish he was more like when I first saw him like I imagined.
Scott: I guess this might be a problem.
Scott: Imagine him being a lot like ginkgo from mushishi because he kind of looks like him Kind of looks like him a little bit and if he was like that kind of character I think the show would be a lot more awesome, you know.
Scott: But he seems kind of just like a normal kind of merchant Like he's just like a normal average dude and the way he acts is sort of bland.
Scott: I really don't care about him that much.
Scott: but other than that like what goes on in the show and the plot and the style Is all really high quality.
Rym: See I like him partly because the way You know, they're whenever there's this sort of alright There's a magical girl something and she meets a guy and the kind of.
Rym: there's the trope of how that would play out in anime.
Rym: You can see what's gonna happen.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And in this show doesn't really turn out that way.
Rym: He reacts more like a reasonable person would react and she reacts in a completely unexpected way.
Scott: Yeah, I guess that's because you know the way they've made the main character guy.
Scott: What's his name?
Scott: Craft Lawrence craft Lawrence.
Scott: the way craft Lawrence is is he's such a normal merchant.
Scott: He's just like hey, what's up?
Scott: I'm a merchant.
Scott: How you doing?
Rym: He talks and he's got his own drama.
Rym: There's a girl who likes him But he has problems with that.
Rym: cuz she's kind of young and blah blah blah blah blah, and he's got his business to take care of.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean he sees this like wolf God and he's like you're not a wolf God prove.
Scott: You're the wolf God.
Scott: Oh shit, you proved the wolf God.
Rym: Oh my god see, I think that's the point.
Rym: that pushed the show over the line because The show was you know serious, but that was the funniest joke in the whole show.
Rym: Oh my god There's there's a there's a little.
Scott: it's not a comedy show, but that was a funny bit.
Rym: It was it was more of.
Rym: it was one of those kind of Jokes that is in the context of the show like a character makes a joke.
Scott: It was sort of an Admiral Pelle.
Scott: you joke if you will it very much was a Pelle.
Rym: You're like, oh you think that's a good idea.
Rym: You really think that's a good.
Rym: Well, you're right.
Rym: It is a good idea.
Scott: No But basically this is part where he's like well, you know prove you're the wolf God.
Scott: She's like oh you want me to transform into my real form.
Rym: and he's like yes transform into your real.
Scott: He's like.
Scott: are you sure he's like?
Scott: yes.
Scott: Well.
Scott: Are you sure no matter what?
Scott: yes?
Scott: I'm sure 100% no matter what she's like.
Rym: well Transforming like that.
Rym: There's always a cost.
Rym: I have to enact a price in order to do that.
Rym: He's like all right What's the price?
Rym: and she's like blood?
Rym: Um Before he's like ah and then she's like or a very small amount of wheats.
Scott: Yeah, he's like.
Scott: oh use the week You sure?
Scott: yes, yes, please use the wheat.
Rym: The show is I guess the the reason I think these two shows regardless of how good they might end up actually being or not being that Lovely complex and spice and wolf as opposed to the vast majority of the new anime out there that I've seen in the last few years They don't fall into the stereotypes immediately and The characters and the designs and just the way they play out.
Rym: or they have heart they have they have charm they have something a little bit fresh and Shows like persona Trinity are just so sterile and boring and bland and not boring in the good way like gassaraki but boring in the bad way like persona Trinity.
Scott: Yeah, I mean lovely complex.
Scott: I care about the characters and if spice and wolf I really care about the plot That's going on there, and you know I guess I care about the characters a little bit in spice and wolf And the plot of lovely complex not at all because there isn't one.
Rym: But the only problem with spice and wolf is that she totally looks like a fox and not a wolf But that's for sure.
Rym: I think that's just because of the coloring because she's a she's a wolf goddess But she's the protector of the harvest so she's kind of supposed to be wheat grain that sort of thing.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, these aren't like the best shows ever by any means, but if you're looking for the new animes Is two that you know can serve two different purposes one for the serious kind of anime watching times and one for the?
Scott: Hilarious slapstick anime watching time you know what.
Scott: and one for the never One for the torturing your friends with incredibly boring anime time.
Rym: or if you have bad taste or if you have bad taste or if you Really really have already seen every show that involves things that may or may not be robot like fighting because this is another one of those generic shows.
Scott: yeah I guess if you like if if if the show can be terrible and absolutely everybody.
Scott: a show can be terrible But like robots is enough for you, then psychic robots and for some eternity souls.
Rym: Yeah, like a show where the main character obviously has the special extra robot, which is a sword.
Rym: Yes, because the sword is always better than a gun Beats everything don't you know that?
Rym: But these other two shows Particularly spice and wolf.
Rym: if you it's the same level of scrap princess I would say I say pretty much exactly.
Scott: spice and wolf and scrap princess are like right in line like BAM.
Rym: They're like a solid a-minus b-plus anime.
Scott: There's something like that.
Scott: They're the same kind of show same genre.
Rym: you like one you like the other and also I will admit Horro the wolf goddess is really really freaking cute, but but and I really I think she is she's kind of normal anime girl Levels.
Rym: well why I mean the years.
Rym: I think the years make her cute.
Scott: I think this is cuz you're furry.
Rym: What can I say?
Rym: I like fox ears and that sort of thing but what what?
Rym: what makes her cute?
Rym: Is that there you?
Rym: I kind of expected this show to go in a bad moe kind of.
Rym: protect me big brother.
Rym: you know that kind of show but the wolf goddess is is she acts the way you would expect a minor God or you know a deity to act and that She's kind of sarcastic and really powerful.
Scott: yeah, she definitely doesn't take any crap.
Scott: I do think that helps the show a lot.
Scott: and what prevents me from being turned off by the girl with the ears in the Tail is that the girl with ears in the tail is the only person with ears in the tail and everyone else is normal and She doesn't act like some moe Whatever she acts like.
Scott: you know the character should act it.
Rym: Just you know ears in a tail throw I don't know Ephemeral or fairy or pixie like and in terms of temperament and that sort of thing.
Rym: and I think that plus the fact that the Plot looks like it might go toward the lines of you know the old ways in the new way
Scott: I definitely think the slide
Rym: is
Scott: definitely heading towards some sort of Medieval war feudalism kind of plot going on there historical something with a little bit of supernatural thrown on top there
Rym: And that that's.
Rym: I guess I've had an itch for that sort of thing for a long time.
Scott: It's gonna be like the Pope versus some feudal lords with some magic on one side.
Rym: I think that's why Claymore appealed to me so much when I first started.
Scott: It's definitely.
Scott: I think it's definitely got some Claymore ishness going on in there in the.
Scott: in the way the medieval world is portrayed You know it's sort of like the way the towns and the villages of the normal people living in them There's.
Scott: the people in the Claymore towns are more sad and the people who this place in Wolftown are happier.
Rym: But if anything the Claymore universe as far as I can tell is basically the same as the universe in Simon's quest.
Rym: Everything sucks.
Rym: It's always dark and everywhere you go people die constantly.
Scott: That's pretty accurate.
Rym: Yeah, of course much like the Middle Ages We should.
Scott: maybe when I Claymore comes out on DVD if it's not already we can watch that.
Rym: Yeah, but I want to finish ergo proxy first because I really want to see the end of that.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: did the out of business genie on ever finish?
Scott: that were the mostly out of business genie on ever.
Rym: I'm sure I will find a way to see the rest of that one way or another.
Scott: I'm sure it can't be impossible.
Rym: But yeah spice and wolf worth watching lovely complex worth watching persona Trinity Pretend it doesn't exist.
Rym: I'm better off watch darker than black first because of those kinds of shows I think that one has more potential than this.
Scott: Yeah, well, we only watch like one or two episodes of that one and it has a lot more potential than this.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.