Rym: It's Monday January 14th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talked a bit about virtualization.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, I survived a skiing.
Scott: Yeah, you and a whole bunch of other people.
Scott: Yeah barely, but not everybody Everybody indeed.
Scott: I'm sure there were some skiing accidents in the recent times However, not so many where we were.
Rym: but It was kind of funny because you know I haven't skied in over a decade.
Rym: and Scott the other Scott the more adventurous Scott who I went who with whom I went skiing Was uh, also had he hadn't skied a long time.
Rym: It was like eight years for him.
Rym: So the whole time I usually you think I'm the one who's kind of rash.
Rym: I'm there was like screw it Let's just go.
Rym: but this time I was like, you know, maybe we should Go a little easy on this.
Rym: Maybe we should.
Rym: I don't know if I can still ski and he's like nah It's like riding a bike.
Rym: You never forget this deal.
Rym: No how to ski.
Rym: You'll start going down the mountain.
Rym: You'll be fine.
Rym: So we get there.
Rym: but I rent my little skis and the first thing I notice is that skis don't look Like they look the last time I skied anymore.
Rym: They look a lot different.
Scott: Are they just flat sticks?
Scott: Well, the thing is, you know pointy bit that's curved at the end and then straight in the back.
Rym: I rented skis and you know, I got.
Scott: why do they have a curved pointy bit in the front?
Rym: Well, actually they didn't.
Rym: now they don't anymore.
Rym: now they have a wide kind of like bloop at the front uh-huh, but anyway that I used to have slightly longer skis with a sharp point at the end and now they gave me shorter skis and There was a blue blobby bit at the end Which apparently makes it like ten times easier to turn and control the thing and it doesn't impact your speed at all.
Rym: So it's just like technology got better.
Scott: So why didn't they make it that way originally?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm standing in my skis.
Rym: I'm like, alright and I move myself around.
Rym: I'm like, alright, I think I remember how this goes.
Rym: I'm like, oh, yeah, I can do the snow plow and I can do the parallel whatever and let's go.
Rym: so He's like black diamond and I'm like bunny hill.
Rym: So we go to the bunny hill, you know, the little green go down it and we look at each other like wow That was a lot easier than I thought.
Rym: Yeah, I could turn holy crap and we didn't fall over.
Rym: Let's go to the normal hills and we did a few of the normal hills and every time we did fine I could turn.
Rym: I got going a little fast.
Rym: I'm like, maybe I should slow down and then I slowed down and I didn't fall over.
Rym: So we're standing there at the bottom of like our third intermediate hill and Scott Johnson says to me, you know what?
Rym: Either we're really overconfident and we're missing something or we got a lot better at skiing than we were eight to ten years ago Or maybe that Particular skiing place was like easy.
Rym: Well, the thing is and
Scott: it was like the woods mountain in general
Rym: there is definitely some truth to the fact that with a lot of things that are physical skills if you do them along like you do them a lot and then you Stop doing them for a while and then you do them again a lot of times you almost get better After you have that interval because you kind of forget all the bad habits But you still have the muscle memory for some of the good habits and it's like you get to start all over.
Rym: You're born again and skiing and sometimes and that seemed to be the case.
Rym: So we're like, all right let's go over to the East Mountain hit those black diamonds and Get up.
Rym: we go down and hey This isn't so bad.
Rym: and then I stop and he's behind me and he's like, why'd you stop?
Rym: We get up there and basically a cliff and there's no way except to go down this cliff.
Rym: now We're looking at it and we're like, well, what do we do?
Rym: and I say fuck it.
Rym: I just go down.
Scott: Well, you know much of a choice.
Scott: I mean you can't go back up, right?
Rym: Well, what what the protocol is if you suck and you go somewhere you're not.
Rym: you're like you can't make it down.
Rym: You're supposed to just sidestep your way down the stupid mountain for like an hour.
Scott: Okay, but what if you can't even do that?
Scott: What if you're stuck on the mountain?
Rym: Well, then you take your skis off and you walk down.
Scott: Oh, is it so?
Scott: I thought but if it's a cliff You can't really walk.
Rym: Well, if you walk laterally eventually, you'll find a place you can walk down.
Rym: Okay, or with those you can usually walk back up or you just wait for ski patrol to find you.
Scott: Okay, let's say the ski patrol finds you then what do they do.
Rym: They'll probably put you on a stretcher and then pull you up the mountain or down the mountain or snowmobile or something laterally Or there's a lot of things they can do.
Rym: Hey, but anyway, I'm just.
Scott: I guess the mountain I'm imagining is like there's nowhere to go.
Rym: So I'm going down and I'm thinking all right this is the the moment of truth because there's a turn coming up and I wasn't sure up until this point if all the fat I'd been turning a lot and slowing down is feeding up and I couldn't Really proved myself if that was accidental.
Rym: I couldn't really figure out if I was going where I expected to be going or if you're just kind of luck that I wasn't running into anything.
Rym: and now there's basically a 90-degree turn at the end of this cliff and My body just turned and everything worked.
Rym: So I think I can ski again.
Rym: So a lot of people can ski so fast forward about I don't know 15 minutes And we've done every black diamond except one and the one we haven't done has a big warning on it warning ungroomed Moguls.
Rym: now mogul is just a stupid skiing word.
Rym: That means a big bump.
Scott: Yeah, I think people know what they are.
Rym: I think a lot of people don't know.
Scott: How could you not know?
Rym: you live in the south and you never been skiing never seen snow And they don't need to know.
Rym: well now you do.
Rym: That's why I if I say mogul and someone's never heard of that term They're gonna think what what the fuck mogul?
Scott: if they if someone lives somewhere where there's no snow then they already stopped listening.
Rym: Probably not because skiing is interesting, especially when you see people Epically fail at it.
Scott: go on YouTube search for skiing accident.
Scott: Well funny stuffs.
Rym: the funniest thing I think we watched this one video where this guy he survived so it wasn't bad.
Rym: But he's doing this like basically it's this gigantic cliff and the camera zoom so far out that it's like wow I can't believe he's doing it.
Rym: then we're watching.
Rym: I'm like, wait a minute.
Rym: There's no way to know.
Rym: He's skiing for all we know.
Rym: He's just rolling down this hill.
Rym: He's already dead or something.
Rym: and then as he gets closer and zoomed in sure enough.
Rym: He hasn't been skiing for some time He's just going head over heels down this mountain.
Scott: Yeah, it was kind of.
Scott: I was afraid it was a snuff film, but it wasn't.
Rym: but then at the end He just gets up.
Rym: Yes, you see him going like ah shit, but he's fine.
Scott: Well, he wasn't fine.
Scott: Well, he's conscious.
Scott: He lived.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: So to make a long story short Scott Johnson and I are standing there at the top of this basically 90 foot or so cliff covered in moguls and He's basically trying to egg me into going down it and I keep saying well All right, you go first and because you're the more experienced skier and he's like, yeah All right, but he wouldn't move.
Rym: and then he's like, yeah, you'll be fine.
Rym: You'll make it and eventually I'm like, yeah I will make it I will.
Rym: let's do this.
Rym: and I jump down and I barely come to a stop on this first mogul and I'm Maybe 10 feet down from the point of no return and I'm facing left and I'm on this mogul and I'm thinking all right There's a mogul about 10 feet down from me.
Rym: As long as I'm facing in the opposite direction by the time I get to that mogul I can do the rest of this.
Rym: I'm gonna be okay.
Rym: So I try to jump do a little pivot turn and I only made it about half way.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: I'm facing directly at the mogul.
Rym: Then I hit the mogul let him in the air Then I land on the next mogul some distance down on my stomach which bounces me back up into the air.
Rym: Then I land on my head and flip head over heels like three times and then I kind of roll to a stop.
Scott: So, why were these ungroomed when they groom them?
Rym: because that's where the awesome skiers go to have awesome times Or where people like me go to hurt myself because I mean on the Olympics they have the moguls, but they're all groomed.
Scott: It's like these nice even bumps like their eat.
Scott: They're all that that and the people go boing boing boing boing boing boing.
Rym: I mean, I saw people doing that with these moguls.
Rym: I just am not that good at skiing.
Rym: But And the funniest thing was before we went down there was a crowd of like 10 other people Standing there like all along with us.
Rym: Everyone's like you're gonna do it man.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I saw someone wait a second you if you went up to the top of this thing, right?
Scott: Wasn't there any?
Scott: there was no option but to do it.
Rym: Oh, no, there was.
Rym: I could go laterally and then there's another great completely smooth slope that I already done twice.
Scott: Okay, but what if you didn't want to do either one of those?
Rym: Well, then I was fucked and I was stupid.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Yes, that sounds I was checking.
Scott: It's like when you go in the water slide, right?
Scott: It's like you can go up the stairs.
Scott: they go halfway up for the stairs to go all the way up.
Scott: But if you go the all the way up the stairs, you know You can't go down the stairs and there's only like maybe three slides up there.
Scott: It's like well, you can't go down one of the slides this half way.
Scott: Yes, you have to take Slides, you don't have a choice.
Rym: see that's the way.
Rym: skiing has this rating system and the rating system is basically How good do you have to be to guarantee that you will not hurt yourself severely?
Rym: And it's like the bunny hill, you know the green circle.
Rym: then it's the blue square, which is pretty much everything.
Rym: It's like if you are able to ski you will not hurt yourself on a blue square.
Rym: And then there's black diamond, which is unless you are confident in your abilities and a proficient skier Then black diamond.
Rym: There's a good chance that you will break something something you don't want to break Alrighty, so.
Rym: and then there's double black diamond, which is basically I regard a short thrill more so than my own life.
Rym: Okay, I don't think I'll ever ski down a black diamond.
Rym: I have no interest in that whatsoever.
Rym: I think those moguls were the worst I'll ever do.
Rym: but the funniest thing was not only was this crowd of people kind of egging Each other on and Scott Johnson included egging me on Why they egg each other on.
Scott: people want each other to get hurt.
Rym: Well, the funniest thing was ski patrol is standing there and I note that They did not stop me or anyone else from hurting themselves here.
Rym: And in fact, they were standing there smiling and I'm sure they were just waiting for us to go down.
Scott: Do they want to see someone get hurt?
Scott: I guess it makes their day interesting and she skis over.
Rym: She's like you.
Rym: okay I'm like, yeah, can you go get my skis?
Scott: Wait, how did he ski over?
Scott: or were they just at the top with everyone else?
Rym: Yeah, they're just awesome skiers.
Rym: They just skied right down to me.
Scott: Oh, but they can't go back up though.
Scott: Once they start going down They got to go all the way down.
Rym: Well, they get went halfway down.
Rym: they grabbed my skis and then they went the rest of the way down.
Scott: No, and then you sort of rolled down.
Rym: then I. well actually I was still on the moguls like on the cliff when they gave Me my stuff bag.
Rym: So I spent a while.
Rym: It was really hard to put that ski back on without falling And then I get it on and I'm thinking how to fuck it and I just jump and I do the same thing I did Before but this time it worked
Scott: and I made
Rym: it down and I didn't see what happened to Scott Johnson.
Rym: But from what he tells me his ski fell off while he was turning and he had a similar fate.
Rym: All right, but he didn't hurt his neck like I did Get a new neck.
Rym: I don't think I broke my neck.
Rym: So I think I'm okay.
Scott: Your neck's no good.
Rym: Anyway, my neck's fine.
Scott: No, it's a crap neck.
Rym: I got a good neck.
Rym: I got a nice long neck.
Scott: now you get a. you get a better neck out of a Turkey at the supermarket.
Rym: Why you could have at least said like giraffe or something?
Rym: No, no draft They got the Kings of next right there.
Scott: your half necks are no good You do.
Scott: you actually have a slow reaction time because it takes so long for the signal from your brain to get to your body.
Rym: Well, I could just have two brains.
Scott: You have two brains.
Scott: You need a third brain All right.
Scott: So, uh So last night I got like the worst sleep I got in forever.
Scott: Cuz sorry about that Should've locked your door Around like, you know, I went to bed like 10 11 ish something like that, right?
Scott: I went to bed at like 9 after taking a whole bunch of aspirin because I my neck still hurts and then Frickin, you know all of a sudden I wake up and every day And I'm like what the fuck.
Rym: and I Love that feeling where you your brain hasn't woken up enough yet to figure out what the hell's going on.
Scott: Not only was I startled and awoken right and such right, but I realized that it was the UPS's stupid UPS's.
Rym: now I find it funny that both UPS's in your room went off, but the one in my room was just fine.
Scott: I don't know what the fuck is going on with them.
Scott: I have to look it up and see what exactly that particular beat means.
Rym: But anyway, you know what that that's the chief UPS.
Rym: that beat means something happened.
Rym: Ah shit That's it UPS beefs no matter what.
Scott: so I just turned him off.
Scott: I didn't care I just pushed the buttons on him or shut him up as quickly as possible.
Rym: You know, that's what I did the last time that happened to me.
Scott: Yeah, do you cares that the computer just turns off?
Scott: I don't give a shit.
Scott: The thing is.
Rym: the last time that happened to me when the power actually went out I remember laying there and I hit my alarm clock until I thought I broke it and the sound didn't stop.
Rym: then I grabbed my Cellphone.
Rym: I'm just like squeezing it trying to hit buttons on it and nothing.
Rym: So I've got my blackberry and I'm like throwing it around like why won't it stop?
Rym: like oh wait I go over to the UPS and there that was it.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah the Base I turn them both off.
Scott: then my clock was off and I'm just like fuck.
Scott: So I go and I take my cell phone.
Scott: I'm like, I'll set the cell phone alarm, right That's why I always use the cell phone alarm.
Scott: So I guess at the cell phone alarm to 6 a.m.
Scott: But the cell phone only said 1 a.m I was like fuck.
Scott: I Imagine it would be like 4 it's 3 or something or in the morning.
Scott: But
Rym: yeah I actually had one of those really like, you know those nights where you sleep and you feel like you slept forever And then you wake up and you only been asleep for like an hour and then you go back to sleep and the same thing Just keeps happening over and over again.
Rym: I'd like the best night's sleep.
Scott: I that ever lie the worst.
Scott: but then like it was not only was I just awoken rudely It wasn't just a rude awakening It was also like I was.
Scott: I was awoken while my body was like digesting something.
Scott: So my stomach was like all uncomfortable Like I felt like complete shit, but I I went back to bed right.
Scott: but then a few hours later Like I never got fully awoken again.
Scott: But I never actually got fully to sleep for an extended period of time because all sorts of plows and other things outside Kept in.
Rym: Oh, yeah, because of that blizzard.
Rym: Yeah, it wasn't a blizzard It was supposed to be a blizzard.
Scott: Yeah It was just being a bit of snow like not even an inch and it was just kind of it melted in the mornings.
Scott: It's just wet.
Scott: It was just mush.
Rym: But well when I got up there was actually still snow everywhere.
Scott: Yeah, all these plows and things kept fucking intermittently waking me up partially.
Scott: He's terrible.
Rym: So, huh.
Scott: and then in the morning right I wanted to like, you know, I had to update my iPod whatever.
Scott: So I wanted to like VNC to the downstairs whatever.
Scott: so get my laptop.
Scott: I turn it on but I can't get DHCP because the server's off.
Rym: Oh pie cuz he turned the UPS off.
Scott: so I was trying to like turn back on the.
Scott: You know the DHCP on the server on the on the router, so I'd had to turn the server back on.
Rym: You know, you could set up an alternate network profile where if you don't have a lease and whatever It'll just take an IP address.
Rym: just reserve once then no one else gets it with DHCP.
Scott: I know I know and then set it up with.
Rym: you know, it's like 129 21 21 1 my favorite DNS server in the world.
Rym: No, I still use that thing, but then I was gonna.
Scott: Basically, what I did is I just took the server.
Scott: I turned the UPS.
Scott: I unplugged the server.
Scott: I turned the UPS on.
Scott: it didn't beep.
Scott: I plugged the server into the non battery-powered port and then I turned the laptop on and I went.
Scott: Yeah, it was it was not good.
Scott: Hopefully tonight will be better and I gotta do some UPS research to solve this fucking problem.
Scott: I never want to be awoken rudely by my computer not turning off.
Scott: I mean it should only beep of this trouble.
Rym: Well, the thing is we bought the cheapest you.
Rym: they don't have any sort of intelligent communication at all.
Scott: They have two modes working and I Just wish they wouldn't go Just fucking.
Scott: if you're not working just fucking, you know, drain your battery and then shut up.
Rym: Well, you could just buy a better UPS.
Scott: I think that's what's gonna happen.
Scott: It's what's gotta happen.
Rym: so speaking of UPS is According to slash dot Ford claims ownership of your pictures.
Scott: There's nothing to do.
Rym: UPS UPS that's my classic non sequitur sequitur.
Scott: It's not good You don't like it.
Scott: No fine.
Rym: You try to say I don't like it.
Rym: You're trying to segue from UPS's into Ford.
Scott: How about here?
Scott: I have some news that's unrelated.
Scott: Let me read it to you.
Rym: It's barely even tech news, but it's copyright and I feel like that seems to fall under Monday.
Scott: Well, I think it's intellectual property and technology Really are two separate topics law and technology.
Scott: But the thing is is that Geeks are really only interested in law unless they're law geeks When it relates to technology and it seems to relate to technology quite a bit in fact it seems to relate to all geekeries and specifically the intellectual property law seems to relate to all geekeries because all geekeries are all about creating and using intellectual property in some way.
Rym: There might have been a momentary interruption there.
Rym: I'm not even gonna try to cover it over because I don't really care.
Rym: but Speaking of we were talking about UPS's and power going out.
Rym: I was fiddling with my computer for various reasons and I'd rebooted and I changed my grub and everything and I forgot to disable APIC and LAPIC which on my motherboard with the current Linux kernels is a trouble.
Scott: I thought you uh, are you like gut seeing?
Scott: shouldn't that fix that problem?
Rym: No, he doesn't fix that for shit.
Scott: No, they shouldn't.
Scott: that's gets kind of screwed up.
Rym: Yeah, it is but I look on the internet.
Rym: everyone has this problem with his motherboard and with similar motherboards.
Scott: So That's that's the kind of shit needs fixing.
Rym: thing is APIC has always been finicky with Linux.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what the hell that problem is because I never had a problem with it on my computer.
Rym: I think it depends on just what chipsets and whatever.
Rym: but Anyway, so my computer crashed but luckily.
Rym: luckily because we're all cool here.
Rym: I mean, I got my UPS and everything, but I also have the Marantz plugged into the UPS Recording to flash all the time with the fancy mixer.
Rym: that lets me do this trivially.
Rym: So I got a backup no matter what.
Scott: Oh backups.
Scott: So before this part of the show, it was all backup.
Rym: Yep So also I'll find out now if I've set that up right to sound good But it should sound the same as the normal show.
Rym: So let me know if it sounded different All right.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, the gist of this story is that Someone some group of like auto enthusiasts own some Ford cars that they fancify up and cuz they're a little club.
Rym: They wanted to make a poster or a cat like a calendar Yep, and every month has pictures of the cars they own with all the fancy things they've done to them.
Rym: They were gonna sell it among themselves as a little fundraiser and cafe press or whatever and then a Ford Motor Company stepped in and said ah, we own the trademark to Ford cars.
Rym: Fuck you, if you do that will sue you.
Scott: well, that's not exactly.
Rym: what they exactly did was trademark Infringement.
Scott: that cannot be done through cafe press whatever exactly, you know cafe press was like and then Ford was like cafe press.
Scott: don't do that.
Rym: Yeah, effectively what Ford has said is that if you take even if you own a Ford car You cannot in any way use other than you know Non-trademark infringing ways though.
Rym: I'm dubious as to how much of a trademark infringement this is, but I'll get to that.
Scott: Yeah, I mean what if I take a picture of my car and put it on Flickr with a Creative Commons license?
Scott: How am I doing?
Scott: Is that wrong?
Rym: Yeah, or what if?
Rym: what if I want to make a t-shirt for myself of my car?
Rym: What if I want to make a t-shirt to sell to my friends of my car that I added a spin is to?
Rym: Yeah, see now what really bothers me.
Rym: is that in my mind?
Rym: Trademarks exist for two reasons because remember copyright and trademark and all these things didn't just always exist.
Rym: They were created in the in the legal structure of the United States for specific purposes and with trademark I'm of the mind that it serves two purposes or at least should serve two purposes.
Rym: that one it protects Corporations that have a that have a good standing in the marketplace because of their name.
Rym: say I'm Joey Jojo Shabbadoo shoes.
Rym: Well trademark prevents someone else from making Joey Jojo Shabbadoo shoes because you see I'm Joey Jojo And I run Joey Jojo Shabbadoo shoes now if someone else wanted to make Joey Jojo Shabbadoo computers There's nothing wrong with that because there's no way in the world an intelligent person would mistake Joey Jojo Shabbadoo computers for Joey Jojo Shabbadoo shoes mm-hmm.
Rym: now These there's.
Rym: there have been complications these ideas in the past like the fact that the only reason Apple computers was able to exist under That name despite the fact that there was also the Apple music label was because Apple computers agreed that it would only be computers and stuff and never music.
Rym: and then uh iTunes on all that came and the iPod and there was trickiness and that all worked out luckily But
Scott: well kinda
Rym: it worked out as best as it could have as far as we care yeah, but And the only other purpose I see the trademark has is that it protects consumers.
Scott: who?
Rym: Can use the names of companies to have a kind of to know how good or bad a company is to see the company's track record To be discerning consumers?
Rym: if I know that Joey Jojo Shabbadoo pizza tastes like ass Then I know not to buy Joey Jojo Shabbadoo.
Scott: Imagine if you know people.
Scott: I mean we look at brands right and brands for marketing people are awesome.
Scott: They love brands because they you know they can just market the brand itself.
Scott: They can get you to love the brand And then it doesn't matter what the actual thing is because you love the brand and that's a marketing people love to do.
Scott: But on the same token if we got rid of brands all together You'd be fucked.
Scott: you go to the store.
Rym: There'd be all these things with all these different labels on them or maybe no labels on the eight different Domino sugars and you know which one's the real domino sugar that you trust and which one is.
Rym: Joey Jojo Shabbadoo's found it in a truck that crashed somewhere.
Scott: Exactly so.
Rym: first you get the sugar.
Scott: You know it's like.
Scott: how would you you?
Scott: While brands are used to market to you and to get you to do things they also Protect you in a way because you you can you know you can trust something like.
Scott: you know What if there are all these iPods at the store and one of them was the real?
Scott: Apple iPod made by Apple you know And the other ones who knows God knows what Apple iPods.
Rym: I think a good reference here is the V. Yeah, the V but I'm of the mind that no intelligent person would mistake a Small auto enthusiast club that fancify up their Ford cars for the Ford Motor Company That makes cars especially since it's not like this cut.
Rym: It's not like this little Motor Club is selling their Ford cars as Ford cars.
Scott: Yeah There's that they took pictures of cars
Rym: that they own and they modify
Scott: Right and they made a calendar out of pictures that they took and the pictures they own the legal right to those pictures They took them right and they want to make a calendar out of pictures They took.
Scott: they're not competing with the Ford Motor Company.
Scott: The what they're doing does it doesn't harm the trademark of the Ford Motor Company in any way.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: you know damaging.
Scott: it won't give people you know.
Scott: If this calendar will not change people's minds to make them think the Ford Motor Company is bad in any way It's really just bullshit.
Scott: I don't think trademark should apply at all.
Rym: So yeah, I don't know what the actual legal full result of this will be but I Feel that the moral imperative is on the side of the small auto enthusiast club and not the Ford Motor Company.
Rym: I'd say I'll boycott Ford but I've never owned a Ford.
Scott: if I never will I Guess my Mazda is a Ford.
Rym: Yeah, but if you want to get into the semantics about who actually makes cars.
Rym: That's a whole other show.
Rym: All right granted I've driven nothing but like Pontiac so Well, it's the same as a Chevy.
Scott: Yep, and whatever.
Scott: Anyway, so a lot of things happen to the CES and we could talk about a whole bunch of them.
Scott: probably over the next few Weeks, we'll probably whittle through them as Oh next week.
Rym: I'm gonna talk about nothing but laptops.
Scott: okay, but anyway and You know the Mac world the big Steve Jobs is tomorrow.
Rym: Oh, man I might watch it live just because if they announce don't watch it live, that's stupid.
Scott: Just go to engage it, right?
Scott: No, no does the live blog?
Rym: cuz I didn't lay when I was at IBM the way I quote-unquote watch it live was I went to IRC.
Scott: No Just go to engage it.
Scott: and there's a live blog and they're doing the live blog this time where the newest parts are at the Really yes, cuz they was a vote today on and gadget because they usually put the newest stuff at the bottom Which is not what I wanted.
Scott: It's a reload scroll reload scroll.
Scott: But the reason they do it that way is that when all is said and done someone who comes to the site after the event is over can read it straight through and What they're gonna do is while the event is going on they're gonna do it with the newest stuff at the top.
Rym: All right That's my solution now.
Scott: and then you just reload the page as it goes on and as soon as it's over They're gonna flip the whole thing up.
Rym: because if Apple announces a laptop that is cool enough for me I am but it's pretty much if they announce a cool laptop.
Rym: I'm buying it.
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: you got to come down to the store.
Scott: Check it out.
Scott: You can't be too sure about.
Rym: well No as in when I say I'm buying it I mean unless something unless a factor appears to dissuade me I will buy it.
Rym: now a factor might appear like it's eight thousand dollars or I go to the store and everyone I try breaks And smells like cheese.
Scott: I think I think they definitely depends on great many factors whether it be worth buying.
Rym: But at the same time if I'm dissuaded then I already know what laptop I'm gonna buy.
Rym: and if I'm dissuaded from that I've got like nine other choices because it's laptop season, baby It sure is.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But anyway, a lot of things happen there.
Scott: Some of them were more interesting than others there, but it wasn't like super huge It wasn't super great.
Scott: But regardless the one thing that I thought was particularly interesting, right?
Scott: Let me tell you this story in the world of people who care about gadgets and whatnot.
Scott: They're basically two blogs.
Scott: There's gizmodo and in gadget.
Rym: right now one of these two might be better.
Scott: Well, okay what happened originally?
Scott: there was just gizmodo.
Scott: It was the only.
Scott: it was the one right?
Scott: I guess there are other gadget blogs, but gizmodo was the big one started by mr.
Scott: Peter Rojas Rojas.
Scott: anyway, he's cool guy rock jaw.
Scott: No Peter Rojas.
Scott: Oh no, so he started gizmodo and It was.
Scott: I don't know if it was part of Gawker media from the beginning It doesn't matter but it was part.
Scott: It's part of Gawker media now, and that's a company that owns Kotaku and Joystick.
Scott: I think now not joystick and gadget and joystick are together.
Scott: No, they own Kotaku and Jalopnik, that's the one and all button Gawker and anyway, and they own a bunch of blogs.
Scott: They're all together right.
Scott: and then there's in gadget, which is part of weblogs Inc, right?
Scott: Basically Peter Rojas left gizmodo because weblogs Inc.
Scott: hired him and which is a Well, which is Time Warner, which is right.
Scott: So in gadget is is owned by AOL and so is joystick and whatever.
Scott: So Peter Rojas now works for the in gadget and even though he started the gizmodo and the gizmodo is still owned by Gawker Which is the same people's Kotaku and it's separate.
Scott: This is not what you care about No, and for a while, they've been sort of the competing gadget blogs.
Rym: Yes competing.
Rym: I have many analogies as to what kind of competition it is or who might be winning.
Scott: Well for a while it was pretty much they were almost exactly the same site.
Scott: You can see the same stories on both sides with slightly different writing similar pictures.
Scott: It wasn't really one wasn't better than the other it was just huh?
Scott: There's two sites and he read both of them.
Scott: You can't possibly miss any gadget news.
Scott: It won't happen right.
Scott: and gadget has some spin-offs like in gadget HD or in gadget mobile, but those don't matter anyway.
Scott: It all started to go downhill for gizmodo quite recently.
Scott: Basically there was an incident where Kotaku remember owned by the same people as gizmodo.
Scott: gizmodo basically I don't know.
Scott: they must have had access to Kotaku somehow because they're both the same company and they put the horrible tub girl picture on Kotaku.
Rym: now had they put a pirate flag or a fake story or a Picture of the laughing man or just change the logo to their logo.
Rym: That would have been awesome.
Rym: Tub girl like you know There's a line like having a bucket of water over a door is a good prank.
Rym: Having a bucket of tire irons that really kind of goes beyond prank and into criminal assault.
Scott: pretty much.
Scott: and this is the same company Here, you know.
Scott: and it's like what the hell they doing in Kotaku, you know Kotaku's owned by the same company But the editors and writers over there.
Scott: They're they're professionals.
Scott: They're not.
Scott: they're like what the fuck gizmodo.
Scott: That was fucking stupid You know, what's the fuck is wrong with you?
Scott: It's like it's like this Misbehaving child and they had to give it a spanking, you know, it's like it's like if your sibling is all misbehaving.
Scott: You're like what the fuck?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, that was that was the start of gizmodo's downhill and that was around around that point.
Scott: I just thought I cut them out of my you know, blah.
Scott: All right, Google Reader there.
Scott: He's now goodbye.
Rym: I I would wager that gizmodo Really really wants to kind of have this image of.
Rym: where are the edgy ones?
Rym: We're the people who who do the bad things.
Rym: We're the bad boys of gadget news.
Rym: Because that because they pulled this shit again, I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, basically at CES, right?
Scott: They got a TV be gone and a TV be gone If you don't know is this little thing and it's you know, you push a button on it and it has in it programmed.
Rym: You know the power button infrared codes for basically every television and it's kind of cycles through them in order of like which ones are most popular out there to try to Turn off every TV in the vicinity, right?
Scott: So you just point it at some TVs push the button and wait and it eventually like a minute or two Will probably turn those TVs off.
Scott: if you know, they're infrared receivers aren't blocked.
Scott: So they went around CES and turn TVs off while people are giving presentations on those TVs.
Scott: now, I Mean for an attendee of CES.
Scott: this could be like a funny joke if you're just some punk kids But I mean you're depressed.
Scott: they had pressed badges.
Scott: They're professionals going around turning off TVs of people's presentations like he.
Rym: Now the thing is if they had done it just once to a Rival or something and then they came up straight forward like yeah, that was us.
Scott: No, they posted it on their site and then later they were like shit guys.
Scott: Maybe that wasn't so funny.
Scott: Yeah, maybe we better write something But yeah, they put it on their site to get traffic to it.
Scott: now I heard a thing on twit this morning.
Scott: Apparently the way the writers at gizmo at Gawker media are paid is they get paid a base salary But then they get paid based on the traffic they drive.
Scott: So if more people read your articles that you write for Gawker media, then you get more money.
Scott: So it's definitely a traffic, you know move they want it.
Scott: You know, they put that video of them turning TVs off on gizmodo and then people will come to see it.
Scott: now Just to show you how on you go.
Scott: listen our episode of being professional.
Scott: if you have any questions about this Why gizmodo is totally lame even though you know The first geek instinct might be to think that they're cool thing is there's.
Rym: I use this example a lot.
Rym: I think it's a good example, but there are a lot of other examples.
Rym: There's professionalism and then there is unprofessionalism and in between the two there is a magic land called Professionally unprofessional.
Rym: I think Dave and Joel's fast karate are good example of that where it feels really like unprofessional by the seat of the Pants, but at the same time it's really well done and put together and they're probably like what the fuck is I'm talking about.
Rym: But I've said this before because they have that they feel a lot less professional than they really are.
Rym: But they don't feel that in a bad way.
Rym: But gizmodo definitely doesn't has not achieved that balance.
Scott: No, they haven't.
Scott: they're definitely just unprofessional.
Scott: I mean and this isn't just you like some gizmodo writer we're talking about here if I was CES I probably would have banned them.
Scott: Oh, they banned the guy who did it for life from CES.
Rym: Oh, I would have banned.
Scott: Yes, I would have also banned all of gizmo.
Rym: I was out event all of gizmodo for one year.
Scott: I would have been all of Gawker media forever.
Rym: Whoo, cuz then Gawker would have come down.
Scott: Well, you know, there's no one.
Scott: there's no other people at Gawker who want to go to CES anyway, but no I mean they would have come down on.
Scott: But this is the gizmodo editor Brian lamb is it wasn't you know some writer.
Scott: this was the editor of gizmodo.
Scott: So there's definitely this culture of unprofessional sort of loserish is going on at gizmodo.
Scott: That's not good.
Scott: and to show you just how unprofessional this is.
Scott: Let me read the comments from dig.
Scott: I'm gonna read the day.
Rym: What are you going to dig for?
Scott: Listen, this will show you how bad it is how much how terrible it is If the dig comments are saying this, you know, it's bad.
Scott: You're ready.
Scott: I'm ready.
Scott: top cam comment on dig.
Scott: That's what happens in you act like a fucking douche.
Scott: Some of that video is funny but screwing over the guy who was trying to give a presentation was just plain fucked.
Scott: Wow and then the next one.
Scott: good that's exactly what should have happened.
Scott: CES is a place for journalists Not dim-witted pranksters screwing up.
Scott: Everyone's presentations extremely low-class.
Rym: on gizmodo's part Yeah coming out of dig.
Rym: It's kind of frightening to get something like dig.
Scott: comments are calling you unprofessional And they're saying that what you did was a dick move in low-class.
Scott: You got to feel pretty bad if as It's like a fortune was calling you low-class.
Scott: That's bad.
Scott: But yeah, the basically the thing that everyone's talking about now is like, oh is this gonna make you know Bloggers look bad and look unprofessional in general?
Scott: and I'm like, no I don't think so because I think in gadget showed the bloggers are very professional and high quality just makes gizmodo Look like a bunch of losers, which they are things of the day.
Rym: So this video is pretty cool.
Rym: I'd recommend you watch.
Rym: it's one of those art.
Rym: films is definitely Designed to be poignant and to make you think or feel something and be a little piece of art.
Rym: But what I've linked to here is just a video of 100 people aged 1 to 100 in order Striking a drum one time each.
Scott: well not exactly well.
Rym: that one guy misses a bunch of times That other guy hits it a whole bunch and that one guy actually knew how to drum.
Scott: Yeah, but This is the same drum.
Rym: this is a really interesting video because you basically see the progression of human aging among a whole bunch of different people and what I found the most fascinating was that pretty
Scott: much
Rym: people are in general pretty together with it up until about the 40s 50s and
Scott: Then
Rym: it seems like half the people are really sad and really bad.
Rym: and after people are super energetic And once you get past like 70, the only people left are pretty awesome Generally energetic people surprisingly.
Rym: It's like if you're if you're well enough to make it past a certain point You're probably gonna make it a whole lot longer than that.
Scott: another thing I noticed is that you know in the middle in you know, Pretty much the the health and the the vitality of people is pretty is a nice curve, you know as you would expect.
Scott: But when you get to the deep end where people are really old Like there were some 90 year olds who were looking better than some 70 year olds in there, you know It's really like hey kind of mixes up Yeah.
Rym: and the sad thing is once you hit 90 or so it really drops off.
Rym: and I'll admit that the way it ends is actually Kind of touching and sad.
Rym: and it is kind of sad how I guess The older people got after a certain point the more confused they were as to what what they're doing and what's going on in the room.
Scott: Yeah, some of them seemed happy though.
Rym: Oh, yeah, there's there's one old guy for it was like 80 or something 81 I think but I don't remember which number.
Rym: but There's this one old guy with white hair and I think he was the most distinguished looking gentleman I have ever seen.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that guy is a good guy.
Rym: Yeah, you'll know the guy when you see him.
Rym: You'll think wow That's James Bond if he were real and he were 80.
Scott: Yeah, that was a good guy.
Scott: I liked him.
Rym: that guy was probably some Duke or Lord or something.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: anyway, a lot of them were In the UK the Albion's Albion.
Scott: I sounded like it at least.
Rym: they were definitely Albion Australian.
Scott: we're all stupid.
Rym: I can't tell.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: I can tell the difference between a fake Albionic accent I almost had accident and I'm sure there's a joke there and a fake Australian accent.
Scott: Well a fake Albionic accent does sound like a accident bloody hell.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So on this show in the past I have talked about the fake medicines and how they pissed me off.
Scott: homie apathy.
Rym: It's not real.
Scott: It's not real and there's a lot of fake medicines that pissed me off.
Scott: And if you know think about it whether you not even considering any specific fake medicine.
Scott: Imagine if there was a fake medicine and someone was selling it as if it was real.
Scott: Isn't that like the worst thing ever?
Scott: now people who are sick and maybe Possibly could be cured and helped by real medicine are now instead using fake medicine and dying because someone fooled them into doing so.
Scott: It's it's pretty close to murder on the on the list of evil things selling fake medicine.
Scott: So fake medicine is bad whether you particularly think any particular medicine is fake or not.
Scott: now Hey, you know it.
Scott: usually you hear people like me or James or Andy or some other non science people talking about fake medicine.
Scott: science people People right.
Scott: so.
Scott: and you also hear fake medicine people talking about their own fake medicine.
Scott: and you hear well-meaning but you know deluded people who believe in fake medicine talking about how the fake medicine is so great and It's it's pretty hard to actually get doctors or anyone who's you know?
Scott: Sort of a someone you can trust a little bit more to talk about the fake medicine because they're too busy just doing medicine.
Scott: It's the same reason it's hard to get like a lot of Biologists to start, you know talking about evolution.
Rym: It's like when those quaint crazy nut jobs come.
Rym: they're like, yeah I have a quantum perpetual motion machine blah blah blah and quantum.
Rym: and they say yeah And the quantum physicists won't take me seriously.
Rym: They they're afraid of me.
Scott: The quantum says is just ignoring.
Scott: you could be so dumb.
Rym: He's doing quantum physics.
Rym: He doesn't care about you.
Rym: He already knows you're wrong and stupid.
Rym: and he just assumed Yeah, people are smart enough to realize that.
Scott: and the problem is that us smart people who are not quite if you're a physicist You're smart enough to spend your time doing quantum physics and ignoring people who say that perpetual motion machine And it creates a predicament for people like us who are smart like to know the perpetual motion machines are fake But don't have the credentials to sort of convince people more easily.
Rym: I like how you the way you phrase that and that kind of the pacing and the diction you use.
Rym: I guess diction isn't the right word, but you get my point was very much set up to equate us smart people with quantum physicists.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Anyway anyway.
Scott: So anyway, there's a blog that started semi recently.
Scott: it started on January 1st 2008. it's a very new blog and it's very very awesome.
Scott: this blog You know who blogs on this blog bloggers for doctors doctors in what real doctors?
Rym: Because I have a doctorate from a couple of fake internet schools.
Scott: Okay, let me tell you the knit before I will give you the credential.
Scott: I was gonna let you read the credentials of the four doctors on the site yourself, but I will read them to you.
Scott: Okay, first doctor Steven Novella academic clinical neurologist at Yale.
Scott: So he probably knows about the kiki booba, maybe doctor number two Wallace Sampson graduate of UC Berkeley with MD from UCSF a recovering hematologist oncologist.
Scott: He's old Harriet Hall MD known as the skep doc is a retired family physician who writes about pseudoscience As a BA and MD from University of Washington.
Rym: and the fourth one guys intention Internship in the Air Force.
Scott: Yes, the fourth MD guys.
Scott: The fourth one is David H Gorski MD PhD.
Scott: He is a surgical oncologist specializing in the breast cancer.
Scott: And actually I read his recent thing talking about breast cancer Randy.
Scott: But anyway Let me tell you some of the titles of some of the articles that are on this science blog.
Scott: The first one is announcing the science-based medicine blog.
Scott: Oh, by the way, the URL of this site is science-based medicine org all lowercase.
Scott: No spaces.
Scott: No hyphens.
Scott: No, nothing just science-based medicine org and will link to it.
Scott: Of course All right, the plant versus pharmaceutical false dichotomy.
Scott: Scrolling up homeopathy and evidence-based medicine back to the future part one.
Rym: It really bothers me that even that in this day and age You actually have to say the words Evidence-based.
Rym: Yeah, because there's some people there are people who think there's an alternative.
Scott: Well, it's actually.
Scott: it's really new.
Scott: I mean, how long really have we had Western science-based medicine?
Scott: Oh, yes, not even not even 200 years.
Scott: No, I've been my point.
Rym: However, is that we've got it.
Rym: We shouldn't?
Rym: it's like we've already transcended making stuff up.
Rym: We've already transcended just giving people stuff.
Scott: and now that we think about how long did it take, you know, we had evolution You know, not even as long and it still it takes time for the ideas to get around.
Rym: It is kind of scary.
Scott: How long did it take for us to get rid of you know?
Scott: Earth is the center of the solar system.
Rym: Well, there are people but You know, all right.
Scott: So who am I?
Scott: is another title?
Scott: Who am I?
Scott: Why am I here?
Scott: That's great Mercury in vaccines as a cause of autism and autism spectrum disorders.
Scott: a failed hypothesis.
Rym: Ah That's that's one of my biggest pet peeve issues.
Scott: and magnets heal question mark.
Scott: Do you hear there's actually a really sad story recently?
Rym: Let me guess someone had a disease and they use.
Scott: no no This is that you ready.
Scott: You want to hear the sad story.
Rym: someone ate some neodymium magnets.
Scott: No, it's related to the Autism, you know and vaccine.
Rym: someone didn't get a vaccine.
Scott: No It's even worse.
Scott: you ready for this.
Rym: I don't know if I want to hear this.
Scott: Well say if you want to or not Yeah, let's hear it.
Scott: Okay, so there's a lady.
Scott: She had a daughter who was autistic.
Scott: Right, or I think it was a daughter a child who was autistic.
Scott: I don't remember all the details, but I remember enough the important part.
Scott: She killed her own child.
Scott: Whoa, because she couldn't deal with the autism.
Scott: She said she loved her kid, but she hated the autism, right?
Scott: Why did she do it?
Scott: She blamed the autism on herself for getting the kid vaccinated and she was because she'd been convinced the vaccines is what caused it.
Rym: Wow
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: you know, I think I use this as news a while ago But I can't let everyone forget that the origin of the whole autism caused by vaccines bullshit was basically from a group of lawyers and doctors who colluded to make this happen in order to Generate lawsuits to make a whole bunch of money.
Scott: Yeah, it does sound like the conspiracy theory when we heard the way room said it just now.
Scott: but at the same time don't take Grim's word for it.
Scott: take the doctor's word for it at science-based medicine org.
Scott: Subscribe to this feed and read it.
Scott: every article they write the newest one is on the nature of alternative medicine cancer cure testimonials.
Scott: and it's really good because Towards the e first he talks about all that, you know, why people why there are these, you know, positive Testimonials for these fake cancer cures.
Scott: and he talks about people who have you know had you know?
Scott: And it's really interesting it's tough it's it's pretty crazy.
Scott: And then he like this one paragraph because this guy he's the.
Scott: you know He's the guy who's the breast cancer surgical oncologist who is the specialist in breast cancer.
Scott: and his one paragraph?
Scott: He just goes full-on with the science and it's just like whoa, but there's no arguing against that.
Scott: I mean hold on with the side not by me anyway, I just pull on with the science.
Scott: Whoa I Can really.
Scott: I could try to find that paragraph and read it but it is way sciency like god damn is it sciency?
Rym: So, uh, it is a Monday night.
Rym: What Scott are we gonna talk about?
Scott: Can it?
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Well All right.
Scott: Well, you know the Mac world is tomorrow, right?
Scott: I do right and The Mac world is tomorrow.
Scott: and but last week at CES Mac announced an upgrade to the Mac Pro and the Mac Pro if you Know is sort of the Mac Tower, you know They make the iMac is the desktop These the MacBook Pro and the MacBook which are the laptops and does the Mac
Rym: Pro?
Rym: the Mac Pro is the I do 3d Editing design right house and up until last week.
Scott: I had always you know, just the Mac Pro was not on my radar.
Scott: I mean, I knew it existed, but I didn't care about it.
Scott: I assumed maybe if I was a 3d person a graphic designer something like that The Mac Pro would be great for me Scott Rubin Mac Pro pretty useless.
Scott: I can ignore that.
Scott: right however, they announced that Mac Pro last week, so I saw the news about it and I took a look at it and Suddenly my mind started to shift.
Scott: I don't know and he I wrote a whole big thing in my blog about why I've been talking about why on You know Friday night party line and a whole bunch of other places.
Scott: I'm not gonna go into it But the one key factor in The reason that the Mac Pro was suddenly a consideration and not just a complete ignoring was that VMware Fusion existed and supposedly VMware Fusion would have allowed me to run and I guess it does allow me to run Windows and Linux and all that business alongside OS X without rebooting.
Scott: so in my mind Theoretically if the VMware Fusion worked as advertised which it doesn't is you can't play portal on it, right?
Scott: But If it works as advertised which it may one day it may one day do I could play my steam games run my Linux to do my real work and run Mac OS and Sync my iPod to iTunes and use adium and use Firefox.
Rym: Oh, man, adium that that alone is like the main reason I want to get a Mac laptop.
Scott: Yeah, adium is like a thousand times better than any.
Scott: I am client for anything.
Scott: But anyway Yes, so I could have done all that on one machine without having to reboot ever and I could have still had the option of rebooting in case the VMware Fusion didn't work to Windows, you know to play a game or something.
Scott: So the Mac Pro because of the VMware Fusion was possibly able to do those things and it was really appealing to me.
Scott: now You might be like hey, how does the VMware Fusion do that?
Scott: And that is the topic of tonight's show and not just VMware but virtualization in general.
Rym: now you a lot of people probably don't fully understand what things like VMware or virtualization do and a lot of what I want to talk about tonight is not so much how it works because you probably don't Care
Scott: but the difference
Rym: but the difference and then mostly why this is a big deal and why this is important?
Scott: Why what you use it for.
Rym: not just you but corporations and large entities have a very very big piece of this pie.
Scott: Yep, as I'll get to and there are a lot of ancillary issues related to virtualization such as virtualization and security and virtualization and you know We and efficiency and performance and we're not going to talk about those.
Scott: But yeah, let me start out.
Scott: I want to talk about the difference between a Virtual machine an emulator and wine because wine is neither.
Scott: wine is not an emulator nor is it a virtual machine.
Rym: wine is an API.
Scott: Anyway, yes, so let's talk about wine is first just quickly, right?
Rym: What wine is is is something that will never work on any program you want it to work on but it works Just fine.
Scott: anything you don't care actually works really well.
Scott: now met better than it ever has.
Rym: Yeah, it does.
Rym: I'll say this before we get going if you have used wine before you gave up because it sucked it did suck and you're not Don't.
Rym: you did suck don't forget.
Rym: I'm not gonna pretend it didn't suck.
Rym: It sucks so much less I think a lot of you.
Scott: just on a side note God tangents.
Scott: Ahoy, right?
Scott: Is that a lot of people, you know, they use Linux at some point or they use Linux application at some point and it's a bad experience and I can see why in many cases and then they know they assume that Experience hasn't changed that experience of Linux.
Scott: things changes daily.
Scott: It's open source.
Scott: There's people developing it constantly, you know.
Scott: So there's new versions of wine every week it then there's drastic improvements every week.
Scott: So you can't.
Scott: that's that's part of the thing that makes Linux great in general and open source Great, is that even if you had a bad experience with it, you had to come back and try it again.
Scott: It's better.
Scott: It keeps getting better constantly anyway, so Wine, what is wine?
Scott: wine is if you want to run you have a Windows application.
Scott: you want to run it in Linux, right?
Scott: So, how do you get it to run?
Scott: not easily?
Scott: You need to you know, basically now.
Rym: Well, why doesn't it work?
Rym: I mean, it's a. it's a x86.
Rym: We've talked about that before.
Rym: it's the same hardware.
Scott: Yep, the all the x86 instructions know how to talk to your Pentium chip or whatever your Intel chip.
Rym: Very likely you wrote a program that Uses some of the shit that Windows does for you.
Scott: So yeah, like it.
Scott: maybe it may be in the program They wrote.
Scott: they use the the code that makes the windows printing dialog show up or the windows file open dialog Or I just want to pop up a window and then I want to use like the windows graphic thing.
Rym: Well, you access those via an API and you know what.
Rym: Windows and Linux do not have the same API.
Scott: It's using all sorts of libraries which are basically a bunch of tools.
Scott: So you don't have to like I don't have to when I write a program that what makes a bunch of windows open up.
Scott: I don't have to write code to describe how windows work anymore.
Scott: I just say new window and windows already has the code to make windows show up.
Scott: But Linux has code to make windows show up, but it's a different code for making Linux windows.
Scott: So what they do is wine is a bunch is they basically from scratch?
Scott: wrote Libraries that are basically Functionally equivalent to the windows libraries, but they work in Linux and other operating systems.
Scott: So a Windows program when it would normally say hey windows open up a window wine says, huh?
Scott: He wants to open up a window.
Scott: Well, I have a library that knows how to do that and it basically is just replacing all those libraries, right?
Scott: It's not an emulator.
Scott: It's not a virtual machine.
Rym: It works.
Rym: Okay, there's performance hits whatever but we're not talking about that any further.
Scott: It's just a different set of libraries that were made from scratch that you're trying to copy the windows libraries that windows applications work.
Scott: Okay, so an emulator.
Scott: What is an emulator?
Scott: Well an emulator Very simply if room gets us, right?
Rym: All it does is like say I've got there's the good example.
Rym: You can all understand.
Rym: I got ROMs, right?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So let's say I used to have a Nintendo Entertainment System which is a piece of hardware and I used to play games on that which were also little pieces of hardware little chips and I don't have my Nintendo anymore, but I still want to play these games.
Rym: well I download an emulator like nesticle which basically recreates the Stuff that the hardware did and then I download a ROM which is basically an image of the hardware in the cartridge And I combine the two and it pretends to be a Nintendo Pretending to run that cartridge and I get to play the same game that I played on my NES back in the day.
Scott: Yep, basically what it does is it's it's sort of like a trend.
Scott: most emulators at least are translators.
Scott: You know you you want to run this Nintendo ROM, right?
Scott: So you need something to translate from Nintendo ROM language into personal computer language, right?
Scott: And the emulator will just sort of do that.
Scott: you know.
Scott: it looks at what the Nintendo cartridge wants to do.
Scott: it translates that into computer speak and it does it and then you're Computer understands it and then he goes back and it tells the NES ROM.
Scott: so it's basically translating between two different languages.
Scott: That's why it allows you to run Software say for a way different kind of computer on a way other different kind of computer.
Scott: It's you know, that's why you were able to run like, you know PlayStation 1 games on the Dreamcast with bleem You know stuff like that.
Scott: It's a translator.
Scott: Now virtual machine.
Scott: Virtual machine is what we're talking about today.
Scott: Virtual machine is exactly what it sounds like.
Scott: It's a fake machine.
Scott: I mean your computer is a machine, right?
Rym: Oh, yeah It's just.
Rym: you know binary bits running around in a processor being added to each other a whole bunch of times.
Scott: now What if I wanted to make a fake machine?
Scott: How do I do that with cardboard styrofoam?
Rym: Yes, that is exactly what virtual machines are.
Rym: They're little pieces of cardboard that you stick in your CD-ROM drive.
Scott: Oh, then why are they useful?
Scott: Now a virtual machine is basically instead of just making a translator from you know One kind of computer to another or redoing some libraries what they do is they write a bunch of code They make a program and the program itself Does the same thing the machine would do.
Scott: so you look at a penny an Intel chip, right?
Scott: And that it that x86 processor does certain things.
Scott: it takes x86 assembly instructions and it processes that.
Scott: you know, it takes those instructions It does those instructions are supposed to do and it outputs right?
Scott: I could write a piece of software Not a chip.
Scott: I could write a piece of software in code that can take x86 assembly instructions Figure out what they do, you know calculate what the output would be based on that input and then output that output.
Scott: you can Recreate a machine.
Scott: They say you can make in software a program that does the same thing.
Scott: the actual chip does You know?
Scott: I write a program in C and that program is exactly the same thing that a 486. does I Effectively have a 486?
Scott: if I go and get a program that will run on a 486 I can just run.
Scott: I can just give that program to the piece of software.
Scott: I wrote that is a 486 and it'll run.
Scott: so VMware and All these other virtual machine things VMware just being a very popular one.
Scott: There's also parallels and I guess bots and a whole bunch of other ones.
Rym: Well, you can use Plex 86.
Scott: No, yeah, there's another one.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of these things, right?
Scott: and what they do is I have a big computer and I run a virtual machine and that virtual machine basically makes a computer.
Scott: on That computer it runs a program and that program itself is effectively a Computer.
Rym: All right, let's cut to the chase now because I'm sure people are getting real bored real quick They are.
Rym: all that means is I can have a bunch of windows on my computer that each one of them is running a Whole operating system.
Rym: Yep, and I actually do this at work a lot at my in my office at work on my computer I have VMware workstation and in that VMware workstation I have like four different Ubuntu servers each one running different stuff and Whenever I want to do development or play with stuff or test anything I do it there.
Rym: that way I have this whole server environment that I can test on do whatever I want if I screw it up I just reload it from the default.
Rym: if I want to like say I want to make a cluster I make one then I clone it four times open all four change the names connect them all to each other.
Scott: Yep, you basically with only one physical computer can have as many computers that are effectively more.
Scott: it's it's like having a whole bunch of computers except you only have one and you can have as Many as you can get until you run out of memory or CPU.
Scott: and if that's why the Mac Pro is so appealing Because it had it would have eight cores and I'd probably get four gigs of RAM Thus allowing me to have plenty of Linux and Windows virtual machines and thus the fact that it was Mac OS X wouldn't bog me down.
Scott: So what are virtual machines useful for?
Rym: Well for the industry side of it one big thing that we were using them for a lot and I I've done this at other Jobs is basically say you got a whole bunch of old servers or old old old software that only runs on like OS 2 or something.
Scott: Keep an old shitty computer around that's running OS 2 that could break at any minute because it's an old shitty computer.
Rym: You can't install OS 2 on a new computer.
Scott: No, that's not gonna work.
Rym: So what if I build one?
Rym: Really really powerful server running Linux and on that Linux I run a hundred virtual machines.
Rym: Each one of them is an old OS 2 and each one of them is running one of those old applications from back in the day.
Scott: Yep I don't need to keep around my old shitty computers that could break down at any minute and probably use too much electricity And have parts that can't be fixed or replaced.
Scott: I can have a fancy new computer but all my old shitty software can run on these fake OS twos and the software doesn't know any better because as far as Disconcerned it's this just a program.
Scott: That is the same thing as the machine that old shitty machine We threw out.
Scott: but that program is new and fancy and updated.
Scott: So it's okay Yep.
Rym: Now beyond that for system administration if you're virtualizing things Downtime isn't an issue.
Rym: You want to test something.
Rym: you want to test to change you just clone your virtual machine in the current state.
Rym: Run it in a net like just run it Make your change see if it works and if it works just do the same thing to your working server.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know Not only because not only do you have something that effectively works the exact same way as a real machine But it's not a real machine, but it has all the advantages of being a piece of software.
Scott: You can copy it.
Scott: You can pass it around you can buck with it.
Scott: You can pause it.
Rym: You can start it I can rewind it you can fast-forward it I can make a machine to test something and then send it to Scott so he can test the thing I made.
Scott: Yeah, and it'd be exactly the same thing because we're using the same fake machine even though our real machines are different.
Scott: Another thing like our hosting is a good example.
Scott: our hosting is Linux, right?
Scott: But it runs on user mode Linux.
Scott: user mode Linux is a little different from virtual machine, but it's pretty close.
Scott: it's effectively the same as far as few people are concerned.
Scott: and what it is user mode Linux is where you have a Linux kernel running on a computer and then you load a bunch of other Linux kernels.
Scott: So it splits up one big computer into a bunch of little computers.
Scott: so as far as I'm concerned right sitting in my house our compute our hosting our web hosting is On a dedicated Linux server.
Scott: It's as if I could not tell the difference if I didn't between what we have and if I had my very own Linux computer with a real its own CPU and its own RAM and its Own everything, but I don't.
Scott: there's one big server with a bunch of Linux is on it.
Scott: But I just log in to some machine as you know me and I log into it normally and I have full control over this Machine, it's just not a real machine.
Scott: It's a part of a bigger machine just running another copy of Linux within a copy of Linux.
Rym: now the ramifications for you Small time developer hobbyist whatever is say you want to play around with a bunch of different Linux's.
Rym: Well, just make virtual machines and play all you want.
Rym: You don't even have to reboot.
Rym: Yeah, and if you mess something up Oh, well If you would need to look up documentation because your gen 2 stage 1 isn't working so well Your gen 2 stage 1 is in a window and you've got a Firefox open next to it.
Scott: Yep, I mean you can.
Scott: you don't have to go rebooting You don't have to mess with your partitions or anything if you want to.
Scott: you know.
Scott: You say you want to make a Linux, right?
Scott: So you make a 10 gigabyte file.
Scott: you install the Linux onto that 10 gigabyte file, right?
Scott: If you don't like it, you can delete the file and you're all good It'll.
Scott: actually the file won't even grow to be 10 gigs unless you fill the 10 gigs, you know And you can have you.
Scott: you know If you need to use like a Windows application and you're running OS X the VMware Fusion It'll just you have Windows running inside of a window You literally.
Scott: you'll have your Apple Doc and then there'll be a window and in that window will be Microsoft Windows.
Scott: and as far as that Windows is concerned It's running on a real computer all on its own.
Scott: It has no idea now it doesn't know that Mac OS X is out there.
Rym: the holy grail of all this that we have not achieved yet is to the point where I can run whatever operating system I want or even maybe a base generic operating system that doesn't do anything by itself and only hosts virtual machines and Then I run whatever operating systems I want for whatever applications I want and thus it doesn't matter What kind of computer I have doesn't matter what operating system I have.
Rym: I can do whatever I want without rebooting.
Scott: Yeah, we're pretty close to that.
Rym: The problem is Steam really doesn't work in a virtual machine worth a damn.
Scott: Yeah, because here's here's the problem right when you make a virtual machine, right?
Scott: Basically, what you're doing is you're not just doing the CPU you're doing the sound card and the video card and you're basically they're writing a piece of software and When the windows that runs in the virtual machine says draw a polygon on the screen They write not just you know, the windows uses its own driver, right?
Scott: But that driver isn't, you know sending its instructions to your actual video card.
Scott: It's sending instructions to this program that's pretending to be a video card.
Scott: So unless that program pretending to be a video card is as good as an Nvidia video card It's gonna be really hard to play a game on it.
Scott: So Until you know, it's getting better.
Scott: I mean They're at the point where some 3d stuff is kind of working and such but not really and it's gonna take a while for The program that is pretending to be a video card to be as good as an actual video card and it when you get to That point then 3d stuff will really start to kick ass.
Rym: now probably the biggest thing but we've already gone on a long time.
Rym: So I think we'll talk about this in a separate show because there's a whole World.
Rym: I can talk about what this is and why it's important whatever but for now I would recommend that anyone out there who doesn't know about this already go download VMware player because it's free
Scott: Yep,
Rym: really free and then just search on the VMware site for virtual appliances and look at what they are.
Rym: Download any that look interesting run them and play with them.
Scott: Yeah They're also how-to guides as to like how to you know Make your own virtual appliances with a text editor and QEM.
Scott: you and you know Linux CD And you don't even need to burn the CDs just need to download ISO's of Linux distributions.
Scott: You could play with every Linux distribution in the universe without ever actually having to format your hard drive or anything.
Scott: You can just fool around with all of them and see what they do and see what they're like.
Rym: And if you're interested someday in the future We could probably talk about virtual appliances themselves and the many myriad of uses that they have.
Rym: Yep
Scott: Now the one more thing one thing I do want to say one very good use of virtual machine is if you're a web developer Right, you're making web pages and you want to make sure those web pages look good No matter what browser no matter what operating system, right?
Scott: Well, it's kind of hard to install ie6 and seven on the same machine, even though it's kind of possible.
Scott: it's it's kind of.
Scott: it's not easy right and it's not perfect.
Scott: and You can you know, what if you need to test Safari on Mac and then they have Safari for Windows now and they have opera on Windows Mac and Linux?
Scott: and you know, You have Conqueror and KDE you have different Firefox versions and you you don't want to get them all confused.
Scott: well just make a bunch of virtual machines for it with a. Each one has a different set of browsers that don't conflict with each other and then you can test your website and all these different Browsers, but you're really only sitting at one computer.
Scott: You have to have a bunch of computers or anything like that.
Scott: You just one computer and you can test all these browsers and all these different operating systems to see how stuff works.
Scott: Also, if you're just programming a program Let's say I want to write a word processor program and I want that word processor program to work on every operating system And I know I've coded it right for every operating system, but I got to test it.
Scott: Well instead of having a computer, you know five computers I can just use one and that is the amazingness.
Scott: That is the virtual machine.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.