Rym: It's Monday, May 12th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We present the humble video card.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So all this week I actually don't have to go to work Which it was weird because I woke up and I had this dream and someone comes up to me and says You have to wake up in five minutes, and I woke up and I go.
Rym: ah and I grab my phone And I look at it and it says 435 which yeah, I would have to wake up in five minutes if I was going to work.
Rym: So I went back to bed and a few hours later.
Rym: I woke up and went to training down on Wall Street.
Rym: I'm doing this training for a BMC service desk.
Rym: It's like this giant enterprise ticketing system.
Rym: I got a week of training to do which I got to admit.
Rym: Going to train I mean everyone else who goes to training for tech stuff is always like I'm going to training But I was super excited.
Rym: I think partly because I missed college, and it was like going to class.
Scott: Yeah, what did they actually teach you stuff there?
Scott: Was it sort of hokey?
Rym: actually it was super good like we got a textbook and there I learned about those training things.
Rym: Well, I think a lot of them are crap, but this one is surprisingly not Crap with.
Scott: the other people there seemed like they cared.
Rym: yeah, because there's only ten people.
Rym: okay The cool thing is I guess if you didn't care you'd stand out when every morning We get bagels and locks and cream cheese That's nice.
Rym: And then for lunch we get a really really nice lunch at this fancy like pub bar and grill down the street.
Scott: Well you go you paid for.
Rym: I didn't pay crap.
Rym: Well.
Scott: I mean someone paid a lot for it.
Rym: Yeah, the class was like thirty five hundred bucks.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but it costs as much as like eight weeks to summer care.
Rym: Yeah, they flew the instructor out from Texas.
Rym: So he's like yeah class ends a little early today at 430. cuz I'm going to see the letterman.
Rym: I got some tickets.
Scott: Yeah, it's a lot of people like to do that when they come to the city.
Rym: I'm really not interested in seeing letterman at all, but as a result I had to take the 705 Express instead of my usual 532 Express And the train was crowded, but the 705 is like the most crowded train.
Scott: cuz it goes straight there.
Rym: But me Emily and Alex we all walk down.
Scott: you want to the 705.
Scott: I thought they were taking the 728.
Rym: no They take the 705 now.
Rym: No.
Rym: I get up early.
Scott: I can't do that 705.
Scott: It's worth it.
Scott: I used to do it now.
Scott: I don't do it.
Scott: I think I'm actually gonna start taking the 820.
Rym: Yeah, well, that's cuz your weird work stuff.
Rym: Yeah, man.
Rym: I used to take like the 732.
Rym: That was when I worked in Yonkers and I'd show up at work like 915.
Rym: I'd always stop and get like breakfast.
Scott: I've been lately.
Scott: I've been taking like the 744.
Scott: I mean I mean to take the 728 by 744.
Scott: I've been at work for an hour.
Scott: You know I was taking the 728.
Scott: I was sort of happy with that one But I think the 44 is like it's sort of its local, but that's the one I've been doing.
Rym: so yeah Well see if I usually if I go home I take the 410 or the 445 which is one of those semi locals.
Scott: I was taking the 509, but today.
Scott: I took the five the like the 552. ah it's not like the.
Rym: the last train you want to take is the 529 of the five.
Rym: whatever 523 the it's the same as the 509 is just later.
Rym: Yeah, this one is not good Yeah, but anyway, so I get on this train.
Rym: It's really crowded and the three of us realize we all can't sit next to each other.
Rym: So the three of us kind of go in a row to like me and I like Emily goes to this one seat of three seaters.
Rym: I go to the three seater behind her and we're both like excuse me can I sit there?
Rym: and The guy in my seat goes up sure thing and he stands up and the guy Emily asked looks at her like are you talking to?
Rym: Me?
Rym: and she's like yeah, can I sit there?
Rym: of all the seats on the train you got to sit here?
Rym: There's plenty of seats, and you have to sit here.
Rym: goddamn tourists.
Rym: Now I'm looking at him, and she's looking at him and the other woman in the three-seater is looking at him and everyone in the car is looking at him like Okay, dude.
Scott: Well you have to let her sit there you have.
Rym: no he does.
Rym: he's getting up But he's like why can't you sit somewhere else?
Rym: there's plenty of seats.
Rym: so this time I you know I decided to intercede a little bit.
Rym: I say actually no there aren't.
Rym: we came from the other side of the train.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: He's like that's bullshit That's a goddamn lie.
Rym: There's plenty of seats on this goddamn train.
Scott: And now just to be kind of in like if there's so many seats, and you're not happy Oh, why don't you go find another?
Rym: I played.
Rym: see I guess I'm just really good at irritating people if I want to.
Rym: so I kind of say to him This is the kind of thing that I would never say, but it's that I knew it was what would take him off.
Rym: Well follow language isn't going to get you anywhere.
Rym: Yeah, and he clairs at me, and he says goddamn tourists I'm a businessman.
Rym: you people don't understand business.
Rym: you got to respond blah blah blah blah, and I'm looking at him like Businessman.
Rym: you're a businessman big fancy businessman.
Rym: I'm on my way to Wall Street, dude You don't work on Wall Street.
Scott: You work right hand 40 second.
Rym: No.
Rym: I was on my way to Wall Street.
Scott: Oh, you're training is you were you're right plus.
Rym: I work for effectively a Wall Street company.
Scott: Yeah, you keep saying you work on Wall Street to sound all fancy right.
Scott: well You know who else who works on Wall Street?
Scott: the Wall Street hot dog vendor?
Rym: alright, so actually there are all the vendors over there Aren't on Wall Street.
Rym: They're on Broadway.
Rym: I'm just saying yeah, but I was going to Wall Street that one day.
Scott: I'm not speeding that one.
Rym: So the guys like I'm a business, and he keeps saying like I'm a businessman I'm a big man you got to respect me and my business II man stuff.
Rym: So he grumbles and grumbles, but eventually Emily just sits down next to him And he sits there like in a huff, and you see he keeps going.
Rym: You know people do that all the time when they're you know huffy huffing and puffing huffing and puffing Big bad wolf oh no.
Rym: and finally Emily's like fine.
Rym: I'll go sit somewhere else mr.. Businessman.
Rym: And he she goes to get up and then he's like And he's real uncomfortable cuz pretty much everyone on the car is staring at him now like dude.
Rym: What's your problem?
Rym: And the woman sitting next to him is giving him, but like the stink eye times a thousand the stink.
Rym: Yeah, she's a pretty she was cool.
Rym: We talked to her afterward like what was his deal.
Rym: Yeah, businessman my ass Think she was giving him the stink eye giving him the stink eye and finally he gets up in a huff And he walks away toward the front of the train.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: then Emily, and I sit next to that cool lady, and she's like.
Rym: I don't know what that dude's problem was.
Rym: we talked for a while And then we all put on our respective headphones and go about our you know train ride.
Rym: Then a few minutes later I see the guy huffing and puffing going back in the other direction because he obviously couldn't find a seat by himself.
Scott: yep Huh is he gonna stand?
Scott: is he gonna sit in the bathroom?
Rym: I love how his thought like his insult was god damn tourists.
Rym: I'm a businessman.
Rym: I think he realized the error when we all had you know monthly train passes.
Rym: Just like him.
Scott: yeah Huh some uh crazy dude.
Scott: What do you want?
Rym: I thought it was pretty funny.
Scott: Yeah, it would be pretty funny if I would have been there.
Scott: I would have been laughing it up.
Scott: I also would have made a much angrier.
Scott: I would have been like oh Yeah, big businessman right and I would have you know I could have turned it up.
Scott: I probably would have gotten him like you know to like.
Scott: I probably would have taunted him until he like would have like assaulted me.
Rym: That would have been fantastic.
Scott: that would have been awesome.
Scott: And then the conductor would have come and he would have gone to jail, and I would have been like businessman, huh?
Scott: Well, there's a lot of businessmen where you're going.
Scott: They know all about the.
Scott: you know behind-the-scenes business Soap business.
Rym: now our business, but that was my trainer.
Scott: Yeah Hello, that's all I got.
Rym: I was playing Civ 4 and watching princess 2 to the rest of the way on the train.
Scott: Yeah, my works getting a little weird now like You know some of the people who were there like longer than me.
Scott: Right it's starting to like leave.
Scott: like some of them leave for legitimate reasons some of them left.
Scott: I don't know why.
Scott: right and then.
Rym: but how can you leave a work for non legitimate reasons?
Rym: It's New York.
Rym: you can quit for any reason at any time.
Scott: Well actually you know what I found out.
Scott: the fact that you can quit for any reason is that they can fire you at?
Scott: You know how some people call that right to work.
Scott: That's not what right to work is.
Scott: right to work is actually something We don't have.
Scott: Right to work means if there's a union you can't be forced to join it.
Scott: I wish we had right to work.
Rym: We don't Because I was always told that right to work states include that clause and all the stuff about able to quit The the stuff about.
Scott: you know quit for any time any reason and fire for any time at any reason.
Scott: our work at will?
Rym: ah I must have conflated the two.
Scott: right to work means you have a right to work there You don't have to join the freaking Union.
Scott: you see that's why I was always confused.
Scott: because right to work.
Scott: I was like how does me how does I can quit any time?
Scott: I want to mean right have a right to work.
Scott: that didn't really match up Yeah, and that guy was like oh, that's work at will.
Scott: and right to work is don't have to pay union dues You can work there anyway, even though you'll probably be strong-armed if everyone else is in the Union.
Scott: well now You know and we don't have right to work in New York State Which is why if there's a union you have to join it.
Rym: But at the same time at least we have the other one because the other one is much.
Scott: I would rather if I had to only pick one I would take part of that because we work in an industry where there are No unions, and there's no reason for unions.
Scott: Yeah, that's correct all right There's a lot of places.
Rym: There's no reason Yeah, but there are places where I mean coal miners.
Rym: I think they deserve a union.
Scott: coal miners do need a union yes anyway.
Scott: So the point is it works.
Scott: get a little weird like my number one cuz like in the tech department right?
Scott: There's the boss right cuz the company is run by four partners.
Scott: So I guess I assume they each own 25% of the company.
Scott: they all started it together, right?
Scott: I'm just a suit.
Scott: that makes sense.
Scott: and So there's the partner.
Scott: who's the tech partner right?
Scott: There's the IT guy who does this is admitting.
Scott: There's the guy who is the developer.
Scott: you're like when I got there plus the the partner the tech partners also Developer and as me I'm like the newer developer right the guy who is pretty much I'm a number one co-worker the the guy who was the developer when I got there.
Scott: He was gonna quit mostly because like you know his family situation like living in New York wasn't so good for him anymore And he needs.
Scott: he wants his kid to go to school somewhere good And he couldn't really afford to live anywhere close enough.
Scott: You know and it wasn't working out.
Scott: so He wanted to move to Boston.
Scott: He's got some family up there You know and such, but so they were like oh, no, we can't let you go.
Scott: We'll be screwed right.
Rym: But I believe we just determined that in this state.
Scott: Right right, but they basically you know they couldn't have stopped them from going But they convinced him to keep saying, but they didn't convince him to physically stay.
Scott: they basically said all right We'll let you go and you'll telecommute whatever.
Rym: that's fine Cuz I remember the hospital tried to convince me to stay and I was like unless you give me a hundred percent raise I'm walking out the door today.
Scott: Yeah, so Yeah, you should have said no hundred percent raise in telecommuting.
Scott: You know the hundred percent raise would have been a hospital job really wasn't a telecommute job.
Scott: No, I wanted to go to places now.
Rym: I have a not my current job.
Rym: I could.
Rym: I could do 90% of the job.
Scott: I could telecommute my job.
Scott: my boss sort of has this hang up about like they want people to be there.
Scott: He's like it's not good.
Scott: It's like it's not as the same as face-to-face.
Rym: You know what though I think it's better.
Rym: in a lot of ways.
Rym: I feel like you should have a mix.
Rym: I mean my ideal work situation.
Rym: cuz even if I could Sometimes what I'm saying is even if I could telecommute right at my current job.
Rym: I kind of like going into the city.
Rym: I actually enjoy my train rides.
Rym: I like being down there.
Rym: I like working with my co-workers.
Rym: I feel like if I could telecommute as much as I wanted I would probably Telecommute like two days a week at most except maybe in the summer You know, I think I would go to work at most one day every one or two weeks.
Rym: Oh, well, I guess our works different.
Rym: I I do a lot of.
Rym: I Guess my charisma counts for a lot in the kind of work I do and the kinds of things I deal with.
Rym: so it's kind Of useful to be there in person.
Scott: I mostly just Sit at the desk and the only time I really need to be there is if someone sends me an email that tells me to Do something but they're not very clear and I actually need to discuss it with them.
Rym: Well, you just do a WebEx Right anyway, all right, we got all that set up.
Rym: now I can video conference with anyone in any of the offices.
Rym: actually It's cool.
Rym: We have like this bought like all these sales offices around the country around the world.
Rym: So the sales area right.
Rym: we have this camera that points at all those people and I can like Microphones in the ceiling and there's a constant teleconference between all of our offices each other's screens.
Scott: That'd be cool.
Rym: You can set that up but we just see each other on that screen and you can like if you'll see because people kind of all stand around the Camera and just talk all the time with all the other offices.
Scott: But we can also share desktops and video and yeah sharing the desktops is key for the tech people.
Scott: But anyway, yes good God it is.
Rym: So I click on this.
Rym: click on it.
Scott: Just get.
Scott: let me give me it.
Scott: in addition to that They were gonna hire this program manager guy Right to sort of come in and sort of manage all the stuff which would have been cool because then I wouldn't have had to Like talk to people.
Scott: he would have like talked to all the people I would I'm talking to now So I wouldn't had to use a telephone or anything I could just you know, he would have sorted all that business out for me and taking some of the work I don't want to do off my hands and such right and also taking care of our databases so I can concentrate more on the apps.
Scott: But the guy he's agreed to work for us and then two days before he was he was gonna start working today and like Thursday Last week.
Scott: He's like, yeah, fuck you.
Scott: So what an ass.
Scott: that was pretty unprofessional.
Scott: I wouldn't do that.
Rym: Well,
Scott: at the very least if I agree to work some that somewhere I would show up and I might quit really quickly like the second Day, but I wouldn't say, you know I wouldn't say yes And then say no if I was gonna say no if I there's any chance of me saying no I wouldn't say yes yet.
Scott: I'd say maybe hold on.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean I can foresee a situation.
Rym: Let's say you accepted a job you were excited about.
Rym: they're paying you.
Rym: I don't know $80,000 a year.
Rym: All right, and then two days later you're supposed to start in a week You get offered a job that pays twice.
Rym: that.
Scott: that's the thing.
Scott: Is that an offer?
Scott: if an offer really came out of nowhere like that, right?
Scott: Like I didn't I didn't have like an appending thing on the table, you know.
Scott: Then I would you know if it just came out of nowhere like someone just called me up randomly and said I'll give you like A jillion dollars, right?
Scott: I'd say well, I just accepted this other job.
Scott: It'd be really rude if I like just you know told them no.
Scott: after I told them.
Scott: Yes I'll work there a couple days and see how it is and You know, just hold on to that money and I'll call you back next week.
Scott: I promise to tell you yes or no, you know I did something like that because it's it's a lot more asshole to be like no.
Scott: Yes No, you know because if you say yes, they've already stopped looking and it's sort of like yeah
Rym: yeah, but at the same time and it's kind of a the IT world in the CS world is kind of weird because Sometimes like there are obvious times when you don't want to burn your bridges.
Rym: I mean, I like the people at IBM.
Rym: I still talk to him on occasion, but Sometimes you just burn all your bridges because you know, you're never gonna work in that sector again, and you really don't care.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway, it's sort of like, you know We're in a situation where my work obviously needs me a lot because they're having trouble like hiring.
Scott: the people well demand a raise Vacation days.
Scott: Yeah, and now they're telling me like yeah, we'd like you to stay later, which is like doom.
Scott: I almost missed the train coming home today, you know Cuz I had the time that they wanted me to leave does not work Well with the train schedule and I got home like an hour later Which pretty much just means I can have an hour less of sleep.
Scott: and you know, I'm gonna take away I might.
Scott: I think I might take work off tomorrow just to get my shit sorted out.
Scott: I got shit to sort out laundry and stuff and and video yeah and stuff like that.
Rym: So it's actually our new boundary.
Rym: microphone will be here in a couple days.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: Yeah, they're doing video a lot easier.
Scott: I think I'm gonna take a day off this week, you know calling sick maybe tomorrow I don't know but regardless works getting a little weird, but it's like.
Scott: I don't want to screw them because I like these people.
Scott: That's why you got a late.
Scott: That's when you lay down working there Despite the work itself being kind of lame is cuz?
Scott: I like the people's but it's like with the hospital.
Rym: one.
Rym: one time There was a couple times.
Scott: You don't like the people at the hospital.
Rym: I like a couple of the people.
Rym: You know what though all the people I liked at the hospital Quit while I was working there.
Rym: Yeah, it's like a lot of the people Was like get the hell out get out as soon as you can.
Rym: I'll give you references.
Rym: You want to work where I'm going?
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I'm gonna do.
Scott: the thing is I was looking at Craigslist and there's mad jobs.
Scott: There's so many jobs now.
Scott: I'm like no wonder having a hard time finding people.
Scott: It's all these freaking job I would do.
Rym: then go to you like tell your boss honestly like look I'm not gonna be a jerk and demand like some crazy high salary or demand like four months vacation.
Rym: cuz I know you need me.
Rym: What I would say is but saying late is not going to make me accomplish anymore, yeah Well, it's mostly not an issue of me accomplishing more.
Scott: It's mostly an issue of for example You know the other people at the office work.
Scott: You know set hours right and they might need something done at like five, but I leave it for 30.
Scott: So it's because they work until like six.
Scott: they might need something done.
Scott: I don't.
Rym: after I leave it seems like a lot of people.
Scott: I know I'm not there.
Scott: It's not gonna get done.
Rym: It seems like a lot of people.
Rym: I know work in the city.
Rym: They always show up to work real late, and then they leave.
Scott: really yeah, I don't understand these people.
Scott: They show up right like yeah like 11, and then they leave it like six or seven.
Scott: I'm like what the fuck is wrong.
Rym: I want to get home.
Rym: Well.
Rym: It's still light out and do stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I want to do things.
Scott: It's like what do you and where do you eat dinner?
Rym: You know well if you're in Manhattan you just eat dinner.
Scott: I don't think these people aren't in Manhattan.
Scott: one of the guys there is even crazy so crazy.
Scott: He fucking takes the bus right over to fucking Jersey like to Bergen County.
Scott: I'm like holy shit that I worked at the hospital Like eight or nine.
Rym: there was a guy who lived in Connecticut far away who worked in Yonkers every day.
Rym: He drove an hour and 45 minutes.
Scott: Oh, that's just crazy.
Rym: I look at that.
Rym: It's like wow.
Rym: I mean I have an hour train ride, but none of that time is lost.
Rym: I mean I realized today I watched two episodes of princess tutu on the way to work, and then I played some sieve.
Rym: for I played sieve for while listening to Dave and Joel.
Scott: yeah on the way to work I listen to podcast and on the way home.
Scott: I was sort of sleepy.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, let's let's move to some news here.
Rym: alright, so it's kind of a running gag at my work But we often make fun of the French.
Rym: The other like production support engineer at my level he's French.
Scott: He's a really cool guy pretty much has the same job as you.
Rym: pretty much I mean, it's like we're the same level and we nominally like we do the same job.
Rym: We support the production servers the revenue generating servers cuz in big.
Rym: actually we should do a Monday show some time about what enterprise Really means like what all those like business terms.
Scott: I got a funny anecdote.
Scott: you ready So what?
Scott: so one of our listeners today sends me a message, and he's like he's like Do you know what data warehouses?
Scott: You know like.
Scott: he's like.
Scott: can you tell me some of the advantages disadvantages of data warehouses?
Scott: I'm like what do you mean by data warehouses?
Scott: like a big building full of data?
Rym: You know storage, you know what that word is.
Rym: hold on I can tell you what that bullet for that fucking word.
Scott: So hold on.
Scott: so then he's like no.
Scott: And so I went to the Wikipedia for data warehouse and data warehouse pretty much just meant use a database you moron That's pretty much what it means.
Rym: Yeah, well usually what it what it really means is database plus saying plus like business.
Scott: But according to the data according to the Wikipedia it pretty much just meant keep all your data in like one database or in some sort of you know Centralized cohesive intelligent ways that you could actually get the most out of your data.
Rym: Let me put it this way.
Scott: so I Tell him I tell him right.
Scott: he's like yeah I'm at this new job, and they asked me if you know you do a data.
Scott: warehouses were right.
Scott: So I'm like.
Scott: that's obviously just a buzzword that just means use a database.
Scott: It's a kind of word you use to explain.
Scott: It's like a businessman who doesn't understand technology that you know you should use a database and put all your data in a data warehouse.
Rym: most enterprise words are Basically just like.
Rym: they carry more baggage like we're.
Rym: the word data warehouse in the enterprise world does carry a lot more baggage than Have a database I know, but it's you know I mean But it involves a lot of.
Rym: but the thing is those words the biggest misconception do not describe Technological solutions, they don't describe technology.
Rym: They describe business processes and like a front-end stuff and like how to put it together and like the methodology and the semantics and all That right and the back end that the core stuff the actual data warehouse is what the techies make and it's just a database.
Scott: Yeah, so I tell him right.
Scott: I tell him yeah You need those kind of words to you know to explain to business people you know because just you know these Common-sense things is even though just having a database you know a relational database You know and making all the data useful seems like common sense to us.
Scott: if you say that to a normal person They'll have no clue what you're talking about.
Scott: so you need to use a buzzword like data warehouse to convince them that You know they shouldn't be just emailing Excel spreadsheets all around the office.
Rym: I'll tell you one other thing.
Rym: in the majority of the IT world or the tech world you can tell the people who deal with this stuff on a daily basis from those who don't because People who don't refer to it as our data warehouse or though it data warehouse But people who deal with it just say I'm working on data warehouse.
Rym: When are we gonna finish data warehouse?
Scott: Yeah, so anyway He ends up IMing me back like a few minutes later right like a little while later, and he's like yeah Apparently they said they need data warehouse whatever because the people are emailing around spreadsheets like you said.
Scott: And I'm like do I know or do I know?
Rym: God we got to do a show we need to do a Monday.
Rym: a very specific like ask What?
Scott: not to use Excel spreadsheets?
Scott: We just do a whole show on.
Rym: oh you want to know the answer to what.
Rym: not to use Excel spreadsheets for anything But except accounting and even then you can only want a dedicated accounting system.
Rym: probably good guy anyway.
Rym: Anyway, that's a whole separate show.
Rym: Oh, I didn't even do my new fucking news Friends and that's right.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: It's your news is friends, so Google Street View which I think is fantastic.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: It's useful.
Scott: You know when you want to see like what a place looks like.
Scott: there's a lot of times You'll know the address and but you won't and you know the number.
Scott: But like you look around you won't see the number and it's like some sort of hidden place.
Scott: So the Google Street View.
Scott: you can like a high sort of see a green sign there.
Scott: now I know it's a look.
Rym: for now else go It's useful.
Rym: say you look up a business and you find the address and you look at the street view and realize that that business Hasn't been there for years.
Scott: I could also you got to watch out if you don't know this hidden inside the building businesses.
Rym: Yeah but I used it to check whether a ski shop was there or not and it wasn't on two occasions and That was after I'd try to go and find the ski shops and they weren't there.
Scott: So like the place I bought my Eddie Modix the hearing aid place is like Inside a building on like the fourth floor deep inside.
Rym: Well, if you're talking about that you can't forget a picopita.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: All right, but and that picopita has a scaffolding.
Scott: So it's even worse.
Rym: Google Street View has run into a lot of problems in the United States partly because One a lot of people do not understand the law when it comes to privacy and photography And a lot of people a lot of people think they have a lot more rights than they do.
Rym: But I'm not a lawyer.
Rym: This is not a legal opinion.
Rym: Do not take legal advice from GeekNights.
Rym: However, as far as I'm aware pretty much in most cases you can take anything you can see with reasonable Accommodation from a public place you can take a picture of and no one's allowed to stop you.
Rym: now Right.
Scott: It's like if you're standing on a public street, you can take pictures You can't.
Scott: the only exceptions are like.
Scott: you can't take like.
Scott: I think you can't take like a zoom lens to peep into someone's house Can't?
Rym: if you take a telephoto lens shot of a naked person through their bedroom window It's if someone has a reasonable expectation of privacy.
Rym: However, the definition of reasonable is much stricter than most people realize.
Rym: But anyway, so as a result a lot of people get really bent out of shape about Google But luckily they can't do much about it and to Google does not have to accommodate these idiots.
Rym: But often they do.
Rym: and if you say hey Google, could you retake the picture of this spot?
Rym: They usually will like there's a naked guy in front of my business.
Rym: Could you please come back when there isn't a naked guy and Google usually like, okay, we'll come back or okay Hey, I'm in this picture.
Scott: I don't want to be in that picture and they're cool about it.
Rym: And that's you know, that's the kind of when it comes to civil liberties.
Rym: I really like the idea that people have freedoms like you should have the freedom to take the pictures and do whatever you want with them and all that.
Rym: but Just because you have a freedom doesn't mean you have to always exercise it and like Google has the discretion to Be nice or to exercise their freedom on a case-by-case basis.
Scott: That's what it's free about it.
Scott: If you had to if you had to you know Keep the picture up and give the guy the finger all the time.
Scott: That's that's also not freedom.
Scott: You know if you have to use every right you have and you can't you know Decide not to use your right then you're not really free.
Scott: you get the free means you have to be able to choose.
Rym: But anyway to quote slash out here.
Rym: to sum this up because we've been talking a little bit Google has begun to scan the streets of Paris as part of the street view service But the company may be hindered from publishing them unedited.
Rym: the reason French privacy laws Google may be forced to blur faces or use low-resolution versions of their photographs.
Rym: the deal here.
Rym: Basically is that France has very strict privacy laws, which you know, a lot of people are privacy advocates, but in this case I Patently disagree.
Rym: I feel like anything that is visible from a public place is Public property in terms of viewing like if you're worried about your privacy, why are you walking around a public street?
Scott: It's like, you know, if you want something be private do it in your house with the blinds closed.
Rym: but there's this very.
Rym: this is an interesting problem because a Very useful very cool amazing technology something that would have been unfathomable to me five years ago and is now like this Daily.
Rym: the you like.
Rym: I use this tool on a daily basis and it's awesome.
Rym: the people of Paris might not be able to get this obviously beneficial technology because they have overbearing laws Restricting the rights of using photographs and images and things to protect their privacy.
Scott: Well, that's been the battle of the past however many years isn't it?
Scott: Is that technology pushing against the the laws designed to work in a world where those technologies are not possible?
Rym: I just I don't know.
Rym: I feel like we need to do a whole show on just the idea of privacy in the modern world Because on one hand I feel like there are certain rights to bastions of privacy But the other hand I feel like medical records.
Rym: I feel like as the world gets more and more interconnected You can't hide a lot of information and it actually I think a lot of technologies are being hindered by the fact That people are so afraid or that like social security numbers You shouldn't have to hide your social security number.
Rym: the fact that people can use that number which is not secure in any way To do things is horrible.
Rym: Yeah That's just like that because social security numbers were conceived in an era before The interlink databases that we have today and I feel like the system is broken to the point of it should just be completely scrapped.
Scott: Yeah, something like that the number system not social security But security is a topic for another show I raised like four issues.
Rym: So this is basically my news is we're gonna do like five shows on stuff like this in the future?
Scott: Yeah, right France and then next time it's time to do a show like that.
Scott: We'll be sitting here.
Scott: What do we do a show on?
Scott: duh?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: remind us in the fall not gonna happen Alright, so check this out, right?
Scott: I'm having some job issues lately.
Scott: Alright, we'll see what goes.
Scott: that you are Of course, I can't.
Scott: I can't.
Scott: I'm not really in danger of losing my job.
Rym: I'm just sort of slightly Gruntled man, every time I think I'm not doing well at my job and all my jobs like man am I doing my job?
Rym: I feel like I'm slacking and then my boss always take me aside like I need to speak with you.
Rym: It's like ah crap.
Rym: Are they firing me?
Rym: Am I gonna bla bla bla bla, but they always give me a raise or something.
Scott: So yeah anyway.
Scott: So there's a lot of things out there Lately that are sort of opportunities for people like me to sort of go out on their own and make software.
Scott: for example Nintendo's WiiWare launched today instead of virtual console games.
Scott: They put the WiiWare out there, which I got to go downstairs.
Scott: We got to buy some games.
Rym: Yes, we do.
Scott: Alright, of course, they're gonna.
Scott: I got to buy more stupid Wii points.
Scott: I think I might just buy the big package of Wii points just to make it easier and I could have to keep typing the credit card number in on the Wii.
Scott: and The way that works apparently is Nintendo is is according to what I've read.
Scott: They're being very open.
Scott: They're saying anyone who wants to make WiiWare go nuts.
Scott: We're just gonna make sure that it's bug-free and We're gonna make sure that it's.
Scott: you know, you have to get it rated by the.
Scott: you know, the the ESRB.
Rym: We got to make a goddamn tower defense game I know.
Scott: and then now they said that they'll let they'll put it on there and you choose your price.
Scott: I guess you can't do free because I guess they get a cut right.
Scott: but you know I don't know.
Scott: they might let you do free.
Scott: who knows?
Scott: and I'm like Hey I could totally do that if I you know If I quit my job right now and Nintendo gave me the WiiWare kit I could totally make a WiiWare game and that'll be my job.
Scott: I'd live off the WiiWare game.
Scott: That'd be set, right?
Scott: Here's another example, which is my news.
Scott: Rym, are I am not our YM like this person?
Scott: Yeah, right Rym, which is stands for if you didn't know research in motion Blackberry blackberry, they're better known as blackberry.
Scott: If you look at the back of a blackberry, it says Rym on it, right?
Scott: R. I am.
Rym: so Rym, well, my blackberry says R. I am and our YM.
Scott: So the blackberry company is launching a 150 million dollar right that's like enough for the rest of my life.
Scott: times a billion not times a billion.
Scott: Venture capitalist fund for mobile apps.
Scott: in other words if you want to make Blackberry applications something Scott can do Scott knows the Java, right?
Scott: They'll get.
Scott: they're giving out 150 million dollars to people and companies who are gonna make blackberry apps.
Scott: Now one if you give me right a hundred thousand dollars.
Scott: Not even if you give me eighty thousand dollars a small fraction of that hundred and fifty million.
Scott: I can afford to just quit my job and spend an entire year on blackberry applications.
Scott: I could write like ten blackberry applications in a year.
Rym: probably got it right first Interfaces to all the Google stuff that works with domains.
Rym: exactly.
Scott: I mean I could do so much I could make like the best blackberry applications known to man if they gave me just 80 grand.
Scott: just give Scott Reuben 80 grand.
Scott: I'll quit my job.
Scott: You know what I'll go.
Scott: sit on a brand new computer.
Rym: You could probably do it on 40 grand because you could live on 40 grand if you didn't have any commutation expenses Maybe but it would be a little.
Rym: but the thing is remember you you have my bankroll cuz I actually Listeners aside.
Rym: I kind of got a gigantic raise the other day.
Rym: I've been kind of geeky about my job lately.
Scott: Yeah, okay, so Okay, my question is how do I get them to give me this money?
Scott: I mean Apple is giving money to people making iPhone apps if I can get that money.
Scott: I can make iPhone apps, too.
Scott: I'll go out and buy an iPhone like tomorrow and start making iPhone apps.
Scott: I can make some.
Rym: you should try it look into it And then I get right and then email all the people and then find out there might be like an application or something you can Do.
Scott: how I can't.
Scott: I couldn't even find right there like yeah, we're letting all these developers make we wear apps.
Scott: I could not find the we wear dev kit anything right where.
Scott: how do I get in on this stuff?
Scott: How do I get these monies?
Scott: I could totally quit my job and just write apps that would like change the world.
Scott: I just I don't know how to get this money.
Scott: I need someone to help me get this money.
Rym: I'll bankroll you.
Rym: I'll be your sugar daddy.
Scott: I need such a small amount of this money.
Scott: one year salaries.
Rym: you laughing sugar daddy?
Rym: I don't know, but I wasn't the late laugh.
Scott: someone helped me out here.
Scott: All right, seriously, I'm not even joking about this Like I would seriously just quit my job and I can take a year off.
Scott: I could actually what I do is I write a game right and I would put put the game on.
Scott: we wear iPhone and blackberry I'd make a cross-platform get NDS.
Rym: The scary thing is Scott Alex and I have been working on.
Rym: we haven't actually made a single goddamn game But we have a lot of like.
Rym: pretty much If the three of us had taken time off like we could ever just take time off like a month and work on one of These things instead of doing our normal jobs.
Rym: It'd be done and amazing.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is if someone actually did this I would probably take like a week off and go to Florida and it but then I would come back and then I would do It.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway, I'm serious.
Scott: I'm dead serious about this.
Scott: Like I am looking at this action I need someone with knowledges to help me get monies from these companies.
Scott: They're giving it out.
Scott: They want someone to write an app.
Scott: I can just giving it away.
Scott: They just need to give me a blackberry dev kit and you'll have blackberry apps probably within the week.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: so a lot not too long ago, you know We play.
Rym: we're playing this burning wheel game on Tuesdays and the burning wheel game is very.
Rym: there's a lot of Roman Empire Inspired stuff in it.
Rym: So we were talking and we thought hey What if we all dressed up in period for one of the games?
Rym: and you know We're just a geeky enough group to where?
Rym: that was a very appealing idea.
Rym: because oh god.
Rym: Oh god.
Rym: Yes toga party Something that we didn't do in college We're gonna do now.
Rym: now that we're like in our mid 20s makes it so much more awesome.
Rym: It does.
Rym: but of course, you know, we were thinking about like yeah, we should actually do the toga party.
Rym: let's actually do this.
Rym: and then Scott and I of course as we always do whenever we think of something like this thought I ain't using no sheet.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Give me a real toga.
Scott: Hey Internet's now.
Rym: first we looked and we found how to make togas.
Rym: It's not that hard.
Rym: This one website was great.
Rym: It was like first off.
Rym: rule number one Don't use a sheet.
Rym: Cloth is so cheap.
Rym: Like seriously, dude, go to a craft store.
Rym: I don't think you understand how cheap cloth is for real.
Rym: also cloth comes in colors other than bed sheet white or stained bed sheet.
Scott: But so well, that's a good website.
Rym: It is but it is not my thing of the day.
Rym: my thing of the day is.
Rym: then we decided alright because you know the way we always handle.
Rym: getting something like this is we Don't get it.
Rym: if we just plan it we decide Alright, what is the best solution?
Rym: Like if money was no object.
Rym: Like what is the good solution?
Rym: doesn't mean we're gonna get the best.
Scott: the ultimate solution.
Scott: get like some Hollywood costume making people.
Rym: Yes, but then we're like like we figure out what's the best we could do and then we decide if that's worth it Or if we're gonna go cheap.
Rym: So we decided alright if I want to just buy a period toga a real one How much would it be?
Rym: and we looked around.
Scott: that's the one that was actually from the period or just a replica?
Rym: Well a replica.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I would like a Roman toga worn by a Roman.
Scott: Yes, well if you robbed the museum You might get it for a while before they catch you.
Rym: and we looked on Amazon and they have some cheap Costumes that look like real uncomfortable crap.
Scott: Yeah, but one of them looked kind of nice, but it looked uncomfortable.
Rym: Yeah, but then you know I found this website Lorenz nest and this site sells if you're into Greek or Roman stuff and you want to dress the part.
Rym: Good God, do they sell everything you need for a price?
Scott: It's not that it's yeah, I wanted the brush helmet and you know what they have the brush how they do.
Rym: It's not even that it's been $280.
Scott: You know what though?
Rym: That's less than I expected.
Scott: there is less but it is.
Scott: it's a reasonable price considering that's a real brush helmet or at least a real replica brush helmet, but as Much as I want a brush helmet.
Scott: I don't want one two hundred eighty dollars bad.
Rym: well, I think what happened here was you think how much would that cost?
Rym: and $280 is a reasonable price for what that is.
Rym: But our hope was what if our expectation of price is much higher than reality.
Rym: It's worth a shot You never know, but this site answered the question and partly because I got that raise I'm kind of thinking about getting one.
Rym: But if you want an authentic like Roman style toga like as they would wear made out of wool or linen.
Rym: I recommend linen.
Rym: They're about 200 bucks.
Scott: That's a little bit too much.
Scott: I'm looking for more like a 50 to 75 dollar toga.
Rym: Now if you want the senatorial one, it's 275.
Rym: Now multiple websites have said don't get wool Don't get wool for the love of God do not get wool.
Scott: Are you supposed to wear something under the toga or not?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Can I don't know a lot about togas to be honest.
Scott: We got to do some toga research.
Scott: Is there maybe a toga expert in the audience?
Rym: There is a toga Wikipedia that I'm not going to read now toga.
Rym: But just in case you wondered if you want a semi-authentic Linen toga the nicest one the senatorial one with the lining and everything.
Rym: It's under 300 lining.
Rym: Well, no like the lines on that like it's.
Rym: it's white but it has like nice embroidered lines around all the edges.
Scott: Does it tell you how to put it on?
Scott: is it come with instructions?
Rym: I'm sure there is a website All right.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: All right, so I'm using the Twitter a little bit more.
Scott: I got this Twitter client.
Rym: Are you a?
Rym: are you a Twitter shitter?
Scott: No, I got the it's like Twitter client that works in Adobe Air Right.
Rym: So I installed the Adobe Air alpha for non-citizens of Rome or forbidden from wearing togas according to Wikipedia in an unsighted sentence.
Scott: Anyway continue and then I. so I got this Twitter client going and then you know It's.
Scott: I'm still not really feeling it, but I'm gonna try to give it more of a chance.
Rym: Oh the Romans were togas differently from the way the Greeks just ignore my thing today.
Rym: Yes continue like you.
Scott: so I Figure, you know if there is something good there I'll give it like a little bit more of a chance before I just forget about it.
Scott: So along the way I sort of found this thing that sort of made the rounds today link wise and it basically what it is is if you're getting a package right you type in your tracking number and It'll Twitter you whenever there's a status update on your package.
Rym: That's a. that's one of the best uses of Twitter I've ever seen.
Scott: the thing is It's pretty much this thing has existed.
Scott: There were jabber boss that did this for a longest, but now it's on Twitter.
Scott: Yeah, but now it's on Twitter.
Rym: Why would I want?
Scott: there's no advantage to using this on Twitter versus any other instant message.
Rym: Why not just have a jabber me whatever jabber or aim or you know, what it emails me?
Rym: Anyway, I always have Gmail open right you can use.
Scott: you can use email or aim or jabber and it's just as good.
Scott: In fact, it's better than Twitter.
Scott: He's better is still more than X because Twitter's slow and Twitter also sort of has this public element And I don't know if you really want to show here.
Rym: Yes, Scott's LCD is now on his dad's porch.
Rym: Scott doesn't get home until 6.
Rym: In fact Scott just told you he's at work late.
Scott: Yeah, you kind of want your package tracking to be like a private to you thing, right?
Scott: So it's sort of like.
Scott: why do this with Twitter other than to get attention?
Scott: because Twitter is the hot thing right now.
Rym: But that's probably the best use.
Scott: Yeah, but regardless I am in someone when they're or text messaging when package tracking updates.
Scott: pretty good idea.
Scott: So that's it.
Scott: It's just a short thing of the day.
Scott: So togas are worn over loincloths Line cloth the most ancient type of clothing.
Scott: after seashell and leaf.
Scott: It's pretty much leaf seashell lung cloth.
Scott: that well you're forgetting.
Rym: heavy furs gave you an armor class of five.
Scott: No, you see the heavy furs were developed in tandem with the loincloth just in different places.
Scott: If you lived in the more tropical close to the equator the close to the equator You got the more odds that it was gonna be loincloth and the small of the law.
Rym: You're forgetting the most important element that you did penis gourd Penis gourd penis gourd penis gourd penis gourd was an advancement of one class.
Rym: See you realize that Anyone who doesn't really how else could they gird loins without loin cloths believe you mean gourd loins.
Rym: If anyone doesn't realize why I said penis gourd three-time penis gourd penis gourd penis gourd.
Rym: It's a farc ism.
Rym: Anytime the word penis gourd is mentioned someone must say penis gourd penis gourd penis gourd.
Rym: It's kind of a thing.
Rym: All right, that's all I got.
Rym: So it's what are we talking about tonight?
Scott: I don't think We're gonna talk about like the history of video cards and such.
Scott: So so check this out, right?
Scott: You have a computer computer has the processing which is the processor.
Scott: It has the inputs and the outputs.
Scott: inputs are mice and keyboard outputs or monitors and speakers and all that other sprinters, right?
Rym: So what has been blurred a little bit?
Rym: I mean the optimist keyboard is also output.
Scott: I know it's crazy.
Scott: Yeah So one of the outputs is the monitor but the thing is your computer doesn't really speak.
Scott: monitor.
Scott: I mean your monitor is a television.
Scott: you need to get the computer which is digital zeros and ones to somehow send out an analog Television signal that the TV can understand.
Rym: now remember that I mean like the computer revolution what made Computers like modern computers special as opposed to other kinds of purpose-built devices.
Rym: Was that their general purpose?
Rym: You know, that was the whole thing.
Rym: It was a the first general purpose computing device, right?
Scott: You had like calculators.
Scott: It was a computer that could calculate and couldn't do anything else.
Scott: you had like Synthesizers, it was a computer that could synthesize but it couldn't do much else.
Rym: but a computer was a programmable computer.
Rym: You could tell it to do basically any series of binary operations and get the results.
Scott: Yeah anything that could be done digitally it could do as long as they could get the input in the out.
Rym: now the the real deal Here is that in general if you make the more general you make a piece of hardware the less good It is at any particular tech, right?
Scott: If I make a chip right and that chip only does that's specifically designed a piece of hardware physical Specifically designed to say add one and one that is gonna add one and one so fast.
Scott: You have no idea.
Scott: Add one and one so fast, it'll be unbelievable.
Scott: But if I make a chip that can add any numbers It's gonna add one and one a little bit slower than the one in one chip.
Scott: Right if I make a chip that can you know do anything in the world like an Intel, you know core to duo It's still wicked fast.
Rym: just because we have wicked fast now We're definitely oversimplified because general-purpose computers tend to take complex tasks and then break them down into smaller tasks and you multiply by doing One and one and one and one and one or maybe you have a special purpose build thing.
Rym: in the process.
Rym: You're multiplying two majors.
Rym: people actually know that's what mostly what video cards do.
Scott: right, right.
Scott: So anyway, the point is is that you have to have this part of the computer that converts digital to what the monitor speaks.
Scott: Because even if the monitor is a digital monitor like using a DVI cable or an HDMI cable The monitor still it's still a different, you know language you need some part of the computer to convert, you know Sort of the the frame buffer, which is pretty much just.
Scott: you're like, okay I'm not gonna explain frame buffers But it's pretty much a piece of memory and in that memory is a picture of what the screen should look like.
Scott: right now You need something to convert that which is what the computer speaks into what the monitor speaks.
Scott: So in back in the day, all you had was on the motherboard.
Scott: They'd be like a chip that would take the frame buffer and turn it into a TV signal and then there'd be a wire coming Out of that.
Scott: they'll go to the TV.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Then over time it got a little more complex, you know, you know VGA.
Scott: eventually We get higher resolutions, right and things are getting pretty complicated.
Scott: then what sort of happened was people wanted to do things like watch videos right or do 3d stuff right and Those are very complicated tasks.
Scott: and having the CPU, you know that was doing everything else The computer was doing also do these complicated tasks was sort of burdening it and it was getting really slow.
Rym: now There's actually there's another.
Rym: I mean, there's another factor here and that it just so happens that a task like doing video Tends to be very computationally intensive in a very narrow band of computations.
Scott: Yep, it also just so happened that these tasks like watching video and doing 3d stuff like 3d games Were very popular among regular everyday people.
Scott: I mean there are other, you know, especially designed Hardware bits such as you know, you can Remember when there was the math coprocessor exactly exactly, right?
Scott: You know if you go get some like wicked science computer, right?
Scott: It probably has all these special science cards in it that do special science stuff But those aren't things that normal people want to do.
Rym: I mean remember we're talking.
Rym: I mean, we're not only talking about the video card.
Rym: But the video card is just a purpose-built kind of extension and it's not like.
Rym: I mean modern video cards are a relatively new thing But similar add-ons to computers have existed for almost as long as the sound card, right?
Scott: It's a. it's a special chip because a lot of people wanted sound to come out of their computers.
Scott: So because that was such a common thing rather than have the CPU do all the work of sound They made a special sound chip You know Which is also an analog conversion kind of thing and you would put that in there separately.
Scott: That way your computer could do really good things with sound without burdening the CPU.
Scott: So video is the same kind of thing and they eventually came out with a special Video card as opposed to just having you know a video chip on your motherboard and at first they were kind of hokey Like I remember.
Scott: there were even some where you would take the video cable from your regular video card Send it into the special video card then from the special video card to the monitor and it was really kind of crazy.
Scott: Need special drivers and it got way weird.
Scott: but Eventually, they just sort of said All right, we're gonna have a you know PCI slots.
Scott: you just put this video card in your computer and you plug the monitor into that and the computer will make sure to Use that as the ma as the video instead of you know Whatever is on the motherboard.
Scott: and then they weren't even putting video cards on motherboards anymore, which you know use like unthinkable.
Scott: You know, you would actually have to have a special video card.
Scott: You couldn't have.
Scott: you couldn't plug your monitor directly into your motherboard it didn't work anymore.
Scott: and You know over time it, you know, it got sort of crazy now in the early days, right?
Scott: They sort of had.
Scott: you know Nvidia was there pretty early ATI was there pretty early Matrox was there really early and so was voodoo.
Scott: I don't people remember the voodoo's right?
Rym: Ah the voodoo I knew better.
Scott: Yeah, I knew better than to buy into that crap and in the early days Voodoo was sort of the popular deal.
Scott: right matrox was pretty popular because they could do Dual monitors and they could do 2d stuff that the other people couldn't do.
Scott: like, you know If you wanted to monitors matrox is the only way to go pretty much and if you want.
Rym: if you were doing like 2d design Or anything.
Rym: matrix cards were like the god cards.
Scott: Yep and also the ATI Wasn't really popular.
Scott: ATI was sort of what you got if you bought a computer with a built-in card like they had that market cornered.
Scott: Like if you bought a computer, you know for that was already put together like a Dell or something or an IBM.
Scott: ATI was in there already.
Scott: Nvidia was sort of like, you know, you want to do the 3d business with OpenGL and Voodoo.
Scott: was you want to do the 3d business with glide?
Scott: now back in the day glide was actually pretty hot because the voodoo cards are really popular and We're not gonna explain exactly what that was.
Rym: We're not gonna explain what show on OpenGL will be required.
Scott: All you have to know is that the voodoo cards use glide and the Nvidia cards use OpenGL.
Rym: A layman's way of putting it is that the voodoo cards Basically had kind of half-assed OpenGL in order to make it affordable.
Rym: Yeah, and it was really fast, but it was also pretty Shitty.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway you say you would buy games.
Scott: right and the games like you'd buy a game and it would say yeah Okay, this game supports glide.
Scott: So if you had like glide card like a voodoo card.
Scott: Then you would get the card to help you out on that game and the game be cool.
Rym: I mean, I remember so we didn't have a glide card.
Scott: Like you've got an Nvidia card.
Scott: then that game wouldn't be helped by that Nvidia cards.
Scott: You needed to have a card that went with your games.
Rym: But I remember so clearly like back in the day There was quake the first modern 3d FPS Even though I consider quake 2 to be the first like playable modern 3d.
Scott: quake 1 was the first 3d FPS.
Rym: Yes, but it was.
Rym: it was kind of awful.
Scott: It was a bad game, but the mods were good technology technology wise that it was, you know, the first one.
Scott: Yep, you got to explore a brown castle and you got to look up and down and left and right.
Scott: you could aim in every Direction walk in every direction, but jump.
Rym: Yeah, that is problems.
Scott: But then, you know, there was an add-on that you could get GL quake and that if you had a GL cards if you had a voodoo card you were SOL.
Rym: Well, not really, but we'll talk about that when we do the OpenGL show.
Scott: But if you had an Nvidia card GL quake all suddenly, it was awesome.
Rym: See the thing is Actual.
Rym: true OpenGL support was not common early on.
Scott: it was very difficult.
Rym: You had to install GL things and and also a lot of car just didn't support it.
Scott: Yeah, it pretty much everything sucked in those days sucked hard.
Scott: There were also like s3 cards Like I remember there was a point at which like if you had an s3 card then descent 2 would be helped out by it.
Scott: But nothing else really and it was bad times bad times.
Scott: But that's what you had to do if you wanted to.
Scott: you know, have you know the 3d games, you know People had to write the 3d game using a specific 3d language to talk to the specific card and all the cards are different.
Scott: You need to match it up, you know, but eventually things got better mostly because DirectX, you know and everyone started just doing direct 3d or OpenGL and that was pretty much the only choices.
Scott: and It narrowed down over time.
Scott: and voodoo.
Scott: they were stupid and they went away right because instead of improving their technology They just made cars that had more and more chips on them without actually making better chips.
Scott: So they got canned.
Scott: the voodoo 3 was a stinker and they never made it anywhere else.
Rym: there were Problems.
Scott: I remember there was a voodoo card.
Scott: They were like, yeah, this voodoo card is so crazy.
Scott: It's like eight chips on it.
Scott: You get to plug it into the wall on its own like there'd be a power cord coming out of your video card.
Scott: And I was like that's never gonna fly and it never flew.
Rym: Yeah, but we're not.
Scott: I mean a lot of that is for other shows at other times But I mean it narrowed down to where is pretty much just ATI and Nvidia and the difference between the two is this Nvidia was a little better with the OpenGL's.
Scott: ATI was a little better direct 3ds until very recently.
Scott: Nvidia had great drivers and ATI had garbage drivers pretty much and also The Nvidia was a little bit more money for it sort of varied like which one had the better price to performance ratio But Nvidia tended to be a little bit behind on that.
Scott: The other thing was that the ATI.
Scott: ATI made the ATI cards.
Scott: if you wanted an ATI chip You bought a card that was made by ATI and that was your option.
Scott: That was the only option.
Scott: Nvidia just made the chips and anyone in the world could make Nvidia cards like.
Scott: my first video card was a TNT to made by diamond But it had a you know, it had the first Nvidia TNT to chip on it, right?
Rym: Well, I had my creative graphics blaster Extreme and what?
Scott: what kind of ship was on there?
Scott: I don't remember yeah, but Nvidia made chips and other people made the cards right and From there, they just sort of had a race and they kept raising and raising and raising until where we are today which is where you know.
Scott: for a time Nvidia had superior Linux support and I still think they do.
Scott: but a AMD ATAT merged and a ATI sort of released all this driver stuff to the Linux people.
Scott: So the ATI driver is getting way better, you know, the open source ones getting way better, you know.
Scott: So at that that department is sort of sorted itself out You know, and that's I guess that's really the history of video cards.
Scott: I mean, what else is there to say about it?
Rym: Yeah, kind of a cop-out show, but we had a lot to say in the beginning about unrelated things.
Scott: Yeah things you probably didn't know about like the early days of the video card and stuff.
Rym: I mean, I guess my question to you is Of all the things we touched on briefly What among there are you interested in because we could do a show on OpenGL Talk about like what OpenGL is what DirectX or just 3d acceleration in general We could talk about.
Rym: I guess on Tuesday that the full history of FPS is.
Scott: Yep, the thing you really just need to know is that you know It's they need.
Scott: people wanted to do 3d.
Scott: A lot of people wanted to do it in their computers.
Scott: the CPU couldn't be bothered because CPUs are really expensive.
Scott: You couldn't have two of them.
Scott: That's crazy.
Scott: And if you had the CPU do the 3d It'd be really slow and shitty because it had to do other things at the same time.
Rym: now one one bit of practical knowledge Pretty much.
Rym: if you're not a gamer it matters very little.
Rym: it matters pretty much not like nowadays Unless you're a gamer you really don't care.
Rym: What kind of video got?
Scott: the cheapest one?
Rym: Yeah, George, just use the one built into your motherboard.
Rym: It'll work.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, you have to get a motherboard that has them built in.
Scott: Yeah, that's actually a really good option if you don't care, but you know They made a special chip that would do just the graphics and then they wrote the games and the drivers to make it happen.
Scott: and That's that's.
Rym: that's the way it is This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.