Rym: It's Tuesday April 8th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk about the new Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles game for the DS.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: David Joe.
Scott: Dave hates advanced.
Rym: Why does Dave hate advanced?
Scott: because it's so hard.
Rym: It's not that hard if you're smart.
Scott: I know but on his latest show he was talking about he likes that He has.
Scott: there are more PSP games He likes than DS But he said it really depends on what kind of games you like and how he doesn't really do the advanced or so.
Rym: Well, I the thing is the advanced wars alone was enough for me to buy a DS Mm-hmm, but yeah, we didn't really have much to talk about.
Rym: nothing exciting happened today.
Rym: Scott's train was weird and I was tired on the train.
Scott: I was real tired on the train.
Scott: I need to eat fierce food.
Scott: Let's go get now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, usually I'm the one who's like, hey, let's eat.
Rym: So here we go tides turn tables And the worst part right is.
Scott: I was gonna buy like a rye bread on the way home But I left all my cash at home and I didn't want to get out more cash.
Scott: Yeah, because I had so much on my desk because I took a later train.
Rym: So I had like a half hour to kill before I took it.
Rym: So I went.
Rym: I would try to buy a belt.
Rym: I learned that hmm hmm didn't have a belt in my size and I went and I got some samosa.
Scott: buying belts is really hard.
Scott: Yeah, I've had this belt I have.
Scott: it's like it's weird.
Scott: when I was in high school I had a belt that lasted like a hundred years.
Scott: Well, it felt like a hundred years, right?
Scott: Then I bought another one and it lasted a super long time.
Rym: I think part of it was when I was young.
Rym: I didn't really wear a belt ever.
Scott: I wore a belt.
Scott: I were on a belt like every with every Every day for a long time.
Rym: and what kind of?
Rym: because we grew up at the same time.
Rym: We were in the same grades and everything.
Rym: But when I was in like middle school and early high school the style of the times was everyone wore blue jeans.
Rym: Everyone wore like.
Rym: I wear a belt when I wear jeans like a black t-shirt Untucked and you don't need a belt if you're wearing on tux.
Scott: I have the belt under my untucked.
Rym: You don't need that unless your pants are way too big.
Scott: No, my pants aren't too big.
Scott: I wear the belt even if my pants stay on their own.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I just do plus.
Rym: it makes it extra little bald.
Rym: You don't want that.
Rym: and then you wear a flannel shirt over there.
Scott: Plus, I think it's also the belt.
Scott: you can hook things onto it, but I'd ever.
Rym: we didn't have cell phones back then.
Scott: What would you do it?
Scott: I had a cell phone.
Rym: Well, I had one but it was too big to hook to my belt.
Scott: No, well, yeah, you're talking about a little longer ago that I'm talking about middle school.
Scott: I'm talking about high school, but that the guardless.
Scott: I always wear a belt.
Scott: but recently my belts have been fault like But not because of stretching or fatness just because of like getting worn out of you know, putting them on taking them off But it's like the.
Scott: you know The mechanism on the belt breaks or you know the holes on the belt like sort of wear out.
Scott: Wow, they don't make belts like they used to.
Rym: I've never had a belt wear out.
Rym: I'm buying a new one solely because my current one is a little chipped on the buckle and it looks bad.
Scott: So I'm gonna buy a new one Perfectly functional the last belt I had wore out and this one's not doing too bad.
Rym: my other belt the only other belt I own other than my dress belt is The same one that I've worn since like sixth grade.
Scott: I think I'm just gonna get a rope because I think that'll do a lot better.
Rym: You know a lot of people use that as a style now
Scott: just like a climbing rope, you know Cuz that right now if I can never break it cost a lot, but I only need to get like, you know I
Rym: know you've been using that fancy new knot on your shoes.
Rym: What kind of knot are you gonna use for your belt?
Rym: There's like a thousand options.
Scott: Oh, see, that's the thing is, you know people have different belt buckles Cowboy buckles.
Scott: that are really awesome, but they keep switching them up from day to day.
Scott: Yeah, I would just have a different knot every day.
Scott: I'd be like today.
Scott: We're gonna do it to enhance.
Rym: How come you're so excited about knots and belts and knots and shoes But yet you only know how to tie one kind of time.
Scott: It's the weakest tying tie because tying a tie is harder than tying a row.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it's really easy.
Scott: I know I watch those YouTube videos and I copied them But the point is is it's because it's like around your neck and you got to use a mirror.
Scott: It's more difficult than this tying a rope.
Rym: That's like, oh, yeah, you definitely need to use a mirror if you suck.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, anyway, I'm a fan of the full Windsor but on the train I Finally because I stopped playing advanced wars.
Rym: I also stopped playing advanced wars and I got to the owl mission That actually that's the only mission I ever got to see on.
Scott: Yeah, I just I I could beat it.
Scott: I just it's retake.
Scott: It's the way I'm.
Scott: I tried to do it And it's just TD.
Rym: Well, you're doing it wrong.
Rym: I'm probably doing it wrong but the way only reason I got to see is because I Basically, there's two ways to play advanced wars the and this is in every advanced wars other than this one.
Rym: The newest one is a not quite like this, but you can either play perfectly and pretty much never lose units or Play realistically and I will like lines of infantry marching forward to their death.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much like over.
Scott: either overwhelm the guy with superior force and tactics and you know But people are dying all over the place or build a very small amount of units very cleverly So you sneak in and win somehow.
Rym: What I love about the new advanced wars is that for the most part that doesn't work.
Rym: Yes a real war game It's like the best like oh my god advanced wars is such a good game.
Rym: It's pretty good But yeah, but I stopped playing it because I had a million other games to play and I've been watching avatar.
Rym: But I suddenly had the advanced wars bug again, which I get periodically like when I lived in the mountains out in poquoi.
Rym: I Saw that was when I decided you know what?
Rym: I'm gonna beat the advanced campaign on advanced wars one and I'm gonna keep beating it until I get an S.
Scott: That's just a great.
Rym: and then I did the same thing in every other advanced wars and as of today I finally beat every single mission in advanced wars on that campaign.
Scott: with an S.
Rym: I got almost all S's and A's Alma and I have like one see the owl mission and I have two B's.
Scott: Yeah, you gotta tell me how to do that stupid owl cuz.
Scott: if I beat that I'd probably pick up the game and finish it Off, all right go around the edges.
Scott: I did that.
Rym: It just took so long Slow how long you think you can beat it in like 40 days.
Scott: That's a long time.
Rym: Let me you might not like the rest of that game then because I'm gonna warn you about something.
Rym: One of the a lot of the missions was one in particular.
Rym: That's called Jay Islands.
Rym: It's a four player every man for himself map against the AI.
Scott: I think I beat that one.
Rym: Did you?
Rym: I don't know How long did you take you?
Rym: because I beat it in like 50 something days with heavy losses.
Scott: Yeah, I did.
Scott: I did play a map.
Scott: That was four islands every man for himself.
Scott: There's a lot of maps like that I know but basically all I did was I attacked one of the other islands took it over and as soon as I had two Islands, the other two islands were just cake.
Rym: I just washed them by taking forever and taking heavy losses.
Rym: I got an S because that's what it expected you to do.
Rym: Yeah, I think I got an S also and whichever one I'm thinking of I don't know why you're having so much trouble with the owl the one after it is a thousand times harder.
Rym: Well, I don't.
Scott: I haven't had that one yet.
Scott: Have I you know what?
Rym: It's kind of like man.
Rym: I can't climb this 10-foot rope.
Scott: If only I could climb the 10-foot rope, but it would it would hurt.
Scott: so it's kind of like.
Scott: it's not fun And it's supposed to be fun.
Scott: It's a video game.
Scott: So I'm not gonna do it.
Rym: Here's the problem.
Rym: All right I don't want to climb this 10-foot rope.
Scott: little.
Rym: do you know that behind the 10-foot rope is a thousand foot rope?
Scott: Yeah in advanced wars really depending on the map in the scenario It's either super fun or maybe not so fun.
Rym: The thing is I've noticed at least for me You don't seem to like maps that involve a lot of tactics or strategy or a very large.
Scott: Yeah, I really I tend to like the smaller maps, but that's cuz.
Rym: then the game's a puzzle.
Rym: It's just it's just battle or but not as right.
Scott: and I and I tend to like the maps that don't have like land sea And air.
Rym: I like sort of like oh, no, you need all three because then there's so much to the game.
Scott: Yeah, I like sort of like, you know, this land and sea or land and air just land.
Rym: Maybe after the show while we're eating Chinese food out we can play some tiny maps.
Scott: tiny maps are okay.
Rym: What I really want to talk about is I've been playing on the Wi-Fi a lot because a lot of people are on there and I like to I don't know.
Rym: I've decided that even though it's not challenging like playing on the Wi-Fi is it almost wouldn't be fun because you can't lose to these people ever.
Rym: but there's something about like beating.
Rym: the AI is one thing even especially if they because AI is really good, but You don't really get that visceral satisfaction.
Rym: But every time I play on the Wi-Fi it's like I get these moments where I'm Spreading out all over the map and my guys are everywhere and it's always fog of war and like
Scott: bump
Rym: I'll see him like run a few of the guys He sent out into my mass to the north and you I know on the other he's going.
Rym: god damn it All right.
Rym: At least I can take the area to the south and then he runs into my guys down there, too.
Rym: Ah, at least I can take the middle.
Rym: then he runs into my guys there and that's right about when they always quit.
Rym: Mmm, I don't know if I'm just a Freak and I'm like beyond good at this game or I just I'm playing against the wrong people, but I've never lost good God.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know me.
Scott: Maybe you just had to keep playing online Until like you have the highest rank or whatever and then maybe someone will realize you're so awesome or I don't know.
Rym: I'm scared because I asked in the forum and no one answered.
Rym: is anyone out there good?
Rym: at advance Wars I want to play against someone who's good.
Rym: No one in the front row crew is good And yes, I'm serious about that.
Scott: you people none of us are.
Scott: You're not claiming to be good.
Rym: pretty much every time we play it'll be a four player free-for-all and it's like Scott will always be yelling.
Rym: All right other Scott.
Rym: don't let Rym win.
Rym: Don't let Rym win.
Rym: Let's all gang up on Rym, but then no one gangs up on me.
Rym: And then the next thing they know I've got three quarters.
Scott: even if they do getting up on you It only helps a little.
Scott: we really we really have to gang up on you full-on.
Rym: I kind of want to make a video of like how to be good at advance Wars.
Scott: Yeah, we need to get one of those DS video capture thingies.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is the.
Rym: the answer is very simple plan 20 turns in advance.
Rym: Count all your money.
Rym: spend exactly all of it all the time.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, anyway, what do you got in the news?
Rym: You can tell it's kind of a light news day.
Scott: Yeah, there wasn't so much news going on, but I did notice something that is very special for me.
Scott: You know Nintendo with the Wii and the Virtual Console, you know It's been a while since we talked about the Virtual Console.
Scott: but you know Nintendo has been releasing new games in the Virtual Console every Monday as Promised since the Wii came out and that's that's pretty impressive.
Scott: They just kept it up.
Scott: They kept on trucking.
Rym: Yeah, well probably because they're selling.
Rym: they're making so much money off of good weird.
Scott: It's like I could.
Scott: I could easily have ROMs.
Rym: I do.
Scott: I buy Virtual Console games anyway.
Scott: The reason I actually the reason it's worth it for me to buy them is cuz number one.
Scott: I don't buy that many.
Scott: so it's even though it's a ripoff price.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: you know, I don't buy so many that it hurts my wall, too.
Rym: I mean, they are perfect.
Rym: Like if you want to play StarTropics, that's the only way to play it.
Scott: Yeah, cuz those wrong.
Scott: There's the ROMs don't work.
Rym: The ROMs are all that curse.
Rym: the game barely worked I know.
Scott: and the other thing that you get by buying the Virtual Console games is you get to play with a decent controller.
Scott: now You might be saying I'll plug a gamepad into your PC.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: No.
Rym: Well one.
Rym: No, it's not good God.
Scott: But well, you could get a higher quality.
Scott: you can use an Xbox 360 controller on your piece.
Rym: I'm still pretty crap for these games.
Rym: What you need is the SNES USB controller.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, you can get that too.
Rym: or you could just associate your remote bluetooth.
Scott: wise Yeah, you could do that, too.
Scott: But you know this just sort of just works and it's easy and it's easy to do to player and all that.
Scott: So, you know for a game that's a really special game.
Scott: I'll buy the Virtual Console game and for a long time.
Scott: most of the Virtual Console games are coming out.
Scott: Some of them have been good, but none of them really made me want to spend money on them in a while.
Rym: You gotta be in the Mike Tyson's punch-out class of game.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's like the last one we bought right?
Scott: Yeah, pretty much zero X.
Rym: I think I also call God if super dodgeball hits that thing.
Scott: Dogil's gonna the DS soon.
Rym: I know I know but I want the original on the VC.
Scott: But anyway this week they came out yesterday with two Virtual Console games that are must buys.
Scott: they're both games I originally owned on the NES and I'm gonna buy him again.
Scott: It's so sad.
Scott: The first game is a little story, right?
Scott: So Emily has this baseball anime she likes right and Like you're in the kitchen once and she was just like Jaja Jaja Jaja Jaja Jaja Jaja Jaja.
Scott: and I was like Are you singing the song from Bases Loaded?
Scott: Cuz like I. you know Emily's cool and she plays video games, but I didn't think she ever played Bases Loaded.
Scott: So I was like, how did she know the song from Bases Loaded?
Rym: It's like.
Rym: most people our age don't know the song from bass.
Scott: I know so she's well, she is our age.
Scott: Guess well close to it.
Rym: Well, it's weird how we're so close in age And yet we're like, we're definitely children of the 80s and she is definitely more child of the 90s.
Scott: Yeah, baby She's just like.
Scott: yes And I'm like, how do you know Bases Loaded?
Scott: and she was like in the baseball anime I watch.
Scott: the guy like came up to bat and he was singing Jaja Jaja Jaja Jaja.
Scott: So obviously the people who make the baseball anime played Bases Loaded for the NES and they had.
Scott: They had their character also play Bases Loaded for the NES.
Scott: and I'm thinking well if I played baseball I would probably be I would have them play that.
Scott: when I went up to the math went up to You know the seat the PA system, but because that is one of the best baseball and bass bass is loaded.
Scott: I mean if you're talking about good baseball games, it's pretty much it's like with every sports game There's an unrealistic and a realistic right?
Scott: So for example with ice hockey realistic you've got Blades of Steel and unrealistic ice hockey with baseball.
Scott: You've got baseball simulator 1000 or 10,000 or a million or whatever 1000.
Rym: Yeah one dot zero.
Scott: and for realistic you've got Bases Loaded, you know for football You've got unrealistic Mutant League football and you got realistic Tecmo Bowl, right?
Scott: So Bases Loaded I think is there's just something about that game.
Scott: It doesn't have any official teams, right?
Scott: But it has great music.
Scott: the controls and the fielding actually work.
Scott: the hitting and pitching mechanic is actually complex.
Scott: You actually have to put in relief pitchers, you know because they wear out and they all have different like pitching styles.
Scott: and it's really interesting to watch the way different guys throw the ball and they and like all the batters have different stances and they have their.
Scott: you see their names up there and they actually Even though they don't say anything they barely have any faces.
Scott: They all have like character and like I always played as this one team and it's like some of the batters just better than others like as they should be.
Rym: and it's like I Used to sit there and make all the stats for all my teams and baseball simulator.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, you know, I had like characters on my team like Warner and I was like, oh Warner's my man He stands up perfectly straight and he just always it's a home run Like I had.
Scott: like I had a you know certain pitchers I chose in a certain order like I remember their numbers.
Scott: I was like I use you first and I use you in the middle of the game and then you come in and you're the Relief pitcher and they they all had a different style and it really it's a high-quality baseball game and it's awesome.
Scott: So the other game is a game.
Scott: I love that Rym hates.
Scott: Well Yoshi's cookie fuck that game.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: That game was not.
Scott: she's cookie is the best Is the best the best the best game to player Versus puzzle game ever.
Rym: I much prefer.
Rym: Well puzzle game Advance Wars one.
Scott: Now, you know what?
Scott: I mean that sort of blocks moving around Tetris II kind of puzzle.
Rym: No, dr.
Rym: Mario.
Scott: Dr Mario is real good.
Scott: It's real.
Rym: Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Mario is awesome but I think Yoshi's cookie has a slight edge because Yoshi's cookie has this sort of mechanic where you line up the Yoshi cookies and with just the right timing to get like the certain You know effect to happen and it's I just love Yoshi's cookie.
Scott: This is the NES version.
Scott: There was an SNES version which is basically improved graphics and sound and a few extra features.
Scott: But really I think the NES version was the best implementation of Yoshi's cookie, and I really like Yoshi's cookie.
Scott: So if you like puzzle games Yoshi's cookie Yoshi's cookie.
Scott: Yoshi's cookie Not the original Yoshi.
Scott: Remember the games.
Scott: It was just called Yoshi for the Gameboy and the NES.
Rym: I'm trying to remember.
Scott: it was like the things would come down and you would like.
Scott: they would be bloopers and goombas And you have bottoms of shells and tops of shells.
Scott: game was crap and you would.
Scott: it was okay But it was pretty bad.
Scott: Mario would just sort of spin the things around.
Scott: you have a lot of control and it you couldn't but That was.
Scott: it was an okay Gameboy game, I guess but Yoshi's cookie was far as a berry.
Rym: So I got a real brief news just because this is kind of interesting.
Rym: but Nintendo has been working with Pokemon to fight Counterfeiters like Nintendo is Pokemon.
Rym: Yes, but it's funny because this headline here says quote Nintendo and Pokemon.
Scott: but I think Pokemon is like a like this game freaks and it's sort of like this subdivision of Nintendo.
Scott: that sort of Nintendo owns it but it's like oh, you know, here's the explanation.
Rym: It turns out that Nintendo sent ash along with Charizard.
Rym: So there we go.
Rym: Okay Yeah, anyway, pretty much the deal here is that there's Pokemon piracy, but it's not the games It's the cards for the card game and there's a multi-million dollar worldwide bootlegging Organization.
Scott: how can owns bootlegging magic cars?
Rym: I'll bet people were.
Rym: maybe I would.
Rym: I mean I wouldn't bootleg them.
Rym: But if I were playing magic back in the day before, you know Kind of this new wave of everyone plays these sealed deck whatever tournaments.
Rym: I Would have had so many bootleg magic cards.
Scott: Yeah I mean Why not?
Rym: I used to play actually with a lot of like Italian magic cards because they they reprinted lotuses and everything in Italy With pretty much as many as you wanted, but then tournaments caught on they wouldn't let you play with non English cards Even though that
Scott: anyway, it's bullshit,
Rym: but I found this kind of funny.
Rym: So kids if you play the Pokemon game like hard game Well, mostly parents your kids play the Pokemon game.
Rym: go to Chinatown.
Rym: You can buy those cards real cheap Yeah, and what's what's the difference?
Scott: as long as they're in English, right?
Scott: You can read them.
Scott: You can play with them.
Scott: So what what the fuck do you care if they're not official?
Scott: real deal, whatever's.
Rym: well, it's bad for Nintendo.
Scott: That's the dirt Nintendo is doing.
Scott: just fine.
Rym: trust is illegal.
Scott: Yeah, I guess.
Scott: I guess it really is a copyright infringement.
Rym: It's no different than stealing a DVD.
Scott: Yeah, I guess.
Scott: but you know buying a poke I don't know.
Scott: for some reason it feels like it's not.
Scott: it's not bad, but I guess it is kind of.
Rym: I just find it funny.
Rym: I'm indifferent.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: from the players standpoint It's like why not?
Scott: the thing is I think it piss off a lot of people who are like collectors.
Scott: But if you're a collector, it's like screw you.
Scott: it's a game.
Scott: It's meant to be played for fun here.
Scott: if you want if you need money get a job.
Scott: You'll make a lot more money get a job than collecting suit Pokemon card.
Rym: There's one thing people who like collected because they like them.
Rym: But I know a lot of people who collect collectible card games because they're sure that much like Magic the Gathering They'll increase in value now
Scott: even if they do
Rym: well the amount of
Scott: time and effort it takes to collect them and do all that bullshit and eBay and Not
Rym: only you could be
Scott: working and making a lot more money at a job.
Rym: my mox emerald and whatever magic cards I've got for like.
Rym: I got a revised set and all this stuff.
Rym: They're not really worth much more now than they were Ten years ago.
Scott: I make enough to buy a revised set in like less than a week.
Rym: Well, lottie done in monocle.
Scott: Well, I don't know how many how much is a revised.
Scott: Let's go see on eBay gonna go find out.
Scott: I'm gonna see how much one's going for an eBay.
Rym: All right, I'll stall for some time.
Rym: cuz God do your news.
Scott: That was my news.
Rym: Okay, so advanced wars, but seriously pretty much everyone I've played against online.
Scott: Oh my god There's a Magic the Gathering complete revised set near mint to mint.
Scott: All right on eBay.
Scott: All right, the auction will be over now.
Rym: Remember revised was the first real release of magic.
Rym: I mean there was unlimited and revised.
Scott: Yep It's the auction only has 15 hours left.
Scott: Okay, guess what.
Scott: the price on this is five bids.
Scott: This is a real-deal auction.
Rym: Guess what the price is $1,000 not even close 10,000 not even close a Hundred-thousand.
Scott: now your way you're getting farther away 20 bucks.
Scott: No, it's a hundred and fifty dollars and 75 cents.
Rym: Wow, my magic cards were worth a lot more ten years ago than they are now.
Scott: Meanwhile right under that there's Magic the Gathering 40 revised dual lands I have like multiples of every dual land.
Rym: Those things were uncommon.
Scott: They're not it's not they weren't rare Yeah, but it's you know, those are the only dual lands there.
Scott: Meanwhile, the set of 40 dual lands has 16 bids is gonna be over in a day And it's six hundred dollars, huh?
Scott: So that revive of you the real the revised set must have one of each.
Scott: do a little bit, right?
Rym: Think carefully.
Rym: does it?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes, it does.
Scott: Ah Anyway Freaking collectors get a job.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: I'm continuing my those were the days theme week.
Rym: I think this is pretty cool by thinking the day.
Rym: I'm using it partly because it's it's so barely related.
Rym: the guy happens to play the song.
Rym: Those were the days.
Rym: but the real reason I'm using this because I'm sure many of you have heard this instrument before.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, it's a really Herman.
Rym: No, not the theremin.
Scott: No the kazoo not the kazoo.
Scott: Oh the Hammond organ Hammond organs.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I like the Hammond organ a lot.
Rym: In fact, my grandma had a Hammond organ that I used to play constantly as a little kid.
Scott: That's the one with like the little.
Scott: there's like two pianos one on top of the other and you could.
Scott: there's these things.
Scott: you can Pull on that sort of point towards you.
Rym: Yep And those different those determine like what harmonics you'll get to play and there's also pedals.
Rym: There's also pedals.
Scott: It's kind of small though, right?
Rym: It's like they can be big but they could be but it's the ones we buy are like what they Were is they were early?
Rym: synthesizers and a lot of like churches would use them as a low-cost alternative to a pipe organ because pipe organs are Expensive most hard things that can ever exist.
Rym: See as down as I am on religion I Really really like pipe organs that pretty much you want to get me into a church.
Rym: the fastest way to do it is tell me There's a pipe organ there.
Scott: They just you know, turn all churches into at least the ones with pipe organs into dis organ concert halls.
Rym: Actually, there's a somewhat famous pipe organ up in Poughkeepsie.
Rym: There's concerts semi regularly.
Rym: I just haven't had time to head up there.
Scott: Yeah, but is it all churchy?
Rym: No, no, not at all.
Scott: No, okay.
Rym: but anyway, the the Hammond organ is used extensively in blues and jazz and The Blues Brothers movie.
Rym: that like you have an organ is everywhere and when you hear it played you'll know exactly What that instrument is.
Rym: part of the reason they're really cool.
Rym: Is that kind of like a pipe organ?
Rym: one person can play the melody and the harmony and the bass line at the same time?
Rym: Mmm, and this exemplifies that it's a good video.
Rym: and if you're interested in Hammond organs, let me know.
Rym: I'll do a show on them because I kind of know a lot about them and they're kind of cool.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: think about Hammond organs other than what they look and sound like.
Scott: I don't know how to play one.
Scott: I don't know how it works.
Rym: what they look and sound like is mostly what you need to know.
Rym: They work is not that interesting.
Scott: it's basically aren't some of them like electronic or all electronic.
Scott: Yeah, so it's a deal.
Rym: They were early synthesizers.
Scott: I remember like that.
Scott: Oh, that's someone's house who had one.
Scott: They plugged in and started like worrying and yeah loud noise.
Scott: Well before you even pushed any keys.
Rym: part of the deal, too Is that this kind of sounded bad early on like they had a lot of problems.
Rym: But now people who use these things like they got used to those bad sounds.
Rym: so technology got better.
Rym: but people want them to still sound that way.
Rym: that sound that's kind of hissy and and Wavery and bad is what people like.
Scott: That's why I'm sure we can just simulate Hammond organs with computers now.
Scott: Oh, we most definitely can know what.
Scott: do you don't need to have an organ?
Rym: See, well, you still need the Hammond organ interface if you want to play.
Scott: Well, you can just take like a double keyboard with levers and plug it into the computer you could.
Rym: yeah I wonder if anyone's done that.
Scott: I'm sure.
Scott: so maybe I'm sure if you went to those people who sell organs to old people to Rip them off that they would have for you and a let a MIDI Hammond organ.
Rym: No, no, you don't want MIDI.
Rym: I already realized a Wonderful market opportunity.
Rym: So we make a Hammond console that has all the interface of a Hammond.
Scott: It's also a computer.
Rym: It's no it's two pieces.
Rym: the piece that goes on the desk and then a pout of the pedal board for your feet is separate All right, and it's just USB.
Rym: and then we sell software.
Scott: All right, that would make we have Hammond Hammond hero, huh?
Rym: You know what I do though.
Rym: I would use the Hammond interface to play like TIE fighter.
Scott: So There's an NES game called glider.
Scott: Have you ever heard of it?
Scott: No, cuz it's kind of scarily new.
Rym: That's why Is this one of those someone put together a hacked ROM and made an NES game?
Scott: I actually know it says here a glider Game and name copyright 1989 John Calhoun, but it looks like a really new NES game At least I never heard of it before now.
Scott: And it says coming early April.
Scott: So it's early April and I think they sold out.
Rym: or are you sure they're not?
Scott: it's not coming early April 1990 I'm sure because this is all over all the video game news websites like right now.
Scott: But basically that's not the important part of this story.
Scott: the game itself.
Scott: the game itself is you know It's a game where you control the paper airplane and like air vents lift you up But you try to get across the room without touching the floor, you know that game All right, the important part of this game is it's on an NES cartridge.
Scott: You can play it in an NES.
Scott: it will work right but The NES cartridge right.
Scott: if you're gonna make an NES cartridge today, right?
Scott: What would you put on the circuit board in the NES cartridge?
Rym: probably an emulator?
Scott: No Like hardware wise a hardware NES emulator it wouldn't be that hard Probably.
Rym: and then a bunch of ROMs.
Scott: now what they did put in there USB.
Scott: Well, like nothing actually is not a USB, but there is some flash memory Instead of you know, just you know ROM like in the olden days.
Scott: So they have a flash memory and then like an an NES interface Note they had if you buy a separate device called a USB copy nests, right?
Scott: Which is a device that is basically takes NES cartridge on one side and USB on the other side Huh?
Scott: If you buy that device which could normally allow you I think to rip ROMs if you get that device then you can put download and flash new levels into this game.
Scott: and You know, that's not so exciting nowadays where we have, you know, like the r4 for the DS and stuff like that, right?
Scott: but Imagine if someone had given you back in the day an NES cartridge.
Scott: Well, you could download you could put new levels onto that card.
Rym: I remember in middle school.
Rym: There was a kid in our street who claimed that he had a ROM dumper.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: It turned out.
Rym: No, he had a game genie.
Rym: Suffice to say no, but like that was the same kid who stole another kid's Megaman 3 and then traded it to me for hide lied.
Scott: Well, he got the worst end of that.
Rym: but then the kid came.
Rym: he's like, where's my Megaman 3?
Rym: and I was like I traded Hydlide for you're not getting it back.
Scott: I would have given it back saying don't worry that kid got me deserved.
Scott: He got highlight.
Rym: I did give it back.
Scott: Yeah, I mean highlight is crap.
Scott: I'd rather have nothing than have highlight.
Rym: You think is highlight was not the worst game on the NES?
Scott: No, it wasn't.
Scott: but like it was weird.
Scott: because you look at highlight and you're like Concept of my blood you go god damn.
Scott: That's awesome.
Rym: But then you play it and it doesn't work.
Scott: if someone made a highlight that works.
Scott: That'd be awesome.
Scott: Oh so awesome.
Scott: But yeah, is?
Scott: it is a cool get any s game you could plan it on?
Scott: Yes, you could flash new levels into it.
Scott: That's pretty awesome.
Rym: I got to say though saying oh what if you gave it to yourself as a kid?
Rym: What if you gave yourself a DS?
Rym: is a kid?
Rym: Holy shit What if?
Rym: what if shit your pants an iPod an mp3 player?
Scott: I just I just pee on everybody the monitor I have.
Rym: now I I don't know what I do if I saw a monitor like this twice.
Scott: I think it was like a TV But it's flat.
Rym: Oh, right.
Scott: It's flat.
Rym: Oh shit Goddamn just give a kid like the USB Drive.
Rym: I got right here.
Scott: I would just sell it to the richest person on earth for like a billion bajillion dollars.
Rym: the USB Drive I'd be like, what's that?
Rym: But - if someone said there are two gigabytes on that.
Scott: Oh my god I remember.
Scott: and so what's a gig of?
Scott: they had this.
Scott: the guy had this big box like it was.
Scott: it was big.
Scott: It was like it was the size of like an automatic card shuffler, you know That's you know, like that kind of yeah, and it was heavy like it weighed a good 10 pounds or more Right, and it had a little apple on it and it was an external hard drive.
Scott: and they said and the guy was from England He was like, this is one gigabyte and there's an Australian accent.
Scott: Sorry, right?
Scott: But it was one gigabyte and it was like.
Scott: everyone was like, holy shit.
Scott: Holy shit one gigabyte, right?
Scott: Wow But now I carry one gigabyte.
Scott: like is smaller than my thing.
Rym: I carry two and in the Marantz is four.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: All right, let's do the show.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So what are we talking about tonight?
Scott: We're gonna tell you about that DS game the terrible one.
Scott: Oh, oh we revealed it was terrible.
Rym: Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles for the DS ring of fates is fades.
Scott: It's not they're not even gonna beat around the bush.
Scott: It's a bad game.
Scott: this game is with little redeeming qualities.
Rym: bad to the point that I'd pre-ordered two copies of it and Then I had pre-ordered a third copy for Emily because we thought oh, we'll all play together.
Rym: You know like the other Crystal Chronicles, which we have described more than once as a trend send an experience even worse because it was A Square Enix game right that said Final Fantasy on it.
Scott: It was $40 instead of the usual $30 DS game price.
Rym: So alright Not only did I cancel the third pre-order for Emily, but I played two of the quote-unquote missions and I poked around at everything else and I don't know anyone want the game.
Rym: Yeah Well, I gotta get rid of this game cuz I think I'm gonna give mine to Emily so she can see and then it will Give it away to someone else.
Scott: Yeah, maybe she'll like it cuz she's never played a game like that.
Rym: But I doubt it, you know The game could have been fun if you'd handed it to me along with the DS back when I had my game gear.
Rym: But even then crystal warriors for the game gear was a much better game.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: That's true?
Rym: Yeah, of course I'll warn you all because it's relevant crystal chronicles for the crystal warriors for the game gear is just advanced wars.
Rym: Yeah fantasy.
Scott: Well, it's that you mean you mean it's Fire Emblem.
Rym: It's more like advanced wars.
Scott: Speaking of Fire Emblem because Fire Emblem DS is eventually coming for sure, but not soon.
Scott: I pre-ordered Rondo of Swords from Atlas which is gonna come out on the 15th.
Scott: I can't guarantee this is gonna be good.
Scott: But you know, it's a normal $30 price DS game and From what I've seen it has the potential to sort of sate your Fire Emblem desires until Fire Emblem DS comes out.
Rym: I'll hold out until Scott tries it.
Scott: Yeah, I pre-order Amazon.
Scott: So I mean it's like a week away.
Scott: So it was.
Rym: I got.
Rym: I got some time.
Rym: I gotta work all my rankings in advance Wars up to s.
Scott: Yeah, two weeks or now.
Scott: I'll tell you if it's a good buy or not.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Anyway, so crystal chronicles ring of fates for the DS.
Scott: I'm pretty sure first we're gonna bash this game directly and then we're gonna compare it to the original crystal Starts out right away.
Rym: I started and the music sounds really good And then I watched the opening kind of like sequence.
Rym: now I remember when we played crystal chronicles for the GameCube and the opening movie was I mean It wasn't beautiful in an animation sense because it was mostly game plans
Scott: mostly the music That was beautiful
Rym: the music and the atmosphere and everything that the potential that they put before me was Wonderful, and it gave us all that feeling of we're about to have a gaming experience
Scott: and we sure did
Rym: So
Scott: even though that game really, you know, well that game was.
Scott: Well the original crystal chronicles right as a game not not the greatest game.
Scott: It was pretty much a walk around hit things game.
Rym: But what it was was it was basically just a tech demo saying it was a proof of concept.
Rym: Look this kind of collaborative game this kind of cooperative Multiplayer game with this kind of hidden information mechanic is solid gold and we've proven that it can be done.
Scott: yeah, even it makes even a crap game.
Scott: great right.
Rym: and The not even gameplay.
Rym: the intro the you know FMV before you play the game game Was little shit kids in a crappy childish story and they took Everything that was good about the atmosphere of crystal chronicles and did a 180 like.
Rym: I cannot express to you How awful and stupid it is?
Rym: It's like yeah, you're a kid and you got a little sister I'm gonna go on an adventure and you're all snarky with each other.
Rym: But then you go and meet the ukes.
Rym: now the ukes were a really interesting race in the original game But the ukes in this game talking this rhyme II sing song II bullshit.
Rym: It's.
Rym: it's painful to listen to.
Rym: and I say listen because it's voice acted But some parts of voice acted.
Scott: some parts are even read.
Scott: the text on the screen is awful.
Rym: It's like if you.
Rym: it's like if we took Star Wars right and then we made a new Star Wars.
Rym: But instead of Yoda like if we all Yoda was he was concentrated into his poor grammar And that was everything that was left of Yoda.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like.
Scott: Yoda is awesome because he has the silly grammar right, but it's simultaneously like Endearing but also wizened right and I think that's what they might have been thinking of when they made the ukes like this like Oh, we can make the ukes talk funny and then they'll be kind of like Yoda.
Scott: But no The problem is the Oaks are just kind of come off as stupid as opposed to being sort of mysterious in it.
Scott: You know like at times like oh and at times ha ha ha it's always Grown.
Rym: we went from crystal chronicles on the GameCube, which if you haven't played the game This is not a spoiler.
Rym: But to me the defining moment of that game the moment where everyone in the room went.
Scott: Wow That Wow is the loaf of bannock.
Scott: Never underestimate the power of a loaf of bannock and that there's no loaf of bannock in this.
Rym: now There's just blah blah blah indubitably blah blah blah.
Rym: and do they say indubitably?
Scott: way too much way too much.
Scott: I wonder who the first person to say indubitably was because I feel like a lot of silly cartoon characters have said that word over.
Rym: Yes, but I Didn't think it could get worse than that.
Rym: And then I met the first little tea.
Scott: The lilt ease in the first crystal Chronicles are sort of like dwarves like, huh?
Scott: But they were you know, they were small and they didn't look quite like dwarves except for their smallness.
Scott: But they were hard core.
Scott: They were hardcore sort of.
Scott: you know dwarves like huh?
Scott: This this little T the main little T in the game is so like it's like a TV.
Scott: I don't know what it is But it's frightening.
Scott: and the main character like always goes in like rubs its head and then it goes like squee Or whatever it does.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: what bothers me, too?
Rym: There's a frightening amount of sexual tension between that little boy and that little T It's but the little T's like a hundred years old which just makes it even worse.
Scott: It's really bad.
Rym: It's really bad and don't get me started on the humans.
Rym: It's like the atmosphere of the game is Nothing.
Rym: It's not a Final fantasy like advanced tactics was a better Atmosphere than this.
Scott: Yeah, I think the thing is the original Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles to the Gamecube.
Scott: Your characters didn't have names.
Scott: They didn't have voice acted it have words.
Scott: It was a lot more like they were, you know, they weren't even like link, right?
Scott: They were not a part of the story.
Scott: They were just people going out to get crystal water to help their town get through the year.
Rym: There wasn't even an epic plot.
Rym: you were just.
Rym: this is your job.
Rym: if you fail You know everyone that you know and love your family who was writing letters to you will die.
Scott: and that and all the plot of The world.
Scott: it was sort of like the plot of the world and you were just happened to be in it and it was revealed To you by people you meet on the road or things you see on your journey to go and collect more water And you know stuff like that.
Scott: and there wasn't this epic plot surrounding your characters.
Scott: Characters were sort of like.
Scott: it was more of a role-playing game Where you actually like.
Scott: my character was named Scott and I felt like he was me sort of.
Scott: you know.
Rym: It's like it's one of those.
Scott: the characters are named not as much as like in a real role-playing game But more than in a final final final identify with them and the world.
Rym: the world was not plotty.
Rym: It was atmospheric and that counted for so much.
Rym: I mean in in this game in the original game when you know We'd move between places then we'd run until into someone on the road and we'd get a little snippet of their story.
Rym: And then someone else's story and everyone's story was a real story was interesting.
Rym: There were real heroes going around the world and we were just some kids Trying to do our job.
Scott: Yeah, that was that one little tea who was like wicked badass with the horns.
Scott: What was his name?
Rym: Oh the Black Knight.
Rym: What's his name?
Scott: No, not the Black Knight the other one.
Scott: His name was like Alto.
Scott: Oh, yeah But yeah, that was.
Scott: it was pretty awesome.
Rym: But so the atmosphere of this game is gone.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically Generic even worse than a Final Fantasy plot.
Rym: It is a generic fantasy plot like quest had a less flimsy plot.
Scott: It's basically like oh the king is good But he's been overcome by the bad guys and the bad guys are in the temple and they're all evil.
Rym: Oh and your family's involved.
Rym: You're a little kid and you're destined to blah blah blah and you got your little kid sister with you and yay And his monsters all around town.
Scott: You got to go clear them out.
Scott: Oh It's pretty bad.
Scott: so that aside let's talk about the actual gameplay.
Scott: now The gameplay is a little different.
Scott: It's pretty.
Scott: it's somewhat similar to the original crystal chronicles, right in that
Rym: it's Superficially kind of looks the same
Scott: and that you walk around and hit things and you have you know Magic spheres you use to cast your magic spells and you have you know, you sort of upgrade your items in a similar way.
Scott: The problem is they added in this platforming element.
Scott: now, I really don't have a problem.
Scott: I like a platforming.
Scott: platforming actually is good because it sort of you know Makes it better than just a walk around hit things game.
Scott: The problem is the platforming is finicky and shitty.
Scott: It's really hard to do especially if you're trying to control four characters at once.
Rym: It also had there been an atmosphere kind of would have ruined it, but luckily there was no atmosphere to ruin.
Scott: Yeah, well at least the gameplay didn't ruin the atmosphere.
Rym: the atmosphere ruined the atmosphere But had the game had good atmosphere, I think jumping up and down trying to get to treasure chests Nothing.
Rym: I care about.
Scott: by the way, here's an example of how the platforming is shitty, right?
Scott: So each character has different power.
Scott: that's needed to do Platforming, right?
Scott: So for example, there'll be a very small platform like enough for one or two characters to fit on comfortably, right and You can only control one character at a time and you switch between them and you can sort of push the L button to teleport All the other characters near you.
Scott: So one character the lilty has to make a pot and then the pot will sort of activate on this platform.
Scott: Then you need to get the cell key to stand on the pot.
Scott: Then the plot will hover.
Scott: then the cell key does like a double jump off the pot.
Scott: Then you need to teleport the uke up to the new platform You're on so that you can use the stylus to turn on a torch to activate a thing.
Rym: and now now now before we go Any further because this this is.
Rym: this is the reason why this game is shit Like this is the core of why this is a bad game.
Rym: Imagine if you would add puzzles like that in the original crystal chronicles where there's four players, right?
Rym: Awesome like if puzzles like that because the puzzles in the original crystal chronicles were as good as they could have been with the limitations of the technology if they had had puzzles like this were like I Have as the cell key have to fight my way to this side of the map and hold a position while you guys go and do this other puzzle.
Rym: then the door opens and then we We work together and everyone has their own information of their own role to play.
Rym: Kid can you play this crystal chronicles multiplayer?
Scott: you can kind of but it's a different game.
Scott: The multiplayer is a different game than the single player.
Rym: Wait, so the only you might tell that I'm asking question.
Rym: You can go.
Scott: you can go to the levels where they.
Scott: this platforming stuff is going on.
Scott: You know and you can do that that platforming stuff multiplayer it can happen.
Scott: But actually because of the way the levels are structured and stuff it's actually really hard to coordinate all the different people to do these platforming things together and be in the same place at the Same time and like one guy makes the pot and getting your friend to jump on the pot And I mean in on paper, that would be really great But in reality it just doesn't work out.
Rym: and part of that I think is because I said one the platforming part was really ill-conceived.
Rym: but to The the way it's like playing the original crystal chronicles that you want to play it with other people because it's the shared experience.
Rym: I mean everyone who played the game goes a loaf of bannock Oh the end and all.
Rym: but playing it by yourself isn't really that fun.
Rym: So you kind of are expected to have all your friends playing through the plot.
Rym: and because your characters are faceless and because the plot In the world, they're just atmospheric around you you kind of get drawn in.
Rym: but with this game if you play a multiplayer It's not like you're all just playing the plot together.
Rym: It's like hey, let's beat a dungeon together.
Rym: Yeah, it's very like it's.
Rym: I don't want to use the term episodic, but it's like an episodic show.
Rym: It's not like.
Scott: it's basically like World of Warcraft, but there's no you know Big world or anything speaking of World of Warcraft unlike the other crystal chronicles.
Rym: The game has leveling.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, the original crystal chronicles.
Scott: All it had was when you beat a level right and Of all the items you've picked up during the level everyone gets to pick one and whoever did the best in that level gets to pick first
Rym: right
Scott: and Some of them would just be like plus two strength, you know.
Scott: but some of them would be like new moogle pocket or whatever.
Rym: and the thing is that wasn't so much leveling as it was kind of a Customization because eventually you start getting duplicates.
Scott: Yeah, you're only allowed to have one of everything, right?
Scott: So eventually or you know moogle pockets You can get more than one of but eventually you're gonna get all the items and then that's it, right?
Scott: But you'd sort of choose which ones.
Scott: Okay, you let the you take the plus two magic.
Scott: Let the normal guy take the plus.
Rym: or maybe you know The uke wants the plus two magic But Rym doesn't want to give it up because he wants to cast spells and he did better in that level.
Rym: So he's just gonna take it and everyone goes.
Rym: Oh, man.
Scott: Yep But the way this new one works Right is you sort of just picking up stuff constantly like you like you kill a guy and his items all over the place.
Rym: So many treasure chests that I didn't give a shit anymore and I just stopped bother.
Scott: You just keep pushing buttons to pick shit up and pick shit up and also have to pick everything up Individually.
Rym: if
Scott: you want to get the good shit You've got to go and do even more tricky platforming to get to trickier and trickier treasure chest
Rym: plus unlike the previous Crystal Chronicles, you know, I'm not gonna compare to the previous Crystal Chronicles in this game like the level of crap Doesn't even matter customization of get all these items to build this item and build this item.
Rym: and it did.
Rym: and it's all this kind of Final fantasy tactics II stuff.
Rym: but unlike Final Fantasy Tactics It has none of the charm and none of the interest.
Scott: I think the real the original fancy fantasy Crystal Chronicles is so great because it was so different from most of the other Square Enix type of RPGs.
Scott: But this one sort of takes that and reels it back into the Square Enix Empire and thus sort of ruining it and making it It's.
Rym: it's like they.
Rym: they made a proof of concept.
Rym: They proved that a new kind of game could be made and that Nintendo had facilitated this.
Rym: you know because back then you had to connect the Game Boy advances to the GameCube to get that experience.
Rym: and now the Technology is a thousand times better.
Rym: We could connect DS's to a we we could connect DS's to each other.
Rym: There's so many screens and so much processing power and they decided well So we proved that we can make that awesome game.
Scott: Let's gonna make something worse.
Rym: Let's not make that game and forget about all the all the new game mechanic things We tried.
Rym: and let's make something like every other game in the world and then make it shitty.
Scott: on top of that Yeah, let's concentrate more on the customizing of how your character looks, you know by changing their items.
Rym: Oh, it is fine in a stateful like massively multiplayer game where you can at least show it to someone.
Scott: Well, you can.
Scott: the idea is you'll.
Scott: when you play against other people they'll see your character but that's not the same.
Rym: it's so meaningless, yeah, I mean how many people care about whether in advance wars your hawk is Purple with gold hair.
Rym: I don't know with white hair.
Scott: Maybe Japanese people?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: see maybe the game appeals more to a Japanese audience But I can tell you this it doesn't appeal to people who like a game.
Rym: It doesn't appeal to someone who likes a story the one at the.
Scott: one last thing I have to say about why this game is bad and it's another comparison with the original and the original.
Scott: right.
Scott: one person had the map One person had where the items were right one person they were the bad guys were and the other person had something else, right?
Scott: Each person on their Gameboy advanced screen had different information.
Scott: All right, and it wasn't perfect.
Scott: I mean the map was so much more useful than everything else,
Rym: but it was
Scott: fun, but it was fun Communicating between the players all this information that like only one person knew where to go But they had to tell everyone else where to go, you know, and there was the pot which you know The the the.
Rym: the buskit which was there was necessary and a lot of people were bleh about it But it made for a lot of really interesting fun game.
Scott: It was it was sort of a double-edged sword the buskit, you know.
Scott: on the one hand It's sort of forced everyone to stay in the same area Alright, but on the other hand it was sort of annoying and you know to carry it around all the time and hurt and you'd get Hurt and shit, right?
Scott: But you know, it sort of helped heat the game together in a way.
Scott: Let's
Rym: imagine with the new technology They could have had places where you can all go wherever you want But then sometimes you got to use the buskit anyway,
Scott: right in this game Basically, if you're all on a screen anyone can go anywhere on the screen that they want, right?
Scott: So that whole buskit stick together mechanic kind of falls apart because you'll just run around all over the place killing things on their own Whatever and then you only need to all group up again.
Scott: when you want to go to the next screen You'll have to go to the door at the same time.
Scott: and the second thing is that Everyone has all these same information.
Scott: Everyone has the map.
Scott: Everyone has the same thing so that Communication with the other players totally sort of falls apart.
Scott: You don't need to communicate You all just need to be like are we done with the screen?
Scott: All right, which screen do you want to go to?
Scott: All right that one or I never go to that one.
Rym: There's just so much wrong with this game that I I think it's not even worth playing.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sad I spent my money on it, but I'll Give it to someone else.
Scott: I guess I can't throw it out.
Scott: this Seems kind of like a waste.
Rym: the people want this game.
Scott: You can try it Well sell it to you for cheap.
Scott: I guess like shipping plus a few bucks.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's a $40 game.
Scott: I'd give it up for like maybe 10 that this is.
Scott: if nothing else Maybe I'll just auction it or eBay.
Rym: original Crystal Chronicles was Like an experience if you played it with a group of friends in One go or even just if you played it with a group of friends because it wasn't just on the same group of friends.
Scott: the Whole time makes a real big difference.
Scott: Actually.
Rym: Yes, it does.
Rym: But I don't know I was I. that experience was such an amazing thing that I was willing to sight unseen spend 40 bucks on a Game that had a good chance of not even being close to that because there was that tiny
Scott: Same name that was and that wasn't you know The other days on the cache of the previous game with the same name We bought the second game of the same name.
Scott: and now this game is terrible.
Rym: And now this is gonna be like a WiiWare one Which is also it might be the good part of Actraiser, but you have to pay to customize it.
Rym: So that's gonna.
Rym: that's gonna be bad now and they've already tell that Crystal Chronicles on the Wii The real one is primarily a single-player game much like this one.
Scott: Screw that too.
Scott: So they basically just they made a great game and then they made three follow-ups.
Scott: They're all gonna be shit.
Scott: and what one is shit, and I'm pretty sure the other two are gonna be shit.
Scott: and Final Fantasy I think is completely dead to me.
Rym: and all except for old Final Fantasy remade the last ones I enjoyed or one two three Six seven six.
Rym: I like seven six.
Rym: I like six a lot though and legend three.
Rym: on the Gameboy Legend two was better.
Scott: No, dad's legend - dad is a stealth fighter I win I don't know legend - had the scene.
Scott: dad is a stealth fighter.
Scott: regain your health by sitting on the toilet.
Scott: in the stealth fighter I win once again.
Rym: Legend - had the scene where you know like you have like everyone has their music.
Rym: like Final Fantasy games are big about the music even on the Gameboy and There was like the heroes theme that played when you the heroes are doing shit.
Rym: And there's one point near the end of the game where you come across a room and your eaves dropping and in the other room are like the three mini bosses of the game talking to each other and they've got these crystals that you need and Then your music starts playing which you think all right We're gonna bust in and fight him now but instead one of them looks up in that you know Final Fantasy look up way in those games where the sprite changes a little bit and goes Where's that music coming from?
Rym: Oh crap.
Scott: Let's get out of here, and I'm like oh Let me ask you does that have in that game?
Scott: is your dad a v2 bomber?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: in Final Fantasy?
Rym: Legend one You instead of a ship you got an entire island.
Scott: Yeah, but uh what was your dad a v2 bomber in for my dad?
Rym: I don't want to ruin Final Fantasy 4, but my dad was like a. No your dad's not the whale I know just and then I go to the moon in a whale still the.
Scott: I Really can't sort of beat the dad as a stealth bomber.
Rym: We're so done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays we have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: you can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website Which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.