Rym: It's Tuesday February 5th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight Advance wars days of ruin.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, it's a super Tuesday.
Scott: Yeah, yeah super because parades.
Rym: well because I've.
Rym: actually the parade was kind of not awesome for me because I get on the Train to go home right and it's full of drunken college kids in Giants jerseys.
Rym: The best part is While they were all rowdy and whatever for some reason they seemed really afraid to sit next to people.
Rym: So they were all sitting on the floor even though there were plenty of seats.
Rym: They just had to ask people to move over.
Rym: that that's so everyone is on the train had nothing to do with those people in particular yeah But I'd like I didn't see a single one of those people Sitting in a seat because they all got to the train at the last minute.
Rym: the trainers already full of businessman.
Scott: It's.
Scott: uh, they're not so good at training talking to anyone who's not also wearing a uniform.
Rym: But despite Scott's complete lack of interest in politics and thus no right to complain when things go to hell No, right to complain.
Scott: I vote that's it.
Scott: That's all I can do.
Scott: that matters.
Rym: It didn't vote the primary which matters more than the election this time.
Scott: I'm not gonna join a party.
Scott: that that's that's Doing something.
Scott: I'm having my say by saying I don't think that we should have a party system at all.
Scott: So I don't I don't participate and I'm independent.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: That's kind of saying I should go against my principles to gain power.
Scott: Yes Oh, no, very much.
Rym: So because the principle there is no big deal.
Rym: Look I joined the Democratic Party.
Rym: It's all about principle.
Scott: That's what democracy is about.
Scott: everyone follows their principle and thus with the most popular Principle is the one that wins out if everyone goes against their principle.
Scott: That's why we're entrenched in the stupid two-party system.
Scott: We're always voting for the worst of the world.
Rym: I don't think that's it.
Rym: I think that a lot of people who vote don't have any principles to begin with.
Scott: that is also the problem.
Rym: I think the primary problem is single-issue voters.
Scott: that too.
Scott: But anyway a lot of problems.
Rym: This is my Super Bowl today.
Rym: Scott had his Super Bowl on Sunday, but tonight is my.
Scott: I don't think I understand the Super Bowl.
Scott: the real one lasts for 365 days.
Scott: Aha, uh-huh.
Rym: You're not gonna be talking about the Super Bowl a month from now.
Scott: Giants will remain world champions until the next Super Bowl and maybe even then if they win again, it could be even longer.
Rym: but in much more important news, I uh, I We're gonna talk about this a lot more later in the episode there in the show.
Rym: But I beat advanced wars on the train this morning.
Rym: Finally.
Scott: Mm-hmm pretty much advanced or is ds2.
Scott: Yes One finally Wow, I beat that game long time ago.
Rym: I don't even know where my copy is.
Rym: once they got an S in every single mission in the hard campaign and the war room I just kind of stopped playing that one.
Scott: I got mine.
Scott: I got all my games.
Scott: I never.
Scott: I never lose a game except one.
Rym: I got him but they're in a box somewhere.
Rym: No, but uh I was kind of disappointed in.
Rym: I mean in one hand the game was great and it's much more of a war game But at the other hand I was sad.
Scott: why are you using up the main bit in the open event?
Scott: I got to do that.
Rym: I was saddened by the fact that with the exception of one mission The game was easy to the point of being laughable.
Scott: The game is pretty easy every mission.
Scott: so far I mean I didn't beat it yet just because you know lack of playing and I'm in mission 20-something and Every mission so far except for this one team mission Which I sort of gave up on.
Rym: but I'll go back the one that Alex and I both beat in one.
Scott: No, I beat that one the one with the bikes and whatever.
Rym: Well, yeah, that one's easy.
Scott: It's a different one.
Scott: I just haven't really tried it but any mission I've actually really tried to win I've beaten pretty handily.
Rym: the thing is that last mission is a fucker and it took me a bunch of tries.
Rym: but at the same time That last mission wasn't even like a fifth as difficult as the last mission in the hard campaign of the first two advanced wars.
Scott: No, the first two all because I think it's a different kind of game and I'm saving all my talking for the real main bit.
Rym: So we don't waste it all now, but suffice to say I beat the game.
Scott: Yeah, suffice to say everyone says if I say what I do Yeah, I'm doing that.
Rym: suffice to say I also have some news.
Rym: The news is not related to video games.
Rym: But so this kind of fell off my radar because I Pretty much gave up on Dungeons & Dragons right about when 3.5 edition came out.
Rym: Yeah, something like that, which was coincidentally around the time when I started really learning more and more about burning wheel.
Scott: Now that is a coincidence.
Rym: But really the thing was it's not like I found burning wheel and I suddenly hated D&D.
Rym: It was more than I kind of always hated D&D.
Scott: Yeah, I also kind of always.
Scott: but at the same time parts of D&D were great and parts were not so great.
Rym: I guess it was just that I was always vaguely dissatisfied with Dungeons & Dragons and most other role-playing systems I played and I never really was sure why I always think whatever.
Rym: I just gloss over it.
Scott: I think the most D&D players are always dissatisfied.
Scott: That's why they're always coming up with house rules and changing things and trying to buy more books to get different rules.
Scott: I think people are.
Scott: it's a game where people really want to play it for certain aspects But they're constantly dissatisfied with it And you know.
Scott: That's why they just keep trying to change it or fix it or do something different and but no one ever thinks play different game.
Scott: That's as you know, like burning wheel.
Rym: Well, I think part of it's the one D&D has such a mind-share.
Rym: I mean Dungeons & Dragons is the role-playing game.
Rym: I mean god today we've been playing burning wheel for a long tabletop role-playing game.
Rym: We've been playing burning wheel for a long time now relative to how long we played other games years, but at the same time When we invite everyone over or we talk about our most recent gaming session we still call it D&D.
Rym: Yeah, it's like yeah, we're playing D&D this weekend.
Rym: We haven't played D&D in a long time.
Scott: They have played D&D like three years.
Rym: That's just how much mine.
Scott: Oh, no way.
Scott: Yes, we have but we haven't.
Rym: Yeah, well, there was the online game, right?
Scott: Right, right.
Rym: Yeah that I was not really in.
Scott: no not so much.
Rym: That's how my game kind of sucked.
Rym: Yeah, okay Oh you admit because I remember I got a lot of flack when I complained about that game on a daily basis.
Scott: Okay, it wasn't like a terrible game.
Scott: I just a yeah.
Rym: Well, I think part of it was that most of the fun of D&D was taken away by playing it in a forum something like That.
Scott: I'm not big on the forum games.
Scott: I think the forum games are just sort of like.
Scott: they provide like one fraction of the experience of real tabletop role-playing but it's you know when a man in the desert will go to.
Rym: Yeah, actually, I think forum role-playing is really great.
Rym: The problem is you can't play forum role-playing with D&D rules.
Scott: I don't think any sort of rules will work so well.
Rym: Well, you what you use is you use some of those dice lists or really really simple conflict resolution rules And you pretty much just take turns kind of taking control of the narrative.
Scott: Yeah, but that's not really a tabletop role-playing game.
Scott: That's more of a a role-playing collaborative storytelling.
Scott: You could just set up a wiki and write a novel together.
Rym: There's a fine.
Rym: I mean, there's this long gradient between one end of the role-playing spectrum, which is just playing roles.
Rym: You just act it's collective storytelling and nothing more.
Rym: and on the other end is We're basically iterating through a video game that we have written the rules for and then are playing in the real world with miniatures.
Scott: Yep, I think the the the funness for geeks at least is getting both at the same time.
Scott: And I think you know in a forum It's at least without some sort of you know software built into the forum to aid with the game side of things.
Scott: You really can only do the story kind of things.
Rym: But the news here is that Dungeons & Dragons fourth edition isn't out yet But they've released for $20 each.
Rym: I hear $20.
Scott: It's the cost of the players handbook to Preview books, right?
Scott: So it's a Pre-play not yet complete players handbook as a beta players handbook if you will for the price of a player's handbook.
Rym: See, I'm not entirely sure what this is.
Rym: The review is basically fluff garbage on slash shot.
Rym: It doesn't really say anything useful.
Rym: The comments are a lot more informative.
Rym: I suggest you read those but Now that there's a lot more details about what exactly fourth edition entails.
Rym: I want to point out a couple of things.
Rym: One actually, you know what?
Rym: I don't need to say anything because I'm looking at a slash shot here and Mongoose disciple said better than I could ever say everything I have to say about D&D fourth edition quotes.
Rym: Am I the only one who feels that they may have simplified the most important and interesting parts clear out of the game Filled the gaps liberally with World of Warcraft and ended up with a game that admittedly has a much lower barrier to entry But is also not particularly interesting?
Rym: Yeah The rule.
Rym: it seems like just a lot of people now.
Rym: granted This is a very qualified statement But I know there are a lot of people who prefer like good old advanced Dungeons & Dragons second edition to third edition or modern D&D iterations and there's some truth to that and there's some kind of fudge into that.
Rym: but I think the main reason people feel that is That because the system was less evolved and kind of crappy and very vague People were kind of forced to play it by ear.
Rym: so as a result good dungeon masters who's run fantastic games It seems like to deal with the problems of Dungeons & Dragons as they have seen them in third edition and 3.5th edition.
Rym: They're just making more and more tight video gamey rules and they're working more and more to balance all the classes as opposed to adding interesting role-playing elements.
Scott: Because most people they wonder, you know people always like well, how do I roleplay?
Scott: but you know I just get the feeling that most people you know Unless you get someone else to bring you in and show you the way Even you know role-playing.
Scott: you don't know from that most and most people even if they do know from that they don't want that.
Rym: Well, I'm reading these comments.
Rym: a lot of people are arguing about Oh, well, the power curve is off or the balance is off.
Rym: for now This class is too powerful or that class is too powerful or exactly.
Scott: That's what most people are looking for Who are into D&D and that's they like, you know what it is.
Rym: I don't think that's it.
Rym: Exactly I think it's just a lot of people have never played any game.
Rym: But D&D and I think GURPS is even a much better system it.
Rym: Well, I guess I Number wise it's better.
Rym: I guess I should qualify that Dungeons & Dragons is not really a role-playing system.
Rym: I don't think it ever will be.
Rym: it's basically now a Miniature a stateful miniatures combat game that is interspersed periodically with flavor text.
Scott: Yeah, it sounds about right.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't know.
Rym: I remember when third edition came out I About I had a freaking nerdgasm and I bought stood in line to buy those books.
Scott: like the night that they came out I played second edition and let you know my youth, you know, but I never actually owned the book someone else.
Scott: I would use someone else's.
Scott: but this day.
Rym: I own more second edition D&D books than I own any other.
Scott: I know that that goes worked and when I got a college I was like, okay now's the time for some serious D&D.
Scott: I'm in college This is where it can happen.
Scott: And I went and people had these third edition books and I was like, whoa I didn't know.
Scott: and I expected to like be going to the game store to get second edition books.
Scott: So nope third edition it was.
Rym: so I went out and bought the books and I remembered Taking that book home the first day and be like attacks of opportunity.
Scott: Yeah, yeah It took me how many years they still had to learn all the goddamn stupid rules in that book.
Rym: You ever knew the rules to any D&D I did.
Scott: I just never you know Knew him as much as the game started required.
Scott: I knew the most basic of rules You you knew and they should have attacked me.
Rym: you knew damage.
Rym: I attacked the monster that has the most hit points.
Rym: That is the biggest threat to me personally.
Rym: Yes Exactly that and I roll a search.
Rym: Yes Exactly, but I don't know.
Rym: I'm so Unexcited about fourth edition like I cannot describe to you like how I read a lot about it in the last I don't know 20 minutes today and Nothing in any way interests me.
Rym: It feels like that guy said like World of Warcraft.
Scott: How could anything excite you if you have tasted the the caviar?
Scott: Why would the can of sardines excite you?
Rym: In fact, the more I think about it, they're basically turning D&D in a World of Warcraft.
Rym: Look, they've.
Rym: they're making the rules so codified and the thing they're focusing on the most seems to be character advancement and the power Curve and the risk/reward curve and the carrots to keep you playing.
Rym: It's basically World of Warcraft that you play with your friends and you have to do all the calculations by hand.
Scott: You know, they have a World of Warcraft tabletop.
Rym: I know No, I was trying not to remember.
Scott: They also have an EverQuest tabletop game.
Rym: I remember when I found out about that.
Rym: I remember I was in a bookstore and I saw it and I didn't believe it was there.
Rym: I went to Pete and said Pete look at that and what is it?
Rym: He said I don't know what you're talking about because I don't see anything.
Rym: that that's.
Scott: that's a role playing has become to Most people is you know, if it's you know, they call it they call like Final Fantasy a role-playing game.
Scott: No, it's not that you don't roll it.
Scott: You don't play any role in Final Fantasy.
Scott: The role is already played for you.
Scott: You're just watching a movie interspersed with this, you know numbers game of you know Character stats and but.
Rym: but you can make.
Rym: in some games you make really important character decisions.
Rym: For example up dust out Love me, but thou must Alright.
Rym: so I don't think I'm gonna talk about fourth edition again until it comes out fully.
Rym: then I'll probably Buy but I put by in quotes.
Rym: cuz I think what I'm gonna do is I mean, I bought the third edition books.
Rym: I even bought a new third edition book not that long ago.
Scott: Me too.
Rym: Sadly Why did we do that?
Scott: I had PDFs.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I will acquire fourth edition I will read it all yes, and then I will write my Unending diatribe and then that'll be the end of it.
Scott: Yeah, it would take.
Scott: it would take quite a surprise.
Scott: basically we'd have to open up the book and see a pirated copy of burning wheel.
Rym: in there It's the churning wheel the churning.
Rym: Okay Seriously, we talked about it a lot.
Rym: But if you like role-playing you like to play roles and you like fantasy or you like dune Or you know what.
Rym: even if you hate those things, I think burning wheel will make you like them.
Rym: There's no excuse on earth not to buy the core books to burning wheel.
Rym: If you have ever two books for the price of the beta D&D books you get a whole game Pretty much if you're a role player a video gamer or even if you're an actor or anything burning wood.
Rym: Actually, yeah If I if I was like a teacher in high school and I taught drama I'd make the kids play burning wheel like once a month in class.
Scott: I would just have the class B burning wheel.
Rym: That's not a bad idea actually.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay go get a job doing that.
Rym: All right Not much.
Rym: I want to have a job being a teacher.
Scott: Yeah, your time is done.
Scott: There we go.
Scott: Ready?
Rym: Okay, so what do you got?
Rym: We're gonna tell you I got.
Rym: I got fourth edition D&D that you know How.
Rym: you know how much of a disappointment that is.
Rym: remember when you heard George Lucas is making new Star Wars movies Whatever.
Scott: remember how you felt when you heard that Not as excited as most other people anyway One of rims favorite games ever find a commando.
Rym: I can beat that game in like 28 minutes, dude Did you okay?
Scott: so They're making a new bionic commando.
Scott: that's all 3d and whatnot.
Scott: All right, wait a minute.
Rym: bionic commando.
Rym: I believe you mean Hitler.
Rym: no Fukkatsu.
Scott: Yeah, hidden no Fukkatsu same game.
Scott: They're making a new one.
Scott: That's all 3d.
Scott: But that 3d one who knows if it'll be good.
Scott: It'll be bad who what system it'll be on.
Scott: I have no idea.
Rym: Well, I think the internet knows.
Scott: the internet probably knows I'm not looking it up.
Scott: Well, I mean, I think the internet knows based on what you're thinking that or your news is Okay, but anyway the in addition to this 3d game They're also making another bad a commando game called bad.
Scott: a commando Rearmed.
Scott: get it rearmed as in re weaponing but also because he has a robotic bionic arm.
Scott: He's rearming.
Rym: I've never played bionic commando for the NES.
Rym: get yourself a ROM because that.
Rym: That is one of those.
Scott: get yourself the GBA cartridge that also has contra on it.
Scott: Yes, and Strider has three games on one cartridge, but that game is like one of the.
Scott: it is contra right or is it super C?
Scott: That's on there.
Rym: It's not contra or super C.
Scott: What game is on there this writer bionic commando.
Scott: one of the game I don't know.
Rym: I only played bionic commando.
Rym: Oh, yeah, like mighty final fight mighty final fight.
Scott: That's the third one.
Scott: I don't confuse that with contra.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: No, I don't know.
Rym: up up down down man.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, so they're making this bionic commander rearmed and basically it's the original bionic commando with my.
Scott: it's still the same game.
Scott: It's 2d game even though they do sort of like the Smash Brothers thing where you know the 3d models, but it's 2d, right?
Scott: but modern graphics and Fixed gameplay cuz as great as bionic commando was.
Scott: the gameplay was not flawless.
Scott: There were many problems.
Rym: part of that were due to.
Rym: there was limitations of the NES part of it.
Rym: Was that?
Scott: Yeah, yeah, so they basically this this may the boss of the game is basically up fuck up fuck up game over.
Scott: Yeah Okay, you know and if you watch this video here that we could link to.
Scott: the guy is both the lead creative You know designer of the game and also the composer.
Scott: and he did you know?
Scott: He did nice quality remixes of all the music for the game and he's also He's pretty Ron target with what was wrong with the original game and how to make it better.
Scott: For example, the original bionic commando, you can choose different weapons, right?
Rym: I I point out that there is in fact only one weapon is the bazooka.
Scott: every other weapon every other weapons useless Right, so he's gonna and you can only choose the weapon at the beginning of the level.
Scott: You couldn't change it until you start a new level.
Scott: so He's gonna make it so you could change the weapons all the time and he's gonna make it so you could do more stuff with The arm.
Scott: and also all the boss fights in the game are pretty boring like basically crouch and shoot then go up and shoot You know.
Rym: or when you fight captain pip pip pip pip, you just stand behind him.
Rym: He can't get you.
Scott: You stand behind him and shoot with the bazooka you win, right?
Scott: Yeah, so he made all the bosses more interesting.
Scott: We're gonna use the arm to fight the bosses and made the environment a little more interactive.
Scott: But in general, you know If you watch videos the game seems to be pretty much intact.
Scott: and if I had an Xbox I'd be pretty excited to play this bionic commando rearmed business.
Rym: I'm more and more feeling an Xbox.
Scott: I mean, it's the only reason one of the I gotta be honest, right?
Scott: One of the reasons I don't have the Xbox is because I feel like without the HDTV It's useless because so many of the games if you try to play them on standard-definition TVs just don't work.
Scott: You can't read anything on the screen and it just it's the system even the crappy.
Scott: You know arcade games like the pac-man are designed for the HD or the widescreen and we don't have that and it wouldn't work.
Rym: Well, we will when we build the geek house.
Scott: Yes, when we move if I had it when I move I'll Eventually get the flat screen hang on the wall.
Rym: HDTV in an Xbox 360 probably well by then might be the 720 or whatever.
Scott: I'll get that sure as long as the backwards compatibility is there.
Scott: and mostly all I really need is the live business.
Scott: The live is where it's at.
Rym: God, I would pay to just have live on Windows.
Rym: I even use Windows.
Scott: I don't do that.
Scott: Why?
Scott: there's no technological reason other than they haven't done it yet that I shouldn't be able to do every Xbox live arcade thing On a PC.
Scott: I mean sure the gate.
Scott: the Xbox games, you know that that you know come out on like a disc.
Rym: You know that for what, you know I'm not excited about any of those games.
Scott: But why can't the games that you download like the Uno with the webcam?
Scott: I could do that with a PC and why not?
Scott: Why haven't they done that?
Scott: They could sell Vista low with that because Vista is cheaper.
Rym: the Xbox even though I just want to point out don't out there.
Rym: I know a lot of you play that Uno game.
Rym: Don't pretend that Uno involves skill of any kind.
Scott: No, it doesn't Okay.
Scott: So yeah, that's what I got here.
Scott: Check this video out and Get excited about bionic commandos, maybe not the 3d one but 2d remake.
Rym: good enough things of the day.
Rym: So check this this this I like watching people perform stunts and feats of strength But you know, sometimes you watch someone doing something dangerous and you can't go.
Rym: Wow, that's amazing because you you feel that sense of one.
Rym: if I were there I would probably pee myself and two.
Rym: I Like you probably feel like they're about to die at any second.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: This is one of those videos up.
Rym: Basically these dudes Climbed onto this crane.
Rym: that's like at the top of a skyscraper that's being built or something crazy like that All right, and they don't have any safety equipment.
Rym: They're just kind of hanging on to this thing Like they got themselves out there and they're looking around like the crane is like an elevator in it, right?
Scott: So they took the elevator up to the little control box
Rym: and then they walked out in like onto the crane like out
Scott: like the Part that goes, you know hanging over with the okay
Rym: Yep, and I
Scott: mean you could be on top of it crawling, you know,
Rym: yeah, but that's not the exciting part.
Rym: I mean that's scary enough.
Rym: I mean I do get a little bit of vertigo if I you know Look over a very sheer cliff or something.
Scott: I do too.
Scott: I get the vertigo even though I'm not afraid of the heights.
Rym: Yeah, well, it's just your body has that those two feelings.
Rym: one There's the normal feeling of you know, if I fall if I sneeze or something, I'll just die Yeah, and then secondary to that there's that somewhat smaller thought of what if I just jump off for some reason?
Scott: There's also that sort of inner ear imbalance thing where it's like try sitting on something.
Scott: That's like maybe six feet tall like the edge of a high deck and then you know Like lean back a little bit and your body goes.
Scott: Whoa You know, it's like no no, no, no, no, no.
Scott: and you know looking over something like that your body goes inside it goes Whoa, so these dudes Start doing pull-ups from this thing.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Yeah If I was you know strong enough to do pull-ups I would have a little bit of more confidence.
Rym: it's not.
Rym: I don't think it's a matter of that because Just watching this video made me very uncomfortable.
Rym: But at the same time it's fascinating and I recommend you watch it.
Scott: Yeah, maybe they had hidden safety cables.
Scott: Yeah, they photoshopped them out.
Rym: I didn't see anything regardless.
Rym: That's my thing.
Scott: Yeah, I'll believe it.
Scott: I'll believe it.
Scott: All right, so a Lot of you know, I'm sort of anti Collecting if you didn't hear that before in the show at any time, but what about my pile of a silver?
Scott: 1930s Liberty Heads, how about your pogs?
Rym: I don't have any pogs.
Rym: Actually, how about your magic card 19 that I have all my magic cards a 1932?
Rym: Silver Liberty Head is one hell of a slammer.
Scott: Let me tell you okay You know, so when it comes to buying things I generally consider What is this useful for right and if something is actually you know useful for looking at you know It's sort of like an important artifact or something.
Scott: It should be like a museum and not something you should collect in your house, you know, Oh Scott I see you look up to what's this, Indiana Jones?
Rym: I think wasn't that always his sh*t?
Rym: this belongs in a museum and the Nazis said no it belongs.
Rym: I don't know we're Nazis.
Scott: Okay, I know where that came from.
Rym: That was always his thing.
Rym: He's like this belongs in a museum.
Rym: Okay, anyway that was like the whole point of the Indiana Jones movies.
Scott: I thought the whole point was Indiana Jones doesn't actually do anything Seriously rid is Laura Stark?
Scott: if he wasn't there everything's would have gone and got good.
Rym: It's not like the Nazis wouldn't have melted.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean the Nazis got the arc.
Scott: He lost.
Scott: he never saved anyone.
Scott: He always he attempted daring rescues and failed at every possible turn and in the end the Nazis ruined themselves.
Scott: If Indiana Jones just stayed home in bed everything would have turned out great.
Rym: in the end It didn't matter but he wanted to put everything in a museum.
Scott: He did.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So Anyway, some guys selling something on eBay and looking at the pictures.
Scott: I believe that it is 100% authentic.
Scott: It is the SNES game, but perhaps the most popular SNES game.
Scott: chrono trigger Sealed from the factory still with the shrink wrap still in the original box the instruction manuals in there.
Scott: It's straight like from the shelf of a toy store, you know stored safely for many years.
Scott: Here it is, right?
Scott: Okay sells it on eBay and it fetches $1217.
Rym: that's Probably about right considering the level of fandom for that game.
Scott: I know but you really think about it.
Scott: Wow, this is just what kind of Person.
Scott: yeah, you either had to be stupidly rich and just want to piss away money, right?
Rym: the thing is To play devil's advocate.
Rym: if I were stupidly rich and I were really into something like let's say I don't know The go the original gold Zelda NES Unopened in the box also signed by I don't know everyone who worked at Nintendo back then That's not worth anything to me.
Rym: That's worth a couple hundred bucks.
Scott: What are you gonna do with it?
Rym: I'm gonna put it a display case.
Scott: All right, and then what?
Rym: and then people can look at it.
Rym: I'll have a little museum.
Rym: I'll put it in the library.
Scott: Why?
Rym: because I like to look at the.
Scott: but why is that worth?
Scott: $200 for $200.
Scott: think about what else you can get for $200.
Scott: if I'm that rings that would actually do Something.
Rym: if I if I'm that rich, it doesn't matter.
Scott: No, it does.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, that's just.
Scott: I really think you know What.
Scott: what's the first thing gonna do with this for $1,200?
Rym: You're gonna put it on display and go wow check this out.
Scott: You could buy like a fucking computer.
Scott: You could buy like a wicked TV.
Rym: get up to add.
Rym: That's not that much money.
Rym: You couldn't buy a great TV.
Scott: no, you could buy a lot of Opened chrono trigger cartridges and play them.
Scott: You'd actually play the game.
Rym: But what if you already have all those things and you have money and you're a fan of the game?
Scott: You're wasting your money in your moron.
Rym: People are allowed to collect things.
Scott: They're allowed to this.
Scott: make them not morons.
Rym: I don't find any problem with it.
Scott: I find a big problem with it.
Scott: People are stupid wasting their money on useless shit Uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah, you should only spend money on things to do something anything.
Scott: any other signature of money is stupid.
Rym: Didn't you have some posters on your wall in college?
Scott: They do something.
Rym: What do they do?
Scott: They cover up the ugly ass wall.
Rym: You mean the beige wall?
Scott: Yeah, and you know what those.
Rym: all they are is something to look at.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: They're they're.
Scott: they're free to Pretty free.
Scott: No, they're not $1,200.
Scott: They were $1,200 posters over there.
Rym: They weren't free.
Rym: You could about a stick of gum for that.
Rym: Oh So why did you buy something useful instead of some stupid poster?
Scott: poster is useful.
Rym: Okay cover up my prison break Or to cover up that hole in the wall in colony.
Rym: Yes until the hole became larger than the poster this this.
Scott: What use could this have besides playing it?
Scott: and if your use is playing it, why did you spend $1,200?
Rym: Well, I think the answer is that Indiana Jones needs to steal it and put it in a museum and obviously Obviously the person who bought it is in fact a Nazi.
Scott: This just shows you how crazy people are.
Rym: so Advance wars.
Scott: Well Advance Wars days of ruin specifically.
Rym: Yeah, we're not gonna talk about the whole Advance Wars Franchise even though I could I could talk forever about the Advance Wars franchise.
Scott: Well, you know, this also goes back to the Desert commander.
Scott: the Famicom Wars.
Scott: as a commander I think is actually a similar game But it's not actually Famicom war regardless.
Rym: The game is pretty much identical.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Rym: it's a pretty close game And there's also a similar game for the SNES plus.
Scott: we did a show in 0 6 0 7 2 5.
Scott: We talked about Advance Wars series.
Scott: We just you know, now there's a new Advance Wars.
Scott: It's one of our favorite series of games.
Scott: So just got talking about the new game and not the old game.
Rym: Yep now now just to.
Rym: we've talked about this before but briefly and if you're wondering where we're coming from We're.
Rym: we're kind of good at this game.
Rym: And by this game, I mean every Advance Wars game we've ever played So far.
Scott: they've been to GBA games in the DS game and this is the second DS game, right?
Scott: And the first three DS games are all sort of the first three games so far.
Scott: in the US We're all sort of similar, you know, they all.
Scott: it was happy times happy cool characters.
Rym: It was pretty much yay war war is great war is fun and war really was fun in the Advance Wars world.
Scott: everything was green and happy and colorful and All the you know, most of them.
Scott: the game also was different in that it was very puzzling as opposed to Tactics II.
Scott: I mean there was tactics action going on especially in multiplayer But most of the single-player was puzzling like, you know, how do I do this exact thing here that they needed me to do?
Scott: you know.
Scott: and then the right number of turns move the things to the exact right spaces or you know, like a Like a puzzle.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean pretty much.
Rym: The game was limited in in scope but it was fun and the characters were very memorable and they're all around solid games.
Scott: Oh, the other thing about those games is that the the characters, you know had all these crazy powers, right?
Scott: They kept in adding more and more to that as the you know.
Scott: The first game they had normal powers and this can give me a little more powers and the third game even more powers, right?
Scott: And they kept.
Scott: you know The game really came down to a lot of rock-paper-scissors because the character powers were very strong.
Scott: Like if you chose grit you had freaking long range that no one else had.
Scott: So you were the fucking.
Scott: that was a huge crazy advantage.
Scott: that really changed the game and there's a lot of rock-paper-scissors.
Scott: action and the powers meant a lot and You know, the powers actually often meant more than you know, how you played the game so much.
Scott: It's a lot like the dune board game where it's asymmetric Everyone has a different power and they lean on that power with all their might.
Rym: now There's actually a lot more to say about that but I guess we just talk about what exactly is different about Advance Wars days of ruin?
Rym: aside from the fact that In terms of story and plot and an atmosphere and mood and everything Advance Wars days of ruin is hardcore.
Scott: They took away all the greenness and the happiness and now it is the the gritty hardcore.
Scott: This is a serious post-apocalyptic war going on here.
Scott: It's fucked up shit.
Scott: There's scary shit going on.
Scott: is everyone serious.
Scott: No one's silly.
Rym: Well except for dr.
Rym: Hibbert.
Scott: Sometimes people are silly, but well just dr Hibbert, dr Hibbert, but also if you go and you in any mission you can say, you know Like give me the the strategy for this mission and sometimes there'll be silly stuff going on.
Rym: You know I never went in there for the whole game until I got to the last mission after I died three times.
Scott: I went in there a few times and I sort of wish I went in there every time not go back and play any mission.
Scott: I know not to get the strategy, but just to see the funny shit.
Scott: Yeah But yeah It's it's the theme.
Scott: Visually and stylistically the game is dead fucking serious as opposed to the previous Advance Wars which is the exact fucking opposite and it hits you right at the beginning.
Rym: I mean you turn on the game the first time and you basically watch this one.
Rym: the music's fantastic But the music really sets a mood.
Rym: music's good.
Rym: I actually well not that the music during the game is just you know Standard video game.
Scott: Yeah, I like the old Advance Wars in the game.
Scott: music much better.
Rym: Yeah, but the opening song that plays over the opening video that's pretty good.
Scott: it's fantastic that's pretty good song right there I mean it really.
Rym: it sounds good.
Rym: It's a good song and it really kind of it hits you right over the way.
Rym: It's pretty much Meteors destroyed the world.
Rym: Everybody's dead.
Rym: have fun.
Scott: and even though I don't I like the other advanced the older Advance Wars during the game music better.
Scott: the Sound quality of them.
Scott: all the music in this game is fantastic Like you did.
Scott: it's amazing that it's coming out of that DS.
Scott: You're like, whoa, that's coming out of DS shit.
Rym: I was playing it with my insertion headphones and damn.
Rym: Yeah, but in terms of game differences I think the biggest thing is that CEO powers don't work at all like they used to and this pretty much completely changed the game.
Rym: This is probably the single biggest change in the game.
Scott: Yet instead of the CEO just slow hat.
Scott: first of all in the old game CEOs had a power that was on all the time.
Scott: Then they had a little power and then they had a big big power.
Scott: and then they in the dia in this first DS One they even had a combo power.
Scott: use two CEOs at once.
Scott: Much.
Rym: you charge that up But nominally by doing damage to your opponent, but more importantly by taking damage from your opponent.
Scott: Yeah so you would try to.
Scott: whoever dealt and took the most damage would build up the power and you debt power.
Scott: if you used it Properly and strategically you just destroy the other person and then they would use it right back and whoa.
Rym: the problem there was basically that you had to really play this metagame of damaging the opponent but not in a realistic war way But in a kind of puzzle game way because if you damage him too much But not to great effect you just charged up their power and got rekt.
Rym: You couldn't.
Rym: just well his missiles are too close.
Rym: I'm gonna send a battle copper over there to take it out because instead it's I Do that then I'll charge up his power.
Rym: I gotta wait.
Scott: Now they still have the CEO power.
Scott: But the way it works is first of all, you have to get a vehicle to your headquarters Right and you tell a CEO to go in the vehicle what?
Rym: no you do it from any factory.
Scott: Oh any factory also, right.
Rym: and then and I don't think you can do it from that quarters Yeah, I've done it from the headquarter.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yes, and I honestly I never used my powers or my people.
Scott: Yeah, I really I don't use them that much either.
Scott: I used them a couple times.
Scott: you put them in and then the vehicle has a radius around it that you can kind of see and The radius.
Scott: any vehicle in that radius gets sort of like any vehicle.
Scott: any unit in that radius gets like a bonus to it.
Rym: You know depending on your power I mean All of your ground direct attack units get more attack or all of your air units get more mobile, you know stuff like that.
Scott: Yeah So you sort of keep the CEO on the field and anything near the CEO that is affected gets helped out and you can Sort of create this zone of power on the map and that could could be strategically helpful.
Scott: It's pretty strong, but it's not like I get two turns or I Do ten damaged all your guys or my battleships shoot everything.
Scott: Oh, yeah, my battleships get a range of the entire map and they rain holy death.
Rym: Yeah, well Calder's powers kind of unfair But that's obvious.
Scott: or I buy everything at half price this turning a double money and can build from any city I own.
Scott: Oh God, that's right.
Rym: Yeah, that's hachi for you.
Rym: Yeah, but Beyond that also you'd have a Like a power you can activate and the way you charge it up is by doing damage with vehicles with it Like within your CEO zone of power.
Rym: Yep, and if your CEOs unit dies You don't lose or anything but all the power you've built up gone and the CEO.
Scott: you got to put him in a new vehicle if you want to and you have to pay money.
Rym: so they've really toned that down and coupled with that they've added at units to the game and fundamentally changed the way a lot of units play and All the.
Rym: the effect of all this is that this is not a puzzle game nearly so much as any other advance.
Scott: There is some puzzle missions in there.
Scott: in the war room in the team missions There's a few puzzles to play but it is not a puzzle game anymore at all.
Scott: It is definitely now a war game.
Rym: It's not like a Advance Wars DS Destroy the battleships in nine days.
Scott: I hated that one the most.
Scott: that was the worst mission in any advances ever.
Rym: I beat it with an S in my second try.
Scott: I'm just saying it was a bad mission.
Scott: I didn't like.
Scott: it was not fun.
Scott: I enjoyed it.
Rym: I did not enjoy I guess partly because there was Missions like that forced you to become the master of the puzzles or decide that it wasn't worth it to become the master of the puzzles?
Scott: pretty much.
Rym: but The other things they've added and we'll go over them briefly.
Rym: one the Navy in.
Rym: in the early Advance Wars games Naval units were useless unless it was a single-player mission that made you use naval units.
Scott: Well, so the Landers could be useful depending on the map All right, and the battleships were useful with their range and holy raining death, right?
Scott: But they were very expensive and very hard to use.
Scott: right?
Scott: but the submarines and the destroyers and and those sorts of things Not really all that useful.
Rym: it was more that things ran out of gas and weren't that useful and were really expensive.
Rym: and Naval like naval on naval combat as a result was incredibly uninteresting and stupid.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you built destroyers and submarines and things.
Scott: it really didn't help you unless the other guy also built them and you Were just gonna fight them against each other.
Scott: He wasn't it didn't you know?
Rym: only Battleships could really help you to win the actual game and even then just they were so crippled and they couldn't easily Refuel.
Scott: or the only purpose of the submarines and destroyers was sort of like to fight against battleships and also Prevent people from fighting against your battleships and it really you're better off just buying more battleships than buying destroyers and submarines.
Rym: now advance wars DS went a long way to make that better.
Rym: They had the aircraft carriers Yes, and it even though that it wasn't the greatest unit now now that I see the light in the new game.
Rym: But also they added the black boat, which is probably the most important unit.
Rym: It was like this boat was okay.
Rym: It was this cheap little you know Naval unit that could hold a troop in it and could repair and reload and refuel other naval units.
Scott: It's like the APC of the sea.
Rym: It actually there's no APCs and APCs on the land black boats in the sea.
Rym: But it allowed you to have a Navy that could go out into the water and be a Navy and you could have naval battles But you can actually refill your battles.
Rym: just they ran out of bullets, but even then it was not great.
Rym: New game.
Rym: one battleships can move and shoot in the same turn turning them from a moderately useful unit to fucking death.
Scott: That is insane.
Scott: You realize no other Ranged attack unit in the game can move and shoot in the same turn except your mom except you're right.
Scott: so the fact that it also is.
Scott: the is the most damaging ranged unit the most long range range unit and Can move and shoot at the same time.
Scott: a battleship is holy shit.
Scott: That is fucking dangerous And if you have a bunch of them you can decimate your opponent.
Scott: thus the rest of the Navy that fights against battleships becomes very useful.
Scott: Everyone who has a Navy is gonna be building battleships really quickly.
Rym: Plus you can build temporary ports on beaches to refill stuff, which is just like awesome I love.
Scott: a big problem in the other game is you could only really have.
Scott: you know You can only refill on cities.
Scott: right all ground units could refuel and re-ammo in cities.
Scott: But if you wanted to refuel and you weren't, you know, if you were in the water, what could you do?
Rym: You had to get a black boat, right or you could go over to the land and go next to an APC.
Scott: But yeah You can have an APC drive up next to your boat Which means you have to bring your boat next to the land or bring your boat all the way back to your Navy Factory.
Scott: at the beginning, you know the other side of the map.
Scott: now you can build temporary naval bases And drive your boats into them and it is super helpful in many many maps.
Rym: and the gunboat.
Rym: just well the gunboat Combined with the way cruisers were the black boat is gone, but we have the gunboat instead.
Rym: Yep I love that little like one shot.
Rym: I'll just build a whole bunch of them and send them out swift boating people.
Scott: Yeah, the gunboat is high-quality.
Scott: it only gets one shot But it's a fucking powerful shot and you can use it in other boats.
Scott: So if someone else rolls their battleships up to you You can build this cheap-ass gunboat.
Scott: roll out there do one shot on it And now it's got a retreat or it's in big trouble and the aircraft carrier works a little differently.
Rym: instead of Basically being a super powerful missile unit that sits in the ocean and lets you hide bombers.
Rym: It lets you make Sea planes.
Rym: we'll get to all the different air units because they did the same thing to the Air Force that they did to the Navy in this game.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but basically Naval combat and naval options are viable interesting and important now and That alone would have been enough to make this the best frickin game ever at least in terms of this kind of game.
Scott: Yeah, but not only that but they change the ground and the air.
Scott: It's like about the ground of the air first.
Scott: Alright so the air right used to have the fighter which is the.
Scott: the fighter does nothing but give you air Superiority.
Scott: if you have fighters in the air then basically the other guy can't fuck with you with air units because your fighters are just so Dangerous, but that's all they still do and that's all they ever needed to do because they were always badass.
Scott: But now they have added in addition to the fighters, right?
Rym: Well and the bomber and the bombers, right?
Scott: Fighters and bombers and helicopters.
Scott: and that was it.
Rym: Yeah battle copters were a generally useful unit.
Scott: Yeah, battle copters are sort of like the anti ground cheap air unit, right?
Scott: It was an air unit So it was pretty hard for you to get it destroyed unless they had anti air and it could mess tanks up.
Scott: Bombers could really fuck things up But you had to sort of like refuel them and supply them and they were a little trickier than the copters but much more dangerous.
Scott: And that was it.
Scott: That was it for the air.
Scott: now Get the seaplane and the duster.
Scott: Oh the duster.
Rym: the duster is like the battle copter equivalents of a plane.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically you mean think about the game had two planes and one helicopter.
Scott: now There's four planes in one helicopter.
Scott: Well to help there was always the transport copter that lets you carry infantry around but that's that's no different than it ever was.
Scott: But yeah, the duster is really cool because it has sort of like the range of a fighter, right?
Scott: But a fighter which can only attack air units a duster can attack anything.
Scott: You can swoop down.
Scott: there was little machine guns and shoot ground units.
Scott: It can shoot boats.
Scott: I think it can shoot anything pretty much but it flies and that is super freakin useful.
Scott: Like if a guy, you know I always use it like to get those already damaged units like up that guy over there has three health duster got him Yep, or the tanks are coming and I don't have my anti tanks in place yet to hold the bridge.
Scott: duster's gonna go sit on The bridge, yeah, you can use the duster because it has such the range of a fighter.
Scott: You can use it to go harass their infantry trying to capture cities.
Scott: You can use it to clean up almost dead units.
Scott: You can use it to shoot at their helicopters before you build anti-air.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's not particularly powerful But it's incredibly versatile and the building a few early on will help you out a lot.
Rym: now the seaplane Badass lo-am.
Rym: I was just a super awesome kind of ground attack.
Rym: air attack like all-around great thing, but The trick is.
Rym: now the problem with all the other advanced wars.
Rym: They had the aircraft carrier.
Rym: Yay Using it for anything in any kind of versus situation was actually not that good of an idea Because in the time it took you to get the money to build one then
Scott: buy planes and put the planes on the air
Rym: Send it out and then bring the planes out.
Rym: that didn't work.
Rym: You were much better off just building neo tanks upon neo tanks.
Scott: Buy an aircraft carrier buy a plane put the plane on the aircraft carrier move the aircraft carrier Get the plane off the aircraft carrier.
Rym: now move the plane.
Scott: It was like so.
Rym: now Aircraft carriers are basically seaplane factories.
Rym: So you drive it I fly it out there drive it out there you sail it out there and then You can just build seaplanes on it.
Scott: and it makes planes in the boat.
Scott: They have a plane factory in the boat.
Rym: and even better when you launch a seaplane you don't just say alright I'm gonna put it next to my thing and next round and move it.
Rym: It comes out.
Rym: attacks immediately.
Scott: Yep So if they have you know any unit near your aircraft carrier, you can just send the plane out shoot Oh, that's so good.
Rym: Yep for land and sea.
Rym: I mean battleships coming.
Rym: Well aircraft carrier just start sending ships out to intercept that fucker as well.
Scott: If you have a lot of money aircraft carriers, I think are the best way.
Scott: if you have a lot of money on a naval map I think an aircraft carrier loaded with seaplanes or two is is the best way you could spend your money.
Scott: because just having that there With the range of the seaplanes because the boat can move and then launch a plane that is so Ridiculously far across the map that you can do heavy heavy damage.
Scott: and if you have multiple planes god damn god damn.
Rym: now ground units.
Rym: Basically, I want to talk about two things because these things bikes and anti-tanks.
Rym: Oh my god war tanks, whatever.
Scott: War tanks are sort of the same as the the mega tank but a little weaker and they got rid of the neo tank Which is upsetting but the neo tank was overpowered.
Rym: We'll talk about the anti-tank first because I think the bike is probably the most revolutionary unit.
Scott: It is the anti-tank though is incredibly revolutionary because first of all every long-range unit in the every artillery unit in the game You know something that shoots something that's not next to it, right?
Scott: You couldn't shoot something direct like an artillery.
Scott: the minute had a minimum range of two, right?
Scott: It did that you couldn't shoot something directly next to an artillery with that artillery.
Scott: It doesn't work.
Scott: the anti-tank can shoot something directly next to it.
Scott: Also every ranged attack unit in the game such as the battleship and such, right?
Scott: If something attacks it directly, let's say I roll my tank right up next to your rocket All right, which is a range unit and I shoot it.
Scott: Your rocket doesn't shoot back at my tank it it goes ah shit.
Scott: it goes ah shit You know, I mean if a guy's sending of the howitzer and you come up and with a tank He really can't shoot you at the howitzer.
Scott: You're right in front of him.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't work like that Right, and it makes sense.
Scott: the anti-tank.
Scott: Not only does it have a it is short range, but it's powerful against tanks At least.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: basically what it adds to the game is another tactical option.
Rym: if you couldn't it wasn't easy without doing puzzle game bullshit to Kind of move into an area secure it and then hold it while Reinforcements come or you like rebuild your supply line or anything.
Scott: Yeah, I mean when you in the older games you would build a bunch of tanks march in and take an area from the opponent but in doing so the guys that were left in that area were heavily weakened.
Scott: and Since you're moving towards the opponent generally, right?
Scott: That those weakened guys are much closer to your opponent than you are and it's gonna take you some time to get new units Out there to refresh and it becomes you pretty much always had to attack or treat attack retreat you know to keep your guys who's getting
Rym: hosed
Scott: and the only way to really move ahead and gain territory in the game was either if it was a map that was built with Factories right up on the line there
Rym: or you just had to play the puzzle game
Scott: or the puzzle game.
Rym: Now the anti-tank.
Rym: pretty much it's a Defensive area denial unit.
Rym: you put it in a city like you take you know attack with it.
Scott: It doesn't work.
Rym: like you take an area you put it in a city.
Rym: It will now allow you to hold not just like a perimeter defense, but defensive depth.
Rym: It'll let you hold that area and That alone adds.
Scott: It's not an unbreakable hold, but it is a strong hold.
Scott: Do you move your tanks in you blow some guys up?
Scott: You're rolling an anti-tank in there.
Scott: now Even if they come and get on you That anti-tank is pretty rough to destroy unless they have just the right units.
Rym: it adds so much to the game that yeah but Equally important if not more so is the bike.
Rym: It's just a normal inventory unit that moves real real far.
Rym: now you might think this is more powerful.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: does do anything special.
Rym: No, in fact it can't even go places normal infantry can go because it's got wheels can't go in a mountain Can't go in a any sort of troop trans and it's more expensive than regular infantry to cost as much as a mech yep.
Rym: So uh what it allows is what mechanized infantry allowed in the real world.
Rym: Basically in the old advanced wars games you could roll tanks over and fight with people and whatever.
Rym: But the game was pretty much a game of play.
Rym: the puzzle destroy the other person's units Eventually destroy all their stuff and get to their base or play the puzzle of you have like the one APC with one mech in it and you get over there, and you're tricky and you capture his HQ, but there was no sort of capture a territory fortify it and then continue.
Rym: yeah
Scott: because what happened was you were very limited by the speed of the infantry and the APCs and the transport copters were very powerful because you know there's a map right a big map where there's a lot of space And a lot of neutral cities right and you want to fight to capture those neutral cities because and neutral factories even more Because that's difference between winning and losing.
Scott: right there you had to build APCs and transport copters And your infantry can only move so far.
Scott: So it was a game of I have to move these guys really far and you had these tanks Rolling up and doing damage, and you had to get these infantry to catch up with them.
Rym: And now that's actually why I pretty much always won when we played like big old multiplayer advanced wars is in the old games is Because the game the fun way to play the game and the tech like the interesting way to play the game Is not the way to win because in the old games the way to win I pretty much built twice as many inventories as anyone else who played.
Rym: yeah And I would advance slowly and you'd have this supply line of infantry Marching forward in every direction.
Scott: I'm advancing all the time because you can't capture anything without infantry even if you have a million tanks.
Rym: you can't capture anything without Infantry and in order to do that you have to play the puzzle game of counting spaces counting APCs Doing the APC moving trick.
Scott: how can I how can I get the infantry to move the farthest and the least number of turns and capture the most cities and Least number of turns and how can I make sure that they're over there when my tanks get there?
Rym: It was much like my strategy in a team fortress classic or mega team fortress or weapons factory.
Rym: do the thing.
Rym: That's not fun But we'll almost always win you the game because no one else is going to be boring enough or insane enough to do it.
Rym: But now you have these bikes that can move really far Significantly far and you can just have inventory intersperse with your tanks and you can attack and then hold an area.
Scott: Yes You can have tanks roll out.
Scott: go boom boom boom boom boom.
Scott: the bikes move right in immediately as soon as you blow the other guy up and take a cities and then your Antitanks roll on top of those cities and you got them now.
Rym: the net result of all these changes is basically that advance wars 2 on the DS days of ruin days of ruin my name varies by nation is pretty much the best Tactical strategy war game I've played on a video game system.
Rym: turn bet is turn based.
Rym: Yeah in a long time indeed this game is So fantastic and I cannot stress enough how different it is From the other advanced wars.
Rym: because the other advanced wars you'd think like oh well you want to be cool like.
Rym: well I'm gonna send up a small hit squad through the fog of war to the south to capture those cities and then harass from the Hills.
Rym: well I said my main force around through the north and attack from behind.
Scott: that's something else and you know that never worked.
Scott: in the real And the old advanced wars there are a lot of fog of war puzzles right where it would be.
Scott: Okay, you can't if you're in the tree.
Scott: No one can see you unless they stand next to the tree, right?
Scott: So you would have to like send guys out recon guys to stand next to trees Then shoot the guys in those trees then move into the tree yourself.
Scott: And it was.
Scott: it was a trick of seeing and not being seen.
Scott: now They got the flare unit the flare unit.
Scott: You just build it It shoots a flare and you can see and all man It totally changes up the fog of war.
Scott: dynamic fog of war is no longer a puzzle Fog of war is now actually a fight, but you just need to use these flare units to sort of back it up.
Rym: So that's it.
Rym: the game is now an actual tactical strategic game.
Rym: you can make strategies you can you can implement them.
Rym: you can Send battle copters on a kamikaze mission to take out those anti-airs in advance of the main bomber squadron getting there.
Rym: Doing something like that in the original advanced wars games was needlessly complicated Usually useless and not the optimal way to get win.
Rym: but in this game That's everything.
Rym: Yeah supply lines matter.
Scott: the game That different on the surface, you know to the average player but in reality the game is super different.
Rym: Also, I would like to point out that the AI is Not stupid now.
Scott: Yeah, the AI used to.
Scott: not it wasn't gene It wasn't smart before but it was sort of programmed to do Annoying things on different maps because they were puzzle based maps.
Scott: So it was like aha the AI is gonna do this and you know.
Rym: But also like an advanced wars one you could on the D of the DBA you could trick the AI Attack an APC.
Scott: Yeah, you said an APC out.
Scott: They would attack the APC with their most powerful units.
Scott: then you counter-attack their most powerful units with your untouched most powerful.
Rym: now the AI is still stupid basically, but It's so much smarter than it used to be.
Rym: You can't really trick it unless you're really pay attention.
Rym: Like I figured out a couple of things you can use to kind of trick the AI.
Rym: Well, I'll give you all a hint.
Rym: the AI is Extremely risk-averse with expensive units, but it is extremely kamikaze with cheap units.
Rym: Case in point it'll send a battle copter right next to your anti-aircraft to do six damage to your rockets But they will never ever ever risk the bomber.
Scott: No, like for example, they had a fighter once right I had two fighters that I had pretty much most of the map covered.
Scott: Right, they would not move there.
Scott: their fighter would keep running into the corner of the map to hide to where I could not get it so that it would not be destroyed.
Scott: but As soon as there was a situation in which they can make an attack that would do a significant amount of damage.
Scott: They rolled in like three power like three war tanks like doom doom doom Because they did so much damage with that.
Scott: of course I counter-attacked and that was it.
Scott: but they wouldn't.
Scott: they wouldn't go into my zone of Dangerousness until they had a significant advantage.
Scott: They wouldn't roll in to do a piddly, you know, ting ting twink.
Rym: They only roll in to do the heavy hit and the AI also in general will pull a lot of Tricky shit.
Rym: if you're not looking for it pretty much Anytime you think you've got an opening.
Rym: if you're you know, if you're not good at these games You're new to them or you're not doing so.
Rym: well Every time you think oh man, this rocket is totally exposed.
Rym: odds are it's not.
Rym: look There's probably another rocket covering it or a medium tank That's just within range of whatever you use to attack it.
Rym: The AI covers its bases pretty damn well, and in the last mission Pretty much the AI will say alright What's the most dangerous unit that's closest to the thing you have to blow up to win the game.
Rym: Oh, I'm gonna send all my fighters over there to kill it.
Scott: No matter what great great How many fighters they have?
Scott: a hundred?
Rym: Let me put it this way in the last mission.
Rym: I like 40 cities and I fought to the last man and I didn't win.
Rym: Wow multiple times.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: I got to get to this mission.
Rym: pretty the worst thing is one time Not to spoil.
Rym: but when you see the mission, you'll know I'm gonna say this the center laser Had two hit points left and it was the only laser left.
Rym: I Could not Get so much as an infantry or anything even within striking distance.
Rym: Yeah, and I died to the last bitter man.
Scott: I built my last ever played at the last bitter man.
Rym: I built my last war tank and it was immediately surrounded by two war tanks and two bombers and I lost.
Rym: Wow Yeah But uh multiplayer is awesome.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about the Wi-Fi because it's Nintendo.
Rym: their Wi-Fi is dick.
Scott: The Wi-Fi is useless shit.
Scott: I basically pretend it doesn't even exist cuz not worth using.
Rym: I'll say this I went and played on the Wi-Fi.
Rym: It works pretty well.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I don't think there'll be many people playing it other than Friends and I could see myself using it to play with like Pete and Alex.
Scott: Yeah, if I was if I was you know, looking for I was pretty bored looking for some action.
Scott: I would you know get it get a friend on I am or something and you know.
Scott: trade the friend code and play online with Them.
Scott: Yeah, it works really well.
Scott: wouldn't do that too often I'd have to be pretty bored to do.
Rym: but I played with some strangers right and I learned one thing they all suck.
Rym: We're playing against people on the Wi-Fi in advance Wars, especially if you're one of those nut jobs.
Rym: You're like it's just plays these games obsessively.
Rym: Yeah, you kind of wreck people to the point that like you can almost feel the frustration as Every unit they move runs into an ambush and then blows up Every round and every time they send someone out to go try to take a factory.
Rym: I've already got the factory.
Rym: But yeah, this game is one of those must-have games for the DS.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't have a DS I know what's wrong with you.
Scott: they got new blue and black DS is coming out.
Scott: finally a Halfway decent color.
Scott: I ordered one.
Scott: It'll be here soon.
Scott: Then I'll have a fat DS to give to somebody.
Rym: Yeah, well, we're Emily's already got a DS.
Rym: So who needs a DS that we know my family.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.