Rym: It's Thursday July 10th.
Rym: I'm Rym Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about a lot of nothing and then we talk about standing in line.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know there's really one bad thing about spending the weekend at the beach.
Rym: is that I?
Rym: Once I spend a few days not at the beach I once again get to that point in my life where I decide wait a minute Why don't I just go live at the beach?
Rym: I could afford it get some crap job and just be a beach bomb the rest of my life.
Scott: Beach bum is on the list.
Scott: It's actually relatively high on the list of you know careers.
Scott: I mean Beach bum is a non paying job.
Scott: It pays nothing yet It is above.
Scott: and in my list of jobs you know sort of like.
Scott: you know like safety jobs like if I fail at this Job, I'll go down to this job.
Scott: I fail at that.
Scott: I go down.
Rym: It's like for us.
Rym: It's it.
Scott: entertainment underwater welding Underwater welding I was about to mention and then Beach bum.
Scott: and you know Beach bum comes above many paying position.
Rym: He's thinking about that life.
Rym: I live that life for a short time when I would meet after RIT and all that co-op and business.
Rym: Me and Scott went to with Scott Johnson down to his beach house, then I lived there for a while.
Rym: You know what I could deal with that life.
Scott: I could well deal deal with that life when you don't have the House.
Rym: the thing is you just live in a shithole near the beach And you sleep in a lot of places.
Rym: those people to sleep on the beach.
Scott: the thing is they have a beach patrol.
Rym: Yeah, well I wouldn't live in if I was a beach bum.
Rym: I wouldn't go to Wildwood if I were to be.
Scott: should you go to?
Rym: you got to California one of those crap where they have Beach Patrol a lot of places you can be on the beach at night.
Scott: Yeah, you know where.
Scott: Cuba Cuba You can live on the beach and not just Cuba besides.
Rym: There's different levels of Beach bum.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: are we talking about?
Rym: I have no money and no job and in basically a hobo Beach hobo Only.
Scott: the difference is hobos like do things like.
Scott: they're hobos that like run pirate radio stations and hobos also Travel bums tend to not travel.
Scott: they work less and they drink more.
Scott: Hobos travel more.
Scott: they work more, but they don't really make money, but they sort of do things and Hobos are saying you could look at a hobo some hobos.
Rym: I read an article a couple years ago about this Emerging class of hobo by choice 20-somethings who just quit college and just kind of bum around.
Scott: Yeah, it's like this homeless people that go to libraries and write blogs.
Scott: You know they spend a lot of time in libraries or beaches or other public places And you know it's all kinds of homeless action.
Rym: No there's different levels of Beach bum.
Rym: I mean the level I'd look at the level that's high on the list.
Rym: Beach hobo is very low on my list.
Rym: I would be Campus hobo before.
Rym: I'd be Beach hobo.
Scott: I'd be Beach hobo before college.
Rym: can't think about it.
Rym: Go to RIT right college campus hobo of course.
Rym: They probably cleaned it up now back in the day There were showers bathrooms and all sorts of stuff in those tunnels that no one else no one ever went down there.
Rym: You could pretty much live down there if you wanted to.
Scott: so you know actually I was in Florida.
Scott: right?
Scott: the hospitals They're like you would want.
Scott: they had this on the front desk of the hospital.
Scott: when you walk in There's like this ball of stickers.
Scott: They're the guest stickers.
Scott: cuz like you go in you they give you a sticker says guest in your name or whatever and then when you leave they take the sticker, and they make a ball out of it as a big ball.
Scott: and I walk in like grandma, and she just keeps walking right past the desk doesn't stop.
Scott: We didn't get any stickers and no one cared.
Scott: no one looked at us.
Scott: We walked right into whatever room We wanted to.
Scott: no one said anything no one cared.
Scott: You could just totally go in the hospital free like just walk right in from the street and do whatever you wanted.
Scott: No one would stop you or talk to you or anything.
Scott: You could totally just walk in and find an empty bed and now probably order food.
Rym: that wouldn't work.
Rym: You could probably get food But yeah.
Rym: And you could probably find somewhere dank to sleep because most hospitals have a whole bunch of like side Infrastructure tunnels and things.
Scott: you go to an empty an empty room, and there's no one in there.
Rym: Realize that in pretty much every metropolitan area finding an empty bed in a hospital is pretty much impossible.
Scott: Okay, but you know in the hospital.
Scott: I was in in Florida like half the beds are empty.
Rym: What kind of hospital was it?
Scott: It was a normal hospital.
Scott: Just completely normal.
Rym: What do you mean completely normal?
Scott: I had an emergency room section, and I had a you know staying overnight.
Rym: I realize asking you what kind of hospital is okay.
Rym: It's like a hospital.
Rym: It's like asking a non-computer guy Yeah, do you have a risk kernel or a cis kernel?
Scott: There was no specialist.
Rym: It was better off going to a college campus because I would have a hard time Differentiating a lot of hobos from a lot of the people I knew at RIT.
Rym: I guess that's true especially considering that half the people we hung out with at RIT We're not students.
Rym: We're well over 25 and just happen to live in the area again.
Scott: if you get one of those hospital gowns You're you're.
Scott: if you can just get the gown on then they'll be like where did this patient come from?
Scott: and they won't be able Identify you and they'll freak out and something will happen.
Rym: I know what'll happen.
Scott: it involves police, but hey hey I wonder what the sentence is for faking hospital stay.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think if you're faking the hospital stay you've got more things to worry about.
Scott: wait well They send you perhaps to the psych ward of the hospital Which is where you're trying to get in the psych ward of the hospital.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: I've been.
Scott: no I just come in.
Scott: they'd be like are you insane?
Scott: I'd be like yes.
Scott: I want to bed And I'll be crazy.
Scott: I'll pretend I'm crazy and I'll just get to stay in the bed.
Rym: I've been in those psych wards.
Rym: you do not want to be in those place.
Scott: Yeah, everyone else is crazy, but I'm in my own room.
Rym: No you're not.
Rym: you don't get a private room.
Rym: Why not you share with other crazy people?
Scott: That's not fair.
Scott: What then?
Scott: how do they expect crazy people to get uncrazy?
Scott: they put him with crazy don't?
Scott: Why they got to separate the crazies or else they're gonna be more crazy.
Rym: It's a complicated issue, but all I will say is the four Crazy more crazy.
Rym: No, it's like when you multiply two even numbers and two odd.
Scott: Yes, you got to put each crazy person on the road or else.
Scott: They will not be un-crazy.
Rym: But the one time that way I can pretend to be crazy and get a bed I got you know I had I had the gigantic I am NOT crazy armband that is not removable from me so that I could get out of this place.
Rym: I get in there and I find the network closet And you know I don't really see anyone around.
Rym: so I open the network closet.
Scott: I go in and I'm this crazy guy in there.
Rym: God you know I found some scary shit in network closets sometimes.
Scott: I'm glad I'm sorry cough a guy Baz.
Rym: really I did open one once and find some guy asleep in it.
Scott: was he a technician?
Rym: No, I don't know who he was.
Rym: all I remember is I quietly went in did my business and just shut the door behind me.
Scott: He didn't say anything now.
Scott: You should have poked him with a stick I didn't want to deal with.
Scott: that should have thrown the bas really bad.
Rym: I really didn't care.
Rym: But no, so I'm working on this switch And I feel a little airy sure wasn't a mummy?
Rym: I turn around and there is a semicircle of like 11 of these people Just staring at me outside the door.
Rym: I'm completely trapped and surrounded.
Scott: Why did they let the crazed people walk around?
Rym: they just wander the halls?
Rym: Why it depends on what kind of psych ward it is yeah?
Rym: So they're all kind of standing around.
Scott: I know you were there.
Scott: They should have put them in their not hallway.
Rym: They didn't don't care?
Rym: the people who run the psych ward like hey have fun, and then they locked me in great I had to go to the airlock to get back up, but anyway When I when I say beach bum I mean
Scott: go live
Rym: cheaply right near a pretty much a year-round beach.
Scott: the problem is beach.
Scott: Closed property is stupidly expensive.
Rym: not always What you can live near beaches in really dumpy crappy places.
Rym: often you'll be living semi illegally Semi illegally is okay.
Rym: Yeah Like you live you work it like say a bar near the beach And then you agree to pay some pittance to be able to sleep in the bar when it's closed at night.
Scott: Or you can just you know sleep in The hospital or you could.
Scott: what's that guy who would get drunk ever and arrested every night?
Scott: Oh?
Rym: What's his name?
Rym: the hero of FARC?
Scott: Yes?
Rym: I forgot his name.
Scott: Ah Just get every night Just get stupidly drunk and from the money you begged or danced or sang for and then get arrested I would leave another Sleep in the local jail, and then they let you in the morning.
Rym: That's a level below the kind of beach bum I want to be.
Rym: that I'm.
Rym: what I would do is live cheaply like in a bar.
Scott: What's cheaper than Free bed at the local jail.
Rym: I would rather have my freedom and just sleep in the bar You only lose your freedom at night.
Rym: No, that's not how that works.
Scott: you go into the police station.
Scott: It's not like the big jail.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's you know It's like all right.
Scott: We like you up.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's crazy.
Rym: It wouldn't work.
Scott: The old TV show what's it called with Barney Fife?
Rym: Oh the Andy Griffith show.
Scott: yeah, just like that.
Scott: That's what it'd be like.
Scott: they'd like you up, and there's the drug It would get.
Scott: he got locked up.
Scott: It would be exactly like that all right fine.
Rym: Here's the deal.
Rym: Next week we'll both go out to Southern, California.
Rym: Somewhere you get arrested every night.
Rym: I will find a job at a bar and see if I can crash there after they close.
Scott: well You'll get the job at the bars that you can provide me with the alcohol to get arrested.
Rym: I will provide you with as much alcohol as you want yeah, and I'll just give it to like some kid.
Scott: I'll get her go to jail for one night, and then I'll be let out.
Rym: We'll see how that works.
Scott: I'm not gonna drink it.
Scott: You know, but you could drink it.
Scott: Oh Actually that would actually if you got the job at the bar and just drank the alcohol that would get you in jail for the Night, no it wouldn't why not They're not?
Rym: they really won't jail you unless you're driving drunk.
Scott: Oh, I just want to be.
Scott: not just being really drunk in public doesn't do it.
Rym: I depends on the place.
Scott: vomiting in the I go to the playground.
Scott: That's a good place.
Rym: I Try not gonna work besides.
Rym: I would rather just have a job.
Rym: That's the whole point.
Scott: then.
Scott: you're not a bum.
Rym: yes, I'm a beach bum.
Rym: beach bum is a very specific thing.
Scott: That is nothing to do with bombs.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's very a lot to do with bum.
Rym: No, because there are beach bums, which are actually above Beach Hobo.
Rym: I'm talking about dude.
Scott: That's just a surfer, dude.
Rym: No you can be a dude beach bum - the only difference is you don't have a future.
Scott: You need a surfboard.
Rym: They're cheap.
Scott: No really.
Rym: I'll learn to have their cheese.
Scott: There's new.
Scott: the new.
Scott: there were good ones.
Scott: Have a good one.
Rym: Okay, I wouldn't surf in once I fell over.
Scott: it was the end of that because you see that crappy surfboard.
Rym: No, I didn't know how to surf, and I didn't get a lesson.
Rym: I rented a surfboard in Florida my all.
Rym: I well rented surfboards And I went out and I didn't know what I was doing and I stood up on it twice.
Scott: I'll just get the you know the ski do and cut your surfboard in half and go.
Rym: Beach bums can't afford see dudes.
Scott: I didn't say I'd be a beach bum.
Rym: I just I feel like I want to be a beach bum because I'll see you go Wake up right every other day.
Rym: Go to the beach fall asleep wake up again Go swimming come back to the beach.
Scott: You know what I see in the future life of the beach bum.
Scott: Skin cancer.
Rym: you know what I see Sunscreens not that expensive.
Scott: also winter.
Rym: Let's go to Southern California where it's always 76 degrees.
Scott: Anyway, I think we've run the course of this discussion.
Rym: this discussion didn't really go anyway.
Rym: I can't say one thing though.
Rym: at the beach I for various reasons bought the SPF 15 instead of the SPF 30. why?
Rym: Because I kind of wanted to tan as opposed to just not burning.
Scott: Yeah, I don't really care about tan I care about not skin cancer.
Rym: You know what it worked real well and actually using that sunscreen as opposed to all the other ones I've used.
Rym: this is the first time I've ever gone to Wildwood and come back without a sunburn.
Rym: Uh-huh first time ever.
Scott: Yeah, usually only get sunburn You know from not applying often enough or not applying to every spot or that sort of or they always the last day.
Rym: Let's go to the beach real quick before we get on the road.
Rym: Yeah, we don't need sunscreen.
Rym: I'm not gonna burn.
Rym: ah shit We're all burn now.
Scott: It really has nothing to do with the SPF's.
Rym: Well the one thing I noticed though is I put it on a lot more because it was the SPF 15.
Rym: So I kept putting it on That.
Scott: that's definitely what it is.
Rym: then you got at the same time.
Scott: I tended to put it on once a day and then late in the day would be worn off because it only lasts a few Hours.
Rym: it always avoid put lazy to keep putting it back on because I actually wanted to tan a little bit.
Rym: So I'd be really hard to not just burn but now with the 15 or the 4 or the whatever I'll.
Rym: I'll just kind of slowly tan the whole weekend.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, I definitely I got a shop around because there was that study that said you know don't stop using sunscreen But you know different.
Scott: well, you know, they're not as effective as you thought they were.
Scott: and then they're like there's this chemical That's in the sunscreen.
Scott: It's not sold in the United States.
Scott: That supposedly is amazing.
Scott: Well, we haven't verified that.
Scott: I haven't verified that I'm saying supposedly supposedly Because I read something like last year that said some chemical is used in all the sunscreens and all the world Except in the United States because it's not FDA approved.
Scott: Yeah, and it's super amazing and awesome And we just don't use it here because we're stupid or something like.
Rym: there's also the the scam of SPF 90.
Scott: Yeah, it's just stupid also, so I'm gonna do a lot of research and figure out the best Suntan lotion sunscreen, whatever.
Scott: Well sunscreen and suntan lotion and sunblock are three different things I know but I'm gonna buy pretty much the best one of those that my research Tells me to and then I'll buy a big one and then use that.
Rym: You know, it's such a shame because on one hand one quarter of my family has a history of skin cancer But on the other hand, I really like laying in the Sun Like it might.
Rym: maybe you know, there might be some sort of genetic correlation because Maybe my desire to lay in the Sun is what caused relatives of the past my ancestors to all die of skin cancer.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'm also next time I go to a doctor I'm gonna have them check out all of my mole freckle things.
Scott: just you know, why not?
Rym: Yeah, you're more moly than me.
Scott: Yeah, I got like.
Scott: I got one on my neck I got one on the back and I got the one on my upper left chest.
Scott: that's been there for like a thousand years.
Rym: See one thing I've always been happy about I've got very few moles and the ones I do are very very small and but Not like.
Rym: the biggest one I've got is like half the size of an eraser.
Scott: Yeah, that's you know, I got eraser.
Scott: Yeah, the one on my neck is about that big.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, well that was talking about nothing.
Rym: That's what you get for Thursdays Especially when we're tired and Scott's whining because I turned off my air conditioner.
Scott: It's a little hot in here.
Scott: Do you want to talk about the all the conventions and stuff for you still do that?
Rym: I guess we could.
Rym: you know it's Thursday, so it's kind of the night which is kind of weird because a Lot of people listen to like Tuesday and Wednesday like together.
Rym: a lot of people listen to the whole show But a lot of people listen to just Thursday.
Rym: So you guys miss out on a lot of the kind of other things we talked about.
Rym: So news wise I just kind of want to point out that for the month of August We're going to be doing live shows all over the place.
Rym: So if you wanted to meet us August and then one weekend in September are pretty much your best bets Yeah, so in the month of August in the very first weekend of August which weekend is that?
Scott: was that the third?
Scott: I think the first weekend in August I'll get the calendar for you in a later show is Connecticut.
Scott: Friday Saturday Sunday in the first Connecticut in the Hartford Convention Center, it's it's the only could be convention center.
Rym: We are going to be there all weekend doing.
Rym: god I can't I don't even.
Rym: actually we haven't got the finalists yet But we're going to be doing a ton of live shows on Saturday and on Sunday, we're gonna be running games.
Rym: We're gonna be running some burning wheel.
Rym: We're gonna be running some like teach and then play sessions with some of the more hardcore board games Where we'll act as a wicked awesome gaming room at ConnectiCon.
Scott: and even when we're not in there We have some front row crew associates who will be in there rocking games from pretty much the entire con.
Rym: So if you like anime or video games or web comics any of those three
Scott: or even video games or you know I mean, there's a miniatures gaming room in there and I swear There's like the same old guys every year go in there and play like a miniatures war for like the whole weekend.
Rym: I really like ConnectiCon because it's not really an anime con.
Rym: It's just a geek con straight up and it doesn't really pretend to be Anything else?
Scott: Yeah it's got a little bit of anime styling like on the face of it and I guess the majority of the crowd is sort of like the anime con ish fan crowd, but it's not really a big con.
Scott: It's sort of like just the right size.
Scott: You can be comfortable and most of the merchandise in the dealer's room is anime con type merchandise.
Scott: But you know, it's.
Scott: it's got some comic book action going on.
Scott: It's got gaming heart really awesome game room was.
Rym: ConnectiCon is really cool in that.
Rym: That's the con where they really pretty much they.
Rym: let us test new events there.
Rym: So when we're gonna do a new live show like we come up with hey What do we do a panel about Semprene?
Rym: All right Well, let's put it together and then we do it always for a test audience at ConnectiCon And that's kind of the place where they really let us play around with like formats of things and it's worked really well for us.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's you know, cuz it's so small and such It's really easy to you know.
Scott: sort of have our run of the place and then like kind of.
Rym: the example I would give is if you see it like One of our live shows that Otakon or Penny Arcade Expo or any of those like Baker katsu con They're kind of chair facing forward.
Rym: We give a talk.
Rym: We teach you something We do something.
Rym: ConnectiCon is the.
Rym: we're sitting backwards in the chairs kind of just chilling and talking with our crowd.
Rym: Yep, like hey, so we're talking about this.
Rym: What do you guys think about this?
Rym: What would make this bla bla bla bla?
Rym: Hey great to hear from you.
Rym: Hmm.
Scott: So the weekend after ConnectiCon the second weekend in August is the Otakon.
Scott: Otakon.
Rym: Otakon is pretty much the best anime convention in America.
Scott: Yep Been to it for the past six or seven years.
Rym: Yeah, I've paid for one Otakon.
Rym: good god We've been doing panels there.
Scott: I think I've paid for two or three, but that's about it.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you didn't jump in on that anime club summit action as quickly as I did not really my bag.
Rym: But yeah, well that was my first foray into doing panels with those club summits back in the day.
Rym: But Otakon we're actually doing two panels this year Which is kind of cool because they denied a lot of people panels and yet they gave us two because we're awesome.
Rym: Yeah, well being panelists for every figure but we're talking about.
Scott: Well, should we reveal what we're talking about?
Rym: Yeah, why not?
Rym: All right.
Rym: What are our panels?
Scott: one of the panels.
Scott: One of the panels is the panel I've wanted to do for a long time.
Rym: but look we're doing know your creator exactly where we talk about like people who create anime and manga and Studios and directors and composers and all these things.
Scott: We're not really gonna go in-depth in any particular creators.
Scott: The idea is that a lot of you know people out there who are anime fans.
Scott: manga fans.
Scott: They don't pay attention to who makes their anime to who makes their manga.
Scott: They couldn't tell you, you know, they could name maybe three anime directors.
Scott: They could name maybe you know, three manga artists Whereas, you know, they could tell you if they'd also like movies or you know American live-action movies or books or they could tell you directs all of them or they could tell you all the actors are.
Scott: they could Everything.
Scott: so how come not with the anime and the manga?
Scott: so is to encourage people to pay attention to that.
Scott: We're gonna do a panel sort of telling them who all the big names are.
Rym: I mean think of this when we like, you know, we're big in the anime convention stuff and anime podcasting.
Rym: But when I first met Daryl Surratt over an anime world order when I was slightly drunk at Katsu Yeah, they're sort of to blame for this thing because you know I was one of those people who didn't pay attention at all.
Rym: I didn't pay attention who made anything.
Rym: and then Daryl Surratt comes up to me and he's got.
Rym: he puts a recorder in my face.
Rym: He's like, can you name?
Rym: Anyone who directs anime?
Rym: I think other than Miyazaki and I was like, uh Ikuhara Tezuka that That's all I would have been able to say back then.
Scott: is those and I might have been able to say oh gee I don't think I had.
Scott: I didn't even know Satoshi khan at that point.
Rym: Yeah, but now we've met him.
Rym: I've touched him.
Rym: Yeah, I was.
Rym: that was it was a good experience touching Satoshi khan.
Rym: I hope to do it again someday.
Scott: was he smooth?
Rym: He was so smooth and deadly.
Rym: And the other panel where anime you should see yeah, which is sort of this generic kind of black panel of hey The thing is Scott, you know in the internal GeekNights Scott is pissy and down on pretty much every panel we ever do.
Scott: Why what are you talking about?
Rym: He always complains that we shouldn't do that panel and we shouldn't do that panel more than once.
Rym: that panels lame.
Scott: We're talking about the point all.
Scott: the only thing I was a about is you know enemy you should see is an okay panel.
Rym: It's an incredibly important panel.
Rym: the
Scott: principle behind it is sort of generic and I was also kind of a because You the wanted us to do the gecky a panel again at the New York anime festival Even though he already did the gecky a panel at the New York anime festival,
Rym: even though we're running it basically completely differently.
Scott: It's not completely different.
Rym: Also.
Scott: Yes, it's mostly it's it's only a little bit differently.
Scott: Anyway, the point is is that It's not every pan.
Scott: All the other panels are awesome and anime you should see is still an okay panel because we're awesome and we can make any panel.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: I just don't get like panels like that.
Rym: What why is generic a bad thing?
Scott: I didn't say it was a bad thing I just said it was generic.
Rym: and a and a it's not at all It is.
Rym: how is it a to talk to people speak any medium any genre of thing?
Rym: Like are into board gaming and you just take give a talk where all right all you nubs you're new into this.
Rym: Here's all the like the important games that no one will ever tell you about it.
Rym: You won't find out about it.
Scott: So I guess it's just not a very glamorous panel to be running.
Rym: Oh, so glamour is what you're after.
Scott: Yeah, perhaps.
Rym: besides I point out that majesty.
Rym: perhaps also if you're going for glamour Those are actually the panels that get the most traction are like the game shows and the generically titled panel.
Scott: Those are glamorous.
Rym: The game shows how are they more glamorous than this in terms?
Rym: I mean the crowds the same get a gigantic yelling crowd special guests making the game show glamorous.
Rym: Yeah, getting like Peter Fernandez.
Scott: Yes, if they had a special guest that enemy you should see instant majesty.
Scott: All right, two weeks after Otakon so Otakon Then the weekend after that.
Scott: Oh, it's been Labor Day weekend the last weekend of August Penny arcade Expo.
Scott: plane tickets to Seattle or purchased hotels are reserved.
Rym: Yes, also we are going to be at the penny arcade expo.
Scott: We're gonna land in Seattle Thursday night go to bed.
Scott: Wake up go to PAX.
Rym: We're gonna be in town until like Monday night.
Scott: So yes, then Monday night.
Scott: So late Monday night on Labor Day We're gonna leave town.
Scott: So all of the Monday after PAX on Labor Day, we're gonna hang out Labor Day in Seattle.
Rym: So West Coast listeners unlike penny arcade who seem to avoid the East Coast We're gonna be on the West Coast.
Rym: if you want to meet us truck up to Seattle.
Scott: That's gonna be your only shot cuz.
Scott: I've never been west of Novi Michigan before my life.
Rym: I was the one who drove Scott to Novi Michigan.
Scott: Probably never gonna be.
Rym: I'm not gonna be west of the Mississippi for many a year Until recently when I flew out to Arizona to see my mom and I hadn't been west of Chicago.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I've been east to Israel which I guess is the middle of the east but I've never.
Scott: I've never been farther west then, you know, no by Michigan.
Rym: Yeah, but we're actually doing an event at the penny arcade Expo called beyond dungeons and dragons.
Scott: We're gonna be talking all about You know all the indie RPGs and the RPGs that are not like D&D and other D&D like our.
Scott: and
Rym: I'm gonna say one thing Now this if this sounds cool to you because I think this sounds really cool but we're going to begin like the kind of the brief bit that we're gonna introduce this panel with is and I title it affectionately a Brief history of Dungeons & Dragons as told through its character sheet.
Scott: Yep Oh They will.
Scott: I've already put Non D&D games like throw in a shatter on character sheet.
Rym: I've already got all that together that that I'm so proud of.
Rym: that little presentation Yep, that little five-minute bit.
Scott: That's a good way to start it off.
Scott: But basically that the thesis of this panel is you guys out there, you know, you might like comic books But you know this indie comic books that are way cool, right?
Scott: You like video games.
Scott: Obviously, this is penny arcade Expo You know, there's indie video games like indie PC games.
Scott: They're always way cool, right?
Scott: But when it comes to role-playing games, what do you like?
Scott: Dungeons & Dragons?
Scott: You know, there's indie RPGs, man You got to be paying attention to that shit.
Rym: And also, you know Thursday listeners who might you know Think of role-playing games and either picture scary white wolf people or scary D&D people.
Rym: There's other kinds of people Yep, especially crab people and that's gonna be.
Scott: that's the convention lineup for August.
Rym: Yeah, then in September New York Anime Festival will be doing three panels there and then you know, I've a. yeah It never ends with us.
Rym: it our con season those pretty much Late July early August through end of September and then it kind of cools off until cops account in February.
Rym: Yep, and yeah, we're gonna be a cops account in 2009 in DC.
Scott: So well crystal city.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well DC, right?
Rym: Crystal City is not a separate city.
Scott: Why does it have the word city?
Rym: Crystal City is the name of that mall that's connected to it.
Scott: Anyway, so that's the convention news there.
Rym: Yeah, so if you want to see us go to one of those events and you will be practically guaranteed to meet us We're we're incredibly hard to miss at a convention.
Scott: There are some other events We may or may not attend and we are may or may not run an event of a small event of some kind.
Scott: It's in the works.
Scott: But for now, that's it.
Scott: That's all I got.
Rym: Well, that was kind of random.
Rym: I guess we'll just do some things in the day and then get on with it.
Scott: Yeah Get on with it.
Scott: So, uh, it's all this.
Rym: then this is this is one of my reserve things of the day But it's something I've known about forever.
Rym: I always saw links to it.
Rym: I never really went to and I finally went there the other day and I ended up wasting about two hours on this site.
Rym: It's Passive-aggressive and the idea is you know, sometimes someone's so passive-aggressive that they won't Do something about something like I don't know your roommate eats all your food.
Rym: You don't say hey roommate get the fuck out.
Rym: or hey roommate.
Rym: Stop eating my fucking Cheerios you ass.
Rym: Instead you write a little note saying please stop eating my stuff and you stick it where you know They'll see it, you know avoiding confrontation that sort of thing.
Rym: Nothing is funnier to me than reading those sorts of notes.
Rym: this website is a place where if you see a note like that take a picture of it and put it online for Everyone to enjoy most of those bright fake though.
Rym: No, actually a lot of them are very clearly not fake.
Scott: How could you tell?
Rym: because I've the kinds of notes that are on this site are the notes that I've seen Many many a time in the real world.
Scott: Alrighty.
Scott: What can I give you?
Scott: some example notes?
Rym: I don't have any up here.
Rym: What do you offer me an example note?
Rym: A lot of them are notes that like a company you'll put up like someone stole someone's lunch.
Rym: So someone writes a note like to the person stealing the lunches.
Rym: blah blah blah.
Scott: Okay, I see you're talking about yeah, okay.
Rym: I could see that or a lot of times a lot most of it.
Rym: It's like half People in businesses writing notes because they're afraid of confronting other people at their business.
Rym: Yeah, the other half is college kids who just never learned how to confront people.
Rym: Yeah, and then I guess the other 1% you know rounding that's not accounted for are the ultra hilarious Just like crazy ones that have all these follow-ups.
Scott: I mean there have to be fake ones on there.
Rym: right people do a good job of verifying them.
Rym: It looks like because a lot of times they'll be follow-up threads and people will like here's what happened the next day.
Rym: Here's the response.
Rym: note.
Scott: Just be really good at telling a story.
Rym: Okay, it fine.
Rym: Maybe one's fake.
Scott: Great, maybe one Is fake.
Rym: Seriously go read this side.
Rym: I get the impression that these are almost all.
Rym: I would guess that 90% of these are legitimate rather Legitimate or not.
Scott: they're fun, but at the point I'm trying to get at is whether they're fake or not.
Scott: if they're funny What what does it matter?
Rym: case in point the classic?
Scott: Hey crackhead hey crack, and that's great.
Scott: And was that was the thing of the day was doesn't early thing?
Rym: I'm sure that was the thing of the day.
Scott: I don't know if I use this as a thing of day or not and if it's a repeat I don't give a shit.
Scott: This is you've probably seen this if you're on the Internet's at all.
Scott: It's basically office war.
Scott: now when it comes to things like water balloons or nerf or you know other sorts of non-lethal toy weaponry Everyone from when they're a child to even when you're growing up a little bit you imagine having really elaborate Well adjudicated battles with these things.
Scott: You know I mean like when your kids you always have a water balloon fight But you never have like a real.
Scott: you always really want to have like a serious water balloon fight with like shit tons of water balloons and like you have like Bandoliers of water balloons and the whole thing going on.
Scott: you actually want people to say you know like have some sort of Rules of winning and losing and there's some appeal to that.
Scott: I don't understand what it is, but it's it's a desire I know I've had and I know a lot of other people have also had.
Scott: so Vision a vision.
Rym: I have a vision of everyone in the front row crew Agreeing to an arsenal all buying a standard loadout of nerf equipment and then going nuts.
Scott: I think tribes do is much better idea, but anyway, you know what we have a better pulling off the former Perhaps I say perhaps a lot today.
Scott: so nerf You know that nerf for a while right?
Scott: I don't know if everyone was.
Scott: I'm sure everyone listening knows about nerf But nerf basically makes foam toys
Rym: I don't think you need to explain most
Scott: of that and they're famous for their foam Weapons in addition to their foam footballs mostly the foam weapons and for many years their foam weapons have been Sort of subpar.
Scott: because if you know over protection of kids and all that sort of bullshit You know the nerf weapons you could buy in the store were not what they were when we were kids.
Scott: the selection is decreased the power And accuracy is decreased.
Scott: The quality of the weapons overall is decreasing me.
Scott: there's no nerf bow and arrow anymore.
Scott: what happened to it?
Scott: You know, meanwhile the original nerf bow and arrow kicked ass like one of the best toys ever made.
Rym: I remember they were so hard to get that over Christmas.
Rym: My brother got one.
Scott: It's like nerf bow and arrow is like on the Super Soaker level of toy, but I didn't.
Rym: I got a knockoff Robin Hood bow and arrow Useless.
Rym: my parents knew it's just what are they gonna do that?
Rym: One of the kids was gonna be disappointed just by don't buy anything and then wait And deny us a nerf bow and arrow.
Scott: Well, no is you buy give one.
Scott: you say I'll get another one as soon as I can.
Rym: Yes, and you know long it took for those to be back in stock.
Scott: That's you know, that's what it takes.
Scott: Anyway, so nerf, I guess they're attempting to make a comeback which is fine by me.
Scott: And what they've done is they've done something that's actually pretty extraordinary.
Scott: Number one someone in nerf must realize what makes nerf awesome because They they realize that people want to have these organized, you know People have this fantasy of organized serious total all-out nerf war.
Scott: they realize this fantasy exists and they made a video That sort of works towards fulfilling that fantasy or stoking the fires of that fantasy To.
Scott: they have re-upped their equipment it seems because in this video There are many many awesome nerf things.
Scott: For example, the nerf sniper rifle something which used to be only made in the homebrew arena is now an official product.
Scott: They've got the nerf like electronic minigun with the chain of suction cup arrow.
Rym: I had the old hand crank minigun.
Rym: It was the last nerf item I ever got and while it was awesome the Belt feed was prone to jam.
Scott: This is basically like a Maxim machine gun of nerf right and when they pull the thing out, it's like oh man.
Rym: and I remember that my the biggest fantasy I had early on as a kid was when I started getting all these nerf guns was I wanted a pistol that I cocked and then fired instead of a kind of bow action.
Rym: and they made that back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, almost right away.
Scott: Well, we I had the ones that hold three arrows and you wouldn't conk and fire You.
Scott: just you know, it's sort of like those.
Rym: watch out those little black arrow.
Scott: Yeah you know the water guns that work by suction like that.
Scott: you'd sort of fill them up and then you pull the two ends close to Each other.
Scott: that's like a shotgun.
Scott: almost That's how this worked.
Scott: is?
Scott: you would pull the front of the gun forward and then pull it back and it would just your own The force of your arm would push the air to shoot the air.
Rym: I had that.
Rym: it was my sidearm.
Rym: What I also did was I learned is those little black arrows.
Rym: if you threw them like a knife they flew perfectly.
Scott: They're really the most aerodynamic arrows, I love those arrows.
Scott: anyway You know They've also got like velcro things going on and the whole bit now.
Scott: the other thing to nerf has managed to do here with this Video is not only advertise their products stoke the fires of you know, a fantasy that many people have etc.
Scott: This is perhaps the first example I've seen of someone Intentionally attempting to make a you know viral video.
Scott: That's also an obvious advertisement Because I mean it has to be an advertisement because they're unreleased nerf equipment's in here and the video production quality is very very high and the quantity of equipment could not be had.
Scott: and let's nerve for provided it Is that they actually made a good thing.
Scott: it's like this is a good video and they made it on purpose.
Rym: Yep, it's any time.
Rym: when have you seen there's one other time in my life?
Rym: It was also recently when we were at James and Lisa's wedding.
Rym: There was also Stanley Cup playoff action.
Rym: So, you know, we're of course we're watching hockey in the hotel room instead of hanging out because that's what you do Actually, we had a bunch of everyone came to our hotel room We all hung out and then the hotel guy was like you can't all sleep in this room.
Rym: They were like, we're not gonna go away.
Scott: I was watching hockey.
Rym: your hotel sucks.
Scott: He sure did.
Scott: We should have stayed at the motel.
Scott: Whatever right?
Rym: I sure did.
Rym: All right, and this ad came on and this it's one of the.
Rym: this ad was so funny.
Scott: I was a good ad I was.
Rym: not only did I watch it and like it and seek it out on the internet to watch Again, but I find it.
Rym: I found it.
Rym: I don't know if it's still on YouTube.
Rym: I'll find it again and post a link but it's basically this guy and It's like in the maternity ward and there's all the babies behind the glass and all the parents are there and you know the nursery.
Scott: Yeah Yeah everyone's looking.
Rym: and then suddenly he starts banging on the glass and screaming and yelling and just.
Rym: And then he starts pointing at all the other babies.
Rym: he's like you suck you suck you suck.
Rym: best baby ever right there best Baby ever you suck you suck.
Scott: It was such hockey right there banging on the glass Pointed at everyone in the other team saying you suck you suck you suck as baby and then pointed at the guy in your team And saying oh, yeah, awesome It's funny out.
Rym: sports commercials in general seem to do this like sports commercials Understand the fans of their respective sports better than almost any other advertising I ever see.
Scott: Yep, and this is a this is this nerf Viral intentional commercial meme thing actually works and really understands the feeling that us kind of people have for nerve.
Rym: so Scott tomorrow What are you gonna be doing in the morning waking up too goddamn early?
Rym: Yeah Why is that?
Scott: because I get one of the stupid iPhones if I don't get one tomorrow And
Rym: we need one for our company because we got to test it because pretty much we all want to switch to it And we got to make sure we can do all of all the same things we do with our blackberries with the iPhone the exchange integration and all that.
Rym: so We had to draw lots to see who's gonna stand in line and get an iPhone tomorrow.
Scott: I mean if that's what you want to test you could have just gotten a first-generation iPhone and upgraded the Software on it, and you'd be the same exact thing.
Rym: yeah Basically because they announced all the exchange stuff after the first one came out and we want the newest one anyway.
Scott: So I mean of course you want the newest one, but yeah, you know to test exchange.
Rym: There were a few ways around this however.
Scott: This is the most fun way yes, so anyway I'm gonna go wait in line.
Scott: now the question is which line Do I waited?
Rym: I would go to an AT&T store because there are AT&T stores.
Scott: there are Apple stores.
Scott: There's multiple of each in Manhattan.
Scott: does even AT&T stores up here in Beacon area Store in Danbury, Connecticut?
Scott: I could go to.
Rym: it's obvious if I were you.
Rym: what I would have done is long ago taking the day off work and just camped out the Apple the AT&T store up near here because Far fewer people are gonna try to camp that thing out.
Scott: Ah, but the steeply supply will also be lower.
Scott: for example if I go to the Apple store in the city sure I might wait Two hours, but they probably have a few thousand iPhones in there.
Scott: So yeah, I'm gonna get Scott the Apple store.
Rym: How many people do you think are already lined up probably right now?
Scott: right now?
Scott: I'm it's actually quite surprising.
Scott: I just probably less than less than 200 there right now I don't know I. I went to an AT&T store and asked her place and I said How many iPhones you gonna get?
Scott: and of course they said we don't know okay, then I said one no no.
Scott: then I said um Last time when the first iPhone came out how many people were there in line outside?
Scott: And she said oh about 250, and I said how many of those people got iPhones?
Scott: And she said all of them.
Scott: so that makes me go Aha, ha ha you see you just have to learn to ask the tricky questions.
Scott: This is why I have a tiny bit of journalism skills.
Scott: course not much.
Rym: We felt a tiny bit when we were trying to get Sensitive information out of the people for that World of Warcraft miniatures game.
Rym: We were like so how's the game work?
Rym: We can't talk about gameplay so suppose.
Scott: I'm playing can't talk about game, but I think they were just much Better at not answering questions, so they actually use judgment whereas this person Just only you know didn't answer the one question.
Scott: They weren't allowed to answer and answered every other question.
Rym: also probably didn't care.
Scott: also Did still knowing people.
Rym: most people actually don't.
Rym: most people probably don't even realize they can go to an AT&T store.
Scott: The other thing is that at the AT&T store the people there were actually friendly and knowledgeable.
Scott: It was.
Rym: it was quite unlike the Apple store where they beat you as you walk in.
Scott: No, but I'm saying it's like I'm compared to say what you would expect from an average wireless You know store.
Rym: can you say this?
Scott: I went to the wireless companies is evil and stupid.
Rym: I went to the Verizon store.
Scott: the other I mean like remember how it was in the Sprint store for you Don't?
Rym: I could do a whole Monday on Sprint right and so.
Scott: So because I'm gonna be waiting in this line tomorrow possibly with my boss also Cuz his trio.
Scott: he went swimming with his trio by accident, so now he's thinking about iPhones even though He always complained that didn't have a real keyboard, but once a long time ago He's asking me like text messaging when I get in line.
Rym: when I was very drunk I ended up showering with my phone in my pocket, but it didn't hurt it right anyway.
Scott: So yeah because of this waiting in line that's gonna happen.
Scott: tomorrow We'll talk about the iPhone itself.
Scott: you know two Mondays from now when actually I've had a lot of time with it and such.
Scott: But I figured we could do it Thursday on waiting in line.
Scott: cuz we've waited in on quite a many line We have the biggest thing you have to know.
Rym: we've learned this lesson very very powerfully But we had a chance to meet someone very eminent one.
Scott: see I think actually in the episode where we talked about this We discussed waiting in line Which is why I feel like we've done a waiting in line episode before.
Scott: But if we haven't done a waiting in line episode if we have done a waiting in line episode before oh well Sorry, but we I gotta wake up early.
Rym: We've decided Oh, let's camp out And then this will be awesome.
Rym: And then we kind of both bailed because neither one of us Really wanted to camp out.
Rym: and why don't we just wait till morning and we'll take an early ish Training.
Rym: don't have to take the first train in.
Rym: yeah I realize we'll get in the way of this awesome thing and we ended up totally failing as a result.
Scott: the thing is we were Pretty close to succeeding.
Rym: there was yes, but we didn't want it enough.
Scott: No we didn't want it.
Scott: And that's really when you're waiting in line.
Scott: There's a decision-making process that happens and you have to weigh three things right.
Scott: how badly do you want?
Scott: well?
Scott: What are you gonna get for waiting in line right?
Scott: How badly do you want that thing that you're waiting in line for?
Scott: Right and then how long do you have to wait in line to get what you want?
Scott: Because you know some lines you just wait in them And you're eventually gonna get what you want.
Scott: like say if you go to cedar point if you wait in a line to ride a Rollercoaster oh no no no you're going to ride it.
Rym: Oh, that's not always true.
Rym: Yeah, at all didn't?
Scott: they close the park, and then they cut off the line.
Rym: now because you see Oftentimes a particular ride for various reasons some routes are more prone to this than others will break down.
Rym: ah and what happens?
Rym: is this?
Rym: Incredible calculus.
Rym: where I'm in line and I see that the line is not moved in a while And I look up and I see some people Abandoning the line as root word spreads that the rides down and people are trying to guess when it is why when you're in a?
Scott: Long line for a ride you spread a rumor that the ride is broken down when it has not here.
Rym: see There's the reason that doesn't work.
Rym: is that canny people who go to amusement parks?
Rym: You don't pay attention to a rumor that comes from the back of the line And no one in the front of the line has any incentive.
Scott: that's true granted.
Rym: ah The real trick is just to cut Because I'll admit this I'm just horrible.
Rym: But the majority of people are too passive too passive to actually do anything about it.
Scott: if you cut in front of them Yeah, well here's the thing about cutting.
Scott: It's like you know you cut in front of.
Scott: let's say you cut in front of an asshole.
Scott: Right he'll be all like gravel gravel gravel gravel, so you say all right man.
Scott: Just chill Then you just cut.
Scott: you know a little bit in front of that.
Scott: You're not cutting directly in front of the asshole somehow.
Scott: He has no problem with it He can't you know?
Scott: even though the effect on him is the same He's still one spot further back in line.
Rym: see the thing is secret.
Rym: point actually did something really good when whenever you if they caught Someone cutting in line they did have people who were semi undercover watching for it.
Rym: They literally dragged you out of the park with no refund immediately.
Scott: Yeah, that's a game.
Rym: I I watch it happen a lot of course.
Rym: I also cut in line, but I was.
Rym: well.
Scott: Here's the thing right all right.
Scott: well cutting in line.
Scott: obviously you want to try to pull off cutting in line if you can But you don't want to cut in line to the point where you have to suffer the consequences.
Rym: That's Are we gonna explain how to cut in line?
Rym: It's a very specific process.
Scott: I will tell you the best line cutter in the entire universe is my grandmother.
Rym: ah See she has an advantage being old.
Rym: well.
Scott: No no no even when she was not old she would write.
Scott: So we're in law she demonstrate.
Scott: I know she's used this skill many times in movie theaters and other places, but it was only demonstrated to me and only one Currents that I can actually remember even though I have stories of other times when I wasn't there.
Scott: We were at I believe Madame Tussauds wax museum in New York City.
Scott: This is like many years ago perhaps even a decade ago I don't know.
Scott: um and as a line and my grandma we weren't in the line right, but the line is sort of going down the Street.
Scott: we just sort of standing on the sidewalk and my grandma just strikes up a conversation with this complete stranger in line And I like I don't.
Scott: yeah at that time in my life I was not the type to converse with a stranger, but my grandma has no problem Just talking to anybody.
Rym: that is in fact the best way to cut it alive.
Scott: She just starts talking to the stranger and walking with them and talking and walking to talk and look that we're inside And we didn't have to wait in the line, and I'm like alrighty.
Rym: The way I often did it was partly because One of the pastimes in my high school was to skip school and go to cedar point whenever it was warm out.
Rym: So a lot of times I'd end up at cedar point like I just kind of cut out of high school and drive down to Cedar point and there'd be a lot of people from my high school there independently of me.
Rym: So this one time the Millennium Force the new when it was the tallest roller coaster in the world they built it.
Rym: It's like this epic thing and I'd been.
Rym: I've been looking forward to this since they announced like Intamin was like rollercoasters and all this business.
Rym: so we show up and We get into the park like a little bit late And there's a huge line.
Rym: huge line not even in the turnstiles yet because the rides don't start right away when the park opens.
Rym: So people are lined up, and I see that in the very front of this line is my good friend Adam.
Rym: Yeah So uh we I walked by and I've got a huge group of people with me because we all cut class at the same day.
Rym: Kind of random wasn't senior skip day.
Rym: It was just we just all skipped.
Rym: So we're all walking in this big group And if I had tried to just do it by myself because other people were so pumped about it We totally would have gotten busted.
Rym: but this giant group with me in it kind of stops next to the line and we all talk and then the line starts walking in and You saw this moment of decision and like three or four smart people including me in this mob that was standing next to the line Took quick action and slipped in in the chaos and everyone else kind of stood there going.
Rym: hey, what's going on?
Rym: Hey, where'd you guys go?
Rym: But then it was too late.
Scott: Yeah, that's how's done.
Scott: so the thing here right?
Scott: We've discussed how to cut in a line.
Scott: How do you what do you do when people are cutting in front of you because you say get the fuck out of line?
Scott: Yep, and if you see people cutting way ahead of you you say hey, hey, hey, are you get the hell out?
Rym: You cut exactly like that.
Rym: That's how you have to go.
Rym: Hey.
Rym: Yep, at least in New York There might be a different way of doing if you West.
Scott: you know.
Scott: if you do so.
Scott: We've said people are very not.
Scott: most people don't want to have.
Scott: you know a confrontation, right?
Scott: So if you you know cut in line, they won't confront you about it.
Scott: But at the same time if you confront someone who is trying to cut who is non-confrontational They would rather give up on their cut then confront you.
Rym: Also, you can usually call down the threat of something because there's always the external force like in the Nintendo store line.
Rym: If you raised a ruckus about someone cutting Nintendo would have come out and dragged him away.
Scott: It really what it really comes down to is how well the line is enforced.
Scott: a very poorly enforced line is pretty much bad news.
Scott: that's really what it is a Poorly enforced line.
Scott: a line without you know management Is very is pro cutter and a line with lots of management is pro anti cutter.
Scott: So if you know a line is gonna have guards or you know official people making sure that everything is legit Then you don't you want to get there early.
Scott: if you know a line is gonna be just sort of willy-nilly then Don't worry about when you get there cuz you just cut.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now bonus points if you cut in line and then within a short span of time Prevent someone else from cutting in line by raising a ruckus and no one confronts you about the hypocrisy.
Scott: That is a classy move.
Rym: That is a goal in life.
Scott: That is that is something you should definitely do.
Rym: Uh, of course, one of my favorite things to do in line is to bother other people.
Scott: Well, that's another thing about lines.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's.
Scott: the line is not just about achieving what you are there for.
Rym: For a lot of people it even though that is the number one thing for a lot of people it is and that's the problem A lot of people if you have to wait in a line somewhere.
Rym: I mean this could be applied generally to any time you're forced to wait for something.
Rym: but lines in particular a lot of people one Don't bring any means of entertaining themselves.
Scott: It's definitely something you got to do and thus did.
Rym: all the time spent in the line is wasted Yep and to a lot of people Will only see the prize at the end.
Rym: the goal of I'm going to get a thing and this line is my means to it.
Rym: But especially with geeky stuff like iPhones or like the Nintendo Store thing or an anime con The line is a self-selected people.
Rym: stop a self-selected set of people.
Scott: Yes, you can form you have similar interests.
Scott: Yeah, you have a line.
Scott: There's almost as line culture this line community that builds and then is dispersed.
Scott: It's like a temporary family and it's it's really something special.
Scott: And if you're not gonna take any part in that really of no place waiting in line At least not for a long amount of time, of course watch out because it's very tricky.
Rym: So, I mean we were in the line of the Nintendo.
Scott: it really depends in who you're in line.
Rym: It was pretty much us and the area we like.
Rym: there were other cool people our age but all the people in line right near us were Punk kids and they were.
Rym: they were like punk kids that were barely sentience.
Rym: Yep, and the conversations that we had with these kids were not shall we say and lightning.
Rym: now And I remember we tried to play advance wars with them and that just did not happen.
Scott: No, I didn't and there were some cool people near us, but they were mostly quiet and their DS's ran out of batteries.
Rym: Yeah, the one guy who was like, oh man, I love advance wars I'm undefeated.
Rym: my group of friends and we were about to play in his battery died immediately.
Scott: Huge taboo.
Scott: having any of your devices run out of battery power in a line.
Rym: I'll give you the hint if your laptops about to run out of battery Don't be like I shit my battery or don't let it just run out.
Rym: just be like I'm done with his laptop.
Rym: I'm gonna relax and kind of shut it down gracefully like nothing's wrong.
Scott: Yes, you don't want to let anyone know your batteries ran out because that is taboo.
Scott: That's like like one of the worst things you could do.
Scott: I guess other than stabbing I guess that was awesome.
Rym: Of course there's also the danger of it's like anime cons has happened to us where you're in line and The person in front of you may be cool.
Rym: You're trying to talk to them But the person in line behind you is one of those people one of those fanboys keeps bothering you and isn't I like Naruto?
Rym: do you like Naruto?
Rym: Was talking about the Naruto?
Scott: If you encounter those kinds of fanboys out and about it's easy to just run away from them or say see ya What's your I am in order something in order to avoid them?
Scott: You would have to like lose your spot in line or find some way to kick them out of line Which good luck with that?
Scott: So it really puts you in a predicament and when you get in a line, you really have to decide, you know do you stand there and wait for there to be cool people and then you get in line?
Scott: that way your line community is gonna be good or Do you just you know is it?
Scott: you can't wait for the line to get any longer?
Scott: You need to get in now or else you're gonna miss out on whatever it is.
Rym: There's also the issue of do you engage or not?
Rym: because if you're in line people will generally leave you alone unless you engage or put yourself in a Kind of body language position where people will look at you and think he wants to be engaged.
Scott: Yeah, like, you know people by default in a line will just not talk not interact.
Scott: But as soon as you know someone, you know, try something, you know, then some interacting might happen.
Scott: It's like no one will try to interact starts talking right away like whoa, we're in a line.
Scott: Hey guys, what's going on dadada?
Rym: cuz everyone will start paying attention to you.
Rym: You'll get this little kind of crowd around you.
Rym: But at the same time if anyone undesirable joins that crowd there is no Safe socially acceptable way to reject them.
Scott: and also, you know, if someone doesn't want to interact They're not going to and no one will try to enter.
Scott: No one will force them into interacting, you know, like if you just stand there quietly and just mind your own business No one will bother you in a line.
Scott: They'll just ignore you.
Rym: So basically Here's the quickie if someone you don't want to talk to keeps engaging you in a line and you're trying to engage other people Don't you know like be like, oh you suck don't yell at him or anything or don't do anything Active or aggressive because you know what we said, yeah passive-aggressive doesn't really work.
Rym: You don't really want to hurt the feelings the person in line behind you because they are only going to bother you.
Scott: the rest Yes, and if you do something to get rid of this annoying person in line, you might succeed but you will also Guaranteed make everyone cool in line near you uncomfortable, which is not good Yeah.
Rym: so what you do is if they're talking to you you like face them and listen to what they're saying and then Rotate your body about 15 degrees off-axis from them probably to the right.
Rym: like if you're facing them kind of have your body your shoulders being 15 degrees away to the right from facing them and still look at them, but don't make direct eye contact and Limit your responses to answers and kind of acknowledgments, but don't like uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: Oh But yeah Gage further and that is pretty much
Scott: the
Rym: Safest least harmful way to disengage from one of those people and then after you've been doing that for a while as soon as they Engage anyone else for a moment engage the person you wanted to engage and everything will be nice and neat.
Rym: you're done.
Scott: Yeah, you can sort of you know when they as you sort of you know Pay less and less attention to them and interact with them less and less.
Scott: they might eventually Lash on to someone else and bother them and then you can interact with someone else.
Rym: if you're evil You can force them off on someone.
Scott: Yeah, you can make a split.
Scott: basically It's like you have a group of four people.
Scott: one of them is bad.
Scott: Well, you foist the bad one off on to say the fourth one and then you keep the second one and you're all good.
Rym: I gotta say though the DS is revolutionized line waiting for nature at least in geeky situations because You're gonna find people to play DS games and there's so many multiplayer DS games.
Scott: Yep The iPhone is also gonna be wicked awesome for the line waiting.
Scott: I can tell already.
Scott: of course It sucks to wait in line for the iPhone which would really helped out while you're in line for itself.
Rym: I just bring your DS.
Scott: I'm bringing the DS laptop, you know, I will go to work right afterwards.
Scott: It's mean the line is right next to my office.
Scott: So, how can I yeah, I gotta I gotta pretty much wait in line Go to work?
Rym: Yeah the only reason I'm holding out on the iPhone is because I got to make sure I'm not gonna get it unless I can get My work blackberry and use it as my only like wireless device.
Scott: I don't have work blackberry to worry about.
Scott: So here I go.
Rym: Yeah, plus I mean I got a curve from work and the curves pretty nice.
Scott: Also the App Store which I. well they're good talk about this in a week for Monday Yeah, but anyway, what else about line waiting?
Rym: Can we say well I have a bunch of stories about that time.
Rym: me and a bunch of my friends drove this woman insane in line to Cedar Point Like we made her actually like completely freak out and then they actually escorted her out of the line and it wasn't even intentional.
Rym: We were dying.
Rym: we were being very annoying but It was not like I'm doing this to drive you insane.
Rym: I'm just being annoying because I'm bored.
Scott: Well, here here's some general line tips.
Scott: All right, if there are multiple lines Right get in the shorter one.
Scott: now that might seem like an obvious thing, right?
Scott: But it usually isn't.
Scott: for example You might go to an amusement park Right, and there is a water slide.
Scott: and like there might be a tower and there might be multiple water slides in the tower But one of the water slides is a much shorter line than the others.
Scott: It's probably because that water slide is scarier than the others and people don't want to get on that.
Scott: Oh, it's usually because it's weaker not that from my experience the scarier ones off.
Rym: now from my experience the higher up and faster and Crazier was the longer the line was rarely because now is the Six Flags New England is a tower.
Scott: There's two blue slides and then one green slide And if you wanted to go on the green slide You basically just walked up right past everyone and said green slide green slide green slide and went down the green slide.
Rym: So I think a better set of tips are the how to make the line interesting.
Rym: Those are good too Because the way we drove this woman insane was.
Rym: we're in line to see your point and one Get in line with a group of friends and you cannot go wrong.
Scott: Oh, yeah You bring your own crew.
Rym: you can't lose because I get when I was a little kid and we get it like I'd be in Family or something for a roller coaster at Cedar Point and the line was always hot and boring and oh my god I just want to ride the ride.
Rym: But once I had a car and I started driving down on my own it was me and all my friends.
Rym: It was like alright The line is not time wasted because the whole time you're in line your whole group of friends is together.
Rym: Just hang it out.
Rym: And then suddenly you're hanging out as interrupted by a roller coaster.
Rym: Mmm, so there's all.
Scott: well, there's the line for the front of the roller coaster.
Rym: Yes, which is almost always worth it Unless you're a roller coaster freak.
Rym: in which case I recommend unless it's a hanging roller coaster You want to sit in the front of the last car?
Rym: That is pretty much the best seat and any non hanging roller coaster.
Scott: Yeah sitting in the back of any car is not so great.
Rym: Well, if you like a rough ride the back the back of the car is fine.
Rym: I'm not a fan of the back because the front of the car is kind of Ballasted or balanced by the connection to the car in front of it.
Rym: But anyway All we did was I'm standing in line, you know, all these people in high school.
Rym: We're in line for this roller coaster and there's the metal turnstiles.
Rym: I just start idly chinking a quarter against it like think think think think think think think think think think think think think think think thing.
Rym: And I keep doing it.
Rym: and then one of my friends starts doing it think to think to think to think to think to think to Think to think and then all of us kind of start doing it And then this woman's like could you guys stop that?
Rym: that's really annoying.
Rym: We're like, all right, and we you know, we kind of stop But then someone further down the line starts doing it.
Rym: Oh, and and then someone else starts doing it and then the whole lines doing it and they won't stop and it just keeps going And keeps going and keeps going.
Scott: Did you start doing it again?
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: Okay at that point All right.
Rym: After we laugh because we realized what we had wrought.
Rym: and then this goes on for a good five minutes and then this unrelated woman who's there with her family, it looks like, just starts screaming at everyone to stop it.
Rym: And that just makes it get louder.
Rym: And then it goes crazy and they took her away.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I felt bad about it, but I totally.
Rym: we stopped when someone asked us to.
Rym: And it's sad, but it's also hilarious that some other guy was like, oh, man, and started doing it right away.
Scott: Well, that's really that's a very.
Scott: it's sort of like doing the wave.
Scott: You know, it's a very basic concept of group psychology.
Scott: is that the more complex thing you want to get a group to do it, the more people you want to do it, the harder it is.
Scott: But if you want to get more people to do something, your best bet is to have many people do a simple thing.
Scott: And then it is easier to get a large number of people do it.
Scott: For example, you're at a baseball stadium.
Scott: You want to get everyone to do the wave pretty easy.
Scott: You want everyone to chant, you know, let's go team.
Scott: Pretty easy.
Rym: You want everyone to see the X, the X, the I see can't go.
Rym: So that's not going to happen.
Scott: That's not going to happen with it.
Scott: You know, as the number of people increases, the harder it is to get them to do something complex.
Scott: So if you're looking for, you know, deep, complex conversation, the people next to you are it.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It's as far as you're going to get.
Scott: So if you want to get, say, you know, a little little chant going on, like, ah, phone, ah, you could probably do that with the whole line.
Rym: And it's a lot of fun.
Scott: Either one, either one of those activities, either good conversation, the people next to you or your line chance are equally valid and entertaining will become a mini temporary society.
Scott: And if you're the longer it exists, the more indenture that society will become.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: And especially like in roller coaster lines, like the cool thing was Cedar Point, like there's pretty much at night when the line was like two hours long because, you know, everyone got in line for like one last ride.
Rym: And then it's all night long.
Rym: They'd have deejays and music and the line was like, you'd get to know a lot of these people in line because the turnstiles keep passing the same people all the time.
Rym: So one, we play a game.
Rym: I forget what we used to call it.
Rym: I think we called it pulling the Jesus.
Rym: I don't remember why, but basically make sure that you're talking about something really weird.
Rym: every time you pass this like one person.
Scott: And they'll eventually back and forth line.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So it's like, turned out Jesus was gay.
Rym: And then, yeah, I met him the other night.
Rym: He was a pirate and then the nukes fell.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: And just go nuts with it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The other off is to just completely like bother people, but that's not my bag.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: You know, it really gets me about lines.
Scott: It's really like to know more about is how when you finally sort of achieve what you're in the line for, you know, you go in, you buy your iPhone or whatever, you ride the roller coaster and then you get
Rym: out of the line,
Scott: even though you're still next to the people that were just like your closest line friends, like the whole line.
Scott: culture is destroyed.
Scott: It's like completely eliminated.
Rym: It's like at the end of Lord of the Flies, when you suddenly wake up, you're like, oh, it's just a bunch of kids, right?
Scott: It's like if I got like, as soon as I get that, let's say tomorrow, I make really good friends with the person in front of me, right?
Scott: I go in, I buy the iPhone right next to them.
Scott: They they're checking out of the checkout next to me.
Scott: I buy an iPhone.
Scott: They buy an iPhone.
Scott: We both go out on the street.
Scott: It's like we're complete strangers again.
Scott: Maybe we'll get a nod.
Scott: That's about it.
Scott: And then we're done.
Scott: Yeah, that's how it is.
Rym: And but within the line, like you can become the king of the line while you're in it.
Rym: But then that's gone when you leave the line.
Rym: The way to become the king is to be the person that starts the first chain or the first game or the person who instigates a long running game of penis.
Scott: Penis, penis, penis.
Rym: We're not going to play this on the air.
Scott: Some cool kids are playing penis on the train a week or two ago.
Scott: It was good.
Rym: I didn't join in because I feel like I'm a bit beyond that.
Scott: But at the same time, I was I had an urge to join in, but also an urge not to join in.
Rym: Yes, because it's like on one hand, I ride this train as a businessman and that would be really annoying.
Scott: I wanted I wanted some way to show my respect for their game of penis without having to play.
Rym: Also, I did not want to engage them because, again, they were also drunk.
Rym: And, you know, once you engage someone, it's difficult to disengage.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But I wanted to find I wish there was somebody to show my like not of approval for their game.
Scott: Like I approve of this penis playing on the train without actually involving myself with that.
Rym: Maybe geeks need a symbol, a symbol.
Rym: We use some sort of like a gang hand sign that I do not wish to engage with you, but I approve of what you have done.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Like you're the awesome or maybe something like you for the win.
Rym: Let's go like that.
Scott: The shocker.
Rym: That's not a shocker.
Scott: Why are you putting up the shocker shocker?
Rym: That is a shocker.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Why are you giving the shocker?
Rym: You know, as horrible as a shocker is, I like it was a horrible thing.
Rym: But the fact that I don't know how it became such a funny thing and not just in our RIT hockey culture, but geek culture, like people make shocker jokes all the time.
Rym: And I don't know.
Scott: I don't know why shocker is not just a geek thing.
Scott: It's a. it's a.
Rym: it's a joke in general, but it's like a lot of geeks have latched on to it.
Rym: Shocker jokes hit FARC like crazy to this day.
Scott: Yeah, it's the shocker.
Scott: Who got anything else to say?
Scott: I'm waiting in line.
Scott: If you want something real bad and the only way to get it is waiting in line.
Scott: If you want it badly enough, you're going to get in line early enough to get it.
Scott: If you don't want it badly enough, you're not going to get in line early enough to get it.
Scott: You might as well not get in line.
Rym: Bring friends or entertainment.
Rym: Enjoy the line.
Rym: Look at the line as an experience to have fun.
Rym: If you're not having fun, you're not in the right kind of line or you're not aligned.
Scott: If you don't.
Scott: Yeah, if you're not a line person, just don't wait in any lines and just, you know, get your iPhone.
Rym: If you have to lose your grandeur from now, attempt to become the king of the line, knowing that you have effectively engaged everyone in the line.
Scott: The best trick, right?
Scott: Better than becoming the king of the line is becoming the shadow king of the line in which you are in control of the line.
Scott: You have started the chance and such, but no one actually recognizes you.
Scott: You don't stand out as the king of the line.
Rym: That's kind of like playing solitaire.
Rym: I took over the line.
Scott: You're in control of the line, but you don't stand out.
Scott: You're just one of the crowd.
Scott: No one notices you or anything.
Rym: If you have a friend who's in the line somewhere else, there's a good game you can play.
Rym: Both of you vie to become kings of the line.
Rym: That's a real good one.
Scott: I stand like a hundred people in, you stand 200 people in, and then I re prearrange like, this is the chance I'm going to try to get started.
Scott: And this is the chain you were trying to go get started.
Scott: And we see who gets which chance started.
Scott: And then maybe they'd like the line will have some sort of a, um, what's it called?
Scott: It might get a little partisan partisan to be like two kings of two different kingdoms in a war.
Rym: I keep saying king of the line.
Rym: I guess I should, cause this happens.
Rym: Like king of the line is something very specific.
Rym: Quite you that happens.
Rym: Hey, if I can be anything like Freddie Mercury, but anyway, I'm not going to wear those vests.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't like that.
Rym: That's not a good style on me.
Rym: I don't think.
Scott: I think I could wear that yellow vesty thing, but I just have to wear a shirt.
Rym: King of the line is this very specific phenomenon.
Rym: And you'll know when someone has achieved it because they'll have done something in the whole crowd.
Rym: Like maybe they yelled something out funny and then the whole crowd, like looked at them and laughed.
Rym: And you see this in sporting events too, like the king of the section where the one guy yells the clever thing.
Rym: And then everyone, like whenever there's a situation for the rest of the line, for everyone who remembers or the rest of the game where someone should yell something out, you'll notice that half the line will look to whoever was the king of the line, expecting them to say something.
Scott: I got one more thing to say about an automatic audience.
Scott: Here's one more thing to say about lines, right?
Scott: Not only should you bring something to entertain yourself with, if you're looking for action in the line itself, bring social currency with you.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Costumes are the best social currency in a line.
Scott: For example, if I show up tomorrow, dressed like Steve Jobs with a little turtleneck and jeans, totally going to rock the house with that.
Scott: Someone should do it.
Scott: Another good idea.
Scott: Show up to a lot, any line.
Scott: It doesn't matter what the line is for.
Scott: dressed up like a Jedi.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: Dress up like a Jedi in any line.
Scott: It will work.
Scott: And if it's a Star Wars line, dress up like Star Trek with Spock and some Spock ears will always work.
Scott: Wookiees work in any line.
Scott: Also Mario and Luigi, they work in most lines.
Rym: or just, you know, have the, the clever t-shirt of course.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Clever t-shirt is good.
Scott: If you, if you're not going for the big costume, I tend to go with the clever t-shirt.
Scott: Typically you want to go with a rare t-shirt, something people haven't seen before.
Scott: You know, if you have the same funny t-shirt as everyone else from, you know, think geek, it's not going to work, but if you get like, you know, a rare shirt, that's sort of from some weird internet site, like a web comic, that's not too popular, then you're going to hit it off pretty well.
Scott: But yeah, get some social currency, bring something with you, usually clothing or a costume or something that will get you some attention or be a good conversation starter.
Scott: Cause that's the best way to get stuff going on.
Rym: Also bring a drink.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Drinks are good.
Scott: Another good example of social currency, especially like a video game line, have a DS from Japan.
Scott: That's a different color.
Scott: or bring an imported DS game with you or, you know, something along those lines and you'll get some conversations out of that.
Rym: So, for the eye of the line tomorrow, of course you're going to bring that Apple G2.
Rym: Just carry it on your back.
Scott: I bring my G2 with me to get my iPhone.
Scott: No, I'm not.
Scott: I'm just going to bring my usual shit to work.
Scott: I have a funny t-shirt and my normal stuff, a digital camera, you know, whatever.
Rym: If anyone out there listening brings an Apple G2.
Scott: Of course I'm going to be ripping out my super Linux-y laptop right in the middle of all the Mac books.
Scott: That's what I got going on.
Rym: Alright, this episode went nowhere.
Rym: We're done.
Scott: We're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our crapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share-a-like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.