Scott: It's Wednesday, February 27th.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, we begin Katsu-Kan coverage.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Now I know a lot of people are listening to GeekNights right now.
Rym: You're listening to this episode expecting some Katsu-Kan coverage.
Rym: And we're going to have that for you.
Rym: But I know a lot of you are probably new GeekNights listeners.
Rym: You've never listened to this stuff before.
Rym: You're just, you were at Katsu-Kan, you saw us, you were waiting for us to do the thing we'd say we do.
Rym: Maybe you skipped those other episodes earlier in the week because you really only care about anime.
Rym: Well, here it is.
Rym: This is GeekNights Wednesdays, the night when we talk about anime, manga, and comics.
Scott: Seriously, though, if this is like, if you were waiting to listen to GeekNights until this episode came out, like, you discovered it's like, how many episodes do we already have you could have listened to?
Scott: Why didn't you go and listen to one of those old ones?
Scott: What, seriously?
Rym: Yeah, I don't think we need to explain what GeekNights is or how it works.
Scott: Well, if you're already hearing this, you've already figured it out.
Scott: Congratulations.
Rym: Well, they might not have figured out that we air four nights a week and we cover four different topics.
Scott: All right, all right, all right, all right, all right.
Scott: They can read that on the website.
Rym: But now's the part where normally we start, we talk about our day like, "Hey, Scott, how you
Rym: doing?".
Rym: "Uh, uh, blah, blah, blah, flat
Rym: tire.".
Rym: "Hey, well, blah, blah, blah, crazy homeless
Rym: guy.".
Scott: Actually, lately I'm feeling a lot better.
Scott: Like, the sun was coming into the office today and I was, I felt like working and I did work and, uh...
Rym: Oh, yeah, well, I got my new laptop, so...
Scott: The winter's almost over, my gears are connecting again.
Rym: I walk outside, it's warm, I take the Express 4 train down to Union Square, go to the bag store, look at bags, go right back to work and order one of the bags I saw online for less money.
Scott: Did you buy that one bag that you said you liked?
Rym: No, actually, I didn't actually purchase yet, but I filled my cart with two bags and I got to pick one of the two.
Scott: I'm not a fan of that bag.
Rym: I like that bag a lot.
Scott: I'll demonstrate to you after the show how the, uh...
Rym: No, I know exactly how it works.
Rym: The thing is, with that bag, it really, really goes with my duster, like in a big way.
Scott: Oh, do you need a purse to match your shoes?
Rym: No, because I'm getting that bag.
Scott: Oh, tables turned.
Scott: Tables turned.
Scott: Oh, Rym was shopping for a purse at the store.
Scott: I had to wait for him.
Rym: Actually, it will match my shoes.
Rym: That was kind of important.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I'm glad we cleared this up.
Rym: Cleared what up?
Scott: Why you took so long to buy a bag.
Rym: Actually, I bought my bag immediately, unlike someone else we know who might be in this studio here, who, uh, when we were trying to get to the beach after being at Wildwood...
Scott: Spent time in the video game store as opposed to the bag, shoe, and such store.
Rym: Went to the mall trying to buy a pair of shoes to match his purse.
Scott: Yeah, Rym buying his cosmetics and his...
Rym: You mean my Cosmo Coie.
Scott: His perfumes.
Rym: Anyway, anyway.
Rym: So, uh, now's the time when we talk about our day, but I gotta skip that because every now and then there's...
Scott: Today was not an exciting day.
Rym: No, it was not.
Scott: I mean, the most exciting thing I might have to say today is that Rym got some more ramens, but he got them yesterday and they're still in his car.
Rym: Yeah, and I got a lot of exciting stories from the last week and a half where we didn't do GeekNights, but those are all big enough to be actual kind of anecdotes as opposed to just, "Yeah, yesterday, blah, crazy homeless
Rym: guy.".
Scott: I got some... Oh, actually, no.
Scott: When I got off the train when I got home and I walked up the stairs, did you take the stairs out of the train station?
Rym: I did take the stairs.
Scott: Did you notice anything on those stairs?
Rym: I noticed something scary that I avoided.
Scott: You did see it.
Scott: It was there that long.
Rym: I didn't know what it was, and I had a couple of guesses as to what it was.
Scott: A couple of guesses.
Scott: What is your number one guess?
Rym: It's doo-doo!
Scott: It was a big doo-doo in a brown paper bag.
Rym: Are you sure it wasn't just like a big chocolate donut that someone dropped?
Scott: I am so sure that was poop.
Rym: Because I didn't inspect it.
Rym: I decided.
Rym: I walked by it pretty quickly.
Scott: I didn't smell it, but I am confident that it was the shit of something.
Rym: You know, sometimes something happens, and you're like, "I gotta go see what that was or it'll haunt me the rest of my
Rym: life.".
Rym: I saw it as I was walking up.
Rym: My brain was saying...
Scott: Well, I was walking up, and the person in front of me, for no reason, dodged to the left.
Scott: So I looked down to see what they dodged to the left from, and it was a really giant, giant poop.
Scott: That's all I can say.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: It might have just been a donut.
Scott: It could have been a donut, but I'm giving a 90% chance of poop.
Rym: See, my brain was calculating, because you know when you're walking, your brain's always calculating stuff.
Rym: Like, you're in the parking lot, and it's like, "Is that my
Rym: car?".
Rym: There's an 80% chance.
Rym: that's my car.
Rym: Yep, it's my car.
Scott: I actually have a new trick for finding my car at night in the parking lot.
Rym: Remembering where you park it?
Rym: Setting off the car alarm?
Scott: No, I push the unlock button on my keys.
Rym: And it goes, "Boop,
Rym: boop.".
Scott: No, and it turns on the lights, so I can see the lights reflecting off the cement in the dark.
Rym: I just popped my trunk because it sounds like a gun going off.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have a trunk popper because I have a hatch.
Rym: But, uh, my brain started to calculate what that was, and it said to me, "All right, Rym.
Rym: I've done some calculations, and if it's okay with you, I'd just like to stop right
Rym: now.".
Scott: Whenever it was, don't step in it.
Scott: That's all that matters.
Rym: My brain said, "Let's just keep walking, and hopefully we'll forget about
Rym: this.".
Rym: And I did forget about it until you brought it up here.
Rym: Yeah, that's doo-doo.
Scott: That was doo-doo in the train station.
Rym: Anyway, instead of talking about my day and the doo-doo, I got something.
Rym: I got to talk about this because it's rare.
Rym: I mean, I read Fark.
Rym: I'm a Farker.
Rym: I used to post on Fark on an hourly basis back when I was in college.
Rym: Now, I post maybe on a weekly basis.
Rym: I don't really post anymore.
Rym: I don't have time for that shit.
Rym: I have a real job now.
Rym: But every now and then, I come across a headline that makes me laugh.
Rym: And every now and then, one of those headlines that makes me laugh causes me to read the article.
Rym: And every now and then, the article is just one of those articles.
Rym: And this is beyond Thing of the Day.
Rym: I got to talk about this.
Scott: I think this might be Darwin Award material, depending on if the subject has reproduced.
Rym: When I was young, I often didn't wear a seatbelt, usually because I'm a good driver.
Rym: And I was driving very short distances with no traffic and broadband.
Scott: I wear a seatbelt if I'm driving out of the driveway into the street.
Rym: Pretty much, though, now, because I live in places where roads curve, and there's deer and stuff, I wear a seatbelt no matter what, because something can happen.
Rym: But there are people who, you know, there's laws in New York.
Rym: You have to wear a seatbelt.
Rym: A lot of places in this country, in the world now, have laws where if you don't wear a seatbelt, you can get pulled over.
Rym: Well, this gentleman was pulled over not once, not twice, but 32 times since February of 2003 for refusing to wear a seatbelt.
Rym: Now, normally, there are two courses of action.
Rym: Course of action number one is...
Scott: Didn't they suspend his license after a point, just that you can't drive anymore?
Rym: No, because it's not a moving violation.
Rym: They probably just kept giving him big tickets.
Rym: I think there's nothing wrong with that.
Rym: It's alright.
Rym: His courses of action were either continue to give the big ol' finger to the police, and pay, well, the finger being keep pulling out his wallet and paying for these tickets, or, I don't know, start wearing his goddamn seatbelt.
Rym: There's a pattern here.
Scott: Well, there's an option of don't pay the ticket.
Rym: Yeah, but you know what?
Rym: That option, that's a road you don't want to go down.
Rym: So, no, he chose not the corners, not the straightaways, but the third path.
Rym: This gentleman made an intricate, fake seatbelt that would lay over his shoulder, so a cop, it would look like he was wearing a seatbelt, but in fact, he was not.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Now, usually the reason people don't wear seatbelts...
Scott: Wouldn't it have been a lot easier just to wear the seatbelt?
Rym: Well, remember, there are two reasons people don't wear seatbelts.
Rym: Reason the first is that they're just lazy, and reason the second is that they're fat.
Scott: Lazy?
Scott: It's hard for me not to put the seatbelt on.
Rym: There was actually an article recently about how there's an inverse relationship between people's weight and their likelihood of wearing seatbelts, because the seatbelts are uncomfortable if you're really fat.
Rym: But this guy was not really fat, and if he's lazy, I'm surprised he went through the effort of making a somewhat intricate system of bullying people into thinking that he was wearing a seatbelt.
Scott: Your explanation of there are only two reasons why people don't wear seatbelts is wrong.
Scott: There must be other reasons people don't wear them.
Rym: Well, regardless, the story was on FARC, so obviously a police officer discovered his cunning plan, and you might imagine...
Scott: Well, you gotta think, if we're telling you that he had a fake seatbelt, they must have found out he had a fake seatbelt.
Scott: If he got away with it, we wouldn't have a news story about it, would we?
Rym: No one who's ever seen a bun yup live to tell about it, but they look like this.
Rym: Oh, well, how do we know they look like that?
Rym: How do you know what a cockatrice looks like?
Rym: How do you know it just looks like some short dude?
Scott: How do you know what the medusa looks like?
Scott: How do you know that it's got snakes for hair?
Rym: Well, you can see the medusa from the back, you just can't look in the eye.
Scott: Yeah, but how do you, you know, you watch, like, Clash of the Titans, and you see...
Rym: Or, you know what, if you make your fucking saving throw...
Scott: I guess, but the saving throw...
Rym: Saving throw against gaze attacks, nonetheless.
Rym: Or was it petrification?
Scott: Perseus couldn't even make the fucking saving throw, he had to use the mirror trick.
Rym: Mirror trick sucks, that's like minus eight to hit, but anyway... So, uh, now I imagine the hilarious conversation between this gentleman and the police officer who discovered his fake seatbelt, but actually, no.
Rym: This gentleman, um, I'm just gonna read a sentence from the article.
Rym: Quote, "His fatal injuries were caused when he was thrown forward onto the steering wheel in a low-impact
Rym: crash.".
Scott: Wear your seatbelt, even if you're driving, like, down your street to your friend's house, not even on any major roads.
Rym: So, dude gets pulled over thirty times for not wearing a seatbelt, makes an intricate device to fake wearing a seatbelt, and then, not too long after, is killed in an accident, where it is clear, according to the coroner, that he would have survived with no injuries, had he been wearing a seatbelt.
Rym: Uh, I think it's sad, but I'll admit that I laughed out loud when I read this article.
Scott: It's sad that someone dies, always, but...
Rym: Um, he was also a meth addict, just to add some, uh...
Scott: That explains a lot there, but, yeah, this is like the least sad death, I think, in the history of the world.
Rym: Nah, Hitler.
Scott: Okay, but...
Rym: Secondly, sad death.
Scott: It's, you know, it's one of the least sad deaths.
Rym: Actually, I gotta say, I finally learned the exact story of how Robespierre met his end, and...
Scott: Robespierre was a jolly fellow.
Rym: Robespierre was probably one of the most pissed off people in the history of pissed off people.
Rym: Good God, did that guy not die with dignity.
Scott: I think if Robespierre was alive today, with his level of pissed offness, he would have been a stand-up comedian, and then killed himself.
Rym: You know, Louis Black, Robespierre.
Rym: Yeah, I can kinda see it.
Scott: That's what I'm telling you.
Rym: Except, but anyway... Louis Black didn't kill himself, yet.
Rym: This isn't, you know, regular radio, this is gig night, so I think that's the end of me talking about that stuff.
Rym: So, uh, anime time?
Scott: I think it is anime time, 'cause it's definitely not comics time.
Rym: Alright, so what's up?
Scott: Alright, so, remember how it was like the end of the world, and in terms of American anime, right?
Scott: We're less time on Anime in the USA.
Rym: Anime in the US, going under.
Scott: ADV had some problems, legal problems, contractual problems with, what, Sojits, or whatever that company is.
Scott: You know, the company that helped them get licenses, and they lost licenses to a bunch of shows, and all kinds of stuff was going on, and people were glooming and dooming, saying, "Ah, the anime industry in the US is dead, no one's buying
Scott: DVDs.".
Rym: And that is all kinda true, I mean, we're not gonna say, "Oh, the anime industry is fixed," but, uh, it's starting to come back.
Scott: No, but remember how, when that news was also happening, one of the things we said, you know, there seems to be a consensus that, you know, there are many problems and things going on, but two contributing things are, one, looking at that list of ADV things that got canceled, right?
Scott: Most of those are things that nobody cared about, and maybe one or two of them were things we cared about, pretty much five centimeters per second, and Project Blue Cheeky SOS, right?
Rym: Project Blue Cheeky SOS, much like Baccano, is one of those shows that has the potential to be one of those shows.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And looking at the list, even ones I didn't care about, you know, I could tell that one's gonna be profitable, that one's not gonna be, et cetera, et cetera, right?
Scott: Well, some of them have been saved.
Scott: ADV managed to save some shows.
Rym: Now, because you have not immediately attempted to kill yourself, I'm assuming that there is good news with Project Blue Cheeky SOS.
Scott: Oh, it couldn't be better news.
Scott: Look at this, right?
Rym: I think it could be better news, because the best news is ADV has already translated it, and they're driving toward our house now with DVDs on gold platters, that they're then going to show to us.
Scott: There could be better news, but this is the news.
Scott: Here are the new ship dates for things that were previously cancelled by ADV but are now not cancelled.
Scott: All right, you ready?
Scott: Shipping on March 18th, Moonlight Mile #2.
Rym: Ah, you know, Moonlight Mile, despite the sheer amount of sex that was unexpected, was actually a pretty good show.
Scott: Yup, shipping on, you know, March 4th, 5 centimeters per second, Canon Volume 3, Amagata 6, Red Garden 4, whatever.
Scott: Shipping on March 11th, Venus vs.
Scott: Virus 3, I'm not gonna read the whole list, all that's important is shipping on March 11th, Project Blue Earth SOS 2, and shipping yesterday, Project Blue Earth SOS 1, yesterday, as in the day before.
Scott: right now, as in probably two days ago, because most of you are gonna be listening to this on Thursday, not Wednesday when I'm recording it.
Scott: Project Blue Earth SOS is probably in Best Buy right now.
Scott: You can go get it.
Scott: You can go on Amazon right now and click Add to Cart with one click, and it will probably be at your house early next week, if not Saturday.
Scott: I suggest you do so.
Scott: Now, the thing is, it's actually, I'm gonna have a tough time, right, because they obviously haven't learned from their mistake of "Why are you releasing all these individual DVDs?
Scott: Just put the box of the whole show out and fuck everything
Scott: else.".
Scott: They haven't learned that lesson yet, right?
Scott: But, Project Blue Earth SOS is a weird one in that it's really not too many episodes.
Scott: It's not like a 26 episode show.
Rym: I would definitely be willing to buy it one episode per DVD.
Scott: It's an OAV, and the first episode is like 45 minutes long, and there aren't too many of them.
Scott: So, should I go out and buy disc one that came out yesterday?
Scott: I mean, if disc two is gonna come out March 11th, that's pretty soon.
Scott: That's like a few weeks, less than a month.
Scott: So, maybe I should go that route on this particular show.
Scott: That might be the way to, you know, because it's such a good show, and I've only seen one episode, and I liked it so much.
Scott: And also, if episode two sucks, I can just sort of stop and not continue buying the other episodes if episode two's no good.
Scott: That might be a good idea, I think.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: But, everyone should buy the first disc, because that's worth having, even if you don't need to see the rest.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: ADV, they managed to save the important show.
Scott: I don't really care about anything else.
Rym: So, in equally important anime news, I'm not gonna dwell on these, because we're gonna wait for a lot more information to come out, and then we'll probably just do a show about this business.
Rym: But, there are two important anime that are gonna be coming out, eventually, in Japan, and I assume the US, because these are shows that did awesomely in the US.
Rym: First off, it looks like, according to the rapper cover of the final volume of the Trigun manga...
Scott: Okay, wait, it's up right there.
Scott: First of all, thank God that fucker is over.
Scott: God damn.
Rym: Are you still reading that?
Rym: Because I like, I mean, the Trigun anime was amazing.
Scott: The Trigun anime is amazing.
Scott: If you don't realize, I say this every time it comes up, but I have to say it every time it comes up.
Rym: This is like top five anime ever.
Scott: I have to say this every time it comes up, even though I'm repeating myself.
Scott: The Trigun manga is bad.
Rym: Well, no, no, no.
Rym: I wouldn't say bad.
Rym: I would say messed up is the proper...
Scott: Terrible.
Scott: Okay, well, actually, the first is two volumes, the gold and the silver volumes, Trigun 1 and Trigun 2.
Scott: Those are actually okay.
Scott: They're average manga.
Scott: If you really like Trigun, get those.
Scott: Trigun Maximum is just terrible and screwed up and crazy batches.
Rym: I wouldn't say it's terrible.
Rym: The only problem with the Trigun manga...
Scott: It makes no sense.
Rym: It's incomprehensible, just random shit.
Rym: You can read a page.
Rym: You will turn the page and read the next page, and you will not be able to figure out exactly what happened between these two pages.
Rym: Or, in fact, you could probably take every fifth page out and just move some pages around.
Rym: I don't think anyone would notice.
Scott: I think they just scramble up the pages is what I think.
Rym: Yashuhiro Naito is a madman.
Scott: Yashuhiro Naito.
Scott: It's not Yashuhiro.
Scott: Yashuhiro is a madman.
Scott: Yes, he is a madman.
Scott: But anyway, I have volume 12 in English, right?
Scott: And I knew there was a 13th volume, right?
Scott: And I'm thinking, well, this has to be pretty much like the end, right?
Scott: And then knowing 14 is the end is like, "Ah, good
Scott: God.".
Rym: But this movie is one of those straight-up movies.
Rym: They don't even really have a title or anything yet.
Rym: It's gonna come out in 2009.
Rym: But the Tri-Gun movie is going to be a completely original story from Naito and Nishimura, who did the original Tri-Gun anime.
Rym: And if this happens, this is gonna be so badass.
Scott: Hey, from what I read, because Tri-Gun movie has been a rumor for a long time, right?
Scott: And I've been thinking recently there's been a definite lack of anime movies that aren't Pokemon, Naruto, One Piece movies, you know?
Scott: So this is really good news on that front.
Scott: And in addition, it seems like, from what I've read, this tiny bit of information that all we have to go on is that they have the right idea and we're not gonna base this on the manga or the anime.
Scott: We're just gonna take the characters people like and the universe and we're gonna make over an hour of animation that will entertain.
Rym: Now, the other thing is that they've got the right people on board here because we've seen the situation where a popular thing Tengi Muyo is taken over by different people who suck and the series just kind of goes downhill in a bad way.
Scott: Wasn't it already at the bottom of the hill?
Rym: Tengi Muyo was a pretty good show when it came out.
Scott: All Tengi Muyo sucks, all of it.
Rym: You suck.
Scott: You suck.
Rym: The original Tengi OAV Ryo Oki and the first Tengi movie are absolutely amazing.
Scott: Why is the original OAV named after the cute animal creature that's the sidekick?
Rym: Maybe you should watch it and find out.
Scott: Maybe I shouldn't because it's terrible.
Rym: I don't get your problem.
Scott: Harem shows.
Rym: Yeah, the first harem show.
Rym: The best harem show.
Scott: Okay, that's like saying the least smelly poop in the train station.
Rym: Let me put it this way.
Rym: Just like slice of life shows, there's a lot of genres or types of shows that are maligned, but independently there are shows in those genres that can be good.
Rym: I think the early Tengi Muyo was actually pretty good.
Scott: Alright, name a good moe.
Rym: I could argue that Lucky Star is pretty good.
Scott: I don't think it's a moe show.
Scott: I think it's a comedy.
Rym: Yeah, but it's got those elements.
Scott: I think it's in the same genre as Genji Ken.
Scott: It just has a different art style.
Rym: Anyway, I'm not going to get into this now.
Rym: You're dumb.
Rym: Tengi's pretty good.
Rym: But also, they're going to make another Slayer.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: I vote Naga the Serpent only.
Rym: What?
Rym: No, the good Slayers was the original TV show.
Rym: The OAV, you know, most of the OAVs were not actually that good.
Rym: Quiet, you.
Rym: And the manga, not so great.
Scott: Every Slayer's OAV, golden.
Scott: Manga I haven't read.
Rym: Have you seen all of the OAVs?
Scott: The vast majority of them, and every one I have seen, classic.
Rym: I don't think they live up to even the shadow of the original TV series.
Scott: The original TV series is pretty good, but OAVs, that's where it's at.
Scott: That's where you get the high comedy, non-stop, hard-hitting action.
Scott: The regular original TV series actually had some seriousness and some fantasy plot going on.
Rym: Yeah, as did the Slayer's motion picture.
Scott: As it did as well, yes, which is also awesome.
Rym: Which, yes, but I think that was better than every OAV.
Scott: Maybe, but Naga the Serpent was in it.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Ah, you see.
Rym: And it had a different tone from every other OAV.
Rym: It was almost completely different.
Rym: It was like a third path.
Scott: Even so, the Slayers where Naga the Serpent is present are superior to the ones where she is not.
Rym: Again, I couldn't disagree more.
Rym: As far as I'm concerned, the original Slayers is such a funny, good show.
Scott: I didn't say it wasn't.
Rym: Plus, you haven't even seen the rest of Slayers.
Scott: I haven't seen The Next or The Tribe, but I saw The Slayers.
Rym: You realize that Next gets less serious, more funny, crazier, and then Try is even crazier still?
Scott: Well, I know about the Claire Bibble action, and I didn't say it's bad.
Rym: You only know about the Claire Bibble, because I talk about it all the time.
Rym: I reference the Claire Bibble more often than I master it.
Scott: Claire Bibble's pretty funny.
Scott: It is.
Rym: You really need to see.
Rym: Anyway, regardless, I'm not going to get into this, but the important parts...
Scott: I'm sabotaging your news.
Rym: The important parts here are that, unlike other franchises, it looks like Slayers has got Watanabe on board and the original studio to pretty much just...
Scott: Shichiro Watanabe?
Rym: Takashi Watanabe.
Scott: Okay, I was going to say.
Rym: And it looks like they're not going to fuck this up.
Scott: Yeah, I don't see how you really could.
Rym: Oh, you could.
Scott: Well, I guess they could, but they haven't made a bad Slayers yet, even, you know, whether you think... You know, I think all Slayers is great, even though I, like, you know...
Rym: Well, I'll say this, a lot of people thought that the second half of Slayers Try really kind of went downhill.
Rym: I kind of agree, but they tried to get too serious and also too crazy.
Rym: It was kind of like the gravitation at this problem, too, where, like, the rollercoaster of funny serious funny serious got way too tall.
Scott: Derailed.
Rym: No, just way too tall.
Rym: Like, wow, that's a scene so sad I'm going to cry.
Rym: Wow, Lina just blew up and in, and then a talking pig, and then something crazy happened.
Scott: Okay, okay, but I guess that may or may not be true.
Scott: Regardless, there have been a... Of all the Slayers that has ever been made, a very small percentage of it is not good.
Scott: So, making more, good chance of being high quality.
Rym: Now, if you've never seen the original Slayers TV series, your homework is to go out and get it.
Scott: That is anime history.
Scott: If you need it convincing, we did an episode on it.
Rym: Not only that, I just want, I'll point out one more time.
Rym: Slayers, the original Slayers is a show where when the heroes confront the bad villain who is going to do the dark ritual to release the big...
Scott: This is your favorite thing in the world.
Scott: The big badness.
Rym: All right, what does he do?
Rym: He says, "Oh, you're
Rym: here.".
Rym: Ah, runs away, locks the door, does the ritual as fast as he can.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And finishes.
Rym: That is what I'm talking about right there.
Scott: I mean, in any other show, it would have been like the good guys come in, they talk to him, they disrupt the ritual, you know, but then he manages to pull the ritual off anyway because the bad guys are dumb.
Rym: But also, this happens pretty early on and there's a lot more stuff.
Rym: Also, I think it was the first show where someone ever took one of those sweat bubbles and tried to kill someone else with it.
Scott: Yeah, it was good.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: Penny Arcade readers are probably aware of this, as are dig people, but in case you're not or you missed it or you just read the comic but not the rants, I gotta talk about this.
Rym: A while ago, we talked about the random Garfield comic strip generator, which just takes three random Garfield panels and prove that randomly assembled Garfields are funnier than anything Jim Davis ever wrote in his sad, sorry life.
Scott: Oh my god, random Garfields are so awesome.
Rym: Well, we have found something, the internet has found something that takes that to the nth degree.
Rym: This is Garfield minus Garfield and what I've learned from this is that if you take Garfield comics, god I'm laughing just looking at these again, and just remove Garfield but leave John in, they move from this level of not funny to a level of hilarity that I almost can't help cracking up looking at these.
Scott: I liked him, especially that one with the pants, that was the best of the bunch, but I still get more laughs out of the random Garfield.
Scott: The thing is, the random Garfield can be hit or miss, but when it's a hit, it's a much bigger hit than this.
Rym: You know what, I patently disagree.
Rym: The random Garfield generator is okay.
Rym: I mean, it's kind of funny, it's usually miss, you really have to go for a while to get a hit, but removing Garfield from Garfield is such comedy gold.
Rym: I mean, the second to last one.
Scott: I think it's comedy silver or bronze.
Rym: This is comedy gold.
Rym: The second to last one, it's John standing there and he's looking down with his slanty eyed "there's something wrong with my pants".
Rym: and then a panel of him not doing anything and he's still looking down at his pants, you can imply that he's looking at some sort of member.
Rym: And then his eyes go wide and that's the end and I cannot express to you how funny this is.
Scott: It's a pretty funny one right there, it's the best of them.
Rym: I don't know, I think the implied suicide in the second one is also really good.
Scott: That's okay.
Rym: And the fervor with which he is reading the newspaper in the first one.
Rym: This is comedy gold and Scott has proven his lack of taste.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Alright, so what do you got for me?
Scott: So because I haven't been internetting as much as I used to, I mean, I can't, I haven't gone to Google Reader, it's probably got like a 10,000 video game newses and 10,000 regular newses, I have no idea.
Rym: 10,000 power curry.
Scott: Actually, let me go to it right now and I'll tell you just how many video game newses I have not read.
Rym: Oh, just be on with it.
Rym: People are waiting for us to talk about Katsucon.
Scott: It just says 1,000 plus because it's gone over the edge.
Scott: Anyway, so because of that, I didn't have a news.
Scott: So where do I go?
Scott: Japanese television, the source of infinite things of the day, of course.
Scott: Basically what we have here is there was a product.
Scott: I can't tell if this is a legitimate product or a joke.
Scott: I think it's legitimate and the product amounts to pretty much just a gold pla- a gold painted plastic bucket thing, right?
Scott: And in each commercial you have these really excited people show you the bucket and then they give you two uses for the bucket thing.
Scott: And like in the first commercial, like someone uses it as a stool and then someone else uses it as like a little tiny bookshelf on their desk.
Scott: And the second one, a guy uses an armrest and a lady uses it as a vase.
Scott: And it's like they- it's just a video and they keep showing you more and more commercials and in every commercial you got two more uses for this crazy bucket thing.
Scott: And actually, you know, wow, this bucket is pretty useful.
Scott: Of course, some of them are- they're pretty- they're stretching it with the uses of the bucket thing.
Scott: But yeah, it's good, funny commercial stuff from Japan.
Scott: You might want to fast forward through it a bit, but it's worth watching, I guess.
Rym: Alright, anyway.
Scott: KatsuKan.
Rym: KatsuKan 14.
Scott: Actually, KatsuKan 14 is weird because I can sum this up real quick.
Scott: I was sick most of the con, but I could tell from my experience when I was out and about, even though I was sick, that the con was super awesome.
Scott: But I don't have much to say because I would spend most of my time in a hotel room in bed.
Rym: And sadly, because Scott was sick, I had to pretty much do double duty.
Rym: because, you know, when we're at cons, kind of like when you do the show, there are things that I do and things that Scott does.
Rym: And we kind of like- the duties are split.
Rym: Like, if you look at the credits of Geeknot, just like, "Rym, producer, Scott, web admin," and we- like, everything's split up.
Rym: And at cons, like, we do all this duty, but I pretty much had to do all of the con bullshit.
Scott: You had to do my duties.
Scott: I had to do the duties.
Scott: Was that what you left the train station?
Scott: That's doo-doo!
Rym: So, as a result, my view of KatsuCon was more- you know, we've talked about this a lot, actually, in other reviews of cons, how there's kind of a- you know, most people go to cons and they only have one view.
Rym: The view of the con goer, like the kid or the mom or the someone who goes to the con to enjoy themselves and go to a con and do all the con stuff.
Rym: But there's all these other kind of ways to experience the con or perspectives on the conventions that are completely different.
Rym: I mean, if you're a dealer, your con looks- feels completely different.
Rym: If you're a staffer, if you're a gopher, if you're the press, if you're the entertainment, all these things, all these ways to experience the con are kind of interesting.
Rym: I kind of want to do a long-running series on getting people who have each one of these perspectives and just interviewing them about it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's like you have an event, but there are many different hats that you could wear at this event.
Scott: You could be the con chair, you could be, you know, everything Rym just said.
Scott: And for each of those people, the same event is a different experience.
Scott: It's like you go to a sporting event, right?
Scott: And the majority of the people there are spectators.
Scott: But what's the sporting-?
Scott: what's the Super Bowl like for the camera guy?
Scott: What's the Super Bowl like for the player?
Scott: What's the Super Bowl like for the coach?
Scott: What's the Super Bowl like for the owner, you know?
Rym: I mean, think about the simple change in perspective.
Rym: A lot of people experience this, you know, in your high school, college, whatever, you got to give a presentation.
Rym: You're so used to sitting at your desk or wherever you sit and, like, you've got this view.
Rym: And a lot of times you're taking notes, you're playing your Game Boy or whatever, and you feel, you know, like you're safe.
Rym: Like, no one's really- but then you actually have to present something or you do something and you get up to the front of the room and you stand where the professor normally stands.
Rym: And the room looks totally different and you realize, like, this totally different perspective on everything.
Rym: And for conventions, at that time, it's a billion.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right, let's talk about what happened to Katsu-kun.
Rym: Yep, well, this Katsu-kun, as a result, we only have one perspective.
Rym: Now, actually, probably next week or whenever we get a chance, I'm going to try to get some of our friends who were at this con.
Rym: We'll talk about this a bit because a lot of them got a lot of different perspectives.
Rym: And I think we're going to have to do a separate coverage of Katsu-kun from everyone else's perspective.
Scott: You want to try that?
Rym: Yeah, we definitely have to.
Scott: We could definitely kill some episodes off that way.
Rym: Because we have exactly one perspective of this con, and that is entertainment, staff, and nothing more.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I didn't do jack or shit at Katsu-kun.
Rym: I spent the whole time doing GeekNights stuff, preparing GeekNights stuff, announcing stuff in the video game room, running tournaments, fetching things.
Scott: Your orange juice is getting warm.
Rym: Hiding in the con suite.
Scott: Yeah, but basically, you know, at Katsu-kun, the last time we were there, there was mad video game room action.
Scott: And basically, this time...
Rym: Well, because last year, we were invited to kind of be, like, guest staff at Katsu-kun by video Katsu.
Scott: Yeah, we're technically staff.
Rym: Yes, now we are, like, full on staff.
Rym: But that time, we were, like, video game staff.
Rym: And they didn't really make us do anything, and we only had, like, two panels to do.
Scott: Yeah, we have a weird status at Katsu-kun, in which we're staff, but no one's our boss, even though technically, I guess, the video game room is our boss.
Scott: But they don't boss us around.
Scott: We sort of do as we please, and people try to please us, but we're staff.
Rym: That's because we're weird.
Rym: It's like at New York Anime Festival, we were guests, and we're kind of straddling that line now, where conventions give us, like, conventions actually give us things that are unexpected.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway...
Rym: But Katsu-kun, like, and I think the funniest thing was that we brought our own personal staff this year.
Rym: Like, we brought the front row crew, our staff, to take care of business for us.
Rym: We had roadies, we had everything.
Scott: And... All we really needed was Pete to help us carry the stuff.
Rym: Well, we used them in the video game room, because actually, Pete and Katsu...
Scott: Well, we didn't use them in the video game room.
Scott: The video game room used him.
Rym: We foisted them off.
Rym: We said, "All right, you guys are going to be staff for the video game room to take care of all the stuff that we would have taken care of last
Rym: year.".
Rym: You know, running tournaments, all that stuff.
Rym: But they don't really have to do anything.
Rym: They could have gotten away with doing nothing.
Rym: But I think they've realized that there's something about being just that one step beyond, like, just past that velvet rope.
Rym: They actually spent the majority of their Katsu-Kan being staff and actually doing work.
Scott: Well, I mean, look at... If I was Pete or Katsu in that position, I would have done the same thing, right?
Scott: You're at this convention, okay?
Scott: You've been to anime conventions before, lots of them.
Rym: You've been to, like, 20.
Scott: And, you know, the things that go on at the conventions are not too exciting for you.
Scott: There were no real, like, events that were, like, you know, really exciting for them, right?
Scott: You go to the dealer's room once or twice, right?
Scott: All your friends are either sick in bed, running events, or an artist's alley.
Scott: Maybe you can go to your friends' events.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, God, I didn't get to hang out with any of my friends at Katsu-Kan, except, like, I ran away.
Scott: I said basically hi to everyone once.
Scott: Like, I said hi to Ananth once, hi to Nuri once.
Scott: You know, it was just like, "Hi, hi, hi, hi, I'm sick, hi, I'm
Scott: sick.".
Rym: The only moment of respite I got in the entire con was Saturday night.
Scott: Respite.
Rym: It's respite.
Rym: After all our business was done was I took Ananth and one of our listeners and Nuri.
Rym: I actually forget the listener's name, but you were totally cool.
Rym: There's a reason I bought you a drink instead of blowing you off.
Rym: And we got drinks, and we hid in the bar, and we actually had a conversation.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Rym: It was crazy.
Scott: But, yeah, you're in that position.
Scott: where what are you going to do with this con?
Scott: You know, you have a staff badge, but no one can boss you around.
Rym: Well, they could if they wanted to.
Scott: They could, but they don't, right?
Scott: You're in the video game room, I guess, nominally.
Scott: You play a bunch of video games, and then you just go like,
Scott: "Huh?".
Scott: And someone comes up to you, and they say, "Hey, do you want to
Scott: work?".
Scott: And it's like, "Huh, I
Scott: could.".
Scott: This is Pete's words I'm taking here, you know.
Scott: So he basically was standing there, and he said, "Huh, I have two choices.
Scott: I could watch other people work or
Scott: work.".
Scott: And, I mean, he's going to be here for three days.
Scott: His choices are stand there and be kind of bored or work.
Scott: So, of course, you're going to work.
Rym: Now, the real moral here is this.
Scott: Working at a con is kind of fun.
Rym: If you've ever thought about, like, either you're getting bored with anime conventions or fan conventions in general, or you've thought about volunteering but never done it, I'm going to say this.
Rym: Being staff at an anime convention is a crazy amount of work.
Rym: I mean, we trivialize it because we've been doing this sort of stuff for so long that even when we do a lot of work at a con, it doesn't feel like a lot of work.
Scott: I've never felt like I've done a lot of work at a con ever because it's so easy or I guess we're really good at it.
Rym: Yeah, because it's really fun.
Rym: That's the thing.
Rym: It is so fun to be staff at a convention.
Rym: I mean, you think, "Ah, I'm going to have to
Rym: work.".
Rym: You, like, stand in there selling registrations to a con, like Otakon, you get to meet, like, four or five thousand people who are going to the con.
Rym: You talk to every one of them for a minute while you give them their badge, and that's kind of cool, and those people actually seem to have a really good time.
Rym: And the way to become a staffer at a con is to either be an entertainer or start out as a volunteer or a gopher, and a bunch of our listeners actually were volunteers at KatsuCon this year, and every one of them said they had an awesome time and someday they want to be staff.
Scott: Yeah, being a volunteer/gopher can suck in some ways because you don't get the privileges of staff as much, you know?
Rym: But if you're not going to be an entertainer or, like...
Scott: If you're not awesome in some other way where you can just become real staff, like, ding, then that's the path you must take.
Rym: And I'll point out that there wasn't actually a ding.
Rym: I mean, we're staff at all these conventions, and that's because we've been doing panels since 2002.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Continuously.
Scott: It's not ding.
Rym: Do you know how many panels we've done at frickin' anime conventions?
Scott: Too many.
Scott: But anyway, so yeah, KatsuCon.
Scott: Let's do a little chronology, just a quick one, right?
Rym: All right, so Thursday morning, we get on the road.
Scott: I'm going to start Thursday morning, get on the road.
Scott: Well, we load the car, we get on the road.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: We got three people, which is good.
Scott: One of those is very strong, which helps, because we have a lot of heavy shit.
Rym: Well, I've been lifting weights.
Scott: No, Pete, not you.
Rym: God, we had this heavy-ass bin full of GeekNights stuff, and we got all our audio equipment and everything, and we can't carry this thing.
Rym: Last year it was even heavier, and we could barely carry it.
Rym: And we're like, "Look how heavy it is,
Rym: blah.".
Rym: Pete picks a damn thing up, like, over his head.
Scott: Of course, even he had... When we actually started carrying it long distances, even he had to, you know, stop and rest, just because of the cumbersome-ness of it, you know, and such.
Rym: We drove to Virginia, took the Metro in.
Rym: If you ever go to Katsucon...
Scott: Maryland or Virginia.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we could have driven to Virginia.
Rym: Other people drove to Virginia.
Scott: That's a little far to drive.
Rym: Yeah, but you do not want to drive to Katsucon directly.
Rym: The parking is insane.
Rym: There's no reason to...
Scott: Yeah, driving into Washington, D.C.
Scott: sucks.
Scott: Parking in Washington, D.C.
Rym: The Metro is cheaper and faster.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: In fact, parking is free at Katsucon.
Scott: We met some people, or we saw some people at a rest stop that were obviously con-goers.
Scott: I think I recognized them from other cons, just the way they look.
Rym: And they actually...
Scott: We saw them at the hotel check-in, you know, and we were carrying heavy things from the Metro.
Rym: We also had the worst-case scenario.
Rym: We got to the platform as a train left.
Scott: Yeah, so we actually, you know, we took the Metro as slow as it possibly could go, you know, carrying a heavy thing, delaying us a lot, and we basically got to the hotel the same time as some other people who drove in.
Rym: Well, actually, we got there quite a bit before them, because they were in line quite a bit behind us.
Rym: Oh, wow, awesome.
Rym: And they left the rest stop well before we did.
Scott: And they weren't carrying heavy things like we did.
Rym: Yes, but yeah, take the Metro, good God.
Scott: All right, so we take the Metro in.
Scott: It sucked to carry the heavy shit, but we got it done, despite sickness.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: We did the same thing on the way back, a little bit better.
Scott: It still sucks, and we still should get a better carrying bucket or something.
Scott: With wheels, maybe?
Scott: I don't fucking know.
Scott: We need to do something about it.
Scott: Anyway, get to the con, check in, video game rooms, looking good.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: I think this is the most telling thing about why Katsucon is so awesome, because GameKatsu, the people who run the gaming at Katsucon, are effectively a completely separate organization.
Scott: We've said this last Katsucon episode.
Rym: Entirely autonomously.
Rym: They all know their shit.
Rym: They're like convention badasses.
Rym: They're even, on their own, putting together their own gaming con.
Rym: We're going to talk about that once it gets closer.
Rym: We're probably going to be there doing stuff, because it looks pretty awesome.
Scott: We talked about all this in the last Katsucon episode, but the arcade cabinets from Videotopia made a comeback, and they were as awesome as ever, most notably Virtua Racing.
Scott: Best racing game ever created.
Rym: Yes, if you want to see a bunch of pictures of us wheeling these things in and setting them up, look at my flicker.
Rym: I got a lot of them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, Satan's Hollow made a notable appearance.
Rym: I got real good at Satan's Hollow.
Rym: We'll talk about that.
Scott: I also played Satan's Hollow, and I did kind of well, but I sucked on the high score list.
Scott: Then, I'm like, "Oh, the
Scott: shield.".
Scott: Right.
Rym: We'll talk about Satan's Hollow, because Peter did some awesome things.
Rym: But I think what's most telling about how awesome the game Katsu staff are is that there was an email in the staff thing, kind of before Katsucon, like, "All right, guys, so you think the video game room will be opened by, I don't know, noon on
Rym: Friday?".
Rym: And the response was, "If it's not ready to go Thursday night, something is seriously
Rym: wrong.".
Scott: And it was ready to go, well, pretty much.
Rym: By like 9 p.m.
Rym: Thursday night, the game room, other than Nintendo's display, which took a while for them to set up, was done.
Rym: We were playing video games.
Scott: Yeah, Nintendo, at this convention, you gotta understand, they had mad Professor Layton marketing going on.
Rym: They had people on Segways going around.
Scott: They had people on Segways rolling around the dealer's room.
Rym: They had people wearing gigantic DS's, and you could play puzzles from the game on them.
Scott: They had this thing that was like projecting onto the floor, and it was a touch interactive floor thing advertising this game in the room that had the arcade cabinets.
Rym: Every time I saw a little kid looking at this thing and enjoying himself, I charged over, jumped on it, made everything scatter, and the kids would always clap and scream and go,
Rym: "Yay!".
Scott: Yup, so basically there was mad Professor Layton going on, and the thing was
Rym: is
Scott: I was going to buy Professor Layton even before I got to the con, and then when I got to the con and saw this marketing, I'm like, "You're making me want to not buy it just to punish you for having all this
Scott: marketing.".
Scott: But I bought it anyway, and we'll talk about it later.
Rym: Yeah, but the video game room was hard fucking core, as always.
Rym: The bag check, which was a difficult issue last year.
Rym: Flawless this year.
Rym: Perfectly.
Rym: There were no problems at all.
Scott: There was a little bit of a line at some busy times, but that was it.
Scott: It was a managed and reasonable line.
Rym: Yeah, and the rock band was going, the DDR was going, the Smash Bros.
Rym: Brawl was going.
Scott: It was going a little bit, a little bit.
Rym: It was going a lot.
Scott: I avoided it.
Rym: I also avoided it, but it was pretty rocking.
Rym: There was a staff and cool people only party at some point where everyone just played Brawl.
Scott: Yeah, basically a web comic artist had brought it and provided it, and they treated it specially as it should be treated, because it needs special treatment when you get a pre-release game like that, but they handled it very well.
Scott: The only thing I could say bad about the video game room was that there was a lack of quality selection in the console room, but whatever.
Scott: What kind of selection do you want?
Rym: Well, the thing is, the people who made that complaint would probably have also complained about Otakon or Ubercon or any other con, because I went around that video game room and there was plenty to play, and every console had a lot of people at all hours.
Rym: I mean, Katsucon, remember, is 24/7 con.
Rym: There were people in that video game room.
Scott: At 3 a.m.
Scott: on Saturday.
Rym: Enough people to where you had to wait in a line to play rock band.
Scott: Oh, you had to wait in line to play rock band at like 4 a.m.
Scott: on freaking Friday.
Rym: Ah, it was hardcore.
Scott: I didn't play it even once.
Rym: We had a pretty cool setup in the room.
Rym: Unlike last year, we actually had a professional setup, so it was really, really easy to play music and generally entertain the room.
Scott: Yup, and there wasn't this clash of loud musics competing with each other, making everyone deaf either.
Scott: It was a very much better setup, and we didn't have those giant projectors to the sides of us.
Rym: Yeah, we didn't get as many projectors as we did last year.
Scott: What was that game that they were playing?
Scott: Pop and music.
Rym: Pop and music is like the stupidest goddamn thing in the world.
Scott: Pop and music is fucking stupid.
Scott: That's all I gotta say.
Scott: Alright, so enough about the video game room.
Scott: Most of what we have to talk about Katsucon is the events that we ran.
Scott: Let's talk about them, and then let's be done with it.
Rym: Alright, first, let's talk a bit about what we did in the video game room, because these are the things that were the unscripted things.
Rym: Last year, too, and I think we're gonna do this forever, you know, we're in the video game room a lot, not so much this year, because Scott was sick, and I was running around dealing with six panels, but we had the Atari 7800 with us, and we had all these arcade cabinets, and last year, randomly, usually at like 2 or 3 in the morning, we'd just say on the microphone to everyone in the room, "Alright, bitches, Street Fighter I tournament, let's
Rym: go.".
Scott: I played, actually, at one point during the con, I just remembered this, I played Street Fighter I single player, and I sort of figured it out, and I went without losing for a very long time against the computer, and then a guy came up and challenged me, and I beat him, and another guy came up and challenged me, and I beat him.
Rym: Were they playing as Ken?
Rym: Because Ken couldn't duck, there was a problem with the controller.
Scott: I think I was Ken.
Rym: So you couldn't hadoken?
Scott: No, I was hadokening.
Rym: Ah, maybe it wasn't broken at that point.
Scott: Maybe, but I was freaking not sucking at every other Street Fighter, and on my first try, one token, I beat a whole lot of people in Street Fighter I.
Rym: But, you know, we had the Rampart tournament last year, and this year, we did not disappoint, despite being tired, I ran, and this went so well, like I cannot express to you how well it went, an Outlaw tournament.
Rym: Outlaw being probably the best game to ever come out in the Atari 2600.
Rym: Uh, maybe.
Rym: The best two-player direct versus game.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: It's just two cowboys fighting, so I announced a...
Scott: They really need to make a modding remake of Outlaw.
Rym: I announced a single elimination game.
Rym: A lot of people signed up.
Scott: We should make an Outlaw Half-Life mod.
Rym: Not only did I run the tournament to completion, not only was it amazing, and not only did we have a large crowd of spectators, because something like that is cool to watch, I did not have to even coach these people to trash talk each other.
Rym: The trash talk was excellent.
Rym: I cannot applaud you people more.
Rym: And furthermore, a good half the people in the tournament were already good at Outlaw.
Scott: Well, there were these two guys who were brothers that had played Outlaw in their youth.
Scott: I think these guys were Otakon related also in some way.
Rym: Yes, it came down...
Scott: I forget their names, though, but I've seen them before at conventions.
Rym: But there were some good people.
Scott: They were really good, and they were the final two.
Rym: Yes, the final round came down to brother versus brother.
Rym: We milled the shit out of that.
Scott: Yeah, they beat me.
Scott: We came close, but he took me out in the semi-final.
Rym: Now, Peter, he was staffing the video game room for Much of the Con, and he decided to go one step further, because we had the music set up, and he had some metal with him.
Rym: So he ran the, I think it was midnight or 2
Rym: a.m.,
Rym: metal hour.
Rym: And during that metal hour, he ran a Satan's Hollow tournament.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: He advertised it all day on the Satan's Hollow machine, and a lot of people showed up.
Rym: I am told it was epic.
Scott: Yeah, I wasn't there.
Scott: I was in bed.
Rym: Also, Pete being somewhat of a sadist, we had
Rym: E.T.,
Rym: the Atari game.
Rym: We put it up a lot, because a lot of people were interested.
Scott: Well, it's a curiosity.
Rym: We kept joking.
Rym: Hey, let's run an E.T.
Rym: tournament.
Scott: I have to say again, you know, E.T.
Scott: is a bad game, but everyone acts like E.T.
Scott: is the worst game ever.
Scott: It is just a terrible game.
Scott: It is not the worst game ever.
Rym: Anyway, so we kept joking.
Rym: Yeah, we're going to run an E.T.
Rym: tournament.
Rym: And some people would go,
Rym: "Haha.".
Rym: And some people would go, "Really?
Rym: When?".
Rym: And those "Really?
Rym: When?"
Rym: people were a little scary.
Rym: But eventually, Pete just decided, "All right, I'm doing
Rym: it.".
Rym: And he ran an E.T.
Rym: tournament.
Scott: How did that work?
Rym: He just had them all play.
Rym: High score wins.
Scott: All right.
Rym: And not only did a lot of people compete, not only was it quite the spectator event, but this little girl who was not even conceived when E.T.
Rym: was shredded and buried in the desert kicked everyone's asses.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Did she know how to play?
Scott: No.
Scott: She's just randomly going around.
Rym: She figured it out because little kids... It's weird how little kids seem to have much less trouble just figuring out old video games than adults do.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: I mean, if I hand, like, someone my age, the controller of Atari, they fall in the pool, they get out of the hole, they fall in the hole, get out of the hole, fall in the hole, say, "Fuck this," and walk away.
Rym: Little kids, much like when I was a little kid, will sit there until they figure it out, and then they'll become the best little kid ever at it.
Scott: That's why we had the mad skills at those NES games like Bionic Commando and Mega Man 2.
Rym: God, I can beat Bionic Commando in, like, 28 minutes straight through.
Scott: I can beat Mega Man 2 pretty much as, I guess, close to as fast as it can be beaten reasonably without some sort of emulator.
Rym: On easy.
Scott: No, on normal.
Scott: It's pretty much eat normal and American mode.
Scott: Nah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: But anyway, aside from that, we ran a bunch of events.
Rym: I'd say about 68% of them succeeded.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: It wasn't total success across the board.
Scott: It was actually kind of weird.
Scott: Let's talk, well, let's, see, the thing is-- Let's do chronological on Friday.
Rym: Chronological, or we could do an order of success, reverse success.
Scott: No, no, let's do chronological.
Rym: All right, so Friday.
Rym: Friday was actually a big night for us.
Scott: All our events were actually, except for one, were late.
Scott: So we had, like, these empty days and then a bunch of events.
Scott: An empty day, bunch of events.
Scott: So first-- And then we had no events Sunday.
Rym: We had the anime match game, which is a perennial favorite.
Rym: We run it at every con we go to, I think.
Rym: I think we're going to be running it at Otakon.
Rym: There's been some interest from events as opposed to panels.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: Because we run this thing pretty solidly at this point.
Rym: We had all new questions.
Rym: They were a huge success.
Rym: The guests on the panel were absolutely amazing.
Rym: It was like the best match game we've ever run.
Scott: It wasn't the best attended match game, even though it was very, very well attended.
Scott: I think we had more people at New York Anime Festival.
Scott: But it was, I guess, game-wise, in terms of the quality of the panel, the quality of the questions, the quality of the answers, the quality of the presentation, the best running of the anime match game we have ever performed.
Scott: The only thing I can say is I wish it would have been two hours and we need a new contestant selection mechanism.
Rym: Yes, we do.
Rym: Because I'm sorry contestants.
Scott: I thought of a few.
Scott: And I think we're going to try them out next time.
Rym: Because I'm sorry contestants who were on the show, if you're listening.
Rym: It was cool and all, but you guys couldn't come up with funny answers at all.
Scott: Yeah, it's like contestants, you were cool people.
Scott: So you were actually a little bit more knowledgeable about anime than some former contestants, so you're not too bad.
Scott: Because the guy said Odongos, right?
Scott: You knew the-- Yes.
Rym: That was actually too hardcore for some of the guests.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But-- And the audience.
Rym: So I had to actually explain what a fucking Odongo was, you people.
Scott: Yeah, but they were not very good at matching the panel.
Scott: They didn't seem to-- It's like if I was-- It was obvious, especially on one particular question, who is the hottest girl in anime?
Scott: It was obvious what answer was going to get you a zillion points.
Scott: Obvious.
Scott: Anyone who was actually conscious and understood what was going on and was paying attention would have gotten it.
Rym: It's kind of like when we were at New York Anime Festival and we had the original voice of Speed Racer on the panel.
Scott: And we said, "Name an old anime," and the guy did not write Speed Racer.
Scott: It's like, "Hello.
Rym: Hello.".
Rym: Yes, God, God.
Scott: Yeah, so--.
Rym: But, you know, actually, you're talking about attendance.
Rym: If you count percentage of Total Con attendees, it was probably equally well attended because there were a lot more people at New York Anime Festival, but-- I don't think there were more people at New York.
Scott: Oh, I guess, technically.
Rym: There were 6,000 and some people at Katsucon.
Scott: Yeah, but that's 6,000 and some people at Katsucon were there from Thursday to Monday, but the people at New York Anime Festival were mostly just there Saturday only and then gone.
Rym: Yes, but that's when we ran our events.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: So it's a tough call.
Rym: The other tricky thing is that usually we run the match game during the day because we've learned from doing all these cons, and Katsucon has proved it.
Rym: What a panel is about has very little to do with how it is attended as opposed to what room it's in, what time it's at, and what else is scheduled at that time.
Scott: And what it's named.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: What it's named on the handheld schedule.
Scott: The description in the con book means almost nothing.
Rym: But the nice thing was, because we ran this match game late at night, we were able to be a lot more risque with the questions, and let me tell you, were the guests a lot more risque with their answers.
Scott: The very first question and the very best answer of the entire match game, Naruto Pregnancy Test.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: And the fact that that kept coming up for the rest of the night.
Scott: It came up one more time.
Scott: It was good.
Rym: Oh man, that was great.
Rym: I'm liking having the daytime events, or the get a whole bunch of people and do a standard panel.
Rym: But I like these late night kind of eerie events.
Scott: I love those late night eerie events.
Scott: I think, next Katsucon, I'm going to actually plan.
Scott: I'm going to come up with some new panels.
Scott: This Katsucon, seeing how things went, maybe part because of my delirium, and because the only thing that I was...
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: You planning panels based on your delirium is like Kazuo Koike writing manga.
Scott: Well, because the only thing I experienced at the con was thinking while laying in bed, sleeping, eating, and running panels, pretty much, with a little bit of Virtua Racing mixed, and Street Fighter 1 mixed in, right?
Scott: I was thinking pretty much just about the panels.
Rym: Also, there was a turnabout, but we'll talk about that Saturday.
Scott: But I think now I have the formula for the awesome panels of the future, and I think it is going to be quite awesome.
Rym: But anyway, so right after that, we had The Late Show, which this was a first for us.
Rym: This was probably our most ambitious attempt yet.
Rym: But sadly, because it was super late at night, there were a lot of people in the audience, but not nearly as many as we had hoped for.
Scott: Well, I think we were also competing with a concert, and yeah, there were not as many people as we had hoped for, but there were enough people.
Rym: 11 o'clock to 1 o'clock is a better time slot for a bigger con.
Rym: Like an Otakon, that would have been one of those packed things.
Rym: But at Katsucon, especially with the dance, which unlike other cons is actually awesome, we had some trouble.
Scott: Well, we were competing with the concert, not the dance.
Rym: Well, there was a dance right after it.
Scott: But remember, we're also competing with the Late Night Video Game Room at Otakon.
Scott: And with sleeping.
Scott: But anyway, I sort of had a little plan for the start of the event, and I was sick, you know, whatever.
Rym: Well, here's the full deal.
Rym: We were sick and tired, but we were okay.
Rym: We were set to go.
Scott: Sick and tired.
Rym: But there were some logistical concerns with the guests we were to have, and as a result, we kind of had to stand up on stage and delay and delay and cover for someone for a little while.
Scott: And then the clever intro that I had come up with like an hour previously couldn't be used because the guest wasn't right there at the beginning, and I couldn't rework it, and I was sick.
Rym: But I'll leave it at this.
Rym: We had Stevie B for most of the show, but for the first half, we had Greg Ayers.
Rym: And let me tell you, I really want to do a full-on better, more well-attended Late Show with Greg Ayers and Steve Bennett again.
Rym: At least because Greg Ayers is a pretty damn cool dude, I have to say.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, the guy, you know, I didn't know much about him at all before, you know, doing the show.
Rym: He put off peeing to be on the Late Show.
Scott: Yeah, big thanks to him because, you know, he skipped.
Scott: He's friends with Johnny Young Bosch, you know, and he was there at the con, you know, Mr.
Scott: Power Ranger.
Scott: And he basically, he didn't go to his friend's concert, which was happening in the other room, and he put off peeing just to be on our Late Show as, you know, he had promised and as was scheduled.
Scott: He didn't have to do that.
Scott: He could have been an asshole, but he came to do our not super well-attended but okay-attended Late Show anyway, and he stayed there and kept answering our questions.
Rym: Yeah, we didn't actually record it, partly because we were incredibly tired and we just didn't have time to set all that up, and also because there was a lot of visual components to it.
Rym: But it was quite an interesting talk for anyone who attended.
Scott: Yeah, I kept asking him questions and he was answering them in a totally cool, open, honest way, like I would have.
Scott: And I don't agree with some of the opinions I learned he has, but it doesn't matter, he was pretty cool.
Scott: And he said cool stuff.
Rym: Yep, and then he finally went off to pee after drinking much of our "orange
Rym: juice."
Rym: It was orange juice.
Rym: And then the rest of the night was with The Depths of Stevie V. And we've talked, I don't need to sing the phrases of having Stevie V at your event at a convention, but we've talked about him before, he's a pretty interesting dude, and we went well into the night learning about Civil War reenactment and the hat story.
Rym: And I think that was a good close for Friday night.
Rym: The people who stuck around to the end seemed to really, really enjoy it, more so than I expected them to.
Scott: Yep, and also Kate, you know, she sang her song.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: It was pretty awesome.
Rym: We had our musical act planned, and it was funny because you could see the audience, like Kate's going out, and Kate's a really, like she knows how to entertain, she learned how to do this stuff in school.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much like we learned computers in school, she learned singing and dancing and all that kind of stuff.
Rym: So, we break for the musical act, and Kate comes out, and you see the audience going, "Ah, some girl, this is like some karaoke
Rym: bullshit.".
Rym: And then she starts with the first verse of "Gotta Knock a Little Harder," and you could see the entire audience go, "Holy
Rym: shit!".
Scott: They're like, "What?
Scott: A real musical act?
Rym: What?
Scott: I didn't realize this was going on.
Scott: What the
Scott: fuck?".
Rym: So, despite being tired and having a lot of logistical issues, we learned a lot, and I think we can pull off this event times a thousand in the future.
Scott: Oh, definitely.
Rym: So, stay tuned for late-night GeekNights, or late-night Katsucon, or late-night something new and improved in the future, because we figured this shit out, is what I can say.
Scott: Yeah, one other thing I had to say about that event is we had Uncle Yo there, right?
Scott: And we promised that we would let him do his, you know, his anime otaku stand-up comedy for a portion of the show.
Rym: There were a lot of timing concerns.
Rym: We had to cut a lot out of the show.
Scott: Yeah, we had to cut stuff out of the show.
Scott: Basically, we made an itinerary for the show, like, you know, this is how long we'll do things, and that totally got blown out of the water.
Rym: Yes, well, you realize, I know a lot about doing panels and giving speeches, and I know a lot about doing a radio show.
Rym: I didn't know jack shit about, like, plotting out and staging any sort of stage performance as opposed to talk.
Scott: Yeah, and sit there and talk for the allotted time is pretty much the limit of our abilities.
Rym: Yeah, we had Emily down there, like, she was queuing us because she actually took charge of a lot of our back-end problems and fixed a lot of things for us, but she was writing, oh, pardon me, like, "15 minutes left for this.
Rym: You got to get him off the stage.
Rym: Stop him from talking so you can have Uncle Yo.
Rym: This is coming up," and writing on the whiteboards from the match game, and that pretty much saved our asses.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I saw Uncle Yo, like, sitting on the side, like, with this box of, you know, props, and I felt real bad.
Scott: I'm like, "I promised you time on the show, but Steve Bennett is still talking about his hat, and I can't stop him, and, uh...".
Scott: But then we got him in at the last minute.
Rym: And I'll just say this.
Rym: Uncle Yo is kind of like, he's kind of new on the anime circuit, and unlike the Geek Comedy Tour, which, they were actually pretty funny.
Scott: Yeah, but they weren't so geeky with their comedy.
Scott: They were geeks doing normal stand-up comedy.
Rym: I don't want to disparage them because they put on a really good show.
Scott: Yeah, I laughed at them.
Scott: They were good stuff.
Rym: I laughed hysterically at a few of those jokes, especially the second Alaska Eye.
Scott: They were on before our anime match game, I think, right?
Scott: Yes, yes.
Rym: But what they do, and this is not in any way going to speak about the level of their comedy, because they're good, but obviously they kind of, they're picking the low-hanging fruit of doing shows because doing a normal stand-up act at an anime con is real easy to get a lot of people to really enjoy
Scott: themselves.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, they weren't, like, professional.
Scott: I'm talking, you know, like, they weren't George Carlin Lewis Black level, you know?
Rym: But they were better than a lot of comedy acts I've seen live in clubs before.
Scott: They were ten times better than Open Mic Night, you know, at the local joint.
Rym: But Uncle Yo does something really different.
Rym: He actually does topical humor about anime and manga.
Rym: And we saw him before, you know, he performed at the New York Anime Festival, and we talked to him.
Rym: We promised him this short gig at Katsucon.
Rym: And, like, you can see him improving.
Rym: Like, his set at Katsucon was noticeably better than his set at New York Anime.
Rym: Like, he's getting better, he's getting good, and we're really trying hard to get him a full-on set at ConnectiCon and Oticon.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, other podcasts may have said that, you know, like, they saw him at New York Anime Festival, and they thought he was lame, and they didn't laugh.
Scott: And, you know, I'll be honest, you know, I have nothing against the guy.
Scott: You know, I met him, he's cool, he's sociable, he's a nice person, you know, and he's trying hard and such, but I didn't laugh at him.
Scott: I didn't think he was funny that much at New York Anime Festival either.
Scott: Maybe, you know, it's just not my thing, kinda.
Scott: And also, my number, actually, the only gripe I actually have with him is that he pronounces a lot of things incorrectly.
Scott: But, you know, no matter what you can say about the guy, he got the audience, really likes it.
Rym: The audience was going crazy.
Scott: So, whether, you know, you think he's funny or not, it worked.
Scott: And even if I didn't think he was funny, and actually, he was kinda funny this time compared to the New York Anime Festival.
Rym: I like to say, I really liked his bit about, like, Shonen manga versus shoujo manga.
Rym: That was a really well-put-together bit.
Scott: Yeah, that bit I actually laughed at, you know.
Scott: And, you know, regardless of that, even if I thought he was a bastard and I thought all his comedy was lame, which I don't, I would let him on any panel I was doing.
Scott: I'd give him time, because freaking, it makes the audience laugh.
Scott: And if he's associated with me, that makes me look good, too.
Rym: So, if you're at a con and you see Uncle Yo, it's worth your while to check him out.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But, moving on to Saturday.
Rym: Now, this is the panel.
Rym: I submitted this because, you know, I handle all the PR, producer kind of stuff.
Rym: So, I get all the panels at cons.
Rym: I do all that business.
Scott: It was our only morning panel.
Scott: Well, it was the noon panel, right?
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: So, noon Saturday is apparently a great time for panels.
Scott: Oh, definitely.
Rym: But, I put this panel in.
Rym: I didn't even tell Scott about it until after I put it in.
Rym: And he's like,
Rym: "What?".
Scott: I thought you didn't put it in.
Scott: I thought you said the con gave it to you.
Rym: No, I put it in because I knew.
Scott: Oh, you suck.
Scott: You didn't...
Rym: And then I had to lie to make sure you do the panel.
Rym: So, I put in this panel, "Anime You Should
Rym: See.".
Scott: So generic and bleh.
Rym: Well, my thinking was, we're badasses at this.
Rym: I've been doing panels forever.
Rym: And my panels are almost always super well attended and super awesome.
Rym: And people always super, super, super like them.
Rym: So, I realized we could do a panel like this trivially with no effort, no preparation.
Scott: Yeah, because it's so... But, it seemed like, you know, "Anime You Should
Scott: See.".
Scott: I mean, come on.
Scott: You go to an anime con and you go to a panel where people say, "This is the anime you should
Scott: watch.".
Rym: But, you know what?
Rym: The importance of a panel like that is that most people who go to anime cons have not seen a lot of anime yet.
Rym: They don't have local anime clubs.
Rym: They have no real way to know what's good, what's not.
Rym: And they don't watch a lot because, you know, a lot of things are bad.
Rym: It's hard to get the good stuff.
Rym: So, much of the panel, I mean, much of the audience had never seen "Cowboy Bebop" or
Rym: "Escaflowne.".
Scott: Yeah, we asked.
Scott: Like, who here has seen "Cowboy
Scott: Bebop?"?
Scott: And about half, maybe a little 49%, something like that, had seen the show and the other half hadn't.
Scott: And I'm like, "What the
Scott: hell?".
Scott: You're such an anime fan that you come to an anime convention for an entire weekend and you haven't seen "Cowboy
Scott: Bebop.".
Rym: See, now you can't malign these people because they came to the anime convention because they like anime and they want to learn more about it.
Rym: So, you can't be a snob and say, "All right, you shouldn't have those generic
Rym: panels.".
Scott: I can't, but think about that.
Scott: That's like, that's so crazy.
Rym: No, because, I mean, think of it.
Rym: You just got into anime.
Rym: You saw two good shows.
Scott: But people didn't just get into anime.
Scott: If you're going to anime cons, you have to be into anime for a while.
Rym: A lot of people just get into anime and then, like, a year later, they see, "Oh, there's anime
Rym: cons?".
Rym: You know what?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Next con, we're going to ask how long people have been anime fans for.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: This is what I have to learn.
Rym: I asked that at a lot of panels I run in other conventions and most people at most conventions I talk to, it's their first anime con and they've been watching anime for maybe a year.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But this panel, we need panels like this because a lot of these people, and a lot of people, like, talk to us afterward, they went out and watched this stuff and they're, you know, they never would have thought to watch Cowboy Bebop, but we told them about it.
Rym: We said it was good and now they're going to go out and see it and they're going to kind of step up their anime fandom and learn more and spread out and branch out.
Rym: And we basically just talked about all the must-see amazing anime out there.
Rym: We got the audience up.
Rym: It was real kind of informal.
Scott: Yeah, all we did was sort of sit around and talk about anime we liked for an hour.
Rym: Talk about a standing room only.
Rym: No one wanted us to leave the room.
Rym: We could have stayed in there for three more hours and no one would have left the panel.
Scott: I couldn't have stayed there for three more hours.
Scott: It was my disease.
Rym: But the audience could have.
Rym: That panel was like, people fucking loved it.
Scott: And then we took this bit that we had prepared for the Late Show.
Scott: that we didn't use at the Late Show because we ran out of time.
Rym: I'm not going to say what it was because we're using this bit again at Otakon and then we sort of just hamfisted the bit into this unrelated panel just to kill time.
Scott: And it totally worked.
Rym: Yeah, you know, there's something good about when you finish your event.
Rym: One, the best part is, is Nick, the T-1000 Robocop.
Scott: Okay, I got to say this now, right?
Scott: Most of the time we go to conventions, big or small, right?
Scott: You know, ConnectiCon, all they really did for us at ConnectiCon was they gave us an itinerary and they would check in on the panels a little bit, right?
Scott: At Otakon, we have to check in with them.
Scott: We have to do our own panels.
Scott: No one comes to help us.
Scott: The tech people, you can't even find them, really.
Rym: That'll probably change this year.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'm not saying it's the--.
Rym: Well, no, there's a lot of news about panels at Otakon this year, but we'll talk about that next week.
Scott: But the thing is, is that pretty much, as panelists at many conventions, the conventions don't help you out that much.
Scott: They might not even make sure you run the panel.
Scott: I've never even had anyone, like, really come and make sure that I was running the panel.
Rym: Well, remember, the first three panels I ran at anime cons were literally the people who were supposed to run the panel weren't there, so I walked up to the front of the room, pretended I was them, and ran the panel.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: At Kotacon, mostly thanks to Nick Ferris and his crew, you know, in the live events organization there at Kotacon, they were so checking up on us, making sure everything was working, making sure we had everything we needed, you know, coming into the panel room when there were five minutes left and holding up.
Scott: They had the big number five written on an orange piece of paper on the back of all their binders.
Rym: I gotta tell you, that dude, Nick Ferris, he would appear out of nowhere.
Rym: Like, if you had a problem, like, you're standing in a room like, "All right, there might be too big a crowd, I need a problem with this,".
Rym: it'd be like, "Zoop!
Rym: Do you need any help,
Rym: Rin?".
Scott: He just--.
Rym: This guy was, like, the badass of running con panels.
Scott: Dude was everywhere, making sure everything was working just fine.
Rym: And I just gotta say, the thing about Kotacon, dude actually was recognized for being a badass at the staff party by the senior staff.
Scott: Oh, yeah, dude, total badass, total amazing.
Scott: I mean, as a panelist, there is nothing that is better for you, that nothing you could appreciate more than the staff who are sort of handling the logistics of panels at the convention, sort of making sure your shit is good and checking up on you.
Scott: Even if you don't need anything, just them being there is like, "Ah, okay, shit's going right.
Scott: You know you're in the right place, you know it's the right time, you know--".
Scott: Just that reassurance is all you need, and they provided it more than any con ever.
Scott: But that event went crazily awesomely well, like standing ovation-- Surprisingly well, I wasn't expecting much out of it yet.
Rym: I wouldn't be surprised if every single person in that room listens to GeekNights after that.
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: Because-- If they connected it to the GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah, but, well, we gotta get a smaller banner, because our banner's a little too big to carry around.
Scott: Yeah, get it.
Scott: We need a smaller one.
Scott: that's good for tables at the panels.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: But then, later that day, we ran Challenger on Fire.
Rym: This is our third attempt at running Challenger on Fire.
Scott: I think we're retiring Challenger on Fire.
Rym: I've got-- I think we can-- I think it can be pulled off.
Scott: I don't think it's worth it.
Rym: I'm talking to Otakon.
Scott: I don't want to have it bomb at Otakon.
Rym: No, I think it could, because the thing is, all it needs is one, it needs a very large audience.
Scott: It does need-- it doesn't work without a large audience, that's true.
Rym: And with a large audience, pursuant to that, we would need-- I mean, we-- you know, we got, like, two guests from the con.
Rym: I realize now that what we actually need are, like, 20 guests from the con, and, like, 20 pre-selected con-goers who have taken a test to prove that they have the minimum skills it takes to be on this event.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This has to be, like, a main event's event, or it can't be done.
Rym: But we've got all the technology together.
Rym: The only thing we're lacking is a con that is willing to take a risk on giving us the full deal.
Rym: Because I think we can pull it off.
Rym: We've learned everything you can learn about running this event.
Scott: I think the biggest problem with this event is that the name, "Challenger on Fire," right, is that-- you know, that's what you have to get people to come to your event.
Scott: Oh, we're renaming it.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think people just-- you see "Challenger on Fire," they go, "What the fuck is
Scott: that?"
Scott: and they don't come.
Scott: And I think-- Well, no, the sad thing is, actually-- Yeah, oh, that's true, that's right.
Rym: "Challenger on Fire," no one came.
Rym: We're like, "Ah,
Rym: shit.".
Rym: But we ran it an hour early because of a rescheduling.
Rym: So we ran it to a very, very small audience.
Rym: It was laid back.
Rym: It was really fun.
Rym: People enjoyed it, but it was not the event it should be.
Rym: I consider it a failure.
Rym: But right at the end-- All our friends showed up.
Rym: Not just all our friends.
Scott: And all our listeners.
Rym: But, you know, all the people who had seen all our other panels and realized that the stuff we were doing was good, they all kind of came into the room expecting "Challenger on Fire," and we had to announce to all of you who came in, "Challenger on Fire" is now over because you didn't check the con errata and realize that we were rescheduled.
Scott: Yeah, I definitely think what we should do at cons, right, if we can somehow control our panel scheduling, right, I want to have early in the con, I want to run panels that'll get lots of people, right, then impress upon them that it's us doing these panels and let them know about the panels they're doing later, and later in the con do awesome panels, and those people, you know, we can sort of get them to attach to us and come to all of our events when they recognize that we're awesome.
Scott: Because it already worked.
Rym: I mean, the Gekiga panel, just because it was late at night, probably wouldn't have a lot of people, but-- It was super late at night.
Scott: Almost everyone-- I literally was sick in bed, got up out of bed, walked to the Gekiga panel, walked back into bed.
Rym: Almost everyone who went to that panel was someone who came because they had seen another one of our panels.
Scott: And we had told them at that panel that we were doing the Gekiga panel.
Rym: And let me tell you, that panel was amazing.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if we're going to do the Gekiga panel too many more times, I think it needs a little change-up, we're going to do something different, but that was actually not-- I was sick, I had just gotten out of bed and was going back to bed, I didn't say half the stuff.
Scott: I usually say at the Gekiga panel, it was a pretty, you know, poor showing.
Scott: Well, the thing is, considering how-- I think it was a success anyway.
Rym: Oh, it went super well, the audience frickin' loved it.
Rym: And also, I would think that if we ran it again at Otakon, I think it would go over really well.
Rym: And I'm going to see about that, because-- I don't want to run it again at-- we already ran it at Otakon, Yes, however, it is very different now.
Scott: Yeah, I think we should change it to something else at Otakon.
Scott: Maybe we should make it like a Sanctuary Only panel or something like that.
Rym: Sanctuary?
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: But suffice to say, we ran the Gekiga panel, and it was super, super awesome.
Scott: Yeah, now I gotta mention this, right?
Scott: There was a guy-- when we were at the Animation C panel, right?
Scott: We thought, you know, we didn't know where we were going with that panel, it was kind of freeform, right?
Scott: So we were thinking, "Hey, what we'll do is we'll bring people up, we'll ask them what shows they've seen and what shows they like, and then we'll tell them what shows are good for them to see that they haven't seen.
Scott: And we'll just do that to a bunch of people, and that'll be what we'll do,
Scott: right?".
Scott: Well, we brought up one guy, this bearded guy-- Totally randomly.
Scott: Rym was like, "We need a guinea
Scott: pig.".
Scott: A bunch of people raised their hands, Rym picked Bearded Guy.
Rym: I was like, "Uh,
Rym: you.".
Scott: You, Bearded Guy.
Rym: Alright, Bearded Guy, I forget your name.
Rym: You were pretty damn cool and knew--.
Scott: Let me tell you how cool Bearded Guy was, sorry.
Rym: One Bearded Guy had seen all the anime that's worth seeing already.
Scott: Right, right, right.
Scott: Let me tell you, alright?
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: First of all, sorry Bearded Guy, I don't know your name, and you'll have to email it to us.
Scott: I know you're listening, by the way.
Scott: Bearded Guy comes up, we talk to him just a little bit, and that sets off the Anime You Should See panel, and we don't need any other guinea pigs because he's so awesome, right?
Rym: Of course, we're like, "What kind of shows do you
Rym: watch?"
Rym: Expecting, you know, some fan to say, "I watch Bleach," or whatever.
Rym: Any names have the shows that we were going to talk about.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Secondly, the guy comes to the Gekiga panel, right?
Scott: At the Gekiga panel, I mentioned the Will Eisner, of course, as you must, right?
Rym: Because, you know, we're talking about, like-- We're talking about the god of Japanese comics, and then-- Like, Gekiga was to manga what graphic novel is to comic.
Scott: Sort of, in a way.
Scott: But, you know, and he asked, like, "Was this sort of like, you know, the R. Crumb
Scott: deal?".
Scott: And I'm like, "Yes, it's sort of like
Scott: that.".
Scott: But he knew the deal.
Scott: And, when I mentioned Will Eisner, he threw at us a button with a spirit on it.
Scott: And I'm like, "What the fuck?
Scott: Who in an anime convention has a button with a spirit on it, other than a cool
Scott: person?".
Rym: Other than Bearded Guy.
Rym: So, Bearded Guy, my hat is off to you.
Scott: Bearded Guy had friends, too, right?
Scott: And they were all pretty cool.
Scott: Bearded Guy is even more awesome.
Scott: You ready for how awesome Bearded Guy is?
Scott: Okay, so Bearded Guy, I'm talking to him after the Gekiga panel.
Scott: Still, I'm about to go-- I'm basically at the stairs, ready to go back to the room and go to bed.
Scott: And he's telling me how he has a cyber cafe.
Scott: He owns a cyber cafe in Virginia somewhere.
Scott: And he plays GeekNights on the radio in the cyber cafe every night.
Scott: How awesome is that?
Scott: So, hello, cyber cafe people in Virginia.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: What's up?
Scott: I think-- Look at Bearded Guy, who's over probably by the counter making coffee or whatever.
Scott: That's Bearded Guy.
Scott: He's cool.
Rym: Now, Bearded Guy, I think we want to get him on the show.
Rym: I just want to talk to him.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Maybe as a guest host, even.
Scott: Guys, guys, way cool dude.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Knows.
Scott: Will Eisner goes to KazuKan, comes to our panels, has cyber cafe, plays GeekNights at cyber cafe.
Rym: Has the spirit pin cocked, loaded, and ready to throw.
Scott: Yeah, it had more of them.
Scott: I was like, "Do you want this
Scott: back?".
Scott: And he's like, "No, I got
Scott: more.".
Scott: All right.
Scott: Doesn't get much cooler than that.
Rym: All right, I hate to say this.
Rym: We've gone long a bit, I think.
Scott: Quite long.
Rym: So, I think what we're going to do is this weekend, we're going to finish our KazuKan coverage and put it up in the Wednesday feed.
Rym: Because Scott's still coughing, we all still have a lingering sickness, and my Swiss steaks are almost done.
Scott: All right, we haven't eaten dinner yet.
Rym: I have not even talked about half of what I have to say for KazuKan.
Scott: I don't really have that much more to say, because I was sick in bed most of the time.
Rym: Well, I went around the con and did stuff.
Scott: I can talk about the dealer's room and the artist's alley, I guess.
Rym: So, wow, we pretty much reviewed GeekNights at KazuKan.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Rym: At some point this week, we will continue with another good hour of KazuKan coverage for KazuKan.
Scott: All right, but next Wednesday, I think we should return to Anime Manga Comics.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Also, there's a lot of news about Otakon I really got to talk about.
Scott: Good news.
Scott: That is your news next Wednesday.
Rym: All good news.
Rym: Otakon is moving in a direction that is, ah, I cannot express to you how happy I am with Otakon right now.
Scott: Well, that'll be your news next Wednesday.
Rym: But I have one last thing to say.
Rym: We'll talk about this again later in the week and next week.
Rym: If you went to KazuKan, go to the KazuKan website.
Rym: On the front of the KazuKan website, there's a KazuKan 14.
Scott: We should have said this at the beginning of the show.
Rym: But I'll say it again in the next show.
Rym: A KazuKan 14 attendee survey.
Rym: Now, every con should have this exact survey.
Rym: This is like the best convention survey ever.
Scott: Technologically and survey-wise.
Rym: They ask the right questions.
Rym: So if you were at KazuKan, fill this survey out.
Scott: Fill it out?
Scott: Honestly.
Scott: Honestly fill it out.
Rym: Because they, all this can do is make KazuKan a better con.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And I'll point out that I asked for Kazu Koike and Ryuichi Ikigami to be guests.
Scott: Me too.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights.
Rym: And Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "Send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.