Rym: It's Monday September 29th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about the cloud buzzword computing.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Hey Rym, you know what today is.
Rym: What is today?
Scott: It's your favorite holiday Monday Rosh Hashanah, oh Okay.
Scott: Yeah now you can eat.
Scott: your eating of honey on challah will be appropriate.
Rym: So what's wrong with the fact that I eat milk and honey and challah only without the milk?
Scott: There's nothing wrong with it, but it's sort of it's like if someone ate a green bagel, but it wasn't st.
Scott: Patrick's Day.
Scott: That's what it's sort of like.
Rym: It's I think it's more like eating cake when it's not your birthday or anyone else's birthday.
Scott: No, that's okay.
Scott: You can eat cake all the time.
Rym: But so you realize honey on bread has been a staple of non Jewish people for a long time.
Rym: The Greeks would eat honey without even the bread.
Rym: They just need honeysuckle.
Scott: Yeah, but because it's Rosh Hashanah, you have to get around challah.
Scott: You can't get the normal braided one.
Scott: You have to get around.
Rym: why would I do that?
Rym: I like the braided ones.
Scott: I'm just saying that's what the holiday is What I don't have a holla Gonna do.
Scott: you should go get one.
Rym: I didn't get one shit.
Scott: You're fucking it all up.
Rym: Actually, the reason I didn't get one is because I got a beard popper, right and I thought I'd bring one home to Emily.
Rym: So I was like, alright and I bought two and I ate one and I put the other one in the fridge.
Rym: And then I you know, I'm working a little late.
Rym: But when I say I work late, that means I worked like two minutes late.
Rym: So it's like oh crap gotta go.
Rym: so I walk out the door and I get to the elevator.
Rym: I'm like no my beard papa.
Rym: So I walk halfway back to my office and then I'm like shit.
Rym: now I won't have time Indecision.
Rym: and I just went back to the elevator and I went down barely got on my train.
Rym: then I'm like, ah I wanted a loaf of bread.
Scott: Yeah, I'll get some breads tomorrow.
Rym: Maybe maybe actually no, I just bought a loaf of bread.
Rym: We've got two loaves of normal bread now.
Scott: Yeah, there was a thread in the forums.
Scott: I started right about bread.
Scott: No, I was writing a post in it and then a post about.
Rym: I can't think of any synonym that rhymes with post.
Rym: That means bread.
Rym: I don't know host host like in Catholic Church About host.
Rym: I'm on a roll.
Rym: You realize that I just needed to read jokes that I could then say I'm on a roll.
Rym: Realize how wonderful that was to actually pull that off.
Rym: No, I don't think you understand.
Scott: He throw me off.
Scott: I was writing a post in the forums.
Scott: I got distracted and then I didn't realize it was time to leave work and I saw the clock.
Scott: I said, oh shit I just deleted the post and didn't post it.
Rym: You know, actually someone who in the forum read and posted forever they posted.
Rym: I've noticed we get a lot of people who join the forum and they like don't post for like four or five months.
Rym: then suddenly they start posting and one of them basically said yeah, actually I've started a lot of posts and then I Look at it and then I just decide it wasn't worth it and then halfway through I just click back.
Scott: Actually, my post was worth it, but I feel like it's too much.
Scott: I don't I don't want to type at all.
Rym: Well, I realize one I do that with about half the thing.
Rym: half the time I start to respond to something in the forum I'll get halfway through it.
Rym: then just go a fuck it and close the tab.
Scott: a couple other items of interest, right?
Scott: I was for people who don't know Commerce Bank, I don't know if there's a Commerce Bank near you, but there's some in Manhattan, right?
Scott: They have a machine called the penny arcade.
Scott: if I mentioned this on the show before I think you did once a lot.
Scott: I mentioned it not on the show, but I you know mentioning on the show just for good measure a second time maybe.
Scott: And the penny arcade not related to the webcomic is basically a coin star machine.
Scott: You dump change in it and then they give you a receipt and then you get cash for your receipt Right.
Rym: Well, there's a cat or a check.
Rym: There's a catch.
Scott: What's the catch?
Rym: They don't take any of your money.
Scott: Exactly yeah, unlike a coin star machine which takes money, you know charges a fee or you know forces you to get gift cards if you want all your money.
Scott: or Other banks which will only accept change if you roll it up and only accept change, you know If you're a have an account there man The Commerce Bank lets you just anyone just dump change it in the machine and convert it.
Scott: I went into the bank today and I said is this for real?
Scott: and there was a person there and then she was all nice And she was like, yes, it's totally for real.
Scott: So tomorrow I'm gonna bring an entire gallon of change down.
Scott: wait tomorrow.
Rym: You've been saying you're going to do this for like a year.
Scott: I'm doing it tomorrow.
Scott: cuz I'm it's full I can't fit any more change in it.
Scott: I have to do it tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, I guess my problem is I have a much larger thing to put change in.
Scott: you're gonna carry that to the city.
Rym: No, it's already too heavy.
Scott: We can carry it together.
Rym: Also at now that I've been reading the life and times of Scrooge McDuck.
Rym: I kind of don't want to ever get rid of it.
Scott: Well, you see yeah, you got it.
Scott: If Scrooge is alive today, he would have dumped it in the machine.
Scott: He would have just you know You would have gone specifically to that machine because it's such a long trek carrying a heavy thing.
Scott: hard work To get it converted.
Scott: and then you know, put it somewhere where it gets interest.
Rym: No, you wouldn't have because it depends if those coins all meant something.
Scott: Yeah coins mean something Couple do?
Rym: there's one sacajawea in there.
Rym: like sacajawea is there's a couple of wheat pennies.
Rym: I really like wheat pennies.
Rym: Like I I don't collect them, but I have a whole bunch of them.
Scott: I wonder if that machine is actually gonna work with dollar coins because I got a few in there.
Rym: The scary thing is because there might even be a half dollar in there how lazy I am when it comes to my pockets.
Rym: So when I get home I basically empty the money contents of my pockets into that thing and it often includes like fives and tens.
Rym: Because you know, I'm in a hurry all the time in the city.
Rym: So I'll get like a bagel.
Rym: I'll pay with a 20 I'll get change.
Rym: I'm in a hurry.
Rym: So I take the change to throw it in my pocket.
Rym: Then I can help when I throw it in the bin.
Rym: So Sometimes I'll be like, ah, I don't want to go to the ATM.
Rym: So I open that thing.
Rym: There'll be like three hundred dollars in like bill change in there.
Rym: I pull it out and use it.
Rym: the thing.
Rym: I feel like I've gotten careless with money.
Scott: Yeah, yeah The only light the only final item of note is the Mets are done.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, they are they.
Scott: they said they sucked it up which is a Classic.
Scott: consider, you know, if you know the Mets it's sort of like sort of poetic.
Scott: It's like how it's supposed to go to.
Scott: the thing is totally sucking it up.
Rym: There's a difference between the Mets sucking it up where People kind of thought like.
Rym: people thought maybe they had a chance but then after they lose in retrospect They're like, yeah, they never had a chance.
Scott: The Mets have always been sort of like, you know the bums and then you know They sort of more recently have been trying to be the Yankees of the Red Sox.
Scott: You know the teams that spend a million dollars to get good players and win and two years in a row It hasn't worked.
Rym: I much prefer the team.
Rym: In fact, it's failed spectacularly to use where the idea of a fairweather fan Could not possibly exist.
Rym: I mean, yes, I'm a fan of the Detroit Lions.
Scott: They're worse this year than ever.
Scott: Well, the thing is, you know, they've only been in one playoff game since the late 50s.
Scott: Yes, I realized that I don't think they won that play.
Rym: if the Lions did better than they do now I would not be a fan of them.
Rym: I would only be a fan.
Rym: It's pretty much if they're a great team I'd be like.
Rym: I'd be really excited about him because I like having like the Red Wings.
Rym: like they're a great team They're always in contention for the Stanley Cup.
Rym: They're always like a dangerous team and if they don't win the Stanley Cup every year They always get close and it's always really dangerous when you're playing against them.
Rym: and I like that and I also like a team That's like underdog scrappy.
Rym: I hate it when a team's just mediocre like they just lose a lot But they don't lose enough to where losing becomes like a thing like yeah, the Lions are playing.
Scott: I'm more, you know, I don't like a team that just wins all the time.
Scott: But I tell you Giants doing so all right now not not gonna not gonna complain not complaining but if they'll be really I think what you really I think is most important in choosing your team is Sort of like for me.
Scott: It's like the history of the team.
Scott: Yes Losing I can't get it.
Scott: Well, it has to just be a deep history.
Scott: one of those like I can't like like an expansion.
Scott: Dean has been around for ten Years, whatever easy story about them.
Scott: Like maybe they were founded by God maybe but you know, it's like Mets.
Scott: You know been around for like, you know since the early 60s.
Rym: It's pretty old early 60s shah the Red Wings are the oldest continuous hockey franchise in the NHL.
Rym: Yeah, so Rich history there.
Rym: They they used to play in the Coliseum which as my dad would tell me had lots of Christians and Lions was.
Rym: so I see what you did there.
Rym: Basically.
Scott: It was very tall and The top seats you almost be like leaning over this day were just like these square stone things that It's a really long and round ish kinda.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, they didn't really have ice back there and the Commissioner would give a thumbs up or a thumbs down.
Scott: Well, you know, there's no gold judge.
Rym: at the time They just basically wasn't hockey so much as they just killed each other.
Scott: Yeah, so like that.
Scott: No, isn't that what hockey is?
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I gotta say while I prefer modern hockey There's something about watching an old hockey game with those leather skull caps and they basically the goalie is at risk for his life at every second and A lot of goalies got killed.
Scott: Yeah Okay, just to wrap this wrap up the opening bits and get to the real bits with the hockey, right?
Scott: The Rangers are currently in Europe playing some Europe teams before the season starts And they they played a bunch of preseason games before they.
Scott: they you know We they they left for Europe if you didn't notice all those people with Rangers jerseys when he went to the YAF Right and calling it the YAF from now on it.
Scott: Yeah You're a Canada festival.
Scott: Yeah, they lost every preseason game so far and they're playing Detroit once this year in Detroit.
Rym: I know you realize if they go I always miss.
Rym: the time the Red Wings will come to New York and play them is the Time I'm going to pay whatever it takes to be there.
Scott: and you've never been to Madison Square Garden anything now the greatest indoor Basketball and hockey facility in the world, but then again, it lacks something very important.
Rym: You see the Joe Louis arena as I am often Likened to say does not have a statue of Joe Louis.
Rym: out in the front of it It has a statue a gigantic statue of Joe Louis's fist.
Scott: That's all right.
Rym: It's pro.
Rym: it's possibly the best statue in the world.
Scott: Madison Square Garden has.
Rym: I like to call it the big O.
Scott: Madison Square Garden has a whole train station, but it doesn't have a giant fist.
Scott: Well, he can go see some boxing down here and it sometimes Lots of fists.
Scott: All right Let's get to the tech.
Rym: All right, so, you know, it wasn't that long ago We talked about how Apple apparently hates podcasting and they did that thing where they basically there was an app that did exactly what everyone who has an iPhone wants.
Scott: and then Apple said well it did it mostly because it The only problem with it it didn't integrate with the built-in iPod function.
Rym: No, but it.
Rym: but that's see that's the point Basically, it did the one thing that the iPhone built-in iTunes thing doesn't do Yeah, and then Apple said no you can't have it because it competes with an existing function.
Rym: But obviously that's bullshit.
Scott: and I asked the guy who made it and he said he wouldn't get an interview with us.
Scott: But then he didn't email me back.
Rym: But I thought you know that was crap.
Rym: and you know We had a lot of speculation as to why.
Rym: and then a couple other apps like big apps that did similarly important things got rejected.
Rym: Meanwhile as someone aptly pointed out on slash dot man I feel like I should just make you know a flashlight app because there's like 50 of those And they all seem to make money.
Scott: yeah, this is this is the problem that's going on.
Scott: is you have a situation in which Apple has provided this channel and through which You can make a lot of money but because of the way they you know, the channel is closed, right?
Scott: People aren't willing to sort of put in a big an investment in making something actually interesting because anything interesting is not allowed.
Scott: It's very difficult to make anything interesting because you can't get any help because the NDA and we can't figure out why Apple's making the arbitrary decisions.
Rym: they are because they don't have to tell us and they won't tell us Yeah, and it's like you make this big expensive app.
Scott: It took you like months to make and lots of money paying developers, you know, and then Apple at the last second could just say Yeah, you know, we're not gonna let you put it on there.
Scott: and then you just wasted all that time and money.
Scott: So no one's gonna gamble on it now.
Scott: I wouldn't have talked about all the apps or shovelware.
Rym: I mean, it's kind of like my old Jack Thompson thing where I've already talked about the bad thing you did.
Rym: You really have to go well beyond that for me to even consider talking about you again Because I only have so many minutes of showtime to talk about tech stuff.
Rym: But Apple what like went so far beyond what I would have expected or what I could conduct like It's I can't even like.
Rym: the magnitude of this just really irks me.
Rym: But basically Apple got a lot of bad press about these apps that got rejected from the tech community.
Rym: so basically what they did is they you know, they got very introspective and said well, obviously what we need to do is cover applications to the iPhone App Store With an NDA so that people can't tell anyone if we rejected their app.
Rym: that way we can't have any bad press.
Rym: No brilliant and evil Totally evil.
Rym: think about this.
Rym: Apple basically has said that if you submit an app to them and they reject it You cannot say if it got rejected.
Rym: That's it's ludicrous.
Rym: It's evil.
Rym: It serves no purpose whatsoever.
Rym: I think it's gonna be some lawsuit action except you basically protect Apple from the bad Press that it generated itself by being evil in the first place.
Rym: Yeah, and Like I used to speculate like oh, well, you know, it's hard to say exactly what Apple's motivations are.
Rym: I mean we had a lot of theory.
Scott: if they would just open it up Everyone be praising them and they'd be rolling in the bank twice as much as they are now.
Scott: So I don't know why they don't.
Scott: here's the.
Scott: what is their thinking?
Rym: Let's say I was Apple right.
Rym: somehow like I am Apple not Steve Jobs, but I am.
Rym: I'm like the avatar of Apple and I don't want iPod like iPod.
Rym: I keep saying iPods.
Rym: I don't want podcasts To succeed at all as an example like that.
Rym: I just do not want them to succeed.
Rym: I have a lot of reasons whatever doesn't matter what they are.
Rym: Instead of doing all this bad PR crap I would have just said something like the reason we rejected this app is because we have something much better in the works.
Rym: But the technology is not quite there yet and we're not going to let you the consumer get something subpar wait for the real thing and Then just not give a date and then slowly let that fade and then all the bad press disappears.
Rym: and then a year later I get the one angry blog nerd saying Apple lied to me and no one pays attention.
Scott: People actually seem to pay attention to that sort of thing, but it wouldn't have generated nearly as much bad Press as rejecting it giving an absolutely fallacious Podcasting either.
Scott: there's a whole bunch of apps that are being rejected all over the place And here's the thing right.
Scott: a lot of the things they say right will reject your app for this or that Right.
Scott: there are apps out there that do things that are technically against the rules.
Scott: Yes, and it's like well, how did that app get it?
Scott: It's breaking the rules, but they say you can't?
Rym: you know They don't want duplicate functionality.
Scott: There's a good enough.
Scott: There's a famous combination of words.
Scott: the famous combination is arbitrary and capricious.
Rym: We've been using those two words a lot lately.
Rym: I mean that the word capricious and the word arbitrary when combined are like the thing of the month for us.
Rym: Well, they're like husband and wife Abbott and Costello, right but I don't know what else I can say about this other than that, it's Bullshit, and I don't want I can't let it lie.
Rym: So Apple the only reason you're allowed to get away with this is because the Android has its own problems.
Scott: I saw you talking about this Android phone, right?
Scott: We've been waiting for this, right?
Scott: I mean think about this.
Scott: I got the iPhone right and you know what I'm sticking with the iPhone and I'll tell you why.
Scott: but I gotta tell you You know, I was when I got the iPhone.
Scott: I was thinking well either I get this now or I wait for the Android and seeing That the Android I'm glad that I got the iPhone but both are flawed.
Scott: They're just different right iPhone.
Scott: obviously we just discussed problem closed platform evil Apple locking you down.
Rym: But I mean don't forget as much you know, it's down as I am on Apple right now The iPhone is still like one of the best pieces of technology out there.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it could be so much more Same as like every piece of technology I ever taught just like wow with a slight modification.
Rym: This could be Transcendent, but instead it's simply okay.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, so the Android phone finally came out.
Scott: And what is the Android phone?
Scott: do that?
Scott: I was hoping from the iPhone.
Scott: Well, it's from Google and t-mobile.
Scott: So, of course, it works better with the Google stuff than the.
Scott: you know, iPhone does but it's t-mobile.
Scott: Well, what's wrong with t-mobile?
Rym: Their coverage is not great in a lot That's right.
Scott: The t-mobile coverage is not so great and their 3g is supposed.
Rym: Oh, wow, when you said what's wrong with t-mobile?
Rym: I thought whatever I said you were gonna argue against me.
Rym: But now t-mobiles coverage sucks.
Scott: now t-mobiles coverage is not as good compared to AT&T.
Scott: Verizon.
Rym: He's not that good either.
Scott: AT&T is fine except in beacon.
Scott: Well, no except at our house.
Rym: Typically, all right in our house and like this hundred foot radius around our house.
Rym: There's like no AT&T coverage, right?
Rym: It's like my Blackberry doesn't work for crap.
Scott: Right anyway, but T-mobiles 3g coverage, you know, it's sort of new.
Scott: they've got it in 20-something cities I think but it's not that big.
Scott: but someone you know, if you're on it, you're like the only one on it.
Scott: So it's actually pretty nice because you have this 3g all to yourself if you have it and in the city I'm pretty sure the 3g is there.
Scott: And the other good things about the Android phone, right works Well with the Google.
Scott: stuff with the iPhone does not do as well as the Android phone.
Scott: So like my Google Calendar, I still cannot sync with the iPhone, which is pretty bad.
Scott: Also, you know, it's open which is you know, the iPhone is closed that the Android is open.
Scott: It has a keyboard.
Scott: if you're not liking the iPhone touchy keyboard Which I've gotten kind of used to but still even getting used to it, you know I can type on it.
Scott: but say I would you know, if I had to type in like a long complicated password.
Rym: It's annoying, you know what I realized like I was holding my Blackberry the other day and like it's weird.
Rym: It's like the iPhone and the Blackberry are exactly equal in terms of input in my idea But they both like.
Rym: what if I was using an iPhone it'd be great until I wanted to type something and I've used the Blackberry It's great until I want to navigate around something Yep.
Rym: But I realized for me personally if I had the iPhone screen on the front and just a QWERTY keyboard on the back I could talk like I could hold it with the screen in front of me and type on the back just touch typing.
Scott: Well, the Android does that it has a slide.
Scott: It's a slider with a touchscreen.
Scott: So yeah, that's what it is.
Rym: The Android is it could do.
Rym: it'd be great for me except for the fact that it has the same level of flaws that the iPhone does right.
Scott: so he is.
Scott: what's wrong right with the Android phone, right?
Scott: Well, the first problem right is that it's open so you can make anything for it, right?
Scott: But there's a lot of things that aren't made for it yet Like it doesn't have a video playing software you to get a yet to get one from somewhere which is fine for someone like us who knows how to use it, but The interface is really bad.
Scott: The music playing interface is also really bad.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's like they have all these.
Scott: it has functionality, but the interface is lacking.
Scott: It's a lot like the Nokia devices.
Scott: then the.
Scott: The functionality of the Nokia devices has this insane insane feature list.
Scott: you basically do anything but The interface is bad and on a mobile device bad interface on a feature as far as I'm concerned Effectively makes the feature useless.
Scott: because if the inner like I used to have a Blackberry All right, when I worked for the other company that Blackberry had a shit ton of features I only ever used it for the company email Even though I could have used it for other things and I try to use of other things Am I?
Scott: even the cell phone I just got rid of has a million features I never used because the interface was so bad and so painful.
Scott: It wasn't worth it to use the feature.
Scott: It was more convenient not to use the feature than to use it.
Scott: and that's the Nokia device the Android whatever Android is it?
Scott: Okay interface in general, but the specific apps, you know have some problems in that department.
Scott: So even though it's a music player if the interface on the music player sucks It's no good.
Scott: And actually it has the Amazon mp3 store built in which is pretty cool You know, no DRM download direct whatnot, but Amazon mp3 store is still overpriced for my taste.
Scott: Otherwise, I'd buy a whole lot of music from it and I'd be broke.
Scott: the main problem with the Android phone in the book of Scott is that to plug in some headphones?
Scott: You need to get this little adapter that connects and then the headphones go into that.
Scott: It doesn't have a headphone hole.
Rym: We already learned this lesson from Nintendo and Nintendo rectified the situation.
Scott: Yes You see the main thing in the iPhone 3g is that it is a iPod Full-on perfect iPod and I need iPod a lot more than I need phone and a phone and an internet device.
Scott: And it does all of those things equally well.
Scott: The Android is a phone an internet device But it's media playing interface is such that it's effectively useless.
Scott: Thus if I had the Android phone, I would still need an iPod nano.
Scott: I Really really want an open device.
Scott: I really really really want to be able to do any software I want and have all these features like tethering and whatnot.
Scott: But the ability to be able to carry one less physical thing on my person on a day-to-day basis Makes such a huge difference in everyday life.
Scott: It's not worth it It's that's how big a deal.
Scott: that is and these companies don't seem to realize that Carrying fewer things is a huge deal.
Scott: huge is like I don't have to remember to have a phone and an iPod.
Scott: I only have to carry one thing and you know what?
Scott: I realized if Technology wasn't stupid and ever in the iPhone was fully open.
Scott: right everything, right?
Scott: I wouldn't need to carry anything but the iPhone Need a while.
Rym: There's one thing I wouldn't need.
Scott: well, I wouldn't need keys to my car I wouldn't need keys to the house.
Rym: one thing you would need what would I need?
Rym: a Camera because the iPhone camera could not have never unless we get some crazy.
Scott: But I wouldn't need to carry on a day-to-day basis.
Rym: No, because if you yeah because that's true because if you're gonna take a picture of the hobo with the funny sign You don't need the like 12 Bring.
Scott: yeah I'd only bring the good camera.
Scott: tell you conventions and whatnot.
Scott: when I expected it
Rym: at least the one thing that is obviated this desired For salt to some degree for me is the fact that now that I have a really nice bag to carry my laptop in Like the bet the bag is basically my murse now And I always have everything in the world that I need in that murse kind of like how before I had the murse But before I also had a cell phone.
Rym: Remember at RIT that trench coat like I once for show that I could carry a full 12 pack of soda Completely concealed inside of that trench coat.
Rym: Yeah, I carried everything in the world in that trench coat Mm-hmm, but then at the same time if I had just like and I a little box that did everything I don't think I would have needed the trench coat, right?
Rym: But I kind of like wearing the trench coat with all the stuff in the pockets.
Scott: you can do that, too.
Scott: But the point is like I also have a bag that I could put everything in.
Scott: but there are some situations where I just want To go pockets only.
Scott: and when you're going pockets only it's cool not to have to you know to have just one thing.
Rym: See, this is where pockets only where I feel like I would always need two devices.
Rym: I will always need like in the ideal devices what you need.
Rym: I need the super awesome computer device that does everything and is the iPhone and then I need the Rugged.
Rym: take it camping with me when I'm out hiking in the rain device because I doubt I'll ever get the iPhone.
Scott: I mean I get a bowl at the same time.
Rym: Oh, no, but I still I will need to own both devices.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like I own a laptop that I use for mobile interneting and I own an iPhone which is for mobile interneting There's a cross You know purpose there I guess like.
Rym: in the end though that the killer at like the real killer app the thing that's going to change the world in A big world the techno technological world in a big way is Going to be not just when you have one device that can do like all these things with a good interface But when you have one device that can do these things that is not in any way tethered to any physical other device or physical location at all.
Rym: Hmm to where the only time it ever needs to be physically connected to anything is when you need to put more power into it.
Scott: Well, even then and so there's some wireless charging technologies, but they're not that efficient.
Scott: They can be because laws of physics.
Rym: there's the fundamental problem that the faster you charge something like that the more More energy there is going through the air.
Rym: that can cook things right exactly, but there's also the Well, there's also the advances in you know Shaking things to give them more electricity and solar cells and heat transfer all that kind of.
Scott: but there's also the the situation in Which you would want to connect it to something else.
Scott: For example, I want to connect it to my computer to transfer everything to a back.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: it should be able to connect everything.
Rym: I should be I could set it up to where when I'm in my house.
Rym: It uses you know the future Bluetooth the thing that's better than Bluetooth and it automatically just connects to all the computers in my house that I told it to And does whatever business they go sharing and syncing whatever that I wanted to do with them.
Rym: But if I carry it elsewhere, it can still synchronize with things through the wireless Yep, that it'll always synchronize with everything when I'm in the car to update its own firmware.
Rym: Yep, when I'm in the car It just automatically knows it's in my car and plays the music and answers the phone through this area.
Scott: This kind of thing we're talking about isn't like some future dream.
Scott: This is Technologically possible right now with things that are already invented.
Scott: It's just nobody's done it.
Scott: It's it's it's done.
Scott: It's like we've invented everything that needs to be invented.
Scott: It's a solved problem.
Scott: It's like aha I figured up to get.
Scott: it's like if imagine if no one ever had been to Mount Everest, right?
Scott: No one had ever made it to the top.
Scott: a guy figured out how to make it to the top Proved that it would definitely work 100% and then everyone just sat at the bottom of the mountain say I'm not going.
Scott: Yeah, I don't feel like going up.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: We know we can do it, right?
Scott: Yes, let's not.
Scott: That's what's going on here.
Scott: is we can make this device.
Scott: Well, you see no one's done it What no one will.
Rym: one thing is that the problem with any sort of because there are a lot of things like this where?
Rym: unified technological advancement or even just unified technological application Could revolutionize industries could revolutionize businesses could revolutionize people's lives but different people have their hands in different parts of the pie and It's kind of a tragedy of the Commons where that one person investing in it will fail and lose money.
Rym: You need many people in different industries or different realms to invest simultaneously But then again anytime people do that other groups of people immediately defect and invest in a contrary technology And then everything gets fucked off.
Scott: And there's a thing open source can do it right.
Scott: open source is ready to make the software that will make these things happen.
Scott: But the hardware isn't open.
Scott: and even when you come with open source Operating system on a piece of hardware the t-mobile g1 doesn't have all the hardware necessary.
Scott: There is still.
Scott: it doesn't have the headphone hole.
Scott: It doesn't have a couple other things.
Scott: It's not perfect.
Scott: We need someone to just make the device I mean even look like the Nokia n810 which comes really close and runs Linux doesn't have a phone in it.
Rym: Well, we really need more than anything our standards that people actually follow for all sorts of communication and all sorts.
Rym: You know we do.
Scott: we have a lot of standards.
Rym: There's the problem.
Rym: we have a lot of standards that are all very purpose-specific and very useless outside of very specific realms and very limited because of different companies trying to push different formats and Also the fact that they just people don't write software to take advantage of it.
Rym: I mean My iPhone.
Rym: like there aren't that many car stereos to where I can just have my iPhone in my car and just play the music Bluetooth automatically without thinking about yeah, I mean that's totally possible.
Scott: You could have a head.
Scott: you know a head unit your car stereo could be Bluetooth.
Scott: well the iPhone does.
Scott: another example the iPhone Could right give you stereo audio over Bluetooth, but they didn't put the a2dp profile on it.
Scott: So it can't know why.
Rym: oh we can't know we don't know.
Scott: But if they did put the a2dp profile on the iPhone 3g or the regular iPhone you could listen to stereo audio With wireless headphones all right, and if they did that right you could have a car stereo head unit.
Scott: Why?
Scott: I don't think there are any car stereo head units and none that I've seen that have a2dp so that any device With stereo audio Bluetooth right could send it stereo audio Bluetooth to the car head unit And then it would come out of your car speakers with no wires and no nothing.
Scott: There's no reason that that can't be but no one's made one.
Scott: I don't know why not.
Rym: oh But anyway things of the day, so uh I discovered Possibly the first example of a riced out car in the history of cars History of motor cars right?
Scott: you're not looking at like some pimped-out chariots are you?
Rym: I'm sure there were some pimped-out chariots Pimped-out horse and carriage.
Rym: there's this gallery here.
Scott: I would have a pimped-out horse modified.
Scott: You know why.
Scott: you know why I pimp out my horse and carriage.
Scott: why scare off Robin Hood?
Scott: You know I was too cool.
Scott: He wouldn't rob me.
Rym: Anyway, I think my bread jokes are better than that.
Scott: whatever.
Rym: Right here.
Rym: I'm gonna link to this.
Rym: This is the fourth picture in a series of nine pictures of Interesting modifications and applications of the Model T. You know the first mass-produced real car and Basically because the car was so simple like the whole body was just this metal kind of shell.
Rym: You just pop it right off pop something else on there.
Scott: I don't know how many people have looked in a Model T.
Rym: I've driven one.
Rym: I've ridden in one.
Scott: Yeah, look at it.
Scott: look open up the hood of a new car.
Scott: There's a lot of shit in there right.
Scott: most of that shit is like air conditioning.
Scott: You know really complicated transmission.
Scott: You know alternators and things right.
Scott: the Model T right.
Scott: open that bitch up.
Rym: I'll explain it in layman terms a bully and a motor?
Rym: not even it looks like a little motor and a rubber band connected to a shaft which connects to the axle pretty much directly and it's.
Rym: it's a Beautiful thing to behold.
Rym: and it was actually.
Rym: it drives a lot better than you'd think.
Scott: yeah I mean you know it takes.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's one of those things where you get diminishing returns.
Scott: You know it's sort of like the space shuttle where it's like okay a big rocket.
Scott: Just plain old rocket gonna get you into space 75% of the way right plain old rocket, okay, we need to get into space 99 percent.
Scott: Well, then suddenly it gets much more complicated.
Scott: You know as you as you get higher and higher in the percentages to get from 75 percent to 80 percent doesn't take much It takes some wheelings, but to get from 99 percent to ninety nine point five percent Takes like this incredibly complicated computer system with a million things all over the place.
Rym: But anyway back in the early Model T days
Scott: you mean early 1900s
Rym: there were companies
Scott: in the industrial
Rym: that would make Race car looking bodies slick looking for like you know metal frames metal bodies And you buy them and pop them on you basically kind of like how you change the face plate on your fancy cell phone.
Rym: You just swap out the body on your car And now you have a hip looking roadster because and punk kids would buy these things and have a little roadster.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I think about Model T. Didn't really have a suspension right as That kind of whalebone business.
Scott: right right, but I mean you could just take the body off.
Scott: You know the little roof and that little.
Scott: you know the seats and whatnot.
Scott: and just it was just two axles in the motor.
Scott: Just put something else on top real easy.
Scott: I could do it.
Scott: You don't need you don't need to go to mechanic school or anything.
Scott: I wonder how mechanics made money back in those days and anyone can fix their own car.
Rym: just people couldn't.
Rym: But anyway all I want to point out is that in the spirit of one of my favorite websites ever I'm even making the face right here at the monitor man.
Scott: I wish there was a race like an actual race.
Scott: We're just all cars like that There were back then.
Scott: no no Model T.
Rym: Specifically There were.
Rym: I'm sure there were local league kind of like out in Canada.
Rym: yet like the local boxing league the local hockey league I'm sure there was the local riced out Model T.
Scott: I want to see a Model T race right now today.
Rym: Anyway, what do you got for me captain thing of the day?
Scott: This is all over the news.
Scott: It's not that exciting, but I didn't have anything else.
Scott: basically this dude.
Scott: He took a bunch of solenoids.
Scott: solenoids Oh, no, oh man solenoids of the wind.
Scott: I don't know if people learn about solenoids.
Rym: I don't think you understand how Pivotal and how kind like my middle school and high school life revolved around solenoids.
Rym: And I would say like a good 10% of the stories I have from high school Were caused directly by the intervention of a solenoid.
Scott: yeah, I mean solenoids.
Scott: if you don't know about them You should learn how they work.
Scott: It's pretty simple.
Scott: You don't have to know that.
Scott: much I like to pretty much know is how a magnet works And how an electromagnet.
Rym: we made one out of glass that then shattered and hurt someone.
Scott: The best is using it to like get rods like hover in the air.
Rym: Oh, we used one to make a lock that could lock a door, and then we couldn't unlock it.
Rym: We we made a rail gun.
Scott: That's what are you supposed to do?
Rym: that's pretty much the second thing you do after you learn what a solenoid is.
Scott: This guy made a bunch of solenoids I don't know he might have bought them I can't tell and he hooked him up to a computer the control system and whatnot and he had.
Scott: he had each solenoid hitting something different which makes you know a noise and He made a solenoid symphony, and it's a. it's got a funky beat to it.
Scott: It's
Rym: pretty cool
Scott: and it's just a little video here and I
Rym: can say this the best or the best thing that ever happened to me in middle school is when we got a hold of a solenoid from an old car and Once we got a 12-volt power supply to it.
Rym: Let me tell you that thing was called the finger breaker.
Rym: That's what it is because it broke someone's finger immediately.
Scott: It was that a solenoid for like the car door locks.
Rym: Yes Oh, yeah, those basically was ripped out of an old car and we applied 12 volts to it and someone stupid got hurt.
Scott: I see I do is you go to the junkyard and you pick those things up real easy.
Rym: actually They're really easy to make two kids.
Rym: Yeah, let's look, you know TI-80x was so important in.
Rym: you know, becoming the kind of technological hackers that we are today I feel like solenoids are like number five or six on the list.
Scott: You know, you can control solenoids of the TI-80x.
Rym: Yes, actually you could also kids.
Rym: you can make a solenoid at home in about an hour Even less depend on it making it from scratch.
Rym: I mean think about it Scott wine wine wine wine wine wine wine.
Scott: You don't have an automatic winder.
Rym: Well, I made an automatic winder out of a screwdriver.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I make an automatic winder out of what you make it out of.
Scott: well, you know If you go, I don't know how people know about these things.
Scott: It's basically sort of a. they have this thing.
Scott: It's a combination Apple core and slicer and peeler.
Rym: Oh, man I love those things.
Scott: and you may see stick an apple on these spikes and then you spin it and the Apple gets pushed through All these metal things and one metal thing skins the Apple.
Scott: Another metal thing takes the core out of the Apple and also cuts the Apple and it's like a thin spiral.
Rym: Stuff like that is really gimmicky, but these things are awesome.
Scott: early works.
Scott: it's suction cups to the table and everything and you can use it to.
Scott: you know, make apple cake or pie or whatever right and You can just put your tube on that and then hold, you know your wire and spin away.
Rym: No, there's a much better way.
Rym: You just take a drill press.
Scott: I got an idea to get a Model T and put it to tube and hold the wires Right.
Rym: So it's a buzzword.
Rym: It's a big buzzword.
Rym: now people are talking about it lately a lot and we're not gonna talk about what it is.
Rym: We're not gonna go into the tech a little bit.
Rym: I don't think we should at all because that's not the interesting part.
Scott: and Go I kind of want to talk about some interesting histories there a little bit.
Rym: Google I think we should talk about the history is more from our Perspective because these things came and went and came and went in the cycle and we lived through a couple of those cycles.
Scott: Yep
Rym: And also if you want the actual history of this or the definite, you know, all that business Google it and you know, if we tell it to you, it'll basically I'll saying well
Scott: I think part of it is that there's been varying definitions over time and That's sort of what's important about it.
Rym: I think the only important thing is that cloud computing is not a new thing at all.
Rym: No, no It's just a new word for that thing.
Rym: It's like the.
Rym: it's kind of like if we made up a buzzword called I don't know the Phlebo.
Scott: Yeah, well basically the deal is right as a flange.
Rym: and read what's this NASA flange?
Rym: What if you could have like what's a summer flange?
Rym: The fuck's a summer flange.
Scott: Anyway, the thing is over.
Scott: the course of computing history There's been sort of like this cycle right and the cycle has gone back and forth between Centralized and distributed computing.
Scott: back and forth.
Scott: right at beginning computers are big filled up a whole room, right?
Scott: What if one more than one person want to use it at once?
Scott: not easy.
Scott: so they had you know one machine and had multiple Terminals so that you know a bunch of people shared is one computer and it was you know centralized computing.
Scott: There's one CPU a whole bunch of people.
Scott: right.
Rym: then when personal PCs came around You could start to have that level of power on an individual desk.
Rym: So individual people got control, but then that wasn't enough because you had more power from Maine.
Rym: I mean basically the reason I kind of want to skip talking about all the technological in the history Is that a long time ago?
Rym: We kind of decided that we wanted to turn the Monday show into commentary and just talking about tech at our level as opposed to always doing these shows or we kind of Explained if
Scott: we talk about this at our level the show is gonna be over and done with in two seconds.
Rym: Not really because I. we have a lot of opinions and commentary and anecdotes.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's a pretty simple pro and con.
Rym: I think I was so Against the idea of cloud computing back in the day like in the I don't know 1994 through 1999 Cloud computing scared the shit out of me.
Scott: Well, the idea back then right was that you would get a computer that was an almost nothing computer Didn't even have a hard drive almost right?
Scott: It was basically the most minimal computer.
Scott: It would be stupidly cheap like a hundred bucks in the which in those days was insane.
Scott: It's still kind of insane.
Scott: No, I guess you know, I guess a computer that 1990s computer nowadays would be a hundred bucks, but a new computer, right?
Scott: And basically, you turn the computer on it would dial up because dial-up is what they had in those days and Everything the computer did would come over the phone line all the software everything and then you wouldn't need to install your operating system update your software anything and all your data would be stored online and everything and that was the idea back then was benefit, right You don't have to worry about hard drives crashing You always have up-to-date software and your computer is really cheap Which was a big deal in those days when even shitty computers are expensive and the cons were Well people, you know sort of underestimated the slowness and shittiness of dial-up
Rym: well
Scott: and it didn't work.
Rym: the real issue was that that was in kind of the early part of the big battle over like internet censorship.
Rym: and you know before the D the DMC and all this stuff is kind of people were fighting tooth and nail between the forces of Controlling computing resources from central authorities and having the power to do what you want with your technology.
Rym: And this was back when companies like real media and Oracle.
Rym: We're basically saying we need to control how people use technology or else It's all gonna go to hell.
Rym: and there were.
Rym: there was a big fair among a lot of technologists I know especially a lot of punk kid technologists who were big into piracy and copyright infringement That like digital DRM and all these things would become come to be like the moment they take away our Hardware.
Rym: the moment.
Rym: I don't have control over my hardware.
Rym: the moment I have to rely on someone else's hardware out there is when the internet dies and the freedom to exchange information dies and Cootie old men control everything.
Scott: Yeah, think about it.
Scott: If all if your computer just got everything over the wire from someone from say Google, right?
Scott: Well, how does it work?
Scott: You're basically turn on your computer and you're at google.com.
Scott: Okay, I want to buy I want to use office, okay, well Google Docs is right there All right.
Scott: I want to play.
Scott: I don't know Bioshock.
Scott: Okay, double click here pay 50 bucks.
Scott: Now you can play Bioshock.
Scott: Congratulations, you know, you can't install anything.
Scott: There's no control by you.
Scott: You're pretty much it's no different than using the iPhone today Which is pretty much exactly the same as using the iPhone today.
Rym: I'm trying to search for it.
Rym: I can't find it offhand but Some like it.
Rym: back then someone made a post on slashdot that has stuck with me to this day And it was basically one of those.
Rym: it was much like the famous.
Rym: Do you hear me?
Rym: I'm not gonna take it anymore.
Rym: speech from that movie and it was a guy basically saying that you know you try to you control this and you take this away and They control this media of communication and then they control this one and they're never going to stop.
Rym: and we always move on to.
Rym: You know, we move on to ad-hoc computing we move on to wireless.
Rym: If you keep taking it away We'll keep moving on.
Rym: if we have to we'll use mirrors and we'll reflect light through the air in a way that you can't stop Us.
Rym: do you hear me?
Rym: Do you fucking hear me?
Rym: You can't take away our right to communicate and we will always find a way around It.
Rym: do you fucking understand what it is that we do?
Rym: We are hackers and we will fuck you.
Rym: Yep, and that was like the rallying call of the internet and to me that back then and I was really afraid of you know Cloud computing even though no one called it that back then.
Scott: Well, some people did but most people just called it like, you know thin clients, you know net computers that sort of thing.
Rym: but then you know Rob down came around and basically cloud computing didn't matter to me in college because we had this crazy network and Instead of cloud computing where I'd rely on someone else It was more like my computer was accessible to me from anywhere I went.
Rym: so I just had a Samba share and wherever I went all over campus I could just go to my computer and get all my crap.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you weren't going around the world We were just going around this campus and the campus had this incredible network right that covered the entire place.
Scott: So it's sort of like, you know, if you made the ghost in the shell world But in this tiny place and you never left the tiny place.
Scott: It was like living in the ghost back then and you had one computer.
Scott: That was like your your Powerhouse that was connected to the network.
Scott: So as long as you stayed in the world You you basically had cloud computing even though your cloud was completely controlled by you.
Rym: And when I went out of the world, I didn't have any way.
Rym: I mean None of us had cell phones like my cell phone.
Scott: I couldn't it's not freshman year Yeah, I couldn't know it had.
Scott: no one had a cell phone that did anything but make calls But until later.
Rym: but like I couldn't afford my old brick cell phone anymore.
Rym: None of us had cell phones and none of us.
Rym: we had one car and like the entire front row crew So we couldn't even leave the campus let alone try to access media at least for the first couple years.
Rym: But even then eventually we didn't have access to internet outside.
Scott: Yep, I mean even if I went home, you know, I could SSH I guess but you know There wasn't like it wasn't like I'm walking around the street or I'm using computers all over the place.
Rym: But I really got to say it was like the idea of cloud computing as something that is viable and useful to me Really didn't come to be until Google Made it happen.
Scott: Well, what's happened is people were using, you know, people were mostly computing locally right for pretty much everything.
Rym: I mean remember when you like the the classic I'm Installing my computer and what did you do?
Rym: You got all your drivers or you know, whatever and you installed all your stuff and then you went around installing like the 30 Applications and games that you used.
Scott: Yeah, and in those times, you know, there are websites but websites were mostly getting information Commenting that sort of thing and there was webmail.
Scott: but webmail was basically the thing, you know Connected to the same exact email account as you connected to with say your outlook or your Thunderbird and what you would do is on Your computer you would use your Thunderbird and be so nice.
Scott: But if you were somewhere
Rym: else Thunderbird back then most people just use Outlook Express
Scott: that I didn't use that but or Eudora Whatever, but well, you
Rym: know what I use because before then I use my geo savings account 3 and I use like Outlook Express something I had some other ways there was
Scott: Thunderbird or Mozilla mail or whatever it was at the time.
Rym: But back then like the internet was ghettoized basically if you had an email address from any of the places you could get email like An ISP you were pretty much a second-class citizen.
Rym: everyone real on the internet Had like basically a dot edu somewhere.
Scott: or they had their own domain or their own mail server.
Scott: But you would use when you wanted to read your email or something like that You would use an email Application that talked to your mail server with pop through your IMAP and you controlled the email server.
Scott: or were you know?
Scott: Pretty close to it.
Rym: I remember most people like we would use pop 3 like I would pop my email down to my own Computer.
Rym: that was like it would physically be there and it wouldn't be anywhere else.
Scott: even if your ISP What went away you still had all your emails on your computer?
Scott: And I think usually deleted the emails from the ISP after you downloaded them because no one we didn't trust our ISPs.
Scott: And the only time you would use web mail or something like that is if you really needed to check your email when you weren't Around and web mail sucked.
Scott: It was like squirrel mail or something.
Rym: Oh my god It was painful to use like even RIT.
Rym: Right when I was at RIT if I wanted to check my email and I wasn't on campus like I went home for break I would like SSH back to RIT to like the VAX cluster.
Rym: And well, actually I use the via the.
Rym: I use the.
Rym: what I think is the HP machine.
Rym: Whatever there's the VMS.
Rym: There's some other one They were like.
Rym: anyway, I would basically SSH back to RIT Telnet into the port that was my email on the special Unix server and then I'd run elm.
Scott: I used mutt.
Scott: cuz I'm not an idiot.
Rym: I used elm because it did the job, right?
Scott: The reason you realize that elm was so bad that they made pine which yes Which is not elm and then mutt was even better than that pine is not elm.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah all that business Yeah, but even then it wasn't the cloud it was more like.
Rym: I trusted our like.
Rym: I feel like the.
Rym: the core of it is Trust one that the resource will be there in the future.
Rym: Trust two that you'll be able to access it from anywhere.
Rym: and trust three that the resource will not unduly control you.
Rym: and Basically, I never trusted anyone on the internet whereas you shouldn't have in the 90s.
Rym: You shouldn't trust anyone the internet ever.
Rym: but back then like the internet was such a wild west that like I did not trust anyone Ever for crap on the internet.
Rym: and at RIT, I didn't trust the internet.
Rym: I trusted RIT because I was paying them a lot of money.
Scott: Yeah You know, I'm all.
Scott: I trusted the CS department more than I trusted the other RIT night.
Scott: It was like this separate network within the network.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Also the IT department also had a separate network.
Rym: Yeah, then basically the rest of the campus was kind of also a while.
Scott: I still have an account on that CS network.
Scott: They haven't deleted it.
Rym: Yeah, I have an alumni IT account.
Rym: I could have paid for my email, but I didn't bother.
Scott: I mean like my regular RIT account is totally gone You know, but the the account I had in the CS department is still there.
Scott: I can still SSH and use their computers.
Scott: Well, I can still they didn't change it.
Rym: I can still tell that in and get to my financial aid information.
Scott: Oh, I can't do that.
Rym: I can go in there because I did something with it like a year ago.
Rym: I don't know if I still can but But but look at this.
Rym: Google got to the point where I may not trust them with my data a hundred percent Necessarily, but I trust that my data is accessible - and I trust that I can get to it to the point that I've basically Started to use Google for just about everything I do.
Scott: Well, what?
Scott: what they've done to make you know to I guess here is that the number one they've actually made something reliable.
Scott: They've made a web user interface that is as good or actually better than the desktop interfaces.
Scott: Right not having to install or upgrade or maintain the software saves you work.
Rym: I've gotten to the point where for the majority of things that I do on any computer.
Rym: I'm not just OS agnostic I'm not just platform agnostic.
Rym: I am computer agnostic.
Rym: Like it doesn't matter what computer I'm on I can access 90% of the things long as it has an unfiltered internet connection and a web browser.
Scott: I'm like, it's like I'm at home.
Scott: It used to be.
Scott: you'd use your computer your personal computer and you'd feel at home But if used any other computer it was sort of like a terrible experience because it wasn't customized for you.
Scott: Yes Now you can use any internet connected device with a browser that's not filtered and it's like you're at home.
Rym: This is actually a really kind of interesting revelation.
Rym: I had many years ago but For most of my life it used to be that I'd go out into the world and I'd enjoy myself and I'd work and I'd go To school.
Rym: I would do things in the world.
Rym: But whenever I was out in the world, I was disconnected from the other world the internet.
Rym: So I kind of would always have this sense of coming home like whenever I return to my home base be it my parents house or my Apartment or my dorm room or my house or wherever I would like my home base.
Rym: It was like I came home.
Rym: and what did I do when I came home?
Rym: I took off my shoes I hung up my coat.
Rym: I would then go and check my messages Like it was like alright, I am home.
Rym: I can now get all the messages all the things that I could not get when I was out in the world.
Rym: I would go to my answering machine and listen to the messages I'll go to my computer read my email then I would go to like my forums read my forums Read the internet and then it like.
Rym: it really made this sense of homecoming not just to my home But to my other world.
Rym: and then at RIT That was kind of shattered a little bit because we had an answering machine.
Rym: No one ever called that phone number except spammers.
Rym: So we basically ignored it.
Rym: the answering machine was just there because it was free.
Rym: We owned it and then you know, eventually I got a cell phone and I just carried that with me.
Rym: So now getting home like I didn't care about my messages because my messages were with me anywhere.
Rym: and then you know I could check my email anywhere on campus.
Rym: So coming home was kind of uptime to check the internet in my email.
Rym: But home was now RIT as opposed to just my put my apartment.
Rym: but then I moved to the mountains.
Rym: I did not have internet access my cell phone didn't even work Like I couldn't even use my cell phone where I lived and I didn't pay for a landline.
Rym: I had no possible means of communication with the outside world and My sense of homecoming disappeared.
Rym: and I became really disconnected from the world.
Rym: and I eventually had two homes.
Rym: I had my internet home, which was work.
Rym: I would often go to work on the weekend for like an hour to use the internet and I would be home But then I would go home to my house and I'd be home But not really because I was disconnected from all the things that I really needed.
Rym: fast forward because of all these revelations I realized that my Intellectual home like my my kind of connected to the world home has absolutely no physical location whatsoever anymore.
Rym: Now wherever I am I can get online and access 90 to 95 percent of everything I need.
Scott: Yep, now the only thing here right is that lately there's been sort of a a bigger push for cloud computing.
Scott: yet again You know into where you know, they're trying to ask you to do more and more of your stuff online.
Rym: Who's they?
Scott: Well, you got like, you know Google and Microsoft and Adobe's trying to do like some online stuff You know where instead of buying a piece of software installing it and running it locally you just use someone else's software through the web or through some other mechanism and Things are saved on their servers.
Rym: and then now here's the thing.
Rym: I say 95% because I use the cloud for the 95% of those things But there's always going to be that 5% where I don't try.
Rym: basically it comes down to trust in the end Not even performance because the old argument used to be.
Rym: you can never have good performance But technology is going to make that go away.
Rym: You will eventually be able to have good performance in the cloud for anything.
Rym: the only issue that will always remain is trust and I don't think I will ever trust anyone in the world other than Myself to manage that last 5% of my information.
Rym: I mean our podcast, you know our radio show.
Rym: my personal documents that like really matter.
Rym: I will always want to have my music collection.
Rym: or You know all the illegal stuff that I may or may not do or the political stuff that I may not want out there.
Rym: I will always need my home base that I manage that No one else has any power over whatsoever that I am.
Rym: I'm the master of my own domain Because that's kind of like the love that last inch in V for Vendetta that that one thing that no matter what happens in the outside World I still have that and they can't get me a hundred percent.
Scott: Well, I think what the fuck that the solution is gonna be actually is Scott's prediction.
Scott: It's almost guaranteed right.
Scott: is that the average person, right?
Scott: He doesn't know or care about computers.
Scott: much is gonna use the Gmail's or whatever.
Scott: They're gonna let the big corporation or the big entity in the sky centralized computer, right?
Scott: They're gonna let all their stuff be on there, you know, Microsoft Apple mobile me Whatever it is, and that's what they're gonna do cuz that's all they know to do.
Scott: They can't handle it themselves Right, and it'll be a much better experience for them a much easier experience And you know what it'll actually be better for everyone else, too.
Scott: I actually agree because but I don't think everyone has that five percents Yeah, but I think what's gonna happen is the people who care about computing the nerds the geeks the hackers the whatnot Right.
Scott: what they're gonna do right is sort of like what we've been moving to which is you have a server Somewhere and you have you know Still getting all the benefits of cloud computing because you have some computer out in the cloud that you are controlling that is yours And you can get it from anywhere and it's just run by you instead of run by companies.
Scott: So for example, the average person is gonna use Twitter, right?
Scott: Someone runs, you know big old Twitter and all these normal people join it and use it.
Scott: The geeks are gonna use they're all gonna run their own iconica servers that will communicate with each other and you get all the advantages.
Scott: but you run it yourself you are in control of the Cloud.
Rym: Yeah your piece of it and that is the thing is, you know, I kept saying, you know the 5% You know, I have control at home, but that's the same control.
Rym: I mean theoretically.
Rym: there's the tiny danger of like what if your colo is evil or all?
Rym: but those people are a lot more trustworthy Because they don't give a shit about what you're doing.
Scott: I think what all could also happen is if I especially could happen much more easily if IP v6 came around right is?
Scott: It would be come very easy for people to just buy sort of like made home server things that you would put in your house And just connect and they would just work and then sort of everyone would be able to run their own.
Rym: But at the same time then CP you'll say now again people out there might say but bandwidth no bandwidth will.
Rym: eventually I'll always be more and plan a band with my ass.
Scott: People are already buying sling boxes and plugging them in who don't know anything about technology and they totally work.
Rym: But not just that.
Rym: the only real concern here is, you know your safety.
Rym: I lost my train of thought like a hundred percent here and I was trying to Talk until I remembered it, but I totally fell asleep box.
Scott: It's like people don't know about this, right?
Scott: It's a device.
Scott: you plug it into your home media center, right?
Scott: And then any device anywhere in the world that has a sling client you can use to connect to your personal Slingbox and control your television forever.
Scott: you are so like you leave a DVD in the DVD player at home.
Scott: You can watch it on like your palm pilot or your I guess your palm trio on the train or something as long.
Scott: As long as this internet thing.
Rym: box is awesome.
Rym: But I remembered my train of thought and it's a good train of thought.
Rym: the other argument will be but there's still that You know the danger because the big concern hackers and geeks always have is that you don't want Someone else to be able to screw you or a single point of failure to be able to prevent you.
Rym: I mean, yes, I have my server in the sky.
Rym: What if the ISP turns evil and decides that they don't like what I'm doing?
Rym: I have a backup Yes, but what is let's say what if I have an ISP at home where currently there's a big monopoly on ISPs.
Rym: you don't have a lot of choices and they decide to limit bandwidth or block ports or whatever.
Rym: and While those are concerns in the end, they'll also be covered by technology.
Rym: I mean in the end, I think where the real action is going to be like in the long long run I'm talking like lifetime maybe even longer.
Rym: in the end all the geek important You know, you can't be the boss of communication is gonna be some sort of global ad hoc anonymous Wireless cloud like cloud in the truest sense to the point that communication There's no point.
Rym: Does anyone have control over the cloud anymore?
Scott: Yeah, there's gonna be a point at which right you can get a device that will plug into the wall, right?
Scott: We'll have a very powerful very fast wireless network with a big radius Right and every and have one it will make.
Scott: it will Automatically form a mesh network with other devices in range and automatically create routing tables.
Scott: No one will have to manage it manually, right?
Rym: It won't just be that Everyone's cell phone or will will do this.
Rym: all the cell phones will link up.
Rym: all the iPhones will link up Every device you carry.
Rym: I mean There's a lot of talking like you know about having cars that have little sensors that have a cloud of car computing So where every car on the road Communicates with all the cars near it and by extension with all the cars down the road and then instead of having a centralized Thing that says, you know, there is traffic ahead use an alternate route.
Rym: The cars all know on their own and This sort of thing is like people.
Rym: the buzzword of cloud computing is such weak sauce and people who use it By and large really aren't thinking far.
Rym: They're not thinking in Asimov terms They're thinking in like Google in Adobe because we you're talking about here is actually beyond cloud computing.
Scott: It's it's mesh networking.
Scott: The cloud computing is really just.
Scott: it's no different than the client server model of.
Scott: there's a server.
Scott: You just get everything from the server, which does the real Call that cloud.
Scott: Well, the reason it's called cloud computing is because there's a difference between the server is right across the room And there's a bunch of clients and the server being somewhere out there.
Scott: You don't really know it's in a cloud.
Scott: it's just a Larger separation between the server is on my internet and the server is some mystical thing in the internet lost somewhere.
Rym: I guess for me I just I feel like the way people are using cloud computing right now like most people.
Rym: when they say it They're really just referring to the kind of the mundane next steps that we already have that are just getting slightly more polished as it.
Rym: But they talk about those things like they're a revolution and I don't think they are yet.
Scott: No, but yet cloud computing the term has been used in so many different ways that it's sort of loaded.
Scott: But yeah, people nowadays are usually just using it to refer to web application.
Scott: Yes, but email or hot man?
Rym: I guess I feel like that is such.
Rym: it's kind of like I've discovered copper and all right.
Rym: What if I made a club out of it and then someone says yeah But what if you made a spear and then the person with the club is like clubs of the future?
Rym: It's all about the club Spears.
Rym: That's like hundred years in the future We can't even worry about.
Rym: Spears are so impossible right now.
Rym: clubs are so awesome.
Scott: I'm talking about Spears Yeah, but eventually, you know if everyone has these you know crazy wireless things everyone will plug one in in their house and just this network will appear that is completely not controlled by anyone and Everything will just connect to everything else.
Scott: Yep, and that's it You
Rym: know, I realize I think the only reason I feel like the why I'm more I guess jaded about the term cloud computing and you are why I'm kind of more Saying should mean more is that I feel like too many technology kind of pundits and bloggers and people When they refer to cloud computing they always kind of refer to refer to it with this air of.
Rym: it's such an amazing Thing when it's really just like the next logical step.
Scott: Yeah I don't really care so much about which terms get used in which ways.
Scott: I'm more just concerned of what the Technological reality is.
Scott: Well, you know what?
Rym: I really can concern about right now eating potato soup.
Rym: So I think we're done for the night.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.