Rym:
Rym: Hey, it's Thursday, February 28th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and Tonight we talk about underwear on GeekNights.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: My name is Inigo Montoya.
Scott: You killed my father prepared to that.
Rym: Will you stop saying that?
Scott: no, I Should start every show with that.
Scott: It'd be great.
Rym: You know, usually on a day like today we start the show with woman.
Scott: Yeah, it's true it was face is one coal cuz in.
Scott: in two or three weeks it's gonna be warm again.
Scott: I'm gonna be wearing shorts within the month.
Scott: That's I declare within the month.
Rym: shorts, you know, I'll put it this 30 days today It was kind of warm.
Rym: So I was like, alright I'm gonna go back to where
Scott: I have to on some day when I'm inside and not going outside I'll wear shorts inside
Rym: and I'm gonna go back to wearing the coat I like instead of the coat I wear when it's like bitterly ass cold out.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I'm wearing the winter coat right and soon I'll transfer to like a leather jacket and then the hoodie and then the Nothing, I'll pretty much go to the blazer until I can get away with nothing.
Scott: I can't wait until I can go to the nothing.
Scott: That'll be good times.
Rym: But uh, I actually had to go.
Rym: I went outside stood there for a second when Woman walked back in took off my nice coat put on the snow coat and went back outside.
Rym: He usually was like one degree.
Rym: this morning.
Scott: Usually I put my hand on the window to figure out how cold it is outside and that's a pretty good test.
Scott: Yeah, that doesn't so I don't ever.
Scott: so I don't go outside and then go back in like a dumbass.
Rym: It was extra cold plus hand on the window doesn't help.
Rym: Yeah, it does now Not if it's just windy cold because it wasn't that cold.
Rym: I think what really brought it below the line was the fact that it was like a billion mile an hour.
Scott: wind hand on the Window is not you know, like super accurate temperature telling, you know, but regardless of that I only have like three or four coat options, you know ranging from no coat to heaviest coat.
Scott: By touching the window I can pretty much figure out which option is.
Rym: I go from Actually wearing shorts and stuff and then changing when I get to work and biking to wear in.
Rym: you know my trench coat to wear in the trench coat with the liner to wear in just the liner to wear in the Winter jacket plus or minus gloves plus or minus hood plus or minus hat.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have these problems.
Rym: I have multiple levels of glove ranging from my nice leather driving loves all the way up to the Ski gloves that also protect me.
Scott: and see I have just these the winter gloves.
Scott: I also pretty much only use them if I have to touch snow.
Rym: I also have my hockey gloves, but I don't think I'll ever need to wear them again in my life.
Scott: Where do you have hockey gloves?
Scott: They're not here.
Rym: You want to see my hockey gloves?
Scott: You have hockey gloves here.
Rym: They're in my bag with all my other gloves that I never use because there's never good skiing weather when I'm ready to go skiing Uh-huh, and no one ever wants to play hockey.
Scott: I would like to play hockey.
Scott: I'll teach you.
Rym: I'll spend as much time as you want teaching you how to play hockey.
Scott: You need to get two goalies and Eight other people and you know ten sticks and a puck.
Rym: I think to rent out an ice rink I think you need to learn first how to skate and then from there how to hold a hockey stick.
Scott: I know how to hold a high.
Scott: I know all the hockey skills except for skating.
Rym: I somehow doubt that?
Rym: Yeah I really somehow doubt that you somehow don't know how to skate yet know how to play hockey.
Scott: if you want to play hockey without Skates just like in a gym with a rolly ball and feet awesome.
Rym: I can realize that skating and shooting and handling a puck is effectively a completely different skill from Walking or running and doing the same thing.
Rym: and also handling a puck is nothing like handling a ball.
Scott: Yeah, you can get one of those floor pucks.
Rym: Those are nothing like handling a real hockey puck.
Rym: I think also they really don't roll.
Rym: Usually they just kind of tumble it over heels.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'll be alright once I get the the skating action.
Rym: you want to learn how to skate.
Rym: no Why not?
Scott: It's not too much money in time takes almost no money.
Rym: You can run skates for like nothing.
Scott: I got better things to be doing.
Rym: Okay, you're never gonna play.
Scott: All right, we get rid of the podcast.
Scott: we can play hockey.
Rym: I really want to play some hockey.
Scott: Goddamn, why don't you go join like the old guys hockey league?
Rym: I'm not old enough for that.
Scott: You can join the semi old guys.
Rym: It's not like when I was a kid where I could just walk outside and there would be multiple roller hockey games Just going every day.
Scott: all I'd have to do.
Scott: I was talking about ice hockey.
Rym: Well, actually if I wanted to get in my car There were just pick up games of ice hockey pretty much every pond and reservoir.
Scott: everywhere didn't people fell fall in.
Rym: What do you mean?
Scott: fall in like, you know, cuz where I was, you know, there was.
Scott: there were ponds and things But they were rarely frozen enough for safe skating.
Rym: I lived in Michigan where people would make a point of making sure that ponds were ready to be skated in.
Scott: Uh-huh As long as you check you can't go skating on some random pond.
Rym: If you grow up above the Messier line, especially in a place like Michigan, I'm well above the Messier.
Rym: you just know you've been not you're not in spirit because you just know you can look at a pond and go that is a Hockey pod or that is a dying pond.
Scott: Well, I think another thing is that your proximity to the Great Lakes offered you many more pond options Even though you didn't play hockey on the Great Lakes.
Rym: No, that's like saying you haven't go play hockey in the Atlantic.
Rym: Yeah, I'll go play hockey in the Gulf of Mexico Sing some Volga boat song while we go out there to die.
Scott: I'll play hockey in the Caribbean.
Rym: You know what you do do on the Great Lakes though ice fishing.
Scott: No great.
Rym: They ever been ice fishing?
Scott: No, I never been fishing fishing.
Rym: You want to go ice fishing?
Rym: No, I'll tell you this ice cold ice fishing Sucks ass.
Scott: if I was gonna do fishing I would go fish.
Scott: I would go sun fishing.
Rym: I have ice fish.
Rym: Have you ever seen a sunfish?
Rym: I?
Scott: Guess in an aquarium.
Rym: What does sunfish look like?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I was talking about fishing in the Sun.
Rym: I'm talking about sunfish because I don't want to fish for sunfish.
Rym: I just want to be friends with sunfish.
Scott: Okay, I want to fish where it is sunny and warm.
Rym: just you google image for sunfishes.
Rym: But anyway All that aside my new laptop is so hot.
Rym: I think it's alright.
Rym: I really really like it.
Scott: Well, of course you like it.
Scott: you bought it.
Rym: Yes after a lot of research I decided on this one and I got to say once my bag comes like a sunfish Normal-looking fish.
Rym: They're big and they're flat.
Scott: Some of them all the cool ones are anyway, some of them look kind of sharky.
Rym: I know a lot of you read my blog early on and then notice that I Haven't really posted in my blog in a long time and many of you complained that Scott and I don't really blog so much.
Scott: Not not much, but I came up with an idea of something to blog.
Rym: Well, actually now that I cuz a lot of times pretty much every day I'd be on the train right and I think I know what to blog about and I'm ready to go.
Rym: but I was on the train and I thought oh, well, I'll write it in my moleskine and I thought didn't happen.
Rym: and Then I'd get home be like time to blog.
Rym: No time to take a nap time to play a game time to do something.
Scott: I mean my blog doesn't even like enter my consciousness off, you know It's.
Scott: it's just sort of like when I think about it completely randomly, then maybe something will happen Really?
Scott: I don't think about it.
Rym: often I got a lot to say about a lot of things that I can't talk about on the podcast Mostly because you don't care about politics.
Scott: So, uh Once my bag a great Rym what we need is another political block.
Scott: Oh, yes, we do.
Rym: Oh, yes, we do.
Scott: is you you can?
Scott: you can contribute so much and all the other 10 billion people already haven't contributed.
Scott: Oh, definitely.
Scott: You have something to say - no one else has to say.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure I can say this though starting Probably a week and a half from now.
Rym: You're gonna see rims blog heavy precipitous Meteoric rise.
Scott: so it's a one post Probably about.
Rym: I think I can manage a post a week at minimum.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: In fact, I'm willing to put money up but I'm still in the process of installing stuff on my laptop and configuring things.
Scott: I know what you need to install besides Firefox Audacity, you know, you don't need that to blog.
Rym: I need that to do night stuff iTunes cuz.
Rym: I'm not gonna use the Mac for that anymore.
Scott: That's very good idea.
Rym: I got a lot of things I'm gonna use this laptop for.
Rym: Right also set up the fingerprint reader and setting up the.
Scott: that's already kind of set up.
Scott: You just wave your finger and then it works.
Rym: I just set up all the like password things I can do with it.
Rym: I can do some cool stuff internally with it.
Rym: Yeah, and also the camera.
Rym: I played with it a little bit and I might just start putting really bad YouTube's of my face off on YouTube.
Scott: How are you gonna record these?
Rym: uh, it comes with some software.
Scott: They can't be good software.
Rym: It's good enough for YouTube.
Rym: Uh YouTube doesn't need much plus.
Scott: The only YouTube you can make is your face talking.
Rym: I could also hold stuff up.
Scott: I guess You could you know, you could use the webcam for actually that wouldn't suck testicles.
Scott: Well, no you could.
Scott: you could Skype people and you could see you what you're skyping them.
Rym: Yeah, I don't really have a need for that though I guess that'd be good if we were interviewing someone because then especially someone who's not used to being on the radio you can get that kind of a People on skype show things to them.
Scott: Like what do you think about this?
Scott: and hold up my testicles?
Scott: great Great.
Rym: Yeah, no You didn't have a leader bit.
Rym: I had to kind of just kind of.
Scott: you know Cuz this is my day is my day has been pretty much.
Scott: wake up get ready to go to work.
Scott: Take one train later than I usually take, you know all this week.
Scott: I've been taking the one train later.
Scott: Oh, why cuz I'm lazy.
Scott: Yeah, and this morning actually forget to set my alarm.
Scott: I Wasn't going to take the later train, but Wow Actually forgot to set the alarm.
Scott: I woke up at like quarter to seven.
Scott: I didn't take a shower.
Rym: you luckily with this IP phone and all this stuff I got if I actually woke up too late to catch my train I could pretty much just do my job from home.
Scott: I could do my job from home, too.
Scott: I just you know don't see.
Rym: I would and they wouldn't you know pay me to see my job would pay me to it.
Rym: In fact, I I have a feeling I'm not gonna test this yet cuz I'm doing a lot of work But I'm pretty sure I'd be a lot more productive at home than I am in the office.
Scott: Yeah, they of course anyone will say that.
Scott: Yeah, I'll be more productive at home.
Rym: Yeah, see I think I would be because when I work when I worked from home at IBM I always got more done in like the four hours I worked from home before I actually drove into the office than I ever did in my office.
Scott: Well, I think I'd be more productive as a whole in my life.
Scott: I work from home.
Rym: I don't know if I'd be more productive in terms of my work for work, you know for work I definitely think I would be mostly because people can't walk up to me and say hey You work on the blah.
Rym: They can only interact with me via email and telephone calls.
Scott: I see that actually doesn't that?
Scott: that's actually Like I'll be sitting there with no work and someone will come and say hey do the blah and that's like.
Scott: that's how I get Work.
Rym: my job is different because my job is basically stare at very important computers and react furiously if anything it all goes wrong with them and also networks and stuff.
Rym: but When nothing is going wrong, I have enough Proactive kind of cool work to do.
Rym: I Have more work to do that I don't have to do which is work that I can do when I'm not working on more important like critical things.
Rym: Then I had in my previous two jobs combined.
Scott: ever is that's the kind of work.
Scott: late is if there's work That doesn't have to be done.
Scott: Usually I don't do it.
Scott: I'll just play like flash games instead.
Rym: Well, see this is work.
Rym: I want to do.
Rym: this is like that big out the stuff.
Rym: I always said man, if only a company would let me do this.
Rym: and now I have a company.
Rym: that's like please do this.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have too much of that.
Rym: I'm setting up a wiki's.
Scott: Amen wiki's.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I can we can we move on to news things today.
Rym: What do you got in the news here?
Rym: All right, actually captain didn't have a news until just now.
Scott: Well, I stopped reading news and things.
Scott: So now it's very hard for me to get a news, especially on Thursday, you know, at least on like Tuesday I can read gaming blogs or Wednesday.
Scott: I can read anime.
Rym: On Thursday, I just go to Google News and there's like four things on the front page I could talk about.
Scott: I went to Google News and I didn't find anything particularly interesting until I looked at the local Google News And I found out a story.
Rym: just it's a story about his doodoo from yesterday.
Scott: No That would have been great.
Rym: I wish cuz I know that it what whatever it was wasn't there this morning.
Scott: No, this is just a simple, you know crime watch news story from the town of B.
Rym: Oh, man At RIT.
Rym: The only reason to read the reporter was the crime one.
Scott: Yeah, you did some stupid Unlike other schools, which have real like school newspapers RIT had this weekly magazine.
Scott: that was you know, no offense to the people who worked on it because they did what they could do, you know what they were allowed to do, but It sucked pretty
Rym: much every year at some point the University of Rochester We're just kind of dropped their school newspaper off and
Scott: which is a real newspaper on newsprint
Rym: as this kind of big.
Rym: Haha Fuck you.
Rym: Here's a real newspaper guys.
Scott: Yeah, and even though I didn't go to their school their newspaper was good to read.
Rym: Also their arcade.
Rym: All right God, we lived at RIT.
Rym: RIT was awesome But if you wanted to play arcade games or read a newspaper, you had to go to the University of Rochester All right.
Rym: So anyway, of course if you wanted to learn, okay, you're dragging it out here.
Rym: I am dragging it out Let's not.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Because I want this episode shorter.
Scott: And I want to eat.
Scott: Okay Anyway, so check out this local crime watch news.
Scott: Usually the best part of the shitty RIT newspaper was the new.
Scott: the crime news is the crime news from Beacon.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: Okay, so a guy He was driving 25 years old around 8 at night on Church Street.
Scott: He's driving.
Rym: I know where that is.
Scott: Yeah, I know where that is, too.
Scott: It's it's in the town we live in right and the cops try to pull him over.
Rym: huh for what?
Scott: You know for not wearing a seatbelt.
Scott: Aha the cops saw he didn't have a seatbelt.
Scott: so the cop goes.
Rym: We you know, I'm often dubious because I look at other cars and unless I am right there You can't tell if someone's wearing a seatbelt or not unless you're really really gunning for him.
Scott: Okay, regardless right the cops start chasing him, you know for the seatbelt, right and he doesn't.
Scott: he doesn't pull over.
Rym: All right, obviously car full of weed.
Scott: Oh So he keeps driving away from the cops the cops chasing down Church Street, right and they see something fly out the window of the car.
Rym: ha obviously a dime bag.
Scott: Okay, so they they pull.
Scott: they finally pull them over.
Rym: I got to say one thing to this dude regardless of where the story goes and this is a public service announcement There are two parts one and I'm quoting someone else.
Rym: No one ever got arrested for pot brownies.
Rym: and two if You're gonna get pulled over Unless it's out in the open or you were smoking it just then which is a bad idea They're not gonna.
Rym: they're gonna give you a ticket from speeding or whatever and you're gonna go along your business.
Scott: So anyway, they got him right for the seatbelt, whatever and they did their police thing, right?
Scott: And then they went and they went they found the thing he threw out of the window.
Rym: So the obvious was this not a dime bag because I'm hoping that the story suddenly turns Park.
Scott: No, it was a. it was a CD case a CD jewel case full of CDs.
Scott: No full of two and a half ounces of cocaine.
Scott: Oh Okay, okay, right.
Rym: So oh because if if you would said two and a half ounces of weed, I would have said wow no, no, that's like that.
Scott: that's Dwayne said right here, but It's in his.
Scott: it fit in a CD case.
Scott: It was two and a half ounces.
Scott: if you would have just left the CD case where your CD cases in your car go how would the cops have seen it were they?
Rym: it's not like if you had just pulled over calmly and Acted like a normal person or pulled over and gone into the tirade of fucking officers seatbelt blah.
Rym: even then yeah They would have gotten you for the seatbelt and maybe you know, like the the dice hanging there or something.
Rym: But they wouldn't really have had probable cause to search your card.
Rym: now You're a dumbass.
Rym: a lot of marijuana people get caught because they were smoking it right then in which case I have no sympathy for You at all.
Rym: No smoking weed and driving.
Scott: No, that's a bad idea.
Rym: You weren't smoking it right then?
Rym: I mean granted if you've got a lot of it Just snorted some of the cocaine.
Rym: but even then there is a somewhat distinctive scent of marijuana.
Rym: I've smelled it often at our eyes.
Scott: smells like trash.
Rym: It smells like dammit Dwayne.
Rym: Yeah, actually no doesn't smell at all like dammit Dwayne because no one would sell dammit Dwayne any damn weed Because he was called dammit Dwayne for a reason dammit Dwayne dammit, but Unless you were just smoking it.
Rym: Well, what cocaine?
Rym: 2.5 ounces of that is not going to smell like anything At least not if it's in a CD jewel case.
Scott: and I think this just this is a really great argument of not to snort cocaine.
Scott: because you know if you If you snort cocaine, it'll make you so stupid that you'll be caught with two and a half ounces of cocaine.
Scott: You see if he wasn't snorting the cocaine Like if I had had that cocaine in my car and if I wasn't snorting it I wouldn't have been stupid because they wouldn't they wouldn't have fucked up my brain and I wouldn't have gotten caught.
Rym: Well anecdotal evidence seems to indicate that Cocaine doesn't really make you stupid so much as it just turns you into kind of an asshole kind of a really intense asshole.
Scott: Well, obviously it makes you stupid because here I have I guess I have correlating sort of evidence and not so much the causation Submit that provides what there's a there's a correlation of one-to-one here.
Scott: in my sample I submit my my scientific study of people who snow who snorted cocaine and people who are so stupid They got caught with a small amount of it.
Rym: simple dude was kind of dumb and panicked and If had he not panicked, he would have had a relatively minor ticket that he probably could have fought in court.
Scott: Yep So I in other news, I think it just goes well with your fake seat belt from yesterday The fake seat belt.
Rym: that guy's almost my hero Is the antihero.
Scott: if antihero meant something different but I like antiheroes I don't like him.
Rym: I guess I like him.
Scott: in the I said if antihero meant something different as in the opposite of hero.
Rym: Anyway, so I'm not gonna talk about the details of this, but I think it's kind of cool.
Rym: There's this article on slashdot about Nanotechnology powered wiperless windshields.
Rym: now people always talk about yeah The future is flying cars and terabit Ethernet and in like levitating whatever and how and collect up.
Rym: The real future of science is things like this simple Technological advances that can just make a known problem go away forever.
Rym: The idea here now, there's also a cool side bit.
Rym: There's no English article.
Rym: There is a translation of the Italian article done by the Google thing.
Rym: How can you trust that if you just read the article and didn't know it was translated You wouldn't know it was translated.
Scott: the Google translators come a long Freaking way because I remember the last time this happened where the only source was a foreign article Was that time where it was like Australia they made werewolves.
Rym: That was Russia.
Rym: I thought I Forget plus.
Rym: that article has come up perennially and it always has the same picture of a dog every time.
Scott: Yep, but this story the idea no zombie dogs, not werewolves.
Rym: Yeah, whatever the idea here Is that what if you made a windshield using you know?
Rym: Nanosurfaces?
Rym: that just was hydrophobic to the point that you didn't need windshield wipers?
Scott: And see this is a. this is the kind of problem where you know solving it or coming up with a better solution right is difficult because it's basically you only notice problems that are problematic.
Scott: and if we have a Solution for something right it's Unless you like our your attention is drawn to it.
Scott: I mean the problem of water on windshields is solved by windshield wipers.
Scott: so no one thinks well Yeah, so no one thinks to solve that problem because it's not a problem It's not an annoyance.
Scott: in everyday life people only think to solve the problems for which there is no solution.
Scott: and since Pretty much most of the things of everyday life are sort of solved to some extent.
Scott: That's why we've sort of switched from Invention to innovation.
Scott: you know where you're sort of improving on things, but even then it's hard to Recognize that something needs improvement when the existing solution is not so bad now.
Rym: beyond that they claim that these Nanosurfaces could theoretically also Remove dirt from the windshield by moving it toward the side and then eliminating it.
Rym: so make the rest of your car dirtier Basically making it an active windshield that does not require wipers.
Scott: That's pretty good if it works.
Scott: I think the thing is does it only work if you're driving.
Scott: I mean cuz like I don't know this is such.
Scott: Does it require the wind of the car moving?
Rym: cuz it looks like it's powered power with electricity.
Rym: Yes, okay, however Someone this is a side that I brought up this articles.
Rym: I think this is cool And I think it makes the point that regardless of how well this specific technology turns out or works or whatever The future of a lot of technology are very very minor subtle improvements to our day-to-day lives.
Rym: that That's how to write good science fiction is to have these little touches like if you write a thing that's set 30 years in the future No cars have winch no sards of windshield wipers because you don't need them anymore and just you know little things like that.
Scott: Can you think of one other thing like that?
Rym: Probably if I put my mind to it But I want to get you.
Scott: I thought see that's not see.
Scott: actually I think that's the harder part than Figuring out like the net the actual nanotechnology of doors that just use biometrics.
Rym: I walk out to my house and the door opens when I walk up no matter what they kind of sort of have that kind Of just without me having to do anything active.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I guess elevators without doors.
Rym: We could have those now, but we don't because of a lot of problems that could be.
Scott: that could be the falling out of them.
Scott: Yes So so what problem?
Scott: what problem is solved by removing elevator doors from elevators?
Rym: You don't have to wait for the door to open and close Wanted me to get to the point because you want the show to end quickly.
Rym: So my point here was simply that it was noted that this was powered and Someone made an argument about wasting power and then someone brought up Daytime running lights now.
Scott: Oh, this is what you're gonna talk about.
Rym: I have a very short rant.
Rym: I don't think I need to get into all the details.
Rym: if you disagree with me, you're wrong.
Rym: I don't think you understand the level of hatred and shit that will come down upon you or me.
Scott: I don't think you realize how wrong you are.
Rym: This isn't a matter of opinion as a matter of fact But someone made the point of yeah, it's wasteful just like daytime running lights pushed upon us by the cartels.
Rym: Whatever waste of resources.
Rym: don't do anything annoying as hell and there are a lot of people who are really against Daytime running lights now, they're morons.
Rym: I'm of the mind that daytime running lights should be absolutely mandatory as they are in Canada and a lot of other civilized nations.
Scott: I think that every single car I think if you don't have daytime running lights You should have to have your headlights on all the time
Rym: Now that the problem with that is that there is a difference in that Headlights do use more electricity are brighter are not designed for that.
Rym: daytime running lights are.
Rym: they're very different.
Scott: I do know this.
Scott: However, the safety that will be increased by having the headlights on is working constant energy.
Scott: I think there's a much simpler way and eventually those people get newer cars.
Rym: just do a candidate.
Scott: All they said was all new cars have to have daytime running lights and eventually yeah, but itself Yeah, but you know, it'll eventually solve itself, but we can actually enforce because people right now They don't even know how to use their headlights.
Scott: They put on like their parking lights on the highway when it's raining and I'm like you piece of shit Turn on your fucking headlights.
Rym: those are like the same people who don't brush off the top of their car after a heavy snow.
Scott: exactly.
Scott: if I were a State trooper those those I would give all my tickets to people who don't know how to use their headlights and people who don't brush Off the top of their car.
Rym: But anyway, I'm not going to get into all the reasons.
Rym: But daytime running lights being mandatory is a good idea from so many perspectives like The anyone who is against it either is an idiot or doesn't understand all of the scientific evidence backing the fact that they are an amazing idea.
Scott: they increase safety but God, so there are numerous high-quality Scientific studies that clearly show that daytime running lights decrease accidents Tremendously, this is why you get such a break on your insurance if you have them.
Scott: Trust me your insurance wouldn't give you a break on something if they didn't have to.
Scott: They're giving it to you for daytime running lights because it does reduce the chances of you getting in an accident incredibly significantly.
Rym: things of the day.
Rym: now I'm probably never gonna do a thing of the day from this again because In case you're not aware of it.
Rym: There's this thing called the onion.
Rym: now The onion is my favorite newspaper my favorite news network.
Rym: My favorite God.
Rym: I've loved the onion pretty much forever.
Rym: Well, I don't think I need to explain what the onion is.
Scott: you can figure it out the level of professionalism Do they have at the onion for their podcast and their video?
Rym: Okay, the onion radio news and the onion news network their production values rival the real news.
Scott: That's the production value that we at GeekNights are aiming to to get now.
Scott: That's the level we're shooting for now.
Rym: It's hit or miss with the onion news network.
Rym: the onion radio news is always solid gold.
Rym: always almost The onion newspaper is hit or miss.
Rym: I mean the articles are always that's got ads in it too are very very clever.
Rym: It just depends on.
Rym: sometimes they're clever in a cheeky way and sometimes they're clever in an absolutely amazing way.
Rym: But this particular onion news network now one it takes a stab at d-bold.
Rym: Oh It takes a very clever stab at d-bold.
Rym: and number three, it takes a vicious.
Rym: vicious stab at d-bold.
Scott: the level of Vicious It's a triple stabbing is what you're saying.
Rym: I mean The onion is usually really kind of tongue-in-cheek and funny and they tend to lean to the left and actually know that I should take That back because in American politics when people say liberal or left they actually mean centrist.
Rym: There are almost no liberals in American politics and haven't been for a long time Pretty much at least any that had a chance or mattered.
Scott: if you think that like, you know Like Obama or Hillary Clinton or the or even Bill Clinton or Bill Clinton.
Scott: if you think that is liberal or leftist if you think that's leftist you have no idea what leftist is.
Scott: Lenin is left.
Scott: That's left.
Scott: Okay, Bill Clinton far away from left Bill Clinton very far away was a socially liberal But right-leaning political centrist.
Rym: Yeah, also a fiscal conservative nowhere near Chums nachos Noam Chomsky.
Scott: No, I'm sorry.
Rym: He's special.
Scott: He's a pretty low.
Scott: I meant to say Trotsky.
Rym: Yes Yes, Trotsky Chomsky effectively the same political.
Scott: Yeah, I know right.
Rym: I'm fan.
Rym: Noam Chomsky is hit 50/50 as well.
Scott: But yeah, I know but the the Oski but got me.
Rym: this is funny and tongue-in-cheek but I gotta say the Onion News Network this particular d-bold leaks the 2008 election results is So vicious.
Rym: but in that court jester, haha You can't actually do anything to me because I'm obviously making a joke.
Rym: I pushed the parody so far that if you actually tried to sue me for what I just said you would be laughed out Of court, but at the same time, oh man, is it vicious, especially when they get the quote-unquote d-bold representative?
Scott: Mmm, man good actors - very good actors.
Rym: They kind of pull that Colbert.
Rym: It's so stupid, but yet they do it so straight-faced.
Scott: It's good.
Scott: It's the onion.
Scott: I really like the straight-faced comedy But I love the interviews of the people on the street.
Scott: That's always the best part of the onion.
Scott: Oh, yes it is Alright, so check this out ready.
Scott: 2008 North Dakota high school state hockey championships.
Rym: There's no way.
Scott: this is not awesome, North Dakota Definitely cares about the hockey because their state hockey their state high school hockey championships are in What looks to be a full-sized arena of hockey right with you know real refs and real ice and the whole thing, right?
Scott: bigger than the RIT's hockey arena.
Scott: this is a game between.
Scott: it's the championship game between Grafton Park River and Grand Forks River.
Scott: Okay, I don't know a GFR and GPR.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm not from North Dakota.
Scott: All I know is is a game of hockey and all I know is that in this video?
Scott: What we have here is a situation in which the game is tied and there is not much time left.
Scott: Now when a game is tied and there is not much time left What do I actually know?
Scott: I think a team is winning by one.
Scott: The score is not on the screen.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So what do you do?
Scott: Well, like the score is not on the screen.
Scott: So yeah, so I can't really you know, figure out Because a high school game it's you know, someone in the crowd with a camera man.
Rym: I was waiting for you to say what do you do.
Rym: so I could say shoot the hostage But anyway, no, so okay a team is down by one.
Scott: All right, the hockey game is almost over.
Scott: What do you do?
Rym: start a fight?
Rym: No Kill the opponent's ref.
Scott: It's a much simpler.
Rym: and a ref.
Scott: Okay Rym pretend you're the coach of a hockey team.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: All right, you're down by one.
Scott: There's not much time left.
Scott: What do you?
Scott: what do you say?
Rym: Well, all right what I do and this is kind of like one of those game theory like there's an obvious answer.
Rym: There is an obvious answer you pull the goalie Yeah, and you put in your special offensive team Which is basically these six people who are your best offensive players, right?
Rym: You tell them score a goddamn goal or I'm murdering all of you after this Okay.
Scott: Now now let's say you want to pull the goalie, right?
Scott: What are the mechanics?
Scott: How do you pull the goalie without having the referee come after you?
Rym: Well, it's tricky because there's a lot of leeway in terms of how many men are on the ice.
Rym: But as long as the goalie is on his way Toward the bench and you put someone else out You can usually get away with it.
Scott: get away with it is what has happened here, basically They just put a sixth man out on the ice, you know
Rym: the too many men if you get away with it That's that's because if there are many times at RIT We'd be watching a game and the Tigers would put out an extra man for like 10 seconds and no one noticed Except us and we kept our mouths shut.
Rym: Of course whenever the other team tried this we had a guy whose job It was to count at all times the opponent's team and at any time.
Rym: if there were even a hint of six men The entire crowd would immediately be queued to start chanting too many men.
Rym: And if you're at a women's hockey game, it was too many people Too many people and many a time the ref would look up hear it because you could hear it.
Rym: We chatted in unison and you didn't see 50 people going.
Scott: too many men too many men.
Rym: look at the ice and go Oh Tweet yeah to which the opponent's coach would always go.
Scott: what the fuck what the fuck you had.
Scott: too many men tweet.
Scott: The refs loved and hated us right anyway, this is a video.
Scott: and watching this video.
Scott: There is no Denying none.
Scott: Absolutely.
Scott: No denying whatsoever That what has happened here right is that a guy came out of the booth, right?
Scott: But well before the goalie was in the booth way before right?
Rym: Not only that He got the puck.
Scott: pretty much as he came out of the booth Which is the definition of too many men is when the puck goes near, you know You can have a guy sort of come out on the ice as long as the puck doesn't go over there.
Scott: Like you know if they if you're far away from the play, it's sort of okay.
Scott: ish The gets the puck he takes it over and he scores.
Scott: he's the sixth man will the seventh man?
Scott: because the goalie was still on the ice and That forces a tie.
Scott: and then they win in overtime.
Rym: So no one noticed from the other team.
Scott: No, well, they totally noticed and everyone's yelling going boo.
Scott: Whoo too many men.
Scott: and then they say there's a. the refs are you know, We're sitting there discussing it like ah fuck.
Scott: and here is on YouTube undeniable video evidence of this travesty.
Scott: I really don't have a stake in either of these two teams But I feel for the team that is lost because they got screwed But at the same time plus one balls for pulling that shit The team that was bad call ref won the game.
Scott: for the other team They definitely too many men on the ice.
Scott: They had like let's see six then they had the goalie so seven and then Three refs.
Scott: so is nine on nine on six?
Scott: not very fair.
Rym: Wow Yeah, so we had a lot of trouble coming up with the show to do tonight.
Scott: We basically sat around for the last 10-15 minutes going.
Scott: Let's do a show on this.
Rym: Originally planned to talk about Disney But like Disney World Disneyland or maybe Disney movies or Disney something just rotten.
Rym: Maybe not Disney movies.
Rym: We wanted something kind of short, but most of my memories of Are actually about the awesome road trips I took with my family or other like all the events around Disney World Disney itself, man Yeah, Disney World isn't you know, there's.
Scott: there are some people who are like Disney World geeks, you know, but It's.
Scott: it's really not the super exciting But there's just.
Scott: there's so many things there cuz you know It's such a big place with such a long history That if you've been there even once that you can talk about it for at least one shows worth.
Rym: Yeah, but tonight was not that night.
Rym: we wanted something quick because we're still kind of recovering from concert con and We're actually already ramping up to get ready for the big stuff.
Rym: We're gonna be doing at other conventions This August.
Rym: Yes, and we got a lot of stuff to get ready.
Rym: Yeah God stupid podcast.
Rym: So, uh, we needed something quick.
Rym: Let's talk about underwear.
Scott: I mean we were basically sat around and I was just like, you know trying to think of other shows we've done and like you know try not to repeat a show and
Rym: It had to be something short and not something good because we didn't want to waste something good on a night when we're tired
Scott: And it's Thursday.
Scott: So I'm trying to think of something like not related to you know.
Scott: I just try to think of something that compete that relates to every human being you know.
Rym: And plus this went like this weekend.
Rym: We're gonna record the rest of our katsucon coverage.
Rym: So we got like another hour to record at some point.
Scott: Yeah, so my brain just sort of eventually wandered from like, you know The masturbation episodes like the hygiene episode underwear.
Rym: I'm like, uh, I'm a boxer's man And I think briefs are like the worst thing you can ever Inflict upon yourself.
Scott: I wear the briefs, but I am NOT.
Scott: I'm not like, you know Adamantly opposed to other types of underwear except for the boxer brief, which I which is terrible.
Rym: I don't know how you can deal with wearing briefs.
Scott: Yeah, I just I just put them on and I go but they kind of hold everything up there and together.
Scott: That's if you get they're too small and you should buy new ones even if they're too big.
Rym: I need to be able to hang completely loose.
Scott: But then you could like See when I hang completely loose, you know, cuz I wear boxers, you know, I like I've one or two pair.
Scott: Sometimes I'll wear.
Rym: maybe I don't have saggy ball syndrome.
Scott: It's not the balls that say it's you know The the stake.
Scott: he'll go down one leg or the other leg or out the hole.
Rym: I'd rather him be able to go down a leg and get his exercise then be crammed into a tiny little space.
Scott: He's not rammed in he's.
Scott: he's going up.
Scott: He's going up.
Rym: I don't want him to go up.
Rym: If he goes down I can hire.
Scott: he's not bouncing back and forth, you know slapping around.
Rym: If he's going down I can hide him, especially if he gets excited, but if he's going up I got problems going up.
Scott: He's perfectly hidden right in the middle.
Scott: if he's going down one leg or the other That's when you can see him one leg protruding if you're wearing span more than the other leg if you're wearing tight pants.
Rym: I can see your point.
Scott: I'm not wearing tight I don't.
Scott: I never wear any tight pants so you can't see him no matter where he is.
Scott: But the point is there's a better chance of seeing him if he goes down one leg or the other.
Rym: I feel like I'd rather have even if it's not a tight pant.
Scott: It could be pulled taut against one leg or the other.
Rym: plus usually I mean I definitely am of the camp of grower Not a shower.
Scott: So not like I'm also the girl without a shower.
Rym: He's not in use.
Rym: nice and compact It's usually.
Scott: that's why he's so nice and compact.
Rym: I can point him up, but I'd rather have him go down.
Scott: No, I would not rather have him go down.
Rym: the sense of freedom the exhilaration just that having so much space down They're so important to me.
Scott: and then why don't you just go commando?
Rym: The only reason I don't is because one Occasionally zipper is exposed to flesh.
Scott: You know, I don't really Like other, you know people they like.
Scott: they open just the zipper.
Rym: That's I'm talking about.
Rym: sometimes, you know There's rough spots in the denim or in the pen depending on what pants I'm wearing and I need that one thin layer of protection.
Scott: That's exactly what the brief is.
Scott: It's just a layer of protection between the parts of your body or the boxers But the boxers.
Rym: it's like you're not wearing underwear But you still have.
Scott: that's the thing is sometimes the boxers are sort of not a complete layer of protection.
Scott: Yes, they are.
Rym: Yeah, only if you have broken boxers.
Scott: Look, it's like they have a hole in the front, you know, that's more loose and the boxers.
Rym: I mean my quality boxers.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing is there.
Scott: they're mad expensive.
Scott: I buy Quality box.
Scott: how much money they cost?
Scott: I've spent between about five to fifteen dollars per boxer see per boxer for 15 bucks I get a sack of briefs like a huge.
Rym: Over the years my policy especially in college when it came to laundry and this is important and I think anyone who wears underwear Should follow a similar strategy and then every time you were forced to do laundry when you were not prepared to Look at take inventory and say alright What was it that forced me to do laundry?
Rym: and you should probably buy more of whatever that was.
Rym: So you're never forced to do laundry, but laundry at your leisure,
Scott: but eventually You're going to have like way too much of everything
Rym: or eventually you'll get to the point where you will get to the debt the time Or day when you are willing and ready to do laundry before you run out of something and are fucked.
Scott: I guess that's possible.
Rym: I've reached that point.
Scott: I would just if I had more like if I had ten more shirts ten more pants ten more everything, right?
Scott: I would just do laundry ten days ten twenty days after all that way, but in college I did.
Rym: in college I would wear the last scrap.
Rym: I'd wear that loincloth before I would do laundry.
Scott: Oh that line fly.
Rym: that was a pair of boxers that was basically worn down to the point because they had having money in college.
Rym: It was basically a loincloth and even then it was mostly Transparent people.
Scott: people did not enjoy when you wore that and nothing else, but it was so comfortable.
Scott: Yeah, not comfortable for everyone's eyes.
Rym: When I hit the point in college It was usually socks or boxers and I'd buy more whenever I could get some money.
Rym: as a result I have like 25 pairs of boxers.
Scott: See the one advantage.
Scott: Yeah, you know, I do wear the boxers sometimes and I don't like how it manages the boys.
Scott: However, there is one advantage of the boxer that I do like and that is the the airflow of the block.
Rym: Yes, the airflow is key because whitey tighties tiny white easy got it backwards cause the Cause the gases and the sweat to be really close to you at all times and not you see if you manage them properly It's really it's not unpleasant events.
Scott: The thing is is actually the boxer is so airy.
Scott: It's like ah, right The thing is right and I have tested this in my in my lab I wearing a lab coat that if you actually keep wearing the boxer at least for me Right, then the airiness you actually sort of stop noticing it because you don't have the brief to sort of compare it to.
Scott: I notice it every day.
Scott: It's like it's a relative thing.
Rym: It's like if you keep drinking cold water then wait a minute, but you know what that argument is.
Rym: You should eat shitty food.
Rym: Just so you appreciate the good food.
Rym: You should drive a shitty car every now and then just remind yourself of it's not shitty.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's different.
Rym: It has shitty.
Scott: No, it's.
Rym: one is good in one way Another way and neither is completely serious one use for for tight underwear But even then I prefer the boxer briefs.
Scott: if I'm gonna wear a tight underwear a box of briefs Oh, no Cuz the way because that basically a boxer brief is the worst thing ever cuz all it is is a pretty cool shield.
Scott: It's a brief right, which is fine.
Scott: But then it just has these leg things which are just really tight.
Scott: cloth against the legs are not that tight.
Scott: It's tight cloth against your legs for no reason whatsoever.
Rym: Because otherwise if you were just whitey-tighty whitey's especially if it's a sweaty environment Oftentimes, especially if it's really hot out you might saturate them.
Scott: and then as you okay, I'm pants I have never saturated the briefs ever.
Rym: Maybe that's cuz you never exert yourself.
Scott: Never have the briefs become saturated.
Scott: that that is not.
Scott: you never go running or actually Biking or a mountain climbing or anything and if I were in a situation where I think they might become saturated I would go for the boxer.
Scott: that way the boxer isn't really touching me.
Rym: It wouldn't absorb any know because if you're in glow in heavy Activity and also the air would evaporate at all if you're engaged in a heavy activity like that.
Rym: You're gonna need some support.
Scott: You can get some support from other places like jock strap.
Rym: You don't want to wear a jock strap you want to wear boxer briefs?
Scott: Yeah, boxer briefs are never doors.
Rym: the other the other.
Rym: the other important part is that nobody has tidy silks But a lot of people have silk boxers.
Rym: not gonna tell you.
Rym: in my life I've always kept at least one pair of silk boxers ready.
Rym: and while you do not want to get engaged Then you strain use activity and silk boxers because wet wet silk is basically very fine sandpaper.
Rym: But that's true silk boxers.
Scott: So boxers can be pretty nice especially for like a pajama type situation something along those lines or a Sexy time situation.
Rym: of course.
Rym: one step beyond that is the dangerous velvet boxers.
Scott: Well, I was about to say in high school.
Scott: Somebody had a a girlfriend of theirs Construct for them the velvet boxer thinking if the silk boxer is so great would not the velvet or velour boxer be infinitely greater?
Scott: Yes, and the answer is yes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It is so great.
Scott: The problem is no, it's too great It is too great that it causes, uh, it can cause problems Problems indeed messes if you will, huh?
Scott: Yes do not Go for the velvet or velour boxer unless you Yeah, unless you know what you're in for.
Rym: and I got one thing to say though There's not this common colloquial, you know skid marks people the word comes up.
Rym: I will say this to you if you've got skid marks, you're not wiping properly and that's the end of that.
Rym: Good God Well, okay Okay, there's there's in the vast majority of cases.
Scott: You are correct.
Scott: However, there is.
Rym: there is the shart incident The occasional shard or the occasional incident is okay.
Rym: however, if you have Perennial skid marks or many a percentage of your boxers have permanent skid marks Then you are either a sharding way too much or be not wiping enough.
Scott: or see all the above.
Scott: got a white bro Got a wife You should wipe so much.
Scott: See the thing is you need to wipe until you don't see anything anymore, right?
Scott: I'm the toilet paper.
Rym: Yeah, did I see a lot of?
Rym: well I guess I don't see.
Rym: but I hear tell of a lot of people who blind wipe.
Rym: they wipe a bunch and then they just Pull the pants up.
Rym: No, no good.
Rym: You got to do that final test.
Rym: It's like the scientist like alright Is it clean?
Rym: final wipe it's clean.
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: Yes, me and Rym agree on this issue that you need to wipe until you don't see anything in more.
Scott: Rym uses much too much toilet paper to accomplish this task and the an Adequate cleaning can be accomplished with far less toilet paper than Rym uses.
Rym: I would.
Rym: I would make the counter.
Rym: this is why Rym buys the toilet paper I would make a counter use is way too much of it that I use a normal amount of toilet paper and that Scott has a filthy ass.
Scott: Yes, skid marks.
Scott: None.
Rym: Should we go charity ass?
Scott: No, no check.
Rym: Pull out all our boxers or briefs if we're heathens and compare.
Scott: We can compare whatever you want, but mine are gonna hold this offer.
Rym: I think we have a separate show on poopin.
Rym: Regardless I why you need a show on poopin?
Scott: I wipe my ass until there is nothing on the toilet paper and I use less toilet paper than you use.
Rym: I was a Somewhat dedicated reader of poop report back at RIT.
Rym: I study the science of pooping.
Rym: I try to make pooping a more pleasant experience for myself and as the eminent Dave Riley said in When asked the question, what are the best and worst things in the world?
Rym: The best thing in the world is pooping.
Rym: the worst thing in the world is too much pooping.
Scott: Yeah, I Just want to go end this on a point We brought up earlier about when when you go to pee, I guess girls this show really doesn't apply to you.
Rym: Oh, this is a guy thing.
Rym: Definitely We know every guy with rare exceptions has experienced this at some point.
Rym: Maybe not to this degree, but there are situations where I don't know if it's primal Whatever like the base of the spine kind of action.
Rym: But some there are certain situations where a man body will say, you know what not gonna pay It's not the time we're not peeing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now some people have this problem a little bit.
Rym: I think that's what Scott was gonna allude to.
Scott: Well, what I was gonna allude to is that some people when they go to pee, right?
Scott: They will you know, just open the zipper.
Scott: Oh Pull the boys out.
Rym: I thought you're talking about the shameful peers and the shame.
Scott: No, no, no, they'll pull the boys out through the hole in their underwears and then through the hole in the zipper.
Rym: I got this to say Most of my pants.
Rym: I really don't think that's.
Scott: that's not gonna happen.
Scott: He's gonna scratch me scratch scratch my John Thomas up on the zipper.
Scott: It's no.
Rym: guess The young master does not really fit well through a zipper or button only hole right.
Rym: bring the whole thing down, right?
Scott: So the thing is other people go too far.
Scott: They drop the drawers to the floor.
Rym: I is also seen someone over the age of seven do that.
Scott: That is unacceptable behavior.
Rym: Hey now if I ever saw a businessman do that, I would probably confront them.
Scott: I've seen it happen where At least five times.
Scott: I can't remember specific side of a highway.
Rym: rest stop where?
Scott: Highway rest stop, I think an RIT restroom once Someone who was older than seven.
Scott: I think in a office building one.
Rym: I'm dubious.
Rym: I've never seen this.
Rym: granted I don't spend a lot of time why it's rare.
Scott: It's rare.
Rym: I don't spend.
Rym: it happens Scott seems to Disagree, but I don't spend a lot of time watching other men pee.
Scott: I don't watch other guys pee either.
Rym: But yet you have all this evidence.
Scott: You can't not notice something like that.
Rym: I've never seen it though.
Scott: Regardless don't do that.
Scott: you unbutton the button undo the zipper you pull down a little bit and that's what you do.
Scott: That's what you do.
Rym: Oh and button fly.
Scott: boo Yeah, button fly is no good.
Rym: All right, I think we're done with this farce.
Scott: It was.
Scott: oh wait, I want to do one more thing.
Scott: We didn't talk about women's underwear at all But there is only one thing that guys can really say about women's underwear right and that is not comfortable.
Scott: Uh, no, I wouldn't know about how comfortable they are.
Rym: I may or may not be wearing women's underwear right now.
Scott: I'm just gonna leave that alone.
Rym: Oh my word.
Rym: You can see am I wearing women's underwear.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: I'm not looking.
Scott: however We can talk about frogs on them, but we can say about women's underwear.
Scott: Is there a level of hotness?
Scott: you see?
Scott: the old frat boy question?
Scott: Do you prefer him the the girls wearing sort of the Lacey?
Scott: Victoria's Secret underwears or do you prefer girls wearing sort of the Hanes her way kind of normal underwears?
Rym: I like a balance between the two.
Rym: Aha a balance you say because I You know, there's a time and a place for everything.
Rym: There's a time and a place for the kind of Sexually charged.
Rym: I'm wearing a garment whose sole purpose is to be taken off in the act of sex.
Rym: You mean a The underwear that just has a hole in it and then and then there is the you know, the the kind of I'm not sure how much detail I should go into.
Scott: Be completely.
Rym: I'm it's normal everyday underwear the the hey, let's have sex underwear.
Scott: All right Isn't that the other way you just talked about?
Rym: No, that's the.
Rym: hey, let's have sex.
Rym: I happen to be wearing underwear.
Scott: Oh Okay, okay Yeah, I am a fan more not so much of the like.
Scott: I like the underwears that are supposed to be sexy like the Lacey Kind of thing is.
Scott: I find them sort of anti sexy like the more normal.
Scott: Well, the other thing is that on the other end of the spectrum you have like the grandma underwear, which I also sort of find Unsexy, it's sort of like the waved about most unsexily quite the the normal underwear that bloomers.
Scott: No bloomers of the grandma underwear I'm talking about, you know, just all that bloomers are comfortable.
Scott: I I don't know I would know but normal like Hanes everyday underwear I think is the the most sexy of female underwears.
Scott: That's what I have to say.
Rym: All right, once again, let's end this farce.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Stay tuned next week when gig nights is normal again.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.