Rym: It's Tuesday September 23rd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight part 3 of our penny arcade expo 2008 coverage Sunday.
Rym: Let's do this
Scott: Alright, so there actually is a lot of video game and other game news going down But there's so much of it, and you know I feel you know because he'd done these three packed shows in a row I've had such a small no opportunity basically to talk about games.
Scott: Actually playing right now instead of a news I just sort of want to Relatively quickly go over all the games that are going on in my life right now because I am playing mad games.
Rym: Mad games yes, and particularly I got to point out It wasn't two years ago But I remember talking about PC gaming was pretty much dead and it really was two years now.
Rym: PC Gaming is full-on now like it came back and remember.
Rym: I never said it can't come back.
Rym: I just said at that point it was dead and it's been slowly like coming back.
Scott: It was just MMOs, but now Thanks to a lot of indie games.
Rym: You know what ever since portal.
Rym: Yeah, it was like portal and now I got so Multi-winning.
Scott: yeah, oh you want to multi-winning first alright.
Scott: Well.
Rym: I'm playing multi-winning yeah, so it's great.
Scott: Yeah, so back there was a game called Darwinia by this company introversion if people don't know introversion They're a British game developer, and they made uplink which everyone should play.
Scott: even though I suck at it I can't beat it cuz I suck.
Scott: they made Darwinia.
Scott: They made Defcon and they're making multi-winning.
Scott: yeah, basically Darwinia was an RTS unlike no other RTS, but it was single-player and Originally they wanted it to be multiplayer, but they failed and they only made a single-player game.
Scott: multi-winning is what Darwinia was originally going to be a multiplayer RTS.
Scott: that isn't like other RTS's and I gotta say I suck at RTS's But multi-winning after playing it a bit.
Scott: I'm actually Okay at it.
Scott: I can.
Scott: I couldn't play Defcon really that well at least against other human beings.
Rym: well I could play no Scott, and I against each other is fun.
Rym: Yeah, because we both suck equally.
Rym: so it's just like yay And then one of us wins by a little bit, but multi-winning I can actually play and it's actually really good.
Rym: well because it's you Know I like the idea and this I think you know.
Rym: there's that article a while ago about how Games from 10 15 years ago Hold up today.
Rym: but yet the majority like a lot most games from now will not hold up 10 to 15 years from now because they're just Tech.
Rym: they are not at the limits of their technology and incremental improvements make previous versions obsolete.
Rym: I mean Soulcalibur 1 was a good game.
Rym: Don't get me wrong.
Rym: It was like a revolutionary fighting game.
Rym: Soulcalibur 2 is just better.
Scott: Yeah, it's just an incremental improvement over Soulcalibur 1.
Scott: Soulcalibur 1 is you know but why play Soulcalibur 1 but like to exist?
Rym: excite bike or Tetris is a distilled game that technology could not beg better.
Rym: You could make a different game, but that game is distilled.
Scott: Yeah, what could you make?
Scott: excite bike 2 in such a way that no one would ever want to play excite bike 1?
Scott: I guess excite bike verse is that but I mean it's the same game.
Scott: basically is the same game.
Rym: I want to talk about that idea more at length because I actually have a lot to say about it And you know it might not be all the things you expect me to say about but the thing about multi winnia, right?
Scott: We'll just get this over.
Scott: It's distilled.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: multi winnia is an RTS But it doesn't have that part of the game where you
Rym: click
Scott: Faster than the other person in order to upgrade your guys fast the other poor
Rym: in order to because they get like a lot of RTS is don't really support Squatting or of that AI.
Rym: you basically whoever can click the fastest to move their units into the right positions quick enough wins.
Scott: Yeah, multi winnia is all about Moving.
Scott: it's all about controlling the flow of your units.
Scott: You know in a way.
Scott: It's a lot more like Trying to think of another game.
Rym: In many ways it's more like real warfare in that you you have you know you can give orders and send guys around But it's real time and you know information propagates slowly.
Rym: like you change your guy flow It takes a while for guys to start arriving at that new front.
Scott: Yeah, you're basically controlling a flow of units and aiming it and you know moving it around in such a way as to win depending on the scenario.
Scott: and It's actually in a way.
Scott: It's a lot like that liquid Tron you ever play that actually yeah It's a little bit like the liquid Tron where you're controlling this flow of liquid in order to sort of Tron the other guy out.
Rym: But I mean, let's not talk about the game at like People hate.
Rym: RTS is however the new just so you know Basically when it came to writing the network part of it.
Rym: They screwed the pooch and like a lot of people can't play the game online and land play Con
Scott: and similar problems, but this seems to have problems twice as bad Which is really sad because it's multi winnia, but the multiplayer is broken seriously
Rym: And it's not like it's really broken and a lot of people are having trouble with it.
Rym: And I like Scott and I were unable to why they just use the built-in steam game matching stuff.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: actually I noticed something weird.
Rym: Once I installed multi winnia none of my steam multiplayer games worked online.
Rym: I got connection attempt failed on all of them until I Restarted and when I was back in like closing steam and opening again It still didn't work, but once I restarted my computer into Windows it worked fine again for everything.
Scott: I didn't have that kind of problem.
Rym: so no, but I'm saying now that I've rebooted We should try doing multi winnia LAN again.
Rym: Maybe it'll work.
Rym: Okay like Something weird with steam.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm sure the details and hopefully a fix will come out anyway.
Scott: So yeah, what else?
Scott: Oh bionic commander rearmed still didn't beat it on normal.
Scott: Yeah, all I got to say once you don't have to play the co-op.
Rym: I think it's the best game to come out since portal.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's really good.
Scott: I don't know if it's the best.
Scott: well There's so many other good games on this list.
Rym: yes But name a better game on the PC that that is played right now by people right.
Scott: this second I guess you have to wait for Left 4 Dead to come out.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yeah, it hasn't come out.
Scott: Yeah, anyway anyway Castlevania Symphony tonight, I've played the DS, and I was trying to play the GBA Castlevania's, but I failed at that.
Rym: You know you have a couple of Chris Agram's.
Rym: yet.
Scott: No, I don't have any Chris Agram's Chris But I just you know I got the PlayStation emulator working, and I'm playing the symphony tonight Which I never played before.
Rym: and now this is another example of.
Rym: it is an incredibly amazing and important game.
Rym: I mean that basically was a revolution in that sort of game, but at the same time it suffers.
Rym: Well, it doesn't suffer, but the genre will eventually suffer from the incremental improvement.
Scott: No Well, there's no because that is actually an instance in which there is no increment.
Scott: Well what I was about to say every single game is exactly the same.
Scott: It's just more of the same which is exactly what you want.
Rym: well I was what I you didn't let me finish because I was saying something.
Rym: I was having a qualified statement.
Rym: But each of these games has enough unique character to where playing an older one is Just as fun as playing a newer one.
Scott: There's no unique character.
Scott: They're all exactly the same game.
Scott: It's just a different map.
Scott: well There is like if someone has got there is unique character.
Rym: the maps are different the characters are different the music and all that like.
Rym: The atmosphere is different Totally different.
Scott: the weapons are mostly the same.
Scott: All these games are pretty much is more of the same game, and they're all awesome because you can't get enough.
Scott: It's like if someone just made Super Metroid with a different map.
Scott: you couldn't get enough of that.
Rym: everyone has a unique gimmick.
Rym: I mean the.
Rym: the first DS one had the swapping loadouts gimmick.
Rym: the second one had the two people gimmick and each Gimmick is ain't it of itself fun?
Scott: It was that the gimmicks barely play into it.
Scott: the gimmicks are not what make the game is fun.
Rym: the gimmick I know I would disagree and say that they they.
Rym: They give each game a very unique character to where each one is independently amazing.
Rym: Yeah, however the the symphony tonight has the gimmick of it's not first one.
Rym: Anyway, also the soundtrack is amazing.
Scott: Yeah, well cuz it was actually on a CD.
Scott: So they actually Say it's amazing.
Rym: I say it's amazing because the music Even if it was never in a game is really good music.
Scott: Well the point that's what I'm saying is that back in those days?
Scott: Games are on CDs and all what they could do with a CD in those days was Put really good music on it.
Scott: cuz CDs originally for music.
Rym: But no in those days like is good.
Rym: in the same way that a lot of Final Fantasy guest soundtracks were good because it was basically semi symphonic or symphonic music composed for the game as opposed to when they CDs for games.
Scott: in those days they because that was their advantage especially on something like the Sega CD and the PlayStation early days They tried really hard to make really good music Scott.
Rym: They tried really hard to make really good music for SNES games to some games.
Rym: I mean, yeah the Final Fantasy soundtrack Final Fantasy 6 Had an amazing soundtrack because it was composed for the game and it took a lot of time and effort.
Rym: But I feel like most games their soundtracks are generic Background music.
Scott: nowadays people don't try hard to make really good music for their game Like music from Halo and it's just kind of generic it like.
Rym: I wouldn't listen to it on its own But I would listen to the soundtrack to Symphony of the Night or the composed music for Final Fantasy 6 on its own.
Rym: It's fantastic.
Rym: Yep Megaman 9.
Scott: Alright, so Megaman 9 came out.
Scott: I bought it.
Scott: I played barely any of it yet, but it's Megaman 9.
Scott: Do I really need to say anything else?
Rym: I got to say one thing you can turn on or turn off sprite flicker.
Scott: That's cool.
Rym: And uh, I'm doing what Scott is doing.
Rym: We're both.
Rym: we're not going to read anything about the game.
Scott: We're going to play it independently of each other and independently of Each other because I mean you want to get the old NES experience as part of the old NES experience.
Rym: Oh, you want to do that watching what your friend did and learning from that, you know Anything to learn from you though, so I will say this though in the playing I've done I'm going to start with Splash Woman.
Rym: I Think that is where I should start.
Scott: I think that's just cuz you like Splash Woman.
Rym: Well, yes, because she is fairly attractive, but that is not the main reason.
Scott: What else is your reason?
Rym: My main reason is that my regular gun did more damage to her than he did to other people.
Rym: How far did you get?
Rym: I got to her and I also got to gem man.
Scott: You actually got the gem man.
Rym: Yes, you know what?
Rym: I couldn't beat him.
Rym: I got there with zero lives.
Rym: He kicked my ass.
Scott: I kept dying on the stupid spikes where the swingy thing is.
Rym: I lost all but one of my lives.
Rym: cuz I got an extra life on that part.
Scott: Is he on the other side of that gate or is someone else in the side of the gate?
Rym: I feel like I shouldn't say.
Rym: Oh, yeah anyway We're gonna do a review of Megaman 9.
Rym: Obviously the game is Exactly what we wanted.
Rym: It's pretty much Megaman 2 but new and I'm getting the experience like the joy of Discovery and like all these feelings that I haven't had in a game in a long time.
Rym: Yeah, like I never got a joy of discovery playing portrait of Roo and I just kind of beat it.
Rym: Yeah, but this game it's like I'm trying to get some of that joy discovery.
Scott: It's in me the night actually.
Rym: Yeah, well simply the night is like an amazing game, right?
Scott: So I got the strong bad game on the Wii.
Scott: the first one.
Scott: actually the second one is out You know, but I haven't gotten that one.
Scott: I only got the first one and I didn't beat the first one, but I played quite a bit of it.
Scott: Actually, it's a point-and-click adventure with strong bad their homestar runner style jokes.
Scott: That's pretty much all there is to it.
Scott: I mean, you know if you if you like homestar runner go for it.
Scott: And actually what I did is I haven't gone to home.
Scott: So I was a fan of homestar runner.
Scott: back before you people even knew anyone's.
Rym: Scott sent an email that became one of the strong Matty.
Scott: remember that.
Rym: well I'm pretty sure that first email where his computer explodes was Eerily similar to an email that I said like it was almost word for word like a couple of words were changed but it was like word for word.
Rym: otherwise, yes, and That's how far we go back like we like we started watching from like the third strong bad email.
Scott: Yeah, when I went to the site originally strong bad email was not the highlight of the site.
Scott: It was just one of the features on the site.
Scott: the tunes and the games were more prominent.
Scott: Anyway, so I hadn't.
Scott: I eventually got tired of it because the same joke over and over again, you know And I felt like around the time when the album came out was sort of like the peak And I hadn't gone there in a long time.
Scott: So bringing back this game I feel like playing the first chapter of it.
Scott: It's sort of like I sort of like a joke.
Scott: you've heard the joke before but you haven't heard it in such a long time.
Scott: So it's sort of funny again in a way and it sort of worked for me.
Scott: I don't know if I'd buy the second episode, but I'll probably go and beat the first episode.
Scott: It does have some of that adventure game problem of there's no logic to what to do next.
Scott: So it's use everything on everything until you win.
Scott: So I think at this point I'm just gonna use a fact to beat it out and just see all the jokes.
Rym: But the game the game is funny like it's really funny.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Scott: It's funny now because I haven't heard those jokes in a while.
Scott: But I don't know if episode 2 will be funny.
Rym: Maybe it all started when I drank 49 glasses of marinade.
Scott: Maybe when I wait a long time and then play episode 2 will be funny again.
Rym: All I have to say is to this day home star like I will crack up uncontrollably at home sour.
Scott: Yeah Almost as much as the bees Wario Wario shake it which I played at PAX is gonna be in the mail real soon.
Scott: Amazon.
Rym: We already talked about that in our bags coverage.
Scott: I'm playing Mega Man ZX on the DS.
Scott: I don't know people realize this.
Scott: on the GBA There's Mega Man zero one Mega Man zero two Mega Man zero three and Mega Man zero four.
Scott: They're all really good and really hard Mega Man games that are sort of different from the Mega Man X games But more similar to the X games than they are to the you know, regular Mega Man games.
Scott: But they're really good and the people who made those games are the people who made Mega Man 9. on the DS There's Mega Man ZX and Mega Man ZX advent and I've been playing Mega Man ZX.
Scott: It is really good Really good game and it's also made by that same team at Capcom.
Rym: So if you're a Mega Man fan, you owe it to yourself to not ignore these portable Mega Man Z's and ZX's Seriously, so before we get into PAX I have to bring this up because I saw this screenshot like right as the news was announced.
Scott: I didn't see the news and It's not a joke, I thought it was the scariest part.
Rym: I didn't even think it was a joke.
Rym: I thought it was satire.
Rym: I thought it was someone making the point that I like I would always make.
Rym: basically, it's a picture of you know World of Warcraft and inside of World of Warcraft Someone has opened a bejeweled window and is playing bejeweled and I saw it and I assumed ha This is someone making fun of World of Warcraft And I don't think I need to say anything other than that.
Rym: This is not a joke.
Rym: They're literally adding bejeweled.
Rym: But you know the mindless crap game Into World of Warcraft so that people have something to do while they're grinding.
Scott: So in other words, I mean, what's the point of a game?
Scott: I mean really, you know The primary purpose of a game like World of Warcraft is to entertain people so they can keep their minds Occupied to pass the time and entertain themselves, right?
Scott: See, but they've made something right.
Scott: that you pay a monthly fee for this thing to entertain you yet this thing You're that you're paying a monthly fee to entertain yourself with is so boring that they have to give you Something else to entertain yourself with.
Scott: now what I want.
Scott: this other thing is boring you.
Rym: what I would say Is that we have some.
Rym: you know, a lot of people in the crew actually play Wow.
Rym: I can't understand why but I Note that almost without exception when they talk about Wow They will often talk about how they'll have like.
Rym: they'll be watching a movie while they play or they'll be playing Another game while they play like a lot of people like yeah, I'll be playing Civ 4 while I play Wow
Scott: but I don't get yeah,
Rym: but basically The irony of putting bejeweled in World of Warcraft is delicious.
Scott: It is Absolutely, but they're basically saying our game is so they're admitting our game is boring.
Scott: Here is another game to occupy you while our game is boring so that I please don't stop playing our board.
Rym: I think joystick said it best.
Rym: There are many ways to deal with boredom that can strike during lengthy World of Warcraft sessions Other than just walking away from the computer to partake in a more enjoyable activity.
Rym: Some people level up new characters.
Rym: some people go into a barons area and spear their heat speed short like my discoundrels.
Rym: One the virtual denizens of Azeroth will soon be wasting their time using a popular real lifetime wasting engine.
Scott: And do you get XP's are playing bejeweled?
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: They show it at least.
Scott: then maybe it'd be faster than killing rats to grind, right?
Scott: I just I would just play bejeweled to level.
Rym: I say it should increase the drop rates of perps.
Rym: things of the day.
Scott: So, you know us we like to think about games in an academic fashion.
Rym: Oh, yes, most definitely most definitely.
Scott: Well in my internet Wanderings today, you know bored at work usual usual I came across this essay or I don't know.
Scott: they call it an introductory catalog.
Scott: it's a it's a five-part essay basically and what it is?
Scott: it's called the arts of contest and It was written for the exhibition of oriental games in New York in 2004 by a name a man named David Parlette and I read this thing and it's in five parts and Each part sort of covers a different area.
Scott: and you know in the beginning the first part He really talks about how games are actually really important historically and should be respected And people shouldn't be looking down on him.
Rym: I can definitely agree with that.
Rym: I mean war games in Prussia is one of the reasons why the Prussians had the Pre-eminent military of the day.
Scott: and he talks about nowadays, you know people, you know think oh, it's just.
Scott: it's just a game It's not important or you know, they're just.
Scott: you know, it's just a silly game To demean something by calling it a game.
Rym: It is important.
Rym: I mean if you lose a game of Puerto Rico people fucking die.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It's serious business.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, but then he goes on to talk about.
Scott: you know other more different and interesting things and if you're someone who cares about Games for serious like we do then this is something that you should read.
Scott: It's not you know, the most deep the most full You know hardcore thing you're ever gonna read but it's a. it's a little better than your average Crap that you read on your gaming vlogs.
Rym: Well, it's definitely an important point.
Rym: I mean actually seriously not that long ago I did a lecture about Game theory and gaming and how by playing games that are game theory kind of games as opposed to just monopoly You know games that don't matter games that actually involve tactical thought or strategic thought or anything like that that have non-trivial decisions are very good for honing your ability to deal with the real world more effectively and to make better decisions as a whole and to think quickly and all those sorts of things and I Have a feeling because I didn't read this thing of the day yet, but I have a feeling I'll agree with this, dude
Scott: Yeah, I didn't read the whole thing either.
Scott: That's why I only talked about part one, but I have something much more important now.
Rym: We over the weekend.
Rym: We were reminded suddenly and with fury that the movie Dick Tracy with Warren Beatty Exists.
Scott: I saw that movie in the movie theaters Double feature I believe with a gremlins movie perhaps gremlins - ah, I saw it by itself.
Rym: I don't remember the end.
Rym: My mom was like.
Rym: she wasn't sure if she should say anything about Madonna and the way she was dancing.
Scott: Yeah, I was a kid.
Scott: I didn't know her care.
Rym: I knew I cared.
Rym: I just I could see my mom trying to figure out what to say to me after the movie.
Scott: Yeah, my parents didn't say.
Rym: thing is I forgot that the movie was put out by Disney And I forgot that.
Rym: as far as I remember it was a fantastic movie.
Rym: The movie is definitely badass times 10, however I talked not that long ago about jmvs, but there's another phenomenon out there.
Rym: I think I have to talk about the DTMV.
Rym: this here is a Dick Tracy music video set to straight out of Compton.
Scott: Well, I'd yet to say what it was said to.
Scott: he gave it away.
Rym: Why cuz the video is the thing.
Rym: usually it's they'll watch it and go.
Rym: Oh straight out of Compton.
Rym: But now this time I just want you to watch the video because I am pretty sure that the majority of our listeners Have never seen this movie.
Rym: I'll bet that half of them didn't even know it existed.
Scott: They should have just used the same song as the jmv.
Rym: Yeah Now I think see I wish someone made a Dick Tracy song just like that jmv song the baddest motherfucker in the world.
Rym: But because that's not terribly game related and because the angry video game nerd recently talked about it.
Rym: I got a double feature.
Rym: so Because this is a good thing of the day I have a bad thing of the day.
Rym: You see Dick Tracy for the NES It's one of the worst games ever made.
Scott: if I didn't even know it existed that I saw the anger video game nerd do his Little thing about it and I was like, oh my god.
Rym: I owned it.
Scott: I owe you really.
Rym: Yes, I bought it from a blockbuster for like 20 bucks.
Rym: Oh, man, I Never.
Scott: you said I'm buying a command.
Rym: I'd never arrested anyone.
Rym: I died.
Rym: that game sucked.
Rym: it was impossible.
Rym: But anyway one you should watch the angry video game nerd about it.
Rym: But - I have a video here of what you get when you win this game Which of course is moot because it's impossible to beat this game.
Scott: But they get a video game genie brah.
Rym: Actually, I remember as a kid I did beat it by using a game genie code that made you invincible.
Scott: Oh, that could help.
Rym: that's pretty much the only reason he couldn't beat it, but Let me tell you what I've noticed that games that suck tend to also have Incredibly unrewarding and unsatisfying ending.
Scott: I know it's like the game is the hardest to beat gives you the like the pieces to shit for beating it.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: I get mr.
Rym: Miyagi winking at me.
Scott: Yeah by these incredibly easy games at the end of it like this full motion video Because it's just.
Scott: you know The game has no substance.
Scott: to just video.
Rym: suffice to say you get the same graphic you get when the cops yelling at you for Arresting the wrong dude, but the text says great job dick Arrested the right dude, and then you see one picture him at his desk and that's it.
Scott: That's it What we had to do some Dick Tracy comics on a Wednesday.
Rym: Oh, yes, we do because I got to say Dick Tracy Badass mofo.
Scott: Oh, yeah in the world.
Rym: So, uh speaking of badass mofos I think we got to finish our coverage of packs.
Rym: It's been a while since packs and yet we're still talking.
Scott: That's cuz you're not doing enough shows.
Scott: Maybe we did more shows.
Scott: He would have been done with this by now.
Rym: Do you want to do four shows a week?
Rym: If I didn't have a job, I see how that is But I think it is telling.
Rym: I mean if you didn't listen to any of our other coverage of facts And you don't plan to listen to the show tonight.
Rym: I'll sum it up.
Rym: We've done three episodes about packs.
Rym: You can probably figure out whether or not it was good.
Scott: Yeah, you don't need to listen All right, you just we did three shows about it.
Scott: Would we do three shows about a bad convention?
Rym: Question why of course, but anyway, I guess the intent of these episodes especially after listening to all the feedback we've been getting from the previous to is That it is not so much for people who want to know the details of packs or been to a packs.
Rym: It is for people who are unable to attend packs who wish to live it vicariously.
Scott: It's also for people who were at packs to relive it vicarious.
Rym: I believe the word of the day is Vicariously.
Scott: what is vicarious mean?
Scott: big mouth?
Rym: Living or experiencing through someone else without actually experiencing.
Scott: That is correct.
Scott: Yes haha Okay, let us continue right.
Rym: so as we last left our heroes We collapsed at like 3 30 in the morning after that last concert destroyed us.
Rym: All right Yes, basically we were defeated.
Rym: we failed.
Rym: we had to leave before the concert ended.
Scott: So we woke up and we had to get out the hotel.
Scott: So we we checked the bags and that the you know little.
Scott: no we didn't this thing Didn't we do that?
Rym: as you recall packs is a con where you stay Sunday?
Rym: Alright, I believe you're forgetting that we actually stayed in Seattle for a whole extra day.
Scott: This is the thing It's been so long since the past Scott.
Scott: I don't have this problem that I forgot sort of what happened.
Scott: It's all one big blur.
Rym: I don't know but I don't have this problem and you seem to have this problem after every convention Because you have a document in front of you with notes and I don't.
Rym: my document doesn't say oh don't forget We didn't check out of the hotel on Sunday.
Scott: Oh the fact that it doesn't say we checked out of the hotel is enough anyway.
Rym: No, because I remembered that we stayed we did a show about the fact that we stayed in Seattle.
Scott: Yeah All right, I think you had some problems.
Rym: anyway.
Scott: Pax doesn't have any problems though.
Rym: The thing about packs.
Rym: other that like anime cons, you know a lot of the cons we go to like Friday and Saturday the big days and Sunday is mostly wrecked because everyone checks out of their hotel room so they don't actually go to the con until like one and then the con ends at like three and then everyone goes home all depressed.
Rym: but Pack starts a little late on Sunday and goes until six.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it starts at what ten o'clock, right?
Scott: It starts at ten o'clock every day except for Friday when it starts at two.
Scott: Basically, you got a you get a good chance for breakfast but going till six that's pretty damn good.
Scott: That's like a whole day there.
Rym: What packs does?
Rym: is they basically shift the con forward in time?
Rym: Anime cons start Friday morning and end Sunday morning pack starts Friday afternoon and end Sunday evening.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but you know we get our stuff together.
Rym: now the previous day because we'd seen the dune game Just sitting there and no one was playing it and every now and then people would look at it I remember a few people would walk up like oh my god.
Rym: It's the dune game.
Scott: I know this is remember.
Scott: This is an ultra rare game.
Scott: We've talked about it on the show before.
Scott: I picked up a pretty good Copy on eBay for an incredible price.
Scott: cuz that's bad luck.
Scott: We got real luck, but we saw a copy there with a sign on it.
Scott: I said don't take it out of this room.
Scott: That's something special when you see another one and you're like oh, man now at some point That's gonna be busted out.
Rym: So I really wanted to play it and I figured Sunday would be the day.
Rym: so the previous day on Saturday I was like I was standing in front of it kind of staring at it.
Rym: They're looking around the room talking to people like you know what that game is.
Rym: do you understand what that game is yeah?
Scott: I mean it's like in that episode of the Simpsons where there's all the people are fighting on the Simpsons front There's the guy in the white suit Doesn't do anything and then as soon as Homer closed the door and it isn't looking the white guy bus out.
Scott: well the guy In the white suit Anyway, so this is one of those things you the dune game sitting there at the beginning of this convention.
Scott: You know the convention is three days.
Scott: at some point that box is gonna open and crazy shits gonna Go.
Rym: it probably would have been worth it to give him your driver's license to get the game and then report your driver's license gone Because replacement driver's license is cheaper than that board game.
Scott: Oh wow it's true Yeah, but anyway the drive home and you get pulled over.
Rym: So um basically I was standing in front of the game And I make an offhand comment about how amazing the game is.
Rym: now I wish I could forget get people to play it with me But I'm busy and a pegs enforcer says leave a note.
Rym: We'll take care of it.
Rym: So I leave a note saying hey sign up to play dune on Sunday.
Rym: I'll check Saturday night to see when the game will be blah blah blah, and I leave it there And I totally didn't check on it.
Rym: not at all not at all.
Scott: We didn't have time and we totally forgot about it.
Rym: Well the reason we didn't have time was because of the epicness that followed our panel on Saturday.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway when we got the piece of paper back on Sunday.
Rym: It was flipped over.
Scott: There were no names on the front, but it said note on other side, please read yep.
Rym: So I flip it over and someone wrote basically oh my god the dune game is awesome.
Rym: Call me and we'll play it.
Scott: Yeah, they said call me and we'll play it Saturday night.
Scott: I'm like Saturday night.
Scott: Were you not going any concerts?
Scott: What's your problem?
Rym: Well?
Rym: No they actually said Sunday night, so my guess is either that they didn't plan well Or they were the person who brought the game.
Rym: Yeah, I have no idea.
Rym: I do know one thing though the phone number They left which I have not yet called.
Rym: so if you're listening dude.
Rym: I haven't called you yet, but I have your phone number.
Rym: I realized in retrospect.
Rym: It's a New York area code.
Scott: Yeah, so maybe we should call.
Rym: so I got to call this number at some point and be like hey I'm a guy Who has your phone number because you wrote it on a piece of paper of dubious nature at PAX.
Scott: It's some guy from New York who moved to Seattle and is living there.
Rym: Maybe I'll bet it's someone who flew out.
Rym: who knows why?
Rym: she's some Moz guy, right?
Rym: So uh yeah, we didn't get to play dune, but that's fine because dune takes a lot.
Rym: well Do.
Rym: it either takes five minutes to play or like four hours.
Scott: Yeah Cuz everyone can bring out their full forces to bear right away, and then the rest of the game is a struggle.
Rym: So what do you do on a Sunday morning at PAX you play via play D again?
Rym: That's right Like four or five more times.
Scott: we're gonna be talking about via play D in the future, but right now is great.
Scott: You just have to know the via play D is great Especially at a convention.
Scott: play it whenever you can
Rym: yes, but on Sunday part
Scott: of it
Rym: We gathered multiple crowd standing around watching this game And we played it and played it and played it and then we handed it off to another group of people who kept the game Going as we left
Scott: all right.
Rym: So then we realized one thing we hadn't done to the entire con was harass watsi.
Rym: We'd planned on harassing watsi.
Scott: We just never really didn't plan on it But I did.
Scott: I sort of realized that you know the whole bottom floor of you know this Gaming annex was all is like the watsi room.
Scott: They had World of Warcraft.
Scott: You know on that World of Warcraft card game.
Rym: well that World of Warcraft the board game, but we'll get to that Yeah, but that's a different company.
Rym: No.
Rym: No I'm referring to Something we're gonna talk about.
Rym: oh Yeah But ever what I did there?
Scott: I made another fun.
Rym: easily
Scott: they had magic the gathering and every other watsi game in the universe was was being played and demoed And all that business, so I thought you know Saturday I was like you because we needed something to do on Sunday right to do before The closing business, and I said you know
Rym: what.
Scott: why don't we go down and play like a fourth ed demo?
Scott: And not because I was enthusiastic about fourth edition.
Scott: I'm obviously not if you if you've listened to the show before ever right, but because I like to be the person who you know tells people hey don't knock it if you didn't try it and thus I like to knock they.
Scott: I'd like to try.
Rym: Yeah, is that a Freudian slip?
Scott: I like to knock things too But I also like to try things for the express purpose of then being able to knock them without being people.
Rym: You know having people talk back to me now I point out that this was not entirely altruistic and not entirely for this reason because The conversation Scott and I had as we were walking up to see if we could get in was Alright, whatever game.
Rym: We join.
Rym: Let's pull out the burning wheel bullshit I'm gonna be questioning my motives, and let's totally fight among each other and not get anything account.
Scott: Yeah, I expected you know do a role-playing demo even a short one right I expect.
Scott: you know even though I didn't expect there to be rules for role-playing.
Scott: I was gonna role-play it up I was gonna be.
Scott: you know I was gonna.
Scott: basically we're gonna walk in in character and Ask what our motivation was frustrate the dungeon master and fight for what we believed Exactly and see how the system handled it But also try to learn the rules and see if our suspicions of fourth edition were correct.
Rym: Yes, because while I you know a lot of people have said it's just wow it's just wow but I was a little dubious.
Rym: I think you know we got to see.
Rym: but and also the other reason and the reason I was going into this with the Adversarial point of view was that the panel before our panel on Saturday was the watsy panel how to be a good dungeon master basically and I really wanted those people to come to because basically it was the oh my god.
Rym: watsy panel followed by the Dungeons & Dragons as poop panel.
Rym: So I really wanted them to realize what was going on and see our panel and get angry.
Rym: however I didn't really.
Rym: I didn't think until after our panel started that Even if they'd wanted to even if all those watsy people with their special badges wanted to see our panel They couldn't have because they were doing the panel before they couldn't get in line.
Scott: And there's no special preference for anyone at PAX unless you have an all-access bed Which they did not have.
Rym: no they had that like four people Gabe Tycho They're their girlfriend.
Scott: I guess their wives and their kids.
Scott: Maybe yeah, maybe Robert coup and such.
Rym: I assume Robert coup had the purple bag.
Scott: Not many people because the computer trust them I mean MC front lot had the same badge.
Scott: we had the light blue special guest slash panelist badge.
Rym: I like saying that.
Rym: I like pointing that out.
Rym: It's just a little ego thing.
Rym: cuz I go to.
Rym: you know anime cons, and we kill it.
Rym: well I would account.
Rym: we collected those ribbons like.
Rym: I got dealer.
Rym: I got press.
Rym: I got artist Ali.
Rym: I got panelist.
Scott: yeah Anyway, so we go into play to this watsy room.
Scott: right and I'm like cuz we you know I'm like hey Rym Let's do the D&D demo.
Scott: why not right?
Scott: so we go in and there's a. this is our PGA people.
Scott: I don't know what the RPG a exactly is but basically it looks like they're a group of DMS who run watsy demos.
Scott: That's what I can tell.
Rym: Wow Scott, okay I'm not gonna get into that but basically what they had going on was they had a living forgotten at Adams Which was more traditional D&D, but still in fourth head.
Rym: But they were scheduled long events.
Rym: that had been.
Rym: the slots have been filled up long before we had a chance to get in.
Rym: yeah And also we didn't have time because we had plans for Sunday.
Scott: So this lady is saying hey who wants to?
Scott: bloody but right and and she's like I need two people.
Scott: So I'm like us and she's like okay.
Scott: You're on and we wrote down our names, and then we're like.
Rym: What is this?
Rym: She's like it's a dungeon delve blah blah blah.
Rym: We'll provide characters.
Scott: be back in an hour Okay, so oh, but she said we needed dice.
Rym: now This is the funny part because she's and as soon as she says we need dice.
Rym: Scott's like we don't have dice and I'm like Will you can we get dice?
Rym: and she was like well?
Rym: Well you can you can go buy some.
Scott: there's a guy upstairs selling emergency gaming supply.
Rym: We both immediately balk.
Rym: We're like oh, I don't know about this I don't know if this is worth it.
Rym: and she was visibly distressed by this.
Rym: like She was really not happy with the fact that we suddenly were not excited and we're thinking of bailing yep.
Rym: So she's like oh well we could probably scrape something Please come back, and then she like went off to do something, but I mean normally like I'm not exaggerating.
Rym: She really seemed distressed about the fact that we lost interest the moment.
Rym: We were told we had to buy dice.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if I would have brought dice with me It would have been all cool, but I'm not.
Scott: you know I'm looking for a demo so I can learn something.
Scott: I'm not gonna pay to try something out.
Scott: You know for you to sell something to me.
Rym: Well.
Rym: It would depend.
Rym: Yeah, I mean Basically, I was not excited about fourth edition already And I kind of knew what to expect.
Rym: yeah, so it's not like.
Rym: I mean it's like hey You want to try this piece of poop?
Rym: I'm not gonna try that.
Rym: I know I know what to expect.
Rym: you're gonna have to pay me to try the piece of poop.
Scott: Well actually you know.
Scott: if you want to try the piece of poop all right.
Scott: Just just you're gonna have to buy this stick to pick it up with Scott.
Rym: take poop use poo on crazy guy exactly which I point out is probably the second most inside joke I've ever made on the show.
Rym: maybe anyway We go upstairs to look at the guys selling dice, and I'm basically like all right if we can't get some cheap dice Let's bail.
Scott: well actually I was sort of looking at like a lot of the fancy d6 dices.
Scott: cuz I'm just like oh Man, but we don't need I don't.
Scott: I don't need.
Scott: I have more d6 is that?
Scott: I know here's the problem.
Rym: D6 is would not have helped us as D&D.
Rym: we need all the.
Scott: I know that, but I was still ogling the disease.
Rym: I don't think you all out there understand how many non d6 dice I have.
Rym: I have like nine d20s.
Rym: I have full.
Scott: I have like six d20s.
Rym: I have like full sets of loadouts to roll combat for various characters I have played over the years.
Scott: Wow like.
Rym: I also have that awesome Die that I. that's right.
Scott: you would always get a character who would like this character does 2d12 damage.
Scott: She would buy a d20 and 2d12s that were the same color.
Scott: Yes Go with the character.
Rym: partly because I was so frustrated with how long combat took that I sped my own turn up as much as possible so I could resume playing advanced wars in the corner.
Rym: Yeah, I would like roll my cop by roll like I'd finish my round.
Rym: I'd roll my attacks for the next round and then just leave.
Rym: yeah anyway.
Scott: So the guy we look around and we actually see a set of D&D dice.
Scott: You know a d20?
Rym: Well first I resigned myself because I see like all right for six bucks We can get some stand like a set of standard dice.
Rym: we can use them.
Rym: And then I look and I notice there's one set of dice.
Rym: That's real playing.
Rym: It's like the grayest and sheep is.
Scott: it's basically a set of dice for D&D.
Scott: But they're ugly just flat gray boring plastic.
Rym: They were the most unadorned dice I've ever seen.
Scott: there are two dollars.
Rym: It was literally.
Rym: it was two dollars.
Rym: and not only that.
Rym: I was like alright I'm buying these two dollar dice.
Rym: They gave me a free dice bag a pretty high-quality Dice bag for free a dice bag that was worth more than two dollars, and I need a dice bag for my d6s.
Scott: Not that one, but I'm gonna.
Scott: I definitely got to go.
Scott: remember that I need some dice bag action, so we're like all right.
Rym: Well, let's do this.
Rym: Let's see what happens.
Rym: so then of course we got an hour to kill.
Rym: We don't really want to leave so we go outside looking for something to drink.
Rym: I just want to give this as an aside, so we find this land party place like down the street.
Rym: So and it's like land party and nachos, so we're like all right Let's get.
Rym: land party was internet cafe, and yeah But it was like a gamer II kind of place we go in and those are.
Rym: that was the worst smelling salsa I've ever smelled like a place.
Scott: the place smelled bad, so we left.
Rym: it smelled bad.
Rym: We were like all right.
Rym: Let's get out of here.
Rym: so next door to the Seattle equivalent of a bodega and there is a line of like 20 packs people all buying things and All I got to say Seattle is a strange and weird place.
Rym: not only did they have Faygo red pop and Faygo rock and rye But I bought both of which.
Rym: They also had the white chocolate kitkats.
Scott: They had pretty much every candy in every beverage in this one bodega stuff that I can't get in New York.
Scott: It's like why was I buying beverages anywhere else the whole weekend.
Scott: I should have been buying them all there.
Scott: I got a gigantic apple juice.
Scott: It was great.
Rym: So you know we hang around we screw around then we walk back in and we walk up to the table where all the characters are.
Rym: so we start looking at character sheets for D&D fourth ed and Warning bells start going off.
Rym: these character sheets don't look like character sheets from previous D&D's like I'd seen the characters even for today But I hadn't really really examined it.
Rym: It looks like a wow Character screen.
Scott: yeah, it was it.
Scott: pretty much everything on there has to do with combat.
Scott: Nothing on there has to do with anything else, but combat.
Scott: I mean there's one at the top.
Scott: There's like a quote and I was like is that quote all I have to go on Really?
Rym: and the quote didn't even have anything to do with your character.
Scott: no, so Basically eventually what happens is that you know our game.
Scott: people the people were in the game with us start getting together And one of the people was the DMS wife.
Rym: now.
Rym: She walks over.
Rym: She's like.
Rym: Oh you're on team.
Rym: Whatever like?
Rym: yeah Oh, she's like.
Rym: Oh, we'll be playing together.
Scott: you pick characters yet, and I'm like now blah blah blah Yeah, I didn't even realize I had to pick a character You know.
Rym: and so we're looking at and she's like oh you got to pick characters.
Rym: And then she starts talking about the strategy and how we're gonna need a cleric and we're gonna need a plan and blah blah blah.
Rym: We probably want this and that.
Rym: and then I'm like yeah, well I want to play someone you know role-playing blah blah blah, and she says and she looks at me kind of strangely She's like oh there isn't gonna be any role-playing They're not even pretending anymore.
Rym: So we balk.
Rym: we're both like really oh Maybe we should go now again.
Rym: There's a different person.
Rym: she seemed Super hurt that we were thinking of bailing.
Rym: I think partly because her husband was the dungeon master running the event.
Rym: Yeah, but like it really visibly upset her that we balked immediately when she said there's no role-playing.
Rym: She was like no No, it'll still be fun come on.
Rym: Don't don't leave us keep forget a play.
Scott: come on.
Scott: well because if we bailed out.
Scott: What were they gonna do?
Scott: They were gonna fail pretty much, so we're like all right.
Rym: We'll try this.
Rym: we sit down and I Will sum this up because I don't want to turn this into the talk about D&D.
Scott: fourth day We'll need another show to talk about D&D.
Rym: basically we sit down, and they're like all right.
Rym: This is a delve and basically delve is Basically it means raid.
Scott: Yeah, all we did was okay.
Scott: You guys open the door monsters fight the monsters, okay?
Scott: You beat all the monsters guess what?
Scott: now you're over here.
Scott: open the door monsters.
Rym: He's like and there's a timer.
Rym: It's like how far can you get in 30 minutes ready, and we're like ready, and he says Go it start on a stopwatch, and then he says the following You open the dank and musty door to the dungeon insider cobwebs and the arcane horrors of ancient blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: You smell a dark blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: before you were four skeletons.
Rym: They're glowing blue Yeah, and then he's like roll for initiative.
Scott: talk about classic roll for initiative.
Scott: I can't even try to talk to the skeletons or run away Or and you know what the thing is.
Scott: it basically comes down to a miniatures game.
Scott: You know with using.
Scott: you know doing the most average damage, and you possibly can given your ability.
Rym: I was a paladin.
Rym: I had to draw agro and Tank.
Rym: yeah in fact those terms draw agro and tank.
Rym: We're used by the other people playing who obviously have had more experience with fourth ed than us.
Rym: again I drew Agro and tanked.
Rym: it is just World of Warcraft with pen and paper.
Rym: It was awful.
Scott: you know Even considering that right that it's World of Warcraft on paper.
Scott: Why play this when you could play World of Warcraft?
Scott: you won't have to roll dice And you won't have to
Rym: do bad thing is you know in many ways they simplified the game but at the same time they actually kind of made it more complex and Despite having this like professional watsy dungeon master dude running the game for us He had to look up stuff a lot and like the rules were really really really fiddly And he had a lot of trouble keeping track of all the numbers.
Scott: yeah And like basically every you could see how they change the game to where you know an old D&D if you're a cleric Right you healed, and if you aren't healing you're doing weak ass damage, and you weren't being helpful.
Scott: They basically everything.
Scott: everyone was helpful all the time.
Scott: every cleric spell that I had Did damage and also as a side effect boosted someone in some way.
Rym: everything you do does damage?
Scott: It's just everything I could do.
Scott: did damage what I mean it even third ed right.
Scott: they started to decrease it somewhat but they always had the fun spells that you know like you know instant fortress or Well some of the other big bees crushing fish.
Rym: now They're they're made.
Rym: I mean there is stuff like that in fourth edition.
Rym: But the game really is not conducive to anything but playing World of Warcraft raids or World of Warcraft combat like.
Rym: there's nothing else to D&D anymore.
Rym: fourth edition is Just a really weak version of World of Warcraft.
Scott: Yeah It's like I could have role-played.
Rym: you are better off playing the World of Warcraft Card game raid than you are playing D&D fourth ed.
Rym: like I'm serious.
Scott: I mean you could have.
Scott: we could have role-played But the role-playing was not in any way helped or hindered by the dice or the numbers on the paper or anything.
Scott: so Any role-playing we could have done we could have done equally well without fourth ed just with no paper.
Scott: No pens No books no dice, so what would be the point?
Scott: Why have D&D if it doesn't help or hinder the role-playing.
Scott: so I asked completely separate.
Rym: I ask all of you out there because I don't I mean we'll talk about fourth ed at some point in the future.
Rym: I will by various means acquire the book so that I can do a full review.
Rym: Can anyone out there defend Dungeons & Dragons fourth edition as a collaborative?
Rym: storytelling game with conflict resolution mechanics.
Scott: I could defend it as a fantasy miniatures game.
Scott: Possibly I could defend it as better than hero quest even though it's the same kind of game But it's basically just hero quest advanced.
Scott: it's not anything else than that anymore.
Rym: It was I'm sorry, but it was Awful really bad, and it was kind of fun because we're trying to figure out at least.
Scott: it only took 30 minutes.
Rym: Yeah, actually we had to play a shortened delve because they're running out of time.
Rym: It's only 20 minutes, and then at the end they gave us like because we lost.
Rym: But we got whatever.
Rym: they give us these wooden coins with like the D&D logo on them.
Rym: We could exchange them for prizes.
Rym: so we gave all of them to some guy, but I stole one and then that was it.
Rym: We left.
Scott: yeah I mean to give them the benefit of the doubt right if we had done say living forgotten realms instead of dungeon delve There might have role play.
Scott: there might have been role-playing involved.
Scott: however That role-playing was obviously in no way related to the anything in the books You know in in in the game, so it would have just.
Scott: we didn't even need D&D to do that role-playing.
Scott: We could have just sat down with some forgotten realms novels and done that role-playing.
Rym: the other thing was that they said you know no Experience necessary just play and I didn't really know the rules to forthhead, but I want to say this Experience was 100% necessary.
Rym: there was no help provided at all.
Rym: I had no idea like our.
Rym: well
Scott: I only reason I was able to get by is because some of my basic knowledge of D of you know third ed and up Previous D&D still functioned yeah, but Lola d20 to see if you hit and some of it was actually I'll give it credit some of it was intuitive to any someone who already knew Third ed
Rym: yes, but at the same time the the way it flowed in general was Largely incomprehensible and unless you would already read the rules and knew something yeah.
Scott: But I sort of figured out the basics of.
Scott: you know you attack It's versus the other guys defense depending on what your attack is you know roll your damages.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not entirely sure how actions work because I always seem to have Fucking clue, I just kept doing things until they told me to stop.
Scott: And the other thing is that a lot of times like my side effects for all the cleric spells I'd be like hey someone gets a plus two bonus Hey, hey, and no one would pay attention and no one would get the bonus of like.
Rym: okay, whatever Yeah, but whatever enough D&D.
Rym: we left that business never to return.
Rym: But then we went to the expo room again again.
Rym: our plan was it's Sunday Maybe we can go do something that there was a line for the previous day.
Rym: the answer The line for the fallout booth was even longer left for dead.
Rym: forget it like left for dead.
Rym: I couldn't even get near it.
Scott: well actually I got.
Scott: I watched some people play it on a screen And that's all I needed to see to know that I'm buying it.
Scott: no questions asked.
Rym: I did watch a bunch of people on a stage playing the Rhythm music whatever game we play or whatever.
Rym: It's called for the DA or the.
Rym: we We like dance and do new instruments and stuff.
Scott: was it was it.
Scott: well there were two.
Scott: There was we music which was going down at the Nintendo booth.
Rym: Yeah, that was also the raving rabbits, which had a stage I saw that - they're playing a multiplayer mode now the raving rabbits one looked a little bit better but I gotta say both games reeked of Dancing around with.
Rym: the wiimote is already obsolete and these games are going to be sold to people who don't actually like games.
Rym: They did not look fun.
Rym: It looked like you could just waggle and always win.
Scott: Yeah, it was definitely not Not something I'm gonna shell out for big time I would.
Rym: I don't think I would even pay for like it.
Rym: just they really didn't look fun.
Rym: And you know what.
Rym: there was really no one in line to play either one.
Scott: Yeah It said yeah, it's kind of weird.
Scott: It's like you could actually go to the Nintendo booth where they had Unreleased games to play and the lines were not that long not as long as they were it.
Scott: You know the big games, but I guess you know as the demographic of the packs.
Rym: Yeah, I mean look Nintendo really also.
Scott: Nintendo's booth is really subdued.
Scott: I expect.
Scott: you know they should have had a big booth like those other guys.
Rym: Well, what would Nintendo have had to offer to the average person?
Rym: a lot more screens a lot I mean in terms of upcoming games.
Rym: What does Nintendo have to offer to the average packs is handy.
Scott: Maybe they should have busted something out new at packs that would have you know attracted people.
Rym: They just they didn't have anything.
Rym: I don't I hate to say like core gamers or hardcore gamers because that that is such a loaded BS term that people use to further their own agendas, but Nintendo more like less and less has anything to offer to me except on the DS like the Wii Has Megaman 9 which is currently the best game on the way.
Scott: Wario is coming in the mail could be here tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, but what else?
Rym: what else?
Scott: not for him up for now nothing?
Rym: Yeah, so we pretty much wandered around and gave up on that.
Rym: anyway We dicked around we wandered around the con a whole bunch and basically we didn't try to go to any panels because the lines for Every Sunday panel were again Ludicrous like there was no way to get in.
Scott: yeah We spent some time laying in the DS area always good And you know DS area B not A or C A or C suck.
Rym: Yes over the course of the con we realized that DS lounge B is the GeekNights lounge.
Rym: like I hereby Officially endorse DS lounge B at the penny arcade expo other DS lounges are poop.
Scott: DS lounge B is greatness.
Rym: I don't care what what configuration they ever use in the future.
Rym: Whichever one is designated B or the closest thing to B is best.
Scott: That's correct But you know the B stands for best.
Rym: We spent some time hanging out with all the cool people.
Scott: he stands for crap and a stands for ass.
Rym: We met at the convention all the listeners and everything.
Rym: Who do we meet?
Rym: I mean godfather?
Rym: I ran into briefly in line.
Scott: I met him waiting for our panel.
Rym: Yeah, he was pretty cool.
Rym: He's like hey, Roman Scott.
Rym: Yeah, I'm the godfather.
Rym: Oh cool.
Rym: We met of course hanging out with Aaron who brought us the chocolate and everything Hanging out with our row and her boyfriend and her Asian posse.
Scott: Trying to think about we met Mitchie D once at the reg booth and never again ever saw him again.
Rym: Also shoutouts to those two guys who we ran into at both concerts.
Rym: I don't remember either your names.
Scott: There were a lot of people I just don't know who they were that we met but no one was an annoying fan person.
Scott: every single person was cool Which is really weird.
Scott: Yeah, totally usually when people come up to me I'm like I'm expecting at least a slight amount of annoying fan person.
Scott: But now everyone was an awesome person.
Scott: like for serious at the average con We go to we should just trade all the East Coast peoples for the West Coast peoples But bring them to the East Coast, which is geographically superior.
Rym: I have a feeling that Paxis coast would be the same way, but it bears repeating and I'm not exaggerating.
Rym: I did not interact in any way with Anyone that I would classify as a fan boy.
Rym: Yeah, no one the scariest person I talked to was like so far above the line.
Rym: I guess maybe my line has been lowered by years and years of anime cons and local gaming cons.
Scott: That could be what it is do.
Scott: is our line is just so low?
Rym: But no one was even close to the line of packs at all everyone we talked to.
Rym: so I'll say this if we talked to You at PAX you were cool.
Rym: It's a say that unilaterally some cooler than others, but all cool.
Scott: Yes, some ice cubes some water bottles in the fridge, but no matter No one was in the heater.
Rym: So, you know, there really wasn't much else to say actually about Sunday.
Scott: So, uh, well there was when you know, we got in line.
Rym: Well, that's not to say there was nothing else to do.
Rym: We didn't really do anything except water around check out stuff water into rooms.
Rym: Some of the stuff we did was actually stuff we talked about as being on Saturday.
Rym: We just you know being journalists moved everything around and make it easier to do the show for us.
Rym: But then we decided alright, let's get in line for the end.
Rym: because you see Instead of having closing ceremonies what the penny arcade expo has is the omegathon final as the last Ultimate event at PAX.
Rym: basically everyone in the con lines up and then everyone in the con Standing room only goes into main events and watches the end of the omegathon.
Scott: I think there's a genius move by PAX.
Scott: as you look at other conventions like Otakon or right and they have an opening Ceremonies and closing ceremonies and the opening ceremonies.
Scott: all it has to offer is opening ceremonies and the closing ceremonies.
Scott: All it has to offer is closing ceremonies, right?
Scott: It packs the opening ceremonies is an action opening ceremonies.
Scott: It's actually a keynote by a famous industry person.
Scott: so everyone wants to go and the closing ceremonies is the end of the omegathon where they reveal the secret game and Whoever wins in that unknown secret game, you know gets a huge huge prize Which is actually a trip to the Tokyo game show.
Scott: and you know that that secret game at the end is either gonna be a?
Scott: Wicked retro game that no one's ever seen before or some new game like Halo 3 was two years ago that no one's ever played Before now, of course You already know what the last game was because it was basically our thing of the day.
Rym: in the first night of packs coverage We decided alright this we can't risk missing the end of packs or being stuck at the very back of the room.
Rym: let's just get in that line.
Rym: and This line actually warrants being talked about.
Rym: you see they know that everyone's gonna be in this line.
Rym: There were.
Rym: there was an Inordinate number of packs enforcers managing this line talking to people making sure everything was smooth.
Scott: Cuz I mean the rest of packs is winding down pretty much, you know The panels were over and everything.
Scott: so pretty much everything came down to this line and this line only.
Rym: So ever everyone is in this line.
Rym: The line was massive.
Rym: everyone's just pamped out sitting down totally hanging out.
Rym: beach balls and balloons are flying everywhere and then the packs enforcers walk in and They all kind of spread out throughout the crowd and they deliver to fairly random people in groups of people Pipe cleaners
Scott: big bags full of every color of pipe cleaner that you
Rym: Thousands and thousands and thousands and thousands of pipe cleaners of every possible color
Scott: and became arts and crafts time
Rym: now this rain.
Rym: No, I gotta say this it ranged from people making like two-dimensional sprite things, you know, like oh my god I made a Mario mushroom.
Rym: That's what we did to people making penises.
Scott: a guy made a penis hat.
Rym: Alright, I think this penis hat warrants discussion But wait to discuss.
Scott: a guy made a hat out of pipe cleaners and somewhere in the tangle of pipe cleaners That was the hat where some pipe cleaners bent in the shape of a phallus not just in the shape of a phallus.
Rym: It was a fully modeled three-dimensional penis complete with balls a glands and ejaculate Uh-huh.
Rym: It hits someone in the eye Rym.
Scott: I know you like those glands.
Rym: You know, if you're gonna draw a penis and you don't draw the glands, you're really not drawn a penis great.
Rym: But anyway, like I got there were a lot of penises.
Rym: Oh my god were there a lot of penises?
Scott: We ended up taking all out like I made some pac-mans and some ghosts and some Mario.
Rym: meanwhile Rose sitting next to us Made a very well model three-dimensional Yoshi, which kicked our asses.
Rym: It was it was frighteningly high quality.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, we ended up hanging all these things from like the caution tape that separated, you know That made the the line go back and forth.
Scott: So as people would everyone who walked by, you know who's behind us in line Which is most people would see it and I suppose they did.
Scott: we have pictures of it online You can guess.
Rym: so basically for all of you who were impacts if you saw a whole bunch of awesome art Hanging from the line about a third of the way from the front That was us and row and her boyfriend and some of the people around us contributing.
Rym: Yeah So yeah, that was our.
Rym: that was our mark on packs.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Wait, so we get in there and there's no seats.
Scott: I guess they wanted to make sure everyone got in and people crammed in like it was.
Rym: It was as tight as the first concert like it was as tight as a tool concert We went to a long time ago and
Scott: not only is it tight and everyone's crammed in they got some music's going on Right and all the people who had the fallout puppet from the fallout booth grouped up on the right side and we're all dancing.
Rym: and now this is a wonderful and Brilliant example of emergent behavior because basically there were no more than like 20 of these things Maybe 30 of them.
Rym: No, no, maybe 20 all told anyway.
Rym: And you there's videos of this online
Scott: at
Rym: the the final closing ceremonies and at first, you know People would hold them up and you seem held up all over the place, but then Two of them like people worked were two people who had them were standing next to each other over in the right side and Then bit by bit the people who had him started kind of fighting the way through the crowd and all making the way to This point.
Scott: this is like this is a piece of swag that not many people got but it was the highest and most coveted piece Of swag at the convention.
Rym: Yes, seriously the status symbols at this con were in order all access badge Omega not shirts.
Rym: one of those puppets pretty much and I'll tell you this if any of you out there have one and You mail it to me.
Rym: I I don't know what I'll do.
Scott: Kotaku was given one away.
Scott: You could have won it but you didn't.
Rym: if anyone sends me one I will make it worth your.
Scott: while I like how Kotaku does that?
Scott: they basically go to the conventions get all the free swag and then give it away on the site.
Rym: But like the emergent behavior like bit by bit they all congregated together and then the music's playing and I'm not actually going to say What music like what kind of music?
Rym: They were playing while the crowd was there because the crowd stood in there hanging out for a while before they started the event.
Rym: But the music was great like it really set the mood.
Rym: and that's all I really want to say about that.
Rym: but you know people start with the puppet start making the puppets dance and waving them back and forth and Kind of like as a group coming up with things to do.
Rym: and you know, it's going okay.
Rym: but then someone did the thing that I would have done if I had the puppet because When one person has the puppet right they stand out in the crowd.
Rym: having that puppet gives you a license to stand out in a gigantic crazy crowd.
Rym: Everyone's looking at you Once you start forming this crowd.
Rym: now you stand out but not you.
Rym: you are now a tiny.
Rym: you're one in 20 of The group that is standing on the crowd.
Rym: You don't stand out yourself as much.
Rym: So had I had one of those I would not have joined the congregation of puppets.
Rym: I would have stood on the opposite side of the arena doing contrary things with my puppet.
Rym: by itself It does maintaining myself as standing out in the crowd.
Rym: Mm-hmm and sure enough Someone did that.
Rym: so the puppets are all dancing and then on the other side, there's a puppet flicking them off and masturbating.
Scott: And of course then on the other side all the puppets started making out with each other.
Rym: Yes, which caused the puppet on the left to masturbate more furiously.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: You might wonder It's a simple puppet.
Rym: How could it masturbate more furious?
Scott: these puppets, you know surprised that you know.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that the people who had these puppets were not puppeteers by any sir.
Scott: No, John Malkovich There's simple hand puppets, you know, you control the head in two hands very simple, but people were able to manipulate them with such mastery and get such expressiveness out of them and I Attribute it to the design of the puppet being so high quality?
Rym: Yes, also just the fact that I have a feeling that the average attendee of packs has fierce masturbatory powers.
Rym: Oh, no doubt but This is going on for a while and like it keeps Escalating like the two sides and no one thinks to Joe like eventually like one other puppet join the lone guy and this puppet thing Went on forever.
Rym: if you search YouTube for the puppets.
Rym: I'm sure you'll find video.
Scott: You'll find too many videos of them.
Rym: so I mean other than that the crowd the balloons is still going around and the crowd is like really into it and people are singing along with the music.
Rym: and and then the lights go down and the music in the lights start up and the the fucking epicness of the end of pegs begins.
Rym: now They you know first off I got as we've said the production values like how well put together How slick how professional everything in that room was throughout packs?
Rym: only Escalated at this point and the music starts playing and they introduced the Omega knots and They're setting everything up for the end.
Rym: But before they have you know, the unveiling and the final challenge They have a little bit of retrospective and then they play This montage of the Omega thon.
Rym: They had filmed the Omega thon throughout the con and put together this video which then aired at the con.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: I mean, I've seen people, you know at conventions like, you know with their final cuts Editing together videos like trying to get them up on the internet real quick They.
Scott: but this like the job they did on this was like wow You would think that this is a video that they took like a year to make and I don't there no other Convention I think can really pull this kind of thing off.
Rym: And it was really dumb like it was great and the music oh my god, but then at the end of it when they they come down to the last two a minute they basically did the Football sports guy thing and if you don't know what that is when you watch the montage you'll go Oh that football sports guy thing.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: and then They unveiled it.
Rym: They unveiled the game and the way like well the game.
Scott: well They took the.
Scott: they had the screen on the stage right this big-screen TV or at least a relatively big-screen TV And there was a sheet over it.
Scott: So they pull the sheet off and then there's two giant You know video screens left in the right of the stage so you can see what's going on.
Scott: There's no way you can see that TV from way back right and it says Nintendo Famicom distance.
Rym: see this is brilliant.
Rym: like gave those two guys ever may.
Rym: I don't know if it's them specifically or the people who kind of manage all this but they really have developed This live-action sense of comedic time.
Rym: Maybe it's just from doing the comic from so long because you know penny arcade often has a good sense of comedic timing.
Rym: It's starting to carry over to the real world.
Rym: like though The staging of the like little reveals as they led up to revealing the game and the commentary they provided was masterful.
Rym: Yeah, it's like we've got.
Rym: you know, we've got another blockbuster game from 1987 and the crowd goes nuts and then they turn it on and you real and you see the Famicom disk system.
Scott: and for people Don't know the Famicom disk system in Japan, right?
Scott: Obviously, they didn't have the NES They had the Famicom which is pretty much the same thing.
Scott: Only the cartridges are smaller, right?
Scott: However, there was also the Famicom disk system.
Scott: and just to get this really quickly because it's not you know that important It was a thing you attached to your Famicom and you put these weird floppy disks into it.
Scott: They weren't floppy they were sort of big and plastic but they worked just like floppy disks and you put them in there and then you would put the.
Scott: you know, you had attached this other thing to the cartridge slot which had a cable that connected the disk system and It allowed you to play, you know basically NES games that were better than other NES games but allowed saving and loading to the disk and a lot of games that we had like Metroid or Blades of Steel or Legend of Zelda in Japan.
Scott: They were actually Famicom disk system games.
Scott: But over here we got them either with passwords instead of save games or we got them with the battery backup.
Scott: You know save games, so we only had cartridges here.
Scott: They were gonna bring the disk system out in the US, but they didn't.
Scott: and in Japan, there were actually a lot of Famicom disk system games.
Scott: and so when you see Famicom disk system, you know It's probably gonna be some Japanese game that we never had in the US.
Rym: So, you know build up build up build up and then versus excite bike appears on the screen and the crowd there's this moment of silence where the crowd shuts up going Like there's an intake of breath as everyone realized like they read it and it takes that second for their brain to register Exactly what it is they're seeing and then the crowd just loses their shit.
Scott: It's like holy shit.
Scott: I didn't even know that existed.
Scott: I mean, I know a lot of things that exist that people other people don't know exist.
Scott: I didn't know versus excite bike exists.
Scott: I'm sure I'm sure that there are people there besides game and Taika who knew it existed but most of the people there had no clue I had no idea and Then they bring him out and it is weird.
Rym: I also didn't realize that in Japan Player two was on top.
Scott: Yeah, he said it was the Coriolis effect.
Rym: I I don't know.
Rym: Japanese are weird.
Rym: Yeah, the live player two would be on top.
Scott: Anyway, so they put this disc in and then it says flip to side B and the crowd again loses their shit.
Scott: So the guy flips the disc over and then you know verse excite bike starts playing in verse.
Scott: excite bike.
Scott: I got to say this is fucking awesome music.
Rym: Also, I got to say it's fucking awesome game.
Rym: versus excite bike holds up today as a good game.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's excite bike, but it's verse.
Scott: that's pretty much all there is to it.
Rym: And let me tell you this is a game of turnabouts.
Scott: Yeah, it is so fun thing outside in realize right is I got?
Scott: when I got home I guess I set up my emulator my NES emulator to emulate Famicom disk system And I got every Famicom disk system ROM including verse excite bike.
Scott: So we sat there playing them all of course, and I learned that Verses excite bike only comes with three tracks built into it for verses.
Scott: You actually there's a track editor and you can save your tracks on the disc which is the point of having a disc instead of a cartridge.
Scott: and When they were playing it at PAX there were seven tracks.
Scott: so four of those tracks were tracks that I guess gave in taiko or whoever owned that cartridge or own that disc had made in advance.
Scott: and They did a lot of play on those custom tracks and they only did some of the play on the pre-made built into the game tracks.
Rym: and then The omega-thon final began and the first round like, you know, the game starts playing.
Rym: It was amazing.
Rym: Like it was like, oh my god, he's winning.
Scott: now He's winning like it was real close back and forth back and forth and when a guy Whoever won the other guy was on the ramp and was literally like one bikes length away from finishing the lap and the crowd like.
Rym: there's something about watching a game of direct competition like this with a crowd of people who understand the game and or into it because it was like oh Losing it.
Rym: and Basically after that first round It was over.
Scott: It was just absolutely complete domination by red over blue.
Scott: blue Sucked at excite, but he didn't suck no hair to say my mom playing but he was not good.
Rym: I mean with this well, I'll I'll be honest.
Rym: I My I mean, I think I would had a 50/50 shot against the guy who did win.
Scott: I Overheated a lot.
Scott: I mean I you know when I was watching him, I was thinking man I never overheat but upon playing the game at home I overheat a little but I don't overheat as much as that guy over.
Rym: He fell every time he hit those little pylon things.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the pylon things are real easy to get over.
Scott: You just go back back back back back It's it's.
Scott: he obviously was.
Scott: not a hundred percent is excite bike knowledge.
Scott: He.
Rym: obviously my guess is that he'd either never actually played excite bike Which a lot of people are like or he had not played it since he was a child.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't have enough and the other guy would and I was sort of rooting for that other guy anyway Because
Rym: one that guy had a really good style and like he looked like the kind of guy that had he been at RIT I would have been friends with.
Scott: also in the in the montage video that they made, you know that with the high production qualities We talked about
Rym: the guy
Scott: basically said, you know, the first round of the omega-thon was peggle and the second round was a boom blocks
Rym: Yep, and the
Scott: third round was geometry Wars, right?
Scott: So when they were talking to the guy who won, you know before he won He was in the montage video and they said they interviewed him during the geometry words out and he's like, yeah This is the first round where there's a skill based game.
Scott: So I feel like it's you know I've actually got a legitimate shot which of course means I'm going to lose.
Scott: and he didn't lose.
Scott: but the fact that he was someone who recognized that the first two games were not skill based and that geometry Wars was Sort of may help me identify with him and root for him a little bit more.
Scott: so he won and Everyone goes.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you won you're going to Tokyo.
Scott: We hate you, but we Simultaneously cheer for you.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Why can't I go to Tokyo?
Scott: Okay, and then Gabe says taiko get your ass in the beanbags and they sit down and they play and One of them was not good at excite bike and one let it just be said that the red bike was.
Scott: I think the blue Bike was just rigged and gimped and the red bike won every time.
Scott: it might not have been the players It might have been you know, the red controller was just better and the blue one is.
Rym: yes The red controller was somehow causing these overheating.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I'm sure it was.
Rym: and then It ended and the whole crowd like walks out together and oh my god it was like it was crazy and like everyone's talking and Gavin and no one wanted to leave.
Rym: and Basically, we walk out of the con right and we kind of took a back way out.
Rym: So we got ahead of the rest of the crowd.
Rym: We're way down the street and we get back on and basically we get back onto the street.
Rym: We're kind of up a hill a little bit.
Rym: So we're overlooking.
Rym: like back toward the con the crowd Leaving the convention center was frightening to behold like it was.
Rym: basically every street in every direction Was completely full of people.
Rym: like the sidewalks were completely full.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it was a lot more like, you know when people leave Otakon Which is real big almost as big as PAX but not quite, you know, it's like to you.
Scott: It's not like this big wave of people coming out.
Scott: You know, it's like the evil trickle out, you know It's a little crowded but the people are tricking out and dispersing.
Rym: PAX ending was like a football game ending exactly.
Scott: It's just a whole bunch of people going in exactly one direction.
Scott: If you leave like a football game or a baseball game you walk down the ramps You know from the upper levels.
Scott: or if you're on if you're cool and you're sitting in the lower level You know You're walking out of the gate and it's just this direct flood of people going in one direction.
Scott: and that's what leaving PAX was like.
Rym: now also remember this the the.
Scott: basically a 12th of the population of Seattle was leaving the penny arcade Expo simultaneously, but the sidewalks are so wide and So empty, you know on this Sunday that it handled it quite quite fun.
Scott: Oh, yeah handling the crepe line the crepe line did not handle it at all.
Rym: But what was amazing was one the locals and the tourists staring at it like what the fuck is going on And to the fact that the state basically Seattle felt really empty the whole time.
Rym: We were there like pretty much at any given time during the day.
Rym: There was pretty much no one on the streets at PAX people Yeah, but then when packs ended like the street was almost as crowded as a New York Street on an average day.
Rym: Yeah, but it was nothing but packs people.
Scott: Well, there were some non pegs people and it was kind of weird.
Scott: But yeah, and then I guess packs is over, right?
Scott: Yeah, don't refer to that other episode.
Scott: We did to find out what happened afterwards.
Rym: Well, the thing is we left right and we're like, alright, let's go to that arcade.
Rym: the game works.
Rym: Everyone said isn't cool.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and there was a it said reserved for private parties.
Scott: So we're like, oh, it must be like the packs after party.
Scott: fuck.
Rym: we know It was some little bad mitzvah.
Scott: It's a bot mitzvah.
Scott: whatever.
Rym: It was some little girls.
Scott: bot mitzvah happened to be.
Scott: the game works immediately after pack.
Rym: So, you know you want you look in the window and there's all these pegs.
Rym: people like walking by going Dammit and looking in the window and in the window is like this tiny party of little girls.
Scott: They would have made so much more money if they would have this kick that bat mitzvah out and let the pegs people in.
Rym: but There's like this little party of like eight-year-old girls 13 years, whatever like there's.
Rym: but they're you know Like little girls to like family members and whatever.
Rym: plus I can't tell the difference between anyone under the age of 14.
Scott: at this point I can tell you need someone who's zero and somebody's five and somebody's yeah, once they're over five.
Rym: I can't tell yeah They're.
Rym: basically it's either baby Toddler younger than me older than me.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I think it's like baby toddler kid teenager college kid Older than me.
Rym: I don't have trouble telling between teenager and college kid.
Scott: Sometimes something depends.
Rym: Yeah, cuz cuz the thing is I feel like I can tell.
Rym: but then like I go back to our IT And look around and everyone looks like they're 12 to me and I'm like, wow.
Rym: Good God.
Rym: Yeah, what's wrong with me?
Scott: I'm not that old.
Scott: Yeah, my little sister's a college kid.
Scott: It's fucked up.
Rym: Yeah, so but like people are looking in the window at these little girls are like doing one-step basic mode And failing a DDR and we're just like we should be in there.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Oh my god It's just not right that packs should get out and the arcade in town The big fancy arcade run by.
Rym: so I have a plan and because I have money I'm thinking of doing this Rent it out.
Rym: So pretty much as soon as they announce the dates for the next packs I think I am just going to rent out that arcade on the Sunday after packs.
Rym: That's right for just my own event and we're totally going to have the GeekNights party and I I can't promise this will happen Because I might not get the reservation like I might cost too much.
Rym: But if I can swing it we are going to have the GeekNights packs after party at PAX 2009 in Seattle.
Scott: Hell's yeah.
Rym: I'm totally gonna commit to this unless either it's ludicrously priced or Someone like.
Rym: in
Scott: other words if we fail at it, you'll be able to get out without you'll be able to save face But
Rym: I will not fail unless like I'm forced to fail If there's some other bat mitzvah or something
Scott: the hard part is gonna be getting enough people to come.
Rym: I Don't think it will be a problem.
Scott: We're gonna have to really hand out invitations and whatnot to every cool person.
Rym: Well, the thing is I've actually been talking to the packs people and we're already working on our panel our tentative panel for the next Packs, uh-huh, and let me tell you I think it'll be a good panel equal to beyond Dungeons & Dragons.
Scott: Maybe we'll see.
Scott: so I got to work hard.
Rym: Pax was over but we're sticking around another day Which the only other con we've done this before was katsu con and I got to say more and more.
Rym: Sticking around the extra day really makes a con a lot more.
Rym: enjoy a faraway con.
Scott: It does.
Rym: yeah kinetic con I don't need to stick around the extra day because I can just drive through the night but for a con like this It's so worth it.
Scott: It's very worth it.
Rym: So we got nothing to do and we can't go play DDR.
Rym: So we get row and she gets her Asian posse Which is basically We got some of the Asian posse.
Rym: as far as I'm concerned the people we're about to talk about are Like one half a point away from being the West Coast front row crew.
Rym: Mm-hmm we gotta call them like the second row crew or something because They're they're just like us.
Scott: They're there.
Rym: They're like us from the West Coast.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: So we meet with row and and all those people row her boyfriend and this cool parkour.
Rym: I just realized I'm gonna admit something horrible.
Rym: Yeah, the only reason I haven't said her boyfriend's name is because I forgot his name.
Rym: I don't remember anyone's name, but dude, you were totally cool.
Rym: Remind me what your name is and I'll say it on the show because you were awesome.
Rym: All right, I feel bad, but I only remember you as Rose boyfriend.
Scott: I don't remember anyone's name.
Scott: What do you think?
Scott: Their forum name if they're lucky.
Rym: Oh, you know what actually?
Rym: the other scary thing We met a lot of GeekNights listeners like a Surprising number like I didn't expect as many of our GeekNights listeners to be at PAX and to run into them.
Rym: among you know 58,000 some people but With the exception of like four or five people everyone we met who was like, oh my god, I listen to GeekNights.
Rym: I'm a big fan Not in the forums.
Scott: Yeah, what's up with that?
Rym: Our biggest fans with a few exceptions are not in the forums at all.
Scott: It got a sign up for the forums and everyone who did sign up for the forums.
Scott: All right, if you when you sign up for our forums, it sends out an email that says congratulations You have been approved but depending on who you use for email if you use like Yahoo or Hotmail or something You might not get the email that says you have been approved.
Scott: if you don't get the email Don't worry about it.
Scott: Just go back to the forums and sign in and odds are 99%.
Scott: you've been approved.
Rym: and I'll say this if you if you actually were denied one It'll tell you you were denied and two You're not welcome in the forums Because our says we're real good at figuring out.
Scott: or it means that you typed into that little box that says why are you joining?
Scott: the forums?
Scott: if you type something into that box that made it seem like you were a spammer or a bot or Stupid or stupid in which case you were not welcome in the forums Yeah, you should type something better in that box.
Rym: because I do need to say You know for all you people who are might be newer to GeekNights or you know Listen this and thinking oh, I'll join the forums now.
Rym: Our forms are not like other forums.
Rym: You could say they're the opposite of the penny arcade forums.
Rym: Real quick grammar intelligence and non annoyingness are strictly enforced and as a result, there's no one annoying.
Scott: Anyway So we'll go hang with these people and we decide we're gonna.
Scott: you know, we got really nothing to do.
Scott: So we busted out some board games.
Rym: So we go to the lobby of the red line hotel where we're staying because our room, you know It's eat.
Rym: the lobby was actually really nice.
Rym: There's a fireplace.
Rym: There's a table and a bunch of couches around it.
Rym: So we don't want to play a game that not.
Rym: we don't all know how to play and we want to include it.
Scott: Well, I always you know Whenever someone brings a game that I don't know how to play.
Scott: I always want to learn how to play because I love learning how to play games But no one else does I don't.
Rym: I would rather learn.
Scott: I would always rather play a new game.
Scott: I've never played before.
Rym: I would rather already know how to play a game so that I can just sit down and play more games with the people Because playing games is the fun part.
Rym: learning a game is just the speed bump between having the game and playing the game.
Scott: I love learning games and seeing how they work and learning.
Rym: Yeah, see I think your problem what you forget to realize is that the amount of time we have to play games is limited and It takes a long time to teach most people a board game.
Rym: So as a result Every time we want to play board games and you want to play a game that not everyone knows how to play you basically delay Us by an hour while you teach the one person how to play power grid again.
Scott: Yeah, but I just it's not the tea I don't.
Scott: I don't like teaching people how to play games.
Scott: already know how to play is I like learning games?
Rym: I don't already know how to play but that but don't you want to?
Rym: you can play two games in the time it takes to Teach someone a game.
Scott: I'm not talking about teaching someone I'm talking about if I'm.
Scott: if I have to teach someone a game already know how to play then yes, that's annoying.
Scott: But if I'm learning a game that I don't know how to play and then playing it I don't feel as if that hour was wasted.
Rym: So whenever we learning a game is as enjoyable for me as playing one see except whenever we learn a game It's always we figure out how to play on our own and teach everyone else.
Scott: Yeah, it is a problem and do They?
Scott: it never was an opportunity for someone else to teach me a game.
Scott: I didn't know but you didn't want to do that.
Rym: Well also all the game.
Rym: it would have taken too long.
Rym: if you wanted a we wanted to actually play a game That is true.
Rym: So we play Carcassonne.
Rym: and let me tell you at one I won by like a couple hundred points Like I was pretty well, but then not so much.
Rym: I won by like a ludicrous amount Like I'm not just saying this to like oh my god, but I won by a frightening amount, but then again To to incite my ego I Seriously without exaggeration win about 80 to 90 percent of the games of Carcassonne.
Rym: I've ever played.
Rym: Yeah Expansions doesn't matter.
Rym: any Carcassonne like I always win.
Scott: I don't know what's up with the Carcassonne.
Scott: Why I can't wait.
Rym: I've told you what to do.
Rym: You just don't do it.
Scott: I do it I just not.
Rym: also you still can't figure out how to win the farm game.
Rym: You'll always be like I'm gonna beat your in this time and you'll put like your big guy on a farm like early on Then I'll just wall that I didn't put my big guy in a farm.
Rym: really Well, you've done that in the past to try to head me off.
Rym: But anytime you're in a farm I just wall your farm off and then like You'll you'll be winning like the one big farm in the game.
Rym: and then at the end like in the last five rounds I'll add three guys to the farm.
Rym: But yeah, I won.
Rym: but everyone playing real like it was a good game a Carcassonne.
Rym: and Here's why I say that all you people the Asian Posse and Rowan everyone are Like real close to being front row crew West Coast.
Scott: Well, there's something.
Scott: there's a culture of people who play You know Euro games in which you sort of have fun with it.
Rym: in addition to you know Not just Euro games all games because you see the same thing was like the cheese and natural selection.
Scott: That's true That's true.
Scott: But it's uh, it's this culture of taking a game and playing the game seriously to win But also adding this meta fun element to the game.
Scott: For example, you'll see four people playing settlers at a gaming convention and they're taking their game of settlers pretty seriously Except except when they trade they'll say things like y'all got a brick I'll trade two wood.
Rym: Yep, or the classic.
Rym: I got a raging wood.
Rym: Does anyone have some sheep to help me with this?
Scott: To wood.
Scott: Oh what for brick?
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: We need to do a show on caveman.
Scott: Talk a whole show on caveman.
Rym: I think we could do it.
Scott: I think that's the snow crash show Which by the way will be this Thursday no matter what that's right.
Scott: You like that joke.
Rym: I like that was good.
Rym: But you know we do this like when we play El Grande, it's not Aragon It's Amagon and it's and it.
Rym: when it's Galicia we say Galicia, but we don't mean Galicia We mean something else that I'm not gonna mention on the show.
Scott: Yeah, or when we play America and when you play Attica, it's like what are they technically supposed to be?
Scott: say m4, but we're like other carrots Except I say I'm for I know I wanted to say carrots.
Rym: so bad We always were like name things like weird things like.
Rym: we'll call things from one gate like for a while We called every Petersburg the Jew.
Rym: We called like everything in every game.
Rym: That wasn't the game that has the doge in it.
Rym: the doge for a while and then we started calling The king the governor and like everything.
Rym: But then we just like we see the m4 and they look just like carrots, and we're like oh my god They're carrots, and we're like.
Rym: that's our thing with this game.
Rym: These are the carrots and Like it just didn't stick and we just say I'm Farah like we tried to do too much with it.
Scott: Yeah, it's rare But you know you'll.
Scott: you'll just call you'll come up with your own set of names For things in the game as opposed to the official set of names to add your own humor and your own flavor.
Rym: So before we get to that though we bust out the Carcassonne set and the first thing I ask is So what expansions do we roll with?
Rym: and the guys like blah blah blah and blah, and I'm like all right.
Scott: Basically there were a bunch of expansions in there.
Scott: We played with the regular game and also with the ins and cathedrals But we played a bunch of other tiles from other expansions, but we didn't actually use their expansion abilities.
Scott: basically
Rym: They have an analogous But basically derived from the same idea set as us like they did the same thing like they added a bunch of sets together And they ignore the stupid expansion
Scott: like they had traders and builders, but we didn't do any trading or building We just use the tiles.
Rym: and what cemented me as a fast friend with these people as the second question as which was So which farmers going do we use to which he says?
Rym: The correct one obviously and I say is that the one with you know XYZ and he says duh Of course so.
Rym: and then we start playing and a certain tile comes up, and it's shaped.
Rym: You know it's like it's a weird time.
Scott: It's one of those tiles where you have Castle on the top and the left and also a separate castle on the right, but then grass on the bottom.
Scott: So it's sort of like this pointy grass field that goes in like this little narrow crook Almost like if the grass is water.
Scott: it would be like a fjord.
Rym: and the guy says oh inverse wizard hat Name for the tile.
Rym: and all I want to say they have names for a lot of the tiles just like the inverse wizard hat the clitoris the clitoris style is so great.
Rym: and the thing is you're like What do you mean, and then you see the tile you're like?
Scott: Oh?
Rym: There we go.
Scott: yeah The fact that they named their tiles shows that they share that same common culture of name things in board games weird things And also jump on the cheese and natural selection.
Rym: ah jumping on the cheese.
Scott: and thus we have a kid Where it's got jumping on cheese boss?
Scott: And thus we shared something with them that was special and thus the penny arcade expo 2008.
Rym: well we into bed yeah, then we went to bed then the next day.
Rym: so all right We did a show on Friday without like without even a news thing of the day.
Rym: We did another show on Saturday.
Rym: We did this show on Sunday.
Rym: We did a show just about the stuff in Seattle that wasn't directly related to packs.
Rym: We did it up.
Rym: Oh my god Did we do a lot of shows about.
Scott: they're gonna still do more shows because we have to do a show in which we talk About you know fourth ed possibly more in depth yep.
Scott: We had to do a show about via Paletti which we discovered it packs.
Rym: We have to do a show about the science fiction museum.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: we have to do a show a meta show like kind of.
Rym: you know this was basically the Like live vicariously packs through Rym and Scott.
Rym: we have to do one more show.
Rym: this won't be right away.
Rym: We'll have a packs break on Tuesdays.
Rym: We'll do a normal Tuesday the next time There's a Tuesday, but then we have to do a show about.
Rym: you know from a conventioneering perspective You know we're like from a technical perspective Like specifically what it is that makes packs good like how it's run the organization all that sort of stuff.
Scott: Yep, stuff that for people who care about convention behind-the-scenes stuff.
Rym: We're gonna do a Wednesday show.
Rym: this will be in a future But it's basically going to be What we learned about running an anime convention from the penny arcade expo, and you might say hey basically to be a?
Scott: scathing criticism of anime convention.
Rym: But at the same time it's going to be a list of suggestions and in the classic suggestions that I will I must admit are Not suggestions we came up with before.
Scott: these are the things we just learned from packs.
Scott: We were not smart enough to come up with these things.
Rym: There are things we always say like anime con should do this.
Rym: anime con should do that But these are like whoa like here's a crazy one.
Rym: Just you guys get an idea.
Rym: I Realized that the convention feedback panel is a stupid waste of time and no anime con should have one ever again.
Rym: That's right, and you might say what that's crazy.
Rym: That's how we're gonna roll.
Rym: Oh like we've like it.
Rym: we had revelations like we walk around packs And we'd see something and we'd stop and go.
Rym: oh my god.
Rym: What if Otakon did that?
Rym: It would change everything it would.
Rym: and if you say oh, that's just the same show as why was packs good?
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: well Kinda well it is except that why was bags good is two hours long.
Rym: so we're gonna split it into two different shows.
Rym: Yeah, but in the ever since ConnectiCon two years ago where we went to ConnectiCon and came back with a shall we say?
Rym: Unpleasant review and the con chair and all the people involved emailed us and said you know what?
Rym: Your coverage was justified.
Rym: everything you said was true Put up or shut up.
Rym: Are you gonna do all the things you said we should do?
Rym: and we said we'll do whatever you want.
Rym: We ran like seven panels at the next ConnectiCon.
Rym: let me tell you We're doing the same thing with anime cons, and I'll talk more about that later.
Rym: But we're actually going to be bringing several of these changes to ConnectiCon and possibly though this is in no way set in stone yet - Otakon.
Scott: oh, man and Yeah, what else?
Scott: I think that might end cuz not really much more we can say about the packs.
Scott: He pretty much beaten that horse, and it's dead.
Rym: however There's one other thing that came out of it.
Rym: as soon as we have a chance to do it in person We are going to interview Jared Sorenson on the show.
Scott: Oh, yeah, yeah, that's another Technically packed show.
Rym: we're going to interview Luke Crane again because I have you know other questions to ask him.
Rym: No, yeah, definitely, and we have a semi secret project that I'm going to say this.
Rym: it will involve Jared Sorenson It will involve Luke Crane.
Rym: It will involve role-playing games.
Rym: It will involve a video camera it will involve a stage It will involve YouTube gay porn and it possibly will involve a DVD gay porn DVD.
Rym: But suffice to say I say it's secret because until I get to the point where it is no longer shit talking I'm not gonna promise anything, but much like Washington.
Rym: It's coming.
Rym: It's come, so I hope you enjoyed this and I will say it unambiguously.
Rym: We are going to be at PAX 2009.
Scott: we're going to be at every penny arcade expo.
Scott: that happens for as long as we live.
Rym: You're going to be at every Pax.
Rym: that is not the man.
Rym: No that is in North America for as barring.
Scott: I'm going to PAX Europe.
Scott: I don't know about you.
Rym: I'll say this if there is a PAX Europe every year I might not go to all of them what?
Rym: I'll go to all of them But I will go to every East West North South Coast packs that there is.
Scott: I would go to PAX Iraq.
Scott: I would go to PAX.
Rym: I would go to PAX.
Scott: I'm gonna PAX Darfur if it was tomorrow.
Rym: ah What tax would I not go to?
Scott: I would not go.
Rym: I would not go to PAX Grant.
Scott: I would go to PAX great.
Rym: I would not go to back screen.
Scott: I would not the only packs.
Scott: I would not go to.
Scott: are you ready for this?
Scott: there two packs I would not go to.
Rym: uh hell no well well No, I would go to hell.
Rym: cuz one.
Rym: all the awesome people are in hell if they're right.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I don't take scare of his own.
Scott: I would not go to PAX outer space Why not are you guys?
Scott: it would be too hard to get to uh?
Rym: Space elevator Japan's building it.
Scott: if there's a space elevator is different story, but besides I'm saying it packs space tomorrow.
Scott: I wouldn't go.
Rym: got packed space is definitely affordable because everything involved costs space dollars.
Scott: If packed space was tomorrow realistically I wouldn't go and I would not go to PAX Antarctica in the winter if it was packed center to get in the good time when the Sun was out.
Scott: you'd be all right.
Rym: I would because if I don't know go if comics have taught me one thing about Antarctica.
Rym: It's full of action adventure and lesbians.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.