Rym: It's Tuesday, May 27th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk about Scott.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, considering the bank holiday yesterday, we decided not to do a show.
Scott: Yeah, probably because it was late at night, walking back from getting ice cream.
Rym: Oh, that was the worst thing.
Rym: We had the Visigoths over, which they were surprisingly non-Visigothic.
Scott: We still have a big mess to clean up.
Rym: Yeah, but not nearly as bad as past, and pretty much everyone pulled their part.
Rym: But we were walking back from getting ice cream after getting dinner yesterday.
Scott: And Rym is like, "Hey, Scott, what are we going to do the show on
Scott: tonight?".
Scott: And I'm like,
Scott: "Ugh!".
Rym: And then I think the conversation went something along the lines of, "Bail,
Rym: bail.".
Scott: Yeah, that wasn't going to happen.
Scott: It was too late, and there were people there, and yeah.
Scott: There was nothing to talk about either.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It was a good weekend, though.
Rym: We played a lot of vidya games.
Scott: A lot of vidya game playing going on.
Scott: I'm trying to clear out the vidya game queue, because once I clear it out, it's like free-sailing on all this other stuff.
Scott: But yeah, I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, it was warm today.
Rym: Warm today.
Scott: Yeah, not as warm yesterday.
Scott: Quite warmer today.
Rym: I was actually surprised.
Rym: I get up, and I'm tired, and I go to work, and I get off the train, and it's like 100 degrees under Grand Central.
Scott: It's really hot, because there's all the train engines under there, and yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I've got to be like all those MTA employees.
Rym: They always get on the train and beacon in their pajamas.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Then they change at work in the locker room.
Scott: I wish my work had a locker room.
Rym: All right, so let's get right into this, because since Scott gets home late lately, he gets home a couple hours later than usual.
Scott: Pretty much exactly one hour later.
Rym: Yeah, but then we don't do the show right away, and one thing leads to another, and now it's late.
Scott: Yeah, well, what do you want?
Rym: Come home earlier?
Scott: I can't do anything about that.
Rym: Yeah, you could.
Rym: What happened to, "If my job ever asked me to do blah, I'd give them what for"?
Scott: I did give them what for.
Rym: And you're still staying late.
Scott: It didn't work.
Rym: But it didn't work.
Rym: What for did you give?
Rym: What for is when you give what for?
Scott: See, the problem I have here, right, is I could just quit, which I would do, but it's like, I kind of like the people at work.
Scott: Then don't quit.
Scott: Make demands.
Scott: I did, but that demand will not be met.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Did they say, "Well, we're not going to, and if you press forward, we'll fire you"?
Scott: No, they're pretty much like, "That's how it's going to
Scott: be.".
Scott: And it's pretty much my options are quit or stay an hour later.
Rym: If I were you, I would pretty much be already looking for a new job.
Scott: I'm looking around a little bit.
Rym: I'm feeling the waters, but the problem is- No, the hospital, pretty much the day the hospital went to, "Yes, stay late for all this BS,".
Rym: the next day I spent the first hour of my work looking for a new job.
Scott: I looked around.
Scott: I could find a new job pretty easily.
Scott: The problem is, unlike the hospital where you hated everyone, the people at my work, it's like I'm needed quite a bit right now, and I don't want to screw them over because I like them.
Rym: If you're needed, then you can make some sort of demands, either more vacation time or more money or something.
Scott: I did.
Scott: I went in with my vacation today, and I think I'm going to get all the days.
Scott: I'm basically not going to work much in August at all.
Scott: I'm going to get the whole week after Otakon and Otakon and PAX and the ConnectiCon day.
Scott: I'm going to get all them days and Monday.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, so I'd like to point this out.
Rym: Xbox Live Arcade is pretty much unmitigated awesome.
Scott: Well, for me, it would be like the only reason to get an Xbox is to play all those games they got in there, like the Carcassonne and the Pac-Man and the Settlers.
Rym: A very important game is now out on Xbox Live Arcade.
Scott: Body Commando Rearmed, right?
Rym: Not even talking about that.
Rym: This is a four-way versus game that you all must, must play.
Scott: Four-way versus, huh?
Rym: It is an ancient game.
Rym: It is one of the most popular games in the history of the Atari.
Rym: No, four-way.
Rym: Combat is two-way.
Scott: Kong Pro-Ab, which is four-player?
Rym: Yeah, it does.
Rym: So does that Olympic game.
Scott: That's a bad game.
Rym: I like that game.
Scott: Oh, you mean the Olympic Pong, right?
Rym: The one that's just like every kind of Pong the human race could conceive.
Rym: No, this is a game where there are four corners and four people.
Scott: Warlords.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: And each person has a little wall to protect and inside of that wall is their penis.
Scott: It's a castle with a guy in it.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: It's a castle with a video frame in Xbox Live.
Rym: Video of your penis.
Scott: Oh, it's a good call.
Rym: I imagine.
Scott: Very excellent design decision.
Rym: If someone were, I don't know, crazy, they might put something in that video other than their penis.
Rym: Maybe if they're a girl.
Rym: But then you've got to have a sham penis ready to go.
Scott: Sham-bun.
Rym: What comes out of a sham-bun?
Rym: Shampoo.
Scott: That's a good call because the basic idea of Warlords is that you're playing this sort of four-way Pong.
Scott: And everyone has this sort of corner of the board to protect and they have a castle wall.
Scott: And they themselves are inside the castle wall.
Scott: So what better, instead of having some digital avatar representing the person inside the castle wall, have a video of them inside the castle wall.
Scott: It's a great idea.
Rym: Of their penis.
Scott: Well, you know, it's a good idea.
Scott: I like it.
Rym: But Warlords.
Scott: And Warlords is a great game.
Rym: It's what I guess.
Rym: I really, I think that the best kinds of games to play with a whole bunch of people, especially like casual gaming, are the very abstract, very directly competitive games.
Rym: Games like my dot's going to push your dot off the board.
Scott: Well, that's why I think the boom blocks is fun.
Scott: for that reason.
Rym: Yeah, we've got to play that boom blocks.
Rym: It's not worth $50.
Scott: No, that's the thing.
Scott: is the boom box looks really fun.
Scott: And I'm sure it's really fun and I can sort of tell that it's going to be good if I play it.
Scott: But seriously.
Scott: But it's not worth $50.
Scott: Warlords.
Scott: Bring that shit down to 30, yo.
Rym: One, you can get, if you have an Atari, you can get Warlords for like a dime.
Scott: You can get Warlords for pretty much almost any system.
Scott: I have Warlords on my DS.
Rym: And in fact, Warlords on Xbox Live is only 400 Microsoft points, which is like 800 space dollars.
Scott: How many, how many is it?
Scott: It's another we, a one point is like one penny.
Scott: So what is it on the Microsoft?
Rym: One Microsoft point is 8.94 pence times a Euro.
Rym: I don't, I don't know.
Scott: Times a Euro.
Scott: That's a lot.
Scott: That's like $10.
Scott: Is that how you got there?
Rym: What else am I going to say?
Rym: It's Warlords.
Rym: I'm going to review Warlords.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: Warlords is fucking awesome play.
Rym: It's really fun.
Scott: As long as you play the multiplayer.
Scott: Single player is lame.
Rym: Terribly deep.
Scott: Well, there's the catching mechanism.
Rym: Well, not only if you turn that on.
Rym: I don't know how the Xbox one goes.
Scott: There's also the speed release mechanism.
Rym: There were a couple of modes in the Atari.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: Actually though, if anyone's hardcore, and I got to see if we can get one of these for Katsu-Con.
Rym: I don't know if we can, but the Warlords arcade cabinet, the upper right was pretty mad.
Rym: It was two player, whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The cocktail version, which is one of my favorite ways to play games.
Scott: That is excellent.
Rym: I love those old cocktail cabinets.
Scott: Like if I had like a room that needed a tiny table, I would get one of those.
Rym: The thing is, there's something about those cocktail cabinets that it's not just like the functionality or whatever.
Rym: That is from a different era of gaming.
Rym: That is back when video gaming was not the purview of punk kids, but video gaming was something that they expected to sell to somewhat well-to-do people in bars.
Scott: When I was a kid, there was a dentist or orthodontist.
Scott: I went to, I forget, but it was in some waiting room of some office.
Scott: And whenever I went there, he had a little arcade and in his arcade, he had a Galaxian cocktail set, right?
Scott: And from until I saw Galaxian upright, I thought that just, "Oh, Galaxian is like
Scott: that.".
Scott: I didn't realize that it was a thing.
Rym: Yeah, but cocktail cabinets used to be just fixtures and bars and restaurants all over.
Scott: Yeah, doesn't Bomber's Burrito Bar have a Pac-Man cocktail one?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: No, I don't remember if it's Pac-Man or Ms.
Rym: Pac-Man.
Scott: I forget.
Rym: But I do remember that it wasn't at all easy.
Rym: It required the precise... Okay.
Rym: Man, we're just playing inside baseball all night tonight.
Rym: But seriously, it just, it harkens to a different age and there's a certain element of class there.
Scott: I had an idea just now.
Scott: Why don't we make cocktail cabinets of newer games?
Scott: Maybe just put a PC in there with some Mame or something or I don't know.
Scott: I'm sure it's been done, right?
Scott: Wait a minute, you know what?
Scott: Just pop an NES and a TV in there with an LCD screen?
Rym: We've been looking for a "use your hands" and not on a keyboard project for a long time.
Rym: And the last one we really got into was "RibMakes a DDR Pad" and that ended in disaster.
Scott: and Check this out.
Scott: Here we go.
Scott: Ready?
Scott: Real simple.
Scott: Get a normal table that two people can sit at.
Scott: It's the right height for sitting at, right?
Scott: Two chairs.
Scott: Cut a hole in the table.
Scott: Put a piece of glass in the hole in the table.
Scott: Mount an LCD screen under the glass.
Rym: Actually, you'd probably be better off with a recessed CRT.
Scott: I'm just saying, mount some sort of screen under the glass.
Scott: Then put some sort of Mac Mini in there.
Rym: I can abstract your idea a little bit.
Rym: Why don't we make a cocktail cabinet and then play games on it and have that in our lounge and be all classy?
Scott: Yeah, but I want to put a turn-based strategy game like an Advance Wars in there.
Rym: I just imagined some Civ 4.
Rym: The Civ 4 cocktail cabinet.
Scott: I don't know if Civ 4 is the best choice.
Rym: The beautiful thing about the cocktail cabinet was that usually when versus, two people would sit across from each other sharing drinks while playing a game.
Scott: I mean, I've seen pictures of older Japanese arcades and when they had versus games, it would be two cabinets and they would be facing opposite each other.
Scott: So if the cabinets weren't there, you would be looking your opponent in the eyes.
Rym: That's because Japan is brilliant.
Scott: But instead in the U.S.
Scott: when there's a versus game, it'd be two people standing next to each other.
Rym: That's because Americans are cheap.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But regardless, to knock it off on a tangent, if you can find a cocktail warlords cabinet, not only are they pretty big, not only are they four player and people sit at the four corners.
Rym: Good God, are they awesome.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much the best warlords experience you can get.
Scott: As long as it works.
Scott: If it's broken, it sucks.
Rym: It's up there with Rampart.
Rym: And I'll say this.
Scott: It's not Rampart.
Rym: No, the experience though of sitting around the cocktail.
Scott: Oh man, Rampart cocktail.
Rym: I don't think that existed.
Scott: I think it would work though.
Scott: I think it would.
Rym: Really well.
Rym: I don't think it existed.
Scott: Because everyone had the track balls, but on their own.
Rym: Huh.
Rym: What if we ported German board games to a cocktail cabinet?
Scott: It'd be okay, but you're better off just playing German board games.
Rym: Well, maybe a Twilight struggle.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: So the Penny Arcade game, the Precipice of Darkness came out.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: And I bought it for $20.
Rym: Well, you and everyone else, according to, I'm not going to quote anyone here, but it set some records for sales.
Scott: What kind of sales did it make?
Rym: The first episode of Penny Arcade Adventures was the highest grossing Xbox Live Arcade debut ever.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: So that was, but that was on the Xbox Live.
Scott: There's all, I bought the PC version.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I just read that paragraph.
Rym: You keep talking and I'll read the sales stats.
Scott: So if you buy the PC version, it's pretty interesting what they do.
Scott: When you buy it, they give you a key and you can use that key to either play the Mac, Windows or Linux versions.
Scott: And you can actually like use the key multiple times because they hate DRM as much as we do.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: This also means I can give the key to Rym, which means we only have to pay $20 to both play the game, which,
Rym: but then again, then again, there's the, uh, we didn't talk about this yesterday because bank holiday, but there's some news on that front regarding the right to first sale of software, but we'll talk about that next Monday.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Um, so this game, uh, it's a Penny Arcade game, right?
Scott: It's their first game.
Scott: It's an episodic game.
Scott: So there's going to be more episodes, right?
Scott: I beat the whole game and this is what I have to say about it.
Scott: The penny arcade ness of the game is delectable.
Scott: If you like the penny arcades, this is the penny arcades full on.
Scott: You got the awesomeness dialogue of the penny arcade style in the awesomeness art of the penny arcade style.
Scott: And you got some animations, you got some nice sound effects and music.
Scott: You got some environments.
Rym: The voice acting is superb.
Scott: The writing is almost none of it, but yeah, when it's there, it is superb.
Scott: Pretty much everything about the game, uh, in terms of, you know, the artistic creation and the visuals and the audios and the story and everything is fantastic.
Scott: The game itself is meh.
Rym: If it wasn't a penny arcade game, there'll be no reason, but I thought you always argued that style and not meant nothing.
Rym: and all that matters is gameplay.
Scott: That's not what I say at all.
Scott: I say that if there's, if there's no, that's not what I say.
Scott: What I say is if the only thing a game has to offer is something that is not gameplay, then there's no reason to actually play it.
Scott: You can always just get that.
Rym: Does the penny arcade game offer good gameplay?
Scott: Not really.
Rym: Uh huh.
Scott: It's only slightly better than your average, uh, it's, it's not, see the thing is it's, it's sort of fighting with itself.
Scott: It's deciding whether it wants to be sort of a Japanese turn-based RPG combat kind of game, or if it wants to be sort of a like point and click adventure game.
Scott: And I really think if they just made it a full on point and click adventure game and forgot about their silly turn-based RPG combat, the game would be a hell of a lot better.
Scott: But it's like, you'll go somewhere and it'd be like, oh, kill all the clowns in town.
Scott: So you walk around the town killing all the clowns, then it's like, oh, now you got to kill all the barbershop quartets.
Scott: So you go around killing all the barbershop quartets and the exact same four screens, you know, and it's sort of like, uh, and the combat itself, while better than say final fantasy where you just choose menu items and wait, you know, it's got sort of that dexterity thing that like some of the Mario RPGs have.
Scott: where it's like, you know, you got to push the button really fast and then hit it with exact timing in order to do the most damage.
Scott: You know, that's, that's good.
Scott: I like that kind of action, but there's not that many moves and actually doing the combat is sort of annoying because there's no like keyboard shortcuts or anything.
Scott: You have to like wait for these, the attacks to ready themselves, then click on them, then click on the bad guy and the bad guys are moving, you know, sort of moving around and fighting in real time.
Scott: So like if one of them is coming in to attack you, it's like, you got to sort of, ah, where did he go?
Scott: Oh, there he is.
Scott: Click, you know, and at the same time you're waiting for these attacks to finish getting ready.
Scott: You have to push the space bar with precise timing to block and that's very, very annoying, but it's also very, very easy and very quick.
Scott: So you get it over with and sort of out of the way.
Rym: I feel like the game is probably worth it just for the style and, and if you're a fan of penny arcade, it's, it's pretty much the ultimate fan experience, sort of, I guess having sex with the two of them.
Scott: See, the thing is playing it though, it really feels like they should have just made a penny arcade, like flash anime, flash animation, TVs, animated penny arcade movie.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Just, you know, just, they could have made it flash just like homestar runner.
Rym: They're about video games.
Rym: So I feel like what they're doing is that instead of making a movie and instead of making a game, they've kind of bridged the two in a way where there's gameplay elements and what is otherwise just a movie and there's movie elements and was otherwise just a game.
Rym: And I feel like from what little I've gone through the game so far and looked at it and read it, I feel like this is a better combination of the two than many other games have done.
Scott: That is what, there is a merger somewhat of the, the plot and the awesomeness and the gameplay.
Scott: Like, you know, walking around looking at the stuff you sort of, you know, the story is sort of delivered and what you see while you're playing and you know, you talk to people in town and that gives you some of the plot
Rym: is made, made by what the first like background NPC says when you first encounter him.
Scott: Yeah, that's for sure.
Rym: I don't think I should spoil it.
Rym: Good God.
Rym: Did that make the game for me?
Scott: But, um, you know, if they didn't have that sort of stuff in there, you wouldn't have to play this game.
Scott: You could just go on YouTube and like watch a video of all the, you know, the dialogue and all the text and then you'd be sad.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: I mean, there's something to be said for experience now.
Rym: Well, games haven't done it very well and I think there's a lot of ground to cover before games.
Rym: I mean, there's a lot more we can do in terms of gaming as a, as a medium for expression, but there's a day, like playing final fantasy form, especially final fantasy six is a good example where if it had been just a movie, it probably would have been a really damn good movie.
Rym: And if it just been a, you know, TV series or whatever, I think it would have been good.
Rym: But because it's a game, instead of investing one hour or if it was like a full season, 12 hours or 13 hours into it, you end up investing 40 or 50.
Rym: And while that gets old, if you haven't experienced that before, I can see how that kind of, you can build more investment into the characters by causing you to have to go through all this stuff with them instead of just watching it.
Rym: I just wish games would do it better and not just make everything a TV.
Scott: Well, that is the one thing that the penny arcade game does, right.
Scott: Is that it's very short because it's only one episode.
Scott: So even though the RPG combat is sort of sort of annoying and not that great and you sort of sometimes in the game you have to do it.
Scott: I mean, when you fought the barbershop quartets, there were like only four of them.
Scott: And then that was it.
Scott: So it was like, oh, I beat them all.
Scott: OK, so none of it really takes all that long.
Scott: So you won't get a chance to be really pissed off at it because when you're about to get pissed off, you sort of you beat it and you're like, oh, the only thing that I could see could be annoying is sort of trying to go around and get everything.
Scott: Like I just tried to blow through the game.
Scott: I didn't try to like get all the stuff.
Scott: And apparently there's a lot of stuff I didn't get.
Rym: So, yeah, I feel like a lot of that's not worth it.
Scott: It's totally not worth it.
Scott: So, yeah, if you like Penny Arcade, then it's probably worth your while to get the Penny Arcade game.
Scott: And I'm actually I'm pretty sure that the Xbox and the PC versions are the same.
Scott: So if you have an Xbox, I'm going to suggest you get that version, because even though I haven't played that version, I suspect the RPG combat will be less annoying using the gamepad as opposed to being forced to use the mouse to click on all these different things all over the place.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And but if you do buy the PC version, you get Mac Linux Windows versions, which is way cool.
Scott: And it totally works.
Scott: like the Linux version works.
Scott: It just doesn't work on my laptop because the video card is sort of bleh, but it totally works on Windows and it works on my Linux computer at work where the video card is good.
Scott: And I'm sure it'll work on a Mac.
Scott: I haven't tried it.
Rym: Ah, but anyway, things of the day, a little old here.
Rym: People who are super cool have probably seen this, but I'm not a huge fan of Warhammer 40K, but I before any I mean, I'll bet you're already on your way with pitchforks, but I don't dislike Warhammer 40K.
Rym: I love big miniature giant armies fighting game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: My only real problems with Warhammer 40K are the price and the amount of time it takes and the amount of space it takes.
Rym: But at the same time, it's the kind of thing where if you're into it like I mean, people who play Warhammer are usually they're into it more for the modeling and the army and the style.
Scott: Yeah, if you're just doing the modeling alone and you never even play the game, that's that's perfectly cool.
Rym: Well, even the game, too, because it's a lot like how we played Battletech, where the game itself is kind of crap.
Scott: Well, it's not that bad.
Rym: I mean, Battletech is Warhammer not so bad, but that's pretty bad.
Scott: That's not bad.
Rym: The way we played it was pretty bad.
Scott: The way we played it was bad.
Scott: But if you play it, you know, big real time, it's great.
Rym: No, because then it takes the rest of your life.
Scott: Same as Warhammer.
Rym: Not now.
Rym: Warhammer is a more.
Rym: it's a tighter game.
Rym: I think it's a better game.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm pretty sure they're pretty equal games in my eyes.
Rym: Warhammer is more of a tactical and strategic armies around.
Rym: And if unless you play make an 80 pound mech and then let's all fight that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you play Battletech, yeah, you're supposed to have like lots of mechs.
Rym: But having lots of mechs bogs down a lot more quickly than the games like Warhammer do.
Rym: It's not fun.
Rym: It doesn't work.
Scott: Well, it's also the difference between, you know, the squad based kind of game and the army based kind of game.
Rym: Anyway, Warhammer like these kinds of war games, I feel like the way.
Rym: the best way to enjoy them is not so much to care solely about the winning and losing and that like the gameplay mechanics.
Rym: I'm going to make the best possible army to win, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, because while that's fun, the depth of Warhammer is not that great.
Rym: And randomness rears its ugly head on more than one occasion.
Scott: Pretty much all occasions.
Scott: Not quite, but as the Warhammer players, if they're if their dice are really good to them, see how many say yes.
Rym: But the thing is, the way to truly enjoy these games is to play with an awesome army and know that that army is awesome.
Rym: Now, what is more awesome than the Hello Kitty army?
Scott: The Cthulhu army?
Rym: I think the Hello Kitty army is better.
Scott: Hello, Cthulhu army.
Rym: Catherine's Hello Kitty Sisters of Battle.
Scott: Alrighty.
Rym: This is the kind of army where if I had time to play a game like Warhammer, this is the army that I would field.
Rym: Because whether you win or lose, if you're playing with an army like this, that says a lot about you.
Scott: Maybe I'd feel a Gundam army or something because I take those robot guys and because I totally be the robot guys.
Scott: How could you not be the robots?
Rym: Do you even know the?
Rym: who are the robots?
Scott: I remember that someone said it before, Tao.
Rym: Are the Tyranids from Warhammer or from something else?
Scott: Tyranids, Tyranids, they're not from Starcraft.
Rym: Anyway, there's some pictures here.
Rym: It's pretty cool.
Rym: But I just feel like this is the utmost expression of everything that Warhammer is and ever should be.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely.
Rym: The guy who comes in with the perfect army who has the best statistical chance of winning is not nearly as cool as the guy who comes in with his awesome orc army.
Rym: I just like the orcs.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Alright, so check this out.
Scott: I heard about this website on the.
Scott: I think it was on the tweet this morning.
Scott: I guess it was the tweet from this weekend.
Scott: But anyway, it's called the Import Genius and it's not a free website, so you can't really get much use out of it unless you're going to pay.
Scott: But what this website does is incredibly interesting and I think I can tie it back to video games.
Scott: What this website does is they access the information from the U.S.
Scott: customs so they know what's being imported into the U.S.
Scott: and to who.
Scott: So, for example, you can go to this website and if you paid, you could do like a search, I guess.
Scott: And you could say, you know, who imported computers?
Scott: And it would say, you know, IBM imported, you know, five crates of, you know, computers to so and so.
Scott: Or, you know, the example that I've made me discover this website was Apple imported like 30 something crates of electronic computers to Cupertino.
Scott: I wonder what those are.
Scott: New iPhones.
Scott: So.
Scott: The reason this is interesting for gaming action is because you could see, huh, Nintendo imported, you know, X crates of, you know, DS's.
Scott: Oh, there's new DS's.
Scott: or, you know, Capcom imported to something, something.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think that you could definitely, you know, sort of figure out when you know, yeah, you know, you can figure out when new games are going to be imported, when consoles are going to be updated, all that sort of thing.
Scott: So I feel like some of the, you know, gaming review sites, you know, or the magazines that the so-called professional gaming media should get accounts on here and keep tabs on what's going on.
Rym: Because I can't afford to kind of some side channel sideband information there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, plus you could there's definitely all sorts of cool stuff in there, you know, like, you know, you could see when like sugar is coming in or, you know, corn syrup, sugar is very important because first you get the show.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: And then you get the power and then you get the.
Scott: I mean, that there's got to be all sorts.
Scott: I can't even begin to think about all the, you know, interesting stuff.
Scott: You could see whenever like a large shipment of goods comes into the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: you know what it is and who's getting it.
Scott: And that that is freaking useful information if you are in the right kind of position.
Rym: So it's me, a Mario, I'm not a real doctor.
Scott: Do not let me touch you genitalia.
Scott: OK, that's the old joke is don't let Dr.
Scott: Mario touch your genitals.
Scott: He's not a real doctor.
Rym: Where is that joke from?
Scott: I forget.
Scott: We made it up.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: No, no, no, we didn't.
Rym: It was from bash dot org.
Rym: Oh, was it?
Rym: That's where I got it from.
Scott: It must be.
Rym: All right.
Rym: This will be a short show talking about Dr.
Rym: Mario.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So there was a WiiWare game that came out yesterday and it's the Dr.
Scott: Mario for the WiiWare.
Scott: And I played it and I'm better than everyone I know, a Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: He's about as good at this as I don't know.
Rym: Some people are in advanced wars.
Scott: You know, it's funny.
Scott: I remember when I was a kid and Dr.
Scott: Mario came out for the Game Boy and for the NES at the same time and they made a big deal out of it.
Scott: There was a big marketing push.
Rym: Oh, there were cartoons between every TV show I watched about Dr.
Scott: I remember being in a toy store back in the day when toy stores were amazing and there was a TV screen up in the store and it showed Dr.
Scott: Mario being played on the screen.
Scott: It was like, whoa, whoa.
Scott: But I never got Dr.
Scott: Mario as a kid.
Scott: Not for the Game Boy, not for the NES.
Scott: I just never got it.
Scott: And I don't think I played Dr.
Scott: Mario until like late high school, early college.
Scott: I just never played it at all.
Scott: It's somehow I'm better than everyone at it.
Scott: I don't get it.
Rym: Well, I used to be pretty good at it, but I haven't played it, I don't know, since I was a kid with any regularity.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I focus more on games like Battle Balls or Advanced Wars.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the thing about I don't want to sit here and explain how to play Dr.
Scott: Mario, but Dr.
Scott: Mario is a color matching game.
Scott: But it's mostly what I like about it is unlike some of the other games, like, say, Tetris and such, it's, you know, when something clears, the stuff sort of falls down
Rym: and
Scott: the game is
Rym: all about
Scott: sort of putting things in a position so that when they fall down, they'll be in a good spot.
Scott: So you're looking like you have this sort of deep look ahead in the game that you don't.
Scott: Other games have sort of the more immediate clear the shit out of the way where Dr.
Scott: Mario has more of the set up things properly so that when you do clear them out of the way, more stuff gets cleared out of the way afterwards.
Rym: But anyway, let's talk about the WiiWare implementation of this game first.
Rym: I mean, you can play it like normal Dr.
Rym: Mario and it's fun and it works and it's Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Rym: It only lets you play one versus one, though.
Rym: There's no other mode.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: See, I thought that they were going to have like a full on for people playing regular old playing Dr.
Scott: Mario at the same time, which they could have done, but they didn't do that.
Scott: I don't know why.
Rym: Yeah, I was hoping for some I didn't know what, but I was hoping for some sort of D.S.
Rym: or some some kind of extra weird mode because there was.
Rym: this is the kind of game where they would test like the weird mode to see if it works at all.
Scott: Well, they put in this flash mode and we figured out how the flash mode works is basically you're playing normal Dr.
Scott: Mario, except some of the little goobers on the screen are flashing.
Scott: And if you get rid of those flashing ones, you win.
Scott: So you only have to get rid of the flashing ones.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's actually a pretty good mode because, you know, it allows for quicker gameplay.
Scott: And at the same time, it's sort of instead of just trying to clear everything out of the way, it's like, well, you know, why waste your time clearing the whole board?
Scott: The goal is to just clear those guys and not anyone else.
Scott: It's like, huh?
Scott: And it sort of makes you think in a different way and put your pills in a different way to sort of make a channel like straight down to the to the deep flashing guys.
Rym: But the only other thing they really added is this mode where you and all your friends can play at the same time, grabbing pills simultaneously and putting them onto the board.
Rym: And it's kind of a, you know, us versus the game mode.
Rym: But it's really not that fun at all.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They made a co-op mode called like Virus Buster.
Scott: And basically it's Dr.
Scott: Mario, except everything is big.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And use the Wiimote to point at the screen.
Scott: You have a little target and you can grab the pills, you know, sort of with the Wiimote by pointing at them, rotate them and sort of drag them into position.
Scott: And what's interesting about this is you can manipulate the pieces that are in like the next area.
Scott: So you can sort of pre flip.
Rym: It's not interesting at all, though, because all you can do is flip them.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: You can.
Scott: you can also when little bits are like, let's say I clear out some horizontal stuff and a stop on top is falling.
Scott: When something starts falling, you can sort of grab it and move it, which allows, you know, a lot more flexible options there in terms of, you know, where you can move pieces rather than just, you know, if something's falling, it falls where it is.
Scott: And when you're dragging the pieces around to position them, you can't drag them up, but you can drag them left or right through other pieces, which is sort of tricky.
Scott: You know, it's not something you can usually do in a normal Dr.
Scott: Mario game.
Scott: So that sort of gives you options of of ways to be able to have four people, you know, sort of collectively trying to beat the Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Rym: I mean, it escalates a little bit or it'll get faster.
Rym: Then it gives you two or three pills at the same time or two or three.
Rym: We're not going to be around the bush.
Rym: The end result is that it's really not that fun.
Rym: It's kind of broken.
Rym: It's just there's.
Rym: you'll play it once or twice and you'll never play it again.
Scott: The reason it's not fun is because if you play it by yourself, right, just one person, it's pretty much impossible because you can't handle three pills at a time when you're only one person.
Scott: And it's no, you might as well just play regular Dr.
Scott: Mario, which is better.
Scott: And if you have multiple people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: First of all, you want to be just playing normal Dr.
Scott: Mario against each other.
Scott: You don't want to be doing this.
Scott: And second of all, what is happening is the everyone's cooperating.
Scott: But really what you're doing is just hindering each other.
Scott: Like one guy will try to put something in one spot and someone else will be trying to do the same thing.
Scott: But the end result is like they both push the button and then it ends in the wrong position.
Scott: And it's really basically everyone just gets in everyone's away and then you lose.
Scott: And it's really frustrating.
Scott: And it's like you're all trying to cooperate.
Scott: But by trying to cooperate, you end up screwing each other, which is very, very upsetting.
Scott: It's not like, say, four swords, you know, where, you know, you any any harm you do to each other is sort of intentional and silly.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: it's very upsetting that you're all actually trying to cooperate.
Scott: Yet you end up just dicking each other over and getting pissed off and then not wanting to play anymore.
Rym: A much better way to play seems to be to sit there with a Wiimote in each hand and play it by yourself.
Scott: That's an OK mode.
Rym: That's actually kind of fun.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: Actually, I played the Wi-Fi because it lets you play Dr.
Scott: Mario against people online.
Scott: And I think it's the first time you've ever been able to play Dr.
Scott: Mario online.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It worked and it was kind of good.
Rym: It's well done.
Rym: It works just fine.
Scott: You know, I was going to say I seem to remember that, you know, the Tetris DS was like the online game.
Scott: I played more than any other online game, at least for the DS.
Scott: Or were we?
Scott: And this Dr.
Scott: Mario, I think that the dropping pieces puzzle game is definitely like the kind of game that Nintendo gets right with it, with the Internet action.
Rym: Of course, at the same time, the original, you know, you play this game on the NES or whatever with your friends.
Rym: And while it's a versus game, it's it's.
Rym: it's not really.
Rym: it's more of a. you're both racing to the finish.
Rym: There's very little interaction between the players.
Rym: I mean, it's not like, well, battle balls, because I mentioned it earlier, where it's this whole game of timing combos to cancel out the other person's combos and then combo them.
Rym: Your combos do very little and there's almost no variation in what they do.
Scott: So your combos do so.
Rym: if you get a big combo, combos do is is determine basically who got the combo first, slightly inconveniences the other person.
Rym: So it rewards you for speed.
Scott: Yeah, but at the same time, the combos can actually might not even do damage at all.
Scott: Like you might drop two bits on the other guy's board that actually help him out and make it easier for him.
Scott: So so, yeah, there's not too much.
Rym: I just I more enjoy games where there's more direct competition like warlords.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or battle balls, even though I'm awful at it.
Scott: I just enjoy Dr.
Scott: Mario more if I played against someone who was actually as good as me, which is actually why the Wi-Fi comes in handy, because everyone here is no good.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Welcome to the advanced wars world of Rym.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's weird.
Scott: It's like I don't understand why other people aren't good.
Scott: Like I look at it and it is sort of obvious where to put the pieces.
Scott: I don't understand.
Rym: Well, I guess the listeners left to play you and prove that you're wrong.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Let's let's do the friend codes for Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Rym: We probably still.
Scott: I've been meaning to fix the I.D.
Scott: share thing and I kind of suck at it.
Rym: But you even you skip these games, you're going to work on stuff and playing games, other games.
Scott: I know.
Rym: I know it's like games, write code or play games and not pretend you're going to write code.
Scott: I don't have enough time to do.
Scott: I need to do both.
Scott: I don't have enough time.
Scott: I should just not sleep.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I don't know how worth it this game is to you unless unless you already like Dr.
Rym: Mario.
Rym: I wouldn't bother to be honest.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This game is like.
Scott: I think this is really only worth it for fans of Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Scott: If you're not a Dr.
Scott: Mario person, you probably it's not worth.
Scott: I think it's like 10 bucks.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: If you're not sure if you're a Dr.
Rym: Mario fan, just get a rom.
Rym: play Dr.
Rym: Mario on the end.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Play some Dr.
Scott: Mario before you actually buy Dr.
Scott: Mario to know if you if it's a game that you're going to like and play a hell of a lot because I can actually see myself playing the Wi-Fi version of this, you know, quite a bit when there's no other Wii games to play.
Rym: See, though, that's that's the I guess the biggest failing of Dr.
Rym: Mario that never got.
Rym: I guess I'm sad that they never added something to it to add this.
Rym: But whenever you talk about a game like Battle Balls or all those other like puzzle games, there's always the stories from the heyday of man, that one game where I totally blah, blah, blah, 100 combo, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: You have like these battle stories of the times you won by some crazy fluke or the times you lost because the other person had this gigantic combo, like the combo of the gods.
Rym: But there's none of that in Dr.
Scott: Mario because people who are much better than me can set up huge combos, but they're not epic.
Rym: They don't do much in the game other than they're cool to watch.
Rym: But they're not you know, they're not memorable like some other games are.
Rym: They don't hit the other guy.
Rym: They're not like this.
Rym: Everything explodes.
Rym: They're just, oh, I beat the game very cleverly and very quickly.
Rym: And I've won.
Scott: Now we will continue as another game because it's mostly a game of slowly chewing away all the viruses rather than blowing the hell out of them really quickly.
Rym: Yeah, there's no timing element at all in terms of get the combo, don't get the combo.
Rym: There's none of that.
Scott: No, it doesn't have that action.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: You never hear people talking about their Dr.
Rym: Mario war stories, but a lot of people have puzzled upon war stories.
Scott: Actually, one thing about Dr.
Scott: Mario is Dr.
Scott: Mario has really good music and they've added a few new musics to it.
Scott: And I don't like them as much as I like the old musics, the old remixes of the old.
Rym: No, no, that's in flash mode.
Scott: No, there's a because they have, you know, fever and chill, but they added, I think, cough and sneeze.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I didn't realize it until just recently that the songs, the original songs and Dr.
Scott: Mario were fever and chill.
Scott: And I didn't realize that the reason they were called fever and chill is because it goes with the theme of Dr.
Scott: Mario fever.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Scott: And then the caught the fact that they added cough and sneeze.
Rym: You're not kidding.
Rym: You're not.
Rym: I thought this was a joke.
Scott: No, the fact that they added cough and sneeze, I said, oh, the songs are named after symptoms.
Rym: This is just like that time when you realized that the Beatles isn't spelled like the bug.
Rym: It's spelled like a beat in music.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't realize that for a long time.
Rym: Well, you probably don't know the answer to this then.
Rym: What are the names of the three bugs?
Scott: The three things in Dr.
Scott: Mario?
Scott: The three viruses?
Scott: Red, blue and yellow.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Annoying, annoying and more annoying.
Rym: Fever, chill and weird.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Really.
Rym: Oh, I think red was fever.
Rym: Yellow was definitely weird.
Rym: Red had to be fever and blue was chill.
Rym: That makes sense.
Scott: Yeah, totally makes sense.
Rym: I could look it up, I guess, but I'm 99% certain that's how it was.
Rym: Huh?
Scott: That's interesting.
Scott: See, it's weird because like Dr.
Scott: Mario sort of has like this mystic lore to it in a way.
Rym: One piece of lore and we've already revealed it to the world.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Another thing about this new Dr.
Scott: Mario is that it incorporates the me's a little bit, which is pretty fun.
Scott: Like when you win and you see your me wearing a lab coat and a stethoscope dancing and like pumping his fist, that's good times.
Rym: Ha ha.
Rym: Fist pound.
Scott: Fist pump, not fist pound.
Rym: Yes, but the Joker's fist pound.
Rym: I can't say fist, yeah, anyway.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: Anyway, in general, I like the falling block puzzle games and I really think that they're some of the best video games from a gameplay perspective because they incorporate the quick thinking, the pattern recognition and the rapid hand-eye coordination action all into one game.
Rym: See, I feel like the most important aspect is just the direct abstracted competition.
Scott: Yeah, that definitely is a bonus added on top, but.
Rym: And I think we're really stretching trying to talk about Dr.
Rym: Mario.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: We were going to talk about sort of falling block, you know, puzzle-y games in the genre.
Rym: But apparently we already did that show.
Scott: We already did that show like two years ago.
Rym: In 2006.
Scott: So we can't do that show again, so we had to talk about just Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: We got a good show lined up tomorrow with the anime and the comics.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share-a-like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.