Rym: It's Wednesday July 30th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm the baddest motherfucker in the world, and it's the juggernaut Tonight we talk about on GeekNights the surrogates.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So the other day Emily and I were gonna watch some anime But we ended up running into a problem where either the soft subs wouldn't work.
Rym: I couldn't make him work.
Rym: so we gave up.
Scott: you push J.
Rym: And it didn't work.
Scott: then you push pound sign didn't work.
Scott: Well, then that means the file is messed up.
Rym: Yeah There was something weird with it.
Scott: a lot of people have been getting worse at encoding lately.
Rym: and if there's a problem with those files Just yeah, cuz I tried to open it later in VLC, and it just wouldn't even open.
Rym: so yeah So it's a broken file deleted, but then you know all right What are we gonna watch?
Rym: so I start patrolling through until I find something that works?
Rym: And I end up picking the first episode of the birdie the mighty remake birdie the mighty decode.
Rym: You know what.
Rym: it's pretty damn good And I really like it.
Scott: I watched one episode of the original, and it was so okay.
Scott: It was so.
Scott: so Here's the thing.
Rym: so I didn't watch some of those old-school like comedy action shows.
Rym: And if you're looking for the comedy action show.
Scott: remake slayers revolution.
Rym: Huh you know what cuz there's been a distinct lack of good comedy action shows lately Maybe.
Rym: and I know I know something else.
Rym: cuz I realize something you know watching one birdie the mighty decode is really good.
Rym: I really enjoyed the first episode to a surprising degree and so did Emily.
Rym: It ended and we're like.
Rym: so I feel like I want to watch more of that.
Rym: She's like yeah, me too Who would have thunk it?
Rym: uh-huh, but you know the birdie the mighty why?
Rym: I think what really made it stand out was that the humor With wasn't.
Rym: it seems like a lot of anime lately is really kind of.
Rym: the humor is expected and stereotypical and just.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe it's just the tropes of the era, but I don't find it that funny, but a show like slayers They don't quite go the wacky anime humor where they just hit you with something out of the blue But they hit you with unexpected jokes at least occasionally.
Scott: Well the thing is they have their own set of slayers jokes that they made like they're in an inn that in ain't surviving.
Scott: It's not gonna happen.
Scott: You know it's not gonna happen But you know what.
Scott: it don't matter cuz you just got to see how it happened, or you know there's got to be a fish man.
Scott: But It doesn't matter cuz you could just put a fisherman on screen and instant funny.
Rym: I can point out one other thing though.
Rym: There's been a distinct lack of Interesting well choreographed action scenes in anime lately.
Rym: That's for sure I I've heard I mean we haven't watched enough black lagoon, but people have said that there are good action scenes in that.
Rym: and Birdie the mighty?
Rym: yeah, not you know.
Rym: a lot of shows lately They have the kind of slow pan action line slow pan pan of the face guy yelling Naruto all that stuff or Like a special move like in.
Rym: I don't know one piece.
Rym: This was some straight-up.
Rym: Just action anime, and it really made me nostalgic for some anime.
Rym: I used to watch when I was younger Speaking anime watching or younger.
Scott: I finished the escaflown a like a week or so ago man And I've been watching the Evangelion for the second time on the iPhone.
Rym: You're not I mean, I'm a huge escaflown a fan like.
Rym: I've seen this show like six times.
Scott: I've seen it two times.
Rym: So I gotta ask as someone who watched it once in marathon format at like the height of our anime fandom to Watching it again today.
Rym: You know older more sober more wise.
Rym: is that a good show.
Scott: Yeah, it's a good show I can't.
Scott: I don't know why you wouldn't want to watch that Joe.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I don't know.
Rym: it seems like it's getting a little bit of hate lately.
Scott: Why would it be getting hate?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's I consider one of the best shows ever made Not top three, but definitely top ten.
Rym: no movies Can't count movies because it's this whole different ballgame.
Scott: definitely I mean unlike the pretty much It's like it was weird because I watch a new anime right and I watch an episode and I might continue to watch episodes And that's alright, but with escaflown I watched the episode and I actually had an incredibly strong desire to watch the next episode
Rym: Because when a show like that's happening you'll be almost done with an episode on the train and you'll be pissed that you're home Yep,
Scott: or I'll be like trying to get out of work and turn it on as quick as I can.
Scott: But anyway, I Got the same issue going on with the evangelical perhaps even more so.
Scott: it's like I. you know.
Scott: I understand like in my mind why people are sort of you know, some people like evangelical and some people don't.
Scott: But I'm pretty sure the people don't are just morons.
Scott: Evangelion I'm watching that again.
Scott: I mean if escaflown is a top ten show watching Evangelion again.
Scott: I Think I just got to say flat-out.
Scott: It's the number two show behind cowboy Viva.
Rym: I think I have to agree.
Scott: I mean, I mean on my iPhone with this incredible shitty video quality.
Scott: This thing is better animated than any anime I've seen.
Scott: Except you know not counting movies and such like, you know Not counting like a Satoshi con or a studio for see you're in a cure or anything like that or the big brudgeon things like Standalone complex is pretty damn.
Rym: Well anime.
Scott: I think Evangelion is better animated.
Scott: the standalone complex.
Rym: Well, you know, I can say one thing There is problem.
Rym: There's more Detail.
Rym: that matters.
Scott: and even maybe if Evangelion was made today with all the CG would look like standalone complex.
Scott: but I think I like Evangelion.
Scott: I think the way it looks is bad not just the way it looks like I Watch an episode and I am desperate to watch the remainder.
Scott: Well, it's like right now.
Scott: I could just stop doing this and go keep watching.
Scott: Let me out.
Scott: and this is on a tiny iPhone.
Scott: It looks better than all these other shows do on television.
Rym: I think part of it is that a lot of people it seems like there's this whole kind of subculture of anime fans who?
Rym: They feel like they have to hate on whatever shows are popular or were popular or were popular in the past in order to I don't know be hip I don't get it because I Under.
Rym: I mean there are flaws.
Rym: Ava's not a perfect show by any stretch.
Rym: It has its flaws, but most of the complaints people have basically boiled down to where it's actually deep or where?
Rym: I don't understand it.
Rym: So I say it's just pretentious.
Scott: Yeah All right there are some things you could say about the end but I'm like 14 episodes in at this point and It doesn't matter if the end sucks.
Scott: Those are 14 of the best Animated 20-minute episodes that have ever been created in the entire history of the world.
Rym: I think it's fair to also say that you you if you take step out from the you know Enjoyment of the show or the message of the show.
Rym: I'm totally okay with you saying that I know pulled a crap move by saying to all of his fans are our kids.
Rym: I Couldn't come up with a good way to end this and I had something to say.
Rym: I tricked y'all into watching my show with giant robots.
Rym: now I'm gonna lecture at you for two episodes But at the same time I feel as though the lecture was good enough and the message was good enough to almost justify that.
Scott: Well, it's it's easily it.
Scott: you can easily Justify the original ending, you know artistically But it's hard to justify it from an entertainment factor that the other episodes do have.
Rym: see what the one thing I can say Those that the it really hit.
Rym: I mean, I remember watching the end of Ava the first time and I think it was good the way it ended that way because it really hits you over the head with.
Rym: you know the show kind of ends episode 24 and Then you see these hints of like what happened in the real world and they're kind of like they come and go and then you Get this whole kind of.
Rym: well Here's what the point of the show was and here's everything we were trying to say and that I'll admit.
Rym: I kind of I cried At the end, you know the clapping and all that business Just fun.
Scott: the whole show clap clapping wide.
Rym: Yeah, who's clapping for who and for what?
Scott: cut for your mom?
Rym: But the one dt.
Rym: I cried at the end there because I think the way the end was put together was just so absolutely perfect, but anyway There reason you're doing that dt Dt.
Scott: I don't know what was that?
Rym: Song song from.
Rym: were you trying to do the the song from the movie?
Scott: You know what song I'm doing tumbling down Maybe maybe maybe didn't come through.
Scott: Anyway, it sounded right to me.
Rym: You know what all we have to do I realize is take the end that the show end of Ava and the non-crazy parts of the movie end of Ava and cut them together into the actual end of Ava is
Scott: the other thing is the Last thing I want to say about the eventually before we get on with this, right?
Scott: I've seen the show.
Scott: once I was watched all the VHS is sort of one at a time Like once a week or so and then I watched again.
Scott: all the VHS is in a marathon and this is only the third time I'm watching the whole thing and it's been at least five years since I've seen the whole thing and I'm watching on I guess DVDs converted to iPhone format and There is absolutely nothing so far in 14 episodes.
Scott: that is not Crystal-clear and absolutely obvious, but the thing is is a lot of that.
Scott: You just have to pay the fuck attention.
Rym: I mean, I remember a scene in particular where?
Rym: Cod suddenly like Haji's like ah shit See ya and he flies away at Harrier.
Rym: Yeah, and he's got that thing in that briefcase.
Scott: Yep there's some things in the show that someone will say something very quickly or there'll be a scene that was very short and Or they'll be.
Scott: you know They'll be like a literally like a five-second scene like at the end of an episode.
Scott: and if you don't remember that you'll be a little confused.
Scott: and because you know the The sort of the context of what's going on in any given episode changes pretty rapidly like you won't piece things together between sort of when they're happy hanging out drinking in the apartment or When they're fighting and monster in the robots and when they're talking all serious business.
Scott: Well, you know like you're more with this weird stuff going on.
Scott: It's all secret.
Scott: Ooh, you really it's you have to connect all those things in your mind and keep all the context, you know consciously thinking about them in order to get what's going on, but it's not hard.
Rym: plus when I think about it Ava what it did is it did something that actually a newer show.
Rym: Bocorano also did really well.
Rym: where there's this a Real or crazy thing is happening, you know and Ava it's God is coming down to kick your ass humans It's the end of the world.
Rym: Yeah, but it's literal like it is literally happening and Here are real people dealing with it and The fact that people don't always cope with things like that so well and Bocorano did that in the same way.
Rym: it adds this Really kind of I don't know having normal characters and a perfectly real setting.
Rym: but yet the context beyond that is something Absolutely crazy.
Rym: but yet people same people have to deal with it in a sane manner.
Scott: Yeah, and even though there's things people don't know and there are things you don't know I mean, you know that like it's the end of the world here, right?
Scott: if they if they fail is game over and that's all your and everyone knows that and it's like Wow, but they're more concerned of these other things and you know, it's just.
Scott: you know They don't say it too often, but you have to keep that in mind.
Rym: Anyway, yeah We're not gonna turn this into the Ava.
Rym: should I feel like we need to do a show someday in the future?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Ava teach the controversy.
Scott: We gotta do some Ava something cuz I. I just feel like everyone else seems to shy away from the evangelical.
Scott: I'm not shy cuz I.
Rym: I still I feel as though Ava gets a bad rap among people who either didn't understand it Saw it once a long time ago or like hate not it.
Scott: Yep Misconceptions about it.
Rym: I've never seen it Yeah, and granted a lot of some of that is justified.
Rym: for example, oh no a little bit crazy.
Scott: Well, yeah, it's.
Scott: it's you know, crazy.
Scott: people make good things But at the same time it's like drugged up.
Scott: people make good things sometimes.
Rym: Remember when they put those spiders on acid.
Scott: they did not make good webs No, but they made much more awesome to look at webs.
Scott: So anyway this coming weekend this weekend the end of July the beginning of August as in August 1 2 3 in Hartford Connecticut and the Hartford convention Connecticut Convention Center, I don't know what it's the only convention center in Hartford.
Scott: Well, I guess I guess the Hartford Civic Center is no more, right?
Rym: So, I don't know I don't know anything about can and it's connected to a Marriott connected Connecticut.
Rym: I see it.
Rym: go into the know.
Scott: It's all 84.
Rym: So we are going to be at Connecticut, which is a fun anime con We've attended for the last.
Scott: that's not really an anime con.
Scott: It's sort of a general geek You know what?
Rym: I'll put it this way It has all the trappings of an anime con, but it is actually an anime web comics geek con.
Scott: Yeah, it's got anime web comics video gaming tabletop gaming sort of in relatively equal parts.
Scott: but in the dealer's room, you'll find mostly anime and manga I guess in proportion to other things and The kind of people who go there tend to be more The anime manga type.
Scott: it feels like in a small anime convention but it has everything going on.
Scott: like there are old guys who will come and play Warhammer the whole time and That you that's all they'll do.
Rym: see it's a con where you walk into any given part of the con and it's basically a completely Different con.
Rym: like you walk into the gaming side and it's just.
Rym: you might as well beat over con but then you walk out and you see cosplayers and then you go into the panel area and it's all web comics and you go The dealer's room and it feels like an anime con dealer's room.
Scott: Yeah, but then there's a couple guys in there.
Scott: There's like web comics in there that are selling their stuff.
Scott: And there's also you know a few things in there that don't fit like.
Scott: there's a comic book store that's set up in there.
Scott: You're like, huh?
Scott: Story set up in here.
Rym: What do you think?
Rym: a net account has always been really good about and I always want to give him props for this.
Rym: is that?
Rym: They are real.
Rym: They always let us experiment.
Rym: Well, you know we do all these panels and all these cons But Connecticut is kind of where we test-drive all of our new panels and some panels have died there.
Rym: They're sad.
Rym: Rightful deaths at Connecticut never to be released to the public.
Scott: Well a challenge run fire should have had that fate.
Scott: Yes, I said it should have but you didn't.
Rym: you didn't let it be kept striking it with lightning But it's you did.
Scott: I was I was just trying to shovel it into the ground and you were busy with your Frankenstein action.
Rym: It's still good.
Rym: Right?
Rym: So, uh We're doing as always quite a few panels but not nearly as many as we did last year, that's good.
Rym: So yes, I'm not gonna bother with the times.
Rym: I'll tell you this though.
Rym: Every panel we are doing is going to be on Saturday.
Rym: So if you really want to see us.
Rym: do panels come on Saturday, we're doing the anime magic game.
Rym: in the morning I do an anime You should see we're doing how to run an anime club Which if you've ever seen the anime club summit or how we've run this as other places We run it completely differently.
Rym: Akatsuka Akatsuka at Connecticut, yep, it's it's a balls to the wall.
Rym: Here's exactly how to do it.
Rym: We don't let the audience talk because no one knows what they're doing.
Rym: Yep, we're doing beyond Dungeons & Dragons the first time.
Rym: This is the one that we're gonna be running at the penny arcade Expo Test around.
Rym: a little test run and of course we are doing the GeekNights late night guest interview.
Rym: now This one is special because I think they were in a hurry to get the con book out.
Rym: the description of this event basically is The text that I wrote to them in suggesting the panel unedited.
Rym: So it basically says yeah, we've done this panel before.
Rym: It's pretty easy.
Rym: We just need you to provide as a guest.
Rym: if you can't provide one.
Rym: I know a noth will be there.
Rym: He's our friend.
Rym: we could interview him, you know Apple Geeks and all that.
Scott: That's literally what it says in the con book.
Scott: That's what we wrote in the email to them and they copied and pasted that into the con book.
Scott: Not so professional ConnectiCon this is why you're our like sandbox if we don't take you seriously.
Scott: If you want us to take you seriously, maybe you shouldn't you know be a little more professional.
Rym: But at the same time I still gotta ask enough, but I'm sure he'll do it.
Rym: So you might get to see us.
Scott: He'll be there.
Scott: Yes, he'll be there I imagine.
Rym: actually if you come to the GeekNights guest interview on Saturday night It is going to be a very informal very awesome roundtable with a lot of really cool people.
Rym: Probably if not, if nothing else, it'll be us talking to you So whatever or we'll just talk to enough and you'll all get to sit there and watch.
Scott: Yeah, another thing is that a lot of the panels there?
Scott: I mean the anime match game will probably be loaded but the vast majority of the panels you're on there have very low attendance Except not because I accept how to run an anime club, which was like standing in your room.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and it's not because of anything wrong with us.
Scott: It's just that's the way the con is.
Scott: There's not.
Rym: you know What's this making the pre-hoc anti trash talk right?
Scott: It's true.
Rym: What's this?
Rym: You're like, oh just in case you show up and no one's at our panel It is nothing.
Scott: but we'll be at the panel no matter what.
Scott: even if there's only one person there We still run the panel because that's what we're doing.
Scott: We're testing the panel.
Scott: Yeah, as long as we have an audience of one person.
Scott: We don't know it's enough to test it out.
Rym: But anyway, I just want to point out that we're running some pretty good panels.
Rym: also Katsunori Matsushita is going to be there.
Rym: I didn't look at the schedule when but he should be running kendo workshops and a kendo panel.
Rym: But who knows?
Rym: The con might have screwed up the scheduling on that.
Rym: so I can't promise anything.
Scott: and the rest of the time when we're not Doing panels.
Scott: We're gonna be in the game room gaming it up.
Rym: Yes Saturday and Sunday the a portion of the front row crew our kind of staff will be in the game room at the GeekNights' table Running all sorts of game demos burning wheel German board.
Scott: Yeah, we'll be in there on Sunday But we have associates who will be in there possibly Friday and definitely Saturday.
Scott: Well, we're doing panels.
Rym: You want us to teach you how to play a German board game and not just teach you the rules but teach you how to win.
Scott: Yeah, and also burning wheel.
Rym: Yes if you are if you if you're curious what this burning wheel business that we've been going on and on and on and on about for like the last two years This is the place.
Scott: come to Connecticut and you know even if we're not there somehow something goes wrong.
Scott: the people who run the gaming room at Connecticut are like The best there.
Scott: there are kind of people Connecticut is like that.
Scott: They like age of steam.
Scott: we don't.
Scott: Connecticut is like an but they taught us to play age of steam away.
Rym: Actually, I like age of steam, but I don't like playing it.
Scott: Hey, that means I don't like it, but I like the concept.
Rym: cuz think about it.
Rym: I've always said man I hate games with ketchup mechanisms.
Rym: I want it to be hardcore like an initial.
Scott: That's the opposite of a ketchup.
Rym: Yes, like you know initial D. I always turn off the boost, but then I played age of steam Which is possibly there's a turning off the boost and turning on me be turning on the you know engine slowly dies.
Rym: Mechanism not the engine slowly dies.
Rym: It's the the game just starts raping you the console itself just drats you down great All right now.
Rym: I don't we're turning this into the con schedule like we've talked about a lot But you know we're on summer sabbatical, so we're not doing as many shows as usual.
Rym: So I think we should talk about what we're doing the weekend after Connecticut so the week Directly after Connecticut.
Rym: oh god.
Scott: I'm only gonna be working Monday Tuesday Wednesday because on Thursday We're driving down to be more for the annual.
Scott: Oh taken man Oh - can.
Rym: it's because you know the the story of our con going was pretty much.
Scott: I've been - Oh taken since - oh -
Rym: in 2002 Scott And I went
Scott: this isn't gonna be the sixth or seventh Oh taken
Rym: Ohio con - which was and we'd
Scott: never been to an end of the seventh oh - out of kind of event and
Rym: we were like And everyone told us all these stories like oh my god this anime convention is going to be the best thing ever.
Rym: We got there and it was so lame that I thought the anime con circuit was crap and everyone was lying and I was so jaded.
Rym: and Then we were like all right if we're gonna go to one.
Rym: Let's go to one more Let's try the big ones.
Rym: we went to Otakon and good god.
Rym: Yeah, it's always been this kind of rite of passage among people who we met who were anime fans Who had never been to an anime con to get them to Otakon Take them into the dealer's room and watch their reaction to how large it is.
Scott: The thing is that reaction is much diminished now that the internet is much better.
Scott: Back in those days and you couldn't get anime anything, you know - and now and you saw that dealers room It was just like pee your pants.
Scott: Nowadays that dealers room doesn't have a lot of stuff.
Scott: You can't get more easily.
Scott: So it's not so exciting but just seeing the size of one of those the dealers room and then someone Tells you the artists alley is half that size.
Scott: Oh and the video game room is also half that size.
Scott: Oh, and there's like 20 other rooms that are all this size.
Rym: In any tradition of every Otakon since the first we were once again not paying for Otakon.
Rym: now We said before we're doing some panels But we're actually now doing due to a very long series of circumstances five panels Five panels.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: We were originally I did seven at ConnectiCon So I'm doing almost as many Otakon panels as I was doing.
Rym: luckily one of these panels We don't have to do crap for because one of them is Katsu's Katsunori Matsushita's Kendo way of the sword All right, so that doesn't actually count.
Scott: all that has.
Scott: I mean it does for awesomeness.
Rym: That one is film it but you can handle and I'm gonna be on stage to Fulfill my obligation to the RIT Kendo.
Scott: Are you gonna do that?
Rym: It's undefeated vice president.
Rym: I have to be defeated.
Rym: I will see it better and but in addition I'm probably gonna be up there and like Stan, you know with the armor on so we can demonstrate stuff and Katsu does a pretty damn good kendo panel.
Scott: Yep, but also on Friday, I don't know who could do a better one.
Scott: I mean, maybe if there was like maybe Katsu's dad maybe but Maybe.
Rym: so, uh, we're doing three panels on Friday at Otakon.
Scott: Oh, I guess that's good because then you know like it cuz Friday Usually it's like dealers rooms not open and you know artists Allie's not fully set up yet and there's not a lot of action.
Scott: So I'm doing panels.
Scott: Friday is a good day to do them at Otakon.
Rym: So Friday noon anime you should see which as you know that that one's like so easy and done and awesome Like.
Rym: it's got a really good reception.
Scott: If you already know about a lot of anime and you listen to our show you probably don't need to go to that panel Unless you just want to see us.
Scott: Yes the panels for people who think they're like, you know, the Naruto.
Scott: It's like they like.
Scott: they like Naruto and maybe they like Dragon Ball, but they don't really know anime.
Rym: Yeah, I mean think about it nowadays.
Rym: So you get into anime you like, you know, I know what's on TV.
Rym: Yeah I watched dumb stuff when I was a kid and until someone told me the RT anime Club was like hey Watch this show called cowboy.
Scott: be like kids these days don't even know what eskaplona is.
Rym: and I was like cowboy Bebop, that sounds stupid.
Rym: And then someone else was like, yes, you know, it's the episode where spike fights vicious.
Rym: I'm like, oh so it's some stupid fighting show with stupid names.
Rym: But then at three we were running comics for the manga reader, oh, I didn't prepare anything for that panel.
Scott: Is that gonna be an off-the-cuff panel?
Rym: I think we're gonna have some slides for that when I'm working on it.
Rym: all right, but we should just Bring a copy of each one of those comics.
Rym: We should just pick out like ten comics that manga readers should read and then yes again If you're if you listen to our show, you probably don't need to go to that one.
Rym: We're gonna tell people to read, you know Dark Knight Returns watch them in V for Vendetta that sort of thing Fables.
Rym: Yeah, oh, you know because you know a lot of manga readers.
Rym: They seem to issue anything American comic assuming that They issue it so much.
Scott: it's that they just really don't know it's.
Scott: they go to borders.
Scott: They look at the manga shelf Which is nice and neat and easy to look at right and then there might be.
Scott: there is there is a u.s.
Scott: Graphic novel shelf or at least a non manga graphic novel shelf, but it's a big mess and it's confusing and it's mostly superheroes Which aren't very enticing and they don't take the time to look through it and really get to know it or anything.
Scott: They don't know anything about it and it's more expensive than the manga in an unfamiliar Uneconomical format that doesn't fit on the shelf.
Scott: So they're not really enticed by that and they don't go to a comic book store They only go to borders.
Scott: So they don't.
Scott: they don't know but they like manga.
Scott: They like comics.
Scott: They read all kinds of web comics.
Scott: It's just they don't know to read the Watchmen.
Scott: They don't know to read Dark Knight Returns.
Scott: I mean, they don't know to read the runaway.
Rym: I wouldn't have known to read the Dark Knight Returns.
Scott: I don't know the people's exist They don't.
Scott: they might not even know the Scott Pilgrim exists if it wasn't, you know on the shelf next to the manga by accident.
Rym: So, uh, and then last and possibly least on Saturday morning now The deal was basically we were gonna do one panel and then they were like, oh, all right We need can you guys do two panels, please?
Rym: We're like, okay, and then they're like, uh, yeah one thing led to another.
Rym: Can you guys do an advanced wars panel?
Rym: Cuz that's one of the things.
Rym: Basically, that was a panel that I put in to do it like an edacon and test.
Rym: Do you have something we could build up?
Rym: and then silly good generic easy fun panel?
Rym: But we decided not to do it anywhere.
Rym: then Otakon is like, yeah, we're desperate for more panelists.
Rym: Can you do that panel?
Scott: and I would rather do a different panel.
Rym: So I was like, uh Listen, that's not our strongest offering.
Rym: We'd rather do this other one called comics for the manga reader.
Rym: Wait, yes, so he's like, uh, could you do both?
Rym: and I was like, uh, Yeah Do you need any more?
Rym: He's like, yes.
Rym: Okay We can do the kendo panel that we did last year.
Rym: fine.
Scott: What about the know your creators panel?
Rym: Well, we're doing that.
Rym: Friday night Great Scott did most of the groundwork for this panel, but I think it's gonna be fantastic.
Rym: We're gonna test it.
Scott: Of course This is the panel that we worked hard on.
Scott: the know your creators panel because people they watch the animes and read the mangas.
Scott: But I don't pay attention to who is the real people making this stuff, you know.
Scott: And it wasn't until I watch listen to the Admiral d'Or that I paid attention.
Scott: So it's basically like hey pay attention to who the director is asshole.
Scott: It's important.
Scott: and here's why.
Scott: Here's who.
Scott: it is just in case because you didn't check.
Rym: and just so you're all aware there is on Friday also right before one of our panels a Podcasting for dummies panel and I'm really curious who's running it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: didn't the Taku generation people do something like that last year.
Scott: I think they did.
Scott: The you know podcasting.
Scott: too many people on the the diet diet days Too many people on the days at podcasting panels at the same time.
Scott: Remember that?
Rym: Yeah, that was that wasn't?
Rym: that was okay?
Scott: Yeah, I'm not doing.
Scott: I'm not doing that again.
Scott: for now on there'll be no more than three people on any days that I'm on A panel for yes.
Rym: Well, I could see a match game.
Rym: But then again, they're all.
Scott: guess they're not.
Scott: that's not a panel It's a game.
Rym: and of course You you shouldn't need any provocation further to go to Otakon because Otakon is far and away the best anime con in America.
Rym: There's just no argument really.
Scott: No, there's the biggest is nothing.
Rym: It's the biggest that matters.
Rym: It's the best.
Rym: that's fun.
Rym: and they've got jam project among other acts.
Scott: How could you if you're with if you're able to go to Otakon, how could you not go?
Scott: I mean even if you just like anime or manga a little bit Why would you not go hell that the concert alone is probably worth the cost of admission.
Rym: How the artist alley is probably worth the cost of admission.
Scott: best artists alley Outside of comic-et and perhaps even better than that one.
Scott: it though not as big.
Scott: Yep I think there's any other artists I've ever seen.
Scott: I mean think about this right the Baltimore comic convention.
Scott: It's an entire comic convention.
Scott: It fits in one room at the Baltimore Convention Center one, you know convention room in the convention center.
Scott: Overflow with that convention on uses the entire Convention Center.
Scott: so the artists arena sometimes and a club down the street The artists alley of Otakon is as big as the Baltimore comic convention.
Scott: Take that as you will.
Rym: And of course at the penny arcade expo, we're doing beyond dungeons dragons and at the New York Anime Festival We're doing four panels.
Rym: No And we've already got our tentative list of events for Katsucon.
Scott: February.
Rym: no, of course We'll be doing the usual awesome at Katsucon not being sick and we've already got some tentative rumblings.
Rym: at the New York Comic Con We're probably going to be running events again.
Scott: It's still July.
Scott: Don't talk to me about February.
Scott: We didn't run up events at New York comic.
Rym: We were pressed.
Scott: We just went in his press and we did nothing.
Rym: this time There's a good chance.
Rym: We're gonna be running manga for the comics reader.
Rym: I don't want to run more than that.
Rym: Actually, I'd rather be pressed at that time.
Scott: Yeah, it's the kind of calm I don't want to hang around for a long time because it's not much going on.
Scott: And of course, we're going to have at Otakon the gigantic Otakon dealers room is bigger than the New York comic convention floor space.
Rym: Think about that.
Scott: Think about that.
Rym: Okay, and of course we've got tables f5 f6 f7 f8 f9 f10 f11 j7 j8 and j9 in the artists alley.
Scott: All right, basically at Otakon when we're not doing something or we're not browsing around ourselves.
Scott: I think you know over 50% of the time.
Scott: the convention is open.
Scott: We'll be in the artists alley at our Artists alley conglomerate.
Rym: our table.
Rym: the one we will be sitting at with our stuff will be either f5 or f6.
Rym: I haven't decided yet.
Scott: It doesn't really matter.
Rym: Nah, it doesn't matter.
Rym: It's not like you'll find f5 and be like where the hell are they?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You will find us easily.
Scott: You can just go to the front artists alley table and say where's GeekNights and they'll say this table right there.
Rym: Man, this is gonna be a nutty couple of weeks.
Scott: I've already lost my nuts.
Rym: So Right, so in other news, I just want to point out that Bakano got licensed and I think that's great because I think that's gonna be a great show.
Scott: I only watched Yeah, why didn't someone license that sooner?
Scott: They said that there was like stupid things that were licensed before.
Scott: that It makes no sense.
Scott: You don't want to know why I'll bet it's because the people I think don't know what the fuck they're doing.
Rym: I'll bet they do know but the Japanese company had one of those.
Rym: you can't license that.
Rym: yeah License it but you gotta wait.
Scott: Someone's got a muscle around these Japanese companies, you know, if you don't muscle them around You know, it's basically you have no choice.
Scott: if you do as they want you to do you're gonna go out of business because you're gonna be doing bad business.
Scott: if you You know muscle them around you have two options Succeed in business or not do business at all.
Scott: So you're not gonna muscle them around which is your only chance of succeeding.
Scott: don't do anything I think.
Scott: why can I resign yourself to failure?
Rym: I think the time of muscling however is nigh because as you all know the anime industry in America is going down the pooper Without that whoop at the end, it's just So, uh as you know Properties and money dry up in the US and licensers go out of business or downsize and things go on.
Rym: The Japanese companies are gonna notice that the market in America is shrinking and that I mean look at having a Bandai visual.
Rym: Eventually, they're gonna realize wait a minute.
Rym: We're not selling anime over there anymore in that gigantic untapped market.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: and then when it's your fault?
Rym: so if there's only one licenser left in America or maybe two and that one licenser is the only chance you have of getting your new show released in the US other than doing it yourself and failing and they Want to negotiate?
Scott: You might have to negotiate.
Scott: Here's the problem the reason They'll pull a super gurry.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much as they have.
Scott: they had this very rigid way of thinking where you know Do having lower license prices or having reasonable?
Scott: You know Not.
Scott: stupid terms on the licenses and things like.
Scott: that is not even something they consider all they only considered things.
Scott: Outside of that they have.
Scott: their mind is locked in that particular area and like changing.
Scott: that Seems to be something that is not it.
Scott: It's like the act as if that's a. you know The way when you're doing.
Scott: it's like trying to invent something right if I'm trying to and make a machine.
Scott: I Just take the third law of thermodynamics.
Scott: In fact, all the laws of thermodynamics as a given, right?
Scott: I don't assume.
Scott: I don't try to think huh?
Scott: This would only work if I could break, you know that law of thermodynamics.
Scott: Let's go for it.
Scott: I think well, this is only I need to break the law of thermodynamics.
Scott: Can't do that.
Scott: I got to think of some other solution to them.
Scott: Changing the way they do licensing is like a scientist or an inventor breaking law of thermodynamics.
Scott: They go, huh?
Scott: We could change the licensing.
Scott: Oh, no, that's not possible.
Scott: We had to think somewhere else.
Rym: See I think part of the larger problem and I think anime world order mentioned this too But the fact that you look at look at OdaKan.
Rym: All right The anime industry is tanking and yet OdaKan is gonna have twenty five thousand plus anime fans Spending gobs of money for an entire weekend mostly on merchandise But at the same time that but also on cheap DVDs cheap ones.
Rym: But here's the thing.
Rym: They don't look at that.
Rym: What they see is.
Rym: All right Buffy the Vampire Slayer doesn't get twenty five thousand fans.
Rym: Seinfeld doesn't get twenty five thousand fans in a building talking about Seinfeld There.
Rym: we can make money off of this.
Rym: Okay, these people are yes, but they don't think.
Rym: how do I make money off of it?
Rym: They think I'm going to make money off of it?
Scott: Well, they don't.
Scott: they do think how but their idea of how is wrong because they don't realize how.
Scott: these are poor high school kids No money, and they don't realize that you know, people don't want DVDs anymore.
Scott: People don't want drms They don't you know, they don't get the details right because yeah, they don't know there's.
Rym: I've said this before but I don't think Piracy has anything to do.
Rym: all piracy did I think was speed up the demise of the end of the anime industry in the u.s by by maybe a year Maybe two because if all the if all the piracy disappeared, it's not like DVD sales would pick up.
Rym: Netflix might pick up but that's not enough money to run an industry.
Scott: I am confident that fan subs do not damage the anime industry.
Scott: if someone is watching a fan sub Right.
Scott: Let's say someone's watching a fan sub of baka.
Scott: No right now, right.
Scott: if that fan sub wasn't there They wouldn't go out and buy the DVD.
Scott: They just wouldn't watch.
Scott: Someone who's gonna buy the DVD is gonna buy the DVD with or without the fan sub.
Scott: People watching the fan subs are people who would not watch anime if fan subs did not exist.
Scott: They just wouldn't watch at all.
Scott: So it's it's not the work.
Rym: It's like they're the people who would watch it on TV.
Rym: I mean, right I think the problem is that anime was treated as a special thing for a long time because it it was it was this Real treated special.
Rym: Well, that's the problem.
Rym: It was this really niche market.
Rym: So they used a business model that worked really well.
Rym: in that tiny niche market with that specific kind of fan base It gets segregated from other television.
Scott: It's like they have they have an anime block.
Scott: It's like oh, we'll put all the anime here Just put the anime in with the other TV shows.
Rym: But see that's the thing.
Rym: the anime industry in the US is still treating anime like it's this special market When it's actually gotten much more broad mainstream appeal.
Rym: But mainstream appeal doesn't mean anything because the mainstream is not going to go through the ropes of getting The content.
Rym: that if it's not just in the mainstream once anime is mainstream.
Rym: It's got to be on mainstream TV.
Rym: Mm-hmm, if it isn't mainstream people they're gonna say oh, it's that weird thing.
Rym: I have to do the special blah blah blah.
Rym: I gotta buy a DVD box set to watch.
Scott: anime has to be on TV when kids get home from school And it has to be on TV.
Scott: You know along with all the other shows that people are watching at the same time.
Scott: People are home at like 9 o'clock So not at 1 in the morning not when everyone's at you know work.
Scott: It has to be on when people get home and after dinner, so you got any anime news.
Scott: Okay, I got some comics news here.
Scott: I cuz.
Scott: oh by the way that lice that announcement of Baccano licensing was I believe is from the San Diego comic adventures last week Which we'll go to one day one day.
Scott: Yeah the problem Promised me to become Hollywood convention and not so much comic convention.
Rym: Yes I mean look it'd be like if we wanted to go to e3.
Rym: there'd be no point.
Rym: We'll just go to PAX right.
Scott: so two important comics news is from the San Diego comic convention here.
Scott: The first one is that Viz.
Scott: This is not a surprise.
Scott: We saw this coming a mile away.
Scott: But you know the last volume of monster by an okurasawa comes out in December.
Rym: It'll be done, and then maybe I didn't like the anime so much, but the manga looked a lot better.
Scott: Yeah, I might try buying the rest of the manga now.
Scott: that what?
Rym: now that I know it's gonna be finished in December But yeah, I didn't want to read further and then have it suddenly dry up.
Scott: Yep now that that's done They announced and I think January February of course 20th century boys volume one will be out But also Pluto will be out from biz.
Scott: That's that's it Gotta be buying that guaranteed by you.
Scott: don't buy that you're stupid.
Scott: You don't buy both of those you stupid and the other news.
Scott: There's gonna be some more Batman comics.
Scott: Oh Hey, that's that's supposed to be news right this?
Scott: Batman comics every month.
Scott: Why is that news?
Rym: oh?
Rym: so up either they're really bad Batman comics, and you're about to make fun of them or They've got someone awesome to write and or draw.
Scott: ah Well these Batman comics that are going to be coming out.
Scott: I'm not gonna give you any details you can look it up But there are going to be in the future Batman comics available for buying and reading that are written by Someone with the first name Neil.
Scott: ha ha Yeah, cuz he's written so many comics.
Scott: It's Neil Armstrong.
Scott: Oh cuz he's alive.
Rym: Neil Adams.
Rym: He did Batman comics already, so he's not doing these Batman, and he draws them.
Scott: He doesn't write though I don't think he writes them, but he's mostly draws them.
Rym: I said write or draw.
Rym: I can't think of any more Neil's I know.
Scott: oh, okay.
Scott: I guess I forgot.
Scott: Let's just go on.
Rym: So anyway things of the day now.
Rym: We've talked in the past about AMVs, and we've got a couple of shows about AMVs.
Rym: We interviewed Jeff to Tarik a long time ago talked about AMVs But I got something a little bit different for you right now.
Rym: You see AMVs are old-school pass a. I'm done with them.
Rym: for now on it's nothing.
Scott: But jam V's for me and jam V's those Jewish music videos.
Rym: no no no no no.
Scott: Japanese music videos not even close, New Jersey music video.
Rym: these are in fact Juggernaut music video bitch.
Rym: It's a problem.
Scott: Yeah, Hollywood cold Dear dub stand the fuck up.
Rym: I Don't know what it is about juggernaut, but I find this hilarious.
Scott: Why is this still funny?
Rym: Maybe it's just us.
Scott: Maybe we're just stupid Maybe it is just us, but this is still awesome and still funny even though it's been played out.
Scott: But it's like my conscious brain says.
Scott: why this?
Scott: why is this funny?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: meanwhile, then my gut goes I actually I'll admit.
Rym: I kind of like this song because it's got everything that I like about this hip-hop kind of beat.
Rym: Except it's not about raping my hoes.
Rym: It's about being the juggernaut and killing people and the baddest motherfucker on the world.
Rym: So Yeah, I don't think any more needs to be said.
Scott: Alright, so back in the day.
Scott: You know like I'm talking Nasr.
Scott: I tell you used to read this Japanese newspaper called The my Nietzsche's in Boone.
Scott: right yep, and my Nietzsche is basically a daily Japanese newspaper But you were all.
Scott: for many many years.
Scott: You've been able to read it online in English for free which is pretty cool because I could read.
Scott: you know interesting Japanese Newses, and I'd find out about like who is winning the sumo wrestling.
Scott: I'd find out about you know.
Rym: So who's winning the sumo wrestling?
Rym: But I have entered you at all.
Rym: Who did you?
Rym: did you look at a picture of the guy?
Scott: there's a period of my life for about four months where I?
Scott: Paid attention to it a little bit.
Rym: Tanaka lost the championship.
Scott: Yeah, I think the guy's name was like Takanohana or something they were.
Scott: yeah, it's all Mongolians these days actually or the sumo masters The Yokozuna is what not any one thing.
Rym: I do like sumo.
Scott: I like watching sumo Yeah, because I watched it on the plane once I was on a jet-blue flight And it was on ESPN too, and I watched like a whole bunch of sumo action.
Scott: So I sort of got into it for a little bit.
Scott: But I was also.
Scott: you could find out about like crazy things that happen in Japan.
Scott: you know Famous people and occasionally stories about well You know what nerds were doing and the best part about it actually that I liked the most was they'd have like these Photo essays of things that were going on like festivals and stuff, and you know somehow Even you know it's Japan.
Scott: so they would always be like some Gundam or some Godzilla or something in there.
Scott: So I remember this Christmas one.
Scott: It was a Christmas photo essay, and there was a Godzilla made of lights, and I was like ah Japan.
Scott: anyway There was one column on there called a yy Wai wai and the yy column always had weird shit in it like Totally like we're talking scandalous and really sexual kind of Violent weird fucked up charge things you know like so-and-so You know prostitutes and something else crazy or so and so in a porno film and all sorts of really fucked up weird shit and I Accepted it because It's Japan is fucked up shit in Japan.
Scott: It makes sense all right, and that was always sort of the fucked up shit column.
Scott: And you know my Nietzsche isn't really the New York Times of Japan.
Scott: It's more like.
Scott: it's more like the daily news of Japan, so it's not really you know a highly respectable newspaper.
Scott: But anyway my thing of the day if you go to my Nietzsche dot co dot JP I think you might have to go to slash English.
Scott: I'll link you there.
Scott: It doesn't matter They got this big announcement on the front page like we're very sorry our yy column was full of shit And it was terrible journalism.
Scott: It is mostly lies and made-up crap.
Scott: We're going straight now.
Scott: We're gonna give you higher quality more respectable news, and I'm like on the one hand That's pretty like you know admirable.
Scott: I guess taking responsibility Etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: on the other hand oh, I like that crazy shit, and I want the crazy shit back.
Scott: I don't care if it's lies just say it's lies.
Rym: make that's like reading the National Enquirer or the weekly world news right.
Scott: But the thing that makes it better the National Enquirer the weekly world news is this If I look at the National Enquirer weekly world news right there is no doubt in my mind that it's all complete bullshit And it's just not entertaining whatever.
Scott: The yy was not that crazy.
Scott: It wasn't like bat boy right.
Scott: It was just sort of like you know famous person does something a little crazy or Some person to other you know is involved in some crazy slightly unbelievable scandal, and it's like I Could believe it because it's Japan.
Scott: and it sort of gave me this impression of Japan of yeah It enforced my idea that Japan had this crazy stuff going on And I'm sort of sad to see that that crazy stuff was less than I thought I Lied.
Scott: you know I like thinking of Japan as land of the crazy moon language.
Rym: Such I guess you've grown as a human sad.
Rym: learn some things Incredulous.
Scott: I've grown along with the my Nietzsche newspaper.
Scott: Alright, so since we're preparing for conventions.
Scott: We don't have a lot of free time here.
Scott: We're gonna do something kind of short.
Scott: We're just gonna talk about this graphic novel.
Scott: the graphic novel is written by Robert Venditti and the art is by.
Scott: what does it say Brett?
Scott: well delay well delay?
Scott: Yeah, and it's published by top shelf.
Scott: And if you don't know top shelf you don't know comics cuz.
Scott: top shelf prints all Awesomeness.
Scott: they print the alley they print the Essex County They print all the James Robinson stuff like box-office boys and whatnot?
Scott: Basically they only print gold and they don't print any poop and one of the gold things that they print is The surrogates which is the comic we're talking about today.
Rym: Yep, now the one thing I want to point out is that the surrogates you buy the trade And it's just one story start to finish it begins it ends.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There's no reason to buy anything else.
Scott: It's one story beginning to end.
Scott: graphic novel.
Scott: you're done right.
Rym: Yeah, there's a sequel coming, but it's not out yet.
Rym: We'll be out for a while.
Scott: They're also making a movie based on this comic.
Scott: Supposedly Bruce Willis will be involved and he fits one of the characters.
Scott: so it makes sense Bruce Willis it better be.
Scott: Yeah, that totally makes sense for this comic.
Scott: if you read it.
Scott: You'll see why.
Scott: yes Bruce Willis is a famous person.
Rym: I know You'll read this.
Rym: and Fifth Element Yes, yes, what else?
Rym: what else?
Scott: Armageddon?
Scott: when they're drilling the hole in the rock die hard.
Scott: Oh, yeah that one too.
Rym: Yeah Okay, all right, but if you read this It'll read like it was not actually a comic but a vehicle to provide Bruce Willis with another movie to be in.
Scott: It does seem like that in many ways, but even though it might seem like that It's still an awesome comic.
Scott: So why are you not reading it?
Rym: So the story here?
Rym: the deal is that it's the year 2050 something, you know far suit future.
Rym: Actually, it's not that far away and we'll probably alive.
Scott: Probably Scott will probably be a lot more comfortable though.
Scott: I hope so with much better than the iPhone.
Rym: I'm thinking more about having a mansion Impossible.
Rym: I yeah that mansion over Newberg's not that expensive.
Scott: I think I'm thinking more like private jet private jet.
Rym: We could live on the jet the jets that never lie.
Scott: 2050. if I save now I can afford a private jet.
Scott: I can fight inflation off Brain in a box.
Rym: But anyway, so Technology's progressed to the point that pretty much everyone in the world at least in the civilized world Uses something called a surrogate to go about their daily life.
Scott: Yeah, anyone who has money if you ever read ghosts in the shell, especially the second one, right?
Scott: you'll note that the major uses sort of like these dummy bodies or sort of Decots, you know like remote decoy bodies, basically She goes to bed right and she remotely controls this robot that is in the shape of a human body So that there's a robot going around the world talking to people doing business hanging out making phone calls, whatever and It's not actually a person in the robot.
Rym: It's completely empty except for you know mechanical stuff, but at the same time It's a little weird there because her ghost actually, you know But she she's it's a.
Scott: it's like if I went to bed and this robot that looked like me went to work and I was Remotely controlling that robot from my house in bed Sleeping.
Scott: so my biological body doesn't really have to do anything anymore and I can conduct business in the real world with a humanoid Robot that looks exactly like me and can function perhaps even better than I can because if it dies I'm completely safe so I can do dangerous things.
Scott: I can jump high can run fast because I'm a robot.
Rym: now see it's not like Ghost in the shell because the big difference is that this like literally you put a thing over your head and it's like VR use control the thing and feel stuff but You can just knock the thing off your head.
Rym: your you know your ghost or your soul or whatever doesn't travel anywhere.
Rym: There's no like.
Rym: no one's brain or body is Like.
Rym: you're not actually in this thing if it gets blown up.
Rym: You don't get affected at all.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Oh shit my robot.
Scott: Yeah It's no different than if I put a robo sapien on the floor and can do the remote control.
Scott: only It's a much more advanced than a robo sapien.
Scott: It can do everything that you can do.
Scott: only it's you know, you have just not holding our mode control in your hands.
Rym: So nominally the story is I don't I mean, I don't want to talk too much.
Scott: I can't spoil it.
Scott: It's just one book.
Rym: Yes, and I really don't want to spoil where it goes but the beginning of the plot is that basically two people who are obviously both in surrogate bodies are Getting it on in an alley.
Scott: Oh man getting it on with the robots.
Rym: Yeah, so someone comes and kills them both Obviously someone who is anti surrogate body or just crazy.
Rym: You don't really know.
Rym: Yeah, but basically and From there this comic follows the story of the police investigating this crime.
Rym: but it also if what it does more so is it kind of explores the world and the ramifications of if this sort of technology were possible.
Rym: I mean and it and you read this and it's one of those instances where The person who the people who put this comic together the person who wrote it obviously Took a page from every comic it ever read.
Rym: that was good.
Rym: It draws heavily from the techniques used in Watchmen.
Rym: it draws heavily from things like Dark Knight Returns.
Scott: Yeah, yep.
Scott: Yep, you can just you read this and you go, huh?
Scott: I see a little sign of everything that is good about comics and it's all sort of comes together right here.
Rym: I mean it even does the thing where like you read and read and read and then like it stops and Then there's a few pages of an article from a newspaper from within the world and it's just a whole article.
Rym: You can just read it.
Rym: Yeah, and the advertisements in the comic are advertisements From the world.
Rym: Yep, and I actually really like those advertisements because I remember thinking oh, yeah, I could use one of these.
Scott: Yeah Wait, that's not a real ad shit.
Scott: Damn it.
Scott: I want a robot body.
Rym: Oh, I don't really want to get into the plot beyond that but in terms of the world I mean that this is actually well thought out in terms of how it considers these issues.
Rym: You think about it?
Rym: If all the wealthy people and even the middle-class people in the world, even some of the poorer people are using robot bodies Gender and race suddenly don't mean anything anymore.
Scott: Yeah, black man.
Scott: He is a white body white guy.
Scott: He's a black body guy could use a girl body.
Rym: I think they even talked about a political campaign where a person who was running for office who happened to be white Used a black surrogate to run.
Rym: now This wasn't like he like hid and like no one knew that it was actually a white man like The.
Scott: deep down they all wants to be what right anyway Ever.
Scott: I only seen it once and I was on a bus bus watching on the coach bus TV.
Rym: The last movie I watched on a coach bus was that was the last movie.
Scott: I watched in the coach bus.
Rym: I had some sports movie anyway, so and it talks about the political ramifications that he did it openly because his idea was if I'm going to be representing this poor urban Area and this poor urban area happens to be filled largely with minorities.
Rym: I should represent them both physically and electorally Mm-hmm, and there's.
Rym: it goes into all these interesting things about how like CEOs tend to be male Even though actually a lot of CEOs are female But they use male bodies because of like the social mores.
Rym: and it talks about how some stereotypes become more enhanced partly because of the fact that they're now completely irrelevant and arbitrary and I Think it does a really good job of addressing the kind of realistic expectations and ramifications of this technology.
Scott: Yeah, and also, you know, it does the thing that every good book and and you know story does is, you know By showing you a world that is not your own.
Scott: They hold up a mirror to the world that is your own.
Scott: like the part that always gets me is the Cop's wife who won't cut you won't.
Scott: his guy is married to this woman.
Scott: They're married.
Rym: yes, you see the cop now.
Rym: the cop is good-looking and young and awesome and His wife is a sex Baba.
Rym: Yep, but they're just surrogate bodies.
Scott: They share a house.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they share a house.
Scott: They live in the same house But the wife has locked her biological body in her room and won't come out.
Scott: because you know I guess I don't know.
Scott: It's hard to tell if she's actually ugly.
Scott: She's probably alright looking in there, but she doesn't look as good as the robot body.
Rym: She doesn't always perfect look as good as she did when she was young.
Scott: now she's middle-aged So she doesn't want anyone to see her not even her own husband Because she only wants you to see the robot body which is perfect in all ways.
Rym: It's just serious image problems, but it's the same that I mean reading this and there's action scenes.
Rym: and How can murders happen if there's no people?
Rym: murders become property crime crimes and as a result people stop murdering anymore Police officers because you can use a surrogate body.
Rym: anyone can be a cop.
Rym: There's no physical requirement So there's only mental requirements.
Rym: crime pretty much disappears because you can just use Effectively deadly force against criminals and even if you do it's the same as stopping someone's car by disabling the engine It.
Rym: it paints a really interesting picture of a future that is not that far out of the realm.
Scott: No, I mean, you know ghost in the shell types technology is a little bit crazy.
Scott: Remote control robots with an advanced user interface Wirelessly is not that crazy.
Scott: That's something that could vary.
Scott: we could do that right now.
Scott: It wouldn't be that good, but we could get.
Scott: we could get that.
Scott: That's definitely reasonable.
Scott: I Don't know if we could get it to the point where everyone could afford it and you'd have enough energy to power all those guys Walking around instead of people.
Rym: but I mean eventually that happens.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah eventually But you know at the same time there's large crazy religious movements of people who think these things are Abominations and they shoot technology and they try to live a primitive life and all the ramifications of that.
Scott: Mm-hmm Now the art in this book.
Scott: I like it actually quite a bit.
Scott: It's mean It's not like the greatest art in the universe, but it's like it's.
Scott: it's sort of like this Swirly painted kind of look.
Scott: it's not you know, things aren't like super clear, but it's done.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: like a lot of times when people do that kind of work.
Scott: You can't really you know, tell one thing apart from the other, you know It's our time to tell.
Scott: you know as the character that character.
Scott: but in this you can tell perfectly who's who and what's what at?
Scott: Times.
Scott: you can even tell like, you know, the someone's robot body, you know Even if they made a robot body that's matches their biological body.
Scott: You can tell them apart.
Scott: So that's you know, it's really cool how it's not like this crystal clear.
Scott: Crystal clear sharply drawn, you know art that everything is perfect.
Scott: But you can still tell what everything is awesomely.
Scott: But at the same time everything is really dark and you get this really sort of heavy Atmosphere that goes with the sort of the painted look Gives you that same level of kind of oppression and claustrophobia that I don't know Blade Runner did.
Rym: really well Yeah, it definitely feels like Closing in and everything's real and gritty and and it and I. the other thing I really like is that you know The main character the protagonist the cop detective who you kind of follow through this whole thing.
Scott: He's like the guy who's outside the the building in Die Hard.
Scott: Yeah The guy from you know, the dad from Merkel.
Rym: But when you see him out of his surrogate body What you do you see a lot of people out of their surrogate bodies because you know the real world.
Rym: Hey, I love the fact that he's paunchy and out of shape and kind of schlubby, but he's still in there.
Rym: It's still him.
Scott: It's still him.
Scott: He's alright cuz.
Scott: he went and got a surrogate that looked kind of like him only, you know Stronger-looking.
Rym: it probably looked the way he did 20 years previous probably But he's a good guy.
Scott: he's a good guy.
Rym: Yeah Honestly, I'd really want to avoid saying more because anything I say beyond this point could possibly ruin this book.
Scott: Yeah, and it's primarily a cop story but also sci-fi but also social commentary.
Rym: It's super well done.
Rym: I highly recommend it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, well, you should buy everything that says top shelf on it.
Scott: Yeah, you have to choose.
Scott: you should probably choose Essex County and then if you've already read that you should choose the surrogates.
Rym: Yes, however, if you're looking for something quicker like a single quick read cuz it's a quick read.
Scott: It's short I mean what it was five mini issues and it's probably going to be an awesome movie someday I think maybe.
Scott: so if you read it now think about how cool you'll be when it is.
Scott: Actually when all your friends find out about it, you can be like.
Scott: I know what that is.
Scott: I read it.
Scott: You could be cool not like the people who are you know only reading Watchmen.
Scott: now that there's a trailer.
Scott: You could be cool like the people who knew about it before.
Rym: All right, and on that note because you're obviously cooler if you know about something before someone else exactly I think we're done.
Scott: We are done.
Rym: Well, we'll see you hopefully at Connecticut.
Scott: See you next year in a few days.
Rym: Don't look for us until Saturday.
Rym: We're gonna be there Friday, but we'll be keeping a low profile going out for drinks that sort of thing.
Rym: Don't don't don't try to find us if you see us just kind of stay away Saturday.
Rym: Come and say hi Saturday We're gonna be all around doing stuff Friday.
Rym: costumes.
Rym: Yep masks.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.