Rym: It's Wednesday, May 21st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Instead of telling you how to get into anime.
Rym: We tell you how to get other people into anime.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So Emily must have not had any work to do today because actually she she decided What she tried to figure out what my name would be in kanji, wouldn't it just be like remove?
Rym: Well, it is.
Rym: it's remove and she you know pick what kanji and all the pronunciation.
Scott: Pick a kanji that sounds like re and then another one that sounds like, you know how Japanese names work.
Rym: So what she chose and I think this is pretty cool.
Rym: So remove can also be pronounced.
Rym: Well, I'll get to that.
Rym: the first kanji means advantage And the second one means rejoice or jubilation Which which is very fitting in German board games.
Rym: So I guess I feel good about that.
Rym: Plus it looks cool.
Rym: The first one's like a sword with things coming out the top Always like the ones that look like little houses.
Scott: Those are the best.
Rym: the second one is one of those million line kanji's with a million like square hedge lines.
Scott: How's the house looking?
Scott: ones are the best.
Rym: it's got a hat and then it's got like little tentacles coming out the bottom.
Scott: Well, technically is it good but it's pronounced.
Rym: obviously remove but the other reading is Toshiyoshi.
Rym: No now Toshiyoshi.
Scott: Well, I don't know what toshi is but Yoshi's a green guy with a big tongue.
Rym: Oh, it's so much cooler than that.
Rym: So toshi yoshi is Actually the name of what?
Rym: Yagu, toshi oshi was the founder of the Oari branch of the yagu shin kage ryu sword style in the early edo period.
Scott: All right.
Rym: He was one of those grandmasters who was around at the same time of another famous Japanese swordsman.
Scott: Yeah Musashi, they're gonna say yeah you juvie.
Rym: So according to legend Musashi Miyamoto was in Nagoya and noticed a man Carrying himself in a way that befitted a great warrior and he asked this man without prompting Aren't you Lord?
Rym: Yagu toshi oshi to which he replied I am aren't you Lord Miyamoto?
Rym: Musashi to which he replied I am and Apparently they'd never met each other and they bonded through the fact that they were so badass.
Scott: And that is the story that I have no citation for whatsoever Sounds like a made-up story, but it reminds me of that part in Fullmetal Alchemist where they They bonded through their muscles.
Rym: That was one of the best scenes in Fullmetal Alchemist.
Scott: That was a good part right there.
Scott: I have to say I think it's in the manga too.
Rym: So I feel like I should start going by toshi yoshi.
Scott: How about not?
Rym: toshi yoshi don't know if you try that shit.
Scott: Everyone's gonna call you Brandon.
Scott: I think that's.
Rym: It's weird how no one calls me Brandon except my like business contacts that are completely separated from my real life.
Rym: Yeah And Tex.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I always found it funny that someone who was called Tex Decided not to call me by my name.
Rym: I think it isn't his name Tex I don't even you know.
Rym: in all these years I never asked him if that was a nickname or if that was a real name.
Rym: I've never seen his ID.
Scott: Maybe that's his strategy.
Scott: is that he's like if I'm the only one who can have a weird name, then I'll be the king.
Rym: All right, lads from now on you're all calling me.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's his rejoicing advantage.
Rym: Well, well there are other.
Rym: I mean Nuri's name is not Nuri, but that does.
Rym: no one calls her anything but nerd.
Rym: I don't think half the people in the crew even know her real name, which I think is hilarious.
Rym: I know sadly even worse Your mom in the forums.
Rym: I'm not gonna reveal her secret identity, but Mrs.
Rym: DeCoster Well the royal your mom Okay, but I knew her from an internet name and as an internet friend at conventions before I knew her real name.
Rym: So for a long time after we became friends, I called her by her internet name in person Her non your mom internet name.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Your mom is a much better internet name.
Rym: I agree That's like the best because it it allowed for the most epic punning of anyone on the internet ever as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: So, uh, that's all I got.
Rym: that's my it's my morning.
Scott: so tonight we're gonna order some pizza action after the show.
Rym: So what kind of pizza we gonna get?
Scott: I suggest some variety of meat.
Rym: I don't know I'm kind of going for a Margarita.
Scott: Yeah, I want sauce and cheese.
Rym: What kind of sauce I like?
Rym: I see.
Rym: the one problem I have is you don't like the pesto pizza.
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: I really like the pesto pizza white pizza a red sauce Actually some sort of cheese the best and some sort of meat and or vegetables.
Rym: the best pizza is not olive.
Rym: We have to do a show on pizza.
Scott: Well, it's a good Thursday easy Thursday You know, we need to get like an expert pizza person to talk to you on the Thursday.
Rym: Oh, yes, we do.
Rym: Maybe we get the guy down the street who runs that pizza.
Rym: She want to get in to come to our house like hey come to our house and be on a radio show about pizza Because he makes that cornmeal crust and it's so good.
Scott: Yeah, I'd rather get.
Scott: I'd rather get like some ancient Italian dude Though who can barely speak English, that'd be much better All right.
Scott: Yeah needs to be crusty.
Rym: that is what Italian people sound like old ones.
Rym: So Scott don't know.
Rym: what do you got in the sky?
Scott: don't know?
Rym: I just don't know.
Scott: I'm not Scott.
Rym: Coon is my is my favorite like of all the honorifics.
Scott: I Because for being silly.
Scott: now, you have to call me Scott son Scott son.
Scott: It's right.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think Coon works.
Scott: No All right, and then your Rym John.
Rym: then Rym.
Rym: John wrote about Rym time.
Rym: No, I prefer a Rym don't know?
Rym: that's tough.
Rym: So what do you have in the stupid anime news captain anime?
Scott: Oh, I forgot.
Scott: What was my anime news?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: Remember that whole.
Scott: This is.
Scott: this is not really an anime news the copyright news but there are all sorts of anime peoples getting up in arms about it because they're stupid right.
Scott: and Finally, there's like a definitive word on it that I can trust so I could bring it up again.
Scott: Remember that orphaned works action.
Rym: I remember that in like 1995 when it was on the internet, right?
Scott: Well, basically there's been recent uproar about the orphaned works action and there was a big uproar and then it went down a bit.
Scott: But now it's rumbling again.
Scott: I'm a rabble rabble rabble rabble You know, everyone was sort of one, you know, there are a lot of.
Scott: there was a lot of FUD going around about it you know and I was sort of like I was taking the stance that hey is a good thing because You know there's a lot of works out there that no one know even knows who owns these things.
Scott: people who own them don't even know they Own them and they're not entering the public domain, you know, it's not really it's not good right and that there's all you know, basically you can't create anything because You don't know if you're infringing on something or not, you know, it's like
Rym: even with video games.
Rym: We have a lot of ideas about taking old Awesome, but forgotten video games and porting them to something or making a pair something fun with them but a lot of times and I actually tried to track down the copyrights of a few old games and I Couldn't find Jack,
Scott: right?
Scott: So You know, I was saying it was good and then all these artists were like saying no, it's bad people take all our shit.
Scott: Well the Larry Lessig if you don't know Larry Lessig is I don't know.
Scott: I've mentioned him a lot of times on the show Mostly on Monday mostly on Monday and Thursday.
Scott: Lawrence Lessig is like an ultra famous Super lawyer and he was until recently like a copyright guy and that was his focus like the Creative Commons stuff.
Scott: That's all because of him pretty much.
Scott: I mean there were other people too, but that that's his business right there and there's a Ted video.
Scott: You can see him talk and basically you'll understand his whole deal from that.
Scott: But He recently, you know sort of quit the copyright business of lawyering because he realized or he sort of came to the conclusion That he couldn't fix the copyright business if he couldn't fix the corruption in government.
Scott: So now he's working on fixing corruption instead.
Rym: I'm curious what will come out of that man.
Scott: I'm very curious what will come out of it.
Scott: He's a very smart man, but that's a very impossible problem.
Scott: So what will be?
Scott: Regardless of that he takes like one month a year off I think the month of May.
Scott: so he wasn't around this month But despite that there was.
Scott: in the New York Times There was an article by Lawrence Lessig a very short one, you know It's only like a little bit and where he talks about the recent orphaned works bill stuff Right, and he agrees with me in that.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: We got to get these orphaned works.
Scott: So people can fucking use them.
Scott: Good God.
Scott: but He actually disagrees with the specific bill that's going on and after reading it I it's hard not to completely agree with them.
Scott: pretty much What he points out is the way the bill works.
Scott: now though as written is let's say Rym made a song and like 1983 when he's one year old.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Okay, the song is by default copyrighted to you, right and that's sort of been the way.
Scott: that's the way it's been for a long Time.
Scott: so people are used to this automatic copyright business, right now Let's say I wanted to use that song.
Scott: all that is required of me to avoid getting sued is I have to do due diligence in order to make sure that no one Owns that.
Scott: no one is, you know, maintaining this copyright and then I can use it.
Scott: So basically what happens is, you know with that situation, you know, I'm sure they haven't like, you know explicitly define the due diligence yet.
Scott: But someone goes like a library, you know or and you know pay someone or you know Does the due diligence they all?
Scott: I didn't find anything and then they start using it, right?
Scott: And then later on someone comes along as I say you did due diligence, but you still didn't find me here.
Rym: I am what the fuck well then that I would argue that that simply wasn't due diligence.
Scott: Well, I know but you know.
Scott: The question is is you know, is there a better way than this due diligence thing?
Scott: because and also, you know They haven't strictly defined what the due diligence is And he has a better solution anyway.
Scott: So it doesn't really matter if you know what if the depth how good the definition due diligence is.
Scott: His better solution is you get your copyright for an amount of time, right?
Scott: And then if you want to keep it longer, all you have to do is file a form and pay $1.
Rym: Actually that has been the the good idea that's been passed around for the last like 20 years in regards to copyright.
Scott: that way I know but it's like that way right.
Scott: if something is orphaned It's basically you just look up.
Scott: did anyone pay the dollar?
Scott: no, okay that the deal is really easy.
Scott: Did anyone pay their dollar?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Is it this old?
Scott: Did anyone pay a dollar?
Scott: very easy to figure out?
Rym: There's some.
Rym: I mean, how long is the period?
Rym: because what if I?
Scott: well he's he said 14 years, but whatever All right.
Rym: So 14 years, let's say I take a thousand pictures Alright, and I want to keep the copyright on all the things.
Rym: I'm using them for stuff.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I gotta pay $1,000.
Scott: Yep, that's great.
Scott: That is great.
Rym: Yeah It's actually not that bad cuz one dollar.
Rym: really we can even make it because what it does is you should be could make it Just ten cents.
Rym: Basically.
Rym: All you have to do is set up the effort.
Scott: Of course I think the reason a dollar is good.
Scott: is that sure it might add up if you have a lot of works, right?
Scott: But any of the works that aren't actually producing money for you You're not gonna bother to pay the dollar and thus it's better for the public because we're gonna get all these.
Scott: You know things that aren't you know, you know They're not valuable to.
Rym: you get all the kind of second-tier work, right?
Scott: Right the stuff that no one could you know thinks they can make money off of.
Rym: But that is the point that people are gonna go crazy about.
Rym: that is but those are the people who have no money.
Rym: You're a flicker full of you know 10,000 pictures all marked with the most limited license they can put on there and then they want to keep their copyright for as long As they live plus a million years.
Scott: Yeah, even though they're not making any money off of those things, right?
Scott: It's like you're not making many off of it.
Scott: You released it and you know you released it to where people can look at it.
Scott: Hey now you sort of want to keep people from making remixes of it.
Rym: Yeah Cuz think if you did like no didn't release it anywhere to the public then no one can get it to infringe on your thing.
Rym: You don't pay the dollar.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: The other thing he points out is that he makes some exceptions.
Scott: He's like foreign country people like in foreign countries like shouldn't have to pay the dollar.
Scott: They should have different rules because how are they supposed to know that they have to fill out a form and pay a dollar in The US, you know, it's it's sort of stuff like that.
Scott: He points out.
Scott: There's a couple other exceptions He throws in there, too.
Scott: but I think you should if you're one of those people who is believing the FUD or Confused about the FUD surrounding the orphan works thing.
Scott: You should read this New York Times article from the smart guy.
Rym: So in some more directly anime related news hal Cali a Japanese band That's.
Rym: they look pretty awesome and they're going to be performing at Japan Day in New York City.
Scott: Well, they already performed at anime central last week.
Rym: Right and I hear from what I read because I was kind of looking up on them for reasons That will be apparent in a minute.
Rym: The concert went really well and they're gonna be in New York performing at the second annual Japan Day event on June 1st.
Scott: You know, so they're.
Scott: they're spending quite a few weeks in the US here.
Scott: It's like two or three weeks.
Scott: They're spending here.
Rym: yeah, so one if you're in the New York City area and you want to see a Concert or two or four in Central Park's East Meadow involving perhaps Japanese music They'll also have a guide you in a go-go and happy fun smile.
Scott: Happy fun.
Scott: Smile is the Brian.
Scott: That's Brian eachies.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I'd guide you in a go-go.
Rym: Apparently is all loco or semi local band.
Scott: I never heard of them.
Rym: But anyway, it sounds kind of fun And they're gonna be playing in Central Park at 3 15 p.m.
Rym: For free.
Rym: Yes, I believe.
Scott: so nice Central Park music is usually free.
Rym: Well, I'll be honest in general when it comes to anime events I don't even think about the price cuz.
Rym: where's the last time we paid for a convention?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: but anyway.
Rym: So June 1st concert that's gonna be pretty cool.
Rym: but if you're super cool, you want to be at the Kinokuniya bookstore on Friday May 30th at 6 p.m Because they're going to be there along with Brian Nishi and Tokyo FM and us.
Scott: Oh, we're doing another one of these things and we're gonna be interviewing them for Japanese radio.
Rym: They'll be there to talk to the fans.
Rym: and for anyone who was at our TMR event last time after the New York Comic Con You can pretty much be about two and a half feet away from these people if you want to be if you get there early Enough.
Scott: Yeah, you might have to get there pretty damn early But I feel really bad that I've never listened these people music, but I promise I will get mp3s right after the show.
Rym: Yeah, we'll be all set.
Rym: believe this is gonna be fun.
Rym: But one if you want to see them be at the Kinokuniya Friday May 30th at 6 p.m New York City.
Rym: if you want to see them or us you can be there and it'll be awesome.
Rym: Yeah, if you're super cool, you might want to get there early.
Scott: I really hope it goes well.
Scott: cuz like the second shot, you know, it's like the first shot was easy as TMR I was like a shoo-in, you know, the second one is sort of like.
Scott: well, let's see how it goes.
Scott: And I think if it goes I think it's really it's gonna be a successful monthly deal.
Rym: that that would be way cool Yes, and also there's a website about a link to it.
Rym: But if these events start taking off you can go to a samurai beat radio calm and they'll be kind of regular listings of all These things.
Scott: Oh nice to get a website going.
Rym: Well, they actually asked us to send pictures of ourselves to which we realize that Scott doesn't have any Presentable pictures of himself.
Scott: Yeah, I'm a presenter.
Scott: most of the pictures.
Rym: I'm in like you're like it's like a wide shot Or you're flipping me off.
Scott: the best picture of myself is a picture We took two katsu kansa go and it was like me you In like Conrad and you go behind the table and I'm like off to the side wearing like my Metroid shirt Just like hey Don't you hate that?
Rym: when like you find the one good picture you and I'm off to the side and I'm kind of small and you Can't recreate that moment.
Rym: And if you zoom in it's too grainy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the only picture of me I have this presentable is Probably not suitable for being used in a press capacity.
Rym: Great.
Rym: Yeah, it's in my flicker and I'm kind of horrified that I was going through my flicker looking for pictures of myself And I forgot that I put those pictures up.
Rym: and I was even more horrified that I don't enough Apparently found these pictures and both left comments.
Scott: I gotta go take this out.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: so I came across this and the main reason this is my thing of the day is because the song is Really really really catchy like it just got stuck in my head for the last week.
Rym: It's kind of bad and you hear it and you go ah, ah, it's in my head And actually for a while like Emily was here and Scott was here and we're trying to figure out cuz it sounded really familiar We couldn't figure out what it was from right away.
Rym: We're like, ah, I know this song.
Rym: I've heard this song.
Rym: Ah, did you hate it when that happens?
Scott: Yeah, it's it's pretty rough.
Scott: Then you hear a song.
Scott: I heard this song.
Scott: I've heard this song before.
Scott: I don't know the name of it.
Scott: I don't know who sings it.
Scott: I don't know where it's from.
Rym: But this song this video for one is pretty well done.
Rym: I mean the animation quality.
Scott: it's 3d is Actually really really natural and surprised standing far away from it and I'm like I can make that.
Scott: and Emily's like no you can't.
Scott: And I'm like, yeah, I could I just need a little puppets and she's like, it's not puppets at CG.
Scott: I'm like, oh I can't make that.
Rym: you couldn't do that with puppets if I had the puppets already.
Scott: They don't move very much, but their faces change constantly.
Scott: If you've changed the face on a puppet all you do is you know, you take the eyes off you.
Scott: it's like it's like mr Potato head.
Rym: and how do you do that without moving it mr.
Rym: Potato head and mr.
Rym: Potato head moves.
Scott: The puppets are really big and you but the cameras really far away.
Scott: That's why they look.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, but the thing is it's very like.
Rym: I guess the mood it's.
Rym: the movement was more natural than that Final Fantasy movie.
Scott: Yeah, I never actually saw that Final Fantasy movie.
Scott: I just knew of it like it's it's.
Rym: the animation is really good Even though like the characters seem like they don't move a lot.
Rym: You might say oh, why would you say it's so good.
Rym: It's so like stilted and blah.
Rym: Well, the second link in my thing of the day is the kind of source to this video Which will let you kind of understand where this came from.
Rym: You see there are two things at play here.
Rym: one.
Rym: The song is from sergeant frog One of the closers.
Rym: cuz sergeant frog closers have like dances in them and the characters are just doing the dance From that closer to sergeant frog.
Rym: Mm-hmm very well, but in addition to that The song itself is not the original song from that closer.
Rym: It's a remix.
Rym: It's a special remix because the voice that is singing is not actually a human being or anything.
Rym: It's that vocaloid program.
Rym: now if you don't know what vocaloid is It's basically a program where you can type in Lyrics and then assign notes to the lyrics and do other stuff and a fake idol will sing your song.
Rym: Surprisingly well for you.
Scott: a fake like, you know singing pop star idol not a fake, you know tiki idol.
Rym: I don't know if I need to specify on a Wednesday night.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yes you do.
Rym: How many?
Rym: anyway So the animations catchy.
Rym: the song is catchy I point out.
Rym: watch the girl in the upper left because she totally doesn't know the day.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's that's my favorite part.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I like the girl in the upper right with her yelling.
Scott: No, I like that.
Scott: I like the can't dance one.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's really good.
Rym: Check it out.
Scott: It's cute stuff.
Rym: It's also I point out not just ripped out of dig or college humor.
Scott: Yeah, so check this out already.
Scott: This is totally ripped out of.
Scott: uh, I forget where but it doesn't matter.
Scott: Take your Lupin the third TV series opening animation.
Scott: replace the Lupin gang with Metal Gear.
Scott: That is my thing of the day.
Scott: You probably saw this on the Internet's maybe already maybe not.
Scott: it doesn't matter Really?
Scott: Like I can tell that this is really funny and some of it is funny But because I don't really know Metal Gear was so well I don't get some of the jokes, but yeah, if you know Lupin and you know Metal Gear It's obvious that this is probably gonna crack you up.
Rym: We're definitely well, we might get a little bit of hate for this but I remember when I played Metal Gear Solid 1 and I didn't really like it that much and it was an okay game from what I played.
Scott: I didn't play enough.
Scott: I mean, I should seek out the GameCube version.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but I feel as though I don't know If this might be one of those things were just mark sauce as from the previous generation of gaming much like the most recent VgCads.
Scott: you like right you like Metal Gear 1.
Rym: Yeah, like Metal Gear 1 is my favorite metal.
Scott: Metal Gear 2.
Rym: Oh my god Wait, wait, there was no Metal Gear 2.
Scott: Oh, you're sorry.
Rym: I have no son.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: How could I imagine such a fake thing?
Rym: So I used the game genie to cheat at Metal Gear 2. cuz fuck that game.
Scott: I thought it didn't exist.
Rym: Well, I stopped playing with my mind and some game right this game and I cheated at it.
Rym: And then I realized that I couldn't save my game because I couldn't die because the cheat code I used and And I'd already gone on halfway through.
Rym: that game is impossible and stupid.
Rym: That's like, oh my god.
Rym: So it doesn't matter.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: Red just made that whole thing up.
Scott: Yeah, but Metal Gear 1 is our business, you know That game is nothing but a pack of cigarettes and a fist and a fist.
Rym: I love how later in the game you get that Trunch Dogs You get that transmitter like you get you get captured and then you get let go and you got this extra item now called Transmitter and I remember I got it and I was like, oh, what's that?
Rym:  and I used it and it disappeared.
Rym: And I was like, oh no, no, I gotta save it for whatever I use it for because it's obviously awesome.
Rym: so I You know started again got to that point made sure I didn't use it trying to think about what it would do or when I was gonna use it.
Rym: and for the rest of the game Every screen I went to the bad guys knew how it was there.
Rym: They tried to kill me because you see the transmitter was a bug placed there by the bad guys.
Rym: You were supposed to use it as in you discover and destroy it But I was too clever.
Rym: I kept it For the whole rest of the game.
Rym: I kept it and then my friend Joe said He basically told me in no uncertain terms that I was an idiot.
Rym: That was the first I realized.
Scott: thus is the way of the NES game.
Rym: Oh man, remember those mazes?
Scott: Yeah, which truck do I get on?
Rym: All the time to move?
Rym: Yeah Okay, we got to do a show on Metal Gear one, I didn't play it enough really.
Rym: Yeah, I can beat that game pretty quick.
Scott: I've only played like maybe 20 screens of it.
Rym: Yeah, that's that's actually kind of far.
Scott: It's pretty far.
Rym: No, it's not at all.
Rym: That barely gets you into the first building.
Scott: I know.
Rym: Anyway, so we were thinking about reviewing Kazu no yo Jimbo tonight, which is kind of an older anime and it's not that old I mean, it's it's this millennium anime.
Rym: Well, no it isn't.
Scott: yeah, what year is it from?
Rym: I might have maybe I think might have come out like 2001 I don't remember but this millennium anime.
Rym: Yeah, whatever that's still seven years ago.
Scott: It came out when we were at an RIT.
Rym: It must have been 2002 at least I'm guessing but it was in the early days before I was a run in the anime club.
Scott: I'm pretty sure anyway, cuz I remember I only watched one disc of it and you have the second one.
Scott: So we're thinking we'll watch the second disc before we review the show.
Rym: We got to give it at least a fair shake and I'm not sure if I'm gonna watch the rest.
Scott: It's sort of a an ambiguous kind of show and it's I can't really tell if it's good or bad.
Scott: So I need to watch some more.
Rym: But as a result instead of reviewing something we're gonna you know Do the classic cop-out and have a have a topic in anime manga or comics.
Scott: It's a little bit of a cop-out show because it's similar to a show we've done before but it'll also be kind of short.
Rym: Hardly because it's late and I'm tired But it really a bunch of pizza.
Scott: the episode also sort of has an agenda.
Scott: in that we've realized People really don't seem to understand what we have to talk about.
Rym: So here's the deal.
Rym: every time someone on the internet asks the question, you know, I Keep hearing about this anime thing, but I don't know much about it.
Rym: Maybe I could get into it.
Rym: What show Should I watch?
Scott: Well, the thing is we did an episode on how to get into anime.
Scott: So if you're asking that question.
Scott: You can go and listen to that episode that I guess it's an older episode of ours and it'll answer the question.
Rym: the short answer However is watch the first DVD of cowboy bebop.
Rym: if that doesn't do it for you watch Anything directed by a man named Satoshi?
Scott: Yeah, but despite us doing that episode, you know You think that episode would also right.
Scott: if someone wanted to get their friend into anime They would just sort of interpret the instructions of how to get yourself into anime and transfer them to the friend.
Rym: It asked watch cowboy bebop.
Scott: Yes But apparently people don't seem to understand this and a lot of people on the internet when confronted, you know Anime fans when confronted with someone who is not an anime fan asking about anime Will tell them all sorts of stupid shit that makes them not anime fans.
Rym: It seems like there's a bunch of different classes of these people.
Rym: There's the Old-school anime fan or the or the other way to put it is the anime fan who's otaku wang is bigger than your otaku wang.
Rym: Yeah, and what he'll do is he'll name drop.
Rym: He will say he'll always name either Shows that are not necessarily that great or weren't that well received but have a cult following Mostly from the late 80s early 90s or they'll name shows that there's no way you've seen them.
Rym: They've never been released in English anywhere.
Scott: Well, I think with those people actually tend to do is they tend to be the older school fan, right?
Scott: So they'll tell you to watch the show that they started on cuz like.
Scott: well this show got me interested in anime.
Scott: So look at you and just anime.
Scott: so they always give you like a star blazers or a macross or something like that.
Rym: But I think a lot of those people also Just they get I think they like the idea of giving the off answer.
Rym: Like if you go into a thread where someone asked hey I don't get an anime and someone says watch cowboy bebop eska flown a Evangelion try gun the Akira movie, you know, they the same list Miyazaki's.
Rym: and so she can yes, that's pretty much it.
Scott: That's pretty much it right there.
Rym: They always want to say something but someone else already said cowboy bebop at all.
Rym: Yeah, so what they do is they think what.
Rym: what can I say?
Rym: That'll make me sound cool.
Rym: Oh, yeah, Macross Do you remember love?
Rym: and while that's a good movie?
Rym: I don't know if that's quite forward.
Rym: I guess an anime new.
Scott: Actually, you know a lot.
Scott: this is a side note, but a lot of those fanboys are all about.
Scott: do you remember love?
Scott: I don't like.
Scott: I think the TV series is what you should watch and screw the compilation movie.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: the compilation movie does its job.
Rym: Yeah, I guess It's not anyway, it's not like.
Rym: it's a bad movie.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: Hey, whatever You're just you wanted to generate some hate mail.
Rym: That's the only reason you said that you're home.
Scott: I've said it before hoping.
Rym: I've said before you said that is you're over.
Rym: the Darryl Surratt is sitting there.
Rym: I've told them before I know and he's sitting there right now going damn it Scott you said that again.
Rym: Yeah I will see here in furious silence and then I'll watch this.
Rym: to the North Star episode 78 Where I don't know if no one has some guy gets a head exploded.
Scott: I so the other thing.
Scott: a lot of people mistake when you know They'll be an anime fan.
Scott: their friend who is not an anime fan will say hey, I'm interested in maybe trying some anime.
Scott: What should I watch?
Scott: that they'll tell their friend their personal favorite?
Scott: Right, you don't tell someone else right your favorite anime.
Rym: I mean, it's hard.
Scott: if your favorite anime is cowboy bebop Then I guess you don't hear him telling people to start watching at Utena if they're not into anime.
Rym: Yes, if someone has never heard of anime and they're asking me for suggestions.
Rym: I do not say shoujo kakume Utena.
Scott: No, that's rims favorite show.
Rym: Well, it's as my love that show, but I think it's a tie between that and captain Tyler.
Scott: Well, even so you don't tell people to watch either.
Scott: one of those is the first show I barely tell anyone to watch.
Rym: captain Tyler cuz while I love it You really have to be in the right frame of mind to enjoy captain Tyler.
Scott: Yeah The earlier episodes work in an anime club.
Scott: They hope the rest of the episodes don't work.
Scott: So well, that's the right circumstances.
Rym: They're kind of it's.
Rym: there's their shows.
Rym: that and not just that.
Rym: but there's a lot like.
Rym: Excel saga is a good example.
Rym: I think it's a great show because when it came out like it the parody level was a Thousand times more parody than any anime I'd ever seen.
Rym: that was parodying other anime yep, and it was hilarious and wacky and here's a zany kind of humor, but It's a show that if you've never seen anime it is not only incomprehensible But possibly stupid and frightening.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: I mean if you were to make a list of Like, you know if you're to rank every anime in the universe in order from you know Number one is the best possible show for a new fan and like number a billion is the worst possible show for a new fan.
Scott: Excel saga would probably be the very last show on the list except for all the hentai has to just come after it And I guess the way I would say it is it's a show for the advanced anime watcher.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's not the show you start out with or at least the experienced anime watcher.
Rym: I mean There's some shows that just they jump right into something that if you're not kind of already familiar with the tropes or the mores or They like the character arch types Lucky stars and the Haru.
Scott: He's are not gonna work on someone who is a brand new to anime and hasn't watched a bunch already.
Scott: So it's just not gonna happen.
Rym: I guess the point there is what you really have to do if you want if someone else if you want them Who then they don't watch anime?
Rym: to watch anime you want to spread your fandom?
Rym: Remove yourself from the equation and think about things in terms of well There's two ways to look at it.
Rym: one is what are the majority of people like like what are the most?
Rym: Popular across the broadest spectrum of people.
Rym: and that second part is key because while like bleach is crazy Crazy popular.
Rym: It's crazy crazy popular among Certain specific groups of people and it's generally maligned or not enjoyed by most other groups of people.
Scott: Yep But something like spirited away is enjoyed by almost everybody except Kalani except one guy.
Scott: But I mean that is that is you know It's something just pretty much almost any human being of any age and demographic can find some joy in somewhere.
Scott: almost It was like 99%.
Scott: So if a random person comes up to you and says I want to get into anime Saying spirited away is something you should watch is not a bad answer.
Scott: in fact I would always suggest using movies as opposed to TV shows as actions to anime because someone can get the whole thing in one shot.
Scott: getting someone to watch a 26 episode TV series is much more difficult.
Scott: Even a 13 episode is much more than even a 4 episode OAV.
Scott: much more difficult than a movie Which is one and done.
Rym: to get someone into anime at IBM once I had to Basically beat them over the head.
Rym: I gave him cowboy bebop and they were like Five episodes and I was like, alright look just watch the fifth one.
Rym: If you like that watch the first one.
Rym: if you like that watch the rest and Finally watch the fifth episode.
Rym: He was like, I'd never seen a cartoon where someone pulled a gun before.
Rym: But sadly that's often the kind of angle you have to go at least with people who aren't.
Rym: I mean There are people who just they know about anime They just don't watch it.
Rym: and then there are people who just are unaware of the idea that animation is not a genre.
Rym: That means shows for people under the age of two.
Rym: Yeah so what you want to do is Empathize with the person figure out.
Rym: All right, what do they like?
Rym: ask them?
Rym: What shows they like what movies they like if they like?
Rym: Alfred Hitchcock like thrillers and they like every Alfred Hitchcock movie and that kind of thing.
Rym: or like the old like Dean Coons books or any like sort of psychological thriller then give them a copy of perfect blue because it's just a thriller a Psychological thriller that happens to be animated.
Scott: Yeah, if they're liking, you know Westerns and stuff then give them you know, the old try gun.
Rym: if they're liking well Well, it depends because try gun starts out a little.
Rym: I had to convince my dad.
Rym: I was like dad seriously, trust me It's not that guy running around with donuts or whatever.
Scott: No if they like, you know, like fantasy action You can maybe give them some slayers or some other, you know, you got.
Rym: well again, that's one of those.
Rym: What kind of fantasy do they like?
Rym: are they?
Rym: if they're busy if they're a D&D playing beer and pretzels?
Rym: Let's go kill the dragons.
Rym: They'll probably find slayers Hilarious probably if they're a. I'm a serious business dungeon master and I play serious business dungeons and dragons.
Rym: The original lotus war is gonna kick their ass.
Rym: They will.
Rym: they will love that.
Rym: they'll eat that up Yeah, so it's like then they'll murder you when they find out where it goes.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you don't know the person you got to go the general route.
Scott: You know stuff that almost anyone will like.
Scott: but if you do know the person Then or if you add you can always question them out - you say what do you like, you know?
Scott: What kind of like, you know, what's your favorite movie?
Scott: if they say, you know Blade Runner?
Scott: Maybe you could give them some Akira's or something or maybe some ghost in the shell action Yeah, or if they like a procedural cop dramas or things like that get him some standalone complex.
Scott: Yeah It's pretty much.
Scott: don't go around telling people it sucks.
Scott: I don't like it, you know, if you're a big giant robot fan that that's great.
Scott: You can like your giant robots.
Scott: your giant robots are awesome But it's not the most.
Scott: but if someone comes up to you and says I want to be an anime fan I'm thinking about it.
Scott: What should I watch?
Scott: Don't be like you should totally watch.
Scott: get a robo because that will not work.
Scott: No, you will turn them off of anime better.
Rym: It's all about great King Mazen Kaiser.
Scott: It's like you're gonna make a bad impression on them even if you know It's something that you like, you know, and I think another part of the problem Is that some of these people out there they know this.
Scott: I'm not telling them anything new But they're thinking in their minds.
Scott: Well, if they're not gonna like the giant robots, I'd rather have them not like anime.
Scott: You know, it's like they don't want to make an anime fan.
Scott: They want to make a giant robot fan.
Rym: I think that goes back into the same mentality that causes people to Name-drop instead of actually giving I guess useful recommendations based on a person's interests.
Scott: This is actually something I've noticed in like reviews in general I mean serious reviewing.
Scott: people don't seem to have this problem as much.
Scott: but like people just giving sort of like their offhand Reviews and forums and blogs around the net, you know, people don't seem to be able to sort of.
Scott: you know Review is an entirely subjective thing But people's don't seem to be able to separate like their personal, you know quirks and tastes in their review from the sort of actual, you know criteria critic Criticisms like.
Scott: you know, if you say something, you know has ugly character designs, you know That's sort of a general criticism Like if it's drawn poorly or you know, it's skipping frames in the animation or something.
Rym: General criticism, but if it's just Escaflowne or something like and something designed by Amano or you just don't like it personally then I think the good reviewer says Well, if you're like me, you won't like these character designs.
Rym: But if you're like if you're the kind of person who likes really really thin angular people then this is your show.
Scott: I'm thinking more along the lines of you know, the people who are like.
Scott: this show has no robots.
Scott: Therefore it sucks.
Rym: It's all the people who say this show has robots and therefore it's like someone on the forum said something to the effect of blah blah blah.
Rym: ribbon Scott really loved those giant robot shows and I found that interesting because I actually dislike the vast majority of giant robot shows.
Rym: In fact, I like the idea of a giant robot is way cool Yes, but I feel like I like it mostly in an ironic way like giant Robo.
Rym: Well one that show is not what you expect and that's that's the time.
Rym: I wouldn't call that a giant robot show almost.
Rym: It's something special.
Rym: Yeah, but like shows like Escaflowne It has robots in it, but it's not a giant robot show.
Rym: In fact, it if anything it's a shoujo with shounen elements or shounen with shoujo elements.
Rym: fantasy.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there were a lot of people, you know when we start did our prince of the nothing thing They were like, yeah, I don't.
Scott: I don't like fantasy books.
Scott: I'm like what it's like.
Rym: What do you mean you don't like fantasy book?
Scott: Well, it's.
Scott: it's like how do you write?
Scott: Oh, it's like you just don't like the theme that's on top of the actual story.
Scott: It's like how do you?
Scott: I don't understand how people can have such sort of especially narrow Short-sighted sort of taste.
Rym: I knew someone at RIT who loved the Star Wars novels, but hated Fantasy novels.
Rym: then I was like I'm exact thing except I'll just replace the lightsaber with get Excalibur Exact kind of story.
Rym: Yeah, it's.
Scott: no, you know, it's.
Scott: I think it's the same thing.
Scott: We have video games.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of like.
Rym: a lot of people say oh, I like I hate science fiction But the only science fiction they know is Star Trek.
Rym: They don't know about the Heinlein's and the Asimov's the speculative fiction.
Scott: Yeah to them.
Scott: It's like science fiction means spaceships.
Rym: No, not really, but at the same time inside his science there are people who also bother me where they say no It's only truly science fiction if it's an Asimov or a Heinlein's like.
Rym: no Can have dumb speculative fiction.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: a lot of people seem to only judge things and see things on the surface level like.
Scott: how many times do we Like, you know we get two different video games, you know And like.
Scott: we'll look at like Ikaruga and Gradius and we'll say those are two completely different games and someone else will look at him And say but they're both shooting spaceships and I'm like no one is a memorization game and what is a reflexes game?
Scott: They're completely different and unrelated and that's sort of the same thing that happens here with anime and everything else.
Scott: is we look through the surface You know, we look at say You know I'm trying to think of to cover and we judge the book by its cover, right?
Rym: Right, of course The one thing I can say is the prince of nothing books the originals at least.
Rym: there was nothing on the cover But some fancy script and the title and the author's name and now the cover has.
Rym: now the cover has a picture of some guy.
Scott: I'm just trying to think of two anime that have completely different themes on the surface level but are very similar underneath.
Rym: It's guys.
Rym: easier to find two shows that look like they're exactly the same but actually aren't.
Scott: I guess Mmm, well like Evangelion looks a lot like wrote, you know other robot shows.
Rym: It even starts like a giant robot show.
Rym: Yes, well like interesting first episode and then it's well like this giant robot This one and this one.
Rym: but big Oh.
Scott: big Oh looks a lot like road even more like giant robot shows in Batman.
Rym: big Oh is just a show where every episode the big Oh punches some other robot in the face But it's not even close to a giant robot show.
Scott: if you look underneath the surface It's actually I.
Rym: I guess that's the thing A lot of people would write off a show like big Oh because they're like, oh giant robots.
Rym: That's anime crap.
Rym: But big Oh in my opinion and I'm dead serious here I think we did this is our first final thought show we did on big Oh a long time.
Rym: Yeah it was a long time ago.
Rym: big Oh is one of the more meaningful more interesting and Deeper anime out there.
Scott: like definitely like.
Scott: in the top 15 or 20, I'd say I definitely say I mean plus There's also this shows out there.
Scott: What was that?
Scott: What the hell was the show with the?
Scott: we're all that it looked like a normal cute happy evil cries of the Higurashi Higurashi.
Scott: no, not good.
Scott: Coronee.
Rym: Yeah Emily reminded us.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So yeah that show.
Scott: you can't be judging the shows.
Rym: I remember the sad show because that was if I remember.
Rym: we're you know, we pick a random anime like alright Let's watch episode one of something.
Rym: so we Turn on this show and we see someone brutally beating someone else to death with a baseball bat and there's blood everywhere.
Rym: We're like, okay kind of show is this?
Rym: some kind of murder drama some kind of psycho drama Some kind of.
Rym: it's not a magical girl unless she's shown it or shoujo bat, but That's not.
Scott: you look at fancy.
Scott: Lala you because a magical girl look like princess tutu.
Scott: Oh, it's a magical girl.
Rym: And yeah, I'm watching princess tutu now and while it is a magical girl show So is utenna in a lot of regards, but that does not mean it's on the same level as Sailor Moon.
Scott: Cardcaptor Sakura Is a magical girl show straight up with no with no not much deep action going on.
Scott: Yeah, Sailor Moon was pretty much just car.
Rym: Sailor Moon was deeper than Cardcaptor.
Scott: only a little More depends on which one you want.
Rym: I think you're Underestimating the depth of Sailor Moon and overestimating the depth of Cardcaptor.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, the point is when you recommend anime to people who are not, you know into anime you need to a Suggest things that are popular to most people and not just your favorite because you actually want them to like anime Even if they don't end up liking the anime you like better they be an anime fan than not.
Rym: now remember and like the Strategy here if you want to just think about it in terms of I'm gonna get them into this.
Rym: you start broad You show them Cowboy Bebop or some Miyazaki's and you say like check it out Animation is good anime can be good.
Rym: and then you you you step it up a little bit like well you liked that.
Rym: Well, this is a little bit more for the refined fat.
Rym: This is you know The next step.
Rym: check this out and you and you start them on Cowboy Bebop and you end them on Great King Mazin Fist Kaiser Joe, right Jojo's Bizarre Adventure.
Scott: and you gotta ask him you got to figure out what their personal taste is in other things.
Scott: You know do they what books they like what comics they like what movies?
Scott: and then you can find anime.
Scott: They're very similar to those.
Rym: the only anime John the only genre you're really not gonna find an anime is Western style horror.
Rym: You really don't see that.
Scott: No, you're gonna find weird Asian horror, which I actually prefer.
Scott: Yeah, it depends actually what I really like.
Scott: the bug boy.
Rym: what I was about to say is I really like the quirky Asian Quote-unquote horror like I really like Kataro.
Scott: the guitar was good I like it's our own and I. I was just actually right before we did the show.
Scott: I was looking at my shelf and I saw the bug boy and I remembered how much I like the bug boy So happy in the ocean I liked it.
Scott: the best part is me is going down the slide at the playground.
Scott: And Then lastly you have to put your personal tastes aside And examine the shows below the surface level to determine what kind of show they actually Are and not you know, what kind of show I mean.
Scott: beard to say.
Rym: you say you meet someone who isn't an anime But like the idea of giant robots beating each other to death like just the sets the rocks off and that's what they like Like.
Rym: oh man, you're telling me I can see giant robots fighting.
Rym: You don't want to show them Ava cuz it's gonna start with giant robots fighting and then it's gonna turn into this Philosophical rant fest and they're gonna get confused and wander away and probably hate you.
Scott: Yeah, that is the person who needs some ghetto robos.
Rym: Yes that some rust hurricanes up in some the messenger's ease or maybe or the same deal.
Rym: They like giant robots.
Rym: Don't show them giant robot.
Rym: It might be confused because the name giant robo You figure if someone likes giant robots.
Rym: But no that show is not about what you think it's about and the robot cries and no man.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I Don't know.
Rym: I think that I think we've met our point Well enough.
Rym: the.
Rym: the catalyst for this show was that someone asked in the forums at one point What should I watch to get into anime?
Rym: and I'm gonna be honest pretty much every suggestion that people gave in that thread was just Horrible.
Rym: Yeah, like there was a lot of them were good shows But that's not how you convince someone to like.
Rym: your thing is by showing them the like the weirdest or the most Extreme or the most inside examples of your thing.
Rym: you start broad and then you narrow down.
Scott: Yep, you know I do find it interesting though a lot of the old-school fans They all a lot of them came in like through the sci-fi's, you know The Akira's the Matsumoto's the Robo tech macross.
Scott: is that you know, that was really like the big original draw I think Including myself.
Rym: Yeah Well there I mean there was a lot of all the niche fandoms kind of had a lot of overlap in terms of if Nerds and geeks get together.
Rym: nerds and geeks tended to like very specific things And now we're having this kind of flowering of geek or Renaissance man.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Oh So this is how we can make more anime fans people.
Scott: you want more anime fans not less, right?
Scott: Okay, so do what we say.
Rym: so again in case you forgot cowboy vbop Evangelion eska flown a try gun Miyazaki anything directed by Miyazaki or Satoshi khan or poker poker.
Scott: Oh, so Poker Rose is a great.
Scott: Oh, man, you can't really you can't be pretty much no matter who it is.
Scott: You can't go wrong saying this is your first anime because the pig in the airplane.
Rym: We got a review poker.
Scott: Oh, so I only watched it twice.
Scott: It was a while years ago.
Rym: I've seen it like seven times.
Scott: I got a two times man.
Scott: I see a thing is like I think is might still be my number one Miyazaki But like pork erosos always like right on top of it and I think if I watched pork erosos, it might jump ahead again.
Scott: I don't know hard to say it's a tough I think.
Rym: what the deal with pork erosos?
Rym: if you want to show it to someone is it because it's older?
Rym: You can play up the one it still got all the charm of like a Ghibli movie.
Rym: Like you look at you're like wow And it's.
Rym: you know, it's light-hearted, but there's some depth there and everything's great about it.
Rym: Animations really good and at the same time it's vintage.
Rym: It looks old so you can plan to play the.
Rym: this is like some vintage animation.
Rym: Look at this.
Rym: This is a classic and the look it and go.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Yeah a classic.
Rym: I should watch a classic a classic at anything.
Rym: Yeah, let's go and then you watch it and it's got that.
Rym: it's got this these quirky charm elements.
Rym: I mean the main character is a pig but yet no one really talks about that and he flies a plane And and that's it.
Rym: That's normal.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.