Rym:
Rym: let's do this hello new listeners from future.
Rym: Katsucon I know you're all out there.
Rym: I know you found out about us at Katsucon and you thought all right I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna follow that URL on that flyer that you put in my hand and force me to take after you tricked me into seeing your panel.
Scott: yeah maybe or maybe you're someone who is waiting to go to Katsucon tomorrow and you're listening to this in anticipation of finding out what's gonna go down.
Rym: well for the latter we're gonna talk mostly about stuff you already know but this weekend in Washington DC is Katsucon 2008. Katsucon is pretty much neck-and-neck with Otakon for my favorite anime khan.
Scott: it's not the biggest khan but it's pretty big and it's pretty awesome in terms of what goes down what it lacks in sheer number of people it makes up for with as the Japanese would say guts.
Scott: yeah I mean you know unlike other khan's that may be in convention centers Katsucon still is hardcore going all night from Friday early when they open until Sunday somewhat late when they close.
Scott: the khan is open especially the game room which only closes for a few hours like an hour or two early Saturday morning for like you know clean up and restoring and refurbishing.
Rym: yeah you realize people that pretty much Thursday night the video game room is already gonna be up and going and we're gonna be in there playing rampart.
Rym: not you though not you you have to wait.
Scott: no not you but us us.
Scott: we'll be playing rampart Thursday and perhaps Rock Band and perhaps Smash Brothers.
Scott: who knows I can't.
Rym: I shouldn't say this but I have it on good authority that the Katsucon game room will in fact have the new Smash Brothers.
Scott: yeah but I don't know if I'm gonna play it though cuz I'm torn.
Scott: it's like oh I could play it.
Scott: yeah but on the other hand I should wait for the u.s.
Scott: release to govern the house and then play it.
Rym: yeah it's straight straight up for the beginning like it's supposed to be played but at Katsucon we're going to be in the video game room.
Rym: pretty much the entire car most of the kind and a good chunk of the front row crew is also going to be a Katsucon.
Rym: this year.
Rym: they're going to have this kind of mass of tables all next to each other in the artists alley and you might like to look at some of the work they've been doing because we're not well we're kind of the I don't know front of the front row crew in terms of the internet.
Rym: the rest of them are all doing stuff and you might like it.
Scott: a lot of them are making arts which will be for sale and I guess you can buy them and maybe they can make some money and if they do me they'll probably make more money.
Scott: in that con the GeekNights is made ever.
Scott: yeah that's my guess.
Rym: well maybe cuz we never actually made all that swag yet.
Scott: no we have made anything.
Rym: we'll have it for Otakon maybe ConnectiCon maybe we'll see.
Rym: all right.
Rym: but at this con we're doing not one not two not four but six panel.
Scott: they're doing five.
Rym: well others costumes kendo panel okay which we are doing.
Rym: but doing mostly means we're going to be there while he does it.
Scott: yeah I'm just gonna kind of sit there.
Scott: I mean I missed his one at Otakon.
Rym: it was pretty good.
Scott: but I heard it was pretty good.
Rym: it was awesome.
Rym: but my job was basically I introduced him and then I just kind of stood at the back of the room and then at the end I said thank you Katsu and I the crowd cheered.
Rym: Katsu's panels are easy but yeah Friday from 3 p.m.
Rym: to 4 p.m live to Katsu.
Rym: no Rima Tashida a good friend of ours member of the front row crew was running his kendo panel which he ran something similar to at Otakon.
Rym: it was hardcore to put it lightly.
Scott: yeah all you punk kids you know you buy swords in the dealer's room thinking you're all cool cuz you like swords.
Scott: and I could understand when I was a kid.
Scott: swords are way cool and I just wanted to play with swords and pretend to fight with swords of the people.
Rym: in fact it's I. it's a good thing that the money to sword ratio.
Rym: in my life I mean my desire for swords was very high when my money was very low.
Rym: but now that my money is very high my desire for swords is very low.
Rym: if that had ever not been true either would have starved to death or I would had a lot of.
Scott: so well it could have not been true.
Scott: you could have had a low money and a low desire for swords.
Rym: I don't think that could have ever happened.
Scott: okay are you saying that desire for swords is inversely proportional to income?
Scott: well it is possible that if anyone wants to get rich here's the here's how to get rich by Rym.
Scott: don't buy sword like swords.
Scott: if you hate swords if you really just want to get rid of sword they the fuck out of an area.
Scott: you're going to get super rich.
Rym: I think it's more that a sword is an implement which can be used to acquire money if you are well maybe or to get shot anyway.
Scott: but all you punk kids who were liking the swords if you want to see what the sorting is really about that's what katsu is gonna lay on you when cops with his pain added at Otakon.
Rym: you know people didn't know to expect and katsu didn't even use a microphone and he was doesn't need to use a microphone and we didn't talk that loudly.
Rym: and this was kind of.
Rym: the crowd was silent and I'm not kidding.
Rym: they were pretty much on the edges of their seats with rapt attention until he forced them all to leave the room.
Rym: mm-hmm it was.
Rym: it was epic but the real business begins on Friday from 9 30 p.m.
Rym: until 1 a.m that is the GeekNights' block number one from 930 to 1030 at 1 a.m on Sunday Saturday sleep we are running the famous the classic anime match game that we've run at a lot of cons recently.
Rym: it has always been standing room only it's always been crazy.
Scott: my prediction this will be the best anime match game.
Scott: yet we might have to retire the match game because we won't be able to top it and have to come up with a new game.
Rym: that might be true.
Rym: you should see.
Rym: we've got all new questions which we've said at every match game but this time it's actually true.
Scott: yeah we have all new questions.
Scott: we probably have the possibly the best match game panel in terms of people who are skilled at the match game and we'll bake it hilarious for you and you've got a big old chunk of time.
Scott: is it two hours long?
Rym: it's only an hour long but right after that for a half hour we still have the room and it's pretty much the intermission between that and the main event.
Scott: what are you gonna do for that intermission?
Rym: uh you know we figured that out actually about.
Rym: no no a couple hours ago you'll see we got a couple things planned but it should be entertaining to say the least.
Rym: all right.
Rym: but then from 11 p.m.
Rym: to 1 a.m.
Rym: late night Katsucon hosted by Rym and Scott we've got.
Rym: we've got Greg Ayers and Steve Bennett as our guest.
Rym: TVV is uh if you don't know who's TVV is he's one of the few people for whom the word epic really applies when it comes to being an anime fan.
Scott: you may have heard many things about this man but there's one thing that is the only one thing about him that matters regardless of whether those other things are true or not is that he is mighty entertaining at the anime conventions.
Scott: he's also the best match game contestant we've ever had and we will be the catalyst for his entertaining faucet.
Rym: I hope he doesn't have any other faucets.
Scott: we will ignore those faucets that may or may not exist for the time being.
Rym: but we've got a comedy act.
Rym: we got some stand-up we got some musical acts.
Rym: we've got a history lesson.
Rym: at the end this is gonna be a pretty good show.
Scott: I practice that history lesson.
Rym: we got to practice everything.
Rym: God we haven't even had a rehearsal of this.
Rym: we have a rehearsal when maybe Thursday Thursday Thursday at katsu-kan will be the rehearsal for late night.
Scott: katsu-kan you're not invited.
Rym: we're so awesome right now.
Rym: then Saturday at noon which is pretty much gonna be when I wake up we're going to have a nice laid-back panel anime you should see.
Scott: oh I thought that was gonna be breakfast.
Rym: well we can eat breakfast at it.
Rym: maybe we'll get some bagels and bring them to the panel.
Scott: yeah anyone to come.
Scott: this is the panel they have the lowest expectations for.
Scott: so I'm gonna buy a whole but we're gonna try to get.
Scott: I guess I'm doing this.
Scott: I get trying to get as many doughnuts as I can.
Scott: it could be anywhere between zero and infinity doughnuts.
Scott: right I don't know how many but I'm gonna try.
Scott: and if you show up I'll give you a doughnut.
Rym: and in fact if you were dressed up as Vash the stampede you get two doughnuts.
Scott: no no you don't.
Scott: what is Vash?
Scott: that's tough shit.
Rym: ah but I get all the doughnuts I want because I think the past four decades have seen a lot of great anime.
Rym: you've probably seen much less.
Rym: now's your chance to learn about.
Rym: why are you reading the blockbusters of yesteryear and the classics for all time?
Scott: why are you reading the ad copy?
Rym: I wrote that ad copy and I'm proud of it.
Rym: great okay but here's the deal for all of you because you know they wanted us to do a panel.
Rym: well the con the con people out there the people who aren't listening to GeekNights aren't cool yet they're uh they're gonna.
Rym: I don't know what they're gonna expect when they come to a panel like this cuz.
Rym: panels with titles like this are at every freaking anime con and they're usually just stupid like it's a when you like Naruto.
Rym: yeah I like Naruto.
Rym: let's talk about Naruto.
Rym: so uh we're gonna.
Rym: we're not sure what we're gonna do with this panel but it's gonna be vaguely related to anime that we want you to see.
Rym: I think it'll be fun.
Scott: I think what I'm gonna do is do a lot of audience questioning of like.
Scott: so why did you?
Scott: why did you come to this battle?
Rym: well we'll get people up be like all right what kind of?
Rym: well I'm sure there's gonna be someone in the audience who hates anime.
Rym: we'll get them up and we'll talk to them.
Scott: yeah yeah we should.
Scott: actually that's a good idea.
Scott: let's get people up there ask them an anime they like what they've seen and what they haven't seen and then tell them what they should see.
Scott: yeah let's do it like that instead of it's just being generic like everyone should see this.
Scott: everyone should see that.
Rym: yeah granted there are a couple things that everyone should see.
Rym: if you know what I'm gonna spoil it right now.
Rym: cowboy bebop Evangelion escaflown a try gun serial experiments Lane full metal alchemist.
Scott: I guess your Tana princess tutu princess too - yeah why you'd be surprised fancy lala before princess tutu.
Rym: big-o big-o - big-o oh big-o - those tomatoes he tests.
Rym: okay anyway keep going with the schedule here and then Saturday night from 5 30 p.m.
Rym: to 6 30 p.m.
Rym: in live one.
Rym: we ran this event as a test and it failed at ConnectiCon last year.
Rym: we've revamped it and now I think we're good to go.
Rym: it is the challenger on fire.
Scott: I'm still leery about this event but we'll for it anyway.
Rym: where the thing is now we're set up.
Rym: we're gonna have a good 20 contestants up there.
Rym: we might do things to people who are knocked out of the competition.
Scott: this is gonna be.
Scott: what are you gonna do to people?
Scott: you'll see.
Scott: you got some pies ready or some clown pistol clown pistols.
Scott: maybe you don't have any clown pistols.
Rym: I've been shot at with clown pistols.
Scott: yeah yeah.
Rym: all I have to say is there's a 1% chance that Daryl Surratt might appear at this con.
Scott: and yeah I like one point like 0.1 percent chance I don't know.
Rym: apparently the last time when he showed up at Katsucon when I met him while I was quite drunk he only went because randomly a bunch of his friends were going and he just hit your ride so that might happen again?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I doubt it.
Rym: Gerald couldn't tell me if he was going or not so whatever.
Rym: but then from 11 30 to 12 to midnight 30 a.m.
Rym: in live 3.
Scott: so Oh 30.
Rym: now notice how all Monday on Sunday all our other events are in live 1 and live 2 but this one's in live 3.
Rym: I think it's kind of like how Otakon puts a certain kind of thing in video 5 every year.
Rym: I think live 3 is gonna be special because we did a panel at Otakon last year that is famous or infamous depending on who you are and who you talk to but it was.
Rym: it was standing room only and people applauded and only two people walked out in disgust.
Rym: so I can stand up now.
Scott: we know those two people.
Rym: yes if the only two people who walked out and discussed where our friends I think it was okay but us along some of the people clapping were people from Katsucon who were like please do it again for us.
Rym: I think the best part is.
Rym: we got called into like the Otakon staff because they heard tell of this kind of epic panel we'd run and they were curious as to whether or not that epicness exceeded certain boundaries but half the staff as we were walking.
Rym: it was a man.
Rym: you guys ran that.
Rym: that was fucking awesome.
Rym: oh my god.
Rym: yeah but gecky guy.
Rym: now we're going to do a very similar panel to what we did at Otakon.
Scott: however however Gerald who is responsible for much of the epicness yeah in fact told us that he wanted us to make sure that we gave him credit for the stuff that he did.
Rym: and though we will oh yes we definitely will.
Rym: you see we're not going to shit.
Rym: we we've gotten a hold of the visual aids that Gerald used and we're in.
Rym: Scott is studying and because I couldn't deal with it making a very careful study.
Rym: yes well I studied mr.
Rym: Tokai enough like studying nitroglycerin plutonium totally gecky goni him.
Rym: yeah but let me put it this way this panel.
Rym: you've got to be 18 and we're gonna be checking ID before you come in.
Rym: and as long as you are not easily offended by things this panel is gonna be awesome.
Rym: if you're easily offended do not come to our gecky god panel.
Rym: I'm serious but if you liked ichi the killer or meatball machine or any of that stuff or if you have a feeling that everything we call this intro everything we just said sounds hilarious that panel is so up your alley.
Rym: you have no idea.
Scott: so what are we doing anything after that?
Scott: or is that it?
Rym: well we had scheduled another the anime match game encore on Sunday from 1 to 2 and live 1. but but I guess this is probably good for us.
Rym: but all the guests said we're gonna leave early on Sunday cuz you know we want to go home after this.
Rym: con will be tired.
Rym: you expect us to be up by 1 p.m.
Rym: huh.
Rym: so I don't know if we're gonna fill that slot with something else or not.
Scott: well we'll see the schedule when we get there.
Scott: yeah there's an event before it has to con schedule still say that?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I didn't even look.
Rym: well they rescheduled and the event before it is supposed to go long but we might do something in that room.
Rym: we'll see.
Rym: now beyond all that in the video game room you won't be hard to find us.
Rym: and there might be some Atari 7800 tournaments.
Rym: no I guarantee there will be Atari 7800 tournaments and actually probably like late Saturday what I want to say to all of you now I will give $100 cash to anyone who can beat me at a game of kaboom.
Scott: I think you better watch out cuz.
Scott: you know there's that guy who could beat Marvel Madness.
Rym: you know what.
Rym: I'll say this this is one of those challenges kind of like.
Rym: when I was I was well I was drunk last katsu-kan but I was betting people money on Rampart.
Rym: but I wouldn't take any money if I won.
Rym: I'd only give them money if I lost.
Rym: I never lost.
Rym: but this is one of those.
Rym: ideas were alright.
Rym: if nobody wins then I just proved how awesome I am and if anyone beats me I basically paid $100 to find one of the most awesome people in the world and become their friend.
Scott: well but I know there are people at katsu kind of mad video game skills.
Scott: I don't think it's a good thing to bet on video game skills at katsu-kan unless you are real sure of yourself that you're God like.
Rym: let me put it this way when I was very young my father played kaboom like.
Scott: I wouldn't even bet on my Megaman 2 or Tetris skills at katsu-kan.
Rym: I have played kaboom since I was four years old and I've played it.
Rym: continue.
Scott: watch that guy play Marvel Madness.
Scott: I'm betting he's also good that good at other games.
Rym: I don't know kaboom that it's tricky cuz even if you're you have you have awesome skill.
Rym: you got to have some some special techniques to get the high score.
Scott: yeah don't use the broken controller.
Rym: so yeah katsu-kan Washington DC at the omnishore motel.
Rym: if you can't find the omnishore motel in Washington DC you probably shouldn't be going to katsu-kan.
Scott: and that's it for the news.
Scott: cuz I'm not gonna look up anything in my RSS feed that hasn't been read in like two weeks.
Rym: anyway things of the day.
Rym: now I'm not gonna talk about the underlying thing here other than that this is not a straight-up Mario Paint music maker because the Mario Paint music maker is kind of limited.
Rym: I actually made a bunch of songs in it for a cloud digital audio class at RIT and this is much more full-featured but it is otherwise still alive done in Mario Paint and it's pretty damn cool.
Scott: yeah if anyone hasn't found this there's some Windows program out there that's basically lets you do the Mario Paint music making but better without stupid limits put on it by the weakness of the Super Nintendo and it's pretty good.
Scott: my favorite is the swan.
Scott: what's your favorite?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I always like the Gameboy.
Rym: I used to write like all these kind of three-part four-part harmonies with Gameboy.
Scott: see the swan was always mystifying to me because the swan is like that techno noise that I love so much but like I never knew what makes that noise or how to make that.
Rym: so now you know it's swan exactly swans.
Rym: actually you know it's called an orchestra.
Scott: hit whatever it's a swan swans are where it's at all right.
Scott: my thing today is super simple.
Scott: it's a picture.
Scott: it's just one picture.
Scott: it's a Photoshop.
Scott: someone did mashing up two things.
Scott: I like it's pretty simple but when I saw it it made me really happy and when I look at it again it still makes me happy.
Rym: I'm smiling just thinking about it.
Rym: Scott sent it to me and said check that out.
Rym: I said whoa.
Scott: so you've probably seen it before on your 4chans or whatnot.
Scott: it's probably mad old and lame and you know whatever.
Scott: but I saw it.
Scott: I never saw it before and I like it a lot.
Scott: so fuck you and fuck your mother.
Rym: that was uncalled for whatever.
Rym: at least go after Scott Johnson's mother all right.
Rym: but yeah the most talked about mother.
Scott: on GeekNights if you're liking some asamanga tiles or maybe some transformers you like this picture.
Scott: it will make you happy.
Rym: so now we I mentioned this briefly yesterday but when it comes to a show that reviews any sort of genre or medium or anything like that.
Rym: there's always kind of those big names the heavy hitters that you almost don't want to talk about because you almost feel like you're not up to the challenge like you're never ready you couldn't do it justice.
Scott: or that it's so big that like what is there to say about it?
Scott: you know it's like why.
Scott: you know why.
Scott: what's the point?
Scott: it's like if you've made a podcast right a move that remove you movies right what would be the point in reviewing say Star Wars episode 4. you know the lead hope new hope.
Rym: have you ever seen Star Wars?
Scott: yeah I was like I was.
Scott: I forgot the words before hope I was like last hope only hope.
Scott: yeah yeah you know that stop but reviewing that it's like.
Scott: what's the point?
Scott: who doesn't know?
Scott: who hasn't seen it?
Scott: who doesn't know everything?
Scott: what's the point in reviewing it other than you know to maybe entertain people who like it a lot that you can sort of give them an install
Rym: as I've learned from listening to a lot of movies you should see is that I pretty much mostly listen to reviews of movies I've already seen because you almost when someone else who knows about film or knows about anime or knows about comics is kind of talking about their reading of something from their perspective.
Rym: you almost relive reading it again and you like those moments where you went.
Rym: ah you go ah again just from thinking about what are you doing a Captain Billy over there I moved it yours like squeezing it.
Scott: yeah anyway.
Rym: so yeah the show is unedited tonight because we got a pack for katsukan.
Rym: we're leaving in the morning and we haven't done shit.
Scott: well we've done shit but we're doing more.
Scott: I gotta do laundry I gotta eat I gotta do a lot of things all right.
Scott: so the greatest Rym agrees and most other people agree.
Scott: the greatest animated television series to come out of Japan in the history of the world maybe even in the world ever.
Scott: yeah maybe maybe debatable but definitely the best animated television series out of Japan ever.
Rym: I would even argue that this is among the best television series animated or not.
Scott: period top 5 easily.
Scott: yes best television shows ever is obviously cowboy bebop.
Scott: there's no question cowboy bebop we're not gonna spoil anything tonight because mostly also talking about it because it is now available in a in a new $40 box you can get all 26 episodes with surround sound and for $40.
Scott: this is the deal of the century.
Scott: if you call yourself an anime fan you don't own it.
Scott: there's nothing wrong with you.
Rym: yes now even more.
Rym: I said we're not gonna spoil anything because I've noticed that unlike Star Wars which everyone has in fact seen except for that one girl in my high school who when we were playing the Star Wars theme we were freshmen you know that the best song in Star Wars.
Rym: she had the French horn part there and she played it wrong and the conductor was like don't read the music did you know how it goes?
Rym: just play the Star Wars thing.
Rym: and she says I've never seen Star Wars.
Rym: and we immediately stopped and and watched Star Wars.
Rym: oh yeah someone went home.
Rym: he was allowed to drive home get the DVD brought it back.
Rym: we watched Star Wars right there.
Scott: your class was that long that someone had time to drive home drive back and sit there for 90 minutes.
Scott: well one band was two periods together but still only about 90 minutes or two.
Rym: Star Wars was important enough to where.
Rym: we just stayed in the room after the bell rang for another half hour and then the teacher just wrote us all notes saying that band practice got held up for some reason.
Rym: he made something up right.
Scott: there's a lot of notes to write.
Scott: goddamn his hand must be hurting.
Rym: well alright you want to give the details.
Rym: he wrote one note and send it to the centralized office.
Rym: then all the other teachers could check it later and see that people did in fact have an excuse.
Rym: but I didn't want to get into the details of the bureaucracy of when we're trying to talk about the greatest to animated television series ever created.
Rym: so if you have not seen cowboy bebop and there are a lot of anime fans who have not because it's garily enough even though it's on Cartoon Network like seven times there's a lot of anime and to most anime fans don't.
Rym: they might go to conventions but they don't watch a lot of anime and they or they're just getting into it.
Rym: a lot of anime fans are new and there aren't a lot of good places to find out what the good anime are.
Rym: so I can conceive of someone who likes anime.
Rym: just got into it.
Rym: I mean God.
Rym: when I got to RIT I'd never heard a cowboy bebop.
Rym: I never heard of it at all.
Rym: I remember sitting at the first RIT anime.
Scott: I was there too but I didn't know you and I didn't see you not at.
Rym: the whole front row crew was there but none of us knew each other all sitting in separate seats complete strangers.
Rym: like one of those scenes in utenna where like it shows the room and then it freezes and then it kind of like all the people who will eventually be the front row crew are in color.
Rym: they're all in different spots of the room and everyone else is in black and white.
Rym: and then like you're looking oh it was that was the day but anyway.
Rym: so uh and this girl behind me is like oh man yeah they're showing four different anime tonight.
Rym: they're showing that episode of cowboy bebop.
Rym: oh which one?
Rym: the one where spike fights vicious.
Rym: yeah that's the best one.
Rym: I'm thinking cowboy bebop.
Scott: now the name alone was quite appealing to me the but then the episode where spike fights vicious.
Rym: now I heard that I thought is that one of those stupid fighting shows is episode five by the way the last episode of the first DVD.
Rym: now then you know we saw this anime and I remember when that episode played.
Rym: I remember thinking right that in there.
Rym: wow that was one of the best things I've ever seen.
Scott: that was at the time the best thing I had ever seen like it just like I was like.
Rym: I was dumbfounded by how awesome that was.
Scott: it's like all the things they showed that night.
Scott: they showed a bunch of music videos including white reflection which none of which had ever seen before.
Rym: now I'd seen that and that was but still seeing it on a big screen like that instead of like my tiny and I don't like it as much as other people seem to like it by the way.
Scott: they also showed an episode of guns with cats which I'd never seen and I don't even remember the other things they showed.
Rym: I barely remember the rest of that day.
Rym: all I remember is that I saw something something I remember it was in room one two thousand something that was so amazing that I I don't know.
Rym: and then not too long after that Scott Johnson who was you know one of the executive board people in the club at the time he decided all right I'm gonna marathon that cowboy bebop.
Scott: he had the entire DVD box set and he said all right so we're gonna do we're gonna go to building was it eight I think.
Scott: and he said we're gonna stay here for two days and we're gonna watch 13 episodes one day and 13 episodes the next day.
Rym: and let me tell God.
Scott: that's what we did.
Rym: there were a lot of people showed up to that and I remember that pretty much for like the last three or four episodes I don't think a single person said a single God damn word.
Scott: no one moved a goddamn muscle.
Rym: like an episode would end.
Rym: everyone just sit there.
Rym: no one would even consider getting up to skip the closer or to say anything or to go to the bathroom.
Rym: it was just we sat there and then the show ended and everyone sat there through the credits.
Scott: credits rolled credits evening menu came on.
Rym: then we started to move around a little bit but even then no one would talk and everyone kind of walked out with just the sense of you know that feeling.
Rym: when you see something really good you almost don't want to break the silence.
Scott: it was that was.
Scott: it's like when you're in a museum and there's that amazing painting or sculpture and you don't talk near it because you'll be disturbing other people trying to experience it.
Rym: it was that kind of thing going on and I mean I've experienced that before and there have been other shows and movies and things.
Rym: they've done that for me but cowboy bebop did it to such an extent and not just at the end but at multiple points throughout the show that I don't know that the the emotional baggage that was thrust into me by certain scenes in cowboy bebop is lives with me to this day.
Scott: all right so there's nothing wrong with cowboy bebop whatsoever.
Scott: it is completely without flaw.
Scott: so let us enumerate the things that it has that are fantastic.
Scott: number one the dub and the original Japanese language are equally awesome.
Scott: seriously the English dub some of the best voice acting ever heard.
Scott: the Japanese some of the best voice acting I've ever heard.
Scott: you can't go wrong.
Scott: you can switch back and forth and you will not even know or care.
Rym: I mean let me put it this way the voice of Spike Spiegel in the English dub was what David Lucas.
Scott: David Lucas slash whatever his name is that he keeps using different names but he's the guy who is also the voice of Rogers Rogers Smith.
Scott: yes the best English voice actor of anime period.
Rym: now at the same time in the Japanese cast and these are all big names but they was played by someone particularly is also the voice actors for Bulbasaur Japanese voice actors for Bulbasaur and Misato and everyone else.
Rym: let me put it this way the cast of cowboy bebop dub and sub were like some of the most high-powered amazing talent and it shows like that is the best English dub ever of an anime.
Rym: I don't think I've ever seen anything that even came close.
Scott: in some of the episodes the English dub is better than the Japanese dub and in some in they in the early episode the Japanese a little better because the voice actors is still sort of the English voice actor is still sort of figuring it out this way.
Rym: the worst voice acting in the English cowboy bebop is in the first episode with one side character that
Scott: you never see again in the next 25 episodes and
Rym: pretty much by the time you hit episode 7 or 8 the voice actors have really gotten into it and there's a scene and there's a scene near the end where a character is talking to other character.
Rym: obviously you know spoilers.
Rym: whatever spoiling cowboy bebop spoiling anything about cowboy bebop is a shitty thing to do.
Rym: yes cowboy bebop is is amazing and if you have not seen cowboy bebop we're not gonna spoil it tonight.
Rym: but for the love of God do not risk having the show ruined for you.
Rym: you need to watch it as soon as possible.
Scott: I'm not I cannot stress that enough and the show has sort of like a hold on you.
Scott: if you start watching and you have more of it available you won't stop unless you really have to do something else.
Scott: yeah I remember we were not.
Rym: we just moved back into RIT after like a summer vacation and we had a box set sitting there for some reason.
Rym: and we just we watched a couple episodes like yeah let's watch some cowboy bebop and then play some.
Rym: and then you know episode 26 ended and school started.
Scott: eight hours later.
Scott: we just watched the last episode.
Rym: but there's a scene near the end and this is some of the best vote where a character is trying to convince another character not to go somewhere and the first the character the first is just start shooting a gun into the air into the ceiling on a ship and that scene and the best acting.
Scott: well that's some of the best acting I've ever heard or seen in my life and you might think oh it's the best acting period simply the best voice acting in an anime.
Rym: well some of that I didn't say the best some of the best that was that was top-notch acting.
Rym: yes I'm not acting for sure and I'm being very evasive but you'll know the scene.
Rym: because I showed cowboy bebop I lent it to someone at my work back when I way back when I worked at IBM.
Rym: we didn't know much about anime what but his kid was into it.
Rym: so I told him to watch cowboy bebop and after he finished he came back to work.
Rym: next came my office and he basically just kept talking about that scene and about how amazing it was.
Rym: now now he seemed like there's this anime and it's amazing and that was like the best thing ever and he couldn't believe and I had to break it to him that that was pretty much the best thing.
Rym: so yeah it's all downhill from there.
Scott: yep all right.
Scott: the next thing that is awesome about cowboy bebop is the animation is awesome.
Scott: it is like made by sunrise here the people who did the Batman's and the big O's and the Gundams.
Scott: I don't see anything wrong in this animation.
Scott: in fact this is from 1998.
Scott: I watched it now on DVD still looks fantastic.
Scott: he could have been made last year and I would have believed you.
Rym: this show was.
Rym: is the character like it is some of the tech.
Rym: the characters are on model perfectly all the time like everything is just perfect.
Scott: every scene every detail every little bit is just right there and a lot and like you watch some like the the action scenes with his fighting and kung fu moves going on and they animated all the kung fu.
Scott: it's like a kung fu movie the kind of motion and energy you get out of the.
Scott: the animation.
Rym: let's get right into that.
Rym: the fights everything that's choreographed in this show is choreographed to a degree that is almost excessive.
Rym: mmm like it is like the first episode is a is a is a pale example but it's a good example of suddenly there's a fight scene where two characters are fighting with each other around a table and like in this outside cantina cafe and that is cool as that is that doesn't even hold a candle to pretty much the rest of the show.
Rym: yeah I need like the the perot episode the fights in that episode.
Scott: bang that's the Batman episode.
Scott: yeah like you've seen Batman the animated series the original good one and then you see that episode.
Scott: you'll know the same people made both these shows.
Scott: there's no question in your mind.
Scott: even someone who knows nothing about our can recognize that.
Rym: but like the ship designs the character designs everything is just amazing.
Scott: yep all right.
Scott: the third thing that is awesome I can't wait bebop is that it has the best music probably of any anime that has ever existed.
Rym: now we're not gonna tell the whole story but yoko kano did the music for cowboy.
Rym: yoko kano is pretty much the best composer for anime and I think that she stands as a great composer independent of anime independent of any soundtrack.
Rym: she's done her symphonic works rival people the people who write symphonic works and nothing but symphonic works for a living.
Rym: and yet she is also capable of doing things that are completely a hundred eighty degrees away from that.
Scott: and not to mention that it is all.
Scott: the music is performed by the seatbelts who would otherwise be unknown without cowboy bebop?
Scott: but instead I have everyone every cowboy beyond v3 there is because they're so fantastic.
Rym: is that all performed by the seatbelt?
Rym: and most of it is but the you know what when you watch the show?
Rym: there's certain stuff like the the walk in the rain song and the real folk blues and even from the movie though I'm not gonna talk about the movie but that's not.
Rym: that's well out of the scope of this but got an ocular.
Rym: there's some good freaking music in that show yeah.
Rym: and also I point out that yoko kano is scored other great amazing anime and her effort in cowboy bebop was up to par with all of those.
Rym: all of those were up to par with cowboy bebop.
Scott: I think I was slightly above all the other.
Rym: I submit that eska flown a has an absolutely amazing sound.
Scott: I didn't say it doesn't.
Scott: I think how everyone's still just better by a little bit.
Scott: well I mean some of the other things she's done have not been as great as cologne a.
Rym: it's because cowboy bebop is more like edgy and catchy and it's more like thematic for the scenes.
Rym: but in eska flown a it's much more symphonic and much more.
Rym: it's a totally different kind of music that she wrote.
Scott: yeah anyway.
Scott: so what else is so awesome a cowboy bebop?
Scott: well perhaps the story and the characters.
Rym: now there's an interesting thing about cowboy bebop because they're basically if you take out certain episodes from the show and there aren't that many of them you can watch the whole show and while characters progress and and and character relationships and all these sorts of things in the world progress the plot doesn't.
Rym: there's no real plot and it's basically just an episodic show.
Rym: you can pick any one episode watch it and in and of itself knowing nothing about the universe knowing nothing about the characters is an enjoyable episode.
Scott: you can watch any one of these episodes yet they're really only episode 5 episodes 12 and 13. or is it 13 or 14?
Scott: I forget there's two episodes in the middle episode 5 and a group of episodes at the end and pretty much none of the episodes really are you know plot?
Scott: it's not a serial plot like a Gundam show where each episode has to be watched in order.
Scott: I mean that helps because you know something will happen to one character in one episode and then they'll bring it up in a future one.
Scott: or they'll teach you something about the universe and then talk about that or make a reference to in a later episode.
Scott: but it's not necessary.
Scott: most of the episodes you can just watch never having seen or know anything about you.
Scott: you just like take episode 20 and just fucking watch it not knowing shit and it'll.
Scott: it'll totally work even if you know nothing now.
Rym: right along those lines one of the greatest strengths of cowboy bebop and again most of my examples I have to avoid mentioning because a lot of what I have to say would involve spoilers.
Rym: but basically cowboy bebop is a character driven show.
Rym: now sometimes people worry about words like that because there's character driven shows and plot driven shows and usually a plot driven show means the characters are bullshit character designs.
Rym: they're just there to have the plot.
Rym: and a character driven show means well there's no setting.
Scott: yeah it's just like as among a time be a character driven show but it's just these people.
Scott: you look at the characters.
Scott: the characters do the same thing every time.
Scott: how we be bots.
Rym: it has a setting that in and of itself could be a show.
Rym: the setting alone is so rich and so detailed and there's so much plot there.
Rym: there there are the plots for three or four solid full season anime in this world that are kind of touched on by cowboy bebop.
Scott: but you know how a lot of a lot of nerdy things like the forgotten realms or or Star Wars or Star Trek right or whatever.
Scott: it's all about setting.
Scott: and you know these nerds.
Scott: they go on and on about the setting in the history of this universe and that they're really big into that.
Scott: it's like the thing they love.
Scott: more than anything is a show or some sort of series of novels or any you know work that really fleshes out a setting in incredible detail from beginning to end as far back into the future and it's as far into the past as they can possibly get you know with everything and that's what they love.
Scott: cowboy bebop simultaneously like makes those people happy and also gives them a giant finger because they make this incredibly incredibly detailed universe that could have this incredibly huge past and incredibly huge future that's super fleshed out.
Scott: but all they do is tell a story about some characters in that universe and they pretty.
Scott: they mostly ignore all that really big continuity kind of stuff that nerds love.
Rym: it's it's just that the story of cowboy bebop is the story of these people.
Rym: it is a story about these five six seven people who grow and change and learn and it's that's it.
Rym: that's what the show is.
Rym: everything else every single thing in this show the plot the whatever is just a conduit for watching these characters evolve and empathizing with them and then finding out how this all comes together with them.
Rym: in the end it there's this.
Rym: there's the kind of background plot there's an instant that happened in the world long time ago.
Scott: it's not really a spoiler because it doesn't matter because the shows about the characters and I want to avoid talking about specifics just anyway because I think it but anyway before the show began there was some sort of explosion of some sort right.
Scott: and then during the show you know there are certain episodes in which use the plot of that one episode only sort of revolves around the results of that thing that happened way before the show started that had nothing to do with these characters and sometimes that it won't even be the plot of the episode.
Scott: it'll just be like a little touch like something that happens in one scene and you know you won't even realize that.
Scott: oh that's because of this thing that happened in the past unless you really pay fucking close attention and it's just ah it's great yep it's.
Rym: the idea is that cowboy bebop is a story about these characters and the mistake that would have ruined cowboy bebop would have been that if these characters were central to like the plot the overarching epic plot of the world and everything going on like the you know the epic we're gonna save the world plot that almost like most anime are about the show is just about these people.
Scott: yeah this is there is a save the world thing going on somewhere.
Scott: maybe it happened already you don't even know.
Scott: but instead you just see these people who happen to be dealing with their own bullshit and then they deal with their own bullshit.
Rym: then it shows over a real good example of that.
Rym: this is such a minor spoiler.
Rym: I think it's worth it.
Rym: just illustrate.
Rym: the point is in the eco-terrorism episode mm-hmm how what the main characters do like oh we're gonna save the world didn't mean Jack.
Rym: the government just fixed it.
Rym: yep think government just did it.
Scott: okay let's let's actually hear the show there.
Scott: the main characters the show our spike badass kung-fu bounty hunter jet X cop bounty hunting partner Faye Valentine a woman with a.
Rym: she's almost like a noir as kind of.
Rym: she's a woman with a mystery in her hit in her past and some sort of dark secret and some debts like a femme fatale.
Scott: yep and she likes to gamble and also be naughty.
Scott: and Ed who sort of does?
Scott: some people don't like it because it doesn't fit but I think it is amazing.
Rym: I think Ed is critical to that show not from a plot perspective but I don't want.
Rym: I can't say why.
Scott: yeah but Ed is a basically a hacker.
Scott: this is young girls.
Scott: was she like you know?
Scott: 10 maybe?
Scott: no really 14 I can't even tell.
Rym: I'd say that ein is just as much of a character - I was gonna get to ein.
Scott: okay and Ed is a hacker who's like the ultimate hacker but she always speaks in rhyme and it's sort of quirky.
Scott: and then you have ein the dog who shows up.
Scott: I think in episode 2 I believe it's just the dog that's on the ship and they're all in this ship the bebop going around bounty hunting.
Scott: you may have their own little fighter ships which are also cool.
Rym: now you might think it's it's and some people have said this that fireflies a little bit like that and I've heard talk that there might have been something fireflies about bounty hunters.
Rym: no it's not.
Rym: but in terms of the idea of a story that just follows people and just like you're in this ship and they're traveling together doing whatever they do and the drama is all from these people's interactions with each other as opposed to the plot of some world well
Scott: it's their interaction with each other and also their inner.
Scott: at each episode is sort of in a way borrows from Galaxy Express 3 9 TV where there's some you know sometimes they'll be at one planet sometimes at another you know because they can fly all over the galaxy or universe.
Scott: who even knows right I guess they go to Ganymede.
Scott: sometimes.
Scott: where's Ganymede?
Scott: is that?
Scott: so I guess it stays within the solar system right but anyway they fly all around hunting bounties you know and each bounty sort of has its own little plot and that's why the show is episodic and some of the plots are really.
Scott: they could make movies out of those plots but instead they put him in a less than 30 minute episode.
Rym: now we talked about you know the characters.
Rym: there's so many like these characters and we gave you a very superficial overview.
Rym: but these characters are three-dimensional to to a degree that is almost like it's almost frightening.
Scott: how much you'll empathize you know I think a lot.
Scott: the reason that that happens in the show so much is because a lot of other shows they will sort of have a big cast and cowboy bebop.
Scott: they might have a in any one episode.
Scott: you'll have plenty of characters but most of them will be just for that one episode and you really only have a very small cast less than ten.
Scott: you know less than five.
Scott: even they get significant screen time.
Scott: it is really only the four when you really think about it.
Scott: cuz ein while he's important is just a dog and he goes woof woof woof right and it's just four.
Scott: so when you've only got four you can you put all your effort into them.
Scott: you can really build it up instead of having to you know sort of spread the peanut butter thin across.
Rym: you know maybe ten but at the same time almost every episode kind of has its own cast.
Rym: like there'll be these characters that are introduced and pretty much all the side characters that are pivotal to an episode or that get screen time or FaceTime or you know speaking line you know their name.
Rym: yeah they're just as fleshed out as the main characters.
Rym: the only thing they lack is enough screen time to see all of it.
Rym: but it's obvious that it's there.
Scott: yeah it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's sort of magical sometimes how they'll bring in a character you've never seen before ever and then suddenly it's like their main character in the show that's been in every episode.
Scott: like they they flush them out.
Scott: so well it's the character design.
Scott: all really fits.
Scott: every character that you know they they make and you know the what they usually will show you that character like they'll give them a scene or two separate from the main characters to sort of you know build them up a bit and then suddenly when the stuff happens you're like ah shit oh man
Rym: slow like water.
Scott: yeah well I guess the best example I think is the full like water.
Rym: again I think an equally important one is grand yeah and even the the duo in the first episode.
Rym: yeah cuz that's them that's a movie by itself.
Rym: actually this is what I want to talk about cuz this is.
Rym: this is like the biggest thing about cowboy bebop and I think we're gonna do a show in the future just about this.
Rym: but episode one the very first episode of cowboy bebop in and of itself is like this masterpiece even beyond a lot of the other episodes just in the sense that it's a movie in and of itself.
Rym: you could take that and make it a movie and it's perfect and it.
Rym: it's less than 30 minutes and it's like this cyclical like I don't want to.
Rym: it's a cycle and it kind of ends where it began and yet it introduces everything you need to know about the show and it's and two of the main characters are in the show yet and it's.
Rym: that episode is absolutely amazing and how it's composed and how it's put together it.
Rym: every single detail is there.
Rym: just everything that happens conveys something.
Rym: there is nothing extraneous in the first episode of cowboy bebop.
Scott: nope and there is the cowboy bebop movie which we're not going to talk about but the movie is a great movie but it's really just a long episode of cowboy bebop.
Scott: yeah pretty much some extended action scenes and whatnot.
Scott: it's sort of like well you finish the show and you want another episode.
Rym: here's another episode and it takes place in the midst of the show.
Rym: so you can just watch the movie if you want.
Rym: it doesn't spoil it.
Scott: yeah if you look online they'll tell you like watch the movie in between this episode and this episode and it'll make sense and like okay sure but man and we're.
Rym: you know we're watching cowboy bebop again because it's hard not to when it's right.
Scott: I bought it for 40 bucks I popped it in and well you're gonna keep fucking watching it.
Rym: I have a lot of trouble not exclaiming periodically about how great the show is when I'm watching it again and just going oh man that oh that.
Rym: I remember that.
Scott: oh yeah and this time I'm watching I'm seeing more in this show than ever seen before.
Scott: there's things that I can't believe I missed in previous watchings.
Rym: yep I mean it's not like utana where you watch the show a hundred times and you still see new things.
Scott: yeah it's not that of a. you know deep there's not heavy you know hard to figure out sort of end of evangelical type stuff going on.
Scott: but there's a lot of symbolism and there's a lot of you know references and coincidences and connections between things and they're not hard to notice.
Scott: they're pretty in your face but you still I don't just didn't notice them all before.
Rym: I don't know what else I could say this show is without just describing the plot or or just peeing all over yourself something like that.
Rym: this show the show will affect you.
Rym: I mean it is hard to not react emotionally not just to the end not just to like but too much of the show and in fact almost every episode almost every episode episode you can get away.
Scott: yes also the mushroom mushroom Samba mushroom Samba shrooms.
Scott: oh that's got to be the third best episode in the show.
Scott: hands down yeah that episode and the chess episode I think is not so good but whatever.
Rym: yeah I mean the thing is the worst episodes of cowboy bebop are amazing.
Rym: yeah the chess episode is better than most other anime and the best episodes will make you react to an emotional level that you might not be comfortable with.
Rym: I mean I talk about how I cry at anime a lot and I I rod.
Rym: you know what I'll say this I cried at a bunch of times throughout cowboy bebop but there were some scenes when it was almost to the point where I couldn't cry.
Rym: that would like.
Rym: crying wouldn't have done it justice.
Scott: yeah what about you gonna talk about how the show originally aired?
Scott: and it's in it?
Scott: they ruined it.
Rym: oh yeah that let me.
Scott: when cowboy bebop had some troubles.
Rym: cowboy bebop was made in like 1998 and they tried to brought ten year old show people ten years on TV Tokyo and the show was edgy for the time too edgy too violent too serious.
Rym: so they actually only showed five episodes which five episode two three seven fifteen and eighteen.
Scott: so like just these random I had it all finished but they only showed five.
Rym: and then it wasn't until 1999 that they showed cowboy bebop in its entirety.
Rym: and even then they showed it on a wah-wah satellite mm-hmm.
Rym: and when it was shown in America too they actually edited a couple took out some of the episodes like the one with teddy bomber the terrorists.
Scott: they take that one out.
Scott: there's another one with the kid.
Scott: yeah it's like that one out.
Rym: yes because the episode ends it with something that is not cool to be shown on American TV.
Rym: nope and they also edited episode 13 yep somewhat heavily and that this show is not.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: my idea is that this show should be promoted and then shown on primetime TV in the u.s.
Rym: and that would push anime to the mainstream.
Scott: this is a show that every human being who is mature enough to understand and watch it will enjoy.
Scott: I've never met anyone who didn't watch this and go oh man is a great.
Scott: unless they were you know didn't understand it or you know something.
Scott: but the vast majority of human beings in Western society will watch this and enjoy it and love it.
Scott: there's more than anything I've ever seen.
Scott: even people who don't like anime have no understand but you can watch.
Scott: have them watch this show and they'll be like oh man's oh man's.
Scott: it's as good as all those shows.
Scott: you're watching HBO that everyone goes nuts over.
Scott: better better better that's for sure.
Scott: yes but I'm talking about you know it's in the same kind of thing and I mean I've shown this to my parents.
Rym: I've shown it to a lot of people who would never watch anime in their life and they love it.
Rym: my dad loved this show.
Rym: yep your dad love it too.
Rym: dads like this show and so do moms moms and dads watching the cowboy bebop.
Rym: I think we should end there because I have to pack for katsu-kan.
Scott: I got to do more laundry.
Rym: but seriously if you have not seen cowboy bebop I watch it.
Rym: it might sound like our Rym.
Rym: and Scott you're just gushing over the show cuz you like it.
Scott: no there's not much else you can do.
Scott: an episode about cowboy you've up except analyze or gush.
Scott: that's really only two options.
Rym: but I feel like I think a lot of people I'm you know I may realize later I may or may not be prone to exaggeration at many points in my life.
Rym: I don't think I've exaggerated at all.
Scott: I don't think you.
Scott: I think you've under exaggerated.
Scott: this show is one didn't exaggerate enough to reach the truth.
Rym: this show is the pinnacle of anime.
Rym: I mean there are great shows that came out after this.
Rym: there are great shows that came out before it but cowboy bebop was the first and only show ever in any medium I've ever seen that had the balls to say openly and straight up in episode I think 13 or 14.
Scott: every episode they have.
Scott: so you know the iCatch you know the thing that they show and then there's a commercial and then they show the iCatch again in episode 13 or 14.
Scott: I forget which one it's.
Scott: it's either part 1 or part 2 of Jupiter jazz.
Scott: right they show.
Scott: the iCatch says right on it in English even though it's a Japanese show.
Scott: in English in the iCatch they write the show that what will for create a new genre shall hereby be known as cowboy or something like that something like that and it's they had the balls.
Rym: I mean think about it.
Rym: if you see a show two shows like yeah we created a new genre.
Rym: yeah that that's immediately sets off the bullshit pretension.
Rym: detect.
Scott: it's like wow you know way to.
Scott: it's like saying I am so great but that's beyond saying I am so great.
Scott: that's like saying it's like if I went up and I said yeah I'm a better radio guy than Howard Stern time.
Rym: no that's like.
Rym: I have changed radio.
Rym: radio is now a different thing because of me.
Scott: yes you know what it's like.
Scott: say it's like putting yourself on the artistic level is like Michelangelo like sculpture and painting are different because of me.
Scott: the world is different because of this thing.
Scott: one work of art that I have created is that great and you know what.
Rym: I can find no fault with cowboy bebop saying that.
Scott: now they said it and they they put it right there and you read it and you go yep you did way to know way to know what you did because most people don't like you.
Scott: did Michelangelo?
Scott: did he really know how awesome he was?
Rym: did he really?
Rym: I think DaVinci knew how awesome he was.
Scott: DaVinci's different story but yeah it's very rare that someone is awesome knows how awesome they are whips out their balls rubs them in your face and says look how awesome I am.
Scott: and you say yep your balls sure are awesome.
Rym: I cannot deny give me more so but cowboy bebop the pinnacle the peak of anime I I look forward I'm sure.
Rym: I hope that at some point in my life someone makes a show to like it that I can honestly say is better than cowboy be.
Scott: really if I was making anime I basically have those same people try to make more shows and I mean that you should eat sugar Watanabe who's director made Samurai Champloo.
Scott: also.
Rym: Samurai Champloo is awesome.
Scott: it tried but anyways it was but it wasn't as good as cowboy bop but he was still awesome.
Rym: yeah but I don't.
Rym: I just someday I'd like to be able to say wow that show was better than cowboy bebop and with the exception of maybe five or six shows that came close.
Rym: nothing's even been in the same ballpark not even close I mean.
Scott: if I was making anime I'd have a really hard time because anything they put in front of me I'd watch it and I say was that as good as cowboy bop?
Scott: and if it wasn't I wouldn't let him put it out.
Scott: I would just keep making him work until they made something better and it would probably sit there until they died making no money.
Scott: all right.
Rym: so on that note we will hopefully see many of you at Katsucon and right now I'm going to pack up the GeekNights road kit and put it in Scott's car.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays we have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: you can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at www.frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.