Rym: It's Wednesday, April 9th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, kind of a cop-out.
Rym: We talk a bit about newspaper comics, but mostly we argue about whether or not Opus was a puffin or a penguin or a platypus.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So as you all know, Otakon's artist alley sold out immediately as it always does and...
Scott: Well, I wonder, I mean way back in the day, right?
Scott: It must have not sold out right away, right?
Scott: I wonder what the first Otakon where it sold out that quickly was.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I mean in 2000, did it sell out that quickly?
Rym: All I know is the last three or four years.
Rym: it's been pretty hard to get a table.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: But the front row crew was together with it and I'm gonna save the details for later, but it's very likely that the front row crew and affiliated artists may be taking up almost an entire island.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: And the thing is it's not like, "Oh, it's Geek
Rym: Nights.".
Rym: It's pretty much all the artists who are friends with us or who work with us.
Scott: Yeah, it's gonna be, there's gonna be like a whole front row crew section so we can turn it into like a party zone or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We should...
Rym: And Dave and Joel, because Dave Riley was like, "Man, I totally didn't get a
Rym: table.".
Rym: And I was like, "Yeah, you want one?
Rym: We got an extra
Rym: one.".
Scott: Yeah, we had a couple extra.
Scott: We might dump one of the tables.
Scott: We might...
Rym: We already dumped one.
Scott: Oh, we got to bring, we got, we have I think still a spare table though.
Scott: We got to bring in somebody.
Rym: Well, we're working on that.
Rym: I have a use for that table regardless.
Rym: But anyway, I got a very interesting email from Oticon.
Rym: This wasn't sent to me.
Rym: It was sent to everyone.
Scott: Well, everyone who?
Rym: Everyone who signed up for a table.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: It is as far... Actually, oh, I just realized that they made a slight mistake and I have a list of everyone who they sent it to.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: But anyway, that happens a lot to a lot of people.
Rym: I can't complain about it.
Scott: Learn to use emails.
Rym: "Hello.
Rym: We were just sending out a reminder to everyone about sending payments since there has been some confusion regarding forms of payment.
Rym: Only payment in the form of certified cashier's check, money order or postal money order made payable to Otocorp Incorporated will be accepted.
Rym: Do not send cash or personal
Rym: checks.".
Rym: Now, this was quite clear.
Scott: Do you want to teach all the listeners about certified checks, money orders and postal money order?
Scott: All
Rym: I want to say is that I didn't even think about this problem, but in retrospect, and I don't blame Otocorp for not thinking about this problem either, but it's a smart move on their part because checks are not the most reliable form of paying for things and they're also a gigantic pain.
Rym: If you got a million of them, you got to cash them all.
Scott: Yeah, a personal check is, you know, someone could just, you know, bounce it.
Scott: You know, you might not get the money and then it's...
Rym: Well, you can charge, you can get the money.
Rym: It's more...
Scott: But it's a pain in the ass.
Rym: Yeah, it's more an issue that cashing all those checks is usually long delays and all sorts of problems.
Rym: So instead, they required, you know, a money order, a certified check.
Scott: And using a credit card or something like that, there's problems with that, too.
Scott: You got to pay the fees, the processing fees, or you got to, if you want to use PayPal, you got to pay PayPal fees.
Rym: But anyway, it was a very smart move on Otocorp's part to accept only these forms of payment because then only people who are serious about having a table will get one.
Rym: But the problem here that I did not really anticipate was that I imagine the majority of the people who signed up for a table have never heard of any of these things, because many times in my life I have been asked by someone at some point, what do you mean a money order?
Rym: Most people, especially younger people, don't seem to know about certified checks or money orders.
Scott: So let me teach you about certified checks and money orders.
Scott: OK, a certified check, when you write a personal check, right, you know, if you check book, what that does is you give it to someone and then when they take it to their bank, their bank tries to get money from your bank.
Scott: And you can write a check.
Scott: I could write a check for a million dollars and give it to him.
Scott: And he can be like, OK, but if he won't find out that it's a bad check until he takes it to his bank, what you can do is you can go to your own bank.
Scott: I could go to my bank and say, I need a certified check for a million dollars.
Rym: Most banks will do it for free.
Scott: It's free.
Scott: If you have an account, you need an account.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they will look at my account and say, oh, there's a million dollars.
Scott: I will give you the certified check.
Scott: If there isn't a million dollars, they won't give me a certified check.
Scott: so you can give someone a certified check.
Scott: And basically that means it has a stamp.
Scott: It's like the seal of approval.
Scott: Yes, Scott has this much money in his bank account, so it's guaranteed not to bounce.
Rym: Now, there's also a cashier's check, but that's not quite the same thing.
Rym: It's not as reliable.
Rym: In fact, there were a lot of scams in the 90s involving cashier's check.
Scott: Now, a money order, a postal money order is the most convenient kind, as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: I'm not a big fan of the other kinds, but basically a postal money order.
Scott: You go to the post office.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And let's say I want a mail Rym.
Scott: Thirty dollars.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I go and I say I would like a postal money order for thirty dollars.
Scott: I give the post office thirty dollars plus, you know, a fee.
Rym: Cash only.
Rym: They will not accept anything but cash.
Scott: I think you can do the...
Rym: No, you can't.
Rym: Most definitely not.
Rym: That's always, always been that way.
Rym: That's the point of a money order.
Rym: It's as good as cash.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I give, you know, the bank thirty dollars plus a fee.
Scott: Then they give me this money order and they print on it, you know, thirty dollars.
Scott: And then I write like Rym's address and my name and address and you fill out these little forms.
Scott: And then that little piece of paper or whatever goes and gets mailed to Rym.
Rym: Well, no, most often they give you it like a check and then you do whatever you want with it.
Scott: Well, usually mail it right there, because that's the point of a postal money order is to mail it to somebody.
Rym: Most people I've seen, they tend to get a money order and then use it like a check.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: In fact, most money orders, if you go to a post office and ask for a money order, they don't ask or care who it's for.
Rym: They give you a blank money order that's certified for the amount of money.
Scott: Every time I bought a postal money order is to mail it.
Rym: So, yeah, but I'm saying they don't.
Rym: they usually don't care who you're writing it to.
Scott: No, they don't care at all.
Rym: But, you know, you it's just a check that is backed by the post office.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Scott: It's all technically is.
Scott: But usually you mail it.
Rym: Anyway, it doesn't matter.
Rym: The point is that a lot of anime fans, I don't think, understood this.
Rym: And I am sure that a lot of punk kids sent Otakon cash in the mail and or personal checks.
Rym: And this reminder is a nice little, hey, kids, just so you know, go to the post office or your bank.
Rym: But, yeah, we'll have some announcements about the front row crew things going on in the artist alley.
Rym: We're pretty much going to set up a blog website for all the artists.
Rym: And you're going to get to see kind of previews of what's going on and all the people and all the artists who are going to be there.
Scott: We're going to try to hype it up like an event.
Rym: I think you're really going to like what all of our artist friends have to offer.
Scott: Yeah, artist friends, don't drop the ball.
Rym: Doesn't matter.
Rym: They have to pay for the tables anyway.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: I know.
Scott: But I don't want to show up with like you like two pictures.
Rym: I don't think that's going to happen.
Scott: I don't think it's going to happen either.
Scott: But, you know, if you if you don't prod the cattle, it doesn't move.
Scott: And if it isn't going to move, but it's not moving right now, prodding it makes it move faster.
Rym: I think they're all excited about it.
Scott: They they're all excited.
Scott: But, you know, once I forced everyone to laziness happens, it has happened before.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: OK, so you have a news.
Scott: Oh, you want me to do my news?
Rym: Yeah, sure.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Well, I don't really have a news because I looked at the news and mostly the only real news we have is what's going down at the New York Comic-Con in a couple of weeks and events near it and related to it.
Scott: And I'll leave that to Rym exactly how much we should reveal and with what timing.
Scott: Other than that, most of the anime comic news is sort of I think they're keeping it real quiet because they're going to bust out like crazy at the Comic-Con.
Scott: So it's sort of like they're holding back all the cars and then they're going to reveal them all at once.
Scott: So last was it last week?
Scott: I think I introduced Scott's box.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I'm reading stuff.
Rym: I don't care.
Rym: Oh, come on.
Rym: I don't read any of the things you get.
Rym: And you just did the box.
Rym: I really don't care about you doing it again right now.
Scott: Well, the thing is, is I did Scott's box like last week, I think.
Scott: And it actually a lot of people emailed me and they liked it.
Scott: And I was quite surprised that, you know, something that was basically a throwaway idea was basically like, oh, people care.
Scott: The question is, right.
Scott: What I did last week was I talked about the comics I just got in the mail.
Scott: Now, the problem with that is it's kind of like, OK, these some of them are a little stale, like they came out maybe a month ago even.
Scott: So I was trying to figure out.
Scott: I ask people, you know, should I talk about ones that I just got that might be a little stale or should I talk about the ones I'm ordering right now and I'm going to get in the future?
Rym: Now, I'll admit straight up, I pretty much feel one hundred percent that it should be the former, because at least then you can actually talk about and kind of review all the things you got.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Meanwhile, now it's not know what none of our listeners, maybe one or two percent are going to actually do the preorder thing like you do.
Scott: Well, you don't have to do the preorder thing, right?
Scott: You can do is because a lot of the books that I order specifically, like most comic book stores will not have them, you know, because like they're they don't.
Scott: I think they're going to sell them their weird books and things.
Scott: So what you have to do is if you want a lot of these books, the only way to get them is to either preorder them or go to a comic book store and specifically tell them this is a book.
Scott: I want it.
Scott: You will get it for me.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But at the same time, without having any sort of editorial or review standpoint, it feels like it's almost useless.
Scott: But anyway, I decided to see what the people say.
Scott: I'm going to see what the people say.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So I'm going to do.
Scott: I'm going to tell you what I'm ordering in the month of April, most of which is shipping in the month of June.
Scott: And then I want people to email me and go to the forums and such.
Scott: And maybe I'll set up a poll in the forum that's like, should Scott's box be, you know, stuff that already came in the mail, stuff that I'm ordering or just forget Scott's box.
Scott: So here's what I'm ordering in the month of April, ordering Black Magic second edition.
Scott: This is like the only Masamune Shiro manga I don't have.
Scott: So that's going to pretty much seal the deal.
Scott: Rym, you wanted that Amano tale of Genji hardcover.
Rym: Actually, I wanted all those Amano things, but I'm only going to get one because I can only have so much Amano in my life.
Scott: It's basically a big, fancy Amano illustrated novel.
Scott: Like it's not a comic so much as it's super fancy pictures with text next to them.
Rym: If you don't know who that is, look at like the art, the not the art from the game so much, but like the cover art from Final Fantasy four, like that sort of thing.
Scott: Or play Final Fantasy six and push go to the status menu and look at the characters faces.
Rym: It's that sort of art.
Rym: I really, really dig that art style.
Scott: Yoshitaka Amano.
Scott: Anyway, I'm getting rain in hell number one, only because it's eighty seven cents.
Scott: I'm getting it.
Rym: That's a ringing endorsement right there.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: I'm getting something called New York for.
Scott: I'm going to read this.
Scott: And Emily, this is like Emily's favorite comic, at least I'm guessing.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: OK, it's written by Brian Wood.
Scott: That's the.
Scott: I think he's the DMZ guy.
Rym: You sure?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: OK, Brian was the DMZ guy.
Scott: Ready?
Scott: Here is the advertising text for this book here.
Scott: Just starting your freshman year at NYU.
Scott: Riley is about to find out what an adventure and a mystery living in New York City could be.
Scott: The ultimate insider's guide to New York City is seen through the eyes of Brooklyn born Riley raised by stuffy literati parents.
Scott: Riley's a shy, straight A student who convinces three other NYU brainiacs to join a research group for fast cash.
Scott: What Riley doesn't bank on is accidentally falling in love with Arty, older sister's boyfriend, advanced solicited son, son, son.
Scott: Ten bucks.
Scott: Of course, I don't have to pay ten bucks.
Scott: I have to pay much less.
Scott: OK, let's see, DMZ volume five.
Rym: Speaking of Brian Wood, I'll admit I kind of liked DMZ, but it the suspension of disbelief as to the fact that that is where the battle lines were drawn is just too much.
Scott: I know that is hard for me to swallow.
Scott: And volume three, I was actually getting a little sour.
Scott: But when I read volume three, I heard already you ordered four and volume four did a lot to reinvigorate my DMZ interest.
Rym: Yeah, it's tough for me to get reinvigorated.
Rym: I mean, Walking Dead, I pretty much just dropped completely.
Rym: I can't imagine anything that would get me back into that.
Scott: No, but volume four, like volume three, DMZ was like.
Scott: volume four was like, oh, right.
Scott: That's why I like this.
Scott: tales from the Starlight drive in.
Scott: I'm buying this because it's sort of like a cool combination of like smaller stories all revolving around this drive in.
Scott: And, you know, they got the cool stuff going on with like what's on the screen versus the, you know, the people in the drive in.
Scott: And then there's supposed to be a twist ending, whatever.
Scott: We'll see that.
Scott: We'll figure it out.
Scott: Killing Girl.
Scott: This is a comic.
Scott: The art was drawn by the Rocketo guy, Frank Espinosa.
Scott: So I buy it automatically pretty much that guy.
Scott: Yeah, of course, he didn't draw the art for all the issues.
Scott: He only drew the art for the first few and then someone else took over.
Scott: But whatever.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Scud, the disposable assassin, the whole shebang.
Scott: The reason I'm buying this is because it's supposed to be really funny and it's like eight hundred pages.
Scott: And I'm paying fourteen ninety nine.
Scott: So it's like the whole series in one book.
Scott: It's like unbelievable.
Scott: Sky doll number two of three.
Scott: This is actually really weird because this is like a French comic about a robot that Marvel's publishing.
Scott: And I'm like, holy shit, holy shit.
Scott: Marvel's publishing like a French comic in English.
Scott: So like, yeah, I'll buy three issues, you know, to show you that.
Scott: yes, this is a good idea.
Scott: Marvel Comics presents number 10 because I always get that.
Scott: Eternals by Neil Gaiman because it says Neil Gaiman.
Scott: And it's something old that he did, but I think it's a new printing and I've never read it.
Scott: Contract number zero because it's thirteen cents ringing endorsements all around.
Scott: Thirteen cents.
Rym: Oh, I know that a lot of times after Scott gets his box, there's a very large pile next to his bed of comics that were worthless.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Mouse guard eleven fifty two.
Scott: Number five.
Rym: Oh, man.
Scott: The weasel sanctuary can't go wrong with mouse guard.
Scott: That's five of six.
Scott: So the one after that's going to be the end of chapter two.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: I like me some mouse guard.
Scott: Rabbi Harvey rides again.
Scott: I got the first Rabbi Harvey and it's pretty funny.
Scott: It's like this rabbi in the Old West telling the Proverbs and like, you know, sort of doing the King Solomon thing.
Rym: You know, there were no Jewish cowboys.
Scott: I know until Rabbi Harvey.
Scott: It's also funny because my dad's name is Harvey.
Scott: So it's kind of funny to show to your dad.
Scott: Yeah, he liked it.
Scott: That was funny.
Scott: But yeah, I'll get Rabbi Harvey the sequel.
Scott: Robot volume six.
Scott: Robot is the is.
Scott: basically it's a giant, awesome manga art book.
Scott: Like it's huge.
Scott: It's full color on super shiny paper.
Scott: And you've got like Yoshitoshi Abe and what's his name?
Scott: That's the lane guy.
Scott: And you've got Rangemorata, the last exile guy and a whole bunch of other people in there.
Scott: And it's like the awesomest art from Japanese manga people in super full color.
Scott: And yeah, I'll keep getting it as long as they keep putting it out.
Scott: And the last thing on my list, Tezuka's Dororo volume two vertical.
Scott: Tezuka can't go wrong.
Rym: Pretty much a slam dunk.
Scott: That's the more than a slam dunk.
Scott: That's like a magnetic three pointer.
Scott: I don't know, three pointers that can't miss magnetic, eh?
Rym: Yeah, just stick to the Rym.
Scott: Well, yeah, that counts.
Rym: No, it doesn't.
Rym: It has to go through.
Rym: If it just sticks to the Rym, it doesn't count.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Point is, there's no way.
Scott: I'm not.
Scott: if that had to if I had to order only one thing on this list, I would take that one.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: So is that Scott's box?
Scott: That's Scott's future box.
Scott: Scott's box to be box to be.
Scott: So tell me if you want to hear more.
Scott: I'm only doing one or the other.
Scott: We're not going to be like doing this every week.
Scott: It's going to be a once a month deal.
Scott: It's either going to be Scott's box to be or Scott's box.
Scott: He just got that.
Scott: Those are your choices.
Rym: I still lean toward the box.
Rym: that has already been.
Scott: I'm a little.
Scott: I'm leaning towards that, too, you know, because like most of these things will arrive two months from now, but some of them will not.
Scott: And, you know, there's also some things I ordered in the past, you know, possibly a long time ago that are going to show up like next month, you know, I just think about it.
Rym: And we either have, well, this was crap.
Rym: This was awesome.
Rym: This was crap.
Rym: Or we have, well, this is only 13 cents.
Rym: Yes, it's only 80.
Scott: The only the the main thing in favor of doing box to be is it helps people purchase things because the way the comic market works, you really have to buy things sort of in advance.
Scott: So like know what's coming out or else you're going to miss out on a lot of things and there's nothing you can do about it.
Rym: Yeah, but luckily, a lot of those like the things that are really great, usually you'll be able to get usually, but not all the time, which is what said, yeah, not all the time, but better.
Rym: You have better odds.
Scott: if it's like that Skydoll, even though it's published by Marvel, most comic shops won't have that and there'll be no way to get it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You might be able to find it, though.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Maybe if you live in like Manhattan, you'll probably be able to find it.
Scott: But like that give you that Dragon's Den might have it because they're kind of a cool comic shop.
Scott: But average comic shop, no way.
Scott: You're never going to see that book in your life, you know, and a lot of the trade paperbacks you'll be able to get an Amazon.
Scott: But, you know, some of the weirder ones, you know, maybe not like Rabbi Harvey.
Scott: Good luck finding that.
Rym: But anyway, I got it real quick.
Rym: I just want to point out that the a trailer was posted for Studio 4C's Genius Party Beyond, which is kind of like.
Scott: I didn't even see Genius Party.
Rym: Genius Party Beyond apparently includes things that were weren't in Genius Party but were made for it.
Rym: And the trailer.
Scott: basically they made too much and they couldn't fit it all in the trailer.
Rym: Looks pretty bad ass.
Rym: I'm going to wait until it actually comes out.
Rym: We'll probably do all the show on just Genius Party as a unit, both of them at once.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But we got it.
Scott: Haven't you seen the first one?
Rym: But in much more pressing news, originally, Scott and I were not going to be attending the New York Comic-Con.
Rym: We had too much to do.
Rym: But I on a lark applied for a press pass because there's a lot of industry people there.
Rym: I kind of want to talk to you and there's a lot of industry events there.
Rym: I kind of want to cover.
Rym: And we were given press passes.
Rym: All right.
Rym: And then, you know, we have our friends at Tokyo FM.
Rym: I mean, we were interviewed for Japanese radio a while ago.
Rym: And there's a tiny blurb about us along with our picture in their little magazine.
Rym: But they are going to be interviewing TM Revolution pretty much twice at the New York Comic-Con.
Rym: First at the New York Comic-Con.
Rym: I think Brian Nishi, who was kind of awesome in his own right.
Rym: We actually met the dude and we'll talk about him another time.
Rym: But he's he's pretty cool.
Rym: I'll say that.
Rym: But basically, there's going to be kind of an interview with them and a panel at the convention.
Rym: But more importantly, after the convention on Sunday at Kinokuniya Bookstore, we're going to.
Scott: Is it still sort of during the convention hours?
Rym: Technically, I didn't even look at what the convention hours are.
Rym: It's like near the end of the day on Sunday.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: There is going to be like if you went to the convention for more than just Sunday, you're not going to need to be there at that time.
Rym: But because it's not in the convention, if you're in Manhattan, you can just drop by.
Rym: But at Kinokuniya, TMR is going to be there and we're going to be taking part in a somewhat interesting sounding, I mean, awesomely interesting sounding interview with him.
Rym: All right.
Scott: I'm looking at the convention schedule.
Scott: The last event on Sunday ends at a quarter to five.
Scott: And that's the most of the events, though, end at like four.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So we're going to have the exact schedule with all this.
Rym: But stay tuned for the news with us and TMR.
Rym: Now, actually, there was an interview posted with TMR from the kind of the pre New York Comic-Con.
Rym: So we're going to make sure we don't ask any of the questions that were already asked in that one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know exactly how many questions we're going to ask, but, you know, we'll add some.
Rym: Yeah, we're still working out the details.
Rym: That's why I'm being kind of cagey about it.
Rym: But we'll have some exact schedules for you.
Rym: And as a result, too, we're going to be at the New York Comic-Con in some capacity, pretty much all three days.
Rym: But if you want to see us, email us or let us know, because we won't have a table or anything.
Rym: We're actually going to be interviewing people and doing press stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Mostly I'm going to be just walking around sort of networking, trying to get interviews, maybe videos, photos, you know, with the new camera stuff.
Rym: I've been posting in the forum talking to people I know as I get tentative approval for the interviews I plan to do.
Rym: So if you're interested in, say, the creators of Avatar and maybe I'm thinking about trying to get an interview with Neil Adams.
Scott: That's going to be fun.
Rym: That would be interesting.
Rym: I'll ask him mostly about Batman, I guess.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And not other things.
Rym: But yeah, we're going to be there in a kind of press capacity, which is going to be weird because usually we're primarily entertainers or guests and then kind of secondarily to that we're press.
Rym: But this time we're just press.
Rym: All we're doing is covering it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you got to take off.
Scott: We got to stop trying to be Penny Arcade and try to be like Engadget instead.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So if I go to a panel, I can't clap.
Rym: I have to sit there and be objective.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's how it's got to be.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day, we're trying to move along a little bit because I'm a little tired.
Rym: I got a lot of work to do.
Rym: Katsu's over and I kind of want to get some pizza or something.
Rym: But, you know, my theme week is continuing.
Rym: It is those were the days a week.
Rym: My things of the day are all related and that they all relate to the classic song Those Were the Days.
Scott: Hey, everyone, when you make your Scott's Box comments, tell me if you like Rims Theme Week.
Scott: I haven't seen a single feedback.
Rym: About Rims Theme Week, because I haven't really asked for it.
Rym: It seems like no one ever sends us feedback unless we ask.
Scott: The reason for that is because like other podcasts, like when they play people's voicemails on the show and they read emails on the show.
Scott: And that really people love it when their emails are read on the show.
Rym: But the thing is, I found that I don't like listening to other people's emails.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But people love even if it's like not their email, like if they sent in an email and you start reading email, even if you never read their email, they'll sit there and suspense like hoping that you read their email the whole time.
Scott: And if you actually do, they'd be like, but it's weird.
Rym: Like I asked for feedback on the ITCS and I got two sets of responses.
Rym: One set said, yeah, it's way over my head and super boring.
Rym: Stop it.
Rym: And the other half were it's way too shallow.
Rym: You need to be a lot more technical.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I don't know what to do about that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The thing is, the one guy was like, I'm really into CS and
Rym: I.T.,
Rym: but I find them boring.
Scott: So I'm curious how the thing is, people keep asking the same questions about like college and what major to go to.
Rym: And they keep asking questions to like they want shows like how do you set up an Apache server?
Scott: That's more will make those things as videos, not as podcasts.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: First, you type app to get install space Apache.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Those are things Google can tell you.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But anyway, enough about that.
Scott: The point is, is that if we did we read emails and put feedback in the show, that would encourage more feedback.
Rym: But yet none of you want to hear the feedback.
Rym: So we're not going to do that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, you know, your motive is if you want GeekNights to be better for you, tell us what you want.
Rym: If you tell us something and no one else does, we'll probably do what you want.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, think about it.
Scott: If you're the only one who sends in a feedback, let's say only one person emails me about Scott's box, you know, even though enough people have already said you should only talk about Superman comics that you buy through the box, then guess what's going to happen?
Rym: Scott's not going to talk about the box anymore because he's probably never going to buy a Superman comic.
Scott: And I buy a Superman comic like once a year.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: What was the last Superman comic you bought or read?
Scott: I bought that crisis in Infinite Earths, which has Superman in it.
Scott: Wait, I bought that Green Lantern.
Rym: God, that Green Lantern was one of the dumber things I've ever read.
Scott: It was pretty dumb.
Scott: It wasn't.
Scott: But I've read some really dumb things.
Rym: So I think that's the line because I actually read it.
Rym: But what was that other thing you gave me?
Rym: Shazam or something?
Scott: Shazam or Captain Marvel, the life and death of Captain Marvel.
Rym: Yeah, I couldn't even get through that.
Scott: You should.
Scott: Mostly the good part is the graphic novel at the end.
Rym: Yeah, but without context, that didn't do anything for me.
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: Because, yeah, anyway.
Rym: Anyway, so this is the second time I've done a theme.
Rym: We like this before I did.
Rym: the Hitler was born to be alive, boring, which actually got a lot of feedback.
Rym: People seem to really like that one.
Rym: But here we go.
Rym: This is a cover of the song.
Rym: Those were the days as performed by the Hermes House Band.
Scott: Does that have anything to do with the...
Rym: Hey, man, it is Hermes.
Rym: No, the Limbo Wing Futurama character?
Rym: Nothing at all.
Scott: Does it have anything to do with the God?
Rym: No, the Hermes House Band runs really fast.
Rym: I really like them.
Rym: They are a college band, like formed by a bunch of friends.
Rym: They're Dutch and they pretty much for as far as I've ever seen, just cover popular good songs in a pretty straightforward, similar way to the way they cover everything.
Rym: And pursuant to that, they make music videos.
Rym: Their music videos are just fun is the only way I can describe it.
Rym: And the one I'm looking to in particular for those were the days is very, I don't know, Moulin Rouge in terms of the way it's kind of put together.
Rym: And I don't know, I'm a sucker for that kind of work and that kind of thing.
Rym: I like the Hermes House Band.
Rym: I like this music video.
Rym: I like this song and I think it's cool.
Rym: Of course, this is only the penultimate.
Rym: Those were the days because tomorrow you will get the epicness, the ultimate.
Rym: pretty much tomorrow is the reason I did this week.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Ultimate follows penultimate.
Scott: So, Rym, how do you feel about X-Men's?
Rym: The only X-Men I ever enjoyed ever was the cartoon and kind of the crappy board game.
Scott: And I have sent you a link to an image.
Scott: Don't click on it quite yet.
Rym: OK.
Scott: And Rym hasn't seen this image.
Scott: This is an image that was made by some graphic designer guy in California named Eric Tan, or at least his blog says his name is Eric Tan.
Scott: Now, I sent Rym the link to the image.
Scott: I'm actually for the thing of the day.
Scott: I'm going to link to the blog post.
Scott: This is an image.
Scott: I think he was paid to make this.
Scott: Now, look at that image.
Scott: Look at it.
Rym: OK, I can look at it now.
Scott: Yeah, you can look at it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: If the X-Men looked like that, I would be a fan of the X-Men like you could never imagine.
Scott: That is the greatest X-Men image I have seen that is up there in my entire life.
Rym: That is right there with the representation of Superman in Batman The Dark Knight Returns.
Scott: Oh, I think it's better.
Rym: That is that is so exactly what the X-Men should be.
Scott: That is the it every.
Scott: there should be one Marvel comic called X-Men.
Scott: All other X comics should be disintegrated and canceled.
Scott: And it should look like this drawn by Eric Tan.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And I want a poster of this.
Rym: I want this to be a poster like all the comments on the thread are like, OMG, make prints.
Scott: OMG, make prints.
Scott: I'll give you money.
Rym: I would get like a door size poster.
Scott: I want this poster.
Scott: frowny face.
Scott: Are you still sleeping?
Scott: Question mark.
Scott: This is a great poster.
Scott: How can I purchase one?
Scott: This is like the greatest image of X-Men I've seen in my entire life.
Scott: And I want it.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Rym: That's a pretty good thing of the day.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's just a picture.
Scott: I always feel bad using just a picture as a thing of the day.
Scott: But when it's a picture, this great.
Scott: There's no way.
Rym: I think the best part of it, aside from the sentinels lined up in the background in that awesome, awesome way.
Rym: And every other part of it is the slanty shoulders on my man in the front on the beast.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Yeah, I like.
Rym: I like shoulders.
Rym: Do it.
Scott: I like the slanty shoulders on the beast.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I like the like the Iceman making a swoosh, but the angel making a straight line through the swoosh and they form an X. Yeah.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And then you got the giant Cyclops head on the right.
Scott: That's good stuff.
Rym: Oh, man.
Scott: You got the Kirby Crackle on Jean Grey's hand.
Scott: You got the little lightnings coming from Storm.
Scott: It's it's all good.
Rym: All right.
Rym: But anyway, we had trouble coming up with the show to do tonight, partly because I've watched a ton of anime and Scott hasn't watched any.
Rym: But yet Scott's read some comics and I haven't read any.
Scott: Meanwhile, we did anime the past two weeks.
Scott: It's comics time.
Scott: I'm ahead now.
Rym: So what comic should I read?
Rym: I think more of our listeners are anime fans than comic fans by far.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Rym: If I gave you that fell comic, because I've noticed whenever we talk about anime, a lot of people like, oh, my God, whenever we talk about comics, a few usually the same people go, oh, my God, are you saying we should get rid of the comics?
Rym: No, I'm just curious if you people, you know, a lot of response on Scott's box.
Rym: Yeah, you did.
Rym: But there's also manga and stuff in there.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: We should do a manga.
Scott: That's you're right.
Scott: We haven't done a manga in a while.
Rym: So, yeah, but I haven't read any manga.
Scott: I'll give you a manga to read.
Rym: I don't have time for that.
Rym: I'm watching Avatar.
Rym: Well, and and Bakano and Kazu no Yojimbo.
Scott: Well, what are you going to do?
Rym: Watch those shows.
Rym: Speaking of which, you should finish watching Kazu no Yojimbo so I can get the second goddamn DVD of it.
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: what's my hurry?
Rym: That is my hurry.
Rym: I want to see it.
Rym: I like that show.
Scott: I'm not big on the watching lately.
Scott: I'm big on the reading.
Scott: And also, you know, I've been doing more coding lately.
Scott: And, you know, I mean, coding, if I'm making software that can consume absolutely all of my free time, if I desire it, I could put absolutely everything on hold.
Rym: Don't forget, we've also got the camera now.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But until I get a newer computer, that's and I get to edit any videos.
Rym: So this will probably be short because there's not a lot to say.
Scott: But, well, I think there is quite a bit to say, but I don't think we have time to say it all.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or nor do we have the research and knowledge to back it up.
Rym: We'll try to talk about this again.
Rym: But this will be kind of the first show of a someday to be completed series on newspaper comics.
Rym: Now, we'll do another show on this.
Rym: I'm almost sure.
Scott: Basically, the deal is, right?
Scott: News comics in the newspaper are way older than comic books.
Scott: I mean, you open up your like, you know, social studies textbook and they got political cartoons about Teddy Roosevelt in there.
Scott: You know, that's a newspaper comic right there.
Rym: Scott, when was the yellow kid?
Scott: Anyway, the yellow kid was not until like the after Teddy Roosevelt.
Rym: Because that's widely considered to be the first actual comic.
Scott: Well, the yellow kid, first of all, was a newspaper comic.
Scott: That's why it was yellow journalism.
Scott: But actually, the yellow kid was the first.
Scott: It's not it's.
Scott: there were comics before the yellow kid.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But they weren't sequential art.
Scott: They were like, you know, they might have been a series of pictures, but there wasn't a sequence, you see, but the yellow kid wasn't sequential.
Rym: Usually.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The first there was the first.
Scott: the very first yellow kid was sequential art.
Scott: I'll show you later.
Rym: Yeah, but usually it wasn't.
Scott: No, it wasn't always.
Scott: No, but the first like comic books were much later.
Scott: We're talking like last century as opposed to two centuries ago.
Scott: I mean, the yellow kid, we're talking like 1890 something.
Scott: But it was like a decade or two before you had a comic book.
Scott: You know, in the first comic books were just newspaper strips collected together, sort of like when you go to the store and you buy complete Calvin and Hobbes.
Scott: That's the first comic books were like.
Scott: it took it took even longer than that for them to actually make original like comic books.
Scott: So there was a story meant for the comic book, you know, and such.
Scott: so newspaper comics.
Scott: strips, you know, have been around for a super long time.
Scott: And even the first web comics were strips as opposed to, you know, big pages.
Scott: You know, there are pages now, you know, webcomics that do it like that.
Scott: But, you know, even most webcomics are just the strip format.
Scott: Penny Arcade is a strip.
Scott: Boasis is a strip.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So let's talk about them strips.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So are there?
Scott: I know pretty much hates most strips.
Scott: And, you know, if you're reading the ones that come out today in the newspaper today, there is a very good reason for that.
Rym: I haven't seen a newspaper comic worth reading pretty much since I left high school.
Rym: And even then, I only read the newspaper comics because that was what I looked at in the morning while I was eating breakfast.
Rym: Yeah, I know that.
Rym: Even then, I'd read like two of them.
Rym: And then the rest were just garbage.
Scott: I've read like pretty much if there's ever a newspaper with comics in it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'll I'll read most of them, but I'll never read like those those like Mary Worth ones.
Scott: Those don't get read.
Rym: Or Studio 3G.
Scott: Apartment 3G.
Rym: Whatever it is.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: What's the Gill something?
Scott: Gill Thorpe.
Rym: And then there's all the you know what?
Rym: Let's get right into it.
Rym: What are there any good comics left in newspapers with the exceptions of those rare newspapers that syndicate something awesome?
Rym: Like there was a newspaper syndicating the Perry Bible Fellowship and Penny Arcade.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But is anyone diesel?
Scott: What?
Scott: I think some people are syndicating Penny Arcade and we're not.
Scott: I'm not sure, but I think it was printed somewhere at some time.
Rym: You sure it wasn't nothing?
Scott: I'm sure it.
Scott: I'll go check it.
Rym: I'm curious about that.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it was printed somewhere at some time.
Scott: Anyway, of newspaper comic strips that are in the newspaper today.
Scott: If you want to say what's a good one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, Dilbert is only funny like twice a year.
Scott: Dilbert was that still a thousand percent funnier than Garfield.
Rym: I'll say straight up that I don't like Dilbert at all.
Rym: I mean, I was kind of funny early on, but even then it never held a candle to Calvin and Hobbes.
Scott: No, it did not even like Foxtrot.
Scott: Now, Foxtrot is doing Sunday only.
Scott: And I think that's actually increasing his funny percentage because he's sort of, you know, putting the full power into each one.
Rym: Well, Foxtrot, I found a lot more funny when I was a lot younger.
Rym: And that's true.
Rym: The older I got, the less I enjoyed it.
Rym: It's also then again, it's hard to tell if it's because the jokes kind of changed or because I changed.
Rym: But Calvin and Hobbes, I could pretty much read forever and never get tired of.
Scott: I don't think Foxtrot is actually any better or worse comic wise than any of the other strips in the newspaper.
Scott: I think it's only because there is geek references in there that I find it more enjoyable.
Rym: I think that the comedic timing in general of Foxtrot was, by and large, far superior to the comedy in any other strip in there for the most part.
Rym: It was actually a better strip.
Rym: There are some strips, some old ones that I would laugh at.
Scott: Some of them, but not a significant percentage more.
Rym: I mean, look at like Garfield.
Rym: We've talked enough about Garfield.
Scott: It's funnier when it's randomized than when it's funnier if you remove Garfield.
Rym: Removed Garfield from Garfield is like one of my favorite comic strips now.
Scott: But I mean, it's basically it's weird because like I can sort of categorize the newspaper strips.
Scott: It's like the never read ones.
Scott: I won't even look at them.
Scott: Right.
Rym: That's like the Mary Worth and all that.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Or the Kathy.
Scott: There's the read and don't laugh.
Rym: That's like a Wizard of Id.
Scott: I usually read those because there's a few words, but I like Wizard of Id just because it's a wizard, but it's not funny.
Scott: It's always the king is short or the king is corrupt or the wizard is lame or Sir Rodney is lame.
Rym: And then there's the equally unfunny
Rym: B.C.,
Rym: which also has sold the guy.
Scott: That one's done right.
Rym: It was in there.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I'm just talking general.
Rym: We need to talk about what's in the papers right now.
Scott: Yeah, especially since we haven't had a newspaper in this house ever.
Rym: I think the last time.
Rym: I mean, the only reason I even saw some modern comics at all is when I worked in Yonkers, sometimes I go to a pizza shop and sometimes it'd be a newspaper.
Scott: You know, when I go to my parents' house, they get the newspaper and there's a page of comics that I usually read when I'm sitting at the kitchen table.
Rym: But I mean, like Kathy, I just find that comic offensive to all of the senses.
Scott: Kathy is so offensive to every sense, especially the eyes, because there's so many fucking words and I can't read.
Scott: It's just painful.
Rym: Never mind the art or the fact that the jokes.
Rym: not only are the jokes not funny, but they're so like stereotypical of everything about certain kinds of American culture that I hate.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I mean, and then there's Luanne, at least I don't know what Luanne is, but at least Garfield, as bad as it is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you look at the earliest Garfield and the newest Garfield, there has been an improvement in the artistic skills and an application of computer technology.
Scott: Kathy is the same art.
Scott: It's always been with no change whatsoever.
Rym: It's also awful.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, it's reminiscent of that bulging bride's thing with those god awful advertisements.
Scott: I have to see every goddamn day walking into those for the ads in Grand Central are pretty bad.
Scott: Frightening.
Scott: I was happy with the the watch over your bank ones with the candidates in the shield, even though they're totally lame.
Scott: Yeah, they were lame, but at least it was better.
Rym: At least they're not offensive to my senses.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But no, it's weird because a lot of newspaper comics.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They actually come from greeting cards.
Scott: I mean, they turn remember that cranky old lady that was on all the greeting cards for a long time.
Scott: They turned her into like a one panel far side style comic.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Are you sure she wasn't a comic first?
Scott: I'm pretty sure she wasn't a comic.
Rym: I remember seeing that comic for a long time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Care Bears Care Bears were never a comic strip, but they were a a greeting card first.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: We got to watch the Care Bears movie.
Rym: I totally got to do a show on that.
Rym: That movie's awesome.
Scott: Not Zippy the Pinhead.
Scott: The other guy Zippy the Pinhead is terrible.
Scott: So not at least it's it tries to be artistically high brow.
Scott: I'll give it that.
Rym: But it ends up being pretentious and weird.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: No, what's the other one?
Scott: Ziggy Ziggy is the one that I think also started as a greeting card.
Rym: I don't like Ziggy.
Scott: I'm not sure if Kathy was a greeting card first or not, but she's on a lot of greeting cards.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Greeting card comics.
Scott: Not cool.
Rym: So I don't know.
Rym: We could either talk about why we think comics are bad in the newspaper or we could just talk about the ones we thought were good.
Scott: OK, so ones we thought were good.
Scott: Check this out.
Rym: Calvin and Hobbes far and away.
Rym: That's like the best comic ever.
Scott: Calvin and Hobbes is closely tied with the far side.
Rym: The far side.
Rym: Like I look back at the far side and it's not funny to me.
Rym: Any any more.
Rym: But remember, on one hand, I've pretty much memorized the far side.
Scott: I know that's always a problem.
Rym: I look at one and I don't go, ha ha.
Rym: I go, I remember that one.
Scott: Actually, you can read Calvin and Hobbes online still and they just sort of cycle through them.
Scott: And today it is a funny one with an Astro Boy joke that I didn't remember.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: A lot of these the good comics, like I look back and if I look at like the first panel of any given Calvin and Hobbes, I remember that entire strip like perfectly.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: There is a string of peanuts.
Scott: That's actually good.
Scott: I mean, the old peanuts.
Scott: The thing is, like I respect Charles Schultz and everything, you know, but like only some peanuts are actually funny.
Scott: Usually the funny ones involve either a try to kick the football and missing, but it's only funny the first time or usually Woodstock playing hockey.
Scott: That's Woodstock playing ice hockey in the birdbath with the Zamboni is funny every time.
Rym: I almost feel like peanuts was.
Rym: it's not really good.
Scott: And even like it can also be funny.
Scott: Snoopy the Air Baron with the typewriter.
Rym: But he was a kid like.
Rym: I never really enjoyed it, but it seems like a lot of people.
Scott: there's a lot of the cartoons like the special.
Rym: Yes, that's totally separate.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot of like cultural cachet with peanuts and a lot of people like respect peanuts and feel like peanuts is something that you have to like.
Scott: It's like it's like an Americana kind of feeling, you know, it's like it's like you look at it and you smile and you identify with it and you might feel good, but you don't laugh because there's no real funny joke.
Scott: most of the time, you know, or the joke is so has such a broad appeal, there's not much of a joke.
Rym: But the far side when I was a kid, because far side kind of started because now there's a million ripoff far sides.
Scott: Some of them some of the ripoff far sides are actually kind of OK.
Rym: The ones in the newspaper aren't.
Scott: Well, I saw one that was funny a couple of times.
Rym: You know, I haven't seen one that was good.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Well, but the far side kind of started that trend of the weird comics.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And it was super funny for the time.
Rym: And I think the best thing about the far side was I bought one of the.
Rym: I bought all the books.
Rym: But I remember one of the books randomly, I decided to look in the index and it listed all the letters, but there's nothing under them like what I'm flipping through and flipping through.
Rym: They get to tea.
Rym: And the first one is the one about the albatross.
Rym: And every single comic is listed under tea as the one about the something.
Rym: And that was funnier than my favorite.
Scott: far sides are usually the ones with amoebas involved or the one where the kid is trying to push open the pull door to the gifted school.
Rym: Yes, I was one of the many people who had a poster of that when I was younger.
Scott: That's a good one.
Rym: Also, our side gets mad points for stopping when he ran out of ideas.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Super points for that.
Rym: Of course.
Scott: Calvin and Hobbes gets negative points for doing the same thing.
Rym: Calvin and Hobbes gets points for being probably the greatest newspaper comic ever written, bar none.
Rym: Probably I defy anyone to bring up a newspaper comic that's better.
Scott: But minus points for being a recluse.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time points because now there's that mystery.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's it's plus it never.
Rym: the comic was just perfect.
Rym: And then it ended on this high note.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Kind of like out not Outland.
Rym: Outland was awful.
Rym: But Bloom County, Bloom County is my other than Calvin and Hobbes, like my favorite newspaper comic ever.
Scott: And I don't think I ever read that really.
Rym: Bloom County, you know, with Opus the penguin and all those things.
Rym: I know the penguin that that comic, maybe just because I was a kid and I had all the books and my parents really liked it.
Scott: But it's more like a platypus than a penguin.
Rym: Actually, he's more like a puffin than a penguin.
Scott: He's like a platy- platyguin.
Rym: He's not anything like a platypus.
Scott: Well, he's got the platypus like Bill.
Rym: No.
Rym: Well, Scott, what does the platypus look like?
Rym: He's more like a puffin.
Scott: I don't know what a puffin is.
Rym: Look up a puffin and then look up a platypus.
Rym: He's not anything like a platypus.
Scott: He's got the bill of the platypus.
Rym: No, he doesn't.
Rym: A platypus has a duck bill.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: I'm going to go to images like Google.
Scott: What the hell is wrong with you?
Scott: And look for Opus to see a picture of Opus.
Rym: Opus does not look anything like a platypus.
Rym: In fact, early Opus did look like a penguin.
Rym: He changed a lot.
Rym: He looked more like a puffin as time went on.
Rym: He never looked like a platypus.
Rym: But anyway.
Scott: He's got a giant platypus bill.
Rym: That's not what it look of a platypus.
Rym: That's not what platypuses look like at all.
Rym: Seriously.
Scott: He doesn't look like a platypus, but his bill is like a platypus bill.
Rym: How so?
Scott: It's big.
Rym: Platypus bills are mostly flat and wide.
Scott: This looks flat and wide to me.
Rym: What picture are you looking at?
Scott: This one where he's reading a book.
Rym: OK, there's a slight cut there.
Rym: Well, I tried to show Scott that platypus bills are small and flat.
Scott: They're big and flat.
Scott: And Opus looks big and flat.
Scott: It looks nothing like a puffin or penguin bill.
Rym: Compare the relative sizes of the heads.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And you'll see.
Scott: I'll not disagree that his body is penguin and puffin-ish.
Rym: One, he is a penguin.
Rym: Two, it's it's.
Rym: it's more like a puffin.
Scott: Anyway, I can't believe why is it looks like a platypus.
Scott: Let's not let this episode disintegrate.
Rym: The comic was all about 80s politics.
Rym: And as a result, I know a lot about 80s politics, mostly from reading Bloom County.
Scott: Maybe because I didn't read it.
Scott: I know almost nothing about 80s politics.
Rym: You don't know anything about 90s politics.
Rym: Or 2000s politics.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I got better things to think about.
Rym: And I think anyway, what else are we going to talk about?
Rym: newspaper comics?
Rym: They're almost all inoffensive and non funny.
Rym: Well, actually, that's the one thing I wanted to bring up is I feel like we should do a separate show on that because we've already gone on long enough.
Scott: I just want to bring up the point real quick is that I've been buying a lot of super old comic strips.
Scott: I'm buying like the Dick Tracy's from like the 30s and the 20s and whatnot.
Scott: And I forget what year it is, but and I've been I think I'm going to buy the Flash Gordon's from way back in the day.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the old comic strips from way back on that are super awesome and super better than the ones we have now.
Scott: Like, go read.
Scott: you can buy the original Dick Tracy and these big hardcovers.
Scott: It is so kick ass.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: And it's really sad that they don't exist anymore in that style.
Rym: Yeah, but just newspaper comics in general are not even like.
Rym: I feel like the medium as a whole is just worthless at this point.
Scott: because I mean that because anyone who's actually going to do something like quality, it's very hard to break into the newspaper.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So they just sort of take that art and they go online where they can do what they want.
Scott: And, you know, they're not limited.
Scott: And that's where the quality comic strip art of today is emerging.
Rym: Plus, it just seems like so many newspapers are so afraid of offending anyone that they choose the least possibly offensive things they could ever get.
Scott: And it seems like a lot of those comic writing Marmaduke is a big dog.
Rym: That's the whole joke.
Scott: It seems like a lot of the the newspaper strip creators are not so concerned with like advancing the art form as they are with cranking out comics and keeping making their money.
Scott: But actually and then they make their money off a side thing.
Rym: It used to not be that way.
Rym: I mean, Bill Watterson, he fought with the newspapers and he's the reason that people could ever have a good, interestingly formatted newspaper comic.
Rym: He he basically had the power to force the newspapers to let him do what he wanted and let him experiment.
Scott: And then he and then he sort of said, oh, it's all bullshit and he stopped.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I kind of agree.
Scott: And then the newspapers just sort of won because he wasn't pushing them anymore.
Rym: Of course, newspapers in general, the only possible use of a print newspaper, at least for us geeks, is local news.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: Local news is almost never has anything to do with me.
Scott: Thing is, the funny.
Scott: what I find so funny is that you can read all of the comic strips that are in the newspaper online for free the same day, because remember, the newspaper and the comic strips in it are not targeted at anyone who knows there's an Internet.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, well.
Scott: Newspaper comic strips.
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't matter.
Rym: It's kind of a cop out show because maybe next week when Scott's watched some Avatar and I've read some comics, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.