Rym: It's Wednesday, May 7th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, free comic book day 2008.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: This is going to be a somewhat difficult show for me to do.
Rym: You see, we're making VLT's tonight.
Rym: So Emily got it to make some fresh bread and she put the fresh bread right next to me and it's sitting there and I can smell it.
Scott: I thought it was wrapped in it like a bath towel, but it's actually some sort of colorful...
Rym: Yes, Scott is not used to nice napkins.
Rym: So when he sees a nice napkin, he assumes it's a bath towel.
Scott: It's just, uh, it looks like a dish towel actually.
Rym: Not so much.
Rym: Yeah, it looks like a napkin.
Scott: It's pretty colorful for a napkin.
Rym: But I'll tell you one thing.
Rym: If you're out there, not many of you are podcasters, but imagine trying to podcast when there's fresh bread that you're not allowed to eat yet right next to you.
Scott: What if, what if it's the bakery cast and you're the baker?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: If you're a baker, I think you're either immune to the effects of the smell of fresh bread or you're obese.
Scott: Uh, both.
Scott: You mean you got immune by getting obese.
Rym: I don't know if I could get immune though.
Rym: I could just eat bread until I died.
Scott: We wanted to quit and become bakers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Let's open up a bakery.
Rym: I remember one or two times, I actually, when I worked at that Tavella's when we lived at RIT for that summer, I was the baker.
Rym: Like I assisted the baker.
Rym: I get in at six in the morning and make the bread and basically make the bread meant I stood there while the baker did everything and then I cleaned up after him.
Rym: The smell was painful and I stole like two loaves and ate him.
Rym: Anyway, since we're not going to talk about anime for the rest of this show, I'll at least point out that I'm watching a show that we're probably going to talk about sometime soon on the train.
Rym: Watching that Princess Tutu.
Scott: Oh, that one.
Rym: It's interesting.
Rym: And what I want to say is I like it.
Rym: I do like it.
Rym: But what Lara said when she gave it to me sums it up best.
Rym: Princess Tutu is a show that you can enjoy and get a lot out of so long as you go into it knowing that it is a show where people fight via ballet.
Rym: And when Aunt Iterina, good God, it's interesting.
Scott: Swan Lake Attack?
Rym: You know, you'd think that, but it's more like by doing ballet with you I have learned the secrets of your heart and now I do something magical to steal your heart because I know the secrets.
Scott: It's like Utena only with ballet instead of swords.
Rym: And with much less subtlety.
Scott: Oh, subtlety was important to Utena because, well, without the subtlety... You get the movie.
Scott: It would have been, yeah, pretty much.
Rym: But it's like imagine if Utena, every character in Utena was either Wakaba or Nanami.
Scott: Of course, Utena's subtlety, you know, there's a question is it actually subtlety or is it just sort of unintentional vaguery?
Scott: Or intentional vaguery?
Rym: Well, the fact that it all comes together in the end definitely leans toward the former.
Rym: But I don't know about Princess Tutu.
Rym: I gotta see more.
Rym: I haven't gotten past the point where people say it gets good, but it's already pretty good.
Scott: I've downloaded a whole bunch of anime.
Scott: I'm gonna start going through all those new episodes and new shows.
Scott: And I also watched the first DVD that got us, you know, Yojimbo.
Rym: Yup, second DVD's on the way.
Scott: Which is a show I watched a long time ago, completely forgot and watched again.
Scott: But I sort of feel like maybe we should watch Yojimbo and also watch Fistful of Dollars and then sort of do a Yojimbo try show.
Rym: I feel like each one could merit its own show.
Scott: I know, but I feel like we should do the three in a row or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: We haven't even watched Strange Days yet.
Scott: We'll watch it this weekend or something.
Rym: That movie's like ten years old.
Rym: Actually twelve.
Rym: Alright, so I think that's it for anime today.
Scott: Yeah, so it's time for Scott's Box.
Scott: Oh no, you people wanted me to do Scott's Box when I got the box as opposed to when I ordered the next box.
Rym: Which I think is the superior option.
Scott: Well, that's what the people voted for.
Scott: And unlike, I guess, in other parts of the world, what you vote for is what you get with GeekNights.
Scott: Are you kidding?
Rym: We pretty much ignore any time someone votes for a banning or anything in the forum.
Scott: Shush, I'm trying to be like other parts of the world and give the people the impression their vote counts.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Alright, so let's start with, let's see what came in the box.
Rym: What came in Scott's Box?
Scott: Alright, so I'll do the issues.
Scott: I'll do the issues first, then I'll do the trades.
Rym: I think we need some Scott's Box music.
Scott: I guess so.
Scott: I don't know, I think it should have lots of percussion to resemble the box.
Scott: Maybe I should just bang a beat on a cardboard box that has full of peanuts and that'll be it.
Rym: I could make a drum loop.
Scott: I guess.
Scott: Alright, so the first thing I got here, DC Universe Zero.
Scott: Why did I get this?
Rym: It was seventeen cents.
Scott: No, the cover price is fifty cents.
Scott: I paid twelve cents.
Scott: This is sort of, from what people have been saying, I haven't read it yet.
Scott: I haven't read any of this yet because I read all the free comp books we're going to talk about in the second half of the show instead.
Scott: This is sort of like, you know, DC's about to go nuts with all sorts of crises that they go nuts with.
Scott: Well, every summer there's crises, who knows, right?
Scott: And this is sort of like, if you haven't been paying attention, like this is like, you know, sort of wraps up what was going on and sort of brings you into the new with like little tiny, like there's a little Batman bit, there's a little Wonder Woman bit, there's a little Superman bit, a little Green Lantern bit, and it's sort of like, here's all the bits to sort of catch you up and, you know, sort of pull you into the next thing.
Scott: That's what it's supposed to be.
Scott: Alright, we got Soleil Free Sampler.
Scott: Remember I was talking about how I was going to get the Sky Doll from Marvel to support their European comic endeavors?
Rym: That's right.
Rym: We got that short interview we did with the people who were pushing French comics at the New York Comic Con.
Scott: Alright, well Marvel has this sort of like Soleil thing they're doing and they've got Sky Doll, Universal War 1, Samurai, and Scourge of the Gods, right?
Scott: And I ordered the three issues of Sky Doll, but the other one I'm interested in, the Universal War 1, is six issues, so I'll probably wait for the trade on that.
Scott: But they sent me a free sampler, just it's like Soleil Free Sampler, and it gives me little bits of each of these for European comics Marvel's going to put out so I can see what they're like and decide if I want to buy them.
Scott: So maybe I won't even order that Universal War, whatever.
Scott: Alright, we got that second part of the three part Logan Wolverine series that I'm only getting because it's written by Brian K. Vaughan and Brian K. Vaughan means automatic buying.
Rym: But does it mean automatic?
Rym: good?
Scott: Usually.
Scott: He's the Why the Last Man Runaways guy.
Scott: He's the Ex Machina guy.
Rym: See, I really like Ex Machina.
Rym: I really didn't like Why the Last Man.
Scott: I don't think you read enough of it.
Rym: It really went downhill for me pretty much right away.
Scott: Anyway, he's never done anything bad.
Rym: Yeah, I can't say that it's bad.
Rym: I felt it was kind of dumb.
Scott: We got Marvel Comics Presents #8, the only book that I buy every month, so you're going to hear that on Scott's Box every month until they stop printing it.
Scott: Alright, check this out.
Scott: I bought this based on two things.
Scott: I bought this based on the title and based on the price, which is less than a dollar.
Scott: The title is "I Was Kidnapped by Lesbian Pirates from Outer
Scott: Space.".
Scott: How can you not buy that?
Scott: Even if it was $5, how can you not buy "I Was Kidnapped by Lesbian Pirates from Outer Space"?
Rym: I didn't read it, but I flipped through it, and you know what it's about?
Scott: Someone who was kidnapped by lesbian pirates from outer space.
Rym: It looked kind of good, actually.
Scott: I know.
Scott: For a dollar, can't go wrong.
Scott: If it's good, I'll wait for the trade.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: It looked slightly more than a dollar's worth of good.
Scott: And the art style, actually, really, that's my kind of style.
Scott: Sort of like old school, hip kind of thing going on.
Scott: Alright, I got "Wonder Lost #2" by C.B.
Scott: Cebulski.
Scott: If you don't know C.B.
Scott: Cebulski, right, I wanted to talk to him at the New York Comic Con.
Scott: He had an artist's alley table, but he was always there when I wasn't there, so I never actually got to talk to him, but me and him have a lot in common.
Scott: He and I, I don't know, have a lot in common.
Scott: You see, he grew up in the Connecticut.
Scott: I grew up in the Connecticut.
Rym: A lot of people grew up in Connecticut.
Scott: He likes the comics.
Scott: I like the comics.
Scott: I think he was involved with
Scott: C.P.M.,
Scott: and he's sort of like, he knows about the animes and the mangas.
Scott: I'm also into the animes and the mangas.
Scott: C.B.
Scott: Cebulski is my kind of guy.
Scott: He did all those Spider-Man fairy tales, X-Men fairy tales things for Marvel.
Scott: He's done a lot of good stuff, and "Wonder Lost" is sort of like his autobiographical childhood stories thing.
Scott: Well, more like teenage years stories.
Scott: There's a story where he makes out with some girl in his car outside of the Wonderland of Ice ice rink, and I've been to the Wonderland of Ice ice rink because I grew up in Connecticut.
Rym: Did you make out with anyone there?
Scott: No, sadly.
Scott: That was in issue one of "Wonder Lost,".
Scott: so of course I'm going to buy issue two of "Wonder
Scott: Lost."
Scott: And the last issue I got was this "Glamourpuss #1" by Dave Sim.
Scott: He's the service guy, right?
Scott: And basically I bought this for the art, because if you say nothing else about Dave Sim, he has the art skills, but "Cerabus" is supposed to be like this ultra-famous indie comic that's like 300 issues long, and I read the first two phone books of it.
Scott: You might not know what it is, but once you see the phone books, you'll recognize it, because you've seen it before.
Scott: And it was painful.
Scott: Reading that second trade was like dragging my brain through a marsh.
Rym: Why did you even bother?
Scott: Because it's so famous, I felt like I was obligated.
Rym: That's how I felt about "Great Expectations," and I cut and ran well before.
Scott: But basically I've actually found out recently that Dave Sim is actually this horrible, horrible misogynist dude.
Scott: So yeah, we'll see what this thing's about, because it's supposed to be about women's parody on women's fashion something something from a misogynist, so we'll see what that's about.
Scott: I guess I gotta view the guy sort of like Mike Tyson, where even though his skills at work might be awesome, he's not a good person.
Scott: Alright, that's the end of the issues.
Scott: Let's look at them.
Scott: trades.
Scott: "Mushishi Volume
Scott: 3.".
Scott: You know, "Mushishi" the anime was awesome.
Scott: And "Mushishi" the manga, the first two volumes, were pretty much the same as the anime.
Scott: Like, I wasn't getting anything more or less by reading the manga, and so unless this manga goes and tells stories that the anime didn't tell, I sort of feel like I might stop buying it.
Rym: Well, part of what made the anime so great was that the animation was just amazing.
Scott: It was super amazing.
Rym: To quote ourselves, it was animated in twosies.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Well, Emily told us that, right?
Scott: Is that right?
Rym: Something like that.
Scott: Yeah, she said it was right.
Rym: But also it was just the sound and the atmosphere, and there was a lot, and it was very subtle and slow, and I liked it.
Scott: Yeah, the only thing in this manga that I don't get in the show is the funny, you know, little omake in the back or whatever it is.
Scott: So, you know, it's a good manga.
Scott: If you haven't seen the show and you like manga more than you like anime, you should probably get this, because it's just as awesome.
Scott: It's the same stories and characters.
Rym: Yeah, but all things being equal, if you're a fan of both, I think I'd recommend the anime.
Scott: Yeah, I think if this volume doesn't really, like, you know, do something awesome that the anime didn't do, I'm just going to stop and maybe buy the anime DVDs sometime in a box set.
Scott: Okay, we got this thing.
Scott: Super Real Graphics presents Gnome.
Scott: And this actually, because I ordered it for my pre-order place, came with a free sketch of the Gnome character.
Scott: This is by Dave Dwan.
Rym: So a gnome with a G, like gnome?
Scott: Yes, it's like a garden.
Scott: The story is, right?
Scott: I'll read the back.
Scott: Ready?
Scott: "Believed to be simple yard decoration, these garden gnomes once roamed the earth as its greatest protectors.
Scott: Long ago, a curse was placed upon them, petrifying them, until the day they were needed to protect the earth once more.
Scott: In 1956, the world was in peril, and one lonely gnome answered the
Scott: call.".
Scott: So this is the adventures of a garden gnome come to life, defending the world in the late 50s.
Scott: Or the mid to late 50s.
Rym: I don't know about that.
Scott: I don't know about either, but it was cheap, and it came with a free sketch.
Scott: And the sketch is actually pretty high quality.
Rym: You know, I realize that your rationale for buying a lot of these comics is getting to the point where you can't make fun of Scott Johnson for his deal hunting anymore.
Scott: I don't know about that, because I...
Rym: How many times is there a conversation, "Why did you buy that show?
Rym: It was only 50 cents if I bought
Rym: 10.".
Scott: Yeah, but his DVDs are like five bucks, not 50 cents.
Scott: If the DVD was 50 cents, then it would be okay.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: And the only other thing is that he watches those DVDs, and he likes them.
Scott: I read comics that are, you know, if they had lesbian Pirates of Outer Space was bad, I would say...
Rym: But that's probably good.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Okay, if the DC Universe number zero is bad, I'll say it's bad, even though I spent 12 cents on it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: 12 cents?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So Osamu Tezuka's Dororo, number one.
Scott: Vertical.
Scott: Tezuka.
Scott: I'm going to repeat this, like, till the end of time here.
Scott: Right?
Scott: They sent me a free copy.
Scott: I still bought a copy anyway.
Scott: And this actually, I read this already, because I read the free copy when I got it.
Scott: I think it's the only thing in Scott's box I've read already.
Scott: And this is actually kind of different from Tezuka's, I mean, it's still Tezuka stylin'.
Scott: But story-wise, it's unlike any of Tezuka's other stuff, and I'm really liking this.
Scott: Like, this might be like my second or third favorite Tezuka manga there is.
Scott: It's so good.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: More and more, I really like Apollo's song.
Rym: I don't know why I like it so much.
Scott: Apollo's song's good, but it's not, like, holy crap, dude.
Rym: Well, no.
Rym: It's no name like five other works, but...
Scott: All right.
Scott: I bought the, see, the complete Persepolis.
Scott: Remember we saw the movie?
Rym: The movie was good, but Emily was reading the comic, and I was flipping through, I read the first bit of the comic, and it's, the comic makes it all a lot more, I don't know, realistic.
Scott: Yeah, I haven't read the comic yet, as I said, but there's the whole thing in one book, and I got, like, 30 or 40% off, so... I imagine... I like the movie, we'll see what the book is like.
Rym: I imagine it'll warrant a review, or at least a geek bite in and of itself.
Scott: Oh, yeah, definitely.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Waiting for Scott to continue to go through his box.
Scott: I got Whiteout, volume one and two, a new printing by Oni Press.
Scott: This is written by Greg Rucka.
Scott: I found out about Greg Rucka when I read Gotham Central, and if you've never heard of Gotham Central, it was this DC comic about the police in Gotham City.
Scott: So Batman's there, but very little.
Scott: He's barely there.
Scott: It's mostly about the police in the city dealing with all the shit that Batman does or doesn't deal with, right?
Rym: Now, that's kind of my alley, because...
Scott: Gotham Central is over.
Scott: Like, you can just go out and buy all the trades and get the whole thing, and you don't have to understand any DC bullshit.
Scott: Like, if you've seen one Batman movie, you know more than enough.
Scott: You know more than you need to know to understand...
Rym: No, forget a movie.
Rym: Just watch one episode of BTS.
Scott: Yeah, if you watch one episode of Batman animated series, you know more than enough to understand what's going on in Gotham Central.
Scott: if you read, like, you know, the little foreword in the first volume.
Scott: And it's super awesome, and it's Greg Rucka and Ed Brubaker, I think, did that.
Scott: So, then, I got, like, these volumes of Queen and Country, right?
Scott: From somebody.
Scott: And I read the first three volumes of that, and it was Greg Rucka, and also, like, Brian Lee O'Malley did the art on an issue, and... Yeah, it's basically, like, sort of like a spy, you know, secret missions against terrorism kind of story about, like, this, you know, British group of people or whatever.
Scott: And that was really good.
Scott: So, I'm like,
Scott: "Huh.".
Scott: And I sort of figured out that Greg Rucka is the shit.
Scott: So, now, Greg Rucka, I think, is on the automatic buy list.
Scott: So, they reprinted... I had the first three volumes of Queen and Country, right?
Scott: But now they came out with these Queen and Country definitive editions, which are much newer, better printings and fewer volumes for less money.
Scott: And I figured out that if I just get rid of the three volumes I have and buy these definitive editions, I'll get the whole series for less money than if I just bought the rest of the normal existing volumes.
Scott: So, actually, in my hands, I just got in Scott's box Queen and Country definitive edition one and two and Greg Rucka whiteout one and two.
Scott: All from Oni Press, all new printings, all awesome.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Almost done.
Scott: -Almost?
Scott: -Almost.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I don't know if this is going to be good or not, but I got the Avengers Kree-Skrull War.
Scott: Now, you know, when I was a kid, I read Marvel comics.
Scott: And nowadays, I still read a few bad Marvel comics and a few good ones, too.
Scott: But there's always references, especially in, like, the outer space.
Scott: Because I like the outer space ones, like Silver Surfers and Adam Warlock and whatnot.
Scott: And there's references to the Kree-Skrull War.
Scott: Like in Captain Marvel, you got it going on, you know.
Scott: And there's always these references to it.
Scott: But I've never actually read the Kree-Skrull War.
Scott: And I assumed maybe it's an old comic.
Scott: It's probably bad because I read Secret Wars and that was bad.
Scott: But I said, "You know what?
Scott: They're printing a new trade of it.
Scott: And I'll check it out and I'll see what actually happened in the Kree-Skrull
Scott: War.".
Rym: I imagine there's a lot of people declaring what they're about to do as they do it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Okay, we got another Marvel comic here, Deadpool Classic.
Scott: Now, Ian, our friend, was a huge fan of Deadpool, right?
Scott: And I recognize Deadpool.
Scott: I know what he looks like.
Scott: And I've only ever read, like, one or two Deadpool comics in my life.
Scott: And he's sort of just, like, you know, a really powerful mutant assassin badass guy.
Scott: Sort of like that '90s cable stylin', you know?
Rym: See, for whatever reason, I liked cable.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That doesn't really appeal to me that much.
Scott: What appeals to me is that it seems like Deadpool is, like, the wisecrackingest guy in the universe.
Rym: Wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Rym: What about Spidey?
Scott: No, he's like Spidey times a thousand.
Rym: How could that be?
Scott: Trust me, you read a well-written Deadpool comic and it's like everything he says will have you peeing in your pants.
Scott: I've read, like, I swear to God.
Rym: Are you sure you're not just in continent?
Scott: I'm pretty sure, like...
Rym: Read some of this Transformers and see if you're peeing.
Scott: He's really, he's just that witty.
Scott: So, I said, "You know what?
Scott: I've never actually read a lot of Deadpool comics, you know, I've never actually...".
Scott: And they printed this Deadpool classic, volume one.
Scott: So I said, "What better way to check and see if, you know, my remembering Deadpool being hilarious was true than to buy this
Scott: volume?".
Scott: Okay, Jonah Hex, only the good die young, volume... I guess this is volume some number, but they don't put the number out of it, they're giving it a name, which is appropriate.
Scott: Because Jonah Hex is a Western comic that DC puts out, and it's sort of like, you know, it's a new one.
Scott: Like, Jonah Hex is actually a really old character, but this is sort of like, you know, a new series.
Scott: And it's really good because if you buy this in the issues as opposed to the trades, each issue is a standalone Western story and has nothing to do with the DC universe.
Scott: It's just a Western story about Jonah Hex, a badass cowboy with an ugly face.
Scott: And I buy it in the trades because it's cheaper and it's awesome.
Scott: I really can't go wrong.
Scott: I mean, if you want to read awesome Western stories where the main character happens to be a guy with a fucked up face, this is pretty much where it's at.
Scott: I could say this is like the best Western comic in print today.
Scott: All right.
Scott: You can't get there from here by Jason.
Scott: You can't get wrong with Jason.
Rym: Jason, I've never been disappointed by Jason.
Rym: I think the best one is still.
Rym: why are you doing this?
Scott: Why are you doing this really good?
Rym: That one really, really got to me.
Scott: It is.
Scott: But yeah, it's a Jason comic.
Scott: I'm going to buy every single one of these until we have every single one of these.
Scott: And whenever a new one comes out, I'm going to buy that too.
Rym: They're fantastic.
Scott: And last book, Rabbi's Cat two.
Rym: I still got to read one.
Scott: I didn't even know this is coming.
Scott: It came out of nowhere.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This is by Joan Spahr, the dungeon guy, also the Klezmer guy.
Scott: Rabbi's Cat one was like a billion Eisner Award winning.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: And I didn't even know there was going to be a two.
Scott: I wish he would do Klezmer two.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: So it came out of nowhere.
Scott: and I said, how can I not order that?
Scott: It's like not ordering.
Scott: it would make you know, would be stupid.
Scott: It's like automatic.
Scott: So it is here.
Scott: I'll read it and I'll see what the deal is.
Scott: But it's kind of weird to think.
Scott: Rabbi's Cat two.
Scott: It's like Rabbi's Cat one was sort of a self-contained story.
Scott: So I really, really wonder what's going on here.
Scott: The cover is a little intriguing.
Scott: Looks sort of like a I don't know.
Scott: We'll find out what's going on with the rabbi and his cat.
Rym: So before we move on to the main.
Scott: That's Scott's box.
Scott: Scott's box for the month.
Rym: But before we go on, I do have a quick news for anyone who lives in, I don't know, New York City, L.A.
Rym: or Seattle.
Rym: Tokiwakakaru Shoujo, the girl left her time is being screened in all those cities this summer.
Rym: I'll link to it because it's actually in June and August.
Rym: So you'll forget if I say the dates now.
Rym: But if you live in one of those cities or Washington, it looks like, then I'd recommend you check this movie out if you've never seen it.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: I guess Scott can go first for once.
Scott: So I found this awesome flash game when I got home.
Rym: It's pretty awesome.
Scott: And on congregate congregate, if you don't know, is this really is pretty much the best site for flash games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And has like a social network.
Scott: It integrates to the Facebook.
Scott: It's got a little chat room.
Scott: It's good stuff, but it has achievements, which is the only bad part.
Scott: So they got this new flash game on there called Chrono Tron.
Scott: And Chrono Tron is a game unlike no other game I've ever played.
Scott: There might have been a game like it, but I never played it.
Scott: Basically, the concept is this is a platform game.
Scott: And in each map, each screen is one.
Scott: It's only one screen.
Scott: There's no scrolling.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You control this robot.
Scott: You can walk left and right.
Scott: Jump and duck.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Every level you come out of this blue door.
Scott: It's sort of like a time elevator.
Scott: You're the chrono.
Scott: try to remember.
Scott: So, of course, time is going to be an element.
Scott: You go from the door and there's a green button somewhere in the room.
Scott: You have to touch that green button.
Scott: Then you have to go back in the door.
Scott: Sounds easy enough, right?
Scott: Walk, touch the button, walk, get in the door or maybe jump over an obstacle.
Scott: Well, the thing is, many of the obstacles are impossible to do because you only have one robot.
Scott: Like there'll be you'll have to step on a button to open a door and then also go in the door.
Scott: But if you get off the button, you know, the door closes.
Scott: Classic Zelda puzzle.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And how do you solve it in Zelda?
Scott: You put a brick on the button.
Scott: What if there's no brick to put on the button?
Scott: Then what do you do?
Rym: Well, you're fucked.
Scott: You're fucked, except in Chrono Tron, because in Chrono Tron, it's very interesting.
Scott: The way this works is you come out of the door, you step on the button, you wait, you go back in the door.
Scott: When you go back in the door, you're you're traveling back in time to when you started the level.
Scott: So you come out of the door and you see your former self go and stand on the button.
Scott: And now your current self, your present self goes in, touches the button on the wall while your former self is holding the door open.
Scott: Then you go back in the elevator.
Scott: Then your former self goes back in the elevator and poof, it takes you to the next level.
Rym: Now, the concept is absolutely amazing, but I feel like someone else is going to take this idea and make a game out of it.
Scott: They definitely need to take it.
Scott: It's basically a proof of concept and it's a little flaky, but it's solid enough to be worth playing.
Scott: And it's solid enough to make you go, wow, holy shit.
Scott: Plus, there's some cool time paradox thingies that can happen.
Scott: Like you go into the past, right?
Scott: You have your past self walk to the left and walk to the right.
Scott: Then you come into the future.
Scott: Your past self walks to the left.
Scott: Then when your past self walks to the right, you open up a door, your past self falls in a hole and you close your past self in there.
Scott: Then you go back in the elevator.
Scott: Time paradox.
Rym: So what happens?
Scott: I didn't actually try to do that because it said do this to do a time paradox and instead of doing that, I just beat the level.
Scott: So I'm going to do it later and see what happens.
Rym: I can't believe you didn't do that.
Rym: It's like a...
Scott: I didn't figure out exact...
Rym: It's like you're going to choose your own adventure.
Rym: The first thing you do is read all the awesome deaths.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: But anyway, I'll do it.
Rym: Or in Chrononauts, you go for that.
Scott: This is definitely a Flash game worth playing.
Rym: So my thing of the day, actually, Emily showed us this, but it's related tangentially, I guess.
Rym: You know, anime, manga, comics, anime.
Rym: It's an animation.
Rym: But this is called Evergreen and it's a music video from Anaboom and it's absolutely beautiful and it's great in every way.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: I don't really want to spoil anything.
Rym: Just watch it.
Rym: It's definitely worth clicking on and watching.
Rym: It's not even that long.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, it's a high quality music video action.
Scott: You know, why not watch it?
Scott: You really got something better to do with those three minutes.
Rym: Well, considering that pretty much whenever we don't have enough time to watch a full movie or something, we'll sit down around the TV with the YouTubes and we'll pretty much drain the internet of everything good.
Scott: Yep, pretty much.
Rym: Of course, we have people like Emily who go to sites we don't go to, so they'll usually have all the things that we never would have seen otherwise.
Rym: Meanwhile, where does Scott go?
Rym: College humor.
Rym: We're already went.
Scott: Yeah, I like college humor.
Scott: They seem to have pretty consistent quality.
Rym: I like college humor a lot more than dig.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: I'll tell you that much.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, free comic book day.
Scott: Yep, it was free comic book day and as I've done for the past few free comic book days, I go down to the Dragon's Den.
Rym: Well, I guess up.
Scott: Yeah, up to the Dragon's Den and unlike other comic book stores that put a limit on you, the limited Dragon's Den is one.
Scott: One each.
Scott: You get one of every free comic that they still have in stock if you want.
Scott: You can take, you know, I guess some people don't take one of each, but I take one of everything and my, my, was it a stack this year.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: We didn't even get every free comic that we possibly could have gotten.
Scott: I'm getting five free comic books, you know, from free comic book day in the next Scott's Box and like at least three of them were not at the Dragon's Den, but you'll hear about them next month on Scott's Box.
Rym: So, I think we're just going to jump right into this and kind of take turns bringing them up.
Scott: Yeah, basically what we did is I read like a handful of these.
Scott: Then I sort of gave a couple of the ones that I read to Rym and then we pretty much divided up the rest that I hadn't read.
Scott: So, a few of these we both read.
Rym: We had a draft.
Scott: Yeah, most of these only one of us have read and we did a draft which is sort of like, okay, you pick one, I pick one, you pick one, I pick one.
Scott: So that we sort of had even quality, at least judging the books by their covers, we had even quality, you know.
Scott: So, that way it wouldn't be like Scott reads all the awesome comics and Rym reads all the shit comics.
Rym: So, I get to read what?
Rym: NASCAR and Jughead.
Scott: You did.
Scott: Jughead's not bad.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah, we'll get to that.
Scott: We'll get to it.
Scott: So, we're going to take, we're going to style start.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: You want to start?
Rym: I'm like, go ahead, go ahead.
Scott: So, the first comic I read and we're probably going to do this in, I don't know, I sort of have mine in semi-quality order here.
Rym: Mine are in random order.
Scott: Maybe I'll shuffle mine up, but I'm going to start with Gumby.
Scott: You read the Gumby?
Rym: I read the Gumby.
Scott: Yeah, the Eisner, Gumby actually won an Eisner award for best like kids comic.
Scott: And I read this Gumby and now I see why.
Scott: I mean, this, this isn't like the same as the Gumby that I remember watching on TV as a kid.
Scott: It's definitely way different than that, right?
Scott: But it's really cute and sort of, you know, like Powerpuff.
Scott: Girls would sometimes have jokes that only adults will get and kids won't get.
Scott: Like Mojo Jojo locked in jail with Bubba.
Scott: Only kids won't get that joke, but adults go, oh man, this Gumby has a lot of that kind of stuff going on.
Scott: And it's actually, this is also a coloring book and I kind of feel like coloring it in.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I mean, this is one that I also read and it was okay, but it, it had a little bit, it reeked of SpongeBob humor just a little bit.
Rym: It seems like most of that, well, at least this one, maybe not other Gumby, but this one, there was a lot of that kind of, yay.
Scott: There was a bit of yay, but there were, and those parts were kind of eh.
Scott: But there were also some funny parts like.
Rym: There were two good jokes.
Rym: There was one really good joke.
Rym: There's the one with the crayons.
Rym: Where he finds the crayons in the thing and then how he reacts to that.
Rym: That was, that was actually really funny.
Scott: The ending I think was lame though.
Scott: The ending was way lame.
Rym: Oh yeah, most definitely.
Scott: Actually in the back, there's these two really good like pinups.
Scott: One is like Gumby, but he's King Kong.
Scott: And the other one is like Gumby, but he's Sinbad and he's fighting a skeleton.
Rym: Yeah, I just, I don't know if I'd ever read any more Gumby.
Scott: No, it's a kids' comic.
Rym: I'm not actually suggesting to read.
Rym: I think there are better kids' comics too.
Rym: It was just.
Scott: I don't know if there's better.
Scott: There's not that many better kids' comics.
Rym: It reeked.
Rym: It's just, there was a little too much of that SpongeBob in there.
Rym: I really don't like that SpongeBob.
Scott: I, you know, I actually don't know what the, I know there is a SpongeBob and it's a popular kids' show, but I've never watched it, so I don't know about it.
Rym: I saw two episodes.
Scott: Except I know the song because when you go to minor league hockey games in Bridgeport, they play the song fucking every game.
Scott: It's really annoying.
Rym: Right, so, Transformers Animated is, is, is garbage.
Rym: I can't even, first off, I'm not going to nitpick here, but you look at the front cover, right?
Rym: And all the proportions are kind of off and it looks kind of weird, but one guy's face, I don't know who this bot is, but he's big and green.
Rym: I don't know if they just like rip this straight from.
Scott: What kind of, what kind of car does he look like?
Rym: It doesn't look like a car at all.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: He's big and green and his head looks like it's flat and squashed up against him.
Scott: Is that Ironhide maybe?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: The shadows, it's like, it just, it's awful.
Rym: Like it looks like they kind of, pretty much what I think they did is they took the animated show and they kind of made an animanga from it.
Rym: That's what it looks like because there's a lot of, every time there's an action scene, it kind of just cuts to this overview where someone like a ray of energy shoots out of the Allspire directly into her dog bot chewed key card and changes it into something spectacular.
Rym: But the sound had drawn the attention of Optimus Prime.
Rym: And it just, it's awful.
Rym: It's absolutely awful.
Rym: It looks terrible.
Rym: It looks like they poorly ripped like screenshots from a cartoon, threw them together into a comic, put some bad dialogue in and hit done.
Scott: I've read a few of the Transformers comics, but some of the more serious ones.
Rym: Oh, those are a lot better than this.
Scott: I've read like Spotlight Shockwave and that was okay.
Scott: Spotlight Soundwave was also okay.
Rym: This also just doesn't make any sense.
Rym: It's like people are talking and then they're in a factory.
Scott: Well, I mean, a few free comic days ago, they had that one that was like the Pokemon Transformers.
Scott: That was better.
Scott: Capture all the mini cons or whatnot.
Rym: But like they're talking and then they're in a factory and then suddenly there's a giant ant larva.
Rym: And then suddenly the Autobots are fighting the giant ant larva and it just goes, it doesn't make sense.
Rym: And Optimus Prime has a really, really, really narrow waist.
Rym: I have nothing else to say about that comic.
Rym: That was not worth my time.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Let's see here.
Scott: I read the Dark Horse Hellboy free comic book day.
Scott: Now, the only Hellboy I actually know is like the movie, which I don't remember why I saw it, but I saw it back at RIT.
Scott: Now actually, you open up and in the front page of this comic, there's a mashup of Hellboy and Futurama characters.
Scott: that is pretty awesome.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: Not bad.
Scott: So already we're off to a good start.
Scott: Then we get sort of like this Hellboy comic that's actually like, it's like made 10 or so pages and it's a complete story beginning to end.
Scott: But the ending was a little meh.
Scott: But it was good.
Scott: The art was really good.
Scott: But story wise, there wasn't a lot.
Scott: I mean, I don't know how much you can do in so few pages, but it didn't really sort of introduce me to Hellboy or give me an idea if I'm going to like Hellboy comics or not.
Scott: It just sort of told me Hellboy comics have good art, which I guess is a good thing.
Scott: And then there were two more stories in here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That are not Hellboy, but they're by Mike Mignola, who's the Hellboy guy.
Scott: The first one was called Out of Reach.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And this seemed kind of interesting, like the characters and some of the what was going on.
Scott: It's about like this robot kind of person and they don't really and there's some sort of military group or they're on a mission.
Scott: But the robot gets left behind for some reason and it's not too happy about it.
Scott: But then it's just sort of contrived.
Scott: It's like, oh, where did the knife go?
Scott: Obviously, the robot has it.
Scott: The end.
Scott: Uh huh.
Scott: OK.
Scott: And the third story was Bishop Olek's Devil, which was sort of a standard Lovecraftian sort of Necronomicon story.
Scott: And I kind of like this little story here.
Scott: It's pretty much, hey, you know, there's a guy and, you know, we're going to check out what's going on in his mansion.
Scott: Oh, he's old and sick and he wants us to take his scary book.
Scott: Let's not take a scary book just yet.
Scott: Oh, what's that noise we hear at night?
Scott: Oh, look, there's a horrible monster that rapes him like every night.
Scott: Let's take the book away.
Scott: Oh, look, now the boss is coming to rape me because it rapes whoever has the book every night.
Scott: This is just great.
Scott: And it's pretty much if you get the book, you get awesome powers from having the book.
Scott: But this monster will rape you every night.
Scott: So literally, somewhat literally.
Rym: Yeah, that that sounds like a bad fanfic.
Scott: No, but it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's pretty cool.
Scott: Lovecraftian kind of.
Rym: Oh, I like the Lovecraftian.
Rym: I'm just I'm dubious of this whole rape element.
Scott: I'm not sure if it's raping, but it does something to you every night.
Scott: that's quite unpleasant.
Scott: It's like a giant starfish kind of monster only with hands on the end of its stars.
Rym: Edge is great.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty good.
Scott: I like this Lovecraft stuff.
Scott: So, of course, I'm going to like that.
Rym: So speaking of something I like, that's all that we got.
Rym: Walt Disney's gyro gear loose.
Scott: I wanted that one.
Scott: You got to give me that.
Scott: It's like, you know what?
Rym: It's pretty much just more Scrooge McDuck.
Rym: But it follows gyro gear loose.
Rym: He was kind of dopey, absentminded professor.
Scott: I was kind of liked him on DuckTales.
Rym: I liked him a lot on DuckTales.
Rym: Didn't it?
Rym: Was he the one who actually made the that Mecca duck?
Scott: What I think he did make it was a gizmo duck.
Rym: Yeah, gizmo duck.
Scott: He made.
Scott: I think he made the gizmo duck.
Scott: But that other guy wore the gizmo.
Rym: Because he accidentally said the word that no one was supposed to say.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: I forget what the word was suffering.
Scott: I didn't like.
Scott: See, I liked gizmo duck, but I didn't like the guy in it when he wasn't in it.
Rym: Well, because he was lame and moto.
Rym: I know, which is kind of the point.
Rym: One thing I got to say about gyro is that his is just a Robocop parody.
Rym: His little light bulb robot dude is a lot smarter than he is.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Oh, of course.
Scott: I love that guy.
Rym: Love that guy, too.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But this is if you like that Scrooge McDuck action, which you probably should.
Rym: This is pretty good.
Scott: Yet Disney Comics, like you might think, ah, Disney Comics.
Scott: Disney Comics are probably the only good Disney thing there still is.
Scott: I mean, you know, all I ever wanted from Disney.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I was like, Disney, you have Mickey Mouse fucking everywhere.
Scott: When was the last time you actually made a Mickey Mouse movie?
Scott: What, fucking Prince and the Pauper?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Bring it on.
Scott: Where are the fucking Mickey Mouse movies?
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I never I never expected a diatribe.
Rym: Please make more Mickey Mouse movies to be so infused with the word fuck.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So the place to get the Mickey Mouse Donald Duck real Disney stories is in the comics.
Scott: They don't animate them anymore because they suck.
Scott: But the comics are still good.
Scott: And if you like, you know, watching like old quality Disney animations with the actual Disney characters, then you'll like Disney Comics, especially if it's a Scrooge or Duck story that is by Carl Barks or by Don Rosa.
Scott: Those are like the best ones.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: We got from the pages of Wizard, the comics magazine, which is already.
Scott: you can see this is going downhill.
Scott: How to draw and for as someone who can't draw.
Scott: I'm not sure how if this is telling me how to draw a good way or a bad way.
Scott: And this really doesn't seem like it's going to be this free comic book anyway is going to be a big help in teaching how to draw.
Scott: It's mostly an advertisement for you to buy the actual how to draw books that they sell.
Scott: And as teaching me how to draw, you know, I've never had I've tried a few how to draw things in my day.
Scott: None of them have been very helpful, but that just might be my fault.
Scott: So but when I look at this, there's a lot of really cool like pencil art in here by real comic creators.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you look at it and I always, you know, with superhero comic art, especially you look at the pencils.
Scott: And these days it's like it feels like back in the day that the pencils would be sort of rough and the inking would be like the full real deal.
Scott: But nowadays, it seems like the people doing the penciling are like going full on.
Scott: And the anchors really are more tracers than they used to be, even though they're not totally traces and not all of them are.
Scott: So, you know, when you look at pencil art, I think the pencil art these days is better than the finished art.
Scott: And I wish that they would just have the guys do the pencils and then print that instead of coloring over it.
Scott: Because whenever I look at like original pencils for like modern superhero comics, I say, holy shit, that's amazing.
Scott: Why did the comic look like shit when the actual printed one, you know, and this is full of a lot of that pencil art that I like so much.
Scott: And I want to sort of tie something else into this, which is the other free comic book by Dynamite, which is The Death Defying Devilman.
Scott: Now, Dedede Devilman, I thought this Devilman would sort of be, you know, the the going a guy Devilman.
Rym: You really expected to be the going a guy Devilman.
Scott: It's not the going a guy Devilman.
Scott: And I wonder if there's some sort of lawsuit that's going to happen.
Scott: But what this is and actually I didn't realize it is Alex Ross, you know, the amazing kingdom come Marvel's art guy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Who does the super painting comics.
Scott: He has this project called Project Superpowers, which sort of is taking all these old Golden Age characters and putting them together in like one story, you know, and sort of doing a thing.
Scott: But now it seems like I bought the first or zero issue with that.
Scott: It was pretty bad.
Scott: I didn't realize this goes along with that.
Scott: This is sort of like the same thing, but it's the story of like concentrating on the Devilman character in that.
Scott: And this is also pretty bad and sort of lame.
Scott: But what really gets me about this is I remember when I read that Project Superpowers thing, right, is they had in there like the pencils from the art and the pencils were amazing.
Scott: And the actual art in this book looks sort of average.
Scott: And I mean, Alex Ross isn't doing the art, but he's doing the plot cover and art direction.
Scott: And I think that he should just fire the colors to the anchor and just have the pencils be printed directly.
Scott: And I would buy this just for the art if they did that.
Scott: But oh, well, it's just a bleh superhero comic.
Scott: that really sort of, I think, would only appeal to people who have Golden Age superhero comic nostalgia.
Rym: So to get away from Golden Age superhero nostalgia at all, Sonic the Hedgehog.
Scott: Oh, you got the Sonic comic.
Rym: There are a lot of Sonic comics.
Scott: Sonic comics are real popular.
Rym: Well, I kind of like Sonic the Hedgehog.
Rym: I like him and all his friends.
Scott: He's all right.
Rym: But so let me take you through this.
Rym: Page one, Dr.
Rym: Robotnik has a rope around Sonic's neck and hangs him.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Sweet.
Rym: Panel two.
Rym: While he's choking to death, he yells at him.
Rym: And in panel three, he kills it.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Then it turns out it was just a pinata.
Rym: And let me tell you, this is like the worst comic of the lot.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Worse than the NASCAR heroes?
Rym: Well, it might have sounded, I don't know, funny or weird.
Rym: It's just it's drawn really, really badly.
Rym: Well, I think that it's.
Rym: no, it's not like other Sonics are drawn really well.
Rym: This is drawn in that kind of super cheap, super off model, no backgrounds, like just really, really.
Rym: It's awful.
Scott: That's sad.
Rym: And the story is dumb.
Rym: And it's even for a little kid.
Rym: I can't imagine a little kid enjoying this at all.
Scott: All right.
Scott: We need to pick up the pace here, I think a little bit.
Scott: Do we?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I went along with the last one.
Scott: So we got Bongo comics free for all.
Scott: You might be thinking, what the hell's Bongo comics?
Scott: Bongo is the soup of the Simpsons Futurama type comics of awesome.
Scott: Now, this it's funny because I don't buy any Simpsons or Futurama comics.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But every year I read the free comic book of it and I really like it.
Scott: And this year, more than ever before.
Scott: And the best thing about this year's Simpsons comic offering is that they actually.
Scott: this actually helps me figure out like what Simpsons comics are published.
Scott: It's like there's a Simpsons comic monthly.
Scott: There's a Bart Simpson bi-monthly.
Scott: There's a Futurama comics bi-monthly.
Scott: There's a Simpsons super spectacular that's bi-annual.
Scott: There's a Simpsons treasure trove that's going to be digest size coming this summer.
Scott: Sixty four pages each.
Scott: So like this teaches me about all the different Simpsons comic buying options.
Scott: And I'm thinking, I like this.
Scott: I like Simpsons.
Scott: I might actually be buying some Simpsons comics soon.
Scott: And the best part, actually, is at the end of this thing, there's a Simpsons and a manga parody that does a manga style Simpsons called Oui Oui called Bartamu.
Scott: And all you need to know is looking at the first page and it's like anime style and Bart like hitting a baseball while Nelson the catcher is like wind from swing is like kamikaze.
Scott: So mighty is its presumption.
Scott: And then comic book guy, the umpire, is taking off his mask and he says best hit ever.
Scott: Yeah, it's I like this action.
Scott: I think I might be buying.
Scott: maybe I'll get those digest size Simpsons treasure trove.
Scott: That looks pretty good.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I don't think I need to say this is good, but Atomic Robo is fantastic.
Rym: I don't think you understand how up my alley Atomic Robo.
Scott: I got all six issues of it in the other room.
Rym: Plus, remember, Atomic Robo, in case any of you forgot, is by Brian Clevenger, the eight bit theater guy.
Rym: And let me tell you, eight bit theater.
Rym: I feel like what that guy did is he made eight bit theater and he learned a lot about characterization and like how to make a good comic and good characters from it.
Scott: He definitely has the writing skills.
Scott: I still want to read his freakin atomic whatever book, Atomic Age or whatever it's called.
Rym: So he took everything you learn from that and from other things he's done.
Rym: and Atomic Robo is just great.
Rym: There's there's a little bit of Black Mage in Atomic Robo.
Scott: I think there's a little bit of like a lot of characters in Atomic Robo.
Scott: He's sort of an Indiana Jones Spider-Man Black Mage robot.
Rym: A little bit of Batman, too.
Rym: A little Batman, too.
Rym: I just I love the little Dr.
Scott: McNinja action.
Scott: The expressions on his face are priceless.
Scott: Even though he's a robot who has no expressions.
Rym: But he does.
Scott: But the art in Atomic Robo is like amazing.
Scott: I first saw the real art at Kinetic Con because they were sitting next to the Apple Geeks table and they showed me the art.
Scott: He had like a hole in his big portfolio.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Scott: Atomic Robo is like so great.
Rym: Irrespective of any of the other Atomic Robos, this one, the free comic book day one, a complete story start to finish is great.
Scott: Yeah, I'm definitely got to read that.
Scott: It's the only Atomic Robo I haven't read.
Rym: It's about a Soviet madman.
Scott: Oh, that's not in these six issues.
Scott: So I guess it's really good to get my hands on that.
Rym: And I like how it ends.
Rym: All right.
Rym: And also in this, they included Neozoic, which obviously that's another thing published by Red Five Comics.
Rym: Yeah, obviously they're trying to promote it.
Rym: It's it's OK.
Rym: It's kind of like well drawn, but kind of generic fantasy.
Rym: But fantasy with a little bit of a high tech edge.
Rym: So I'll have to read more before I pass judgment.
Rym: But I kind of like it.
Scott: You want you want me to order you some Neozoic?
Rym: Yeah, why not?
Rym: I kind of like it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I don't know if it'll be good.
Scott: I'll see if there's a trade or something.
Rym: It does the thing that always I always get a little irked when dragons are just like dumb animals as opposed to the awesome things there in D&D.
Rym: But yeah.
Scott: It's got kind of spoiled on those dragons.
Rym: And yeah, I'm used to a gold dragon.
Scott: But I think the balance is to have the really smart dragons, but had to be really rare.
Scott: But then because everyone likes seeing dragons all the time, you should have like dumb worm type creatures that people can fly around like Lindwurms.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Lindwurms don't have wings.
Rym: They can't really fly out.
Rym: But anyway, they're both pretty good.
Scott: OK.
Rym: Red five just seems to be busting out.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Red five is like sort relatively new publisher, relatively high quality.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Tiny Titans.
Rym: You know, I almost liked Teen Titans.
Rym: I decided I didn't.
Rym: But it took me two episodes of the show to realize that my problem with with Tiny Titans is that I don't know the Teen Titans at all.
Scott: Like I know Robin and I can kind of tell by looking at them like, OK, that's kid Flash and that's kid aqua kid and that's little Wonder Woman and that's, you know, a little green arrow guy, but he's red.
Scott: But then it's like, OK, robot dude, green kid, semi.
Scott: It's like Wonder Woman girl with blond hair girl who is the same color as like an X-Men sentinel little devil guy and girl with an X on her chest.
Scott: So I don't know any of them are.
Scott: But that didn't seem to matter because the art in this was just really cute and it was really silly.
Scott: But some of the jokes I didn't get because I didn't know the characters like this one joke where it's like, you know, oh, we're going to have a substitute teacher to substitute principal today.
Scott: It's Mr.
Scott: Slade.
Scott: Hello, students.
Scott: And then one girl in the class is like, my dad's the principal is so embarrassing.
Scott: But I don't know who the girl was or who the dad was.
Scott: So I didn't laugh.
Scott: But the second one is the green kid who I learned as Beast Boy.
Scott: And he goes and gets a dog and the dog won't play with him.
Scott: But then he turns into a green dog because he is turning into a dog.
Scott: powers that it's happy, cute.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I like that action.
Scott: Then the next one I also liked.
Scott: It was a funny story with like, you know, Robin.
Scott: And he's like, hey, your name is Speedy.
Scott: Can you run fast?
Scott: No, I shoot arrows.
Scott: Then the flash kid is right behind him.
Scott: So he's like, hey, flash kid.
Scott: And the flash kids looks like, yep.
Rym: OK, that's kind of lame.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: Maybe, you know, maybe describing it doesn't quite do it.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Scott: It's pretty much just cute and happy.
Scott: And there's some jokes about wearing jeans and playing with dolls.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So broken Trinity prelude.
Rym: I I had a bit of trouble trying to figure out what the hell this was about.
Rym: To be honest, there's a lot of words and the art was kind of generic.
Rym: And then at the end, it looked like it was just Witchblade.
Scott: But if I had one thing to say about this, I actually say the new Witchblade comic is not like Witchblade.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I'm looking at a big spread about the Witchblade comic.
Rym: And if one thing summed up like the selling points of it based on this promotional picture, it is tits.
Rym: She has gigantic breasts, like to the point that they stand out painfully to.
Rym: nipples are exposed through the shirt, which is unnecessary.
Rym: Three, she's grabbing one of them and she's like squeezing it.
Rym: And I don't know what kind of consistency this thing has, but she has put quite a dent into it.
Rym: It is surprising.
Rym: It does not look comfortable.
Rym: I don't think Witchblade is good.
Rym: I think it's just big tits.
Scott: Well, the my theory, I have a thinking going on now.
Scott: It's like, OK, if a comic or something has lots of boobs in it, right.
Scott: They made a conscious decision to put those boobs there, right?
Scott: If the thing you have, your comic, your anime or whatever is good, why would you put boobs in it?
Scott: That would only cheapen it.
Scott: Well, they can't remember it.
Rym: The only possibility is they're pulling a chareau, right, pulling out the best scenario.
Scott: And that's still.
Rym: I've got to trick people into reading my philosophy and sci fi.
Rym: I'm going to put jiggly butts and then around the jiggly butts will be science fiction.
Rym: OK, but the other thing, all the art in this is just that kind of fantasy art.
Rym: I hate of like semi naked women with chainmail bikinis straddling swords with snakes around their necks.
Rym: It's just crap.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Del Rey and Dabble Brothers, 2008 preview.
Scott: Now, this is one of those.
Scott: I hate these because they do these on free comic book day.
Scott: instead of actually giving you like a whole bunch of one comic where you can sort of get your teeth into it and decide if you like it or not.
Scott: They give you like a tiny bit of a bunch of different comics.
Scott: So you have no idea what they're about or if they're good or not.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So we've got, let's see, Dresden Files, Wild Cards, Frankenstein and In God We Trust.
Scott: So this is Jim Butcher, George R. Martin, Dean Koontz and Dean Koontz.
Rym: Dean Koontz?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I used to read a lot of Dean Koontz novels as a kid.
Scott: Basically, what we've got here is we've got people making comics based on, you know, books and TV shows or whatever in order to try to get sales.
Scott: It's like a licensed property deal, right?
Rym: I wonder if they'll ever get together and just make a comic about strangers, which was an OK novel that Dean Koontz wrote, except for the fact that the end is the stupidest thing ever.
Scott: Anyway, the Dresden Files one makes no sense.
Scott: Scott Johnson had to explain it to me.
Scott: Wild Cards, completely lame.
Scott: All I got from it was it's sort of like X-Men, only the mutants are ugly.
Scott: Then we got Frankenstein, a sort of Frankenstein story that sort of got a little B. Shonen twist on it.
Scott: But the art is all sort of ugly.
Scott: It's a little eh.
Scott: And then the in God we trust, actually, the art is sort of like this black and white manga styling like U.S.
Scott: sort of mix up kind of thing.
Scott: And this could actually, you know, regardless of the art, the story was seemed a little bit like Silence of the Lambs.
Scott: ish kinds of story almost.
Scott: And I don't know, I'm a little little intrigued by.
Scott: I don't know if I'll buy it, but it's a little.
Scott: maybe it's got something to it.
Scott: Maybe we'll check it out.
Scott: I like some of the characters in it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So real quick, Jughead, generic Archie comic.
Rym: It's there's really nothing there.
Rym: But if you like that sort of thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Amelia rules is I don't think I would read it.
Rym: This is definitely aimed at kids.
Rym: There's not much for, I don't know, anyone over the age of 12 to get out of it.
Rym: But I feel like it's not that bad for a certain like demographic of 10 to 12 year olds.
Rym: Yeah, it's an OK, solid story, you know, touches on issues a little bit.
Rym: Doesn't get too deep into it.
Rym: I don't know what the deal is with all these other Amelia rules things, because halfway through, well, near the end, it cuts to all these photographs and I don't get it.
Rym: But I think there's a lot of other Amelia rules stuff that I don't know about since I'm not really connected to the current Nickelodeon generation is even a Nickelodeon thing.
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: But I don't even know what Amelia rules is.
Rym: I don't know either.
Rym: All I know is it's OK.
Rym: OK, it's a kid's thing.
Scott: So check it out.
Scott: I got this one graphic classics.
Scott: And this is actually really cool because it's free, but it's a lot of pages and there's almost no ad.
Scott: There's basically no ads in it except for it for itself.
Scott: And what this is, is you got a story by Po, a story by Beers, a story by Lord Dunsany, I like a story by Conan Doyle and a story by Mary Shelley.
Scott: But these aren't stories that most people are likely to know.
Scott: And they took short stories by these people and they just made comics to those stories.
Scott: And the best one is the Ambrose Pierce one about the diet called Diagnosis with the monkey and the oyster.
Scott: That is, it's one page is the best one.
Scott: But the rest of it, you know, the stories are quality and there's like different artists on each story and they sort of some of the art I think is better than some of the other art.
Scott: But definitely not a gyp.
Scott: They could have charged me money for this.
Scott: And actually they got the ads for all their other graphic classics.
Scott: And I'm thinking, huh, maybe I'll get the fantasy classics or maybe just like the H.G.
Scott: Wells ones or something like that.
Scott: See what's up.
Rym: Right.
Rym: So Worlds of Aspen, I'm not entirely sure what the hell this was.
Rym: I think it's a whole bunch of different comics.
Scott: Aspen is a publisher that does like a whole bunch of fantasy kind of things, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Because two of them are written by the same guy.
Rym: And if you open it, it starts with three bikini girls.
Rym: So I think they're, again, trying to target a certain demographic.
Rym: The art's good, but the first story, there were too few pages.
Rym: I have no idea what it's about.
Rym: So that was useless.
Rym: It's called Fathom.
Rym: The second one, Soul Fire, was also too short to figure out what was going on.
Rym: It was kind of generic.
Scott: It's just like that Dabble Brothers one.
Scott: They give you a whole bunch of stuff, but each one is too short.
Scott: They should give you one big one and then forget the others.
Rym: The third one's just really dumb.
Rym: It doesn't make any sense.
Rym: It's called Shrugged.
Rym: I don't even want to bother trying to explain what it's about.
Rym: And the last one is super stereotypical and kind of annoying to read.
Rym: It's basically what if we made a comic about a woman who is just as bad ass as Oren Ishii and we had every possible like Chinese triad stereotype in the world.
Rym: It's just it's dumb and it ends with nakedness.
Scott: OK, so for free comic book day, DC thought it would be a good idea instead of making a new comic to just reprint All-Stars Superman number one and put that out as a free comic.
Scott: And I've never read All-Stars Superman number one, so I read it.
Scott: It's a pretty much average Superman story with really good arts because it's Frank quietly and his arts are really awesome.
Scott: But other than that, it's sort of like a generic Superman story.
Scott: Oh, Lex Luthor is bad.
Scott: He's coming to get you.
Rym: I got to go back to World of Aspen.
Rym: I forgot I read this on the train and I was like, there's no way I can go with.
Rym: the writing is awful.
Rym: I'm going to quote something a character is saying and see if you can point out the grammatical problem here.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Release the boy, relinquish the box of which you hold and turn yourself in.
Rym: Uh, of which?
Rym: what the fuck?
Rym: Sorry, I couldn't let that slide.
Rym: That was just that was bullshit right there.
Rym: But speaking of bad comic, this is here's another one.
Rym: A lot of these comics, they kind of start in the middle of a story.
Rym: Don't tell you what got what's going on.
Rym: And they're just really generic, like they don't stand out.
Rym: But Salem, Queen of Thorns is about one bad ass Puritan, a bunch of lame Puritans and a bunch of evil Puritans who all work for the church.
Scott: So so what does it think appears to say good or bad things about Puritan?
Rym: I can't tell pure.
Rym: Obviously, the Salem witch trials are bad, but I don't know why there are crusader knights, because I don't think there were crusader knights in America in Puritan times.
Rym: It's it's.
Rym: I think it's going for that.
Rym: Check it out.
Rym: We're dark and we're full of religious symbolism.
Rym: Oh, man, look how dark and and like we're going to make fantasy and history together.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: Yeah, I think we got to move along here.
Scott: Yeah, we do.
Scott: So let's do this X-Men one that we both read.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Basically, you had here a one shot X-Men story and the actual X-Men themselves, you know, the characters, you know, in love weren't in it that much.
Scott: And actually, they have the ugly cat beast I don't like.
Scott: But it was really a story about, you know, one girl who's a mutant and she has her, you know, troubled mutant life.
Scott: And that's really where X-Men stories have always shined.
Scott: I think, you know, you get your kiddie pride, your jubilees, kiddie pride.
Rym: Scott Johnson's having a fit right now.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So this is just sort of like one of those stories executed in a really good and modern way with very high quality arts.
Scott: And it was decent.
Scott: It wasn't amazing, but it was good stuff.
Scott: And it kind of makes me wish that X-Men comics were just all like this, as opposed to the way they are, which is unreadable.
Rym: Yeah, because, I mean, I enjoyed it.
Rym: It was pretty good.
Rym: Had a couple of corny moments, but it was pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, it had some corny moments in it, like when the X-Men showed up with their, you know.
Rym: But I'll say this, I liked it and I like the style of art now, as opposed to Iron Man and Hulk and Spider-Man.
Scott: Oh, God, let's see.
Rym: And they fight Mandarin.
Rym: And it starts out with a page explaining Mandarin's rings and what they all do.
Scott: What do they all do?
Rym: Oh, and Ant-Man is also in it.
Scott: Doesn't Ant-Man like actually get really big?
Rym: Yeah, well, it starts out little.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's really, really cheesy.
Rym: And I guess if you like that sort of thing.
Scott: That's actually, the X-Men was just Marvel straight up.
Scott: That is Marvel Adventures, so it's meant for kids.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I guess it wasn't bad.
Rym: It was just not up my alley, necessarily.
Rym: There's one good part where they're all about to fight, and then Spider-Man's like, "Wait, wait,
Rym: no!".
Rym: And then everyone kind of stops fighting.
Rym: They're like, "What's going
Rym: on?"
Rym: And he's like, "All right, guys, we're in this ancient world of the, like, Wonder of the World temple, and the Hulk's here.
Rym: So I don't think I want to be responsible for destroying it.
Rym: Can we all just agree to walk outside and then start fighting
Rym: again?".
Rym: And then they all go outside and fight.
Scott: That's, see, that's the reason I like Spider-Man is because of shit like that.
Scott: They should, that's why, you know, that's what makes Spider-Man comics good, is that Spider-Man has that attitude on most of the time.
Rym: But the Hulk is just dumb, but I don't know.
Rym: I like the Mandarin.
Rym: I kind of was rooting for him because...
Scott: Yeah, you like the Mandarin.
Scott: You like the Mandarin in Marvel Team Up also.
Rym: Well, because he's evil and he's not stupid.
Scott: I think you're a Mandarin man.
Rym: I think I am.
Scott: I like it.
Rym: You know why?
Rym: Because much like Jafar, he sneers.
Rym: And he sneers in this way.
Rym: that is very endearing to me.
Scott: Maybe we'll have to go get you a copy of, like, Best of the Mandarin if such a thing exists.
Rym: All right, but let's move along here.
Rym: Dan Dare is crap.
Rym: I don't get it.
Rym: I don't like it.
Rym: It's really, really lame and kind of, like, it takes itself way too seriously for what's going on.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I only say that because I've actually received multiple Dan Dares from the publisher before ever since I got in this press mailing list from, you know, being at the New York Comic Con.
Rym: They keep sending me these Dan Dare comics.
Rym: None of them are good.
Scott: Yeah, people are talking those up, but Rims doesn't like them.
Scott: I'll have to check.
Rym: You should read them.
Scott: I'll read that one.
Scott: I'm not going to read the other one.
Rym: It's just, it could be OK, but the art is generic.
Rym: It takes itself way too seriously.
Rym: And Dan Dare has got kind of this, look at me.
Rym: I'm perfect.
Rym: And I'm going to save everybody all the time.
Scott: I got here Comics Go Hollywood.
Scott: Now, what this is, it's not actually a comic.
Scott: It's by Tomorrow's publishing.
Scott: And if you're looking for sort of a high brow alternative to like Wizard magazine, Tomorrow's is where it's at.
Scott: Like if you want to learn shit about comics and get like high quality real interviews and awesome arts and all that sort of stuff in a black and white magazine, Tomorrow's provides like tenfold.
Scott: And what this is, is a little tiny magazine in the Tomorrow's style that contains a bunch of articles relating to, you know, comics and Hollywood together and TV and movies and all that stuff.
Scott: They talk about, you know, the people who are animating some, you know, DC New Frontier DVDs.
Scott: They talk with Jeff Loeb about something.
Scott: They talk about the X-Men movie that might have been made in 1984, but didn't actually get made.
Scott: They talk about like the history of the art style of the Joker.
Scott: And it's pretty interesting.
Scott: And it was really wordy and is pretty impressive for something that's free.
Scott: And Tomorrow's usually puts out high brow stuff.
Scott: I just don't read it because I don't care enough to actually read a magazine about this kind of thing all the time.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I got like four more here.
Scott: And I got three more.
Rym: I feel like we should just wrap it up.
Scott: We should just wrap it up.
Rym: Let's just give like the plus or like the hey for the rest of them.
Rym: And I got one I want to talk about.
Rym: OK.
Rym: So the stranded kind of generic modern fantasy issue look pretty cool.
Rym: I actually wasn't that bad.
Rym: Love and Capes was just really not up my alley at all.
Rym: I guess if you're into superheroes, but I didn't like it.
Rym: It's like superheroes, but live in normal lives.
Rym: But they're all still superheroes all the time.
Rym: And one guy wants to like top 10.
Rym: One guy wants to ask like he's Superman.
Rym: He wants to ask this girl to marry him.
Rym: But I don't know.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I got very little to say about it.
Rym: Gekiga is Gekiga.
Rym: You should read Gekiga.
Scott: Yeah, actually, that was originally.
Scott: they were going to misspell the title.
Scott: They were going to call it Gekiga.
Scott: And then I guess they corrected it, which I guess someone told them.
Scott: All that is, is a preview.
Scott: If you don't know, if you want to read the Yojihiro Tatsumi drawn and quarterly real Gekiga stuff that will let you know if you want to read it or not.
Rym: OK, you should.
Scott: Of course you should.
Scott: OK, what do I got here?
Scott: I got an entertaining comic sampler, E.C.
Scott: Comics.
Scott: They used to publish like all the pulp comics way back in the day.
Scott: We're talking like, you know, Cryptkeeper type stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And basically like Tales from the Crypt and Weird Science.
Scott: E.C.
Scott: was who published all those.
Scott: And Gemstone, which are the people who publish the Disney comics, are publishing the E.C.
Scott: Comics.
Scott: And this is a sampling of some E.C.
Scott: And I like E.C.
Scott: Comics a lot more than I thought I would.
Scott: And I maybe I'll buy some trades or hardcovers or something of some weird science because that's like in that action.
Scott: Very Twilight Zone ish.
Scott: Pulpish kind of stuff.
Scott: Ape Entertainment's cartoon palooza.
Scott: Yeah, this is just like really bad cartoons in comic form, like, you know, like those kids cartoons, but like the art is sort of bad.
Scott: And, you know, of course, the art on the final one, the Ursula Wild was actually pretty good.
Scott: That was probably the only thing worth reading in here.
Scott: Everything else in here was just sort of like bleh and whatever.
Scott: And then the last thing I got is Kid Houdini and the Silver Dollar Misfits.
Scott: This was a little bit better than some of the other ones in terms of, you know, kid stuff.
Scott: But the art was really sort of it didn't really grab me.
Scott: And the plot was sort of like this really generic and obvious of, oh, there's a bunch of misfit kids stuck at the evil carnival.
Scott: In the back, there was actually this other story about like, you know, kids and they're like detective agency of checking out, you know, cryptozoology, whatever.
Scott: And the art and that was actually really cute.
Scott: But the story was lame.
Rym: And that's all I got to end this because I'm really hungry.
Scott: I'm also really hungry.
Rym: NASCAR heroes.
Scott: Oh, I forgot that it was now we thought we were done.
Rym: I thought this would be about like people who are NASCAR racers.
Rym: And it seemed like that was it.
Rym: What what it was going to be about.
Rym: And then there was this ghost of a NASCAR driver who had died and he's like a headless NASCAR's man.
Scott: And that sounds pretty cool.
Rym: No.
Scott: Imagine if, like, you know, look at the track.
Rym: Look at that.
Rym: This makes no sense.
Scott: I kind of.
Scott: I mean, if you wrote a comic about like the ghost of Ayrton Senna coming and beating Michael Schumacher, that was awesome.
Rym: But it wasn't that it made no sense.
Rym: And then in the end, he falls into this alligator pit and he beats the alligators up.
Rym: And then like the plot finishes for the story.
Rym: And I was thinking, wait a minute.
Rym: How do you beat the alligators up?
Rym: They kind of mentioned that he has superpowers.
Rym: And then after the comic, they have a little kind of preview.
Rym: explanation of yes, this comic is actually about NASCAR drivers with superpowers.
Rym: If you have superpowers, why would you drive NASCAR?
Rym: I'm going to read for you the introduction, the yellow text.
Rym: NASCAR, a sport not like no other.
Rym: Eight hundred horsepower driving action.
Rym: A sport like no other with fans like no other.
Scott: There's a lot of other.
Rym: Sure, being a janitor, I got picked on, even pushed around by him.
Rym: Jack Diesel.
Rym: He was the hottest driver in NASCAR.
Rym: Not very nice, as I would find out later.
Rym: He was a very bad man.
Rym: Less successful.
Scott: He was a very bad man.
Scott: It says that.
Rym: Were my friends on the flat stock racing crew.
Rym: Gus, Zip, Ed.
Rym: Now these guys are so generic.
Scott: Gus, talk about a mechanic's name.
Scott: He was the mechanic.
Rym: And Zip was the engineer.
Rym: And Ed is like the pit crew guy.
Rym: They had they had just lost their driver to another team.
Rym: I thought like their boss, Esther, Esther Shockington said that the next race would be their last.
Scott: I mean, I saw that we had NASCAR heroes.
Scott: I knew that that would sort of like be the, you know, the shitty kid in class.
Scott: I don't think I realized where this is going that bad.
Rym: I don't think you realize I haven't gotten that yet.
Rym: Oh, God, I point out that there's a bunch of typos here.
Rym: Oh, God, I felt bad for my friends who might lose their job.
Rym: And for me, because Esther Barley knew I was alive.
Rym: That would soon change.
Rym: OK, that doesn't make any sense.
Scott: I don't get it.
Rym: And there was a bunch of typos there.
Rym: I had to read over.
Rym: Everything would change.
Rym: I stumbled upon Diesel as he experimented with what seemed to be an illegal fuel source.
Rym: And it shows him in a lab holding up this beaker and like going.
Scott: If he has superpowers, wouldn't he be better off with like have superpowers yet with a bicycle powered car?
Rym: You got to see this picture.
Rym: Jack Diesel is holding up this pedal faster than the engine.
Rym: And he's looking up at it with that scientist look.
Rym: And there's this evil looking Doberman just kind of watching him.
Rym: Maybe this was his secret to winning all those races.
Rym: As I looked closer, Diesel dropped the mysterious substance dropped to the floor.
Rym: But as I looked closer, Diesel dropped the mysterious substance dropped to the floor.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: Did a NASCAR fan write this?
Rym: The results were explosive.
Rym: I was thrown across the compound.
Scott: Can we can you please spare me any more pain?
Rym: But was completely unhurt.
Rym: In fact, when I woke up at a time and heard cries for help, I realized I'd never felt better.
Rym: I was faster, stronger.
Rym: Best of all, I was a hero.
Scott: Are you done?
Rym: As it turned out, that explosion had affected us all.
Rym: Gus was super strong.
Rym: Zip could well zip.
Rym: An ad could duplicate himself over an hour.
Rym: We all had superpowers.
Rym: Later, Esther's electric personality would pour over into her own superpowers.
Rym: Jag Diesel, we found out, had acquired the most powers of all and had plans to use those powers to cheat in the NASCAR Sprint Cup series.
Scott: He's going to cheat at NASCAR.
Rym: His eyes are like on fire.
Rym: If my eyes are on fire.
Rym: I couldn't let that happen.
Rym: The explosion had also enhanced my natural driving abilities, so I donned the flat stock fire suit and helmet.
Scott: That's the new identity.
Rym: Jimmy Dash.
Rym: It goes on.
Rym: This was awful.
Scott: It sounds like, though, it's so awful that it has some qualities.
Rym: No, no, no, it does not.
Rym: It it was much more funny with me reading.
Rym: You do not want to read that.
Rym: That is the worst comic a free comic book day.
Rym: And it's time to go make some bacon.
Scott: You want to have sort of a free comic day verdict?
Rym: I'm I don't know.
Rym: I feel like a lot of companies just do it because they have to.
Scott: They don't have to.
Rym: It's completely up to them, but they feel like they have to for marketing purposes.
Scott: Well, they should.
Scott: It is.
Scott: It's good marketing if you do it right.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: companies don't do it right.
Rym: I think we should talk about free comic book day as a concept on another night.
Scott: All right, we'll do it.
Rym: Time to make some bacon.
Rym: Good night, Internet.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rimon Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution, non-commercial, share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.