Scott: It's Thursday January 3rd.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight epiphanies.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Woman.
Scott: it is cold.
Scott: It is.
Rym: I think today was the coldest day.
Rym: It's been all year.
Scott: It is the coldest.
Scott: It's definitely the coldest day.
Scott: It's been this year.
Scott: Yeah, I do think so, but I think it's.
Scott: I think it's also the coldest.
Scott: It's colder than any day last year as well.
Rym: No, definitely not.
Rym: it didn't even get below zero.
Scott: No, it was.
Scott: there was just something about the way it felt you know because temperature feeling you know isn't really related that much to The absolute measured temperature.
Scott: by a thermometer I mean if you put your hand in some cold water And then put it in some warm water the warm water feels hot.
Scott: so there was just Something about the way the weather was today.
Scott: it felt Stupidly cold.
Rym: that's because it was stupidly cold 9 to 10 degrees this morning, and it got up to a record 15 16 by the midday.
Scott: Yeah, like every car was having the smoke come out the exhaust you know and the condensation and the man we my actually the Coldest part of the day surprisingly enough was indoors is.
Scott: My boss got back to work And he locks his office and his office is big windows.
Scott: So he got back to work and he opened his office and we went in there And it was so cold in that office colder than it was outside.
Scott: It was just crazy.
Rym: I think the worst thing is I get on the train right and The trains heater just messed up in the car and I went to another car was the same just couldn't keep up Really it.
Rym: I mean all the heat was on full blast, but it wasn't enough and the car was out of Chile.
Scott: I didn't have that problem, but sometimes like today both trains I took to work and home were nice and warm and toasty, but sometimes like I'll be on a train and beacon It's nice and warm.
Scott: But then as soon as it gets to Croton and switches to the electric the heat won't be so good anymore.
Scott: And I think that the diesel heat is superior to the electric heat.
Rym: That's my theory about probably on the crappy old train cars.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I wish they just build that third rail all the way here.
Scott: I wish they would too, but they need probably more power plant to do that or something.
Rym: well that the thing is that is in The plan, but it's not in the near-term plan.
Scott: Yeah, couldn't they just build like a transfer station like in Cortland or something wouldn't that were?
Rym: I don't know What do you mean?
Scott: I don't know some sort of electric boosty machines.
Scott: You know if those big coily things on him and hot wires the reason they don't do it is because it's not cost-effective.
Rym: Yeah, probably there aren't enough terrains going to Poughkeepsie or beacon to justify it.
Scott: Oh funnily enough you know I've always kind of wondered like how close you have to get to the third rail for it to be Dangerous.
Scott: you know cuz I just stay clear away from it as far as I can.
Rym: but I think instruction guys like just jumping over It.
Scott: yeah today I was just.
Scott: I saw some guys and they were standing like two feet away from it, and they were just fine.
Scott: So I was like huh, okay that that little guard protect II thing on it must be pretty protect II.
Rym: Well the thing is it's not gonna arc over to you unless you are kick it or Provide some sort of very convenient path.
Scott: take a metal rod and stick it down into the tracks.
Rym: You don't want to pee on it either.
Scott: Yeah peeing on it's probably on.
Rym: It's probably the last thing you want to do.
Scott: don't whiz on the electric fence.
Rym: Maybe we should do a show about Ren and Stimpy and how it was funny.
Scott: You want to tell we could do that today?
Scott: Kind of Wednesday show.
Rym: save it for Wednesday cuz there's two.
Rym: we could talk about two related things.
Rym: We would talk about utenna and red and Stimpy.
Rym: no because they're related in a very important way in that by taking a crazy person and then Limiting what they are allowed to do you can make great art.
Rym: Let's take that limit away.
Scott: You get crazy person you get.
Rym: you get that thing that they called Ren and Stimpy when it came back.
Scott: Yeah, that was all that other cable network where I only watched one episode.
Rym: It was all.
Rym: everything was like man.
Rym: was it spike TV or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't watch TV anymore.
Scott: That was years ago.
Rym: I just remember buzz about it and then a YouTube Ren and Stimpy and it was disgusting But it wasn't funny.
Rym: at least the old Ren and Stimpy was disgusting and funny.
Rym: Yep, usually usually All right, so, uh, I found this a while ago.
Rym: I've been waiting to talk about it.
Rym: It's definitely a Thursday thing But I saw a flurry of news articles about this pretty much from about a week and a half ago on Mm-hmm, and this.
Rym: I'm just linking to one of many.
Rym: I don't know if this is a marketing campaign or if it's just the time is right But I tell you tell me what it is and I'll tell you the thing is.
Rym: I feel as though it's about time Because I was way ahead of the curve on this one.
Rym: Prices fall as more people discover handles ease of use the doorknobs.
Rym: days are numbered.
Rym: You know this.
Rym: you find your hand clenching a doorknob and twisting it.
Rym: less often more people You know.
Rym: You just push down on a lever whether it's a simple 5-inch bar or a brass handle curved with the line of a dog's tail.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and there's this whole article about.
Rym: and there's a bunch of stuff why in the last several months suddenly Door handles are a lot cheaper than doorknobs and suddenly becoming very popular in new homes.
Scott: I can give you one reason that I just thought of cuz I'm so smart.
Rym: I have the biggest reason handicap accessible.
Rym: That's part of it.
Scott: But the thing is yeah smart I am.
Rym: yeah The thing is that that's been around for a long time and a lot of public buildings had to use that.
Rym: so If there's so much better, which they are I think doorknobs are just this obsolete horrible thing.
Scott: Yeah, they're the most think about it.
Scott: the friction I mean you pushing down a handle easy turning a knob you might slip.
Rym: not only that but all right Sam walking And I got a cup in each hand.
Rym: How the hell am I gonna turn a doorknob?
Scott: Exactly exactly.
Rym: Well, I got some kind of maneuver, but you probably don't want to see it involving feet Involving something involving mouths and who knows what crotches Good God, well, it could be a pot of kiki Musume.
Scott: That is that isn't a pot of kiki Musume It's a greased up doorknob and you're holding two boiling hot cups of coffee.
Rym: But I did see actually someone on Farg pointed out the the one drawback of the door handle that door handles are Actually designed for one purpose and only one purpose.
Rym: if you're wearing a robe and you walk past one They will invariably catch in the sleeve of the robe and pull it off of you.
Scott: Isn't that a good thing?
Rym: Not if it's cold?
Scott: I guess not but I mean it's.
Scott: I would think of that as an extra utility not as a oh Crap, I forgot.
Rym: I was wearing this robe.
Rym: Good thing.
Rym: I'm naked now.
Rym: Thank you doorknob.
Rym: Well door handle.
Rym: Thank you Precisely.
Rym: if the doorknob did it.
Rym: I'd be a little scared.
Scott: cuz I mean think about it.
Scott: when if I'm wearing a robe When am I gonna pass by the door handle on the way out of the bathroom?
Scott: That's not really gonna happen.
Scott: It's gonna happen on the way into the bedroom Which is when I was gonna take the robe off anyway to put on normal clothes.
Rym: So what if you have a door handle on your exterior door?
Scott: Don't do that.
Rym: Well, you will eventually.
Rym: you know why the prices are going down suddenly because I actually for a long time and I remember this as a kid because you know We moved and basically for most of my life.
Rym: I had my brother and I had separate bedrooms and One day I was a little kid and I came home from school and I saw.
Rym: I almost said came home from work But I came home from school.
Rym: I saw you know, I saw the front door and I realized wait a minute how come?
Rym: the bathroom in the house has a lock and The front door has a lock but my bedroom doesn't have a lock Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I went to my mom and said I want a locking door.
Rym: My mom said what do you have to hide?
Rym: You're seven.
Rym: Yeah He just wants to play with the lag and I said there's none of your business.
Rym: I have my rights.
Rym: Yeah, actually they said alright fine you can have privacy.
Rym: my brother and I both got Doorknobs with locks.
Scott: They're like 30 bucks.
Rym: Well, the thing is we went to the store right and Home Depot doorknobs were between 15 and $40.
Rym: You could get a fancy one or a glass one or something But I'm like a brass one with a with a decent lock.
Scott: that was kind of expensive.
Rym: Well, the thing is most of them are just a bathroom style lock.
Rym: that is basically.
Scott: those are cheap.
Scott: I'm talking about ones that have an actual key and a lock that would require an average amount of picking to open.
Rym: But even then I mean the bathroom lock though those really only serve one purpose and to prevent accidentally seeing someone naked.
Rym: Yep, it doesn't stop you from opening the bathroom door.
Rym: Oh, it doesn't stop your mom from catching you masturbating.
Rym: All it does is give you precious time.
Scott: Well, I think that you should never have an actual locking bathroom door.
Scott: Cuz what it you know, the bathroom is someplace that someone is likely to have some sort of problem.
Rym: Oh, it's the most dangerous room in the house.
Scott: I mean, you know if someone they always say.
Scott: I think I've heard someone say this if someone's having a heart attack Don't let them go in the bathroom.
Scott: and you know, someone could be like having crazy diarrhea in there.
Scott: You know who someone could pass out in there.
Rym: You know if it's the crazy diarrhea and my choice is open the door and save them or just let it be well No, I mean like there's a.
Scott: if someone in your house Right is in need of going to the hospital the room that they are most likely in is the bathroom.
Scott: Therefore if the bathroom is locked you're delaying them precious time in which they could be on the way to the hospital.
Rym: I know you pause between the word precious and time and I also pause.
Rym: did you almost say ambergris?
Scott: No, cuz I almost said ambergris ambergris it is, okay.
Scott: But uh, I got you know, a normal if whales live in your house and vomit in the bathroom.
Rym: And then I realized that wait a minute I didn't think my clever plan through.
Rym: sure I can do whatever I thought I was gonna get away with.
Rym: my door will be locked.
Rym: Mostly was my brother can't get in but now I can't lock the door when I'm not in my room Mm-hmm, and if I do You can just open the door trivially.
Rym: so I demanded a better one.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And then they said we'll buy it yourself.
Rym: So I saved up my money and I bought or I spent a lot of money.
Rym: as a kid I spent like 50 bucks on a handle instead of a knob and the handle had an actual lock.
Scott: We have key for the outside.
Scott: pretty much every handle I've ever seen has an actual serious, you know reliable lock.
Scott: It's not some master lock of doom But it's it's a.
Rym: it's a lock that no not no normal person could open, of course I know for a fact later that my parents did exactly what I would do if I was a. They copied the key before they installed it.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: Yeah, well, you can't.
Scott: you can't let your kid have a. What if your kid like, you know as a screaming in the night, you can't go in there and rescue them Whatever that you don't do that.
Rym: What about butters?
Scott: That's that's exactly why.
Scott: But and of course you remember the the most important thing about a lock for a kids room is you need to also be Able to lock your kid in there when they're bad.
Rym: You know, that was probably the best thing my parents could have done if they wanted to punish me.
Rym: I had a TV in my room.
Rym: I had the NES.
Rym: I was said yep Now if they locked me in the room and then cut off the circuit breaker to the room and I didn't have any batteries for The game gear then I was fucked.
Scott: Well, even if you had batteries to the game gear you'd be fucked pretty soon Unless you went out the window to the to the convenience store, so The reason doorknob door handles are suddenly becoming popular is that the price has dropped crazily.
Rym: and the reason the price has dropped is because Basically people have had to put these in public buildings for a long time because of ADA requirements and whatever.
Rym: But as ADA requirements have gotten more and more strict they've had to make these things in more and more bulk as opposed to just for places of business.
Rym: and normally when a place of business buys it like if you buy a doorknob for a Public building it cost a hundred two hundred dollars sometimes because it has to be able to deal with the public.
Rym: Yeah, so the mechanisms in a lot of the lever handles and lever met things were Generally more robust and better and as a result cost a lot more money.
Scott: Mm-hmm people don't really understand how expensive doors are.
Scott: like a front door for your house is hundreds of dollars.
Scott: if you go to like some Building and they have those doors were like on one side There's a bar and you sort of push the bar to open and the other side is like a. you know Pulling, you know thing and then there's the mechanism at the top with that You know that closes the door automatically.
Scott: those doors could be like almost $1,000 sometime.
Rym: Actually when I used to work at IBM, there was a really damn good pizza place right there.
Rym: we went there like every day and Every day for as long as I had ever gone there and I'm pretty sure it's still this case.
Rym: The front door was broken clearly broken barely a door and The only reason he didn't repair it was that it would cost $3,000 to repair it.
Rym: So instead he just kept the broken door.
Rym: It didn't even lock.
Rym: He figured no one's gonna steal the pizza.
Scott: Oh, no, someone stole my pizzas.
Scott: as long as they take the cash home at night I'm okay.
Rym: The funny thing was it was run by one guy and he was the biggest fattest Sweatiest most stereotypical pizza owned shop owner guy you've ever seen like on Futurama.
Rym: Yeah, exactly like that.
Scott: All right.
Rym: but the other reason is that a lot of people are getting old and I mean, there's more old people now in the US than we've ever had and old people have.
Rym: So they've been buying Door handles and there's been a market now for cheap consumer grade meaning they break in ten years door handles.
Rym: So as a result levers The long standard in Europe apparently are now becoming viable in America.
Scott: Now if we can just get the Japanese toilets for set you think I can take the the door handles as like, you know For the interior doors.
Scott: I don't know if I like it for the exterior doors so much Why I'm more a fan of the the handle.
Scott: Well, not so much.
Scott: I guess not the rotating handles.
Scott: I like the straight on vertical handle with the button on top of it for the front doors.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I I had an old old house that had those in Detroit.
Rym: Well, I had it my mom had it but Those things I don't think.
Rym: I don't think a single handle like that has ever been functional.
Scott: So the thing is believe it or not it the what I'm pretty sure install and broken the one that's true the one of my that we had in our house never worked.
Scott: and you know, that button doesn't do anything.
Scott: but My grandma when she lived in Queens it worked there.
Scott: that little button thing He worked.
Scott: you better go find that house in Queens and the house already sold for like a zillion dollars Probably because of that door handle, you know, she bought that house for like $50,000 a long time ago.
Scott: But then again a long time ago $50,000 was a lot more money.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah funny how inflation kind of kicks that hole.
Rym: Yeah, real estate is the best investment you can make in the bud.
Scott: Well, it still beats inflation by a lot Yeah, but even a decent mutual.
Rym: I can't talk about that.
Rym: Anyway, yeah Anyway, that's enough about doors.
Scott: I gotta do knobs.
Scott: So I gotta do news I guess.
Scott: okay My news is sort of a pre news.
Scott: I'm not actually gonna do a news I'm gonna do.
Scott: the prequel to news is next week cuz pretty much next week.
Scott: almost every news I'm gonna do is gonna be something that came out of CES.
Scott: cuz Next week, which is 7 the 7th 8th 9th and 10th of January in Las Vegas is the consumer electronic show And that's probably the main reason I'm waiting for a new laptop.
Scott: pretty much everything Important in nerd news is gonna happen there at least everything important like the next month.
Scott: We're talking video games.
Scott: We're talking computers.
Scott: We're talking audios.
Scott: We're talking, you know car GPS anything electronic Which is almost gadgets phones everything geeks care about.
Scott: we should go except for anime and comics Which is a separate show.
Scott: it's gonna go down at CES.
Scott: and if you listen to John Z Dvorak, there's no reason to go to CES because So many journalists go and talk about everything that happens there on their websites that you don't need to go.
Scott: You can get.
Rym: oh, I would go almost entirely to cause trouble exactly.
Scott: I would go to schmooze I go to the lobby, but Yeah, if you just reading gadget if you don't read and gadget any other time during the year reading gadget next week It's the only week you should read and gadget just every day.
Scott: go to in gadget and go through all the stories and See what went down because you're gonna see things and go And within a month or two you be able to buy those things.
Scott: maybe.
Rym: so if you're holding off on a laptop or you're thinking About buying a laptop anytime soon or phone or anything particularly laptop because stereo TV I'm buying a laptop in the next few months, and I'll do all your research for you.
Scott: monitor compute computer anything monitors Easy.
Rym: buy a Dell GPS.
Rym: buy a widescreen ultra sharp Dell.
Scott: They got new tells now though that are different.
Scott: so you got to wait and see.
Rym: Not really because well the thing is I know something good is gonna come out of Dell because they already did.
Scott: there's like this Clearish monitor.
Scott: that's very strange.
Rym: Well the prices of ultra sharps dropped by like two three hundred bucks recently.
Rym: Actually it was only ten dollars more to get the ultra sharp instead of the non ultra sharp of my monitor.
Scott: They got these new monitors.
Scott: It's like a piece of plastic and the monitors kind of behind it and the speaker.
Scott: you should see it.
Scott: It's pretty crazy, but yeah, this is the kind of stuff It's gonna happen next week.
Scott: so pay attention now And then maybe when I do news next week you can fast forward because you've already read it.
Rym: Yeah, especially when we start seeing the articles about the fancy new door handles.
Scott: Oh door handles electronic door handles fingerprint reading at all Things of the day.
Rym: so whatever I don't have a thing of the day.
Rym: I do what Scott does what every sane person in the world does I?
Rym: Look to Japanese television man.
Scott: We should just make a separate podcast.
Scott: That's like daily and it's like here is your funny Japanese television bit of the day.
Scott: of course There's a bunch of sites like that, and we just steal things from them.
Scott: ah the Internet's.
Rym: So uh you know those giant sticky men or those little sticky men at least not the giant ones.
Scott: the giant one I'm about to tell you about the ones like the hands on a string that you stretch And you fling them and they grab onto something there.
Rym: the similar idea kind of toy But the ones where it's like a little man, and he does back flips down a wall with little sticky pause.
Scott: Oh, I used to get.
Scott: I remember the first time.
Scott: I had one of those.
Scott: it was in a Captain Crunch And it was an octopus and you put it on the wall and the tentacles and sort of go.
Scott: ticket ticket ticket ticket ticket ticket.
Rym: Well, I remember we had something like that at Wildwood one year And I believe this is right after we'd gotten the multiple speeches from Scott Johnson's mom of don't make a mess Don't break anything.
Scott: I think that was a sticky hand in fact.
Rym: It was one of those sticky things.
Scott: they're all basically the same toy 25 cents from a vending machine at the biggest diner.
Rym: and So you know we get this whole speech about hey don't mess up the house Don't cause any damage seriously.
Rym: And there's fancy like the textured ceiling and the textured walls in the house, and I don't remember who did it, but pretty much Immediately after that speech it ended and the mom was gone.
Rym: one of those sticky men got thrown at the ceiling and I watched as it proceeded to not move.
Rym: And when it finally fell the next day there was a sticky hand shaped stain.
Scott: You know my grandparents the.
Scott: you know they when they were in Florida They were in one condo, and then they moved to another condo in the same sort of development, right?
Scott: But when they were in that first condo I used one of those sticky hands.
Scott: and in Florida You know it is really tall roof.
Scott: You know it's like way tall like Like the room itself was like two or three stories tall.
Scott: But you know you only were at the bottom, and there was nothing above you just air.
Scott: And then you know skylights, and I got a sticky hand stuck way up there, and it didn't come down anything for years.
Rym: But of course the Japanese decided that something had to be done with this idea.
Rym: so they They made a gigantic one and they put it on the side of a skyscraper, and that's all I need to say.
Rym: Amen it kind of works not really it works a little bit.
Scott: There's something about scale that makes things not work.
Scott: That's why we can't have giant ants.
Rym: That's probably a good thing.
Scott: I don't know I'd like to be a giant, and I'd rather be some kind of dinosaur.
Scott: No, no I think giant ants could beat dinosaurs.
Scott: cuz think about little ants can beat people.
Scott: so giant and Yeah, they can.
Rym: little ants can't beat people all right.
Scott: Then I'll go get one and you let it bite you and we'll see what happens.
Rym: See thing is I don't let it bite me.
Rym: I go squish.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is that big ant sneaks upright on a dinosaur With his mandibles or it collapses under its exoskeleton mandibles.
Rym: Meanwhile the t-rex actually existed.
Scott: yeah, okay anyway.
Scott: So here's a video that's been going around the internet a lot lately, but it's from April 20th 2006 and I think it's some stoned guys.
Scott: cuz the subtitle on YouTube is how he passed the time dot dot dot on 420. oh great Some stoned guys, that's that's great right, but this video has been getting pretty popular on the net lately.
Scott: this guy basically He's way downtown in New York City like near the Brooklyn Bridge or whatever.
Scott: He throws a paper airplane out the window a paper airplane Just like the kind that I know how to make and you know how to make the normal kind and throws it out the window And it goes on quite a dramatic flight, and that's it.
Scott: It's a throws it from pretty high up.
Scott: So I he might.
Scott: I think there might be a way to win like the Guinness Book of World Records her longest paper airplane fight By making like a high quality specialized sky airplane.
Rym: that's been done.
Scott: the records are Well beyond, but whenever they make a new tall building you can beat the record.
Scott: So you someone could go like that building in Taipei.
Scott: That's like the biggest building and probably beat the record.
Rym: actually I think a lot of them They do the throwing from level ground instead.
Scott: See I would do like longest paper airplane flight period and I throw it out of it like a jet.
Rym: We used to do that a lot at my back of the jet.
Scott: so well I throw it out the side of the jet where it wouldn't get sucked into the jet engine.
Rym: basically a Lot of times we were bored in high school.
Rym: We go to the Arts Department and get big things a poster board and make gigantic paper airplanes, then throw them off the roof.
Scott: Yeah, that's always a good time.
Rym: They would pretty much always go off over the horizon and into the park and then disappear And we never found any of them.
Scott: the trick is I would always make paper airplanes with these secret paper clip weight.
Scott: Paper clip is where it's at.
Rym: paper clip weight is for people who are absolutely incompetent at simply doing proper folds.
Scott: No, no the paper clip weight.
Scott: you do the proper folds And you add the paper clip weight for the extra boost and also to do tricks.
Scott: you can put it on like one side Of the other.
Rym: you can do that By folding the paper airplane properly.
Scott: you want to make some.
Scott: right.
Scott: you got to make the rudders.
Scott: But if you make the rudders and stuff and the paper clip you double on.
Rym: you don't need that.
Rym: We have to have some sort of a paper airplane contest.
Scott: all right.
Scott: Let's cheat.
Scott: I'll go on the internet type in best paper airplane print it out and fold it now.
Rym: Actually the best paper airplane I've ever seen in person was was in the science Olympiad You know in middle school.
Rym: in high school one of the events was You had to make a paper airplane that would stay in the air the longest Mmm, and you know I made one that went okay.
Rym: It was actually kind of tubular spiral, and I threw it really high that it unfolded and kind of helicopter down Mmm, and it did pretty well, but I didn't get a medal because uh the one that won I'd have to show it to you.
Rym: It's kind of this weird long flat design, but he threw it up, and it went sideways about 40 feet And then it flipped over dropped a little bit and went sideways another 40 feet or so and then flipped over and it just went back And forth and back and forth and it was up in the air for a long freaking time.
Scott: My favorite paper airplanes now are like the ones that it's a circle and you go to and it goes.
Rym: Those are actually pretty easy to make.
Scott: yeah, I know and people there have been a lot of you know for a while now.
Scott: I don't think anything's ever gonna come of it, but like you know aerospace engineers have been trying for a long time I think to design actual flying vehicles that use these circular shape like that But obviously no one succeeded because you don't have giant circles flying around
Rym: Right Wrong Time for the main vid I guess.
Scott: I guess what was it again?
Rym: Well, we were gonna talk about something and we were planning it.
Rym: We're ready to go.
Rym: and then Emily being infinitely wiser than us pointed out that we've already done that exact show.
Scott: well the thing is I don't think we haven't repeated any shows, but a lot of times we have a show and Invariably you know we talked about a thing of the day or a news and we'll go on a tangent of some sort.
Scott: right
Rym: I'm pretty sure we did a show about how to do what we were gonna talk about which included every anecdote I had planned on bringing right,
Scott: but like we'll tell one anecdote here an anecdote there And I think
Rym: we told them all in one show in this
Scott: I know But I think eventually what happens is a lot of times as we think all right What do we do a show on?
Scott: hey?
Scott: How about we do a show on this?
Scott: and even though we didn't do a show on that it was we did like some of it in its part of a show.
Scott: so there'd be like a little overlap and I don't know if we should keep trying to avoid that or if we should just deal with it.
Scott: Or because I mean you know I don't many shows there's gonna be overlap.
Scott: We can't.
Rym: really.
Rym: it's going to be a problem as long as we don't do the exact same show Which we were about to do and we're gonna start spicing it up a lot with interviews.
Rym: We've got a fantastic interview lined up for next Tuesday.
Scott: I'm not air until the following Tuesday But we gotta do to a Tuesday show this weekend then to fill in.
Rym: probably all right.
Scott: Well, we can do a lot this weekend as soon as we should we reveal because I think this is pretty big.
Scott: no No, that's not okay.
Rym: I'm excited about this one.
Scott: actually we'll get buzz.
Rym: I'm even going to play the game this weekend to prepare.
Scott: oh, man Oh, they already know it's something about a game.
Scott: Well.
Scott: It's a Tuesday.
Scott: They might They definitely know it's about a game.
Rym: I'm going to play this game my computer my ordinate.
Scott: Oh, they know it's a computer game.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Maybe not.
Rym: maybe it's an NES game.
Rym: I have a ROM.
Scott: Oh could be okay Interviewing what's-his-name?
Scott: Good pay yeah, no or not.
Rym: I wish.
Scott: so what are we doing the show on today?
Rym: Well Emily after shooting down our aspirations actually had a pretty good idea because Scott's Scott fries the best of these.
Scott: But you know something my that one's the best.
Rym: that one is just very poignant and also very hilarious okay, but it's no fusiform gyrus, but it's But just.
Rym: you know we kind of realize that And I'm sure you do.
Rym: you think back through your life and there there are times in your life where much like in burning wheel where suddenly you have an epiphany and You get a stat or you go to the aristocracy or whatever and have the mad powers Or you're in the middle of something mundane and suddenly you just realize something so profound that it changes your life Forever mm-hmm, and I realized that being geeks.
Rym: We've had a lot of these many of them pertaining to things such as video games Mmm, so I figured that would be a good thing to talk about.
Scott: We could tell you want me to talk about the one that you're hyping up first.
Rym: I think so because I think this kind of gives you the idea of where we're going with this.
Scott: all right.
Scott: well I'm not sure how true This is you know because I'm basically telling a story of my memories from when I was like zero one two and three here.
Scott: So who knows how accurate they are to real life or anything?
Scott: But my memory of when I was that young is you know as everyone's memory when they're that young?
Scott: very you know Speckled and feel like I have memories when I was that young of like jumping down The entire flight of stairs in my house in a single leap and landing just fine.
Rym: I also remember that I don't think that that really happened Because I've seen other kids do that.
Scott: I've never seen a kid do that.
Rym: I jumped out my second story window once now But I like.
Scott: my memory of it is basically like you know like I was Superman basically And I remember it like it was real.
Rym: so either there was magic in the world when I was a kid Or the head injury caused you to remember something not quite like what really happened.
Scott: Oh, no, okay, but anyway when I was a kid I remember coloring books and such and coloring because that's what kids do.
Scott: and you know I can still kind of like coloring even though I can't really color very well at all.
Scott: and now that Photoshop exists There are people who can color better than people have ever colored in the history of coloring And I can't but I can take some crayons, and I can do a mean color by numbers, but anyway When I was a kid I remember coloring and I remember people telling me coloring the lines in the lines Because that's what adults say to kids who are coloring that aren't coloring.
Rym: You know kids Just what la and they just keep scribbling.
Scott: yeah I just I remember being a kid and coloring and I remember people saying color in the lines And I remember not really understanding what they were saying, but that's all they said.
Scott: and Then I also remember that basically you know this.
Scott: I have a. there's a lot of people in your life And my mom has some like one of her friends from like high school like ancient times.
Scott: You know it's like still a friend.
Rym: You don't want your mom to hear you say that no You know ancient time.
Scott: it's one of those people like you call aunt and uncle, but they're not your aunt and uncle They're just you know friends.
Scott: They're not ancient.
Scott: They're just been friends for like a zillion years.
Scott: You know since my mom was like in high schools.
Scott: It's like 30 Something years long time you know and they they had kids.
Scott: cuz you know they're whatever and you know I'd go when I was young we I was much closer to that family, but you know I was over there I think for one of the birthday parties or something when I was maybe three something like that.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: and there's coloring going on everyone's coloring and I remember someone said color in the lines like they always did and for some reason at At that time or at least I remember that.
Scott: I remember coloring.
Scott: I remember coloring there.
Scott: I remember someone saying it there, and I remember going oh in the law And on that day Scott Reuben gained sentience, I think maybe yes or at least English language skills.
Scott: I Think I could talk.
Scott: I must have been able to talk by then.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: you know it's weird I it's very hard for me to place temporarily a lot of the memories from pretty much middle school and earlier.
Scott: I can do the middle schools.
Scott: elementary school gets a little faded towards earlier elementary schools.
Scott: I mean, I can't remember any of my problem right as I remember School has this delineation of grades.
Scott: so like the memories that are associated with school and stuff I can attach to the grades Yeah, but not the things.
Rym: they have to count backward to figure out what you think that happened in the summer or outside of school.
Scott: I can't match up with the year because I don't have the school to go by.
Rym: I mean I remember I went on this Gigantic road trip with my whole family and my grandma's conversion van.
Rym: We went all the way down the coast of Florida and up throughout And it's like all over the whole like eastern half of the country.
Rym: we went to space stuff And we did everything yeah for the life of me.
Rym: I have no idea when that happened.
Scott: Yeah, like I remember going to Disney World one or two times.
Scott: Don't ask me what years those were I have no clue.
Scott: Anyway got it got an epiphany that you want to share.
Rym: well I think the mo one of the more important ones in my life is that you know I?
Rym: Really cared about school when I was really young like you know kindergarten elementary school I was pretty much I'd never gotten a grade that wasn't an a and I always did my homework And I tried really hard and I was like grades mattered and you know everyone said I fell for that.
Rym: live for every long Like I'd sit there like I can't
Scott: hold no better They ever exist
Rym: so hard and like if I were thought that I was gonna get a beer something I'd worry about it like oh, no And I'd never cheat on homework and other people would cheat and I was horrified at this prospect.
Rym: and then Right around the I think was the last month of my sophomore year of high school.
Rym: The sophomore year of high school was when I that was probably the most difficult academic Period in my entire life.
Scott: those around the same time.
Rym: I figured it out, too But that might be a common thread, but for some reason I had like I was.
Rym: basically.
Rym: you know now I had my blog post about maximal output.
Rym: I think I was at the maximal academic output of a person of my intelligence who was in the 10th grade at that point.
Rym: Yes, I had no less.
Rym: I had no lunch and only one band class and the other seven classes were all like AP classes and like craziness like a full crazy stupid school schedule and Four nights a week.
Rym: I went to local community college to take chemistry and to be in their jazz band Mm-hmm.
Rym: I was like it was like I was doing everything I possibly could and I was getting all A's and I did.
Rym: all my time was spent working on homework and doing all this crap and and then right around the end of that year, I looked back and thought wait a minute.
Rym: and Forsona what prompted it to this day?
Rym: I have no idea what prompted it, but I remember very clearly.
Rym: I was walking down the hallway in the science wing of the high school Toward the advanced placement room where I guess they let the smart kids have this room instead of dealing with lockers where we could just keep Our stuff away from the general rabble and it was nominally a study room, but we just played poker in there Usually.
Rym: yeah good time and I saw all the other kids playing poker as they want to do and I suddenly realized wait a minute None of this matters and I skipped class for like the next three days.
Rym: Yeah, and I pretty much didn't really go to class again until my senior year.
Scott: Yeah, I mean when I you know, I got to high school I was still falling for the old lie like your grades in high school matter, you know in middle school They said your grades matter so much.
Scott: if you don't get good grades here you in high school You won't get to take honors or AP classes and then you'll be a homeless bum and you never be able to go to college.
Scott: Your grades matter so much.
Rym: I remember the worst thing was the the lies they were telling me when I was a junior and a senior.
Rym: and they're like To get into college.
Rym: you have to do all these things and all that You won't get into college.
Scott: and they yep, and then I got to high school and in freshman year of high school I got the best grades.
Scott: I probably ever got actually at RIT.
Scott: I got the best grades.
Scott: They ever got at RIT my fresh.
Rym: I mean you do have to be relatively smart and do things to get into a college.
Rym: Yes, but the things they were telling they basically actually like.
Scott: if you didn't do well enough to get Into Harvard you weren't good enough to get to anywhere.
Rym: Well, the worst thing is that they kind of they always like you have to have extracurricular activities and they tried to sell kit like out.
Rym: so many people were members of the National Honor Society or Sad.
Rym: sad is like.
Rym: that was like the saddest thing in my high school because sad was consistent Nothing, the only people in it were goody two-shoes kids who didn't have any other extracurricular activity or anything to make them stand out for college.
Rym: So they all joined.
Rym: sad because the school said you have to join a club or they won't let you into a college.
Rym: Yeah, and sad was sad.
Rym: and the National Honor Society I think what I really clinked clinched it for me was you had to do community service in order to get the honor society thing and independent of that the school was saying if you don't do community service, no college will let you in.
Rym: and Every one of my high school is doing crazy community service.
Rym: and I did a bunch of park cleanups because that was the only thing I was interested was going to the park and Basically getting yelled at by the city for doing something we shouldn't have done.
Rym: but that's a story for another time.
Rym: We basically spent two days pulling About in the end probably several many hundred pounds of trash and like old barbed wire and just rotted out cars and debris out of the woods and The city didn't want to pay to dispose of it.
Rym: so it left.
Rym: it was left there in a pile in the park for Months and they threatened to sue the school because the school let us do it.
Rym: But the school's defense was you sent them to clean up the park and they clean up the park.
Rym: you agreed to pick it up.
Rym: There it is.
Rym: And yeah, all sorts of fun happen, but right around my junior senior year I realized that you can get away with ever you want in high school.
Rym: So I I just lied about all my community service and no one ever even questioned No one even considered the possibility that I didn't do it.
Rym: Yeah, and that's right around when I also stopped doing homework Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah about that time.
Scott: I just realized hey, wait a minute Grades don't really matter that much.
Scott: I mean, you know There are people who are like doing better than anyone else in this world and they like dropped out of school Granted as much as pendulum likes to say.
Rym: Yeah, just for.
Scott: so I'm not talking about pendulum.
Rym: talking like Bill Gates He loves his pendulum is always talks about oh, yeah I quit school and I was stupid and I'm rich and famous and he always forgets to mention the Hundreds of thousands of equally stupid people who don't go anywhere.
Scott: Yeah But you know, I figured hey if those guys dropped out of school Right and they made it and now they're the richest guy in the world or whatever.
Scott: If I just go to school, I'm like, you know a 4.0 gets me into Harvard.
Scott: I'm getting into somewhere.
Scott: You know, I don't need to get all A's.
Scott: I can still have fun now and now the more out.
Rym: The moral is not, you know, totally slack off in school.
Rym: It's because then you get all laughs.
Scott: you really if you get all laughs you really won't go anywhere.
Rym: It's more subtle than that because remember Scott and I and a lot of these people what we did is we thought it mattered and We tried hard up until 10th grade.
Scott: The lesson is don't try though.
Rym: The lesson is Basically do all the work up front when you get to your high school.
Rym: be that smart kid your freshman year.
Rym: get all A's.
Rym: It's not you pretty much.
Rym: if you want all A's in high school.
Rym: You can get all A's.
Rym: So Most people.
Rym: so get all A's.
Rym: try really hard.
Rym: be a model student for your freshman year and most of your sophomore year.
Rym: You will now be as far as the administration and the teachers everyone and the faculty are concerned One of the good kids.
Rym: and I'm making fruit like little quotation marks Because in high school I learned time and time again that if the school thought you were good you were good Regardless of what you did.
Rym: I mean I remember when Brian Smith and I had both skipped the same amount of class Throughout the year our sophomore or junior year and we got called down to the vice principal's office.
Rym: You always know you're in deep shit when the vice principal calls you down as opposed to the real principal.
Scott: Yeah, the real principal is only there for good things and the vice principal is there for bad things.
Scott: Yep They should just call him the good principal and the bad principal instead of the principal and the vice principal.
Rym: and I listened as they threatened to expel him and not let him graduate for skipping all this class.
Rym: and then they brought me in who would skip the Same amount of class and asked me about that one time.
Rym: I didn't show up to the class that I obviously had a doctor's note for Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah, you can get away with anything if you're a quote-unquote good thing in high school.
Rym: You'll never need a hall pass.
Rym: If you don't if you write a crappy essay, you'll still get an A because the teacher knows you're smart Yep, or at least thinks you're smart.
Scott: Remember the teacher teachers in school.
Scott: There's someone.
Scott: there are people who are our age who are teachers in high school, right?
Scott: They know.
Scott: Imagine if I could be your teacher.
Scott: I could be your teacher I think is a teacher Do you think that I would actually read all those goddamn essays or do you think I would just give grades after looking at the?
Scott: Name, what do you think I would do?
Scott: What would I do?
Rym: See, I would read it but there was definitely cuz.
Rym: I remember there was one particular moment in my senior year because you know Basically all the quote-unquote smart kids were in one group for this project.
Rym: The project was this huge like month-long thing that involved Hamlet and all this Shakespeare stuff and Basically, we totally dropped the ball.
Rym: did jack all we wrote cobble together the crappiest essay you would ever Imagine.
Rym: and then for the like the main presentation we poorly and somewhat inaccurately acted out a short scene from Hamlet and we got A's and People who were maybe not necessarily as known to be good students who basically worked their asses off.
Rym: It did a much better job than us got lower grades.
Rym: I'm not saying it should be that way.
Rym: I'm saying it is that way and you got to take advantage of it.
Scott: All right, let's move on to some other epiphany before this becomes.
Scott: the grades don't matter show.
Rym: Okay grades don't matter.
Scott: Okay, I had an epiphany with Computer programming stuff one time.
Scott: No, actually it was sort of I don't know if it was one big one.
Scott: Well, there was sort of a big one and a bunch of little ones.
Rym: I had one really little one with the T command.
Scott: Okay, but anyway, you know, like I learned computer stuff gradually from the time, you know And I was in kindergarten to the time now and still into the future, you know I don't know everything there is to know but there was some point in like maybe 10th 11th grade, you know I was doing some C++ kind of action, you know stuff like that and I You know, I was basically I had this book
Rym: about
Scott: object-oriented programming and I didn't really get it because I had been taught procedural Programming up until that point, you know and there was sort of I don't remember exactly when it was or what happened, but it was sort of like oh Objects oh And then I didn't need to pay attention in CS 1 2 & 3 when I got to college because I already knew you know
Rym: I had a similar but opposite epiphany when I was reading it a long article about aspect oriented programming and I didn't quite get it.
Rym: And then after reading the article again, I suddenly realized oh It's just bullshit It's not too bad.
Rym: It's not too bad.
Rym: It's guys.
Scott: It's one of those things That's a good subject for academic papers and inquiry, but you're not gonna write something that's practical for real world.
Scott: You know production use.
Scott: it's sort of like one of those ideas that people play with it in academic arenas.
Rym: Yeah I mean the only real epiphany I had regarding computers was when I had a computer finally in my house.
Rym: And what something went wrong, you know, eventually it's a computer.
Rym: something goes wrong Especially if you don't know what you're doing is running Windows 3 1.
Rym: Yeah, and I remember thinking what do I do?
Rym: What do I do?
Rym: And then I realized wait a minute No one can help me and there's no way to look it up.
Rym: I just have to figure it out on my own And I think everyone needs to have that epiphany.
Rym: You can figure it out on your own.
Rym: the computer tells you what's broken and tells you how to fix it.
Scott: For me because basically when I got that IBM whatever in the house, you know I mean like I knew how to use apples and stuff at that point and this thing had OS 2 on it and I was I was lost right, but I knew how.
Scott: to you know work.
Scott: it could based on what the screen said but I didn't know how the inside of it worked or anything yet really.
Scott: and You know, I'd be calling their support whenever I screwed it up and stuff like that.
Scott: And you know, I understood how to do some things but not really.
Scott: and eventually like I got a copy of Windows 95 My dad brought home from work.
Scott: I want to put it on there.
Scott: So I called their support, right?
Scott: And you know, they wouldn't really help me without me paying the money.
Scott: But the guy I happened to get was not a dumb guy and he sort of like gave me hints But without, you know getting in trouble from you know being recorded or whatever.
Scott: and he was actually, you know It ain't an English guy, you know from the u.s.
Scott: Spoke English and an English guy from the u.s Right, right As in not not from some other country where there might be customers.
Rym: it's not like pip pip Cheerio and all that.
Scott: No, not that either not from Albion.
Rym: I don't know what this England is you speak of right anyway.
Scott: So basically with this guy's hinting like vague hinting and me sitting there tooling around I suddenly understood all there was to know about F disk and formatting and dual booting and that whole thing.
Scott: and Then when I got a computer out, well, you know, I finally built one.
Scott: I had the whole business already laid out and that's I discovered.
Scott: aha and I suddenly I went from basically the personal computer knowing how to work it with the mouse and keyboard to knowing it fully in like Less than a year like BAM.
Scott: I get it.
Scott: Now.
Scott: The PC is mine, bitch That was a good time Actually, all right.
Rym: I got a good one here because it's actually scum in the forums a lot when the old men have been very Pessimistic as to our attitudes on life.
Rym: Oh He's gonna attack the old man, they always seem to wonder how we can be so optimistic.
Rym: Maybe me more so than Scott because Scott is is the most cynically optimistic person I've ever met.
Rym: I think that's the only way to describe it.
Rym: Whatever But it's often been said about me that I tend to take everything in stride and it's very difficult to actually get me angry.
Rym: and Pretty much there's there's glad Rym and sad Rym.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: are you much like Batman?
Rym: However, Batman did not have glad.
Rym: he only had sad and mad and every time glad came It was immediately taken away by a gang-up of mad sad bad.
Rym: Yep, or the phantasm whatever.
Rym: but I mean I can't really I'd take too long to explain I guess the fullness of this but I Really it's really not that difficult to avoid Having life get you down because when you think about it the worst thing that could possibly happen to you The worst thing that could
Scott: ever be
Rym: is that you no longer exist that you don't exist that nothing exists And you know what you do exist.
Rym: so you're already better than that and you're on your way to something better.
Rym: most likely and the worst thing anyone can ever do to You is kill you and everyone dies eventually.
Rym: So there's really no reason being afraid of that either.
Rym: and after you're not afraid of not existing and you're not afraid of dying There's not much else in the world to be afraid of and then there's really nothing worth being angry over.
Scott: Yeah, I Mean, sorry, you're gonna tell the anecdote of how you came to this biffany or not.
Rym: I'm not really sure how I came to that epiphany.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I've thought of it before and I thought of several times where oh it was then or oh it was then.
Rym: But in the end I've pretty much always been this way except for I guess when I was very very young
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: and I cared about things a lot more and I was afraid of things I was and then I just stopped being afraid of things and stopped caring and stopped being angry and just never really Nothing ever bothered me.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know when I was a kid, you know, like most kids So it's weird because you know We sort of have this idea that the world is full of like, you know bullies and then kids who get picked on but really Everyone sort of seems to remember getting picked on Like
Rym: funny that.
Scott: yeah, it's like you read these like there's a book right now called the diary of a wimpy kid.
Scott: It's actually a kid's book, but I think it's good for all ages and it's selling.
Scott: It's a comic actually But I think it's actually it.
Scott: you should you get it at Borders or whatever and I think it's like the best-selling Kids book in the country.
Scott: is that's ridiculous But it's like diary of a wimpy kid and you relate.
Scott: the only way to you know I guess enjoy that book is if you relate to being picked on if it's selling.
Rym: so well Well, if you're listening to GeekNights, right?
Scott: But anyway, you know like like every kid whatever and you know all you know I'd complain about it and I'd always say oh you teachers and your parents and your people you're always.
Scott: You know this kid picks on me or whatever like he took my hat or you know He said I was stupid and then I beat him up and then I get in trouble.
Scott: What's up with that?
Scott: You know that he's the one making the trouble.
Scott: if you just punish him or kick him out of school or something Then there'd be no problems here.
Scott: I'm smart.
Scott: They're stupid You know, I'm beating them up because they started it and I was right and they did start it and you know, whatever.
Scott: and Adults said no, you just got to ignore them and I was like you're just being lazy.
Rym: No, it's funny
Scott: how lazy and you suck
Rym: I think as kids I mean every kid gets told when they're picked on just ignore them and it's very difficult advice - I mean It's very easy advice to give Especially for someone who's older and went through all that as a kid and then it's like oh just ignore him.
Rym: Being a kid and being in that situation That's like tell that be.
Rym: it's like hearing someone tell you when you're in a wheelchair.
Rym: Just get up and walk Just just start walking.
Rym: Why are you sitting there?
Rym: It's it's it's not the easiest advice to follow.
Scott: No, it's.
Rym: but then you get older and you go.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: Ah I could have just not.
Rym: I could have just ignored him.
Scott: You could have just ignored him.
Scott: Hey, basically what happened is, you know people picked on me You know bothered me less and less or whatever and you know less beating people up and less You know fighting and less such over the years.
Scott: Yeah, you know, but eventually, you know, I just sort of like And in high school, I think I was in some class.
Scott: It was a geometry class Maybe I don't remember but it was like.
Scott: it was some class Where I it was for something was geometry because no one in the class is in my grades.
Scott: like all these people I didn't know right so they didn't know me that I was a complete stranger.
Scott: I just sat there quietly doing my maths, you know, whatever and You know, they didn't have any reason to pick on me or anything.
Scott: they didn't care about me they didn't know me.
Scott: But you know, they would come mr.
Scott: Bean and I guess you know, if you seen a picture of me and you see a picture Of mr.
Scott: Bean, I guess I kind of look like mr.
Scott: Bean.
Rym: I mean if you squint you're from a distance.
Rym: or if you're you know a kid and you're looking for something to pick out a Kid for all right, so they just be like mr.
Scott: Bean.
Rym: I mean someone we know has a big head big head.
Scott: So at first I was like, okay.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Bean sounds like kind of like a weird name.
Scott: It's probably something stupid.
Scott: But I know they're picking on me, but I didn't know mr Bean was at all at the time.
Scott: so and now I still I've really only seen a few things at mr Bean like the that what you know the thing where he pretends to play the drums and the the turkey in the oven thing But whatever I didn't know who he was.
Scott: So like the fact that they were calling mr Bean didn't bother me because I didn't understand what they were saying.
Scott: It wasn't like they were saying, you know, you're retarded or something because I would I would understand I didn't understand what they were saying.
Scott: So it's like huh you kiki booba.
Scott: Yeah, I was like what I didn't get.
Scott: So it didn't bother me even though someone's making fun of me and Then eventually got to the point where they'd be like mr.
Scott: Bean and I'd be like, what's up?
Scott: and they'd be like, what's up?
Scott: And I was like, huh?
Scott: They're like all acting like a bully, you know, like they're mean.
Scott: but if I just say what's up They're all what's up.
Scott: It's all.
Rym: and Well, there's definitely the the aspect of stolen Thunder.
Rym: I mean it is very easy if someone in any situation is giving you grief and you steal their Thunder by not caring That that usually they don't know how to react to that, you know.
Scott: But really like these people just by I mean I could have done the same thing that most nerdy kids do when you pick on them which is go start crying or start fighting or yelling or or Yelling trying to come up with comebacks that are not witty or making yourself look like a moron
Rym: The stairway.
Rym: come back you come up with something like after fourth period but it's too late.
Scott: It's too late, right, you know.
Scott: and and then if you try to do that people just make fun of you for that because you're being stupid and crazy.
Scott: and Well, I realized as soon as I stopped doing that a lot of those people who I thought you know We're making fun of me or didn't like me or hated me if I just had this different attitude.
Scott: They you know, they didn't become like my close friends or anything, but they were just like, you know Hey, what's up in the hallways as opposed to knocking your books down on the floor?
Rym: Well, I mean actually most alive the the classic the book job I think it is called most of life just comes down to attitude because generally if you're confident and you look confident Most people will get out of your way and give you pretty much anything you want.
Scott: Yeah, and from that point on it pretty much became impossible to pick on me.
Scott: pretty much I mean, even if someone hits me, I'm like, all right You can hit me one more time before I start hitting you and I'm like a warning them Whereas before like if someone touched me, I'd be like trip over smash their face in the ground or try to anyway.
Scott: I was like in middle school.
Rym: I can never get the situation where someone's holding you by the forehead at arm's length while you're windmilling.
Rym: No I don't think that everybody middle school.
Scott: one time this kid like took my Mechanical pencil and he broke it and then I tried to choke him and then I got suspended.
Rym: Well, I had a similar situation.
Rym: I think was in sixth grade.
Rym: I was sitting on the bus.
Rym: that was like the only year of my life.
Rym: I wrote a bus to school And this kid just grabbed my headphones and broke him.
Rym: just broke him into oh man I'm like what the hell.
Rym: and he yelled something.
Rym: and then I just jumped on him much like in a Christmas story when he jumps on that bully and basically Destroys him.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's how it went.
Scott: But as we both got suspended as soon as you just sort of take it differently It really is more you than it is.
Scott: I mean because think about if everyone is having remembering experience of being picked on right, you know No one remembers like being a bully when they were a kid.
Scott: I mean, have you ever met anyone who says hey, I was a bully when I was a kid?
Scott: Not really.
Scott: So it's really just.
Rym: that might just be the circles We keep.
Rym: it
Scott: could be but I've never met anyone like that and I really think that More so than what I mean everyone sort of treats everyone that way when their kids really
Rym: well kids are vicious little bastards a lot of the day
Scott: are pretty much all kids are vicious little bastards to all to everyone and the happier kids are the one you know, the sooner you just Act differently and don't get all crazy about it and just be cool You
Rym: know not is not the more
Scott: happy you're gonna be.
Rym: not to espouse religion or anything like that.
Scott: But in the end the Gandhi Jesus way, yeah I mean like think of even nowadays right go to anime con right and I see a scary fanboy.
Scott: If I go to that scary fanboy I go.
Scott: man you were the scariest fanboy you smell bad you like the hentai's you're terrible right, and so most of those fanboys freak out because they still haven't learned this lesson and though that's why I Kind of keep making fun of them for being scary fanboys.
Scott: Yeah Right, but yet again There are other people who are big who are exactly the same as those fanboys in every way.
Rym: Like what's in that Ramu guy in the forum who came in?
Rym: He's like, I like hentai and people like yeah, you're creepy.
Rym: He's like, I'm creepy and I like hentai.
Rym: What you gonna do about it?
Scott: And there's there's no more thunder left and making fun of someone if they don't care Yeah, and it's just basically they're you know, and it their attitude sorta, you know determines whether they get respect or not Even though they particularly like.
Scott: I could have some.
Scott: I could have a friend who's like a hentai nut and I can have someone That I bash and trash who's a hentai nut for being a hentai nut and have a hentai nut friend at the same time.
Scott: Right and it's it somehow works.
Scott: just because of the way the person carries themselves Determines their level of respect more than what they're actually getting the risk to make it feel more noble than just like bully.
Rym: Whatever think of it this way.
Rym: Imagine that you are the a great general in the Roman army and you're going off to face against Hannibal somewhere Right now.
Scott: obviously the cannibal.
Rym: Uh, no, no not Hannibal the cannibal.
Rym: No, there's there's a No, I Think Hannibal works the best.
Scott: Genghis Khan.
Rym: Nah Genghis Khan not so much.
Rym: I'm talking about, you know, the kind of honorable fight between two Generally urban civilized civilizations.
Rym: All right, not so much hordes of horsemen coming in saying give us all your stuff And we'll come back fine heavier way.
Rym: But all right, so you're marching out right now.
Rym: you disagree with Hannibal.
Rym: In fact, you might say that were you two to have to deal with each other in person There might a fight might break out might draw sword.
Rym: Someone might get hurt, you know, those things are dangerous and Obviously you're gonna come to some sort of disagreement and Hannibal is of course Trash-talking you back in Carthage and you have no kind things to say about him now.
Rym: The Romans kind of sucked around when Hannibal came in.
Rym: So the Romans were effectively being bullied and there's nothing they can do about it.
Rym: But they got to go fight him and Hannibal's.
Rym: All right, I'm just gonna kick their asses.
Rym: But even though the Roman army basically hid in the hills and did jack all and just took it they held their heads high the whole time and as a result Hannibal came to very much respect the Roman army and even fear them because even though there were no match for him and He could just come and kick their asses anytime he wanted There was kind of this mutual respect among enemies and if you can get a bully to respect you even if they don't like you They'll leave you alone because they're easier pickings, of course Hannibal did not go get easier pickings.
Rym: He stuck around and eventually got his ass kicked.
Scott: Well, that's because the other thing is you don't you know Rome had giant piles of gold that he wanted.
Scott: No, they didn't.
Rym: No, they didn't.
Rym: this was way before the Rome.
Rym: Most people know about Hannibal was way early and Rome was a much Funnier and not so powerful place.
Scott: Even so the only reason I could see for someone to continue going after a prize that's much more difficult to get Would be if the prize is bigger.
Rym: Well, yes, and you know what?
Rym: Here's another epiphany most analogy.
Rym: In fact all Analogies break down because if it break if it doesn't break down, it's not an analogy.
Rym: It's the thing.
Rym: Yeah, they're identical.
Rym: It's not an analogy.
Scott: Yes, people only use analogies to help explain something.
Scott: That's not.
Scott: if you can't if someone makes an analogy.
Scott: They're trying to help you understand what they're saying.
Rym: Much better developed fusiform gyrus.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: They're not tried, you know, if you destroy their analogy That doesn't mean that the thing they're actually saying is wrong.
Scott: You have to destroy the thing they're actually saying but just think of it this way.
Rym: It's kind of the.
Rym: you know, two people can be enemies or disagree on Fundamental principles and yet still have the respect, you know The two generals meet and have the respectful like.
Rym: I am going to destroy you.
Rym: Well, you can try ha ha ha See you on the battlefield tomorrow.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And as soon as I figure that out life was a much better.
Rym: Yes now there's one more.
Rym: that's probably the most important epiphany you can have.
Rym: Um, if you still play the doorknob safety game and you listen to the previous half of this episode You might be able to put two and two together and realize that you're heading very quickly toward dangerous territory.
Rym: There will be a time if you continue this game where someone will say doorknob and you will realize there is no longer a doorknob In this continent and you sir are fucked.
Scott: Don't stop playing the doorknob safety game.
Scott: I'm trying to stop playing.
Rym: I stopped.
Rym: You know what way back.
Rym: It's actually been almost a year.
Rym: I gave it up.
Rym: I was sitting there one day and I farted straight up not not like pizza somewhat epic eruption overnight at the New Year's party, but I Was sitting there and Scott and I were playing like Mario Tennis or soccer or something and I farted and it was.
Rym: it was loud Resounded in the in the video rocker pretty pretty soundly and he looks at me Because it's kind of you don't see the honor among enemies.
Rym: It's kind of like.
Rym: he knows I'm going to say safety and he's going to let me say it.
Rym: he just give the pause to let me know that he could have said doorknob and All I said was I'm not saying it.
Rym: I'm done with that and I haven't done it since.
Scott: Yeah I've been trying not to say Comes out every now and then.
Rym: yeah can't help it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.