Rym: It's Monday August 18th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about the magnificent Ti-80x.
Rym: Let's do this Well despite the total lack of live at the beach.
Rym: GeekNights episodes.
Rym: We're back from the week of crazy.
Scott: Oh, that was quite.
Scott: It was like almost like four separate vacations.
Scott: I got back to work, and it was so weird I forgot how to do my work.
Rym: almost I got back to the house.
Rym: I remember walking in being like oh, yeah, I have a house.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I don't have the house.
Rym: I'd live in the house, but it's like I'm walking up the stairs.
Rym: I'm like this kind of weird to be here again.
Rym: I kind of felt like I'd never come back here.
Scott: I got home And there was the.
Scott: there was stuff that I bought in the dealers room at ConnectiCon.
Scott: that was on my desk And I was like oh yeah, that's mine.
Scott: Forgot about that.
Rym: I got back to work and the thing is unlike other jobs.
Rym: Or you know like I expected to check my eat my work email at least once because it just happens I mean when I worked at IBM like I checked my IBM email when I worked at the hospital I'd check my hospital email and this job.
Rym: It's so much easier for me to check my work email that it ever has been.
Rym: I mean I have a work as it actually works.
Rym: I have my work laptop and my laptop both of which can use the VPN to get in.
Rym: They gave me a Verizon card so I can connect from anywhere.
Rym: I also have the blackberry anywhere.
Scott: with Verizon service.
Rym: I did not once get a pocket to the point of actually seeing an email from my work my work.
Scott: I have the push email to the iPhone, so I checked it the tiniest bit, and it was like half spam.
Scott: So I didn't actually check it.
Scott: But I think I did like open it once.
Scott: but
Rym: I can't believe it because when I when I left IBM for like a week Or two I'd come back and there would be like 2,000 emails in my inbox most of which were critical issues and everything would have gone to hell And I'd I'd have to spend weeks and weeks and weeks just like catching up and fixing things.
Rym: And the hospital was the same way like they try to page me and call me the whole time.
Rym: I was gone of course.
Rym: I left my pager at home, so that didn't really help and I never gave him my real phone number.
Rym: yeah, but you know this job.
Rym: I get back and I check my work email and One person asked me a question and at the end.
Rym: He basically said yeah, no rush.
Rym: We can deal with this when you get back.
Scott: Did you actually set the auto away?
Rym: I did in exchange but no one even people knew I was away and they didn't pull that crap at every.
Rym: it seems like every tech worker has the Problem.
Rym: or if you go out of town You come back and like all your co-workers dumped all their work on you because you weren't there to say no I don't really have that problem because there's no one who can dance more.
Rym: an IT problem a lot of IT jobs.
Rym: You'll come back and you'll find because you know you get your.
Rym: if you're dealing with tickets Especially like there'll be like a million tickets that come in and about half of them are easy.
Rym: You know people like to grab the low-hanging fruit And you'll find that people tend to play hot potato with the issues that take more than a cursory glance.
Rym: And if you're not there to throw the hot potato you'll come back and be buried in potato.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We don't really play how.
Scott: I've never had a job where they play the hot potato.
Rym: Well, you're lucky.
Scott: Yeah, no, but I got back to work and there was something I was working on before I left And I guess they wanted it done, but they couldn't find my work.
Scott: I don't know why.
Scott: so they sort of did it without me.
Scott: They started from scratch.
Scott: So my work didn't get used.
Rym: Oh, that's great.
Scott: And then I got like most of the.
Scott: I made it to-do list because I was like, oh, yeah work and I did most of it.
Rym: You know what the scary thing is.
Rym: All right, you know before we go any further.
Rym: Hi all of you new people.
Scott: Are there new people?
Rym: it seems to be.
Rym: we met a lot of people at these cons.
Scott: I hope there's new people.
Scott: if not, what did we just do?
Rym: Well the thing I want to say before we go any further as many of you are probably here looking for Oticon coverage or maybe even more ConnectiCon coverage or you met us.
Rym: you're looking at.
Rym: you can see the title of the episode.
Rym: You know what's coming through what I basically the deal with GeekNights, right?
Rym: Is that it's four nights a week with four separate shows Mondays which is now our science and techs and Linux and neck beards and all that stuff and With the neck beard joke, it's not funny.
Rym: I think it's hilarious.
Rym: That's not good, especially because I had a neck beard throughout much of college and the entirety of last week.
Scott: Yeah, I had a neck beard.
Rym: last week I shaved the neck beard off and I forgot how good it feels to shave a neck beard off.
Rym: Yeah, of course, then I lost a lot of my CSH skill.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: You don't need that skill.
Rym: But if you're here looking for Oticon coverage or the list of you know anime You should see.
Rym: or all the things we said we'd tell you guys from the con or all the people we say we've shout outs to.
Rym: Tuesday night is gaming talk about gaming Wednesday night anime manga comics.
Rym: our coverage of Oticon 2008 will be this week on a Wednesday.
Scott: Oh, no, it's.
Rym: and also for people who complained.
Rym: Well one person complained that our ConnectiCon coverage was mostly us talking about ourselves.
Rym: There's a there's very specific reason for that.
Rym: We didn't do anything at the con except do our thing.
Rym: Yeah Fortunately for you at Oticon we were actually press and we actually have a lot to talk about.
Scott: We do because we spend much of Oticon conning as opposed to running thing.
Scott: Well, no, we did run a whole bunch of things.
Rym: We also can we also kind of plenty.
Scott: another thing a lot of the people that I met a lot of the listeners I met at Oticon and Connecticut such a Surprising number of them.
Scott: In fact, I would say the majority of them.
Scott: We're not in the forums.
Rym: Oh even further if I realize something, you know looking at people in the forum and one guy quit our show again He's quit our show a bunch of times, but he's like, yeah I'm done with geek dice now blah blah.
Rym: And I noticed that a lot of people it seems like a lot of the people in our forum do not listen to GeekNights.
Rym: but yet Everyone we made outside like we go to a con we meet like 50 or so people are all like, oh my god I listen to GeekNights.
Rym: None of them are in the forums.
Rym: So how come the people who are our biggest fans are not in the forums and the people who don't even listen to the show Are hanging out in the forums.
Rym: I don't get it.
Scott: I don't get it either.
Scott: So we need to fix this.
Scott: So check this out people.
Scott: if you listen to this show You probably have a lot in common with other people who listen to this show and enjoy the show and you probably Want to talk to them and you know what I talked to them.
Scott: I met them in person and they were all pretty smart especially you.
Rym: you know that guy.
Rym: Yeah, you are I told was cool and you were better than all our other listeners, right?
Scott: That guy so our girl you should probably go to front recruit calm and on the left It says discussion for him until we're gonna.
Scott: we're gonna fake update the website sooner or later and that won't beat on the left anymore.
Rym: But night's is perpetually on the cusp of change.
Rym: But there's a lot of big change coming and the website is gonna be the first roll of that.
Scott: Yeah, but we don't say dates for anything.
Scott: that way we'll have no broken promises.
Rym: But the one thing you should know if you join our for if you're sick of you know The internet and places on the internet where people talk about things I recommend you check out the GeekNights forums because the ignite forums do not allow idiots to exist.
Scott: Yes, so you should probably go to the forums and where you can for free on the internet talk as much or as little as you like to other people who you share things with and It's a good idea.
Scott: So go there.
Rym: That was a real lame promotion.
Scott: That's all right.
Rym: All right, check it out It's not fortune.
Rym: All right, if you're on the internet a lot everything in the world except fortune is not fortune.
Scott: A lot of my poop is not fortune.
Rym: It's close Right, but I just wanted to get that out of the way.
Rym: So in case you guys are like, oh my god, those GeekNights guys did a great anime panel.
Rym: I want to listen to their anime show and we're here talking about neckbeards.
Rym: Well that this is why come back on Wednesday night That's enough of that.
Rym: So anyway, what were we talking about?
Scott: What's in the news?
Scott: I get you want me to go.
Rym: I think you can go.
Rym: check this out right.
Rym: check in.
Scott: It's been this big problem where you know we have these open source licenses right for software programs and other things also like Creative Commons for this show and They're interesting in that what they do is they pretty much cuz in the United States.
Scott: by default you get copyright full-on 100% rights reserved, right?
Scott: So the idea of these open source licenses is to say hey look I'm gonna keep the copyright on this thing But only some or most of the rights will be reserved, right?
Scott: So you say for example, well our Creative Commons license says, you know what you can copy this You can give it to your friends you can You know remix it a bit you can do all these things but your remixes have to also be Creative Commons and You can't go selling it, you know.
Scott: So you can't be taking an episode of GeekNights put it on a CD and sell for ten bucks and I'll do that Right.
Scott: So basically we're not reserving all the rights.
Scott: We're telling where.
Scott: we have a legal document which says only these rights are being reserved and these ones aren't.
Scott: now There's a lot of other licenses the GPL notably You know the MIT license the BSD license like yada yada yada.
Rym: Don't forget all the weird licenses.
Scott: Yeah Apache license Mozilla whatever right the Aladdin whatever that there's like don't use that one anymore.
Rym: I actually had to write an explanation of that life because there's one piece of software That we really needed at IBM because it did something really useful and nothing else did it and it was only covered under that license.
Rym: So I had to basically explain to IBM why we couldn't use it because that license was really really dumb.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Anyway The Problem with all these licenses is that they've never really been tested in court like people always talk about.
Scott: Oh look links is used Linux in their routers But they didn't put the source code to their routers on the Internet's as a GPL violation, but they fixed it.
Scott: They you know, they put their service code on the Internet's but there wasn't any court issue.
Rym: No Here's the fundamental problem is look at this.
Rym: our court system is designed to where you prove damages and then you know You get some sort of restitution.
Rym: But how do you prove the damages if you're giving it away for free?
Rym: Anyway, I mean I have something and I give it away for free.
Rym: So then someone else takes it makes money off of it or does something that I didn't approve in my copyright licensing, whatever.
Rym: So how does the court determine?
Rym: because usually what the court to do is say?
Rym: All right You were stealing that software and that person sells the software for hard $400 a license and you stole five Licenses.
Rym: you owe four hundred times five dollars back to them plus interest whatever.
Rym: What do you do when you're giving away from free especially when it's a judge?
Rym: He doesn't really understand the technological issues and lawyers don't really care and you have a jury who has no idea if there's even a Jury involved.
Rym: So how do you what sort of restitution?
Rym: you're giving it away for free?
Rym: So, alright I hereby give you 500 licenses times the cost you were giving it out of zero.
Scott: yeah, and it's not.
Scott: it's mostly what it is is you have this license and You say you basically say well, you know what if you do this It's not copyright infringement as it normally would be but if you do this other thing then it still is copyright infringement.
Scott: Then you go to court.
Scott: No one's ever actually gone to court against someone who is you know Say distributing GPL software without also distributing the source code and said hey you're infringing on my copyright Give me money.
Scott: No one's ever tried that right.
Scott: and still no one's ever tried that or at least no one's ever tried That without having some sort of settlement, you know, there's never been a decision.
Scott: So People are very going.
Scott: Oh, you know, they really don't want to go to court.
Scott: because if you go to court and you lose That is basically end of the road for the GPL.
Scott: Goodbye.
Scott: All the open source software is in big trouble.
Scott: The whole thing's gonna fall apart.
Scott: So they'd rather just keep things the way they are Then test it out.
Scott: or you know, it'd be good if they tested it out in court and they won.
Scott: That'd be all good.
Scott: But you know better to not test it than to lose.
Rym: Well, there's a bunch.
Rym: I mean even if we test it what I mean It could go either way in terms of how the courts deal with it.
Rym: Yeah Because no one in the chain really kind of understands the purpose of this software let alone How to actually I mean what art.
Rym: so the license cost was zero.
Rym: do we do punitive damages?
Rym: Is that the only way to have a deterrent?
Scott: Maybe the maybe Just be copyright infringement and then it'll be up to the judge I guess to figure out.
Scott: you know I'm not a lawyer, but probably the judge would figure out some way.
Scott: You know, I mean when someone the RA when you copyright infringe on music They have some method of figuring out a man.
Rym: that is usually something along the lines of how much they sell it for.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it's actually a billion times what they sell it for.
Rym: that's because you obviously pirated a billion time I know right.
Scott: But anyway So the news is is that one of the open source licenses the artistic license Which is used for Perl and some other things mostly CPAN things which are Perl modules was tested by a US Federal Court of Appeals circuit court, I think and They said artistic license all good.
Scott: So this is like oh man is that you know?
Scott: Based on that ruling, you know barring I guess farther up courts say the Supreme Court reversing it Which I don't think is too likely.
Scott: This isn't really seem like a Supreme Court issue.
Scott: Open source licenses and such and Creative Commons and all these sorts of things are legally the real deal.
Scott: That's good news.
Scott: This is accompanied by bad news, which is not obvious to the you know to the average person.
Rym: But the doll is evil that's bad.
Rym: but it comes with a free Frogger.
Rym: that's good.
Scott: the Frogger is also cursed That's bad.
Scott: All right Here's the bad news.
Scott: If some license I just slap on a piece of software like that is upheld by the law, you know And I can you know do that then Other EULA's have a much stronger ground.
Scott: Well in courts.
Rym: There's a really I mean it depends in a lot of ways But we are most specifically right.
Scott: Look at the those people the size star company where they're making max.
Scott: Basically, they make you know normal PCs and they put OS X on them the old.
Scott: they haven't really committed a crime except for Copyright infringement of the Mac OS.
Scott: but not really.
Scott: but you know because they I guess they buy a license for each computer But because they have violated the you know terms that are in the agreement that Apple gave them.
Scott: You know what defines what Apple considers, you know Acceptable use of their software and what isn't.
Scott: so that's a very.
Scott: that's a case that is very close Legally to sort of like these open source case, but yet we'd rather have that one go the other way.
Rym: No, here's why we don't because we die doesn't matter.
Rym: either way with EULA's There are only two possible cases really.
Rym: either EULA's are found to not really be enforceable which means we as techies win a thousand times over or EULA's are found to be legally binding.
Rym: There's no way around them in which case Real quickly.
Rym: They're going to be a lot of problems with people making software that has absolutely insane licenses attached to it like Apple OS X which says you can only still install it.
Rym: I'm imagining spyware that if you install it you agree to never uninstall it Huh?
Scott: Yes, I guess stuff like that.
Rym: But I guess I expect that.
Rym: I wholeheartedly expect that and if that happens Then there'll be such an outcry and a backlash against the enforceability of EULA's that will win in the end anyway.
Scott: But see that if there's no EULA enforcement Then the default of everything is super copyrighted comes into play and we can't open source things.
Rym: But if that's the case Then it'll win because things will be open source anyway.
Rym: The only drawback will be the companies will take open source stuff and try to use it.
Rym: But at the same time I could see the war escalating to where open source people just start subtly sabotaging those uses.
Scott: Well, I think for legal reasons businesses would pretty much had to abandon open source and open source would die.
Scott: and it'd be necessarily.
Rym: they can keep contributing to open source because it's useful to them because the bottom line to any Software is if it is useful to a corporation.
Scott: That's the thing that Microsoft is always trying to scare people about like oh the legality of open source.
Scott: You know, if you use it, you'll be screwed.
Scott: You'll be copyrighted infringers.
Scott: If you use it, don't go there.
Scott: So if EULA's are not there then suddenly all open source software Becomes fully copyrighted software and these people can't be using it.
Rym: Well, then it becomes the case of you.
Rym: I just have to agree to the license like bad an extra step ad steps.
Rym: You actually have to agree to a license before you use it in some sort of verifiable way as opposed to the shrink About the shrink wrap.
Scott: This is just about light software license in general I know and they're so.
Scott: it doesn't matter how it's accepted within with a signature or anything.
Rym: What I'm saying is in the end it probably will be because EULA's.
Rym: There's kind of this implicit idea that no one reads them or understands them.
Rym: but if software is made available with there's absolutely no way to get it without reading it first and That's true.
Scott: But that's a completely separate issue from what's going on here.
Scott: This is just the question of software licenses in general.
Scott: regardless of how you agree to them Do they mean anything at all?
Scott: and the court has said yes.
Scott: Yes, they do So we'll see what comes of this.
Scott: but in the meantime The experts tend to agree and I'll trust Larry lesson because he's the expert.
Scott: He says this is awesome because it means all these open source licenses.
Scott: are they mean something?
Scott: they're the real deal and they count.
Scott: so if some company decides to use Linux in their TiVo or whatever and Doesn't do what the GPL says to do There's a good chance we can beat them in court with this previous ruling used as you know prior whatever.
Rym: So, you know what the issue here is that it seems like if they're if the licenses aren't enforceable Then things can still be in the public domain and can still be given away free.
Rym: And if they're not enforceable then companies can use it anyway, because no one has any recourse against them.
Rym: Yeah, they are enforceable then the open source part of it works and the companies can still use it.
Rym: Yeah, I don't foresee any situation where companies could not continue to use open source.
Rym: There is What situation.
Scott: but if they decided that open source licenses right that it was copyright infringement Even if you you know, they don't count right?
Scott: They're not legal whatever.
Rym: I don't think that was really an option though.
Scott: if they decided they don't count right then all open source software would be 100% fully copyright of the person who it's copyright to.
Rym: but there's the other part of in that specific case if Someone is giving it away for free.
Rym: And even if the license is super strict.
Rym: Well, how do you enforce it?
Rym: What are the damages?
Rym: if it was free the damages would be zero.
Scott: no, but you know because you could technically be sued.
Scott: It doesn't matter what the damages are If you know.
Scott: it said if you could technically be sued Companies won't do anything that puts them in a position where they can be sued.
Rym: I just I don't feel like that was really the issue because if someone gives something away under a license Then it seems like the issue is more that if the license isn't enforceable Then the person who gave it away with the open source license would not be able to exercise other rights that they had properly.
Scott: No, it's pretty much if the the open source license is not about enforcing things It's about removing existing enforcement.
Scott: The default enforcement is full copyright.
Scott: the open source license Gets rid.
Scott: it says I'm going to get rid of things that I already have but here's the opposite.
Rym: What other lies?
Rym: because there's the problem.
Rym: if because there's the other A lot of court cases been were court cases that have almost happened but didn't deal with the idea that alright I released my software under an open source license And if it is valid then that's fine.
Rym: But then the license basically is tantamount to public domain.
Rym: if it can't be enforced or if you can't get down Oh, it's the license doesn't count.
Scott: then you weren't able to give up the rights that the license is giving up.
Scott: No, it's full copy.
Rym: There's a whole other issue where the license does count.
Rym: you can give up the rights But by giving it away for free.
Rym: there's the other issue.
Rym: if you can't actually enforce the rights you did reserve which people have run into because what's the deterrent?
Rym: if the Damages you have caught that have caused to you by someone stealing and reusing your free software are zero There's no incentive not to just violate your non-commercial clause or violate whatever clause you've got.
Rym: I can remember the brouhaha where a lot of people had the.
Rym: you cannot use our software for military or weapons of mass destruction.
Rym: Yeah, so if someone has that sort of license Then that's kind of.
Rym: there's this third issue of the licenses are valid but not enforceable and that is the fear of a lot of Open-source people because a lot of open-source people have bugs up their butts.
Scott: Anyway, it turned out I guess in a really good way in this case.
Scott: So continue to open source license things with less fear than before.
Rym: in fact As inside to all you podcasters out there seems like a lot of people who make content Don't actually attach some sort of license to it Which as a result means that technically no one's allowed to do anything with what you made?
Scott: Yeah, pretty much, you know if you I mean technically speaking right.
Scott: if you make an mp3 and you put it on your website and You don't license it in any way.
Scott: You have full copyright in which Technically speaking not a lawyer again.
Scott: if they just download it from your website and listen to it They're infringing on the copyright because you didn't give them.
Rym: it's already been shown in core.
Rym: There's been a lot of cases where they really can't go after people for downloading.
Rym: They can only get them for uploading because if something was made available There's a reasonable expectation in a lot of cases that it was actually available.
Scott: Oh, that's okay.
Rym: then because notice how the RIA only really goes after people who are uploading.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: But I mean they can't.
Scott: you know, someone can't come get your podcast then share it with their friend.
Rym: now They can't.
Scott: so you have to.
Rym: you know There are the exceptions for fair use and private viewing and all that right, but then again legally You really wouldn't be able to play a podcast That doesn't have a license associated with it in a bar because there's too many people and that's a public performance,
Scott: right?
Scott: So even if you don't want to be all hippie open-source something you should find some legal license.
Scott: There are plenty of them to choose from to apply to the media that you create.
Rym: Most restrictive Creative Commons license.
Rym: There you go.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: But anyway that that's all boring.
Rym: and there's much more important news here.
Rym: Seattle's five million dollar toilets failed and now they're gone.
Rym: and they they Seattle lost a ton of money.
Rym: man.
Scott: five million dollar toilets.
Scott: Really somewhere they made a gold or platinum.
Rym: There's a problem in America.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: We have a lot of overseas listeners where As time has gone on there are basically no places for people to pee in public.
Rym: If you're out on the street somewhere and you have to pee you're done.
Rym: you pee in the bushes.
Rym: You're a sex offender.
Rym: Most stores won't let you use the bathroom if you're not a customer.
Rym: No, most stores just won't let you use the bathroom period.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: And if like food restaurants will often let you use a bathroom But you usually have to be a customer So you have to go in and buy like a Starbucks like a coffee and then you can go and pee But like a department store half the time won't let you use the bathroom?
Scott: Yeah The only places you can really go to the bathroom in public are gas stations.
Scott: gas stations will always let you go to the bathroom.
Rym: I've run into bad gas stations that wouldn't let me go to the bathroom.
Rym: They was locked.
Rym: They wouldn't give me the key unless I bought something.
Scott: Ah, it's really bad.
Scott: Yes Let you.
Rym: I actually got into a Mexican standoff for the gas station.
Rym: like I was in high school I was gonna pee.
Scott: you're gonna pee in the gas station.
Scott: That would have been a much better Mexican standoff.
Rym: No, basically He was like you have to buy something or you can't use the toilet to which I said I would like to buy this five cent stick of gum.
Rym: and he said all right, and I said with my credit card Mmm, and he stood there and he realized that he was going to cost him money to let me pee.
Scott: You should have made American Express.
Scott: the fee for him will be double.
Rym: I don't have an American Express.
Rym: That's why I got one.
Scott: so I could do that.
Scott: Because you realize if you the reason credit card companies make money is not just from stupid people collecting interest.
Scott: It's mostly for merchants fees.
Scott: if you open up a store Let's say I own Scott's grocery store right and someone comes in uses their American Express card.
Scott: Well, they use a MasterCard.
Scott: Let's say they buy $100 of stuff and they use their MasterCard.
Scott: I have to give MasterCard me the grocery store.
Scott: I have to give MasterCard like a buck.
Scott: fifty It's or something like that.
Scott: But if these American Express I might have to give them five bucks.
Scott: Alright, so you actually it costs you money when someone uses a card.
Scott: if they paying cash.
Scott: It doesn't cost me anything I get the full price.
Scott: So stores hate it when you use a credit card.
Scott: They really hate it when you use American Express.
Scott: That's why a lot of people don't even accept American Express because it just caused them so much to take it from you.
Rym: Granted larger retailers get better deals and it's actually really complex.
Rym: We're not gonna get into the exact prices.
Scott: This is why the guy didn't want Rym device ticket.
Rym: If and this is the secret that if a store accepts credit cards They have to let you purchase with the credit card any amount of a store ever has a sign that says $10 minimum $5 minimum $20 minimum.
Rym: Basically, they're not allowed to do that.
Rym: Well, I think to their merchant agreement with Visa or MasterCard or wherever they did it with exactly do.
Rym: then All you have to do is call the number on your credit card and tell them what that which store it was and that they Wouldn't let you buy something with a minimum.
Rym: or they had a sign up saying there was a minimum and they will come down on That store like you wouldn't believe.
Rym: they are basically destroyed.
Scott: It's not against the law for them to say $10 minima to put it, you know.
Scott: But if they refuse to accept your credit card as payment Just turn your credit card over.
Scott: call that number while you're standing there and say I'm in such-and-such store You know, they will not accept my credit card.
Scott: They're claiming there is a $10 minimum.
Scott: bla bla bla bla bla and Either that store will get like huge fines or they'll be taken a court or they'll be forced to not you know.
Scott: at the very least they'll be Severely reprimanded and forced to remove their minimum thing.
Scott: or if they don't cave in and you know to what the their agreement was They won't be allowed to accept MasterCard Visa, whatever anymore.
Rym: Thus tip number 485 for people who like to be jerks in public yes, but anyway.
Rym: so I had to stand off and he looks at me and he I could see he still didn't want to let me pee and He I think he was considering not letting me pee anyway, and you know, I kind of stood there like I'm gonna pee I want to pee and a credit card.
Rym: I got this gum and eventually he said just use the bathroom and he gave me the key Mmm, and then after I peed I bought a Red Bull.
Scott: Yeah It was Red Bull in those days, well, it was actually it wasn't.
Rym: it was the Red Bull back then it was that whoop-ass.
Rym: In fact, it was that can of whoop-ass.
Scott: Was it?
Scott: I thought you bought the can of whoop-ass at like a con.
Rym: No, I bought the can of whoop-ass halfway to Saginaw.
Rym: Uh-huh All right.
Scott: I realized just recently the whoop-ass is made by Joan soda.
Scott: Yeah, it was the people who make like the Thanksgiving soda.
Rym: tell you one thing that whoop-ass tasted like balls But it's never been.
Scott: it's not open.
Rym: I opened it and drank it a long time ago, it's an empty can.
Rym: Oh, I opened the can of whoop-ass.
Scott: Did you know long ago?
Scott: All right Rym likes to open the ass.
Rym: It was my last.
Rym: can I opened it.
Rym: It's done.
Rym: Anyway, so these toilets, right?
Rym: Basically, the city was like we want public toilets, but homeless people will live in them.
Scott: exactly.
Scott: This is a big problem in the US is that there are a lot of situations where we can't have nice things in public Because hobos will use them especially in cities.
Scott: I mean small towns can usually have them.
Scott: but in a city like in New York, right you install benches Bums will sleep on them and normal people, you know, and there's everyday people won't be able to sit on that though Prostitutes were using them.
Rym: people were living in and people are shooting up drugs in them.
Rym: They were people would just walk in and like destroy them.
Scott: Yep So, I mean it's really hard to have nice public facilities like always envious.
Scott: if I go to Canada even just to Niagara Falls Right on the border of New York and Canada, right?
Scott: You go to you know, New York Niagara Falls kind of Blair.
Scott: go to Canada Niagara Falls.
Scott: There's like really really well maintained parks and everything is pretty and clean and it's right in the same geographic location.
Scott: There's just one piece of water and a bridge in between but anyway cool the city.
Rym: But the city canceled its contract this spring after the commodes became filthy hideouts for drug use and prostitution.
Rym: Now They were 12 million dollars because they were self-cleaning.
Scott: Whoo self-cleaning tools like.
Scott: I need one of those in the house.
Rym: But you know and I wondered like alright why I can come up with ways to make a self-cleaning public toilet that prevents drug use Prostitution and hobos living in them.
Rym: I would have them open the door after like 10 minutes if someone's in.
Scott: What if I had diarrhea?
Rym: Well, you know what the door is gonna open and then you can close it again after a minute and you're gonna have to deal with that.
Rym: Maybe 20 minutes to Every every instead of having it wash like after someone's in there Every hour.
Rym: if like if no one's in there, it'll just wash and if someone's in there It'll give them 20 minutes and then it'll just wash.
Scott: Well, it should give like a wash warning.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it'll say in 20 minutes.
Rym: You're gonna get wet.
Scott: But what if I have diarrhea?
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: You've got a tough.
Scott: This is serious problems with your with your strategy.
Rym: You know what, you know what needs of the many greater than needs the few.
Rym: Star Trek taught me that no One guy with diarrhea is much less important to me than hundreds of people who need to pee every single day.
Scott: You say that until you're the diary again.
Rym: I'm never that guy.
Scott: I'm that guy.
Rym: But anyway someone pointed out something interesting.
Rym: because well one they were so expensive because they were self-cleaning.
Rym: It would have been cheaper to hire like two or three janitors per thing 20 all year round.
Rym: you can have janitors going to these things every hour to making sure there's no hobos in them and washing them.
Scott: Yeah, this is a problem in that in the u.s.
Scott: You know minimum wage is going up, but it's still pretty low.
Scott: It's cheaper to hire people to do menial labor than to automate very, you know, unless it's you know Extremely mass-produced.
Rym: I have a feeling as a result that the city just basically took a wash on these.
Rym: Perhaps they there was some shadiness because they spent way too much money.
Rym: Yeah, but even then I wondered, you know, like why did they spend so much money?
Rym: Why does this work in France?
Rym: Why do they work just fine in Paris and not here?
Rym: What is the difference?
Rym: and someone on slash that actually pointed out something very interesting?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: They had to be handicapped accessible.
Rym: as a result They were very very large and very comfortable for people to do stuff inside of them.
Rym: Mm-hmm in Paris.
Rym: they're not handicapped acceptable accessible at all.
Rym: They're tiny.
Rym: They're just big enough to do your business and get in and out if you're in a wheelchair.
Rym: You're screwed.
Rym: now the way they get around.
Rym: that is instead of America where you have the American You know the disabilities act that requires everything to be handicapped accessible.
Rym: They have normal ones all over the place But then also all over the place.
Rym: apparently they have special handicapped accessible outdoor restrooms That you can't get into without a handicapped card.
Rym: Oh and if you if you ever pry if you're handicapped if you have a disability the government gives you a card that Opens up all these handicapped accessible things like public toilets, huh?
Rym: The odds of a handicapped accessible toilet being used by hobos and prostitutes is greatly reduced as a result.
Scott: Yeah, because I mean they would have to get the card somehow.
Scott: But then again, I see a lot of like hobos and wheelchairs.
Rym: They could probably get the card But at the same time that's still a small percentage of a hobos overall and I think they would.
Rym: they would work a lot better.
Rym: Maybe I guess I just I feel like there there has to be a solution to the fact that I often have to pee in Public and I have oftentimes.
Rym: in fact on more than one occasion I peed somewhere near a train station in Yonkers because there was nowhere else to pee.
Scott: Yeah, they really had to do something about that.
Rym: in fact I pee outside a lot just in case anyone wondered Perhaps you may have seen me.
Rym: Anyway, let's get right into things of the day now.
Rym: You might have seen what we're talking about.
Rym: I'm sad we went so long on the non main bit bits because I'm really excited about this.
Rym: This is something that I've spent a lot of time on but me too.
Rym: My thing of the day is directly related to this and it is a nostalgia video of a ton of games From a ton of different TI calculators over the years and it shows like games on the TI 82 to the TI 92 plus the 83 plus the 89 All these different games, you know Mario 1 on the TI whatever Alien strike aspirin.
Rym: remember that drug wars game.
Scott: I love drug wars.
Rym: It was quite a nostalgia trip.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: All right, so check this out.
Scott: I was complaining a little while ago right?
Scott: that if you want ringtones for your iPhone or whatever You got to pay money like a dollar to then you got it first You're gonna buy a song on iTunes then you got to pay a dollar to turn into ringtone.
Scott: But if you have the new version of garage bad, not the version we have, you know that we can't upgrade without paying money.
Scott: But the old the new version that comes leopard you can turn pretty much any mp3 or any audio you can make Into an iPhone ringtone with garage band for free.
Scott: But if you use Windows what the fuck you supposed to do?
Scott: Well, someone made a program called I ringer.
Scott: it Convert songs into iPhone ringtones.
Scott: It just works day to day All right.
Scott: So for the main bit Back in the day, you know when I was in high school Right when Rym was also in high school.
Scott: He's the same age as me I'm a little older not much.
Scott: We didn't have iPods.
Scott: They didn't really exist so much.
Rym: and we didn't have Cellphones cuz they were you know, well, I had one but it's not like the cell phones you used It's not like now.
Scott: it was basically a non-functional brick and we had game boys But they're in me, you know, maybe even GBA is getting you know later on.
Rym: but no I didn't have a GBA Game Boy Color.
Scott: I had but I didn't.
Rym: I had a Game Boy and a game gear and you know what it didn't matter because you realize back.
Rym: Then you kids I don't know some high schools are probably still like this if I brought my Game Boy to school They would take that shit away.
Scott: so You have that shit.
Rym: They took away my Walkman my cassette Walkman Wow.
Scott: Okay, we had Discman.
Scott: actually They didn't take them away.
Rym: I had a cassette Walkman when I was I think a junior.
Rym: I bought a disc Walkman.
Scott: yeah, they never took any of my music players away, but but even so Discman were pretty rough and Really portable, you know laptops.
Scott: Give me a break.
Rym: There was one kid.
Rym: He had like a 486 laptop.
Rym: It was gigantic and he brought it to school.
Scott: battery lasted for 30 minutes.
Rym: I remember he'd bring it on the bus and he'd like play games on it for like 10 minutes and then the battery would die.
Scott: Yeah So there wasn't so much portable computing going on.
Scott: It's pretty much get home use your desktop get to go to the computer lab use the machines there.
Scott: There's no wireless internets.
Scott: It was all wired internet.
Scott: So Not too much options for computing.
Scott: the only computing device that you had Was calculator and in high school You know when you started learning more better maths like stuff beyond geometry like say trigonometry or calculus is They required Graphing calculator.
Rym: I'm sure I mean we have a lot of high school listeners.
Rym: I'm sure you all own whatever the current TI calculator is.
Rym: Yeah, it's the.
Rym: it's that thing You're gonna spend a lot.
Rym: your parents are gonna spend a lot of money on in high school.
Rym: You're gonna use it.
Rym: really not that much money like a hundred bucks.
Rym: Yeah, you're gonna use it once or twice in college and then you're gonna lose it.
Scott: I never use money.
Scott: god, I guess I did use someone's 89 in college a couple times.
Scott: I
Rym: used it in college because I was forced to take a stupid math class that I didn't want to take in my senior year Because they said yeah You need a math credit because we decided suddenly that we're not gonna give you full credit for your calculus C test.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: so Everyone was sort of forced to buy these things as a class requirement.
Scott: And I don't know if you want to go over the history of DTI Into that because I sort of know it.
Scott: see the real important thing.
Scott: I'll just to sum it up.
Scott: TI made some you know Fancy calculators and then they actually listen to what teachers had to say and they designed the calculators such To match what teachers taught and then they backed it up by providing teaching Materials on top of that and then teaching tools on top of that and they basically created this huge Educational platform.
Scott: on top of their calculators they had overhead displays that work with the calculators.
Scott: They had a sign.
Scott: they had sensors like thingies for science class and physics and chemistry that work with the calculators.
Rym: Thanks didn't work for shit though.
Scott: Those things work pretty great.
Scott: ours were great.
Scott: Now we even work with the graphing programs.
Rym: ours didn't work at all.
Rym: Of course worked awesomely.
Rym: We didn't really.
Rym: I mean we didn't use them and I mean they didn't work.
Rym: So we actually had real equipment that we use like we just use big oscilloscopes to do everything.
Scott: So we actually had you know the sensors.
Scott: we had actually worked.
Scott: You mostly used them like the temperature sensor and that sort of stuff.
Rym: We just had thermometers.
Scott: yeah, we actually.
Scott: it was cool because you'd plug it in and then a graph would show up on your calculator and then you plug The calculator to the computer and it would transfer the graph to the computer And then you'd print it out and put it on your report and then you get an A. Anyway, so they built this huge platform on top of these calculators and in my school the calculator They told everyone to buy was the TI 83.
Rym: Ah, you're the suck.
Rym: our school required in 85 or you couldn't do anything.
Rym: our school told everyone to buy the 80.
Rym: No they told if you were on the track of not going to college or if you were on the track of Not making it to calculus in high school.
Rym: Then they told you to buy the 83 and and basically had to buy the 83 in middle school.
Rym: But if you were in the high school Then you were on any sort of other track like the Cal track.
Rym: you're gonna take any of the real classes.
Rym: You had to buy an 85 or when the 86 was out you could buy an 86 because it was similarly functional.
Rym: It's basically the same thing.
Scott: They didn't you know, we didn't have.
Scott: our school was like that.
Scott: They basically told everyone to buy the 83. now The 83 was a calculator that TI actually made after the 85 and what it was weaker though wasn't as good.
Scott: Yes, it was weaker.
Scott: The idea was the teachers looked at the 85 and they said that has a lot of stuff We're not gonna use and a lot of the stuff we will use isn't polished enough.
Scott: So it's sort of like it was like the Apple and where they reduced functionality and reduced other features But streamlined what they did keep.
Scott: yes, it was basically algebra.
Scott: teachers love the 83. thus That's what they told everyone to get.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: See the thing is algebra.
Rym: I mean most people took algebra in eighth grade.
Rym: when our school.
Rym: so get to high school You need the real.
Scott: well those algebra 2 and geometry and trigonometry and for all those things the 83 was still the business.
Rym: The thing is the 83 couldn't do anything geometry wise that the 85 couldn't do better, right?
Scott: So If I was a smart kid, and I went and I looked at these calculators and said, you know, what?
Scott: Why should I get that 83 that everyone else is getting?
Scott: I'm a nerdy kid.
Scott: I know better.
Scott: I'm gonna get the 86 which has three or four times more memory than any of these other calculators.
Rym: 86 and the 85 are basically the same.
Rym: I mean the 86 had an updated OS and it had more memory but that was somewhat misleading because it had More really shit slow memory.
Scott: It actually wasn't slower memory.
Rym: No, it was the same kind of memory But it actually had two different memory banks that had a fast memory and kind of a slower storage memory and it would swap Them.
Scott: Well, it wasn't the problem of swapping was the problem.
Scott: It couldn't address the same number of memories.
Scott: So I had to flip.
Rym: the TI 85 also had these secondary memories But but the TI 85 could access its memory on average a lot faster and they both had the same speed processor.
Scott: Yep, though like most of these calculators all had the same z80 processors which are actually part of the reason that there is so much awesome things you can do with these calculators because z80 Processors if you want to learn some assemblies z80 is the business.
Scott: it's real simple and pretty much run-of-the-mill and you can program all sorts of shit for it and Once you learn that you're ready for some jobs in the world of assembly programming.
Scott: I'm getting many chips.
Rym: I remember when I actually when I actually bought my 85 the 86 was not out.
Rym: yet No one had an 86. an 86 came out and everyone got him in there.
Rym: And the thing is people had 86 is actually ran into a lot of trouble because certain graphing functions just because the way the memory Was addressed like especially if you were doing difficube.
Rym: We're way slower and you just couldn't do it.
Rym: Basically.
Scott: Well I didn't have problems with that because I mostly use my 86 for Programming and games.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is I never did the assembly programming because I never had the link.
Scott: I did a little bit but it was.
Scott: it's not easy.
Rym: But here's the thing now.
Rym: you kids can't get away with this these days for the most part.
Rym: but back then Teachers in high schools did not understand.
Rym: you realize that the calculator was a multi-purpose device.
Rym: They thought it was a calculator or nothing more.
Rym: so a lot of times kids would like in French class just whip out their calculator and start poking at it during a test and Most teachers didn't think anything of that.
Rym: They didn't even conceive that the calculator could be used to cheat.
Rym: Meanwhile Rym here wrote French dictionary and gave it to everyone in the school for a small fee.
Rym: Aha, it even had copy protection because it you know, it said you don't made by Rym blah blah blah.
Rym: Here's my website.
Rym: And if anyone tried to change that page it gave wrong answers.
Scott: Yeah Well, here's the thing.
Scott: because in my school, right?
Scott: We bought the graph link Which is basically a serial parallel cable went from the computer to the calculator and we were loading up the programs big time.
Rym: Oh see the way our school worked is.
Scott: we actually had cross calculator links.
Scott: So you'd send you one guy would get all the stuff from the internet and then transfer it to other people.
Rym: That was how we did it.
Rym: But remember the only way to get the assembly things on if you didn't have the computer link you basically had to get someone else to load up all the stuff like the OS and the menu and Then he would basically wipe out your calculator and give you over the cross link an image of his calculator.
Scott: No, we didn't have to do it that way.
Scott: We could just at least with the 86.
Scott: We didn't have to do that.
Scott: we find over the program.
Rym: you could do.
Rym: you could just send over the programs But to get the menu to show up in the way where you could hide it from a teacher You had to give the image.
Scott: Oh, it's a hide from a teacher.
Scott: Yes now Here's the thing.
Scott: Some of the teachers are smart.
Scott: I had teachers that knew the calculators are loaded with Tetris Yep, I remember in difficult class one day.
Rym: The teacher was like in high school.
Rym: He was like, alright You can use the calculator on this test because we had to.
Rym: we always broke up the test into the hardcore math test And the kind of theory knowledge test like it was a multiple-choice essay test about math.
Rym: and on that test He'd said you can't use a calculator unless you let me wipe out your calculator.
Rym: and you know when you want to wipe out a calculator There's the menu you go through and it takes you to a special thing.
Scott: Well, we all wrote a program that you'd run that looked exactly like that menu Exactly that actually download a program like that and it basically the program Fooled the teacher into thinking you had to raise the calculator.
Scott: like the one teacher I remember walked around the room and said show me the screen that says memory erased.
Scott: and we all showed it.
Scott: and Then I used the program.
Scott: I wrote which factored polynomials and so do my friends.
Scott: and we all got A's.
Rym: We all wrote the program the factored polynomials.
Scott: Everyone wrote the polynomial factoring program.
Rym: Actually mine was multifunction.
Rym: I could do a lot more.
Scott: I wrote a really complex one Ax to the something power plus BX plus C and you just put a the something power the B and the C and then it Tells you the number and you just go.
Rym: There you go Yep, but see here's there's the real gist of this and kids can still do this today But it's it.
Rym: it's kind of a lost art.
Rym: I mean it's people still do it.
Rym: but it's a lost art because teachers are more tech savvy and Like if you have an iPhone you can just use the calculator for a lot of things.
Rym: But at the same time these calculators are very purpose-built.
Rym: And while you can do a lot of this math like the differential equations and the Radial graphing and the complex graphing and all these sorts of things With a computer all these other things the calculator does it really well and it's really built to do that.
Scott: Yeah, I mean try doing that stuff like try doing that graphing on your computer.
Scott: What software you gonna use?
Scott: MATLAB Which cost a zillion dollars?
Scott: Excel, I don't know the the graph thing that's built into your Apple OS X There aren't really, you know, if you want to do a lot of these basic Mathematic functions, I guess the sort of ones that are above standard calculator and above scientific calculator But below like wicked crazy mathematical model of amazingness
Rym: Well, you know what I would
Scott: use.
Scott: graphing calculator Does it better than a lot of the software that you can get.
Rym: I would use new calc and you can do a lot.
Rym: It's really powerful and you can do a lot with it.
Rym: I actually use it use BC also Yeah, but it just in terms of quickness and access.
Rym: the calculator especially like the TI 85 86 is So well designed for that purpose.
Rym: The 89 is actually not as good for some of the lower-level math But it's a lot better for the very high level.
Scott: Well, here's what happened is the 85 was sort of like the Original in a way and then you know, the algebra teacher said it's too much.
Scott: They went the 82 the 83 that was down for them, right?
Scott: But the calculus people the next step up they wanted the 89 the 92.
Rym: Well, the 89 can.
Rym: that's how come the big fat one Big fat one.
Rym: Oh the 89 was the big fat.
Scott: No, the 92 is the big fat one of.
Scott: the 89 was the same size as all the others But it had a lot of the 92 functionality.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: I'm a hundred percent sure.
Rym: I thought it was the other way around.
Scott: the 92 is the big fat one.
Scott: That was like almost like a laptop.
Rym: There were people who went to a special about these special classes out of my high school and I skipped on him because I realized They were a scam.
Rym: but basically they had to have the full-on calculator.
Rym: the 85 wouldn't cut it now.
Scott: But the 89 came out, you know too late.
Scott: I guess they had the 89 when you were at RIT.
Rym: I used it for I borrowed someones and use it on a couple tests borrowed mine I bought it cuz I had a bunch of money and I was like, ooh 89.
Rym: I'll do crazy math.
Scott: Yeah, the 89 had a lot of the calculus like it could derive like.
Scott: it didn't just derive like, you know You know give you the number.
Scott: It derived.
Rym: Well, now you type in a thing and there it is Symbolically, yes, it does symbolic logic as opposed to simply numeric logic.
Scott: Yes, it could do symbolic equation solve and it did it with pretty print like better almost as good as course.
Rym: here is the problem with those calculators and a lot of kids who try to use them to be fancy, but basically they could solve anything that you could solve trivially.
Rym: if you knew even basic calculus and The things that you had trouble solving.
Rym: they also had trouble solving.
Scott: Yeah, they would sit there for a long time and then they would come up with something But it wouldn't help you actually get the right answer.
Scott: You'd still need to do work to honestly kids.
Rym: if you're in high school now by an 85 or an 86 Probably 85 and 86 are not available anymore.
Rym: You can get them trivially on a heavy Bay.
Scott: I guess you can really.
Scott: yeah Yeah, oh man I remember the the trials of battery charging like cuz.
Scott: basically rail vac made these rechargeable triple a.
Rym: everyone who've used rechargeable batteries My school had problems all the time.
Rym: I just bought double A's.
Scott: people were constantly basically the school.
Scott: I guess when they bought the Calculators gave everyone these batteries.
Rym: school about calculators.
Rym: Yeah, you had to buy the calculator or you basically were screwed.
Rym: Well, you could buy it through the school, but the school wasn't any cheaper.
Rym: They just go into the store.
Scott: No wasn't.
Scott: but at the school got all these chargers and all these batteries.
Scott: everyone was using chargers and batteries all the time and you'd be like coming to math class and put their batteries in the charger.
Scott: and I just sort of asked and teacher gave me the charger.
Scott: So I died.
Scott: I had like three sets of batteries.
Rym: Batteries sucked.
Rym: I would put double A's in there.
Rym: They'd last for like a charge.
Scott: Basically the batteries didn't last for crap at all.
Scott: That's why people were recharging them constantly and they'd have like power strips and all the math classes and everything.
Rym: and wow Actually, I like my high school was kind of funny.
Rym: The policy was if your calculator ran out of batteries during a test you're done Deal with it, that's rough.
Scott: That's rough Of course I can.
Rym: I was actually really infamous at my high school because I wrote all these crazy programs like.
Rym: I wrote this thing.
Rym: That was this crazy menu program that had every physics equation ever.
Rym: And the thing is it did Euler's method instead of the kind of kinematic thing that a lot of physics teachers teach now Which I. I'm of the mind that Euler's method teaches better physics fundamentals and better algebraic fundamentals, but I digress Mm-hmm, but I wrote this program that you would kind of say what kind of problem you're trying to solve and it had all the fundamental equations for everything in it and it was massive.
Rym: and It got passed around and passed around and passed around to the point that eventually the school Banned my program from class
Scott: Because
Rym: the like the math the physics classes were all dead theory tests and they had doing tests and in the theory tests They wanted people to use calculators.
Rym: They didn't want them to have the equations available Mm-hmm, so because they wanted you to kind of know the fundamental.
Scott: Yeah, this is a big problem in that You know, I could understand, you know, if I download say a program all the equations in it What does that really get me?
Scott: Well, it saves me from having to memorize the equations and it saves me for doing the busy work.
Scott: But if I don't understand what's going on, it's still not gonna help me.
Rym: Yeah, I kind of will.
Scott: I mean, here's the thing and if I wrote the program Then that proves I understand it.
Scott: So what's the point of making me guess?
Rym: Because everyone else just got the program for me and didn't make the program.
Scott: Yeah, it seemed like even though even though I wrote the polynomial factoring program They still didn't like it and I just really never understood that it's a big one.
Scott: Look, I wrote this you just give me an A and not let make me stay in the stupid class.
Rym: Yep But the thing was the.
Rym: the theory tests were designed such that you could figure them out trivially.
Rym: if you were smart You just had to sit there.
Rym: if you knew the theory you could derive the equations from thin air But I had the equations in my calculator because I was done with that.
Rym: I'd already derived all the equations.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: then I wrote the masking program that hit it.
Rym: But then I told the physics teacher how to detect my masking program in return for him letting me use my own program.
Rym: That was the best of the best days in my life because I remember there's this huge test.
Rym: It was like this midterm and it accounted for like 30% of our grade.
Rym: It was a curve and everyone came into class and was.
Rym: he goes he goes around and you know He does the check and everyone's calculator and he goes to mine.
Rym: He goes and goes and when he hit the first person who was using my masking program He hit the escape key and he says well insert name here I see you have rims program and the look of horror on his face.
Rym: Were you trying to hide this for me?
Rym: Uh, no, I don't know how it got there.
Rym: Well, uh, I see that you're running Rym mask.
Rym: Where'd you get this?
Rym: And then he looks around the room and he could tell because half the class sitting there going what he he he and half the class Is going oh shit.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: Oh shit type type type type type type.
Rym: Almost everyone in the class failed that test.
Rym: it was one of the great was one of my triumphs.
Scott: Yeah, so I imagine that nowadays, you know They probably newer calculators like I've seen like stuff like the ti-83 plus silver platinum edition and crazy shit.
Scott: and You know, I'm pretty sure the people in the schools are still using TI graphing calculators and there's still the bomb.
Scott: But you probably don't care about running games on them anymore cuz they have DS's and iPhones and iPods.
Rym: I don't think you understand how important those games were to us back then.
Rym: Yeah, because again, it's the golden ticket.
Rym: No one knew what your calculator was doing except for smart people.
Rym: Yes, so in you know math class the teacher looks around and he thinks oh wow, everyone's really trying hard on their homework.
Rym: No, I was totally playing pong with the link cable with the guy behind me every day.
Scott: Yep, so you people have the calculators and aren't having enough fun with them.
Scott: You should go to ti calc org.
Scott: that is pretty much the site and the site.
Scott: I just went to it for the first time in a long time.
Scott: It is still updating.
Scott: Hardcore.
Scott: the community is still rocking the house if you have a chance.
Scott: site hasn't changed since I was in high school.
Scott: This is like a 10 year old website here.
Scott: If you have a ti-85 still I highly recommend you 80 anything No, or 90 and 85 specifically.
Rym: it is trivial to overclock it.
Scott: Oh, it's trivial to overclock a lot of these things.
Rym: Yeah The 85 more so and you can get a solid 4x.
Rym: and I'll tell you one thing if you have an 85 that is overclocked And you were still if you're an engineer you're doing any sort of math On a daily basis that thing is gonna be your lifeblood once again, because it is so fast.
Scott: Yeah, you know they didn't.
Scott: oh, they didn't clock a lot of these things as fast as they could go for whatever reason.
Scott: But I've seen like overclocked 86. is that like they claimed like 200 X and it they're pretty fast.
Scott: I don't know if it's 200 X.
Rym: Well now those people had some cooling.
Rym: that was unjustifiable.
Scott: But basically it's like hey take out this resistor and suddenly everything's fast.
Rym: The key is make sure you do the mod that has the switch so you can on overclock it.
Scott: cuz all the how-tos are NT.
Rym: I caught that or yeah, but some of those programs especially some of the older games will not work with an overclock day.
Scott: Well, they will.
Scott: they just be stupidly fast and those broken.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is it started out like a lot of these programs.
Scott: just be like Tetris, you know text-based game.
Scott: That's written in the basic not the assembly.
Rym: Yeah drug wars drug wars was like the most popular game.
Scott: drug wars is pretty good But later on it was like Megaman Zelda Wolfenstein 3d.
Scott: it was getting hardcore wicked hardcore.
Rym: It's good times Yeah and the thing is there.
Rym: there was this culture of the people who were smarter than the teachers and were in the know were Hacking these things like no tomorrow.
Rym: I learned more from hacking my ti-85 and Cleverly cheating on tests that I ever would have learned with any other tool and I feel like some of that is lost on kids.
Scott: But at the same time I definitely feel like the generation before us, right?
Scott: those were like the Steve Jobs's and the Bill Gates's who had like Altair's and they had like, you know, they built the original Apple and they were hacking on these things like, you know Right in basic, you know all this stuff right then, you know, it kept going like that.
Scott: But our generation we used the Apple twos early on and then later on we had the graphing calculator And we were using.
Scott: we were playing PC games on DOS.
Scott: We had to fuck with DOS to get the PC games to work now.
Scott: And that's how we were forced to learn, you know about computers.
Scott: And I feel like the generations that came after us where they didn't care about their calculators.
Scott: They were just calculators.
Scott: They had Windows 95 and it just worked.
Scott: games just worked.
Scott: You know, they didn't grow up using a computer.
Scott: They never use a Computing device.
Scott: there were forced to use any sort of electronic device where they had to program It had to fiddle with it had to get down and dirty.
Scott: and you can tell by looking at What those people of the different generations are doing on the internet their computing knowledge levels.
Rym: However, don't get us wrong.
Rym: We're not.
Rym: I would never say we have to go back to those days.
Rym: No, those days really sucked and it's much better now.
Scott: It is much better now.
Scott: Look at the enrollments for you know CS as a major in college over time and you'll see that People who are forced, you know to use these things their generations.
Rym: They're still enrolling.
Rym: the difference is they're failing.
Scott: I mean now enrollment is still down.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but it's down in a lot of the tech fields for a lot of reasons But except for IT, but even then is gonna go down.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't know.
Rym: I feel like we need to foster a culture of Hacking and messing with technology which is because actually I see where this is coming back in The mod scene for like the DS using those are whatever chips.
Scott: Yeah some of that.
Scott: There's a little bit.
Scott: that really though.
Scott: That's a lot of drag-and-drop There's not a lot of.
Scott: only the people are.
Scott: actually most of the kids are just using they're not writing Different from what we did with the calculators.
Rym: look back at the high schools.
Rym: there were like in my clean my high school You know we have like a thousand kids right and there were maybe 30 or 40 people who are writing all these programs and hacking them and Everyone else would go to these people and be like oh my god.
Rym: Can I have that game you got?
Rym: oh my god Can I have that physics program you wrote and they had no idea how they worked and they didn't know anything And they just they kind of just used it.
Rym: It was it.
Rym: I feel like it's the same way now and the kids who were hacking stuff today are the kids who are going To succeed at computer science and IT tomorrow.
Scott: I think that something that we could do you know short of doing my you know true belief, which is that you know?
Scott: Computing should be the fifth.
Scott: You know basic subject.
Scott: You know in all schools.
Scott: It's elementary school to high school you know is Not just computer Technology in general.
Rym: yeah, if we see schools should teach kids how to use online banking.
Rym: Yeah, how to type.
Rym: well No elementary schools use how to type.
Rym: high schools should teach how to use Linux and Windows and Mac and everything.
Scott: yeah But we should have some sort of rule.
Scott: I mean where there's only one Technological device allowed in school, and this is it.
Scott: and design it in such a way because right now A lot of the schools are like get a graphing calculator You know, but you can bring your iPod to school your phone and whatever and you know.
Scott: they'll maybe have real computers in the classroom.
Scott: So I guess is good.
Scott: You know or they'll have give everyone real laptops.
Scott: Maybe like Apple laptops We had to make some sort of laptop.
Scott: That's actually sort of down and dirty Where you kind of had to program it?
Scott: Maybe it runs like squeak and small talk or something?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's a lot of things that could run that do exist.
Scott: and You know instead of kids playing with Like stupid educational programming kindergarten give them logo like we had where you're forced to sort of program something a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the the release.
Rym: your time when I've my first computer classes when they'd say like today's a free day The only thing you could play with was logo, and you would have to be clever if you wanted to have fun.
Scott: Yep, in fact.
Rym: You know what it seems like in general.
Rym: That's the idea is Instead of lockdown zero tolerance because if I pulled even half the shit today in high school Then I pulled when I was in high school.
Rym: I would have been expelled easily.
Rym: I mean I broke into the computers and fussed with things.
Rym: I looked at my grades.
Rym: I showed my teacher how I could have changed my grades that I. but I didn't.
Rym: I wrote programs that would like shut down all The computers during class and we'd laugh about it nowadays done jail Things have changed.
Rym: I feel like you need to lock down to the point that Kids who are clever will get around the lockdown and instead of being malicious.
Rym: They'll be creative and funny Especially if you give them their own devices like you give everyone Some sort of lat like a cross between a laptop and a ti-85 some sort of.
Rym: it's locked down just because it's complicated But yet it's still usable.
Rym: and if a kid pays attention in class They'll be able to do all their lessons and they'll learn.
Rym: but the kid who already learned the lesson and is bored will start fussing with it because he can't get there's nothing else to fucks with and he's bored.
Rym: and by fostering this climate of the 10% of kids who are bored and clever will be so bored that they'll fucks with it and They'll learn more as a result is probably the best way to get an education to people who are smarter than their school.
Scott: Yeah, and this is actually a major problem when you look at a lot of technology We have today people like oh, you know, they're like, oh we don't need open source, you know I'm happy with my non open iPhone, you know, and well the iPhone.
Scott: Not only is the iPhone locked down to where you can't do anything that you you know Can't program for it without a kit and money and all that jazz But it can't program for itself.
Scott: something very important about computing is Devices that have the ability to program themselves.
Scott: You can't write an iPhone program on the iPhone You know, you need to be able to see 86. any TI calculator can write programs for itself while you're using it.
Scott: Yeah, you don't need to plug it into a basic handle.
Rym: It's like basic.
Rym: It's it's basically basic.
Rym: it is CI basic, but if you were smarter it had a bunch of functions you could use.
Rym: that did stuff.
Scott: Yep, but It's it's the divide.
Scott: the only way for people to actually learn Programming I think right is essentially for devices is there has to be a device that can program itself live.
Scott: You know if it's.
Scott: you know, if you need a computer to program something and transfer it over, you know That's a necessary technology in the world But it's not something that people can learn with.
Rym: Oh granted.
Scott: I need to have a device that they use Understand that device and then use that device on itself, but granted not everyone needs to be a programmer.
Rym: It's more the idea that give kids tools that can do their educational job in school.
Rym: I'm forget consumer technology because at the same time I want my consumer technology to just fucking work.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Yeah, but when it comes to to educational stuff school It should be usable for the things that are being taught But extensible for the clever kids and you can apply this to non technology.
Rym: look at in English class, right?
Rym: You have the default assignment, you know read Hamlet and we'll do Hamlet.
Rym: but for the kids who are bored set it up to where if they want they can choose to read something different and only offer this to the kids who kind of show promise and the kids were obviously bored or Only all like.
Rym: give kids the choice.
Rym: be like you finish your homework in class.
Rym: Let's say if there's time left over you can't bring your calculator into class.
Rym: You can't bring your phone You can't bring other classes homework or anything.
Rym: But there's a whole bunch of Greek literature in the back of the room and if you're bored Go on back there and if you read something and write a paper on it extra credit.
Rym: Yes, that's the sort of thing that you know.
Rym: parochial school was terrible in a lot of ways But that was how it was set up when I was a kid.
Rym: if you finish your assignment in class All the extra free time the only thing you could do was either twiddle your thumbs like a moron or go to the back of the room and there would be classics to read and stuff to do.
Rym: And if you were bored enough and smart enough and clever enough and you went back there and did these things You learned a hell of a lot more than that teacher was ever going to present to you.
Rym: Yeah And you need to offer these opportunities to kids who were bored without holding kids who aren't that clever or who aren't interested in that subject Without hopefully holding them to this high unattainable standard.
Rym: I mean a kid who is good, you know They're a writer and they're creative and they want to draw and read and write but they're never gonna be a programmer.
Rym: You don't force them to be a programmer.
Rym: You don't force them to learn TI basic in order to pass algebra one.
Rym: Give them the device and then you kind of offer this room for expansion for kids who care in that field.
Rym: Yeah, that is the same thing in every field.
Scott: This is why the TI calculator is such a beautiful educational device in that Primarily it is used for teaching the maths and it does teach the maths and if you are not clever It cannot be used for things other than math, right?
Scott: But it has these other things it can do.
Scott: it can do a lot of things and teachers never teach you about those things.
Scott: They never tell you about those things.
Scott: But kids who are bored and sit there and poke at their calculators because there's nothing else, you know to keep their attention We'll learn things on their own just playing where the device teaches itself.
Scott: It is because it's so well designed and that is how technology helps in the classroom.
Scott: not having video screens instead of you know Chalkboard that doesn't really do that much every kid.
Rym: a laptop doesn't help.
Scott: It doesn't help that much either.
Scott: You know, it's all about having devices that are designed in this clever awesome way.
Scott: and if I have kids I'm probably gonna give them the TI calculator as well before high school when they're told to get them.
Rym: Yep, like here's one example or real quick.
Rym: Let's look at the laptop.
Rym: typing like nowadays.
Rym: you type things.
Rym: I actually have trouble writing anything long But the way I learned how to write very well was that in high school We were forced to write essays extemporaneously in class with a pen.
Rym: Not even let's use a pencil.
Rym: you write it with a pen and then the next day they'd give it back to you and with corrections and you would have to rewrite it and write a better essay again in pen and Every like we'd have.
Rym: these assignments were for a whole week.
Rym: You'd write one essay every day.
Rym: You'd rewrite it better now.
Rym: No, that was an archaic horrible way to do things, but it worked back then I think like one way you could apply the principle to the future would be to have kids write essays But in a word processor that has change tracking enabled and not able to be turned off.
Rym: Mm-hmm the idea that it you know, someone just writes the way they do normally, you know type type type erase type But it keeps this kind of record of the changes you have made and then force people to go through the changes They made and consider why they changed and what they changed.
Rym: and you know You got to be creative with using technology and then kids will learn a lot more.
Scott: Yep Bats it's cool how the device teaches itself.
Rym: Yes I mean look like people.
Rym: the big deal with Bill Gates.
Rym: that one of the he did at a pretty young age is.
Rym: he wrote A basic compiler in basic.
Rym: Yep, and that might sound dumb But that's that's kind of one of the tests of.
Rym: are you a good programmer?
Rym: write a compiler in the language to compile itself?
Rym: Yeah, and if you can do that You've proven that you'll learn a lot along the way.
Scott: if you've never done something like that before Well by the time you've done that you've already learned most of what you need, you know, yes Yeah, TI calculators are the awesome you should.
Scott: if you're ever been to high school you probably had.
Scott: you have you either in high school and using it right now or You're out of high school and you have it in a bucket somewhere that you haven't used it in a long time.
Scott: like me.
Scott: Pull it out.
Scott: go get yourself a USB to TI cable.
Scott: go to TI count org.
Scott: Have yourself some fun because there's been a lot of development since you've last checked and if you're in high school Hack that thing hack it to all hell.
Rym: see what you can do with it.
Rym: Try to get away with cheating in every class you can.
Scott: yeah, put away your iPods and your cell phones.
Scott: The TI is where your attention should be.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.