Scott: It's Thursday December 11th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rick and this is the GeekNights book club and tonight We discuss a wizard of Earthsea.
Rym: Let's do this as I said on the show last night.
Rym: I took Wednesday off to go skiing.
Rym: I'd planned this for quite some time.
Rym: I was looking forward to it.
Rym: I figured on a Wednesday No one would be out there and it had been beautiful weather like this.
Rym: according to the mountain.
Rym: They even had a half a foot of powder up there.
Rym: so Tuesday night.
Rym: I'm getting all my stuff together.
Scott: That's enough.
Scott: like six inches doesn't seem that much well and like two or three feet of other snow, okay?
Rym: But no, I mean they're basically anytime you ski.
Rym: There's two surfaces.
Rym: There's like the underneath, and then there's what's on top.
Rym: Uh-huh like you'll have the pack down underneath dirt.
Rym: well that I guess.
Rym: yeah There's rocks, and then there's the mantle and then there's the magma and then there's the bitter horrible core.
Scott: you go to the skiing website.
Scott: What are the conditions today?
Scott: bedrock?
Scott: It's really.
Scott: it's not looking too good.
Rym: Well, I do recall last year when I went skiing in for the first time with scojo that it was in spring basically And there was this path of snow and then either side was green grass Man, I could imagine like pretty snow skiing in this an earthquake.
Rym: Anyway, so you know I'm all set for this.
Rym: I packed all my stuff together.
Rym: I'm getting ready to go.
Rym: Look in the weather And it's gonna be like 50 degrees and it's gonna rain.
Scott: It's gonna rain and sure enough it rain, and it was 50 degrees.
Rym: the conditions went from packed powder with a first layer of powder to Loose granular, which is a code word for crap.
Rym: Okay, so uh I basically see.
Scott: why do they even say like you know like loose girl?
Scott: I don't.
Scott: they just say good ski today or bad.
Scott: Don't see today?
Rym: Well, they kind of do.
Rym: But there's different kinds of good ski.
Rym: like some people like to ski on packed powder because it's easy and you can go real fast.
Rym: But some people like powder powder because you can kind of float in it, and it's really cool.
Scott: And you may have a mess you know, but it's like they should just be like ski able unskiable You know.
Scott: and then you know.
Scott: put the details there for the people who care.
Scott: But you know most most people just care is ski able unskiable.
Rym: loose granular is perfectly ski able.
Rym: the only problem with it Is that it was also raining.
Rym: Uh-huh imagine skiing in the cold or rain Mmm.
Scott: Yeah imagine Maybe the mountains above the clouds and you'll be all right.
Rym: No I looked on the website.
Rym: I looked at the webcam.
Rym: It did not look happy.
Scott: webcam is a very good idea for the skiing.
Scott: yes You know what you see.
Scott: anyone skiing on the webcam.
Rym: No No one even the website.
Rym: They were like great skiing later in the week.
Scott: Okay, so god damn it that must see that's thing.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: you know.
Scott: farmers their you know livelihood is controlled by weather, but no they can irrigate and such ski mountains.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's money.
Scott: That's controlled by weather.
Rym: Yep, and you know what they haven't been doing well lately around here.
Scott: No, you gotta go go to someplace colder and northerner go to Canadian or Vermont or something.
Rym: yeah well pretty much I looked.
Rym: I would had to driven two and a half more hours north to properly ski, so I figured it wasn't worth it Especially in that Sunfire, which probably wouldn't make it back.
Scott: Yeah, you just ski back.
Rym: You know what the sad thing is.
Rym: ski technology being what it is the skis I have would be basically worthless for cross-country skiing.
Rym: uh-huh they can only go down and they can only go fast So they can't go up Kinda, but not so great.
Scott: Well fast is what you want for getting home, right?
Rym: Yeah, but only if I'm going downhill.
Rym: these are for going at an angle like that not so much like that mm-hmm.
Rym: So I took off Tuesday next week, I'm hoping I can ski.
Scott: then Why don't you like look at the forecast before you pick the day?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: when I pick the day the forecast would you look at the farmer's almond?
Rym: I think the forecast said it's gonna be cold.
Scott: You had a. the forecast isn't accurate so you get close.
Scott: Yes, but I don't For five days.
Rym: yeah, yeah, it doesn't matter.
Rym: I've already planned like two weeks of next year's vacation.
Rym: I'm taking good days.
Scott: You got the next year's farmers on the day.
Rym: Well, no other than skiing.
Rym: most of the stuff I'm doing next year is like go to Japan or go to a convention or go to see Barack Obama.
Scott: Waste your time all right.
Scott: So you want to do things of the day before we talk about the book?
Rym: We should probably do some things of the day.
Rym: My ulterior motive is that it's actually easier when doing the show to do things of the day than to not do them because I never Really wrote my awesome make the granular granular The modular show script.
Rym: so it's basically the script's always gonna put the thing of the day music in the middle.
Rym: So if I don't do a thing of the day, it's actually much more difficult to not have that there alright, so um So check this out.
Scott: this dude drew a funny picture.
Rym: Funny in a haha way or funny in a slightly offensive way both.
Scott: It's a too soon I don't know.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: he drew the picture of the Twin towers, but they are cartoonish Twin towers.
Scott: one of them is like sort of got sad droopy eyes and sticking his tongue out And the other ones got like an o-mouth like oh, no Wait, you said oh mouth.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: and his eyebrows are up in the air like he's surprised and dismayed and They have little you know cartoony arms and legs and they both have you know airplanes stuck in their heads
Rym: as is expected
Scott: right and it Is soft 9/11 and his I guess it's what his wife yeah his wife based on this doodle Made plush Twin towers.
Scott: Oh my one of which looks like it has the flu and one of which is like oh, no They even got like little logos on the planes here And you know some people.
Scott: it's weird because if you forget about the fact that this references a horrible Event right they're really cute.
Rym: Just right you know that's kind of the The problem.
Rym: Emily's been having reading italia because it's adorable and hilarious But at the same time the jokes are all about horrible wars from the pre-world war one era.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's difficult and also, right.
Scott: So all the people who post comments you know and all the various places that have been posted right some people are like oh, man it's but it's Like everyone's torn like everyone but boing boing actually it was did something pretty smart right.
Scott: they were like look at this right.
Scott: and Then they're like I know you might think that this is in poor taste But then they're like if you think that's in poor taste look at this.
Scott: They the link went to one of those 9/11 Commemorative coins, and they're like yeah if you think this is tasteless look at that.
Scott: and like like.
Scott: this has hearts That's just you know money-grubbing Disgusting bullshit, so it's like okay, all right You know this this we can accept and that you know it's.
Scott: it's not making fun of anyone.
Scott: It's not saying like.
Scott: you know if you you know fuck you people who died in 9/11.
Scott: It's not saying anything like that.
Scott: It's not saying terrorism good.
Scott: It's just you know portraying an event in a Way that you know.
Scott: let's see think about it more easily.
Rym: I guess it helps that I'm generally actually very much a fan of tasteless humor.
Rym: if presented in a clever manner.
Scott: yes I just don't want to say something a hundred percent tasteless on my show.
Scott: well You know what because I'm not a big fan of producing having humor.
Rym: having seen these I Can't call it tasteless because it's it's it's in good taste It's what well played.
Scott: good, sir You can make a lot of money.
Scott: people don't want to buy them.
Scott: Yeah, I actually had an idea once to make a contest and the contest would be submit the most tasteless thing you can possibly make and See what you know.
Scott: people toss in there, but tell me the style project.
Rym: It's already been done.
Scott: No, no like like this is like you got to go for it.
Rym: I Don't know.
Rym: I think the style project went for it.
Scott: No no not really.
Scott: I Already thought of ideas that were worse.
Rym: Anyway my thing of the day that this is a college humor.
Rym: But I can't really pass this up and everyone you might have seen links to this and just ignored it.
Rym: No, watch it because it's so fantastically done.
Rym: It is 40 inspirational speeches from movies cut together into one Contiguous speech and let me tell you it is fantastic.
Scott: See what he did.
Scott: that was clever right is?
Scott: he took you know the inspirational speech slowly mounting music And instead of taking the music from the movies and having them go Right he put the one music behind the whole thing.
Rym: I think what helps is that it starts out kind of standard.
Rym: You know you got brave hard.
Rym: the Mighty Ducks are in there, but at the center Independence Day is in there.
Rym: But then there's a lot of really unexpected things in there that really really just add to it.
Rym: They make it brilliant as a result.
Scott: yeah Having seen most of them it really adds to it like if you have no idea what any of these are it's like Okay, but knowing what the majority of them are is like.
Scott: Oh, you've got to get mad Not gonna take it anymore.
Scott: say what again.
Rym: Sayeth what to my ears again.
Rym: good, sir No I don't at all Right?
Rym: So it's the geek guides book club.
Scott: Did you read read a book?
Rym: read a book see?
Scott: Because we're having trouble getting people to read the books because many people were I don't know illiterate I you know even though I think I'd like to think GeekNights is a show for smarter people's.
Scott: People who listen to GeekNights will be smart and read.
Rym: it takes four hours to read a Wizard of Earthsea.
Rym: This book in four hours talking for distracted hours, I started reading it on the train this morning.
Rym: I finished it just now.
Scott: I thought you've been here.
Scott: I started reading yesterday.
Rym: Well, I read like ten pages of it, and then I played NS.
Scott: Yeah, you suck.
Scott: I read two hours one day two hours the next day.
Scott: boom done right.
Scott: so I knew this book.
Scott: This is the reason I chose this book.
Scott: right number one easy to read, but not so easy to read.
Scott: It's insignificant.
Scott: I mean, I guess I could have chosen Cat in the Hat, but you know that's a little prince is easy to read.
Scott: That's a good.
Rym: doesn't make it bad.
Scott: Maybe I'll do it next time.
Scott: um yeah But this is you know be warned the shorter books you pick the longer ones.
Scott: I will pick in retaliation This is easier to read, but you know significant still enough book to be significant in quality.
Scott: Also, it's a fantasy book which nerds like right.
Scott: third It's sort of like one of those like forgot.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's weird because it's sort of like the odd fantasy series out.
Scott: it's like you got the Lord of the Rings and you got your.
Scott: What's it called your what?
Scott: Narnia's.
Scott: And then the Earthsea is sort of like the in-between and it's not like totally forgotten like people know it But it's not super big.
Scott: you know it's definitely not Harry Potter big either.
Rym: I guess that's fantasy even though I'm gonna say it straight up Harry Potter I'm not gonna say it drew It's poop from this at all sucks.
Rym: if you want a story about a young boy going to wizard school and becoming a wizard Harry Potter is not the story.
Scott: I think I think actually you know if you do like the it.
Scott: It's sort of like a Naruto thing right Naruto.
Scott: They start out with ninja school, but the ninja school is gone after like five episodes right in Where Earthsea right at least in this first book the wizard school is there for a bit?
Scott: you know it's Mostly the whole.
Scott: if you look at the whole series the wizard school is like nothing in Harry Potter at least.
Scott: I haven't read You know more than part of one book of it Which I can't.
Scott: I can't either, but I can watch the movies My understanding of it.
Scott: Is that the majority of it is wizard school.
Scott: You know it's like with the wizard school.
Scott: Is the setting?
Scott: this is a world setting where a wizard school is one thing in the world setting oh?
Scott: Having trouble there hello little belt burping anyway.
Scott: The other reason I chose this book is because there was a terrible sci-fi miniseries based on it.
Scott: There were that was not the only bad No, no based on and there was a Studio Ghibli not a Miyazaki movie.
Scott: What wasn't a Miyazaki son.
Scott: Yes It was a Studio Ghibli movie based on this series.
Scott: We're not gonna talk I haven't seen no, but you know it's I think The author of the book Ursula K. Le Guin who is the amazing sci-fi fantasy author of all time.
Scott: She plain didn't like the sci-fi thing and and get I thank you I think ghetto thank you.
Scott: I think she said if I remember correctly.
Scott: She said she didn't say it was good or bad.
Scott: She's just said you know it's his it's not mine.
Scott: You know it's his store You know.
Scott: so I don't.
Scott: I don't get the feeling she wasn't like a huge fan of it either.
Scott: So you know this thing that people are trying to make works of.
Scott: I think people should be encouraged to read the real deal Lest they you know get bad ideas about it.
Scott: It's really the people trying to adapt this thing or the failed and it's not a matter of the original thing being failed.
Rym: Well, what has been said of ghetto Sankey primarily is that it?
Scott: Yeah?
Rym: I haven't seen it, but people have said that it has nothing to do with Earthsea except that they call the guy dead.
Scott: Well, I think let's to start right off the bat right.
Scott: the first thing that the miniseries And I'm pretty sure good Sankey get wrong is They make get white.
Scott: he's not white.
Scott: almost no one in this book is white except the jerk barbarian invaders.
Scott: The jerk barbarians invaders are basically just Vikings right there white and blonde and the bad people in the north who?
Rym: Knew where the stone is?
Scott: yeah, they were.
Scott: why is the stone right?
Scott: the enchantress chick right?
Scott: She was white or the?
Scott: no she was like the enchants his daughter I don't know, and I think the art the archmage was white.
Scott: ish mostly white.
Scott: But everyone else in this book is like black or like you know dark.
Rym: Well, they make the distinction between between the brown black and the red black.
Scott: yeah I sort of imagined it.
Scott: my mind is like you know like the Native American color and then like an African color.
Scott: You know sort of like that.
Scott: Anyway, it's just really interesting because you don't think you know most fantasy stuff.
Scott: I mean look at the Lord of the Rings right everyone.
Scott: It's all I do all white dudes right and it's like the book isn't about.
Rym: think about it.
Rym: Scott Gandalf the white.
Scott: Well, he's also getting up the gray.
Scott: No white Yeah, but I mean the only things that aren't white are like you know fucking orcs and elves and shit also.
Rym: I note that.
Rym: anyway I'm not gonna make all the jokes I could make.
Scott: no But I think what's really interesting about it right is norm like if you went to the movie theater And you watch like a medieval you know a fantasy movie.
Scott: We're like the powerful wizards were like you know African Americans Suddenly like race would be an issue in that.
Scott: but like in the book race is not an issue.
Scott: They just sort of.
Scott: it's just part.
Scott: It's just like.
Scott: yeah, the people aren't white.
Scott: well I think they don't make a deal out of it has no effect on the story.
Scott: race is not an issue at all It's just that's.
Scott: the people are different colors of course.
Rym: I think part of the reason we see this sort of thing is that most Western style fantasy is set in a generically Western medieval Medieval.
Scott: you know medieval times were in Europe where white people lived and so when you think of you know actual medieval stuff you think of you know European people and fantasy worlds tend to be you know Medieval European worlds plus magic, but at
Rym: the same time I feel like someone who reads this book and doesn't pay attention Would just automatically assume that the characters were white or at least were the same color as them because it doesn't.
Scott: if you're a western Person probably it just don't read carefully and realize you know the two words that say his skin was dark red Because it only gets mentioned a couple of times course That's actually.
Rym: the thing I find most interesting about this book is because I'll admit Part of the reason I was looking forward to this is that despite all the wide reading I've done I'd never actually read any of the Earthsea books, and I was really not familiar with Ursula K Le Guin style of writing at all.
Rym: and This book is I mean a lot of people would say it's at the level of a middle schooler and that anyone can read this Book.
Scott: well you know the.
Scott: the reading level is middle school.
Scott: a middle school kid could read it understand the story and possibly even You know read between the lines a bit, but at the same time part of that, and it's appropriate Subject material.
Rym: it's not because it writes or I guess reads down to anyone and it doesn't even shy away from Difficult words or very very subtle interplay, but it's not like Harry Potter where the writing is simplistic and terrible.
Rym: I'm sorry, but those books are written so badly like it bothers me.
Rym: every pair every word just like burns into my soul.
Rym: But the style of this book is very terse very to the point and it's very descriptive.
Rym: but it's not descriptive of Ged it does.
Rym: it kind of is like you're being told the story of Ged From a far and from a far future.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely.
Scott: you know how.
Scott: in like the Hobbit right you know in the at the end of the Hobbit you sort of get Bilbo writing the Hobbit thing going on and it's like am I reading the book that Bilbo wrote?
Scott: or am I reading someone telling me?
Scott: About Bilbo writing the book?
Scott: get this you know that sort of situation, but this is clearly.
Scott: you know Someone who.
Scott: it's weird.
Scott: It's almost like this omniscient narrator right who and They're telling you what really happened.
Scott: like they know right, but there are books in the.
Scott: you know in the history of the world in which this takes place in the history of the world of Earthsea.
Scott: you know Ged.
Scott: the main character here is.
Scott: You know like he is the Gandalf he is the big bad wizard.
Scott: This is not like a spoiler.
Scott: They tell you this right up front right that you know Ged is like the ultimate Wizard in the history of this world like you know the major Historical figure and you're getting his story from the beginning here, and he's.
Scott: you know that.
Scott: so in that world where this is great wizard Obviously later on there become books in this world about the great wizard Just like we have books in our world about.
Scott: you know great generals and historical figures.
Scott: You know so this narrator will say things like oh yeah, and then this happened But you won't find that in the tales of Ged.
Scott: You know as if the tales of Ged are a book that exists in the world.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: it's pretty cool.
Rym: Yes Well, I particularly like how many times there and this could be done to very poor effect and I'm sure there are a lot of authors who have done this poorly, but It'll always.
Rym: the book always gives little asides and says things like Ged sees a certain land in the distance from a ship and As an aside the narrator's informs you.
Rym: But it wouldn't be for many years that he actually set foot in those lands and saw the blah blah blahs of blah blah blah.
Scott: Yeah, most actually what they was talking about there was the tombs of Atuan which is the second book the second book he goes to.
Rym: the Mentioned that that's actually the second part.
Rym: That's with the Old people living on that shoal in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: Yeah now I was speaking of on the very beginning of the book.
Rym: There's a whole other thing they remember.
Rym: they reference Mm-hmm, but it happens often, and it's done very well into very good effect and you get you.
Rym: It's interesting how you a lot of books will.
Rym: you'll know how they end or at least you know that the main characters will succeed.
Rym: But yet at the same time you're full of suspense as to whether or not they will succeed, but this book I was never like.
Rym: I know they'll succeed and I know Absolutely, and I never doubt it, and I never have that suspense.
Rym: Instead I mostly.
Rym: I read it the same way I read a history book in that I'm desperate to find out how he succeeds and why and what happens and what the story was Mmm, but it was never a question of will he make it.
Scott: Hey, he's good.
Scott: There's a bunch more books.
Scott: Yes He's gonna make it.
Rym: you know it says so straight up, but there are books where I know they make it But yet, I still fear for the characters.
Scott: Yeah, there are.
Rym: this book does not do that, and I think it's a strong point.
Scott: for well I think it's.
Scott: I fear for some of the characters, but not you know they don't all make it.
Scott: No, they don't all make it.
Scott: But you know the ones you know that are gonna make it are gonna make it.
Scott: the others are.
Scott: you know more momentary.
Scott: But Rym what is the one thing I always complain about in?
Rym: you know fantasy books god You always will read a fantasy book And there's the awesome old wizard and you hear the stories about the awesome old days when the awesome old wizard is an awesome.
Rym: That's right, but the book is always about today when everything sucks exactly right.
Scott: you read the fantasy book right?
Scott: And it's like the all these characters like the Knights and the Wizards will be saying Back in the day with the old powers.
Scott: You know the old powers are always stronger than the new powers.
Scott: back in the day there were dragons everywhere.
Scott: Nowadays if you find a dragon in a cave you're lucky.
Rym: you know of course There's the prince of nothing which takes the take of look.
Rym: Everything in the old days was great, and then everything went to crap and you know what.
Rym: the old days are back right now This is the new old days.
Scott: That's true, but this book right.
Scott: there is some amount of old days in this book.
Scott: You know they used to be more dragons and such, but this book is the story of get who is the Gandalf.
Scott: It's like you don't really hear them talking about like oh this great old wizard.
Scott: There aren't a lot of names of historical figures.
Scott: They don't talk about Kate great kings of the past or and when anything like that.
Rym: when they do that the interesting part is it's always Indirectly and you never get these.
Rym: it's not like it's hulkin book where
Scott: like you don't even know like you know you sort of get The idea that there's these islands in the middle sort of where there are great kingdoms or like you know the bellies the biggest kingdoms Around but they don't like really talk about them.
Scott: They don't really have an effect so much really.
Scott: you know it like maybe couple times They mentioned like oh, yeah, not like in.
Scott: you know a very civilized highly densely populated place like this island.
Rym: You know oh, but no what I'm saying is that when you hear about history in the context of this book You don't hear about it directly.
Rym: you hear about it indirectly through the times when it is noted that a character or a group of people were singing the tales of ancient days the Verbal unwritten stories that are not widely known throughout the entire world of Earthsea.
Rym: Yeah, and it's very you know burning wheel the songs of the elves the songs of the ages or Tolkien the songs of the ages.
Rym: but What it really evokes?
Rym: maybe partly because I just finished reading that History of the Peloponnesian Wars as seen from the Persian side even though it totally copped out and just talks about the Greeks for like this all second half.
Rym: but It talks a lot about the idea that the Greeks during the Peloponnesian War period the history they had before that Was so steeped in myth that it wasn't even a history like what they looked at.
Rym: his history was the Odyssey
Scott: Cyclope
Rym: and the Iliad and the Trojan War and things that barely ever even existed The fact that their actual history was so new that it went back to purely Mythological origins or origins so lost a time that all you had left were these kind of fantastic stories of you know heroes from the age of heroes and the Trojan Wars and all that sort of thing.
Rym: and This world feels that old.
Rym: it feels like I mean most fantasy books are kind of Middle Ages But this one feels more like Greek Ages.
Rym: You've got archipelagos.
Rym: You've got you know ord ships with barely a concept of how to truly use sails.
Scott: Yeah, boats are really really important and like you know they have sails, but they're not.
Scott: you know good sails like in a British Navy, it's just mostly flat sheets.
Scott: And then Wizards do you know?
Scott: move the wind to keep the boats going sail wise rather than?
Scott: You know and mostly just to keep the boats from sinking not to make them go fast.
Rym: So they've definitely they've got trireme style technology here and their armor and weapons.
Rym: What little is known about them.
Rym: whenever you know things like that aren't brought up.
Rym: often are?
Rym: Clearly bronze made for the most part except for the few iron wielders And it's very much.
Rym: This is more early Greek history than middle European history Which does really lend itself to the fact that not every peep there aren't really white people.
Rym: Yeah, I just I like the fact that the setting is different like that.
Scott: But anyway as I was saying I'm always looking for you know Where is the story of?
Scott: you know the great times the Golden Age when you know there was the most?
Scott: Magic going around.
Scott: and you know the Silmarillion sort of offers that.
Scott: but the Silmarillion isn't really a character narrative.
Scott: It's more like you know a few separate short stories.
Scott: It reads almost like a you know like the Bible sort of disjointed and all these separate parts that don't really flow.
Rym: I'll be honest the what happens in the times of this?
Rym: what the Silmarillion Basically amount to?
Rym: epic level characters with a million balrogs and dragons And we're all playing 10th level characters, we're all like Gandalf the Grey.
Rym: We're going around and then the DM says this is boring.
Rym: Let's play epic level Let's all be 40th level badasses fighting other 40th level.
Rym: Well.
Scott: I forged the greatest artifacts of all time.
Scott: So great.
Scott: They'll be in the players handbook.
Rym: No, but that's what I got from the Silmarillion.
Scott: Yeah, but Earthsea tells you the story of the wizard I mean get.
Scott: is the wizard the number one you know I mean He's got people who are above him at least during the story.
Scott: right you've got og on who's fucking awesome?
Rym: Hey, he's the man.
Scott: Oh John is.
Scott: oh John.
Scott: I think is my favorite.
Rym: He reminds me of Odin so much.
Scott: kind of he's definitely my favorite character in the whole book.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, so he's all quiet But like he's super.
Scott: well anyone who's super wise like that always gets you like the quiet wise one.
Scott: I like the quiet wise ones a lot because you're another quiet nor wise.
Scott: No, I'm wise.
Scott: And You got the guys at the wizard school right who run it.
Scott: And I think you know the best of which is probably my second favorite character the doorkeeper.
Scott: ah the doorkeeper right And you know they're.
Scott: they're you know great wizards at all greater than get is at the moment.
Scott: but it's like they all recognize that get is like either gonna be like the worst thing ever or the best thing ever.
Scott: and You know while they're great wizards.
Scott: They're not like all-powerful can't stop me now.
Scott: They're just strong wizards and magic while it can do a lot isn't Super strong and it usually has a high price and requires a great deal of knowledge.
Rym: But they don't do it.
Rym: the feeling of that and like the sense you get of The state of the world and the fact that these wizards as powerful as they are are not super powerful I think also harkens back to the the setting in the time period and that the whole feel of the book is much Older than almost all fantasy books I read.
Rym: it's set in a tie.
Rym: it feels so ancient like very little came before it Mmm, and then like that more than anything defines this book.
Rym: Of course that might just be the fact that I've been reading a lot of Greek history lately.
Scott: It could be.
Scott: you always seem to whatever you read lately.
Scott: you always tie into everything else you do.
Rym: But at the same time it is true that the setting is very Greek like early Like other books.
Scott: right they like they'll talk about the time of a billion dragons, right and when they talk about it it feels like there was a civilization then and That you know, it's now.
Scott: we're just farther on in the civilization.
Scott: Yes You look you really feels like in the times that are older than this book when there were a lot of dragons there wasn't really civilization as much and even now a lot of places like you know that he goes to that place for a time near the Dragon Mountain whatever where it's really not that civilized.
Scott: It's like a bunch of little separate islands and each person lives on one island and you know They're they're not doing too well and it's very sort of you know, it's like once one or two steps past cave people.
Scott: Yeah, and the only place that really has civilization at all is is the Magic School.
Scott: every other place is sort of like, you know
Rym: It's kind of like when you look at the the same setting well setting the same time period of the real world where there were civilizations that came before but there were a few far between and are so lost to history and shrouded that they're already Barely legends to the people who live.
Scott: Mm-hmm And it almost feels like you know, the time of the a lot of dragons in this book is almost like the time of dinosaurs.
Scott: You know in the real world, it's like yeah, there used to be a bunch of dinosaurs or dragons or whatever But there was no one around then.
Scott: so it's not really an interesting time to talk about as much.
Rym: I just I definitely get the sense that reading because I haven't read nothing else this is the book that talks about kind of the dawn of civilization on a true scale and like that's the point where the world really starts changing.
Rym: and then If it were a standard fantasy book, it takes place like a hundred years after this book.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yep All right, let's talk about.
Scott: let's talk about some interesting scenes, right.
Rym: So one stuff was could anyone but a middle schooler be surprised that all he had to do the beat the shadow Spoilers, by the way Was say his own name.
Scott: Well, no, they sorta it's it's alright.
Rym: So let's talk about the main plot thread here Which I just want to say was obvious the moment the dragon said he knew what the thing's name was.
Scott: I knew I knew before then but maybe that's because it's the second time I've read.
Scott: No, so check this out, right?
Scott: So normally when you have like a hero character Especially someone who's like try to think for a second, right?
Scott: You only ever see Gandalf in the Lord of the Rings when he's old and already powerful, right?
Scott: Do you ever try to think about like what the history of Gandalf was?
Scott: Like what was Gandalf growing up?
Scott: How about Merlin?
Scott: What was Merlin like I guess growing down, right?
Scott: What was it like?
Scott: was he?
Rym: well I have read Elminster making of a mage and by the way if any of you have seen this book burn it Burn it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what was Elminster like when he grew up?
Scott: Did he go to like a little wizard school?
Scott: Was he a punk?
Rym: Yes, you know what?
Rym: I'm pretty sure that Elminster making of mage was stolen Wholesale from a wizard of Earthsea really and in fact, I feel cheapened for having read that book.
Scott: See cuz that's one thing.
Scott: you when you try to if you see someone who's wise and great right someone who's like the mage Right you think about their history and you can only fill it with like wiseness and greatness.
Scott: But I can't you can't imagine.
Scott: possibly look at this You're the greatest wizard in this entire world ever like the most major historical figure and in his early days Just some like country bumpkin kid right who furthermore and then when he went to cuz it done fucked up, right?
Scott: And then he fucks up twice.
Scott: He gets fooled a bunch of times right and when he goes to wizard school He's totally prideful and ass ish, you know, even though and they give you that other character Jasper Right, who is like it's to show you this contrast of like look.
Scott: Here's the typical Prideful asshole guy.
Scott: what normally happens when there's a prideful asshole guy in a book?
Scott: Well, he ends up failing in the end He didn't get his wizard staff and he is the lose right.
Scott: but here they competing with him is the other prideful guy again, which is so atypical for you know, some a character like that, especially the main good guy character to be all prideful and whatever.
Scott: and What happens to him?
Scott: Oh, he totally makes it in the end.
Scott: Yeah, it's all good.
Scott: All right Where else do you see the story like that?
Scott: I don't see one.
Rym: Well in Al Minster making of a man No, but what happens?
Scott: right?
Scott: the main plot thread right?
Scott: He Cast this spell.
Scott: he shouldn't be doing so, you know, he's up to no good right.
Scott: a bad monster shows up But oh John saves him right and warns him.
Scott: so he's right.
Scott: then later on right probably still he's get you know Half of him is all nice and cool, right?
Scott: And that's you know, he's got the two friends at wizards.
Scott: Go on out friends.
Scott: One of Jasper is not his friend, but you got Jasper and you know vetch Australian or yeah Whatever.
Rym: You shouldn't say his true name.
Scott: I know right?
Scott: Yes, we'll talk about that in a minute, right and that's sort of like you combine them and you get get at that point Right.
Scott: half of him is like the wise awesome.
Scott: Cool.
Scott: Good Friendly loving dude and half of him is the prideful asshole, dude.
Scott: And then you know He cast the spell and the black monster.
Scott: he comes out when he's doing something you shouldn't do.
Scott: and what?
Scott: Obviously the metaphor.
Scott: and as soon as from that point on he does learn his lesson.
Scott: now He's just you know good and smart and not prideful or assholes anymore.
Scott: Obviously all that pridefulness and ash holiness went into the black monstery shadow thing, which is now separate from him.
Rym: You know, and of course they keep bringing up to the whole book.
Rym: Well, they Ursula K Le Guin keeps bringing up through the whole book that there can't be darkness without light and light without darkness.
Rym: You can't have words without silence and silence without words.
Rym: both sides needed come together whole.
Scott: it's the typical Adam warlock You know from Marvel Comics story where all the magus comes out and it's the good side and the bad side Are split up into two separate beings and and in the end they had to combine and whatever, you know, it's funny.
Rym: I just watched an old episode of South Park that I just must have never watched Where Cartman has that exact same thing happened to him as evil Cartman and good Cartman.
Rym: they split up and those They they don't actually split into two, but there's the inner battle and it's hilarious.
Rym: the inner battle Ah, but the inner battle spills out into the real world in a hilarious way away, right?
Scott: This is an inner battle.
Scott: the shadow while it sort of has a manifestation isn't really a being.
Scott: you know As soon as he decides I'm gonna go and get this shadow.
Scott: Yeah, the shadows on the run.
Scott: Well, why would the shadows suddenly be on the run?
Scott: it if it was, you know It was much more powerful than he was because it's actually inside of him.
Scott: It's not really, you know, this this outside being.
Scott: that's why he just sort of you know He's following his gut feeling when he's chasing it down because he's chasing it down inside of himself.
Scott: He's not actually chasing that.
Scott: well He is and he isn't actually chasing down a physical magical thing to because I don't think to chase it down He leaves all magic.
Rym: he gets to the edge of the world to where there's all pretty much no magic or anything He's known before.
Scott: Yeah, there's more about the edge of the world later.
Scott: Yeah I figured and I mean he even goes to like, you know death's door to I guess You know chase down slash get away from this thing.
Scott: Like when he's saving like he's trying to save that kid's life and he pretty much goes all the way.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's sort of like a Fullmetal Alchemist you go all the way to the evil door and then you call that evil door.
Rym: I was disappointed with what that evil door was when.
Scott: well in Fullmetal Alchemist.
Scott: I was disappointed but in Earthsea I was not.
Scott: now it's like when he's you know going down and like, you know, the kids getting away and he's like And then he does that whole.
Scott: it like getting there is real quick.
Scott: But then like there's that law it's like a couple pages Describing how he gets back from like the land of death where he's like It's like he's walking uphill in sand and every step is harder than the last.
Scott: It really it reminds me of like a lot of those D&D worlds were like, you know, the demons are trying to escape from you know Whatever demon world it is in the farther away.
Scott: They get this more gravity pulling him back and it's you know, it's it's it's pretty good And I think that the and it's sort of like the same thing.
Scott: It's like when he goes to the end of the world.
Scott: at the end of the book It really feels like he's going to the death's door that he was at before like it's.
Scott: you could imagine it being the same place But I'm not quite sure because I don't remember the other books as much.
Rym: So so it's well I can say this and I can say this openly It's a fantastic book and anyone.
Rym: of course you've all read it But you should convince other people to read and you should if you like.
Scott: the book There's like a whole bunch more.
Scott: There's like tombs of ahtuan and tahanu.
Scott: It takes four hours to read.
Scott: Yeah, it's I mean and it's cheap too.
Scott: What was it on Amazon?
Scott: I mean I bought it at the bookstore for like eight dollars.
Scott: All right, that was the bookstore price Amazon price Course.
Scott: I know that the book you bought Earthsea now an original miniseries event More expensive one there and I felt like thing is I already owned all the books, but someone has them.
Scott: I don't know who has them and So I had to go and buy another one real quick cuz I was like, oh shit The show was on Thursday crap.
Scott: So on one day I went to get it and then I read it Monday Tuesday room What Wednesday Thursday and that was that?
Rym: Do we have anything else more to say about this book?
Rym: I mean it's short enough to where other than saying man that scene was awesome.
Scott: I got a few that scenes was awesome.
Scott: one right when he's in the wizard school, right and That like the master patterner right and they don't tell you what goes on.
Scott: that a lot.
Scott: It's like yeah, there's that Grove, right?
Scott: Chekhov's gun with the Grove right?
Scott: You can't get to the Grove of Illidan, you know.
Scott: You can go there later and then later he finally gets to go to the Grove of Illidan.
Rym: And it's literally like he went to the Grove and learned many things and came out of the Grove.
Scott: Yeah, it's like oh the master patterner was there.
Scott: the things he teaches you they're sort of crazy.
Scott: and in one way I felt like it was a cop-out like didn't want to describe what the master patterner does and never you know.
Scott: But on the other hand, it's like whoa.
Scott: They still kept it a secret from us.
Scott: this omniscient narrator kept a secret from us what goes on in the Grove of Illidan.
Scott: It's like that's.
Scott: that's some pretty rough.
Rym: There are things you shouldn't know.
Scott: now I guess there are also the whole thing with the doorkeeper, right?
Scott: It's like you think about.
Scott: if you think about what the doorkeeper does even more.
Scott: It's like he really is The doorkeeper.
Scott: cuz think right in this world.
Scott: We got to talk about you know, the true names of things.
Scott: right to have security Right, especially at a wizard school.
Scott: They got to know the names of all these wizard kids, right?
Scott: Otherwise they you know, the wizard kids can go nuts and they got nothing on them.
Scott: So to get into the wizard school, he's got to tell the doorkeepers real name.
Rym: But you can only get your true name if someone tells it to you.
Scott: Well that you get it, you know earlier in life.
Scott: It's like you know bar mitzvah.
Rym: someone tells it but you have to get me.
Rym: he was given his name by the Grey Wizard.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: So, you know, he goes and when he goes into the wizard school He's got to give up his name to the wizard school.
Scott: That's in, you know, ensuring the security of the wizard school.
Rym: It's kind of like how our IT wouldn't give your transcript back if you still owe them money.
Scott: exactly exactly Right.
Scott: and then on the way out.
Scott: you got it, you know The doorkeeper won't let you out until you tell him his name.
Scott: You know, it's like you figured my name out.
Scott: now you can leave.
Scott: and it's like as soon as you go in the wizard school You give up all your freedom in exchange for you know, the incredible learnings and power, you know It's like that's the price you pay.
Scott: and then you can get your freedom back, you know sort of once you proved you're the real deal.
Scott: and then you know how he when he just do any figure and he figures out the name of the doorkeeper to get out and he like he basically says like.
Scott: He says the cleverest thing.
Scott: He's like you keep an hour.
Scott: He's like you keep a narrow door.
Scott: Let me go sit and grow thinner.
Scott: So may I pass?
Rym: Yeah, but then he comes back and says well, I can't figure it out.
Scott: He's like I can guess and I can't kill you to get through but I'll leave if you'll answer one question for me.
Scott: Yeah, what's your name?
Scott: It's like oh so and it totally works.
Scott: and it's like they don't even tell you the dude's name.
Scott: They're just like.
Scott: and he told him his name and he repeated it back to him and then he walked out.
Scott: I like that part.
Rym: Yeah, plus I like the way true names are taken kind of to an extra extent here.
Scott: Secondary like I don't know.
Scott: I think it's maybe not even a secondary but like the other primary You know theme of the book the fact that the world itself is nothing more than the slowly spoken words of the stars.
Scott: Yeah, yeah pretty much.
Scott: I mean and think about that, right?
Scott: So the true names of things like hold power, you know when you say any true names of things Right aren't just there is not like some objective name thing.
Scott: It's the names of things.
Scott: as dragon It's the dragon language, right?
Scott: Whatever dragons call things is what they are.
Rym: I really like the fact though that because dragons converse in the old tongue They are the only beings that know how to lie in it.
Rym: Yeah Humans because because of their nature can only speak the truth in that tongue because it's the tongue that truly names things.
Scott: It's like if you're saying the true names of things you can't possibly lie But a dragon can because they're older and smarter than you.
Scott: and by saying the true names of things That's where the magic comes from right.
Scott: you say the name of a rock, you know to to get power over that rock.
Scott: It's just like a true name of the bird to have it come to him, you know and stuff like that.
Scott: But notice how when they get to like the end of the world, you know closer to the edge like magic works differently over there You know, it's like.
Scott: he's like, you know, he's like yeah and my island all the way over here So far from the center of the world, you know spells that used to work don't work or act strangely.
Scott: yet I see other people with different spells that are working.
Scott: So it's like they don't fully explain like, you know the science of the magic but it's it's really interesting how it's like.
Scott: maybe dragons over.
Scott: is it?
Scott: is it the dragon?
Scott: the power comes from the dragons and you know Whatever they called things in that part of the world is where the power comes from.
Scott: or is it you know?
Scott: The power is somehow our power of belief.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Oh, you know what actually would make a lot of words.
Scott: You know if there's enough power in those words where they're met.
Scott: They're spoken often here or they are known here that it's like there's a rock over on this side of the world.
Scott: Well, there were never dragons calling it this name over here.
Scott: So it doesn't know that that's its name.
Scott: It doesn't have any power over.
Rym: it does point out several times in the book that you know They were so far from places that the things out here didn't even know their own name.
Scott: Yeah It's like how does get get his true name?
Scott: Someone tells it to him.
Scott: It's what he's called.
Scott: Someone calls him that right.
Scott: so in the middle of the world where the dragons were right Dragons called the rocks by that name and thus that name has power over those rocks.
Rym: But well, you know, it really makes once Mm-hmm.
Rym: I can't spoil the other books.
Rym: Well the other books that aren't that you haven't read.
Rym: but Think about how the magic and the prince of nothing works.
Rym: if if you take it to be the exact same system the exact same way magic works on a Fundamental level then it kind of makes perfect sense.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of similar but it's just.
Scott: it's a really interesting way for you know, the magic to work and Simultaneously get a message across about you know, the importance of names, you know It's not a shallow book Despite being short despite being sure short and deep.
Scott: It's the way I like it nice and easy get a lot out of it.
Scott: I'm trying to think of this anything else awesome going on here.
Rym: pretty much the most awesome part for me was when dragons can lie In that tongue, but humans can't.
Scott: yeah, that was pretty cool.
Scott: and how he totally how he gets the dragon.
Rym: Yeah By the way, I know your name.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like why did he know his name?
Scott: Well, because you know, yes Well, he guessed based on a story he heard and that's it's like all you know, the power of wizards isn't in this book.
Scott: I mean he had they.
Scott: obviously He has some sort of natural affinity to you know magics, right but power in this book really is knowledge Right.
Scott: It's like he's a quick learner and that's why he's so powerful.
Scott: It's he learned quicker than everyone else.
Scott: He knows more names of things.
Scott: He's it came easily to him.
Scott: It's not about you know.
Scott: Oh, I have more midi chlorians or the forces drawn.
Scott: It's not about you know, I have magic items or I have more levels.
Scott: It's I know more.
Scott: I know more names of things and I am I learn these things easily and that's why I'm the most powerful because I am more knowledgeable and Knowledge is where magic comes from.
Scott: whoever knows more knows more magic, you know, it's not you know.
Scott: Can you you know manipulate your hands in such a way or any you know sort of skill like that?
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time some people even if they're otherwise bright just don't have the gift.
Scott: Well, yeah, you know that that's you know, the other part of it Yeah, yeah, I don't know they didn't go too deeply into that.
Rym: so Moving on.
Rym: I mean we have to choose the next book and I So we're done with the earth sees you have anything more to say.
Scott: I'm kind of I feel like I have something more to say but none to come to mind.
Scott: Yeah Well, I feel like we should conclude though.
Scott: It's a great book.
Scott: There's other books in the series should all be read Yeah, but you didn't read any more except the first one.
Scott: No, but I will see.
Scott: the thing is the second book actually, you know gets there right at least I. he's there in books Two and three as far as I remember.
Scott: I only read these things once way back and someone has my copies.
Scott: So, I don't know but I remember like at least in like tombs of Ottawa and he's there but he's not like the main character.
Scott: It's like it's about someone else.
Scott: but like he's there, you know, and then you know, they sort of get into later on.
Scott: You know Kings and things like that Which is the way they do.
Scott: that is actually completely well the way she does.
Scott: that is actually completely different for the way Other books have handled it yet again.
Scott: So it's like double whammies upcoming All right.
Rym: So I actually had a lot of trouble trying to decide what book I want to choose because the deal was that Scott could pick Any book any book in the world and I picked.
Scott: I picked what I gave it to you listeners.
Scott: I picked a book that was good for you.
Scott: Not a book.
Scott: Well, it was kind of good for me, but more good for you than Scott Scott.
Rym: Was it good for you?
Rym: It was good because it was good for me.
Rym: I know real good.
Scott: But you know, I picked a book that would satisfy listeners and listeners.
Scott: in mind that I made my selection.
Scott: Really I don't know if it's gonna be so generous.
Scott: he might you know, just be like, yeah, fuck you all Ulysses.
Rym: Hey, I don't like that book.
Scott: or you might just be like, yeah, fuck you all, you know war and peace.
Rym: Hey, I don't like that book either.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: but my trouble is that well Scott Gives one to you in that he picks something that you will clearly enjoy and probably read.
Rym: My brand of giving one to you is forcing you to read something that you otherwise wouldn't read but yet is a fantastic work.
Scott: However, yeah, you might have a hard time reading because apparently you're all literate.
Rym: However, I'm not going to pick the Count of Monte Cristo because wallet is one of my favorite novels ever.
Scott: actually, I just read an interview with Jason and You know the comic guy.
Scott: Yep, and he was like Yeah Dumas uses five words when he could use one.
Scott: Cuz he you know why he was paid by the law I know but he you know easy cuz he wrote.
Scott: he did the last musketeer and he's like, yeah I tried to read three musketeer seat.
Scott: I didn't finish it.
Rym: I Remember in particular the the Count of Monte Cristo spends like three paragraphs describing the chain mail that he's wearing at one point.
Rym: But so I'm not gonna pick something like that.
Rym: So I wanted to pick a book that I haven't read that I'm going to read soon.
Rym: That's in my queue But I looked at my queue and it is 50% fantasy and I want to get away from fantasy because we've been talking a lot about fantasy, you know, prince of nothing.
Rym: this And at the same time all the other books in my queue are nonfiction and I don't think you want to read a history of the Peloponnesian Wars or Contemporary Greek history like Xenophon or Herodotus.
Scott: I don't Herodotus.
Rym: No, it's Herodotus.
Scott: quiet you Captain Agricola.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: So what are you gonna?
Scott: What are you gonna give the people?
Scott: Are you gonna throw the P people something that's like Roman?
Scott: or maybe you're gonna give them like some of your Victor Hugo your French a file is ever gonna do?
Rym: I don't like Victor Hugo Who says I'm even a Francophile?
Scott: Oh, you know it.
Rym: I'm more of a Greco-Roman a file if anything.
Scott: Yeah, you're Europhile But only South or southern Southern Europe or France's north south east and west Europe.
Scott: In fact, it's in the middle except for Germany, which is more in the middle.
Rym: So I kind of narrowed it down to I. on one hand I might want to do a Farewell to arms because I really do like Hemingway and while the Sun Also Rises is a better book that meant more to me.
Rym: Everyone's read the Sun Also Rises.
Rym: At least I hope everyone's read the Sun Also Rises.
Scott: I've read the Sun All Rises.
Scott: I've read Old Man in the Sea.
Scott: I did not read Farewell to Arms But you know what?
Scott: That's one for the listeners because Hemingway is really easy.
Rym: It is it was dark.
Rym: I was drinking coffee.
Rym: The window was open.
Rym: It was dark outside.
Scott: It's like reading Cat in the Hat 20 times.
Scott: You just read a Hemingway book.
Rym: No, it's reading the Cat in the Hat.
Rym: if the cat was depressed and drank all the time to cover up his horrible.
Scott: That's that's what it's about.
Scott: I mean if you want breaks into the house and molest children, it's it's pretty dark.
Rym: If you want to get a taste of Hemingway without reading a full Hemingway Just read A Clean Well Lid Place because that Encapsulates pretty much everything that Hemingway ever wrote into one concise short story.
Rym: but I don't feel like a lot of people have read Farewell to Arms and of All the books I've read in my life.
Scott: Oh god.
Scott: Oh god chainsaw juggling.
Rym: Of all the books I have no idea how he died.
Rym: When In Rome that book has perhaps the most cold depressing end I've ever seen because it hits you like a brick and then the book ends with not even so much as a Typical.
Scott: everyone dies at the end.
Rym: No, it's even worse than that the book basically.
Scott: how could it be?
Scott: I mean, I've read you know, so many things that you know purposefully depressing endings.
Scott: How could you possibly You know do worse?
Rym: because it it hits you in such a horrible cold ham-fisted manner.
Rym: it's like you're reading and then Someone comes out and says something and the main character walks away in the at the end.
Rym: Like that's it.
Rym: It's like BAM done and it.
Rym: it really affected me because I read this book in middle school and it It was really sad.
Rym: It was perhaps the saddest thing I'd ever read up to that point.
Rym: I have a couple copies of it.
Scott: All right good I don't want to buy anything.
Scott: I have a.
Rym: I have a small collection of first editions of books.
Scott: I really like you've decided on for.
Rym: maybe not though because I have a first edition of.
Rym: well anyway, skipping all that.
Rym: but the other option which I Partly want to talk about because the book is very relevant to a lot of things going on in society right now And I have more social commentary to say than I do Commentary about the book and it would probably be a two-hour show and Scott and I both just read it recently.
Scott: Yeah, that's what this if you pick this one.
Scott: This is one for us because we just read it and we don't have to read it again.
Scott: Oh, this one is farewell to arms.
Scott: You have to go and read it.
Rym: But if you have to read it, I've read farewell to arms like four times you pick this book.
Scott: We don't have to read shit cuz we just read it.
Rym: Hyperion is like one of the best books I've read.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is that's not one for the listeners who are all illiterate because it's long ish.
Scott: It took me a few days to read.
Scott: Oh my god days and It's hard.
Scott: Like it's not a baby book.
Scott: Well plus middle school kid wouldn't get it.
Rym: if you're not terribly literate You better know your Keats at least a little.
Scott: if you don't have knowledge of like, you know art history at least a little bit and Keats and Poetry and and you know things you're not gonna get a lot of the book You have to know like you have to know like sci-fi.
Scott: you have to know like detective Canterbury Tales, even though I'm going to say I haven't read the Canterbury Tales.
Rym: The Canterbury Tales are not entertaining and are not worth reading except as an exercise in literary frustration.
Scott: It's like I hate the everything there is to get from my period.
Scott: you have to be a smart and well-read person.
Scott: Otherwise it will do nothing for you and you'll just be like what the fuck.
Rym: of course the other problem is You would all hate us because you get to the end of Hyperion and you look up.
Scott: You got to read Fall of Hyperion.
Scott: Yes, you got nothing.
Rym: But not only that all the social commentary.
Rym: I have all the relevant discussion about what we are doing to ourselves as a society now And the fact that reading Hyperion and Fall of Hyperion has changed in a few Not in substantial ways my political views.
Scott: the thing is there's also in Demian and rise of in Demian.
Scott: I didn't read.
Scott: I know I sort of they give.
Scott: they tell you at the end of Fall of Hyperion Like what is gonna happen in in Demian?
Scott: But then I look at those two in Demian books and they're real big.
Scott: so I wonder like what the fuck is in those.
Rym: But at the same time I don't feel like it matters.
Scott: It does.
Scott: it doesn't matter that much because there's really only one thing that is left a mystery and it's not a mystery that you Really need to know yeah
Rym: as opposed to Hyperion Which doesn't leaves
Scott: every mystery that explains them all in Fall of Hyperion except
Rym: for
Scott: one
Rym: is it is such an incredibly satisfying book.
Scott: It's real satisfying.
Rym: and yeah I have a couple.
Rym: the other option the third option that I get a third option that I really really want to do Because I don't feel like enough.
Rym: people have read it and I have some interesting takes on it.
Rym: I've read this a couple times in my life not contiguously, but the Odyssey.
Scott: Okay Homer's I've read parts of the Odyssey a few times.
Scott: I've never read the whole thing like all at once.
Rym: I'll admit I'm kind of ashamed to admit that I've never actually read the Iliad or Several other of these ancient of these great words need or whatever.
Rym: but I but I've read the Odyssey several times partly because I really dig Athena and I Don't like Odysseus that much, you know, my man is.
Rym: Your man is probably precise Besides an ass and I'll say Fucking man.
Rym: No one beats Poseidon cuz Athena beats Poseidon every time because wall Poseidon is strong.
Rym: He's stupid.
Rym: He's a stupid motherfucker.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what?
Scott: Everyone's afraid of him because you know what.
Scott: you can't get anywhere without a boat Can't get anywhere without a boat and every time everyone gets in a boat.
Scott: They're like, please Poseidon don't throw don't tip me over and drown me, please.
Scott: Oh my god Sometimes he goes.
Scott: I will let you go and so and but I will actually even though I'll let you go and live I will Steer you to a horrible island with a monster.
Scott: But other times Poseidon goes, you know what?
Scott: I'm just gonna fuck you you drown.
Rym: Haha.
Rym: See unlike you I will not prostrate myself before gods.
Scott: Yeah, so what besides?
Scott: just gonna tip your ass over?
Scott: Yeah, you know Poseidon.
Scott: I'm so smart and you're so stupid.
Scott: It'll be like yeah, but you're so dead.
Rym: But at the same time all I have to do is be Odysseus like enough to where Athena will totally have my back.
Scott: Totally stupid.
Scott: See How to beat Poseidon's and his stupid his stupidity, but anger be just as stupid.
Rym: See the thing is Odysseus isn't stupid.
Scott: He's not that stupid.
Rym: He's clever really clever.
Rym: It's just reading the Odyssey the most recent time.
Rym: I read it I got a different perception from the other couple times.
Rym: I'd read it and instead of seeing him as this clever amazing, man I kind of saw him as this Brute who just kept making things worse and then when things got bad enough He'd do something miraculous to get himself out of it and then make it lucky.
Rym: Lucky lucky lucky, but everything he does is of his own scale.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: he could have avoided all that in the first place by not Continuing to yell insults back at the island after he escaped for one good job.
Rym: So should I do farewell to arms or the Odyssey or?
Rym: Hyperion?
Scott: you have to pick.
Scott: it's up to you.
Scott: You know, it's not a don't put it out for a vote.
Rym: You know what I'm doing.
Rym: a farewell to arms.
Rym: that is my book Ernest Hemingway's.
Scott: I recommend it.
Scott: hello to legs.
Rym: if you've never If you've never read Hemingway before I really would recommend reading III believe it's called a clean well-lit place, but I might be mistaken and then from there read farewell to arms and Yeah, that's my book.
Rym: I think it's good.
Rym: also for those of you who are worried that it'll be boring It's kind of an action story.
Rym: There are several Surprising moments of harrowing heroic action.
Scott: I should pick old man in the sea just to continue making it even easier.
Rym: So we're gonna end on what.
Rym: where's Waldo Now?
Scott: where's?
Scott: although I spy with my little eye something red.
Scott: Oh, there it is.
Scott: You say it here Did you spy the button on page five?
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: Did you see the paper clip on page six?
Scott: Oh shit?
Rym: All right, I know I think we're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.