Rym: It's Wednesday March 12th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: kick-ass Let's do this.
Rym: Amen, it's finally here despite my love of it.
Rym: I actually haven't seen past the first episode of avatar until now.
Scott: Yeah, I saw like a few minutes of it when I was walking around the house.
Scott: Yeah, it looks like a Saturday morning kids show.
Rym: Avatar is a really freakin good show especially Pretty much from the last two episodes of the first season.
Rym: from what I hear all the way up to the end and ongoing is Just absolutely amazing.
Scott: well I don't know.
Scott: I can't really say other than I saw two minutes of it which isn't really enough got him walked through the room and went.
Scott: That's not enough to pass any judgment on whether the show is actually good or not however.
Scott: I can say I'm not too Excited or enthused to watch the show never excited or enthused about anything.
Scott: there are other things I have you know to consume my entertainment time that I will choose.
Rym: before I choose that well I'll say this it of all the things competing for my Eyeballs avatar pretty much is at the top now And I'm probably going to watch it to the exclusion of everything else until I've seen all of it.
Scott: Yeah, that's the exact opposite.
Scott: right here I'm gonna be playing Smash Brothers, and I played some Smash Brothers and some DS games, and I'm gonna be reading some comics.
Rym: man I'm rocking through Layton.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Layton's a good one.
Rym: I'm too picker at short of a perfect score.
Rym: so far.
Scott: well We'll see.
Scott: we'll see.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I haven't had any trouble so far.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, how far are you?
Rym: I'm pushing a thousand.
Scott: yeah see part of the thing is you know it's not so much.
Scott: if you Really pay attention to every puzzle and try really hard to get a perfect score you will.
Scott: But there comes a point where like your patience will run out And you just feel that you know.
Scott: and also some of the puzzles They're worded poorly and us rules lawyer II types would be like oh fuck you I don't know.
Rym: I haven't run into anything like that yet.
Scott: I've run into.
Scott: there are only like a small handful of them But they're there and they're annoying.
Rym: plus the thing is maybe it's just because as a kid I was in math Olympiad, but so far the vast majority of the question
Scott: you've seen before
Rym: are actually exactly From questions I answered to get my little trophy in fourth grade
Scott: I would say about 10% of the puzzles in there I had seen before at some point in my
Rym: life of all the math and geometry ones.
Rym: I think I've seen all of them Mmm.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: well I guess yeah like the you know have a pyramid of coins Flip it upside down by moving and of them or you've got a bunch of pictures the different sizes that aren't marked.
Rym: How do you get certain amounts into certain pictures all those things?
Scott: Mm-hmm hey Anything else going on not really?
Rym: I'm just kind of waiting for you to do your news.
Rym: slow talker quiet tired, dude.
Scott: I'm actually sort of like.
Scott: the reason I was being slow right there is because I was reading things while Talking.
Scott: and how great hoping you would just keep yapping so I could finish reading.
Rym: I got nothing to say.
Rym: I'm waiting for you to do your crap.
Rym: Oh news, so I can do my big news.
Scott: Oh you think my news is crap.
Scott: Oh, do you?
Rym: I let's see what it is.
Scott: Maybe I just won't tell it to you all right?
Scott: No, actually I have to tell it to you or else the shows gonna be real boring real fast.
Scott: so bone you like bone right.
Rym: I Liked the first three quarters of bone, and I'll be honest.
Rym: I thought the end was pretty shit.
Scott: all things considered I think it was shit.
Rym: I think the end was good But like the whole last third of it was just really kind of cliche and tired And it was obvious that he didn't wasn't quite sure where he was going with it.
Scott: It seemed to me like definitely the parts that were planned were the earlier parts, but anyway regardless Bone.
Scott: a while way back they tried to make an animated movie of it.
Rym: How well that went.
Scott: yeah, basically they tried and You know Jeff Smith fought with Nickelodeon, and it didn't happen.
Scott: basically you know more details.
Scott: whatever right they tried to make a bone movie.
Scott: No good Well Warner Brothers has acquired the film rights.
Scott: that doesn't mean they're gonna make one.
Scott: it doesn't mean they're not gonna make one.
Scott: it means they have the right to make one and We'll see what comes of that.
Scott: there could be within a year or two some sort of bone movie in the movie theaters.
Rym: It could be most likely if they just got the rights to it.
Rym: within a year or two They'll announce a bone movie at best.
Scott: Yeah There might be a live-action Bone.
Scott: you could you know give you anything like.
Scott: they haven't said anything yet.
Rym: live-action bone would not I don't know about that.
Scott: Yeah, I know right That's it's kind of like huh, but seeing is how you know.
Scott: the last time They tried to make a bone movie Jeff Smith you know with be not being happy with it was able to sort of stop put a gum in the works.
Scott: I'm sure that if he wasn't happy with it.
Scott: He would have the ability to put the gum in the works again.
Rym: Well the problem is one thing Nickelodeon did not offer him that other people might is the bag of stop carrying money.
Rym: There's always for anyone except possibly the creator of Watchmen There is a bag of shut up money.
Scott: well the thing is is that You know the.
Scott: he already has a whole bunch of money.
Scott: I mean You know the color editions of bone that they sell in like the scholastic book catalog.
Scott: Those sell like the crazy like millions and millions of copies.
Rym: There is still money.
Scott: doesn't really need more money.
Rym: only Alan Moore is untouchable.
Scott: Yeah, all right and luckily they tricked him, but yeah You know I usually hate like all this sort of preview news not really news.
Rym: yet How much shit did you give me when I talked about how Peter Jackson is really interested in doing a Temeraire movie Yeah, and how I'm waiting every day for there to be more news on that.
Rym: well Difference between look that up right now while you're talking.
Scott: There's a difference between someone's interested in something It means like someone said something versus someone actually did something Which is acquiring rights and on the also.
Scott: the only reason this is really newsworthy is because of the previous Failed bone movie attempt.
Scott: if there was not a previous attempt.
Scott: This would not be really newsworthy.
Rym: Well Peter Jackson option the rights to the Temeraire movie uh-huh and that was my original news actually All righty, and there is no news since then At least according to Wikipedia.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, well they might be waiting for more books to be written.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I really want a movie.
Scott: so So all this news really translates to is you have like two years to read bone before so you can read it before the movie.
Rym: I'd recommend you do that.
Rym: if you don't know what bone is listen to our review.
Rym: bone is a fantastic Comic and yet, it's two minutes ago.
Scott: You're trashing it.
Rym: no I was trashing the last third or so which is really.
Rym: it's better than most comics And it's even better than most manga But it's really kind of cliche and tired at the end you
Scott: ever you ever notice that it same thing happens with Death Note Where you know you'll have a body of work that is you know perhaps serialized perhaps not
Rym: Death note.
Rym: epitomize that to the point that I never bothered reading after.
Rym: yeah, it's like a climax.
Scott: You have some sort of collected.
Scott: You know unified work of art.
Scott: You know that spans many pages or many chapters right and Some of the chapters are so great.
Scott: You know like amazingly great, and then some of these chapters.
Scott: You know they might not be amazingly great, but they'll still be okay.
Scott: But because they're together You're comparing that part to the previous part And you like you treat it like shit even though if it was only the okay part on its own you would treat it Okay, it's just because you have the added disappointment of you know the high expectations set by the earlier parts of the work.
Scott: But it depends more negative feelings about the other part.
Rym: after the cool thing happened in Death Note.
Scott: What came after was not something I would have read and I might not have read it But I wouldn't have said it's terrible.
Scott: I said it's okay.
Rym: Yes, it's kind of normal.
Rym: I didn't say that the third last third of bone was terrible either.
Rym: I said it was tired and cliched which it very much was.
Scott: yeah, but You know it's like people.
Scott: you know if you look at the general opinion people have of you know the the parts of things.
Scott: It I don't know.
Scott: I see it happening.
Rym: Yeah, though.
Rym: I have to death note would have been better off if it had ended shortly after the climax.
Scott: I mean here also.
Scott: You know I guess Star Wars might be like the ultimate example because episode one did really suck.
Rym: see that's the thing.
Rym: Scott Johnson always made this argument with us for the longest time.
Rym: we bring him up a lot I've noticed, but we'd always trash Especially after the first two Star Wars movies that come out the new ones.
Rym: ah those movies were crap.
Rym: They're nothing.
Rym: They're awful Ah, and I never even bothered watching either one of them again, but he always said no.
Rym: They're not actually worse You're just your expectations and your childhood nostalgia.
Rym: You got to be a kid to see those movies, but one kids who saw those movies also didn't like that.
Scott: Well, you know episode one was just terrible all around.
Rym: episode one was an awful movie.
Scott: Yeah, episode two was an okay-ish movie that had some bad parts.
Rym: episode two was a movie I would watch like if I was sick in bed, and it was the only.
Scott: That's the kind of movie you'd watch for free on TV when you're bored And you can't get up and then I work on my laptop and not care that there were commercials.
Scott: right episode three was actually a slightly above average sort of Entertaining shallow romp kind of movie.
Scott: Yeah, you know and Watch episode three.
Rym: I could maybe watch it one more time in my life.
Scott: Yeah, I couldn't watch it repeatedly repeatedly forever like I watch the Empire Strikes Back right now.
Scott: I can watch the Empire Strikes Back right now and put it on repeat until I die.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I might have to break it up with a new hope and possibly the Lord of the Rings.
Scott: I could watch any move any of those movies in any combination on repeat until I die And I would pretty much not have a reason to get up.
Scott: But anyway, yeah.
Scott: But I do think that episode three gets less praise that it possibly You know it deserves a little bit a tiny bit of praise.
Scott: you know what I don't think it gets that tiny bit To four or five and six.
Rym: I think it got all the praise it deserved.
Rym: Yeah, plus we can't forget never forget the feeling you had because I know you all had this feeling.
Rym: remember Way back when the news came out They're making more Star Wars and everyone in the world lost their shit including all of us everyone.
Rym: This was gonna be the biggest thing ever.
Rym: Remember how you felt sitting in that theater when Star Wars appeared on screen?
Rym: episode one and that music started playing and that tech started scrolling.
Rym: and Remember how you felt when you walked out of that theater.
Rym: Yeah, remember that feeling Where no one wanted to admit out loud how absolutely shitty that movie was to anyone else.
Rym: Everyone was kind of waiting for someone to say it.
Rym: Anyway, that was some bad times.
Rym: bone is not like that.
Rym: the bone is good.
Rym: Don't get us wrong.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: Let's do anyway.
Rym: All right, so I got some real news here.
Rym: This is that I don't know how many of you are aware.
Rym: I'm sure every punk kid out there listening is aware This is one of those things that just doesn't.
Rym: it's not in my demographic.
Rym: It's not something that gets on my radar.
Rym: So it's one of those things I know about but I don't care about.
Rym: So to explain to those of you who might not be hip to the internet as a website called crunchyroll crunchyfrog crunchyroll Okay, and crunchyroll Basically, you can go there and watch fan subs straight up streaming in real time.
Rym: Just click on and watch him and also anything licensed that no one happens to have complained about yet.
Rym: No, and this is one of those semi shady dubious kind of deals.
Rym: But they got a lot of anime in there and even good stuff.
Rym: You want to see some Galaxy Express?
Rym: You want to see anything?
Rym: It's all in there Except for stuff that has been specifically demanded to be taken down But because of copyright law due to people having licenses to distribute in the u.s.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: now this word gets interesting.
Rym: Everyone kind of assumed.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I like that'll eventually get shut down that that happens.
Rym: There's no way that's legal.
Rym: well You see crunchyroll Just got four million dollars in capital from a legitimate and well known Well-funded very very I can't say legitimate enough.
Rym: It's a real venture capital firm Ben rock.
Scott: Why can't we get venture capital?
Scott: I mean, it seems like everyone in their mother even like really unprofessional not big people is getting venture capital.
Scott: Why can't we get it?
Scott: It should be so easy.
Scott: Let's just quit our jobs get some and then write software and make podcasts.
Rym: I'll tell you this out there if any of you know a venture capitalist There's a good investment right here.
Scott: Yeah I'm telling you if you can pay for me and Rym to not have to go to the city Every day all we will do is sit in our house and make things that are worth money.
Rym: God, you know in forms of entertainment and software We can probably do four or five hours as long as we had a staff of like Podcasting radio television whatever every day.
Scott: So anyone who knows like about business, which is the one thing we have No clue is what to do.
Scott: We need a business person to business us The same way that Robert coup business penny arcade.
Rym: There's the minor problem of.
Rym: I have two competing desires in my life And these are two desires that have been fighting within me much like the forces fighting within.
Rym: Dr Jekyll for all of my life.
Rym: on one hand I am ambitious and I will really not stop short until everyone in the world knows my name.
Scott: on the other hand you're lazy now.
Rym: on the other hand I Very much very much Understand and respect the decision of anyone who is able to make such a decision to live the life of the idle rich.
Rym: Mmm idle rich is the way to go idle rich is high quality I think.
Rym: in the end if I was idle rich though, I'd probably just podcast a lot maybe Casting from my yacht.
Rym: I'd read a lot of softwares Anyway, so yeah four million dollars in legitimate not fake not laundered capital.
Rym: Now this tells me something that either there are only really three possibilities here.
Rym: one Four million dollars worth of money just got totally hoodwinked.
Scott: That's quite possible
Rym: - The thing that I have been telling people who run anime clubs for the longest time The belief that I have had for pretty much as long as I've known about anime that pretty much Unless someone in the United States has the absolute legal right to distribute an anime There's almost nothing that can be done against you legally because the people in Japan the way international law and copyright law works It's really not worth it that I'm to sue you even if they can Mmm, which might be true or three?
Rym: There's some other legal loophole where these venture capitalists realized that they can totally get away with it.
Scott: Well, it really seems like this is just.
Scott: I don't know why it's.
Scott: are they investing in this site?
Scott: because it's a popular video site And I think that that's they.
Scott: think that that's like a you know, the hip new thing, you know to go along with.
Rym: You know YouTube it's like Is they're going to have?
Rym: they unveiled their first legal anime stream.
Scott: So that's the plan they're going with.
Scott: but the thing is they want to be the legal YouTube of anime sort of like that Hulu site.
Scott: they came out today.
Rym: It's a short flash animated series Entitled Eagle Talon the movie the Chancellor only lives twice in other words.
Scott: Oh, I thought that was something like from Adult Swim or whatever.
Rym: Well, it eventually became that Apparently the short flash animation is the series that turned into that or something.
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: I know that I'm just reading from anime news network.
Scott: Okay but what it seems like because it seems like to me what the plan here is right is You start out by being a site with illegal shit, right?
Scott: You get a bunch of visitors coming for the piracy stuff.
Scott: you put out some original stuff next to it You get an audience for that.
Scott: Then when people actually start to get on your case and get rid of the piracy stuff and you still got this audience for original Shit, and now you got money see while that's possible Which only your bait is illegal bait?
Scott: It's not just sort of like if you go to the you're playing Zelda and you use that meat.
Rym: It's not just venture capital.
Rym: Venrock general partner David Simonov actually now sits on crunchyrolls board of directors.
Scott: They have a board of directors for the sort of hackish Unprofessional looking crummy website that I could put together.
Rym: I'm like a few days realize that if you get venture capital you pretty much have to put together a board of directors.
Scott: But I mean like I could make a website that does everything crunchyroll does.
Scott: it would take a few days And the only thing I would need is money for all the servers to host it.
Rym: And the only thing front and a copy of flash has to offer is that they already exist and they already have the market.
Rym: No one's gonna go to your site because they already know about crunchyroll.
Scott: I know.
Scott: but the point is is like they didn't do much and that they didn't do anything I couldn't do and they got four million dollars.
Scott: So why can't I get four million dollars?
Rym: Anyway, I don't.
Rym: this was this news.
Rym: wasn't Scott bitch about how he doesn't have any money?
Scott: I just have yeah, what have enough money to work for myself.
Rym: I don't care about you and your stupid.
Rym: Eh, I want venture capital.
Rym: Anyway, I want it.
Rym: So the thing that this site has to offer is four million unique visitors and 50 million streams a month.
Scott: Yeah, well because the piracy now the thing is they.
Rym: they straight up just show fansubs.
Rym: They say they're showing fansubs They just totally show whatever they can get and if anyone complains they just say oh, sorry and take it down.
Rym: Yeah, and even better I didn't even know this cuz I don't use this site but according to anime news network the way they make money is that you can get higher quality videos and Badges for your screen names.
Rym: if you quote unquote donate money to them.
Scott: Who?
Scott: why would you pay money to have an icon appear next to your screen name?
Rym: A lot of people will remember all the people who paid money to the natural selection developers to get that little shield.
Scott: I never understood that.
Rym: Anyway, beyond that they're actually now to make full-on money with his venture capital going to start putting video ads Into the full length episodes they offer.
Rym: Oh, well people are gonna go right back to the fit torrents and they say they intend to work directly with quote a select number of Japanese firms unquote to acquire content legally, but the fact remains that they're just showing fansubs.
Rym: and Here's what I really want to talk about.
Rym: Funimation had some strong Bandai, but funimation's words are the are the best here.
Rym: quote Funimation has been carefully monitoring the activities of crunchyroll.com for some time now.
Rym: I point out if they've been monitoring and obviously everyone in the industry Probably in America and in Japan is fully aware of what crunchyroll is doing.
Rym: yet crunchyroll has not been sued at all.
Rym: I just want to note that yeah since 2006 Funimation has provided several letters notifying the site's operators of copyright infringement issues in connection with content that has been made available through the site.
Rym: To date crunchyroll.com has complied with Funimation's demands to remove applicable content.
Rym: now again All this says to me is that people in the u.s I only are able to go after these people if they have the license and No one is going after these people if no one in the u.s.
Rym: Has the license.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if they're got a fansub up there of some anime that you know It's maybe old or is maybe super brand new and no u.s Company has the rights to it then it just let they just let it go.
Scott: the Japanese companies don't do anything about it.
Rym: now it is a question of whether they they don't because they don't want to because it's not worth the effort because they can't because they Can't might be an option.
Rym: that might actually be what's going on.
Rym: But this is gonna get real interesting now.
Rym: the rest of what Funimation said was basically, you know here Here's don't pirate.
Rym: Please don't pirate.
Scott: Yeah, here is something interesting I'm thinking of.
Scott: right if the Japanese anime companies try cuz fansubbing is sort of like, you know Unique to anime and manga right and not so much anything else, you know What if like we took some DS games that were made in Japan and aren't don't have a US release Right, and we took those and we translated them and then distributed them for free all pirate Like would we get away with it?
Scott: Like the fansubbers get away with it?
Rym: You see the thing is I'm pretty sure it's covered under all the same rules.
Rym: I think the only difference there is that if the game Involved licensed properties like but there's the same thing with anime I guess like if I have the license to distribute everything I don't know involving Ichigo from bleach then the US company that has that right could possibly go after the fansubber For distributing.
Rym: but then again, it gets tricky.
Rym: I don't know exactly how it works.
Rym: But I would believe that if this works with fansubs, it'll work with any Foreign copyright that does not have a legal distribution in the United States.
Scott: Yeah It's gonna be interesting.
Scott: Yeah Basically if crunchyroll doesn't get totally fucked and shut down because they could be a lawsuit just you know Sort of being prepared by lawyers takes time.
Scott: It's not like you can just be like lawsuit right now like Phoenix, right?
Scott: You got a you know You gotta have lawyers work on it and they create a case and then they finally go to court and say
Rym: alright but if they don't get shut down and they don't take away all their fansub stuff and I find it interesting that fansubbers a lot of fansubbers seem to not like them.
Rym: But at the same time what the hell can a fansubber do?
Rym: I guess technically they have the right to their fansub, but I don't think any fan.
Scott: I don't think you're gonna be able to claim that you you would have the right the copyright to your subtitle track.
Scott: Yes, I guess maybe that'd be a really tough case Even if you did.
Rym: the problem there is that no fansubber has the money to sue these people even if they are right And also if a fansubber had the money to sue them.
Scott: If fansubber had the money to sue someone with venture capital, they would have the money to license the show and release it.
Rym: You know what.
Rym: when it comes to online distribution, I'll say this real quick I think the best way to deal with all this crap right now is to hire the fansubbers that don't suck and License for distribution digitally in the US via iTunes.
Rym: All the anime as it comes out in Japan like two days after it comes out you should just know.
Scott: I think the.
Scott: I think the really the only way to do it is to team up with Japan and Create animated TV shows that have appeal in both countries.
Scott: I'm just talking about distribution.
Rym: What are you always bringing up?
Rym: the moe crap?
Rym: I'm talking purely about distribution.
Scott: I'm okay.
Rym: one of the biggest complaints that fansub people who watch fansubs and I Agree a little bit is that the shows we want to watch are the new shows because we've seen all the old shows and the New shows are coming out in Japan right now.
Rym: by the time they get licensed.
Rym: There's already newer shows coming out and a lot of people just want to watch the shows right now.
Rym: So they watch Spice and Wolf fansubs and then they're not gonna buy the DVD when Spice and Wolf comes out on DVD?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: whenever I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, but even if it was on iTunes, you wouldn't buy it I might you then why don't you go buy the stuff that's on iTunes now?
Rym: Let's remember then they could shut down all the fansubbers because they have legal distribution rights Yeah, but they can't get the rights because the Japanese companies.
Rym: Yes, it all comes down to the Japanese companies not understanding that they're basically destroying their market in the US by being so afraid of Re-importation because their prices are way too high in Japan to begin with.
Scott: and we're gonna have the same discussion over and over again.
Rym: Yeah, but this whole crunchyroll thing is gonna be interesting.
Rym: But once again, they totally haven't been sued and they're totally getting away with it.
Rym: Yeah, and the best anyone has done has written a strongly worded letter that came to nothing.
Scott: Yeah, basically what this comes down to is the story hasn't changed But crunchyroll has sort of thrown this interesting wrench in the works.
Scott: I think that's going to basically like, you know, pull the sheet away and you know reveal the man behind the curtain.
Rym: This is gonna be really awesome one way or the other I think.
Rym: so Things of the day.
Rym: This is a little old.
Rym: It's from Katsucon but at Katsucon We brought among a lot of other people some of our own personal staff and one of our staffers is actually named katsu And katsu has done kendo panels of.
Rym: I believe his most epic one was the one he ran at Otakon last year Which was if you've ever seen, you know, you know most anime con panels.
Rym: It's people like yelling and screaming like if you search YouTube for like anime match game You'll see a lot of videos of us running the anime match game at various cons and it's pretty much mumble mumble mumble mumble Pokemon and then the crowd just loses their goddamn shit.
Scott: It's really kind of scary.
Rym: But katsu, right?
Rym: He just he does this panel and He didn't even use a microphone so he's talking kind of quietly for a very large room.
Rym: the room was so silent You could cut the tension with a knife and everyone was on the edge of their seats.
Rym: Just like wrapped with attention It was it was all they were all straining to hear.
Rym: No, they were wrapped with attention because even when he was loud everyone was like.
Rym: Of course it also helped that I filtered the questions so all the dumb crap people were asking didn't get up there and only the good questions like How is kendo different from real sword fighting?
Rym: Mmm, but yeah katsu does these awesome things.
Rym: and While he was staffing the video game room one of the other game katsu staffers was like yeah Blah blah blah swords and there there's some talking in it.
Rym: There happened to be some objects made of foam stiff foam that resembled swords.
Rym: So like people are want to do this person challenged katsu to a sword fight.
Scott: Well, that's real smart.
Scott: that's like if I went up to Mike Tyson and said hey you want a box everybody has a plan.
Scott: Hey Kasparov wanna play chess?
Rym: But hey Rym and Scott you want a podcast.
Rym: But Katsu was never one to back down from a challenge and I think we've told the story of when he completely owned those punk kids At Otakon a couple years ago.
Rym: We have some pictures of that somewhere but this video was taken.
Rym: and If you ever want to see the difference between someone who knows how to use a sword and someone who thinks they know how to Use a sword this I don't think he thinks he knows how to use this hard But he did.
Rym: you can always tell the people that don't know how to use swords are Swinging them around and they always have some cool looking stance.
Rym: and meanwhile katsu's just standing there and I As katsu explained to me whenever he played fights against someone who doesn't know what they're doing.
Rym: It's like you're standing there and another person is dancing around in slow motion And you just have to pick where you want to poke them and when you want to poke them and it happens This is mostly epic for the last little duel because it looks whoa the guy finally blocked something.
Rym: then you realize no Katsu sword is on the inside there.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty hard to tell like exactly.
Scott: It's not like the most obvious Demonstration of his incredible abilities and that's the thing about kendo.
Scott: It's like unless you know what you're looking for.
Scott: It doesn't.
Scott: it's not like holy crap.
Scott: He got bashed over the head knees on the ground or holy crap.
Scott: There's a sword right through his guts You know, it's sort of like the sword pokes him somewhere.
Scott: but it's like you look at the speed and the reach and You know the fact that the other guy was like, oh shit, he couldn't do anything about it.
Rym: It's like guy standing there.
Rym: suddenly katsu was hit him with the sword and the guys like what?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: Yeah, but speaking of cons, this is kind of a lame segue, but I want to talk about this a little bit.
Rym: I mentioned before that, you know that summer con seasons coming up and Let me tell you This year has been a bigger season of us doing crap at cons than we've had previously.
Rym: and the content We're probably going to be running at the cons this summer.
Rym: There's going to be a lot of it.
Rym: suffice to say So, uh suffice suffice.
Rym: So Connecticut where I'm working on that make a t-shirt that says suffice to say it looks like a Connecticut.
Rym: We're gonna be running panels pretty much all day Saturday and we're we're working on getting uncle yo to do something awesome because we like uncle yo and Katsu might be running not only a kendo panel, but some kendo workshops.
Rym: We're still working out the details of this but katsu might be running kendo workshops much of the time.
Rym: Oh man, and what we're working on this is by no means set in stone But Connecticut has a better gaming room than most gaming cons have a gaming con.
Scott: That is for sure tabletop gaming room.
Scott: We're not talking about the video game room.
Scott: the video game room in all honesty at least last year was kind of a Most cons.
Rym: gaming rooms are kind of a separate atzuka, especially compared to Katsucon, right?
Rym: But no the tabletop gaming room at Connecticut top-tier top This is not like oh he's coming don't even think this.
Rym: but I have mentioned to Luke Crane that Connecticut is a place He should run burning wheel stuff and all he said back was duly noted.
Rym: Uh-huh, but you never know you never know.
Rym: but even if he is not at a Connecticut someday in the future we are going to try to run some burning wheel demos at Connecticut.
Rym: and we got this cool idea where some board gaming stuff, but it's anime night So I'm not gonna talk about that.
Rym: But uh, our panel lineup is getting kind of long.
Rym: That anime you should see did crazy.
Rym: Well at Katsucon's we're gonna see the most generic panel.
Scott: It's like this what anime you should watch.
Scott: It doesn't get more generic than that people and somehow that's a crazy popular panel.
Rym: but yet when a full third of the people in the room had never seen cowboy bebop and When we get a standing ovation at the end for our history lesson, yeah, I think it went well completely non sequitur Misplaced history lesson.
Rym: Well, but it worked Well, like it actually kind of like doing it in that panel instead of at the late show almost worked better.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I think that it just really had nothing to do with the panel But it works anyway, which proves people go to a panel.
Scott: They're not looking for anything specific.
Scott: They just want you to say anime anime anime.
Rym: I don't think it was a non-sequitur at all because one of the ideas of that panel was that there's a lot of anime You'll never hear of and you've got to find this stuff and watch it.
Scott: Yeah, I guess actually you could shoehorn it in.
Rym: the results of this are not public yet But I can say one thing.
Rym: based on the surveys from Katsucon It seems like the biggest kind of panel people want at anime cons is Anime panels.
Rym: that might sound crazy but if you look at the schedule for any major con very few of the panels and workshops at anime conventions are Actually straight up about anime.
Scott: Yeah, I think back and it's like you see panels like Megaman something cosplay something DDR something this video game series Do a cosplay ball join a ball join a doll something and those are all well and good.
Scott: But it's people apparently want.
Scott: at least people who fill out surveys want anime panels.
Rym: I only that.
Rym: but this was a generic panel.
Rym: and you know, you might balk a generic panel.
Rym: But think about this.
Rym: I bought a generic panel not anymore I don't at all because a lot of people talk to us afterward and said wow I never would have known about those shows.
Rym: and Remember these.
Rym: a lot of great shows are not talked about.
Rym: a lot because all the hardcore anime fans Everyone's seen eska flown a everyone's seen cowboy bebop.
Rym: I won't even deign to discuss it.
Rym: Why would I do a panel about that?
Rym: I have to do a panel about the new stuff for the obscure stuff that no one likes.
Rym: Yeah I mean while you're new.
Rym: All right, I like bleach.
Rym: I'm watching my bleach.
Rym: Oh man, check out one piece.
Rym: It's the same kind of show.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: I really like that.
Rym: How the hell are they gonna find out about cowboy bebop unless someone says all right kid You want to see the good stuff cowboy bebop eska Ava?
Rym: You never heard of these shows.
Rym: check them out.
Rym: So panels like this are important and we're gonna try to run this at Pretty much every time we go to this year and then phase it out because you got to move on.
Rym: But I think this panel is gonna do a lot.
Rym: All right how to run an anime club We do forever gonna go through every single panel.
Scott: We run.
Rym: I want to talk.
Rym: We're gonna do a new kind of panel.
Rym: know your creators.
Rym: we're gonna try to talk about the directors and the character designers and the composers and the people that a lot of anime fans don't pay attention to.
Rym: That they probably should because then it's real easy to find shows you like.
Scott: That's a panel that I think definitely has to be run.
Rym: I definitely I think that panels gonna go over really well.
Rym: Yeah, you know all our anime match game crab katsu's kendo stuff.
Rym: We got a Suffice to say you got to think of something better to say than suffice to say watch out for us at ConnectiCon Otakon anime next.
Scott: are we doing anime next?
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: I'm working on it.
Scott: You're making all like these tentative announcements here.
Scott: I'm not too comfortable with that.
Rym: I Their tentative announcements.
Rym: We're working on doing stuff.
Scott: as long as you make it clear that you know, this is all maybes.
Rym: Yeah, well, we have the official announcement.
Rym: once we have the official announcement But I'm definitely trying to do stuff at ConnectiCon Saturday and Sunday.
Rym: anime next.
Rym: I really only want to do Saturday unless they make me a guest or something.
Rym: I'm not gonna stay all weekend.
Rym: Yeah, and Otakon, you know, we've all we have done stuff at Otakon every year every single Otakon since 2002.
Rym: I doubt we are not going to be doing stuff at Otakon this year.
Scott: That is is highly doubtful.
Rym: and actually I can say this We're already planning next katsu kon game.
Rym: katsu is already working on how to arrange the room For the next katsu kon.
Rym: Oh, yeah, seriously katsu kon my favorite kon to be staff at at least.
Scott: All right, so Tezuka God Synonymous, yes.
Scott: Yes, I think so if you need further proof more obvious evidence Even to the complete layperson on the godlike omnipotent Omniscient qualities of the man that was Osamu Tezuka, but perhaps he you know lives on in some supernatural form.
Scott: Here's an animation.
Scott: You should watch this animation is actually taken off of YouTube and then put right back on YouTube.
Scott: So if the link doesn't work Search free on it for you.
Scott: search YouTube for and you might find it.
Scott: It's called Jumping and by Osamu Tezuka, it's a 1984 animation short film that won some awards.
Scott: I think it's some you know film festivals or whatever and all it is is basically It's a bouncing ball of some sort, but you don't see the ball.
Scott: The camera is sort of from the view of the ball.
Scott: so it's as if you were a ball bouncing.
Scott: and you're bouncing around this world looking at stuff and It's the way this is made in 1984 and look at the kind of animation He was able to produce even in the shitty low-resolution YouTube.
Scott: It comes across so obviously and it's so great because every time the ball comes down to the ground There's like another surprise there waiting for you and oh, oh, it's so beautiful.
Scott: Oh my god, you gotta watch this.
Rym: Yeah Pretty much you should watch everything Osamu Tezuka's ever animated.
Scott: if anything has the name Osamu Tezuka on it and you haven't watched it or read it You should probably do that.
Rym: Some of it's not exactly amazing.
Rym: Yeah, you don't really need to read like ambassador magma, but at the same time it's kind of important.
Rym: I mean It's like when you read like there's a great author and you read their great works.
Rym: You also read they're not so great works to get a lot of perspective on them as artists.
Scott: It's like watching really old bad like Mickey Mouse cartoons.
Scott: they were not all great even though many of them were.
Rym: yeah But I'll admit I'm not terribly entertained by Steamboat Willie.
Scott: Oh Of course I love the one with the musical skeletons even better.
Rym: ah the musicals we watched that recently didn't we?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We can watch it again.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway before we get into the main main bit here There's a little bit of housekeeping.
Rym: Scott after our wonderful relationship with our friends at vertical incorporated vertical Inc We got some stuff to give away and we're having a contest here.
Scott: Yeah, we're actually gonna do real contest.
Scott: We have a real prize.
Scott: We're actually gonna deliver the real prize.
Scott: There's no deadline for the contest.
Scott: Yeah, but basically here's how that how it.
Scott: what's going on.
Scott: We have the three volumes of the goo and saga manga.
Scott: It is a side story to the goo and saga series of novels.
Scott: I'm not gonna get into it, you know that much because I talked about it last week.
Scott: You know, you can go find out.
Scott: but basically the contest works.
Scott: the prize all three volumes of the manga That's the entire manga from beginning to end.
Scott: In order to get them you must email us an essay at least five paragraphs in length with zero Errors as far as punctuation grammar and spelling the end.
Scott: you have to do it properly.
Scott: Do you have any other rules besides that?
Scott: The subject of the essay must be something along the lines of why you deserve the manga or why we should give the manga to You or why you should be the one to win the contest and not anyone else.
Rym: and you know, you might say well What's the deadline of your contest and pretty much?
Rym: We're gonna end it as soon as or near about when we either get enough injuries or an entry is so good.
Rym: We've already got an entry.
Rym: that's pretty good.
Rym: So you better get on this.
Scott: Yeah Pretty much the idea is that all the contests you've run in the past people don't follow the rules so much and Pretty much we end up with no valid entries and just pisses us off.
Scott: So Odds are that anyone who submits to this contest.
Scott: I mean, we've already gotten some invalid entries.
Scott: I mean, come on, even though we talked about how you shouldn't send it an invalid entry.
Scott: We got some.
Rym: however I'll say this the one valid entry that we have.
Scott: I still have to check to see that one's valid.
Rym: It looks valid from looks valid at a cursory glance.
Rym: It also includes some very important things.
Rym: I see the phrase non masturbatory activity, which definitely is always a plus whenever oh, I see bondage fairies.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, so the other thing is that I learned a lesson from one of these submissions so far to the contest.
Scott: Is that someone sent us their submission as an attachment to their email in the form of a doc X file?
Scott: Which is I guess in Microsoft Word 2007.
Rym: I couldn't open that on any computer that I own including my work computer or my Windows Vista computer.
Scott: Yeah, we're Linux people here.
Scott: We can't open that shit.
Scott: you need to send us either just put your essay in your email directly or Send us a file format that we can read like I don't know a text
Rym: file an open format
Scott: an RTF file an open document Format file an HTML file something like that something that anyone can open, you know If it can be open with open office, then you can send it to us.
Scott: That's pretty much how it works.
Scott: All right there.
Scott: any other rules to the contest?
Rym: actually, you know what?
Rym: Yeah, I got nothing.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So yeah, try to enter the contest.
Scott: Maybe you'll win if your entry is valid.
Scott: your odds of winning are crazily high.
Scott: They're like a million times better than your odds of winning the lottery.
Rym: Well so far your odds are pretty much 50% as long as you meet the rules and don't suck because we only have one valid entry.
Rym: Yeah, come on free manga people free manga free pretty good manga from people who have never failed to bring us amazing manga.
Scott: Yeah, can't go wrong.
Rym: Anyway, luckily you might have noticed we kind of Terried a bit and getting to the main bit.
Rym: that's because there's not a lot to say about this But mostly because there's not so much of it yet.
Rym: something must be said Scott.
Rym: What is the title of the comic we're reviewing tonight?
Scott: Well, you know Rym he's not a fan of the underwear perverts.
Rym: I'll say this I there are two depictions of underwear perverts not counting anything by Alan Moore that I've actually enjoyed.
Rym: Also not counting when I was a kid watching the x-men cartoon.
Scott: x-men cartoon cuz.
Rym: that's special and I really like that.
Scott: Didn't you like those x-men movies that I don't like?
Rym: not really.
Rym: No, that's that's all everyone else.
Rym: Okay, I've been different to them.
Rym: I saw that the one with the juggernaut in the theater and you know what that movie wasn't a bore.
Scott: Well people seem to people seem to mostly laud the first one and second one.
Scott: Right, I think I saw the first one and didn't like it.
Scott: I don't think I saw the second one which people say is better whatever.
Rym: But anyway, and I kind of like the spider-man live-action movie, but the first one was good.
Rym: Yeah, it was but in comic book form.
Rym: I didn't see the others pretty much.
Rym: I've liked Superman as depicted in Batman the Dark Knight Returns and I have liked Batman in The Dark Knight Returns and the Watchmen I saw excluded Alan Moore.
Rym: Okay That's that's not really underwear perverts.
Rym: they don't wear underwear so much.
Scott: Yeah, they do anyway.
Scott: not so much It's a superhero book whether you like it or not, but they're not underwear.
Scott: pervert doesn't matter.
Rym: You said underwear pervert.
Rym: It's underwear.
Scott: pervert is superhero.
Scott: This is the same word.
Rym: But the thing is if someone's not in spandex, I'm so much more likely to read it All right.
Scott: Anyway, so here we have a comic and let me it says on the front of this comic The greatest superhero book of all time is finally here.
Scott: this is like the recipe for a comic.
Scott: Rym will not like also on the cover a Spandex or at least very tight glove with some sort of spandex sleeve Punching a guy in the face through a door.
Rym: Ah, see I only like punching in the face if it's robots or Hokuto.
Rym: No, Ken.
Scott: Yeah, so this kind of comic.
Scott: judging by the cover Something Rym probably wouldn't give a second eyeball to and something I wouldn't give a second eyeball to either.
Scott: The reason I bought this comic is because it was incredibly cheap through my discount comic book server.
Rym: Yeah We've learned something bad.
Rym: no matter how awful a comic sounds if it's a nickel or a dime or a quarter hell if it's 50 Cents, it's hard not to buy it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Anyway, the comic the title of the comic is kick - ass.
Scott: That's that's kind of hard to pass up something called kick-ass.
Rym: no, no Scott Is this a?
Rym: is this a comic about someone kicking ass?
Scott: That that is what I was trying to find out when I read it.
Scott: I ordered the first issue with this comic and because that's what I usually do when there's a when there's a one They really regularly discount the first issues of comics.
Scott: that way you'll get the first issue You'll get hooked and you'll buy the rest of the issues that you know.
Scott: Normal discount instead of excessive discount.
Scott: Of course What I do is I buy the first issue.
Scott: if it sucks, I just stop and if it's good I'll buy the trade paperback of the first volume and then maybe the second and third volumes if it goes on.
Scott: So I got this first issue and didn't get any of the further issues.
Scott: But you know and if it's good, I would get the trade.
Scott: and let me tell you I think I'll be getting the first trade.
Scott: now.
Scott: Let me tell you a little bit about this book first.
Scott: The book is called kick-ass.
Scott: It's written by Mark Miller or Millar.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm not sure he's from Scotland Skorin.
Scott: yep It's drawn.
Scott: the art is by John Romita jr Who is a famous Marvel comic book artist the son of John Romita senior who is also a comic book artist and it's published by icon.
Scott: Now when it says icon on the book But if you know comics you'll look inside and it says kick-ass.
Scott: number one copyright 2008 all rights deserved.
Scott: Published monthly by Marvel Publishing Incorporated, but wait, it doesn't say Marvel on the outside It only says icon on the outside.
Scott: That's basically, you know, it's called an imprint like vertigo.
Scott: comics are actually DC comics.
Scott: wild storm Comics are actually DC Comics.
Scott: This is a regular thing in the publishing industry where you will put a different logo a different trademark as the publisher even when it's the same company that is doing the publishing.
Scott: for example when Tokyo pop publishes a Hentai or a yaoi.
Scott: they put some sort of different logo on it.
Scott: They don't say this is Tokyo pop.
Rym: There's two reasons for that.
Rym: in the case Scott is brought up There are many reasons.
Rym: yourself from something you're releasing that will be popular and you will make money off of.
Rym: But you don't want to scare away other people by associating your brand with it.
Scott: Yep The other reason you do it is because if someone reads something, you know What you want people to sort of have some sort of publisher loyalty.
Scott: and there's a lot more publisher loyalty with comic books And there's other things.
Scott: so if someone likes, you know a comic book by Marvel, they like other comics by Marvel.
Scott: They sort of do that like a lot of comic book stores organize the stores by publisher.
Scott: So if you group together like all the vertigo books together, there's a lot of people who are vertigo readers.
Scott: You know, they read vertigo books.
Scott: They don't care, you know who the actual publisher is doesn't matter so much.
Scott: But but the publishing label on there does matter and it's sort of it.
Scott: It sort of means something, you know that because they're basically consciously saying ah This is a book that those kinds of people enjoy.
Scott: So we'll put the same label on it as those other books that people enjoy.
Rym: It's not quite to the level of what goes on in Japan.
Rym: I kind of wish it would get to get there, but that's neither here nor there.
Rym: No now The get into the story of this.
Rym: you're gonna get into the book because I can I can synopsize The story as in what it is about.
Scott: We've only got one issue of a comic book here.
Scott: This is like less than how many pages is this thing?
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: How many pages of content do we have here?
Scott: There are no page numbers.
Scott: That's fantastic.
Rym: But like Batman the Dark Knight Returns is about Batman returning.
Rym: if I was gonna you know Put it together.
Rym: Watchmen is about realistic superheroes in a realistic setting or it's a I'm not gonna get into what it's really about.
Rym: You know.
Rym: X-men is about spandex wearing people hitting other people.
Scott: This is like 23 22.
Scott: It's between 22 and 24 pages of content.
Scott: in this one issue kick-ass is about what if Someone in the real physical modern world where there's so far nothing supernatural has occurred Nothing supernatural whatsoever.
Scott: No powers.
Scott: No magic.
Scott: No nothing.
Scott: It's a world in which everything is normal Just like the real world.
Rym: I mean Watchmen could have been that way except that people were a little larger than life.
Rym: and then doc man had dr Manhattan 20 feet tall make a roommate of radiation.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Manhattan versus dr.
Scott: McNinja.
Scott: who wins dr Manhattan?
Rym: yeah, probably You know in the nerdfight dr.
Rym: Manhattan really can't lose.
Rym: Oh he can lose.
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: Well, maybe Unicron?
Scott: Let's not do this.
Rym: I think dr.
Rym: Manhattan could kick Unicron's ass, but I digress be close Galactus, that'd be interesting.
Scott: Oh Galactus versus dr.
Scott: Manhattan.
Rym: Anyway, we might have to do another Thursday like that.
Scott: We did one a long time ago.
Rym: It could be so long ago that we can do it again But it'd be interesting to do it again and see if we are consistent.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: I don't remember the old one at all.
Scott: You couldn't listening to.
Scott: the old one would be considered cheating.
Rym: Yes, at least for us.
Rym: All right, but anyway, all right.
Rym: so this comic is about what if in the normal real world some high school kid was inspired and actually decided to get a spandex whatever costume and be a superhero and Basically be a vigilante go around and do the things that superheroes would do.
Scott: Yeah, it's um, you know, it's sort of a normal kid.
Scott: He you know, he's a little bit nerdy.
Scott: He has some family problems as is common in comic books, right?
Scott: He you know, he has some school issues right He's a stalker.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically one of those.
Scott: Hey, if you're some high school kid, we're here's a main character to identify with.
Scott: There you go, you know, you'll you'll find they they give a kid so many, you know Small or and sometimes large everyday ish sort of real-world problems that no matter who's reading It will be able to identify with.
Scott: at least one of the problems, you know, it's a typical Underwear pervert comic kind of thing, you know, I don't know.
Scott: I did spider-man does the same kind of thing.
Rym: I didn't terribly identify with.
Scott: you're not a high school kid.
Rym: Oh even in high school I wouldn't have identified with a lonely nerdish stalker kid who wants to be a superhero.
Scott: No, but that's what the comic tries to do.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's going for the target audience here.
Rym: So we're pretty much gonna have to spoil this.
Rym: cuz spoiling that's like what this comic is about is like saying I'm trying to leave a Terminator 2 Arnold's the good guy.
Scott: This is a single issue of a comic book.
Scott: We really if they don't spoil it, there's nothing to say about it.
Scott: So other than this they read it.
Rym: this what this is about is foreshadowed because it begins with someone who looks like a superhero Jumping off of a building and then activating his wings and the wings fail to activate and he dies.
Scott: Yeah, he falls onto a car and dies.
Scott: and then they introduce the kid and they show you all his problems That he has an everyday life and they show him fantasizing about being a superhero.
Scott: and then the second half of the comic book is he actually goes out and tries to do some Superhero and he gets himself like a little cudgel and he puts on some spandex costume practices for a couple of days walking around on Rooftops stalking around in the dark.
Scott: Yeah, he does a little practice actually a little training, right?
Scott: And then he sees some guys, you know making mischief in an alley, you know some graffiti and he's like, all right.
Scott: Here's my chance.
Rym: I'm gonna say this this plays out pretty much aside from the cherry on top of the delicious sundae.
Rym: That is the ass-kicking.
Rym: this plays out Exactly how that would play out in the real world.
Scott: Fucker gets stabbed he gets they guess Lee.
Scott: he goes over and he starts talking trash and you know what?
Scott: Actually talks a good trash like you don't.
Scott: from knowing the kid before it doesn't seem like he's the kind You know, that would be good at the comebacks, but it's like, you know, they're like what the fuck he says Here, let me read it.
Scott: Let me read it.
Rym: I'll point out there's a lot of.
Rym: for some reason all the slurs tend to lean toward homosexual jokes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So here go The the vandal.
Scott: the person for spray paintings sees him and says hey what the fuck you looking at?
Scott: So the kids like oh shit, he says I said what the fuck you looking at asshole I don't know if it was the mask they gave over blah.
Scott: He says three homos making a mess.
Scott: The best part of the vandal is like what the fuck did you say?
Rym: but the thing is.
Rym: then he steps out.
Rym: they see his words like this wetsuit and Their reactions.
Rym: Ah, all right.
Rym: Screw this.
Rym: This guy's just high.
Scott: Yeah, he's like screw this the guy's just high and then he attacks him.
Scott: I'm not high just pissed off with guys like you making this place even more of a shithole.
Rym: and that's a good line.
Rym: That's the kind of line someone a Batman s character would use Someone's.
Scott: he did some good training with the coming up with lines Apparently or it's just you know, good writing which I think is is in abundance in this guy.
Rym: Yeah, but then he attacks the kids and they yeah, that's interesting.
Scott: how you know The.
Scott: these vandals are basically sort of you know, ignoring him like let this crazy guy go whatever, you know He's insulting us and we're sort of getting angry.
Scott: But this guy's crazy.
Scott: What the fuck dude, and then he actually attacks them.
Scott: It's like you don't see even real superheroes with actual powers.
Scott: You don't see them doing.
Scott: that fight goes like spider-man which if there was some vandals he just webbed them up.
Scott: He wouldn't beat them up.
Rym: That man would make them pee themselves Batman.
Scott: Yeah, you just make them pee themselves and then the police would take them away.
Rym: Yeah, but after the element of surprise he pretty much gets beat.
Rym: But then he fights back with a broken bottle and it gets serious.
Rym: so the kids just stab him and run away.
Scott: Yep, the vandal stabs him right in the lung right in the freaking lung.
Scott: It's like oh shit.
Scott: So he starts.
Scott: he's like, ah crap.
Scott: So he starts stumbling away stumbling away.
Rym: Now.
Rym: Here is the cherry on top Cherry on top of this comic.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So first of all, this seems like such an obvious idea, right?
Scott: Write a comic about someone trying to be a superhero in the real world and just play it straight and play it straight And then obviously the result they're gonna get stabbed or shot or something obviously, right?
Scott: So that's exactly what happens.
Scott: and you go.
Scott: Wow, that was such an obvious idea for his story.
Scott: Why didn't anyone do this before?
Scott: I'm sure here it is I'm sure maybe but I've never read it before.
Scott: and you see it right here on the page and you go Wow, that's pretty entertaining right there.
Scott: I can't believe I've never read this before.
Scott: and then Well after he stabbed and he's stumbling away in a bloody stupor.
Rym: His nose is also broken and he's bleeding from a lot of places and he's wearing spandex all over his body.
Scott: then He stumbles into the street and gets smashed by a Benz going real fast.
Scott: and then the Benz does a hit-and-run and he's left lying in the street.
Scott: a Bloody broken stat.
Rym: what's the line?
Rym: What does he say?
Rym: My dad's gonna kill.
Scott: he doesn't say it.
Scott: He thinks it.
Scott: All he says is unt.
Rym: No, you got to read that whole line cuz that line is beautiful.
Scott: What he's what he thinks in his mind while he's lying a bloody mess in the street is two broken legs My spine crushed and dressed like a fucking pervert.
Scott: My dad was going to kill me.
Rym: So, yeah, this might be good, I don't know.
Rym: we'll get the trade.
Rym: we'll review it in more fullness.
Scott: You can probably get it cheap and While we well if you go to the comic store, it's gonna be three dollars.
Rym: Maybe we should have a contest to give this away.
Scott: No, I guess if we get the trade.
Scott: I don't need this issue, right?
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but yeah if you're the kind of person who reads Individual comic books look for kick - ass kick ass.
Scott: and if your comic book store doesn't have it Tell them to order it and then they will order it and then get it to you All right, and then they will know that it's good and then they will order more.
Rym: But I have something much more important that we got to deal with right now.
Rym: All right, brah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.