Rym: It's Thursday January 31st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is geek house.
Rym: tonight We talk about the GeekNights geek house that may someday be.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know I'm kind of impressed as to up how much effort is going into this door fortress succession game that our forum Forumites I guess have started up now.
Scott: Yeah, you know people unlike us are passionate about things.
Rym: Uh Speak for yourself.
Rym: You're the only one who's mad about everything in the world lately man, man, man.
Rym: But seriously that the thing is.
Rym: I think part of it's that One thing that I don't have anymore is a whole bunch of free time.
Rym: And if I was in college like say I was in college right say we're both still back at RIT And we weren't doing GeekNights, but something like GeekNights existed, and we listened to it.
Rym: We were hanging out in those forums.
Rym: We would be doing the same things that these kids are doing now in our forums.
Rym: Yeah pretty much we would have like this dwarf Empire and ah man dwarf Empire.
Scott: I would have multiple dwarf empires.
Rym: God dwarf fortress would have been the end.
Rym: of course you know what tribes - was the end of me?
Rym: I didn't go to class for like a month after that game came out.
Rym: Yeah, you did Barely, I didn't go to class often.
Scott: I would come back from class.
Scott: play play play play play play play.
Scott: go to class come back play play play play play.
Rym: Yeah, and I'd skip all the non-essential classes like labs or Friday classes or Monday classes.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: But yeah, I mean seriously we talked about this on Tuesday, but just in case you Thursday listeners Don't know much about the video games.
Rym: I'm not saying so much you have to play it, but there's a thing called dwarf fortress.
Rym: I recommend you look in the forums And you look at what these people are doing because I feel as though if you're not a gamer Or you're not willing to put forth the time and effort Reading about a game of dwarf fortress is more fun than playing it.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I think that definitely the the the Sort of metagame of having a forum thread and sharing the save files and all that business.
Scott: it definitely Enhances the game itself.
Scott: It's like oh the game on its own is okay But then you add this and it's suddenly super awesome.
Scott: And it's like ah who would have thought that there'd be a game where you could add your own bits to it to make it Awesome?
Rym: oh you mean like role-playing?
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: Anyway, the other thing I have to say also related to the forums Is that get a lot of new people in the forums and now that we've identified a problem that was slowing the?
Rym: Forums down you might have noticed that they're a lot faster lately.
Rym: not gonna say what the problem was But we both feel kind of stupid, but I'm not sure exactly what the problem was.
Scott: oh There was a. that was a different problem.
Rym: Oh, there's another problem.
Rym: Well.
Scott: No they were just you know general thing.
Scott: there were many factors.
Rym: I'll explain it this way This is something that happens commonly on Linux.
Rym: like like.
Rym: you won't happen on your desktop PC But if you're running a Linux server This is going to happen to you at some point, so yeah be warned You'll see this someday.
Rym: You got a demon a little demon and he sits there And he does stuff for your demons a program that stays open all the time and does stuff for you in the background.
Rym: So we got a little demon that handles the database for the forum.
Rym: well for whatever reason there were two demons And one of them was just lazing about and And eating CPU and eating RAM and the other one was doing all the work And we don't know why.
Rym: there were two, but we murdered one of them and everything's finding it.
Rym: well We killed it.
Rym: Yeah with the sort of nines.
Scott: So now I didn't use any nines.
Scott: you didn't have to know because I know what the fuck I'm doing.
Scott: I don't need.
Scott: I don't need to use nine nights of her amateurs.
Rym: I had to use a nine the other day at work.
Rym: I'd I'd weave the amateur.
Rym: there's what happened.
Rym: I had a demon wouldn't die right?
Rym: it was a weird state.
Rym: I killed it in world.
Rym: the real way to kill it with within the program didn't work.
Rym: And I killed didn't work, and it was pretty much not responsive to anything.
Rym: so I kill 90 Amateur.
Rym: what would you have done?
Scott: I would have investigated exactly why it was all hung.
Rym: Oh, I knew exactly why it was hung.
Scott: Why was it hung up?
Rym: it all complicated thing that no one on a Thursday wants to hear about right?
Scott: Well, you know if I if I would figure based on that thing I would figure out a way to Get it to kill with normally there There was no way.
Rym: it was deadlocked in a way that we could reduce the ways.
Scott: You don't know because you are not wise in the ways of writing to see.
Rym: You're not gonna find a way to fix that one.
Rym: Yeah, anyway anyway.
Rym: So in regards to the forums however in also with them being faster There's a lot of people joining the forums lately and as you might have known there is now in auto-humiliate option that mr.
Rym: Period has access to a Mind your grammar mind your spelling to all you new listeners if you're gonna go.
Scott: Yeah, I guess we haven't really talked about this since like the begin early days of the show and you know one person out there You know who got the the virtual dunce cap is probably thinking we're singling them out, but we're not we're not.
Scott: You're like.
Scott: there are like ten other new people who also are unawares and might also receive the dunce cap.
Rym: But plus seriously due to as the dunce cap now you are neither the first nor the worst by any means.
Scott: I don't feel too bad no, but basically we enforce Correct grammar and spelling on the forum for two reasons.
Scott: reason number one We don't want our form to be like the penny arcade forums, or it's just oMG woot poop shit cock right and There's not a lot of ways to do that without you know difficulty.
Scott: the second reason is if you even if you know you're You know good at grammar and spelling if we enforce good grammar and spelling and we sort of give an incentive to have you Spell and grammar correctly when you post something in the forum.
Scott: You're gonna reread it.
Scott: You're gonna proofread it You're gonna think about it And hopefully that will get people to only post things that they really.
Scott: you're not gonna post something unless you really Took time on what you're gonna say.
Scott: you know if it's a serious threat in a non serious threat You can just be like woot what you know.
Rym: I mean you've definitely noticed that mr.
Rym: Period and myself and Scott and waters poison are very so it really depends on what the conversation is.
Rym: It's okay to use lol oMG.
Rym: It's an lol oMG thread.
Rym: It's common sense.
Rym: that's why the only rule on the forum is post intelligently and don't be annoying.
Scott: Yeah, so you know we if you put the time in to spell and grammaticize something correctly that means you probably put in the thought Into what you're actually saying and you'll say something better.
Rym: Yeah, so we always say we haven't said this recently, but join the forums.
Rym: They're awesome They really are.
Rym: there's a lot of people and they're faster now than they were and they're really rocking And you're probably gonna find someone you you like and make some internet friends in there.
Rym: Internet friends great, but you'll also make convention friends as people has been happening more and more.
Rym: But I will warn you if you're going to join the forums If you can't write and you don't understand the English language in some form You're not gonna enjoy yourself there.
Scott: a lot of people who have English as a second language have Improved their English greatly in them forums.
Scott: Yes, but if you don't know English at all, that's gonna be a problem.
Scott: And then why are you listening to this?
Scott: Who did you just hearing people go doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo?
Rym: Maybe maybe they just really like the American accent because I could listen to about an albionic person talk.
Scott: But there's being a language, you know, mostly but it depends mostly.
Rym: Oh Plus I can listen to Russian talking pretty much forever and I have no idea what they're saying.
Rym: I'm sorry Pockner ease Pockner ease Okay.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know what that Russia is.
Scott: Do you ever really made up?
Scott: were ever real news over there?
Rym: All right, I got a real news.
Rym: now I want to talk about the Democratic presidential primaries, but Scott doesn't care about politics and the discussion would have been.
Rym: Here's the discussion Rym.
Rym: Oh my god, blah blah blah Barack.
Rym: Oh my god, Florida, Michigan blah Scott It doesn't matter.
Scott: There's nothing you can do about it.
Scott: It's no different than this.
Rym: I can I've donated money.
Rym: I'm gonna vote.
Rym: I'm interested this history unfolding.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, I know different than why.
Rym: anyway Yes, it is anyway.
Rym: I'm going to talk about an issue related to politics and related to the elections that Will not involve the names of any candidates.
Rym: So Scott won't zone out into my land.
Scott: We'll see what this is.
Rym: And also I love the ACLU right the American Civil Liberties Union.
Scott: They're mostly good.
Rym: I'm a member.
Rym: I donate money to them on a semi-regular basis.
Rym: However, they do not always do the smart thing.
Scott: No Not always Now the product.
Rym: but the thing is I agree with them no matter what in the end because they always stand up for people's rights Even if those rights may be bad or stupid.
Scott: they always kind of well see when they stand up for like You know the free speech rights of like a KKK person.
Scott: I'm like, okay, but sometimes they do stuff where it's like, okay No, actually that shouldn't be a right and it's not.
Scott: what are you doing?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but they they generally they Do more good than harm.
Scott: Yes, they do.
Scott: They do more good than than the bad.
Scott: I'm more more times nine times out of ten.
Scott: when I see an ACLU story It's like yeah and one times out of ten.
Scott: It's like oh what the fuck.
Rym: but here's the.
Rym: here's the deal in Ohio, Ohio.
Rym: They use touchscreens to vote but you know how voting machines are awful.
Rym: We've talked about that.
Rym: I think you know, yep Well, Ohio is thinking.
Rym: All right, we're gonna move back to paper ballots that are perfectly verifiable.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: As long as paper ballot is properly designed and counted.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's one of those optical scan sheets.
Rym: It looks like all right, as long as it works the ACLU says hey, you can't do that Why not?
Rym: the ACLU is pointed out that with the touch screens if you make an error?
Rym: Voting as in you do try to vote for a candidate.
Rym: that doesn't work.
Rym: or you like you mess up the ballot in some way Like you voted for four people.
Rym: It won't let you do it.
Rym: I didn't let you change it and it'll.
Rym: it'll verify that.
Rym: what you have done is a valid voting choice Mm-hmm and with the paper ballot you can't do that.
Rym: You've lost the rights and as far as the ACLU is concerned to get verification that your vote will be counted and as a result They're saying that you have to be able to verify the legitimacy of your vote before and during while you're casting.
Scott: So, how about you fill out your scan Tron sheet?
Scott: They run it through the machine.
Scott: then they give you a receipt.
Rym: I Have a much better Point to carbon copy.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: No.
Rym: All right, if you a human being are unable to read the instructions on a voting machine or a Voting piece of paper and you vote incorrectly.
Rym: I'm of the mind that your vote shouldn't count.
Scott: Yeah, it is a case to be made for that.
Scott: But there's also a case to be made like someone's a citizen.
Scott: They're sentient.
Scott: Yes, and you know, they should be able to vote even if they have Their illiterate see.
Rym: now they have the right to vote.
Rym: The thing is they have to follow the instructions.
Scott: Yeah, but what if a literate person goes to vote in the kind of voting machine we use with the clickers and the lever?
Rym: They probably shouldn't be voting.
Rym: That's what I'll say.
Scott: Oh, but they they have the right to vote.
Scott: So what what do you do for that?
Scott: They can't use the machine, you know.
Scott: What should they be able to just tell someone who they want to vote for and then that person should do the workings or no?
Rym: Because your vote has to be confidential.
Scott: Well, you know, there's got to be some Sun to do.
Scott: We already determined that having a literacy test for voting was unconstitutional.
Rym: What?
Rym: I kind of disagree with that, but I agree with how it was done.
Scott: Yes, because originally they had a literacy test for voting to keep black people from voting.
Scott: That was the original intention.
Rym: But and that was perhaps so the fact that the courts overturned that and said no literacy test for voting was a great thing.
Rym: back.
Rym: Then yeah, I think we're past that.
Rym: Oh, here's the deal.
Rym: I am of the mind.
Scott: I don't think we're past that.
Scott: I think that you know in many places people would use that literacy if we had a legitimate literacy test.
Scott: I think in a lot of places be misused for discrimination against various groups.
Rym: And well, that's why instead of having a test you just their instructions for voting.
Rym: And if you need assistance you can ask for assistance.
Rym: but people have the right to vote and the government will provide you a means to vote if you are unable to or choose not To take advantage of the thing they have given you then you can't.
Scott: well I guess you can go up to the person right with a sheet and say You know if I want to vote.
Scott: if they'll say if you want to vote for a person a check in this box.
Scott: If you want to vote for person B check in this.
Rym: but here this isn't even like.
Scott: I could have someone tell you the instructions.
Scott: You know the election worker tell you exactly what to do.
Rym: plus.
Rym: I mean look at this.
Rym: it alright.
Rym: the the argument isn't even.
Rym: It's like.
Rym: alright.
Rym: someone say they're literate and they're just dumb and they just fill out the ballot completely wrong.
Rym: Alright, what should we do with that?
Rym: Uh shouldn't count.
Rym: I Want how much verification do we have to do?
Rym: what if someone goes to the electronic voting booth?
Rym: I just mash his buttons until they break it and then well, but I mean here what if a?
Scott: What if I go in to vote?
Scott: I'm not gonna you know stupidly fill it out wrong, but I have no confirmation.
Scott: So what it?
Scott: you know I I vote and I vote for person a you don't get confirmation anyway And then it ends up getting.
Scott: oh I can see the little red check next to the name on the thing and you can see the little check on the piece of Paper, but what if it actually ends up getting counted for person B?
Scott: Cuz it's something I have.
Rym: no This is only covering mistakes that you make not mistakes that the ballot system makes.
Rym: System can screw up in any case.
Rym: This is very specifically.
Rym: They're saying that you have the right to Have your ballot corrected by someone or have an ability to have the ballot corrected before you send it off.
Rym: now It doesn't matter the courts The ACO is gonna get creamed because as was pointed out by the Ohio Board of Elections Absentee ballots have the same problem, and they're not unconstitutional.
Scott: Dynafire yeah, yeah, I don't think they're gonna win win that there.
Scott: But there there are issues here that need to be dealt with.
Scott: I really think we just need some sort of Making a voting machine is so stupidly easy if they just let an intelligent person do it.
Scott: And we should really have some sort of state worldwide standard voting machine that could be configured for any sort of election.
Scott: That would be perfect and simple and it would work and that could be done trivially.
Rym: and the fact that it hasn't been really bothers Me.
Scott: but so we should start a company that does that it just.
Scott: there's a big difficulty in Nonprofit company that's worldwide and we administer elections in any country with our Guaranteed voting machines guaranteed everything.
Rym: I wouldn't be my I wouldn't mind at all and all software be open source.
Rym: Maybe the only test to vote was there's a there's a little maze and you have to make it through the maze and somewhere in The maze is the voting machine That we'd have mice voting that we don't want that it's better than the cut anyway, yeah, okay, wait.
Scott: So I like how you're paying all attention to selection and then you just insult all the people voting and then you claim that All the people voting.
Rym: I insulted the people who don't understand how to vote and and do it wrong And then get mad when their ballot doesn't anyway anyway, so Audible calm right if you don't know audible calm is a website where you can.
Scott: it's also.
Scott: It's a service and if you want audio books in digital format to listen to on your iPod or other device or your computer They sell them to you, and they give you one free book if you sign up.
Scott: You know whatever.
Scott: you get one free book before you sign up.
Scott: So it's not too bad, and there are a lot of really long books.
Scott: You can get your free books worth.
Scott: They have DRM though, which is part of the reason I never you know considered signing up for them.
Scott: because you know if I'm paying for an audiobook right you know some reasonable price.
Scott: I didn't actually know what the pricing was until today, but I'll get to that.
Scott: You know if I'm paying for an audiobook I'd like to you know maybe give Rym that audiobook or give it to.
Scott: you know some.
Scott: I mean if I buy a book at The bookstore you know from Amazon or whatever I can give it to Rym to read.
Scott: you know why should we you know if there's An audiobook why should we be paying for it two or three times just for multiple people?
Scott: so that DRM?
Scott: Made me consider.
Scott: You know never actually consider audible seriously.
Scott: now.
Scott: Today Amazon announced they're buying audible, which makes a lot of sense because Amazon's really busting out with their mp3 store That's selling non DRM music that from like almost every major label pretty much out there I might and depending on their prices.
Scott: I might even consider buying some of that action, but You know what happened today is Amazon bought audible and since Amazon's kicking out the DRM I said hey Maybe audible will lose the DRM and then I can go and sign up for audible and get mad audiobooks to supplement my podcast.
Scott: right so I go to audible.com.
Scott: right and For the first time ever I actually looked at Audibles pricing scheme and After I look at it.
Scott: I say to myself Even if this didn't have DRM who and they're you know outside of it a ludicrously rich person Who in their right fucking mind would ever sign up for audible?
Scott: all right check out the four different plans?
Scott: You can have you ready.
Scott: plan number one For seven dollars and fifty cents a month for a few months for the first three months But after the first three months is fifteen dollars a month well 1495 right.
Scott: you get one Audiobook a month one book.
Rym: It's not that bad.
Rym: It takes a while to listen to an audiobook.
Rym: You know that they are yeah, but I mean Liz.
Scott: 750 for the first three books and then $15 for every other book.
Scott: $15 for a book for $15.
Scott: I can get like three or four paperback books.
Rym: I think you're forgetting.
Rym: There's as far as I'm concerned There is only one use for audiobooks, and that is really well.
Rym: I guess the subway and all that sort of thing could cover.
Scott: basically It's no I see more people who I see about equal numbers of people with paper books and headphones in the subway And I don't think the headphone.
Rym: people are all listening to audiobooks, but basically if I'm driving somewhere I used to drive to work I used to drive about an hour to work every time.
Rym: I you know commuted an hour there an hour back.
Rym: So I can't read while I'm driving.
Rym: well, I shouldn't read while I'm driving.
Rym: at least I can.
Rym: not a good idea.
Rym: So uh audiobooks are totally worth that because how else am I gonna read books?
Scott: Okay, okay?
Scott: How much is an audiobook on CD?
Rym: a similar amount of money?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: yeah, I've seen him pretty cheap.
Rym: Yeah, if you get look get him like on sale way after the fact discount.
Rym: even then you don't find him like that.
Scott: usually you Know.
Scott: plus if I'm going on a trip There's enough like podcast fiction that I can get for free.
Scott: I could just load up on like 10 escape pods for nothing.
Scott: But if you were if you were commuting an hour each way every day You know when I was commuting an hour each way every day podcast It's pretty much filled up the ride both ways.
Rym: see mine would but I hate almost all podcasts.
Scott: Yeah, all right, but anyway You can also pay 150 a year for 12 $23 a month for two a month and $230 a year for two audiobooks a month.
Scott: If I'm paying $230 a year I expect unlimited audiobooks.
Scott: pretty much You should be able to give me as many, but it doesn't cost them any more money to give me more books.
Scott: They're all digital files.
Scott: Yeah, whatever trivial amount of bandwidth Audible you know as even if you really like audiobooks I consider this to be a horrendous ripoff in terms of how much audiobooks cost outside of audible.
Scott: It doesn't matter at this price.
Scott: They're not worth it for any audiobook.
Scott: Screw audible.
Scott: I'm not signing up.
Scott: unless the price goes way down I'd be willing to pay like two dollars for a single audiobook.
Rym: see I do.
Rym: I Understand why they have the DRM though just because as we were saying all right if audible didn't have DRM And I got it I'd probably lend every audiobook I ever got to all my friends as I do with DVDs currently.
Scott: yeah, so what's the problem with that?
Scott: I bought it.
Rym: well see that's the problem with DRM.
Rym: But yeah as then I'm saying I understand why they do it because then they probably wouldn't be profitable otherwise.
Scott: And I don't think I don't see how you cannot profit with prices like this and a seemingly large customer base.
Scott: It seems like a lot of people do sign up for this.
Scott: so oh Well yeah audible.com.
Scott: out of Scott's consideration.
Rym: I don't think the price is.
Rym: I mean I'll agree I think it's a little overpriced.
Rym: I don't think it's nearly as bad as you're making it out.
Scott: It's pretty bad as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: some years ago We were in Wildwood, New Jersey And we for various reasons decided to deep fry some pizza.
Rym: You can see the pictures of that in the forum.
Rym: it tasted like a hot pocket And that's really all that needs to be said.
Rym: yep, so uh We've ever since then we've always had an interest in.
Rym: I don't know maybe the word is awful perhaps horrible Dangerous food.
Scott: well, but the first sort of encounter I had with the eating strange food for sport was way back in high school.
Scott: I was watching like some public access TV.
Rym: Oh, that's always a good idea.
Scott: And this guy basically this is his show is he was sitting there with a telephone taking stupid calls right and He had this.
Scott: his friend at the grocery store right apparently found this soup and the package said There was a picture of a chicken on it right like a you know a silhouette of like a chicken icon Right like sort of like chicken at the VNC, and it said cock flavored soup mix.
Scott: So they made it and then he drank it out of a mug and he said that's good cock.
Rym: That was possibly the most anticlimactic and lame story I've ever heard.
Scott: that was that was sort of the point of the story.
Rym: But seriously we uh It's a tradition.
Rym: I guess but not really.
Rym: I just I find horrible food like that hilarious and cock flavored soup mix.
Rym: I discovered An item an item that frightens me a little bit from the trekking miles.
Rym: Is a cheeseburger a cheeseburger that comes in a can?
Rym: now you might say oh well Is it like a patty in a can?
Scott: yeah?
Scott: I assumed it was a patty in a can and you just heat up the patty and then put it on some bread.
Rym: it is an entire cheeseburger with bun and cheese and sesame seeds and Britain meat Can and in the can is a fully intact already cooked cheeseburger with so it's bread cheese and meat and Condiments and pickles.
Scott: so there's ketchup and pickles and mustard and yes sesame seeds.
Rym: you boil the can in water for like 10 minutes to heat it up, and you open the can and Greeting you in.
Rym: the can is the top of a cheeseburger.
Scott: How do you get it out?
Rym: you just turn the can upside down.
Scott: the hot boiling hot can.
Rym: it cools down pretty quick is it?
Scott: boiling hot Yeah, I guess she is kinda hot.
Scott: Radisco Give to Radisco No coffee for Radisco.
Rym: Radisco having good dream.
Rym: But uh This looks all levels of awful And I think the worst comes up with who can't?
Rym: someone came up with this.
Rym: Oh, they also someone eats it actually actually they.
Rym: they also sell powdered wine.
Rym: now the reason for all this Powdered wine.
Scott: that could be a way to get a lot of wine in a small amount of space.
Scott: or you have a lot of More powder.
Scott: you like double the powder per water to get more drunk.
Rym: that would that's port basically, but anyway the the reason this looks so awful is partly because All the grease in the burger and all this just kind of like oozes down into the bottom half of the bun.
Scott: Just throw out the bun part and eat.
Scott: put the patty on a new bread.
Rym: But the reason this thing exists is it actually kind of a good idea.
Rym: It's something you bring camping.
Rym: It's like a camping food.
Scott: if I'm camping.
Scott: I'll just bring some wieners and put them on sticks and stick them in a fire depends.
Rym: I mean if you're hiking you don't you're not gonna have refrigeration or anything.
Rym: you got to bring preserved food And this is something that's really convenient and quick.
Rym: And I will admit and the guy said it didn't make him sick And it wasn't the worst thing in the world he'd eaten.
Scott: so It can't be worse than McDonald's.
Rym: so if I was in the middle of nowhere And I'd been like when I went hiking in the Adirondacks if I had had one of these I probably eaten it raw right then and there.
Rym: And if I would have been the best thing I'd ever eaten Trail mix man.
Scott: There's a reason they invented.
Rym: Yeah, you know what.
Rym: I'd already eaten all my trail mix And I'd eaten all the power bars.
Rym: I brought and I drunk all my water.
Rym: Well, I still had like eight miles to go.
Scott: you're supposed to bring it up provisions for your entire distance.
Scott: You're supposed to figure that out beforehand.
Scott: Oh, yeah, bring it up provisions.
Scott: That's your own fault.
Rym: I didn't bring it up provisions by far.
Scott: Yeah, all right, but The pictures on this thing of the day are kind of epic right so way back Back in the day right there was a. it was like some guy made like the first or one of the first Google Maps mashups before.
Scott: there was like a Google API.
Scott: even it was and what it did is it showed like the crime in Chicago.
Scott: I think the website's still up somewhere right?
Rym: Oh, yeah Well, I think I remember that being cool cuz you look and there were some street corners like wow what's going on there right?
Scott: Well that guy has a new site and the site It's could be a lot better of a website mostly because it doesn't have Google any sort of map Integration.
Scott: and if it had some app integration be the best site ever.
Scott: But regardless of its lack of map integration This information available on this site is so awesome and so useful that is totally worth it.
Scott: now The website is called every block.
Scott: calm right and right now.
Scott: He's covering Chicago New York and San Francisco.
Scott: right.
Rym: is it what's on every block.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not exactly.
Scott: It's not everything of what's on every block right.
Scott: it is specific information of what's on every block.
Rym: pick up pick a block all right 59th Street and 7th Avenue the Northwest.
Scott: That's the first problem with this website.
Scott: right is right.
Scott: I can go to 59th Street.
Scott: Okay, I click on 59th Street, and now it wants to know like the numbers so we can do like you know 1 through 99 West odd a hundred through 198 West.
Rym: I don't think I've known the address of a place in New York City ever.
Scott: I know that's.
Scott: the one problem with this website is if it had a map it would be super useful.
Scott: now Once you actually find the address you're looking for right it gives you a shit ton of useful information.
Scott: Here's the useful information you get ready recent building permits.
Scott: recent building violations issued.
Scott: Recent violent building violations resolved.
Scott: not too exciting yet, right?
Scott: Business reviews crime reports graffiti cleaned graffiti pending cleanup.
Scott: landmark building permits.
Scott: liquor licenses lost and found postings Misconnections news articles photos and the most interesting of all the thing that makes this website thing of the day worthy.
Scott: restaurant inspection results that are recent.
Scott: Huh, let's see the cocoa gourmet restaurant was inspected and got 15 violation points and two violations cited.
Rym: That's not that bad.
Scott: No.
Rym: It's not that bad, but I just remember the one day I was in the city with Emily.
Rym: I think and we're we saw a call Steve Austin cream room.
Rym: We're like oh, man You know get some ice cream after we go do this.
Rym: other thing we came back And it was closed with a health violation warning on the door.
Scott: Yeah Thing is you can't search for like the name of a business.
Scott: you got to go to the street And the streets are arranged in the way I just described.
Scott: so you really have to know the the address of where you're at or like the zip code or something.
Rym: Set it up where I could use my GPS Google Maps.
Rym: I got going on my blackberry now And it would just give me the information about the block right next to me or the two blocks right next to you.
Scott: another interesting thing about this website right is If you go to like the type like if I go to the restaurant inspections page for the whole city There's like this little graph going on.
Scott: you can see the graph goes up And it goes down on the weekends when no one's inspecting.
Scott: right, but let's see so far they have 1,830 restaurant inspections in the last 30 days.
Scott: someone's doing their job.
Scott: Let's see by neighborhood.
Scott: most of the most of the inspections are in Midtown Most of them are in Manhattan then Brooklyn and then Queens and the Bronx are way down there.
Scott: Oh, we got it's by zip code.
Scott: How many there are okay by violation?
Scott: 7,873 violations of non-food contact surface improperly constructed.
Scott: Five thousand eight hundred and thirty five violations of not vermin proof.
Scott: four thousand seven hundred and sixty six violations of mice.
Scott: Three thousand nine hundred and sixty flying insects and a partridge.
Scott: Three thousand three eighty six cold gun.
Rym: I apologize for that.
Rym: that was like one of those radio guy jokes I or like a letter.
Rym: I'm sorry that was dumb.
Scott: Yeah about three thousand cold food held above 41 degrees Fahrenheit.
Rym: That's the danger zone.
Scott: yeah food not protected from contamination.
Scott: signs not posted.
Scott: improper plumbing.
Scott: hot food not held.
Rym: We get the idea improper plumbing.
Rym: we get the idea expired milk rats.
Rym: We had some expired milk.
Scott: use of vendor lacking a permit.
Scott: improper sewage disposal.
Rym: so speaking of improper sewage disposal.
Scott: proper cooking of poultry.
Rym: Scott and I and And pretty much the rest of the crew here in Beacon are thinking about buying a house.
Scott: Yeah, well, we'll see exactly how it's gonna work out, but we've been renting this place.
Scott: It's a good place.
Scott: it's a good deal, but we have money and Were there.
Scott: a few things where we're not fully satisfied.
Scott: I don't think they can be rectified without moving to a real house that we own now.
Rym: It would be fun to do like fantasy geek house like.
Rym: well We would have the Tezuka reading room in the the land gaming room in the atrium and the planet Arion.
Rym: But now the gymnasium The forum.
Rym: we need a forum the the Olympic pool.
Rym: But now we're gonna talk about is something much more professional Marco Polo court bowling alley bowling at Malta Largest arcade roller coaster.
Rym: Oh don't forget the cart track.
Rym: I think the most important thing is the formula one track is the ice hockey arena that doubles as an ice Paintball arena.
Scott: Zamboni to Zambonis.
Rym: Oh, we'd have a Zamboni racetrack anyway.
Scott: But now now Well, hey, I just thought of something.
Scott: You know, there's speed skating where you see it in the circle real fast Zamboni racing.
Scott: No, no, no, no.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Why don't they have Grand Prix speed skating?
Scott: We have to turn left and right on like a Grand Prix track.
Rym: That'd be really cool.
Scott: I know right Why the fuck is not anyone made that's a legitimate sport.
Rym: That was a really interesting grammatical structure.
Scott: You just used why it's a legitimate sport.
Scott: No, no.
Rym: No, why is that not?
Scott: Why is it not?
Rym: I like that.
Rym: That was good.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Anyway, I don't know why that's not.
Rym: it should be because I like those speed skates a lot with the Clacking going on in the back.
Scott: Yeah, and they go whoosh whoosh whoosh and they're all wearing like nothing.
Scott: Okay Uh-huh.
Rym: That's what you focus on.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, so Be a little more realistic, but I guess I just want to talk about because it seems like in general geeks Think about their lives a lot.
Rym: geeks and nerds one thing we have in common is that We look at things in our lives and we think like like, you know The classic joke they don't go like.
Rym: a nerd is a system for everything like that.
Rym: Nerd is a system for eating pancakes and stuff like that.
Rym: But it's more than you think about things in your life and you think how can I make these things better?
Rym: heck things we change.
Scott: Yes, other people seem to you know, everyone is subject to doing most things by habit or by you know automatic miss, you know and we could do all show about that whole stuff, but you know it seems like geeks and nerds tend to do.
Scott: let things with a little bit more or you know of Thinking put into them and and then they build a habit as opposed to just having a habit now arbitrarily more often
Rym: and you know We're the more we look at houseplants and think about buying a house the more I realize
Scott: plants
Rym: plans
Scott: burns.
Rym: I want some houseplants to the fern big old fern.
Rym: Okay, but The more I think about it the more I realize very obvious changes that could I could make to a house I lived in to make it so much nicer to live in that it would just be like you would be worth almost any cost.
Scott: Well right now there are really only three things I need, you know above and beyond what we already have in this house to be sort of satisfied and not really desiring anymore with a. You know, it's like there are three things I super want and everything else is sort of like it would be nice.
Scott: the three things I super want that I don't have Are a dishwasher.
Scott: Yep a dryer yeah, and either a garage or basement one or the other.
Rym: I prefer a basement because I don't.
Rym: I Really got spoiled as a kid because I've always had a garage.
Rym: I always kept my car in the garage never had a garage never had to deal with like snow and ice on my car Anything stupid like that.
Rym: I was always parked indoors never mattered.
Rym: Then I got to college and I learned for the first time that oh in Rochester It'll snow point five inches and then turn into ice every single day from November until May.
Rym: Yep And I got used to that.
Rym: but I don't live in Rochester anymore.
Rym: I don't care I don't even use my car that much so I don't need the garage.
Rym: I know a shed would be fine.
Scott: Yeah, I mostly need a place to store all this kind of shit that you know Normally be stored in garage or base because right now we're storing it like under the stairs.
Scott: It's not so good like the air conditioners.
Rym: We'll get to that.
Scott: We're like, yeah, like air conditioners in the winter.
Scott: Where do you put them?
Scott: like the bikes a box full of tools?
Rym: Yeah, GeekNights bin full of stuff that we only use at conventions and don't need any other time ever.
Scott: Yeah, this all the stuff that normal people put in garages and basements.
Scott: We have nowhere to put it and you know We have a washing machine and no dryer.
Scott: a dryer would save me from having to go to the laundromat to dry my clothes after I watched them in the house.
Scott: So that would be a huge, you know improvement in my life.
Scott: I'd save all that time and effort.
Scott: I'd be able to do laundry more often have less clothes Etc also having a better more efficient washer would count.
Scott: Yeah something I was better at washing.
Scott: Also, my clothes be cleaner smell nicer use less water, I guess and a dishwasher.
Scott: I spent a lot of time cleaning dishes and running out of dishes.
Scott: a dishwasher would make really improve our lives I think more than any other device in the known universe.
Rym: yep, now the basement counts for a lot too because one there are two things two things that are very important to me in my Life that I don't get to do as much as I would like.
Rym: one is dance dance revolution and the other is air hockey.
Rym: Now we can't have an air hockey table in this house because there's no room for her.
Rym: We could put it in the middle of the living room and it would fit.
Rym: In fact, if we put it over by the back door, it wouldn't even really be in the way.
Scott: It would probably fall through the floor into the basement because it's so heavy.
Rym: The problem is the same problem we have with DDR the floor would collapse.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I'm sure in a better house or I mean our house isn't bad.
Scott: But you know in a high a super high quality house with awesome floors at the floor could support an air hockey table.
Scott: But I mean, you don't put a pool tape.
Scott: everyone puts pool table in their basement.
Scott: You can't have a giant stone putting weight on a wooden floor, you know, you no matter how sturdy the floor is It just you don't do that.
Rym: It's goes the general the front row crew gathers at our house.
Rym: pretty much This is where everyone always gathers.
Rym: We have the biggest house and we're kind of central to everyone like beacon to the center of the front row crew right now.
Rym: Yeah, except for those outliers out in tejas, whatever Tejas tejas.
Rym: Yeah, but Whenever everyone comes over we basically have one big living room and a kitchen and that's it downstairs.
Rym: So as a result, we kind of have this blob of people and if we had another room that we could kind of entertain it.
Rym: I'm thinking a finished basement because I've always had finished basements.
Rym: finished basements like the best thing ever.
Rym: you have a wet bar down there You have the pool table in the air hockey table and then a big open space with some like cheapo couches and a TV And you can just chill and play games down there.
Scott: Yep Dungeons and dragons in the basement was a tradition in my life up until I went to college and then run to dragons no longer In the basement, we sort of made it not the same.
Rym: Yeah, I mean even now it really sucks to set up to play.
Rym: well burning wheel now But you know role-playing because we got to get like all these different tables.
Scott: Yeah, I ordered a burning empires and burning sand.
Scott: So now I go.
Scott: you ordered dune and I'm soon going to be the proud owner of every Loot crane game so far.
Rym: Yeah, if you haven't listened to GeekNights much just there's a thing called burning wheel.
Rym: Just go buy the books.
Rym: Don't even think about what it is.
Rym: Just buy them.
Rym: All right, you'll find out.
Rym: Yeah soon enough read them.
Rym: But yeah a finished basement would make.
Rym: because you know we was complain about the Visigoths wrecking our house.
Rym: The main reason they wreck our house is because there's like 15 people and There's nowhere for them to put their stuff and they're all in the same room.
Scott: Yeah, they're all crowded in and if you had one if you had a basement we can stuff them all in the basement.
Scott: Who cares?
Scott: the basement gets messed up.
Scott: That's what basements for.
Rym: Yeah, and there were.
Scott: oh, no Someone spilled something on the concrete floor.
Scott: Whatever will we do?
Scott: I think we'd tile it if we're gonna finish it I know but you see that you see my point.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, maybe a big throw rug or something.
Rym: Yeah, but just having it seemed because I've noticed that the primary cause of messes in my life is simply that it's like if I Had more space to put things away in an organized and
Scott: the same amount of the same amount of mess would look less messy Because it would be spread out Whole bunch of cups piled up on top of each other.
Scott: There'd be a cup here and a cup a few feet away and a cup a few feet away.
Rym: Well, the cups would be solved by a dishwasher.
Scott: I know I know I know But uh, yeah basement.
Rym: But then we started thinking about all the things that you could do if you owned your own house.
Rym: That would make your life great, especially for a geek and I think the biggest one.
Rym: I was inspired upon reading up.
Rym: Well Horatio and all that gave it to me, but I was really inspired when reading up the terror Because I realized you want a boat in ships, right?
Rym: Those old ships.
Rym: the tables were mounted in the ceiling on ropes and you lowered them When you needed them and you put them back in the ceiling when you weren't using them.
Rym: So in the basement of our house, what if we just have some gigantic table in the ceiling?
Scott: It's not it's not a bad idea.
Scott: I've seen guys who have model railroads or you know slot car racing sets and they have you know A system that lowers the table from the ceiling and that you have a remote control.
Rym: you hit a button table In fact, the coolest.
Rym: it's pretty slick.
Scott: I mean you could have it right above the air hockey table, too.
Scott: So like you're playing air hockey then you step back you lower down this piece of wood from the ceiling You know on top of the air hockey table and then everyone pulls chairs up around it and poop table.
Scott: You didn't lose any space in your house.
Scott: so you can pay for less square footage of house yet have utility of basically a whole extra room because one room turns into another room sort of Like transformer.
Scott: so no sort of like a tavern turning into a casino Swinging his pet shop in.
Rym: But I also the coolest one ever saw was a model railroad and it inspired.
Rym: this.
Rym: also inspired me was that the guy would stand In the middle and hit a button and the sections would all come down around him to where he was now surrounded by table.
Scott: I don't think that's so useful for us.
Rym: Yes, it is.
Rym: The dungeon master is sitting in the middle.
Scott: You could it's a little corny, but I guess it's possible But it doesn't work if you want to do it on top of the air hockey table unless they're gonna sit on the air hockey table.
Rym: Yeah Well, if you put in the middle of the room the way they do it is.
Rym: he actually had a section that filled in the center where he could be and He had if he had different buttons different sections came down.
Scott: So it's getting a little too complicated.
Scott: No idea and principle is good, but I also looked into the systems and people.
Rym: there's already pre-made systems that do this with stepper motors.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, you just buy one and you know mounted on the ceiling which is you know I guess you screws into the concrete there and then you're good to go.
Rym: Yeah Now I'm also think this isn't really a geeky thing, but I definitely I want a foyer or a Foyer as it may be.
Scott: I don't really need the foyer so much.
Rym: Yes you do.
Rym: You leave your shoes all over the house.
Scott: You're the only one who gives a shit about where the shoes are.
Scott: your shoes you take them off and you put.
Scott: wherever you take Them off is where they are.
Rym: No you put them in a closet or something.
Rym: get them out of the way.
Scott: Don't just leave them when I need them again.
Scott: I got to go in the stupid closet.
Scott: It's right there.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: You're some sort of ostracothic barbarian.
Scott: I do not care about the foyer Plus.
Rym: there is Scott.
Rym: you I think you for underestimate the power of the foyer.
Rym: Yeah Forget your shoes.
Rym: when the visigoths come there's always a pile of crap in the hallway because they all do.
Rym: they all bring coats and Things and bags and crap.
Rym: you leave all those in the fire all the shoes all the crap stays there all the dirt that stays in there.
Rym: also When it's woman out and and and it's cold You know it's like an airlock.
Rym: You open the front door people take care of all the coats and crap and that door gets closed.
Rym: And then they open the door to the house, and there is never that moment of shut the door Pete.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Shut the door god damn it Pete.
Rym: Why are still open?
Scott: that is that.
Scott: that is a good point You know to make that the advantage of the foyer.
Scott: there are many advantages there are but that's such a small thing.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's a huge thing if you keep you think that that's huge.
Scott: I mean it's huge.
Scott: Washing dishes is huge.
Scott: It's huge if you're not having a cool breeze once in a while is not huge.
Rym: It's huge if you're not some sort of shoe leaving barbarian.
Rym: a
Scott: foyer I'm not gonna say you know I would purposefully avoid getting one But I could live without
Rym: let me put it this way every other than the house the two out the world of one house the earliest house ever lived in in Detroit and The house I lived in momentarily in New Baltimore.
Rym: Every house ever lived in had a foyer and once I moved to a place where I no longer had a foyer It really I noticed not having a foyer.
Rym: I didn't think I'd notice not having a foyer.
Scott: It doesn't bother me that I can live without it.
Scott: It would be.
Scott: it would have advantage.
Scott: Semi foyer and I didn't have two doors, but in my house and connect you know my parents house is a foyer.
Scott: It doesn't have a second door.
Rym: ah see the second door.
Scott: It's one door and then a closet and then a portal, but no door on it.
Rym: You know we just have portals.
Rym: Yeah, but it was actually was cool that the house.
Rym: I lived in in Detroit.
Rym: It was like the Detroit's equivalent of suburban like brownstones, but it was just like old brick house like two-story.
Rym: But it was one of those old fancy houses meaning.
Rym: It's fancy, but the fanciness is mitigated by the fact that it's ancient and drafty.
Rym: But the front door was like this solid like two inch thick oak door And it was like rounded at the top and at this big like iron door like door knocker on it and this crazy old handle And once you open it you're in this big like not big.
Rym: it was big when I was a kid.
Rym: It's probably not so big now that I'm an adult, but there's a little fire.
Rym: There's a coat closet, and they're like iron stuff everywhere, and then there were French doors leading to the house.
Rym: It was pretty cool of course.
Rym: Uh we broke those French doors so often you wouldn't even.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: Well, I was a kid.
Rym: I just hit it with a hammer.
Scott: see that's that's something to me.
Scott: It's even I give up the foyer, but there's something that I really would want and that is and it's actually really expensive But high quality doors and windows are so important because a high quality windows, right?
Scott: You may if you never lived somewhere with shitty old windows like pizza old apartment Or if you've only ever had shitty old windows and you haven't experienced what new windows are like.
Scott: imagine if they always opened and closed Easily and just right all the time.
Scott: they locked perfectly.
Scott: they could sort of swing out to Ventilate in many different ways.
Scott: the glass was very insulated.
Rym: There's no draft at all.
Scott: Yeah, it just perfect.
Scott: you know you want to stick something like an air conditioner or window fan And it just fits perfectly because it's a modern correctly sized standard window.
Scott: It's not a cheap piece of wooden shit that's getting stuck or expanding and contracting with the cold and the heat.
Scott: It's plastic with glass and it's it's a real window.
Rym: speaking of windows I don't want to talk a little bit about HVAC because I Miss having proper heating and cooling in a house.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I've been in houses that have the central air You know and the you know the better heat and it is super nice But I've never actually lived anywhere that has it.
Scott: I could live without it, but I would really like it.
Rym: Yeah it's having to deal with you know like the window air conditioner is sort of annoying and use a lot of electricity and also having the Wall radiant heat is one of the worst ways of heating house you have.
Scott: well We have like you know that.
Scott: the problem is we live up in the Northeast where you know It's the old part of the country.
Scott: You know not like California or such where it's much newer.
Scott: you know so many.
Scott: you know the houses were built with much older technology and no one updates a lot of these things.
Scott: the house because It's so expensive and only newly built houses have the new technologies like the house I lived in in sterling heights was built in the 70s.
Rym: So it had pretty much modern.
Scott: I think aren't my parents.
Scott: I was built maybe like the 40s.
Rym: I guess yeah the house I lived in in Detroit was built like 1918.
Scott: Yeah, there are houses like you know in my town Like around here that were built in the 17 18 ancient times.
Rym: This house was so like old and renovated that we didn't have central air.
Rym: That house was just old like Detroit disaster But we had air conditioners mounted in the wall not in windows, but in the wall.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yep I know how it has like that.
Rym: Yeah, it really sucked.
Scott: Yeah, but at least you could replace it with a better air conditioner.
Rym: but I you know you think oh what why does it matter if you have ducted heat and cooling and all that?
Rym: but All right in my room now, especially in the winter I got a humidifier and in the summer And I got a deal with the fact that the one part of the rooms war once card whatever.
Rym: in a real house with normal HVAC You can just set the temperature in every room and it stays that temperature.
Rym: you pick a humidity and the whole house stays that humidity.
Rym: I've never actually seen a house that has the humidity control, but pretty much every Modern house with central heating and cooling has a humidifier built in.
Scott: I've never seen that.
Scott: I've never seen it.
Scott: I guess you know I've seen dehumidifier because an air conditioner is a dehumidifier It's just part of the furnace.
Scott: you don't even see Humidifying controls in any house even the one you know newish ones with central air.
Rym: I've never found the digital thermostat.
Rym: people might not know how to use it But it's there.
Scott: I've never seen it before in my life.
Rym: modern stove stoves modern furnaces have.
Scott: I'll temporarily take your word for it.
Scott: I'm just saying I've never seen it before.
Scott: I mean it must exist.
Scott: It's kind of common.
Rym: you know besides How often you go to someone's house then just go go to the thermostat and start poking around in it.
Scott: I poke at them quite often actually especially places where it's you know fancy houses.
Rym: you also poke at Alarm systems that you don't know what they do.
Scott: yeah, I poke at lots of things, and then they go off.
Rym: I'm not lying about poking at things but and also having the centralized HVAC Set up properly means that the whole house is ventilated properly because a lot of houses actually are not ventilated properly.
Rym: It's actually a science in terms of how to make sure a house circulates air Oxygen and all that through all the rooms and ventilates out.
Scott: you know bad stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I mean one of the.
Scott: you know when you're doing architecture one of the most difficult parts is you know okay?
Scott: You design a house so things line up and the house won't fall apart.
Scott: You know that's hard, and then you design it so the house actually practical and good for living and you know traffic Or people going around the house is nice and easy and you know that's hard again.
Scott: Now you to make sure air goes around the house properly.
Scott: I see that's the super hardest part.
Rym: I can say this our house now does not do that.
Rym: our house is not HVAC whatever it's like.
Scott: It's not terrible, but it's it's not part.
Scott: It's not good.
Scott: It's not like the best it could.
Rym: closing doors in this house definitely makes room stuffy Which it shouldn't yeah, and there's lots of times.
Scott: You'll see like doors in this house opening closing on their own Happen plus.
Rym: I also miss having an attic fan a lot.
Scott: No, not the attic fan, but an attic to sort of shove shit into is nice.
Scott: Yeah, bodies know that or even like better like one of those attics.
Scott: That's actually a room.
Scott: Those are nice, too.
Scott: But yeah
Rym: an attic fan actually I'd really love because that what they do is if it's cool like you want to ventilate the house Right you open all the windows Turn on the attic fan And it basically just pulls air in from every window in the house and shoots out through the attic And it makes like this perfect breeze in every room.
Rym: Yep, of course a lot of people turn them on without opening windows because they don't know better.
Rym: That's not something you should do, but anyway yeah.
Rym: But yeah enough talk about HVAC.
Rym: I want proper HVAC.
Rym: I also want green HVAC I want a heat pump, and I want solar panels and skylights.
Rym: You see I only.
Scott: well skylights are nice so I can look at the sky and whatever from in the house.
Scott: You know like if it's raining a skylight is way cool.
Rym: Also.
Rym: The natural light is really nice.
Scott: Yeah the green stuff I obviously don't care about it for its greenness because I don't give a shit about that but because you're horrible But I care, but I do give a shit because it saves the fucking bills.
Scott: if I'm paying this much money for a house Goddamn, I can like save my electric bill like super times and also the water bill will be super cheap, too.
Rym: Yeah, that's the other.
Scott: I want a gigantic water eating bill be super cheap.
Rym: Oh save so much money and solar panels and all that and you buy a new house.
Rym: I can't get that so easily in an old house, but a new house I just put it in.
Scott: yeah you buy a bunch of like equipment.
Scott: You know with your mortgage money, and then your bills that you actually have to pay month to month and not so big.
Scott: I Mean you know even just the central air alone.
Scott: if you get a normal central air conditioner Just an average run-of-the-mill one.
Scott: your house is super cool everywhere Right and you're paying less money for that than you're paying for like a few window air conditioners.
Scott: Totally awesome.
Rym: Yeah now.
Rym: I mean that's we're thinking about this.
Rym: We're still looking most likely because there aren't We either.
Rym: if we buy a new house is gonna be a McMansion.
Rym: if you don't buy a McMansion We pretty much have to buy an existing house knock it down and build a new house on the ruins.
Scott: Yeah, it really you know.
Scott: it kind of sucks out here where the houses are not so modern that you know if you want A house with like cat5 cables running to every room and all this stuff We got to have to buy a shit house and pay a fortune to renovate it buy a shit house knock it down or Buy a plot and put a modern house on it.
Rym: But there aren't so many plots and all the plots are owned by McMansion makers.
Rym: Yeah I've been looking at the floor plans and a lot of the McMansions Actually aren't that bad.
Rym: we could we could pretty Cheaply turn them into what we wanted.
Scott: yeah The McMansions aren't really that bad in terms of floor plan.
Scott: my major problem with them Is that when you live in one you're living in this sort of community with a whole bunch of them?
Scott: See the kind of people that live in them.
Scott: I don't want to live next now.
Rym: and also There's a way around that most of vegan doesn't have homeowners associations, and there are crappy old houses for 180 to $200,000.
Rym: let's knock it down there.
Scott: They're yeah, but it's a bit.
Scott: you need a lot of land to put one of those things.
Rym: There's enough land?
Scott: Yeah, you got to make sure.
Rym: the thing is the McMansion builders will build pretty much wherever you want them to.
Rym: so if we get A plot we could build a McMansion on it and as long as we worked with Contractors to get the green stuff put in and all the things we want you
Scott: got to be up to code And there's all sorts of laws you got to follow.
Rym: yeah, that's that's anywhere.
Scott: Yeah, but you got to check all that shit out before you buy the plot.
Scott: because what if the plot isn't big enough to have All the shit we want?
Rym: I know all about that.
Scott: Just say you know it's.
Scott: it's a tricky situation.
Scott: You can't just be like oh get any old plot of land and get the perfect house on it.
Scott: No, you got to get a good big enough plot of land with.
Rym: yes You have to do research for all this.
Rym: yeah, we're not talking about in this show.
Rym: We're talking about we want not what we're gonna do because.
Scott: but to go back I didn't get to talk about how doors are just as important as windows because they are.
Scott: how many doors in your house don't actually Close easily or properly or how many of them like have locks that don't work or low-quality knobs Or you know shit like that.
Scott: like the root the doors to my room.
Scott: right one of them kind of flaps around Right and the other and you have to like really pull it tight to get it to shut my closet door in the.
Scott: in the summer You can't close it because it expands and in the winter You know it closes nicely.
Scott: You know I should get a fucking door that opens and closes perfectly like a chunk a chunk all the time.
Scott: the handles actually work The locks actually work.
Scott: that sort of thing is small But it actually makes your life a lot better when all the doors in your house.
Scott: Just kind of work properly.
Rym: Yeah, also sound isolation and that sort of thing.
Rym: and speaking of that We're getting to the point where I don't think we need a like to room with the glass panel like dedicated recording studio But we need some sort of recording studio.
Rym: doing this in my room is getting more and more annoying Yeah, and I'm a big problem with it.
Scott: so much.
Rym: Yeah, plus.
Rym: I'd like to kind of separate work and life from bed.
Rym: I like my bedroom to be a small desk with my laptop and a bed.
Scott: I definitely do want to get the computers out of my room You know and I want to have a bedroom that is for Bedrooming and I want to have a separate room that is sort of for office computer.
Scott: And you know having the computer in the bedroom is sort of like okay those days are over.
Scott: That's sort of like the you know college high school because I can't afford to have another room.
Scott: deal You know and it's like all right time to get another room.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean briefly also I want a kitchen with a lot of counter space and stainless steel.
Scott: I want a kitchen with an island.
Rym: Yes, the island is key the island where you can lift up the center and now there's a griddle, but otherwise It's just an island.
Rym: ah yeah, it's pretty fancy, and I want a nice stove.
Rym: all that business, but that's that's not interesting.
Rym: But also I think the area for the most improvement would be the bathroom because why don't you just have a bathroom?
Rym: Where everything in its waterproof, and you have a shower stall?
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I'd like a separate tub.
Rym: shower stall is for washing tub is for bubble bath.
Scott: Yeah, if you only like one tub in the house You're not gonna use it that often.
Scott: That's why the tub would also have to be some sort of jacuzzi hot tub and have many moods.
Rym: Oh could get the we could get the outdoor hot tub.
Scott: Yeah, you could do that, then you don't need a tub at all.
Rym: the problem is you have one hot tub.
Rym: pretty much Undoes all the green we did and then some you realize how much energy hot tubs use.
Scott: well You're only gonna use it.
Scott: You know so often.
Rym: even then you know how much they use like on an hour-per-hour basis.
Rym: It's crazy.
Rym: Yeah, they also require a lot of money to maintain.
Scott: You can get like a sauna or something right?
Rym: Sonnet be the hot coals and then whatever but even then that that's it.
Rym: going into the realm of would be nice Yeah, just sort of like a luxury item.
Rym: But I want a bathroom where one.
Rym: I'd like to full bathrooms instead of one and a half bathrooms.
Scott: Yeah, well what I want is you know I want to have.
Scott: you know I definitely got to be more than one shower.
Scott: But I kind of like you know when I was a kid I didn't.
Scott: when I was younger I didn't like these sort of bathrooms that were attached to bedrooms, but now I kind of really like that action Especially when you're living with more a lot of people.
Scott: what I like having the separate bathrooms You know just like you know shower stall and a sink in a toilet.
Scott: it for each bedroom is kind of awesome.
Rym: But I like the idea of having like a you know shower stalls and bathrooms for normal stuff And then a tub for just taking a nice bath.
Rym: But beyond all that the bathroom should be all Waterproof and have a drain in the floor so that when I when it's time to clean the bathroom I just power wash the whole thing.
Rym: it takes five minutes.
Scott: Yeah, definitely nothing in the bathroom should be made of wood and no wall in the bathroom should be painted or wallpapered.
Scott: It should be all tile or stay steel.
Scott: I guess you don't want to steal to.
Scott: What's toilets made of?
Rym: porcelain.
Rym: porcelain You know what you know actually?
Scott: Metal.
Scott: those should be the only things your bathroom is made of.
Rym: ideally I'd like to separate bathing and going to the bathroom.
Scott: Yeah, so necessary that's sort of.
Scott: it's sort of like an insane high-priced luxury to have a separate.
Rym: That's definitely in the.
Rym: wouldn't it be nice?
Scott: Yeah, you know generally when you design a house, right?
Scott: You want to have sort of like as many of the plumbing things like the bathrooms and things vertically aligned.
Scott: So you'd have a bathroom directly under it on the floor below the other bathroom That the hot water heater.
Scott: that way the plumbing is much simpler and cheaper and everything works.
Rym: I think the simplest most ideal way would be to have the upstairs bathroom is like a shower Tub like we have now and then below that on the main floor is a shower stall full bathroom And then in the basement under that is just a bathroom.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh basement bathrooms always cool.
Rym: You always had a basement bathroom and every house I lived in you need the best thing about basement bathroom right?
Scott: is you can fool around in the backyard or something.
Scott: then take the Secret entrance to the basement, you know directly from the outside and then get people to clean off in the shitty-ass basement bathroom.
Rym: Also, if you're hanging out in the basement bathroom.
Rym: It's nice that plus when we have 15 people over two bathrooms are not enough.
Rym: No Now this is also one of those wouldn't it be?
Scott: you need you need a gigantic water heater to handle all those bathrooms going at once.
Rym: this is wouldn't it be nice?
Rym: but Honestly if because I wouldn't want a lot of people to live in the house but a lot of people would come to the house a lot a lot of open like common rooms that people would come over and use but in the basement instead of It'll always be worth it to have a urinal.
Rym: nah just for the sheer number of guys Yeah, yes, then in that trough.
Rym: No, not a trough.
Rym: I don't think we need a trough.
Rym: That's that's that's NASCAR.
Rym: Hey, but a urinal would actually be really useful and would save a lot of water.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it would.
Scott: the thing is I don't know how to clean urinal.
Rym: She's put the cake in it And I don't know.
Rym: we hired someone to clean the urinal.
Rym: you just scrub it Scott.
Rym: It's like any toilet.
Scott: You can clean it.
Rym: it's no different.
Rym: In fact, I'd rather clean a urinal because a urinal just has one thing going into it.
Rym: Hope you know what I'd like unless urinal poop calm.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I just thought of something I'd like in the bathroom.
Rym: What'd you like in the bathroom of those hand dryer dealies?
Rym: Yeah Yeah, those.
Scott: the thing is they have this.
Rym: no.
Rym: No, no, we don't need that.
Rym: The only reason you get that is because you don't want to waste money and and resources on having those stupid paper towels.
Scott: Oh, but you see they have this new kind that doesn't actually heat doesn't blow with hot air.
Scott: what it does It blows up high-pressure airs.
Scott: you just kind of put your hands in and it goes whoop and you're dry.
Rym: but we have the luxury because we live it here of Just uh having towels.
Scott: I actually like the hand the air dryer better than towels for hand drying Not for body drying.
Scott: But anyway, I guess I would like for body drying but a dryer that large would be too much money.
Scott: I'd have to like go to the car wash to dry off my entire body.
Rym: I hate to say this but We probably.
Rym: it would be nice that now we could integrate this with the computer room den But we might need.
Rym: we don't need a separate dining room But we definitely need a library of some kind.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I Should.
Scott: I really should get more bookshelves already, but I don't have any place to put them.
Rym: It's not just books but board games and all that stuff.
Rym: We really need.
Scott: I mean if I had a bigger house They're probably every free wall space would probably have shelves on it, you know Eventually, so it's really just a matter of having more space.
Scott: But if there is a spare room to dedicate to just bookshelves That's really cool cuz like a quiet place to read.
Rym: when I when I was a kid It was a fun room to decorate You know, we we had a dining room and a living room and a family room and the kitchen had basically a dining room in it.
Rym: I don't need a separate dining room.
Rym: That's just silly.
Scott: well, it's it's.
Scott: what's cool is if you have like sort of like a like a portal from like the Kitchen to the diet to like another area then you can sort of get a table when you need it to go through the portal To get a long table for when you need a long table.
Rym: But anyway, what I'm thinking is when I was a kid we had the Dining room which was next to the kitchen, but there's a door between him And then there was the the nook which was bigger than our current kitchen where we normally ate.
Rym: That's where the real dining room table was.
Rym: So we turned the dining room into the library and Also the aviary.
Rym: we put all the birds in there because we it's not like it was valuable rare books that the bird Feathers would ruin.
Rym: it was just.
Rym: that was a way to have a multi-purpose room that actually worked really well And it was really nice to.
Rym: you know Like on a weekend I'd go into the library and there were just two nice wicker chairs in there and all the books and I'd Get my book and I just wicker chairs.
Rym: Well, they had nice pads because my mom was on a kind of African safari kind of cake.
Rym: So the house was outfitted like one of those Like you see in the movies like where Teddy Roosevelt would stay when he's out hunting Animals, I never
Scott: understood like you go to like these fancy mansions, you know, I see at every fancy house I ever see especially like we're rich people the room
Rym: where there's nothing anyone can touch.
Scott: No, not that but like in the backyard They'll have like the table the steel like iron Like cast-iron really fancily ornate like chairs and table like an.
Scott: and I'm like, how can you sit on that?
Rym: It's so uncomfortable I would like to have.
Rym: it's like the fans here.
Scott: It's like the fancier the furniture the more uncomfortable it is.
Rym: Yeah All right, I think we've talked enough about the house we want to buy.
Scott: I don't know if I want birds in like the library though because I was sort of Sort of defeat the quietness of the library.
Rym: Well, see as a kid.
Rym: It was really I was used to the birds.
Rym: I've lived with birds my whole life.
Rym: It was kind of comforting.
Rym: Yeah, I guess if you're I don't think we're gonna have a menagerie of birds in the new house.
Scott: No, I don't think I'm not gonna have 20 birds.
Rym: No, I think we have any 15 of which are zebra finches going.
Rym: meh meh meh meh meh.
Scott: Yeah, you can keep birds in your room.
Scott: They're.
Rym: I might get about pregnant parrotlet or something.
Scott: I like little if I'm hearing it around the house.
Rym: Teach it to talk.
Scott: Yeah, if it says Rym is stupid then you can keep it.
Rym: I'll teach you that.
Rym: Oh, no All right.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: It's Thursday.
Rym: Hey you and you listeners live in the New York State area like downstate and you ski.
Rym: I'm probably gonna go to either hunter mountain or Thunder Ridge on Sunday.
Rym: So if you want to go skiing with Rym and you don't suck at skiing you have to be able to take the black diamonds P.m.
Rym: Me and we can go skiing together because I'm gonna be there.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.