Rym: It's Monday December 15th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: portable words.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: You know I'm pretty good with the with the softwares.
Scott: You know it's that's sort of what I do.
Scott: You know make softwares, but for many moons.
Scott: You know the physical bits the electronics have sort of.
Scott: you know mystified.
Scott: You know it's like I can stick a video card in an AGP slot And I can understand.
Scott: you know the abstracted metaphors for how these technologies work.
Scott: And now when I understand on a fundamental level that there You know pins and electricity and the electricity goes on and it goes off, and there's like these square waves You know if it's at five volts It's one.
Scott: if it's zero volts at zero, but it'll thing.
Rym: But I'm guessing if someone handed you a pile of resistors and such and with said without Google make a flip-flop.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: I know PV equals nRT But if you give me a calculator that even though I know that it won't help me for shit cuz I don't know I only know what the V is I?
Scott: Don't know what the n RT or P's are.
Rym: the problem is what will stop most people is the lost art of looking at a resistor And knowing the resistance.
Scott: see I know that there are colors and that they mean something right and I know that those colors match up With a number of ohms.
Scott: I could not tell you which one of those letters in the in the equation is the ohms so That I'm sort of lost.
Rym: I almost feel worse because I was kind of a hobbyist.
Scott: Yeah, I'm when I say hobbyist I'm like I can make a circuit like I know the electricity goes from the.
Scott: you know the positive to the ground.
Rym: well well No, the electrons come out of the negative.
Scott: Yeah, but you know you connect it.
Scott: This is circuit.
Scott: it goes in a circle.
Scott: I know how it works right, but it you know I don't.
Scott: I Can't actually do it.
Scott: You know even though.
Scott: I worked with like James who does this for a living for like you know?
Scott: I guess 20 weeks, and I didn't learn enough.
Scott: I mean I learned but not enough to actually do anything.
Scott: But basically the extent of my electronics was you know I?
Scott: Wrote some C code that turned one pin on the motherboard like on and I connected a thing to it so I could detect Like I could detect if it was a one or a zero, but that's as basically software.
Scott: I didn't actually do any electronics all right.
Scott: everyone else did all that.
Rym: No, I feel like I'm kind of in a worse situation because I used to be really into that like in middle school elementary school I was soldering stuff all over the place and inside Stuff at summer camp Completely forgot how to do it like.
Rym: I made a really like.
Rym: I made an alarm system for my bed.
Scott: I also made an alarm system with two buttons.
Rym: Oh see mine wasn't buttons.
Rym: mine actually was if the circuit was broken it went off.
Scott: Well the button was broken.
Scott: the circuit was broken by a button.
Rym: see mine was just.
Rym: I had a wire.
Rym: I wired it into the door frame.
Scott: well see mine.
Scott: I made it and it was sort of loose.
Scott: so right and one button was sort of like the arming button.
Scott: It was one of those clicky ones like it locks in.
Scott: So if you lock that button in then it was armed and if you unlocked it It was off.
Scott: there's also a power switch right and then there was a very loose button.
Scott: It was like one of those silent sort of.
Scott: you know you could.
Scott: it would get pushed if you like tapped it a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, yep, and so if it got pushed past a certain point It would cut it and then in the alarm was set.
Rym: so there was basically a current Going across where the door is and the window.
Rym: and if the voltage?
Scott: Yeah, I mean I could have done the same exact thing.
Scott: Just you know by taking the wires off getting longer wires and putting different switches on instead of using switches I set it up to where.
Rym: if the voltage dropped across that whole why could he just use like magnet switches?
Scott: You know what the magnets are closed to each other, but then when they move up that cuts it, and that's it You know.
Rym: yeah But do you remember how to make a circuit where if you lose signal on one wire the other wire?
Scott: I know when I made this thing I was in summer camp But I had a little chart.
Scott: And you know even though we even made the boards there like we drew on the boards of the magic marker And they were just copper and then they put him in acid for us And they came out.
Scott: and then you know the tree.
Rym: we didn't get to do that.
Rym: I just had piles of bread boards that I periodically broke.
Scott: See I could use a bread board to practice some soldering on.
Rym: so I remember very specifically I was saying it's soldering.
Scott: I got taught by an Australian guy.
Rym: I was in like third grade and then I forgot I was soldering something together And I was following this diagram and the the friendly gnome I knew who taught me how to solder and taught me how to do all this stuff.
Rym: no But this this man was the closest thing to a gnome that the real world has ever seen.
Rym: Him and his whole family were gnomes.
Rym: they lived in a house That was nothing more than a giant engineering project lived in a tree.
Rym: They were all and they rode on a. him and his wife and his daughter red triangle hat.
Rym: Him his wife and his daughter were all engineers for a living.
Rym: they both had him and his wife.
Rym: both had doctorates in engineering.
Rym: I forget what.
Scott: David the gnome rode around on fuck.
Rym: This is the guy who would hand me two wires and say you may feel a shock don't.
Rym: But I remember I was in soldering something together.
Rym: he's like can you read a schematic?
Rym: and I'm like.
Rym: yes Yes, I can.
Rym: and he's like really.
Rym: so he shows me a schematic He's like does this look like?
Rym: what you think a schematic is now is like.
Rym: no No, I'm using this and he's like that's a diagram.
Rym: This is a schematic sit down boy, and you're going to learn ha electronics actually work, so
Scott: I went and There's this Arduino thing right which is basically like this open-source Board and there are plenty of other plenty of other like boards and chips you can get that you can program stuff on.
Scott: there's like There's like basic stamps and all these other things right there basically Chips that are really easy to program.
Scott: you connect it to your computer with a serial port you write some software You push a button the software goes over to the chip and then the chip is connected to a board and then there's like some pins on the board and you can program whether they go on or off and then there's some other ones That are input so you can detect whether the in what's coming in is on or off and then you can make things happen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: so this Arduino one is like these super open-source one.
Scott: You know it's not like super powerful It's not like the best thing ever.
Scott: It's you know it's limited, but it's super open-source and super everything like that and works with USB.
Scott: So I went to like to make magazine store And I bought like the whole thing and then I went to some other places And I bought all the other stuff, and I pretty much have everything now except I actually need some solder.
Scott: I got to go to some Radio Shack.
Rym: Yeah, you know it's solder.
Rym: right yeah, but I got Okay, as long as you admit that it is actually solder, which you just did, but I'm Australian now.
Rym: Oh Are you?
Scott: yes, I got a solder.
Rym: So the circuits what's the capital of Australia, Melbourne, okay, yeah anyway?
Scott: Right so I got all this stuff, and I can learn how to use it.
Scott: I'm gonna be all dangerous.
Scott: And then maybe one day I will make something that will you know sort of appear on all the websites like oh my god guy Makes you know small version of something.
Scott: Guy makes this piece of technology.
Scott: talk to this other piece of technology.
Scott: There's another.
Rym: It really depends which website you get on because the article headline might be guy solders finger to other finger found dead.
Scott: I thought that's gonna happen.
Rym: I can say one thing I did once drip hot solder Into my thumbnail once like between the nail and the finger mmm.
Rym: That was possibly the worst experience of my life.
Scott: Yeah, it's not gonna happen But I have to.
Scott: I need to get like it like a. I think I'm just gonna take some of the old things we have Lying around that's that are crappy and try to practice the soldering on them.
Rym: You know you can do.
Rym: I got that old motherboard with all the busted caps.
Rym: you should take them all off and put them back On.
Scott: I could try that.
Scott: The thing is that all the soldering I have to do is through the hole and a lot of stuff on modern Technology is surface mount and surface mount is like very hard and also.
Scott: I'm never gonna do anything I'm only gonna do through the hole, so I don't know.
Rym: Anyway, well I can say one thing if you're not worried about it actually working you can treat all those as through the hole.
Scott: I guess that's true.
Scott: I just poke holes in it.
Rym: No There are things because they're not the little Tiny goings that are on the side or surface mount.
Rym: the big ones on my old a bit motherboard are through the hole effective really.
Scott: So I could like in the hole.
Rym: Yeah, I know through the hole you could do it.
Scott: anyway I got a you know what.
Rym: well I got.
Scott: go buy like a pack of resistors that are like you know less than a cent each And they're just like sold to the mall to a thing full of holes.
Rym: just to practice You know I like the idea of what you know getting a house and all that and then trying to make the whole house Super awesomely automated like a lot of yeah, but it's a lot.
Scott: You know that you know it's much easier.
Scott: Just buy something that does that rather than try to make all.
Rym: yes to a point But you buy the things that do the basic things.
Rym: But if you want to do the one complicated thing for which no one made a simple thing That's true.
Rym: Then you got to do this.
Scott: actually I was thinking of one thing that might be cool.
Scott: right?
Scott: is You get a Wi-Fi thing right and you get the chip and a battery or you connect it to the wall or whatever right?
Scott: and basically have a switch like physical switches for all the people who live in your house right like maybe three-way switches and then LEDs and then you just write their name on it And then you flick a switch and it will like connect to the jabber and be like so when you leave the house you could Just be like away with a switch.
Scott: Huh when you come back call me be like home and it will just change it.
Rym: by that logic Why don't you just have an app on your iPhone?
Scott: that that's what I'm saying.
Rym: You know a series of presets like left the house or even better the night tie it to the GPS.
Rym: the main problem When you get home, it just says rims.
Scott: Oh, yeah I thought of that.
Scott: you know what the problem is because the iPhone doesn't have any sort of multitasking or background tasking.
Scott: you would actually have to go turn on the iPhone Go to the app push the buttons while this internet around and then like, you know Turn off the iPhone and like you have to wait for the GPS to get your location.
Scott: It's like you have to do all this stuff.
Scott: There's a lot more work than flicking us away.
Rym: So, you know, this is the problem.
Rym: We're so close to having all the things I've wanted my whole life.
Rym: Did she want?
Scott: yeah get the get the g1 from t-mobile, you know what?
Scott: the battery doesn't last all day.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it sits there all day doing all that shit that you wanted to do.
Rym: That's why I just gotta wait.
Scott: Yep Maybe the zinc air batteries that they're talking about will help you.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: Yeah Alright, so check this out, right?
Scott: There's a the.
Scott: there's been a recent hub of mostly today.
Scott: It's sort of been like the comeback of net neutrality as an issue, right?
Scott: and basically what's happened here is the Wall Street Journal and some other people have sort of Not understood what net neutrality means.
Scott: So I feel I have to re-explain this to everyone to make sure that it's clear right.
Scott: so Originally, this is where net neutrality first became an issue.
Scott: was this right?
Scott: I Go to someone who sells internet internet service provider, maybe the cable company the phone company someone else, right?
Scott: I get a connection.
Scott: It's a t1 whatever right?
Scott: It's so many megabits per second.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: They I pay for the t1.
Scott: That's all I pay for.
Scott: if I use it a lot or if I use it a little bit I pay The same right?
Scott: It doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't change, right?
Scott: What they wanted to do was what what some of the internet service providers want to do is They wanted to say hey look right, you know on the other end of the internet service, right?
Scott: So I'm on this end with my t1.
Scott: on the other end is Google, right if I visit Google Right, then Google's data is going over their line.
Scott: So they feel like they should be able to charge Google.
Scott: They are charging Google Google's paying for internet connections on its side to some you know to someone else and then it's just this big Network.
Rym: everyone pretty much just boils down to that.
Rym: pretty much everyone who knows about the technology agrees that the ISPs and the high-level providers and the internet itself Should be completely agnostic to the content and the originator of the content.
Scott: Yes, so what they wanted to do is they wanted to say, all right, look, you know Google You should pay us, you know more because you're using more of our bandwidth.
Scott: or they were gonna say, all right, look Everyone we're still gonna let all the traffic go through.
Scott: So if you visit Google, it'll still make it to the other side.
Scott: But if Google pays us money Then it'll be faster for you people to visit Google.
Scott: then it'll be for you to visit.
Scott: You know say Yahoo, right unless Yahoo also pays us money.
Scott: So what that would be is actually It's not net neutral because different things you are visiting are getting like You know preferential treatment and the other things that you are visiting are getting sort of demoted, right?
Scott: So the actual what is going over the lines is being discriminated against right?
Scott: Basically what happened here right?
Scott: is Google said hey look here.
Scott: We got a plan here called open edge I think is there.
Scott: is there a profit?
Scott: the name of their plan here and The idea For Google's thing was that they were gonna put servers.
Scott: They wanted to pay ISPs to put their Google servers, you know co-locate them at the ISP.
Scott: So I use we have Cablevision here right Optima online.
Scott: So instead of Google getting preferential treatment on the networking side, right?
Scott: What would happen is Google would just put a server at Cablevision and then they wouldn't get any preferential treatment.
Scott: But it would just be faster because Google has the server right there instead of it going all the way to you know Mountain View, California, or wherever it is, right?
Scott: So that's perfectly net neutral as long as anyone who can afford it is also allowed to.
Scott: you know Put servers there.
Scott: so What happened is, you know, Google came out with this and you know, Larry Lessig Who's a who's a net neutrality supporter came out and said that was cool.
Scott: But all these other people who misunderstood it were like, oh, you know, I thought you guys are for net neutrality.
Scott: Now you're against it.
Scott: given Google preferential treatment, you know, you know, why should Google be faster?
Scott: It's like it's not.
Scott: it is net neutral.
Scott: They're putting up servers in a different place.
Scott: We're not modifying the network to make Google packets go faster and other people's packets go slower.
Scott: We're just putting Google servers out there And as long as anyone who can afford it can do the same thing.
Rym: because at the same time ISPs do have the discretion to.
Rym: if you're gonna host a server to Refuse to do business with people on various reasons Like for example, if someone's the known spammer lost ISPs if they find out we'll say look No, you can't use our service and all the spammers then up on those shady ISPs.
Scott: Oh you want to see that there's a difference between Spamming and putting out viruses where you're sort of violating You know the the terms of service and whatnot.
Rym: and as opposed to just what I'm putting out a podcast that they don't like What if I just make a terms of service that I update every time I get a customer I like that says I only offer this to these specific companies and no one else.
Scott: that's not net neutral.
Scott: It's not cool.
Rym: But what's the specific line?
Rym: What?
Rym: what am I allowed to discriminate against?
Rym: and what am I not allowed to discriminate against?
Scott: You're allowed to discriminate against spam and illegal things not like.
Rym: what is what is spam?
Scott: Unsolicited emails.
Rym: Alright, so how do you know for sure?
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: How do I know for sure?
Scott: It's obvious.
Rym: Is it really though?
Rym: Yeah, a new company.
Rym: They have you you know, they their name isn't Google anywhere.
Rym: They're a fresh new company and they want to buy hosting with you.
Rym: All right, they're actually spammers.
Rym: they start spamming.
Scott: I look at the emails which are perfectly visible.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: you look at the emails?
Rym: What do you look for?
Scott: Viagra's OG.
Scott: I wonder or hey, look, I'm getting a bunch of emails to abuse at me and they all say hey I'm getting fucking spam from you bitches.
Rym: All right, but spam in many cases is not actually illegal if it's done in certain ways.
Rym: So where are you gonna draw the line?
Scott: because Eddie legal spam?
Rym: Okay, so the only way the only thing you can possibly discriminate against if you're an ISP is If the thing that they want to do is actually directly illegal.
Rym: Yeah Alright, what if you don't you ran out of rack space?
Rym: We mean somebody one more person wants to buy a service and you don't have any more rack space.
Scott: Yeah, you know more.
Scott: it's that's like if someone wants to buy a banana and I'm the girls All the bananas so I may I buy I have one you of rack space.
Rym: I sell it to Google's.
Rym: now I'm full.
Rym: All right, is that okay?
Scott: You sell it to first come first serve.
Rym: I open I make the rack space for Google and then I don't make any more.
Scott: See, but we're not talking about making rack space for people.
Scott: We're talking about co-location.
Rym: Yes co-location So they co.
Rym: look I allow Google to co-locate in the one cubby hole that I have free for co-location And now it's full that no one else can do it.
Scott: That's fine because you're not doing anything on the network side.
Rym: Okay, that's what I was saying because it sounded like you were saying that if I offer a service to anyone as an ISP I have to offer it to everyone no matter what unless it's illegal, but it sounds like now that's not the case.
Scott: Well, no, it's just you know, I was just talking to.
Scott: but net neutrality is about the network.
Rym: Yes That's not what I'm trying to make.
Scott: it's not about you know Who puts servers where anyone could put servers anywhere they want to.
Scott: it's about the network.
Scott: You shouldn't filter packets.
Scott: You shouldn't you know make some packets slower in some packets faster.
Scott: All the packets are just treated as faceless packets headed towards their destination and they get sent to their destination With you know, the best possible service available.
Rym: So how do I do QoS though?
Rym: What if what if my network gets saturated and not everything's gonna get through?
Scott: am I allowed to you just do it evenly?
Rym: What do you mean evenly though?
Rym: That doesn't really work so well because UDP versus TCP taking it evenly from TCP will greatly affect performance while taking it evenly from UDP, especially if it's like streaming video.
Scott: Yes, but you are.
Scott: if you're doing a TCP versus UDP thing Then you're doing a fair and even thing across.
Scott: you're not discriminating by Content or by who it is.
Scott: So the line emanating by it's all TCP and all UDP.
Rym: So it's okay to discriminate at layer three or four but not layer five or layer Based on people or content.
Scott: you're just you know, it's just across the board.
Rym: It's the content.
Rym: It's the content of the layer two packet.
Scott: But it's not the what they're doing.
Scott: It's not Skype versus eBay versus Google.
Scott: It's you know, it it's just you know, it's all.
Scott: UDP needs to slow down because we don't have any more.
Rym: Alright, so I just completely throttled UDP Which will screw up a lot of the a lot of these shady peer-to-peer things and Happens to.
Scott: but it's all UDP and it's you're not.
Scott: you're not cutting it.
Rym: You're Equally, so I'm just here.
Rym: I'm allowed to discriminate against all UDP.
Scott: Am I allowed to?
Scott: you can't do it, but if you you know, if you're if you're net where you got to manage your network Yes, so am I allowed to discriminate against all port 9008?
Rym: Regardless of content, I'm just see.
Rym: here's here's the point.
Rym: I'm trying to make no.
Rym: net neutrality Is very difficult to define from a legal perspective.
Rym: This is the biggest issue.
Rym: Is that how do you specify in?
Rym: legalese in an unambiguous way what is allowed and what is not?
Rym: because Technologists like I can look at it and say that's neutral.
Rym: That's not that's neutral.
Rym: That's not and it's obvious to me and most text would agree with me, but that doesn't really fly in a court of law.
Rym: I mean the whole.
Rym: is it pornography?
Rym: Well, I know it when I see it.
Rym: That's BS.
Rym: That does that works even less for technology.
Rym: So, how can we fight for net neutrality if we can't define what it truly is on a very specific logical unambiguous level?
Scott: Is true in a way But the point is is people need to understand, you know, what exactly like when these issues come up, you know Like you got to really pay attention and you know, think about what's being said and what's going on.
Scott: You know, it's really common sense once you understand even like a little bit what you know.
Scott: The issue the current issue is like what's fair and what's not fair, you know, and what would be okay?
Scott: And what would not be okay?
Scott: It's like is it okay for Google to pay someone to put a server somewhere?
Scott: Yeah, is it okay for someone to make Google go faster and to make something else go slower, you know, Yahoo goes slower.
Rym: What's the line between like?
Rym: do you do based on like one layer of ISP versus another layer?
Rym: and what if I Buy a t1 for myself and I sell it to my two neighbors and it's just our little network?
Rym: Am I allowed to discriminate against their stuff even though they're paying me?
Scott: It's a tough question exactly.
Scott: I guess.
Scott: if you're a company you can definitely do it and It depends on what your agreement is with your neighbors, but an ISP is just a company.
Rym: So all the all the customers who sign up for ISPs the agreement just says yeah, if you use peer-to-peer We'll I would are you I would agree with that.
Scott: Possibly that right.
Scott: the problem with that.
Rym: So, you know the problem with that is twofold.
Rym: number one I'll get to a false advertising of the I.
Scott: Wait, no, there's the other issue the monopoly of the ISPs.
Scott: you often do not have a choice in broadband ISP.
Scott: if I could choose between FiOS cable vision whatever then maybe it would be okay for them to.
Scott: you know start doing shit, but Because I have no other choice You know, that's reasonable, you know, we can't be.
Scott: you know It needs to be treated like utility and not treated like that's it because it's not just false advertising.
Scott: That's why you know, the phone system is so heavily regulated because in 99% of places you don't have a choice.
Scott: It's you get Verizon because you live here, but it's not just.
Rym: I mean Looking at the false advertising perspective Even if it's not technically false advertising.
Rym: The fact is that every ISP basically makes their terms of service say that they can do anything at any time for any reason.
Rym: Yep, but then again, how do we stop that?
Rym: Of course the easy way to stop that is to allow competition in some way.
Scott: I mean our ISP started doing the stupid DNS thing and they also started doing.
Scott: they've always blocked I think port 25 unless you pay for the business thing, but that's all they do.
Scott: Otherwise, they're cool for now.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the only reason we haven't had issues is that as far as I can tell none of our neighbors really are internet People.
Scott: no, not really Far more bandwidth and we should be getting yeah, the real the real thing that goes on here right is that You know you the the ISP gets an internet connection from someone else, right?
Scott: They buy an OC 3 let's say right and then they want to sell that to everyone in town.
Scott: now Yeah, let's say the OC 3.
Scott: I don't know how much bandwidth does it have like a hundred two hundred something like that.
Scott: a lot Right, but they've got a hundred customers.
Scott: They if they give each customer one, right?
Scott: That's only a hundred customers for an OS.
Scott: for one OC 3 That means each customer has to pay hundreds of dollars a month.
Scott: not gonna happen.
Scott: No, no No, and the thing is even if they do that, right?
Scott: They're not gonna use all of the OC 3.
Scott: I mean Every single customer would have to bit tour it full on at the exact same time for the OC 3 to be used up Snake.
Scott: and the way to make money on this right is if you just if you actually have enough bandwidth to Support every customer going full-on all the time.
Scott: You're losing money You're not or your customers are paying way too much.
Rym: See the problem is everyone always advertises unlimited internet with a tiny asterisk Yep.
Scott: So what you have to do is you have to buy a hundred megabits of bandwidth and then sell More than a hundred megabits of bandwidth.
Scott: you to sell.
Scott: it's like a thousand customers giving them ten each But at the same time percent of the time.
Scott: it'll be just fine.
Rym: No but the problem is that as our society is more technological more people are Utilizing the resource that is given to them in the manner that they expect.
Scott: But they're not using it a hundred percent and it's economically infeasible to actually be forced to be able to handle a hundred percent Capacity.
Rym: Yes, but at the same time, what do we do when we're basically?
Rym: The there's no way to handle this situation because no one is willing to pay what it actually costs and yet at the same time There's the monopolies.
Rym: You don't have any choice regardless.
Rym: What do we do?
Scott: You gotta?
Scott: basically the thing that John C Dvorak is actually kind of right and even though people think he's crazy is that He says there should be metering and not net, you know net neutral metering It's just yo you pay for how much bandwidth you use.
Scott: The problem
Rym: is they can't sell metered bandwidth in the US because people are so used to seeing Unlimited with the tiny asterisk that if they see a per hour or per kilobit or whatever charge They're gonna freak out and think it's the days of AOL all over again, but
Scott: the price is reasonable then it's all good.
Scott: You know, the thing is this everyone who you know argues against this is always like oh the price is gonna be crazy.
Rym: The thing is the prices are unreasonable I know.
Scott: but if the price is reasonable, I would be totally cool with you know Being metered as long as it meant I could.
Scott: you know I could do as much as I want if I do more.
Rym: The other issue is I get this impression that if like a cent per megabyte if all the ISPs decided to start Metering they wouldn't like lower their prices and then just meter accordingly to cover the cost.
Rym: They would simply keep their current prices and charge more for anyone who goes above a certain amount.
Scott: Yeah, see that's the thing is like.
Scott: it's basically saying yes metering would be cool If you if the person doing the metering was not a dick, but the people who are running this Metering would be cool.
Rym: If the person doing it, even if they are a dick was regulated in some way They don't have to be regulated.
Scott: It doesn't mean not a dick charge people to a fair correct price, but of a fraction not a cent.
Rym: That's impossible.
Rym: So we need to regulate it Because there's not impossible.
Rym: it is because the way you still have to have a physical wire.
Scott: go to everyone's house And yes You have a flat fee for the wire and that maintains that wire.
Rym: because the people who maintain the wire Don't they want to have the monopoly people who pay their what they maintain the wire now Yes, the people who actually also sell you the bandwidth in many cases or they lease it from the local like telco.
Scott: It just.
Scott: it needs to be a utility just like phone and electricity and water and then it'll be done.
Rym: Yes, it does.
Rym: if it was treated like utility as opposed to this I mean it is.
Rym: I mean
Scott: I think about every other utility though is metered electricity is metered water is better
Rym: But at the same time there are a lot of laws like for example We get our electricity and our gas but by law Even though the what the pipes and wires that come to our house are owned by one company We have the right to buy our gas and electricity from anyone else out there within.
Rym: there's certain limitation but we can buy it from other people and The people who own the wires to our house are forced by law to accommodate that and they are forced to charge us a certain Minimal regulated amount.
Rym: and they can't charge us extra because they have a monopoly on the wire.
Scott: Yeah Well, I mean it's it's possible for people to do this without having the government tell them to but it's never been never happened.
Rym: So we have to have been telling what to do.
Rym: I'm just saying I mean as much as I'm an advocate of deregulation and libertarianism.
Rym: History has shown that deregulation ends in ruin.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh if we ever get some sort of ymax wireless meshy network We don't need these bastards anymore.
Scott: Anyway, cuz unlike water and electricity we can push it over the sky.
Scott: and Even is actually strongly considering, you know Allocating some spectrum to free Internet's even better.
Rym: that allows all the crazy things to happen because then Nerds can make mesh networks that are entirely independent of any possible government control or interference.
Scott: Yeah, there's absolutely no way for the government to do any government in any part of the world to do anything about it.
Scott: Which means two things well short of technological jamming and you know, all those Aurelian things You know, it would be it would be a war that the government would lose.
Scott: any government would lose.
Rym: Well, the government even the Chinese government could win by going one step further and cutting the tall trees.
Scott: I Guess that's the only way that's the only way.
Rym: but but I that happened.
Scott: you don't get a. you would a nerd awesomeness everywhere and be Child porn would be all over the place.
Rym: Well, if you got if they had to cut the tall trees situation I think you'd run into the member.
Rym: that article we talked about a long time ago about how Engineers think like terrorists and or terrorists think like engineers.
Rym: Yeah, you don't want to piss Like engineers, it's well.
Rym: now the good terrorists think like engineers.
Scott: Again anyone every engineer right?
Scott: I mean look at like this some of the stuff that like What's the Bruce Schneier rice?
Scott: He's like the foremost security expert in the world, right?
Scott: He's like, oh, this is so easy.
Scott: Look how you can get through the airport.
Scott: Look how you can do this.
Scott: Look how you can do that.
Scott: It's so simple.
Scott: It's like if I wanted to make a knife on an airplane I would go and get some like iron epoxy at Home Depot and a piece of cardboard.
Scott: Bring it on the plane, you know, I fold the piece of cardboard.
Scott: I put in the iron epoxy.
Scott: I hold it there now.
Scott: I have a sharp knife on the plane.
Scott: Tada, right?
Scott: Nope engineers think like this and they come up with these things all the time.
Scott: I come up with these things all the time.
Scott: It's trivially easy to ruin the world if you have an engineering brain but anyone who is smart enough to think of these things and be an engineer is Not a terrorist because smart people aren't evil That's it.
Scott: There's just.
Scott: that's.
Scott: the reason that the world is still in one piece is because no smart people are evil.
Scott: if there was even one Engineer who was an ass and wanted to kill everyone we would all be dead.
Rym: Anyway, before we talk too much more about that I'd like to read for you a a quote from an article that this is kind of my news bit and You're gonna feel a lot of righteous indignation, but
Scott: I'm not indignant or fat
Rym: Maybe not you but the rest of you.
Rym: you're gonna feel some sort of bristle perhaps and I'm gonna read the whole thing.
Rym: I'll let you mull over it for a second.
Rym: Then we'll talk about what what actually was going on there.
Rym: quote Mr.
Rym: Starks, I'm sure you strongly believe in what you're doing But I cannot either support your efforts or allow them to happen in my classroom.
Rym: at this point I am not sure what you are doing is legal.
Rym: No software is free and Spreading that misconception is harmful.
Rym: This is a world where Windows runs on virtually every computer and Putting on a carnival show for an operating system is not helping these children at all.
Rym: I am sure if you contacted Microsoft They would be more than happy to supply you with copies of an older version of Windows and that way Your computers would actually be of service to those receiving them.
Rym: The story here was basically that you can read the articles.
Scott: I don't really want to parrot like explain the whole situation and make sure that you read the article Written by the guy that he wrote sort of after it exploded so you can get the real story.
Scott: basically Dude shown off open source teacher who I'm not just any dude He's a dude that like puts together like junky old computers He gives them the people who can't afford computers and he puts Linux on him.
Rym: Yes, but uh teacher sees this going on has no understanding of technology.
Scott: She sees like kids in a class with computers right looking at something.
Scott: They're all gathered around obviously up to mischief, right?
Scott: They got some CDs.
Scott: they got from some guy Running on computers, you know and the teacher doesn't know anything.
Scott: She's not technologically literate or anything.
Scott: You know, she's a Windows world like 90% of people.
Rym: and of course freaks out and leads to this guy writes an article article gets read by people who then paraphrase article full of righteous indignation gets crazier and crazier and crazier and Makes a little internet explosion.
Rym: and then there's a whole follow-up article where the guy who wrote the article was like, dude Yes, she was wrong.
Rym: And yes, she was dumb.
Rym: But seriously you people are overreacting times a million.
Scott: Yeah, he like he found out that the school system actually even though they run Windows has like shit tons open-source.
Scott: They got the open office and the Firefox and the whole, you know, it's just.
Scott: there's one teacher who didn't know.
Scott: She saw some kids in her class up to mischief.
Scott: She was not technologically literate.
Scott: So she said some things and you know from her, you know Understanding or whatever.
Scott: and then she learned a lesson that oh my god Linux open source.
Rym: I didn't know but The the point.
Rym: I want him.
Rym: I don't want to talk about the article I don't want to talk about the oh my god, the internet overreacted.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh shit but this brings up a lot of really important issues that we have all as technologists run into and first off the fact that if you're in school and the authority figures that are Responsible for your education appear to know less about the things you know about than you You are not going to respect them.
Rym: and one of them one of the biggest problems I've seen Among smart kids especially kids who were smart in technology in schools in public high schools in public middle schools Is that because of the curriculum and because you'll often have teachers who while they are very knowledgeable in their subjects or whatever At the same time they are completely Unknowledgeable in the things that the students are knowledgeable about?
Rym: it's very easy for teachers to lose all Respect and in fact gain the contempt of the best and brightest students in their classes Simply by the fact that on the surface they appear to be completely ignorant and illiterate.
Rym: effectively.
Scott: Yeah, I mean back and that you've always had a problem of students disrespecting teachers.
Scott: This is nothing new.
Scott: and students thinking they're smarter than teachers.
Scott: That is nothing new either, right?
Rym: I'm sure you all think you're smarter than your teachers.
Rym: Yes, I did too.
Rym: The only difference between you and me and that I was right.
Scott: But Nowadays right you have this compounding problem of the kids basically live in a completely separate world.
Scott: Then the teachers do except for the very young teachers, you know It's like these are I mean like in the 50s even in like when I was in school, right me and my teachers.
Scott: We lived in the same world.
Scott: We had you know, it's like we understood.
Scott: everything was sort of an even understanding.
Scott: I might have known about more than them in computers, but it's like they knew more about George, Washington.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, there weren't like this huge gap between the generations, right?
Scott: but now there's always a generation gap, but now the generation gap is Ginormous.
Rym: I mean look here's here's an example.
Rym: when I was in high school.
Rym: I watched the Simpsons when it was on TV.
Rym: I watched it as it came out on TV.
Rym: All my friends watched it and all my teachers watched it.
Rym: Yeah, so we there like we all knew there was a common shared culture.
Rym: But now a kid in high school now, he he watches like a YouTube poop and that is what he is into.
Rym: The teacher doesn't know it doesn't even know what that is.
Rym: Yeah, they wouldn't even understand it if you showed it to him.
Scott: I mean like think about think about this right in the 50s.
Scott: You'd have a problem, right?
Scott: The problem would be kids got a playboy in class, right?
Scott: But the teacher understands Playboy magazine, right?
Scott: Understand the student.
Scott: the student understands Playboy magazine.
Scott: They have a common understanding and they and they know shit.
Scott: I better hide this shit from the teacher and shit you in trouble mister, right?
Scott: There was this common understanding even if there was a lack of respect or a generation gap.
Scott: nowadays There is actually that it's difficult to communicate because the gap has widened.
Scott: something that has always been a problem is now a Tremendous problem.
Scott: the teacher sees a student like, you know Doesn't understand that Wikipedia is actually kind of good kind of bad kind of not in between, you know I mean like.
Scott: how long was it?
Scott: Like don't cite any websites in your paper because it's not it's like dude It's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: that's not how the world works anymore.
Scott: Yeah, just cuz it's in a book versus a website.
Scott: There's nothing inherent about the medium that says this is right.
Scott: This is wrong.
Scott: All right, you know, it's just so huge.
Scott: My problems like this will happen now.
Rym: I don't think this is the fact that part of the gap is just the.
Rym: the fact that the modern world requires Technological literacy.
Rym: and yet be a lot of teachers and people who are in positions of authority over children Do not have technological literacy and while they can still get about their lives and while they are extremely Knows about fucking history never used a computer.
Rym: He knows the Peloponnesian Wars He will go to great lengths of explaining about themistically is in democracy And I'll write you a hundred page book about it on his typewriter.
Rym: But maybe you know, he's never.
Rym: he doesn't use a computer and you see this a lot.
Rym: There are teachers that don't use computers.
Rym: They don't really understand them.
Rym: There's that recent South Park or butters was a vampire where mr.
Rym: Garrison's at the front like now click on the Thing.
Scott: Oh, that was the perfect illustration.
Scott: What's going on?
Scott: Every single student's playing like.
Scott: so I'm like it was one of those, you know FPS war games like the Call of Duty's or something like one of those.
Scott: Yeah, right and mr.
Scott: Garrison's like.
Scott: No, I know.
Rym: But the student who I mean imagine it.
Rym: It's the equivalent of in the 1900s where I'm in school and my teacher is illiterate and yet I know how to read.
Rym: And that is the way someone who's technologically illiterate comes across to a young student in a school.
Rym: They see a teacher who has trouble making PowerPoint go and they they look at that teacher as though that teacher is completely illiterate.
Scott: Yep So I remember this actually reminds me of some time when I was at RIT.
Scott: I was taking this computer security class.
Scott: It was a pretty cool class, you know with this cool guy.
Scott: I won't get into that now.
Scott: But you know there was some time in the class is spent talking about open source and such right and there was a person in The class.
Scott: it was an older woman, you know, she wasn't like a college student age.
Scott: She was someone who went back to college which is totally cool.
Scott: But you know, she didn't really understand the open source.
Scott: She was like why why would you make something and then that was so great and then give it away for free?
Scott: You could you could make money.
Scott: I just don't get it Right and I bet at the time what I said was because we're not assholes, right but upon later thinking about it Here's here's the correct answer to this question right of why would you do open source and such, you know?
Scott: Because people just don't understand it and that's one of the fundamental miss.
Scott: it's just misunderstanding.
Scott: this lady had right.
Scott: why?
Scott: No, software is free.
Scott: who would possibly create something for free.
Scott: That's that doesn't make any sense, right?
Scott: Here's the answer to that question and it ties into what we were just talking about the illiteracy, right?
Scott: Okay, we talked about why would you do something if you weren't getting compensated for it?
Scott: Well, if you actually saw like a hobbling old lady who is sick, you know, not a homeless lady But just a regular, you know who is you know, sick and crazy And you give her an Ubuntu CD.
Scott: No, no, and she's actually having a problem, you know.
Scott: Let's say an old lady like falls over in the street.
Scott: Yeah, are you gonna require conversation to call 9-1-1 and you know help her out and such?
Scott: No, you just do it, right?
Scott: Well from a technological person looking at most of the world, right?
Scott: Everyone is old ladies falling over in the street with heart attacks.
Scott: That's how stupid the vast majority people are when it comes technology.
Scott: So open source is Calling 9-1-1 for the old ladies.
Scott: We're doing it for free because you were fucking going to die because you understand this shit.
Scott: You're that stupid You're that screwed.
Scott: So the read, you know It's like why could we charge you to call the ambulance and rescue you from your insane technological stupidity?
Scott: I think that's what open source is.
Rym: But there's another factor there with open source the fact that I don't think a lot of people in previous generations other than of course people are hip to technology and Really have understood the fact that in the modern world many hobbies while they're hobbies And they're enjoyable to the people doing them produce valuable fruitful works.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like in the olden days I mean there were a few hobbies that produced few fruitful works like ham radio sort of produced fruitful works.
Scott: And I guess you know some people like photographers and that's produced.
Rym: Some people think of hobbies like.
Rym: they think making a ship in the bottle and that doesn't help anyone Anyone except your mantle, but I guess nowadays like kids today our ship in a bottle is the YouTube poop Which I guess doesn't add anything to society either.
Rym: or.
Scott: but some people ship in a bottle is like, you know me foes Which is a software program that allows you know Banks in all sorts of you know poverty stricken places to manage micro load
Rym: or say GeekNights Which provides entertainment to at least dozens of people
Scott: at least
Rym: dozens
Scott: Dozens of possible human beings.
Rym: I always like how it's all politics.
Rym: I mean they're very widely listened to but they all whenever they talk about the listener They always refer to the listener, and I hope the listener enjoys the show.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, I'd steal that if it wasn't stealing.
Rym: Yes like we got a letter from the listener today So they ever named the listener now.
Scott: It's always the same one.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Oh, that's great.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: I like that show.
Scott: Let's move on.
Rym: Anyway things of the day.
Rym: was that okay?
Rym: Should I say it that way?
Scott: should I say it to consider ever you want because it's whatever all right check this out.
Scott: MSI which is a motherboard maker mostly.
Scott: But they are they're making netbooks now like most people are and they got this one called the MSI wind.
Scott: Pretty popular pretty popular the MSI wind.
Scott: right.
Scott: apparently the MSI wind is Almost exactly identical to a Mac.
Scott: You know hardware wise you know it comes running XP or Linux or whatever.
Scott: Right now it was missing something though.
Scott: They didn't have the driver for the wireless.
Scott: so if you installed the OXX on it, right You know you just need a little hacked version of OS X and you're good to go, but You didn't need any hardware mods or any firmware updates or anything like that.
Scott: all you needed was a hacked version of the OS X Software on a DVD and you're good to go.
Scott: right the problem was that there was no driver for the wireless, right?
Scott: So you wouldn't be able to do any wireless if you saw the OS X. otherwise it'd be just fine.
Scott: There was a. there was a little leak.
Scott: well will possibly almost guaranteed intentional leak with a wink wink from the MSI people.
Scott: So now you can install OS X and the MSI wind.
Scott: oh snap And that's that's.
Scott: that's my thing of the day.
Scott: cuz that's just so awesome that there was one of those wink wink leaks.
Scott: Yeah, intentionally releasing the Wi-Fi The drivers.
Scott: you know I can install OS X on a non Mac because the thing is having OS X for like a TV PC plus.
Scott: you're not gonna be paying for this copy OS X. you're gonna get a hacked one.
Rym: Yeah, but like right now we have we have the oldest slowest like the very first Mac mini like the first one.
Scott: Oh, we have the very first Intel one.
Rym: I'm going to consider that the very first Mac.
Rym: There was a g4 one Yes, but that does not count right, but anyway It's old and slow, but for being a TV PC.
Rym: It's fantastic.
Scott: That's okay.
Scott: It's not perfect No, it's not, but while we lose a few things like easy emulation It'd be better if you had an HD TV would be better but that is that's true for any plugged into the.
Rym: I could perhaps foresee buying one of these motherboards and taking the OS X we have hacking it and Putting it on the second TV in the house.
Scott: Oh, you would need the newer OS X the one that we don't have.
Scott: ah crap Yeah, because you have the tiger we would need the leopard which is one newer.
Scott: Yeah, I would actually consider, you know, if we had a new house and whatever, you know first we need to get newer TV.
Rym: God, yes, but I'll be I'm done with CRT.
Scott: CRT's belong in basements Yeah, but they belong in the trash.
Scott: But anyway after we're after we're done with that I could foresee eventually buying like, you know If they ever come out with a newer Mac mini we just get like the newer better one that way like, you know Wouldn't have trouble like Decoding videos sometimes
Rym: because the the benefits of having like Linux or building it ourselves are somewhat mitigated by the fact that
Scott: you get that little remote control
Rym: and the fact that the 99%
Scott: of the time all you want to do is watch a video.
Scott: and even though we can't run an emulator on it very easily Who cares?
Rym: plus this the guys?
Rym: The fact that that thing is a tiny silent box.
Scott: Yeah a lot.
Scott: It's like I could go and build the most amazing like, you know Home theater PC HD PC, but it would be loud.
Rym: Yeah, even if you like you water cool like you went the craziness it still have that little And it's big.
Scott: So the smallness and the quietness and the limited functionality of the Mac Mini is worth it because it still achieves 99% of the functionality we want even though it's not a hundred percent.
Scott: and It you know that quietness and smallness outweighs the lack of functionality.
Rym: So so I'm going to teach you all a word and I hope that you will start using.
Scott: I think we've discussed this on GeekNights before we may have.
Rym: it might have been a long time ago And there's definitely a wicked long time.
Scott: It was pretty interesting.
Rym: But just so you all are aware I'd forgotten about this word.
Rym: But today I was setting up some Apache stuff at work and I had a reference because I don't have all the Apache Directives and things memorized.
Scott: No one does.
Rym: I was Maybe one person does.
Rym: no, there's something.
Rym: there's got to be some guy whose whole life is a patch.
Rym: He's like the Rain Man.
Scott: No, even though even like the Apache Foundation people don't fucking know.
Rym: No, not those people, but there's got to be an Apache Rain Man.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: anyway long story short One way to refer to the hash sign or the pound sign is the Octo Thorpe.
Scott: Yep See I knew there was a word.
Scott: Octo Thorpe and Rym said it and I go I've heard that word and then it say he's Like.
Scott: oh, it's the pound sign.
Scott: I'm like, oh I knew that it's like, you know hate it when you know something But you can't recall it at the moment.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: You knew it, but you couldn't come up with a pointer in the leaves.
Rym: You know it.
Rym: the pointer in the relational database that is your brain is pointing that like it's.
Rym: there's a pointer pointing at it But you can't find that pointer.
Rym: you find all these other pointers that get close, but there's like a link missing and You know.
Rym: that happens when you're trying to remember something and like you're thinking like, you know, you know it but you don't know What's the word.
Scott: and then as soon as you're reminded suddenly you're like, oh I did know that but there's no way to prove You're like you could be lying.
Scott: Dr.
Rym: Pachto Octo Thorpe.
Rym: like it comes suddenly when you get to the right pointer, but yeah This is an article talking about the etymology of the word Octo Thorpe and all the different theories of where it really came from.
Rym: if you're a tech or You listen to GeekNights.
Rym: They're the kind of person who would like to have an affected way of saying Octo Thorpe.
Rym: To give a little quote just you you know, see where this article is going.
Rym: He says that it was a joke term originally Octo Thorpe Invented by two friends John C Shaq and Hubert T Outhlaut Who deliberately included the th sound.
Rym: knowing that it would be difficult for speakers of certain languages to say No, they then went on to quietly introduce it into various documents until it was too late to retract it.
Scott: Let's see about that.
Rym: Yeah, the articles fun and hopefully we'll get some affectations going here.
Scott: affectations are good All right, so today we decided we were having a hard time coming to the tech topic But I thought it might be interesting to talk about.
Scott: you know The the ebooks the e-paper ebook readers that sort of thing, right?
Rym: Especially because today I carried a very heavy and large book to work and then home from work And I didn't even have my bag.
Rym: and let me tell you I'm getting real sick of carrying gigantic books around and then spilling things on.
Scott: I think my strategy right now is I'm not gonna buy any more Non comic books that are on dead tree, right?
Scott: And then when I finish all the ones I've got that are on dead tree Then I will go and buy the Kindle 2 or whatever it is and then go for that because you know what my one of the Major things I've been had about the Kindle that I don't like is that the selection is not as strong as it is with the dead Tree, right, you know you can get any book on dead tree, but you can't get any book on Kindle.
Scott: But you know what.
Scott: you can get enough books on Kindle more than you're gonna read in your whole life.
Scott: So does it really matter?
Scott: does it really?
Scott: So I think that's my plan.
Scott: But even though that's my plan.
Scott: It's not everyone's plan and I think people, you know, they have a hard time, you know sort of understanding.
Scott: what sort of holding Ebooks back what's holding e-paper back?
Scott: Why is the Kindle the way it is?
Scott: Why isn't it there yet?
Scott: You know, why is all this other technology like crazy?
Scott: Why can we do a 3d game, but we can't do a freaking ebook?
Scott: It should be the simplest thing.
Scott: It's just text, right?
Rym: Well, the short answer is displays Batteries.
Scott: Yeah, the RN let let's talk about the displays, right?
Scott: Unlike, you know your LCD screen on your computer an e-book reader has, you know different needs, right?
Scott: I mean, it's only displaying text hopefully and only.
Scott: you know, we'd like to get more colors But right now we can't even get black and white.
Scott: So let's just stick with that for now.
Rym: Yeah, well, I mean in the long run what like?
Rym: I'm reading this book on advanced skiing techniques And it consists half of text and half of pictures of guys doing the ski techniques and showing how to do them.
Scott: Yeah, so that really wouldn't work out on the Kindle.
Rym: Yeah, no Kindle for that.
Scott: But you know for most books like a sci-fi novel.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: it's just text right and even if there's a few illustrations They're mostly black and white.
Scott: Anyway, it's a pain.
Scott: It's a you know, mass-market trade paperback.
Scott: You're all good Right and you could do those right?
Scott: So you it's not anyway, but In the long run new on color right now black and white.
Scott: why can't we make a black and white screen?
Scott: That's good.
Scott: Number one.
Scott: We need to make a screen that doesn't hurt.
Scott: when you look at it for a long time You look at a book for a long time.
Scott: If you look at an even a good LCD look at it for a long time.
Scott: It's bright It's shining light at you and it you get some eye strains, you know, it's.
Rym: it's tricky business because you want to.
Rym: One philosophy is to emulate as much as possible what actual printed paper looks like because you have been reading that for a long time and I think that's the best way to Go right now because it'll if we perfect that we'll get to an acceptable point.
Rym: but at the same time We really need to go beyond that because the printed paper while it's great for a lot of things at the same time It does have its limitations Can't read in the dark.
Scott: Yeah, I was just gonna say all right, you can't read printed paper in the dark.
Scott: Well, okay, so we don't need the light behind the screen anymore because you can't read the Kindle in the dark either.
Scott: We'll make it sort of like the original GBA screen where the light came from outside and bounced off.
Rym: But now do you want to have a book light on your Kindle?
Scott: Yeah I mean seriously a book light on the Kindle.
Scott: Is that really necessary?
Scott: You could have a switch that turns on a light behind the screen.
Scott: that could work But even then that drains the batteries.
Scott: no light.
Rym: be also light behind the screen.
Rym: Lightning the light The background behind the text is going to increase the eye string.
Rym: cuz now again You've got this direct.
Scott: Well, it can be like the ever see those Timex watches.
Scott: you push the button.
Scott: It sort of has this greenish light.
Rym: that doesn't you know, it's pretty cool You do something like that, but at the same time that color might be really fatiguing in the long run.
Scott: It could be.
Scott: it really you gotta really you got to figure these things out that I.
Rym: this is a part where we need to Do a lot of like just research of you know testing humans and looking at their physiological reactions to reading things.
Scott: So LCD screens right as we have them for our computers and TVs and whatnot.
Scott: and plasmas also use too much electricity.
Scott: they're too bright and You know, they're actually too thick.
Scott: I mean an e-book.
Scott: readers got to be small or else.
Scott: What's the point?
Scott: I might as well carry the freaking book, you know, it's got to be small and light and last a long time.
Scott: Otherwise, I'm just gonna take the book with me.
Scott: There's no point right plus.
Scott: I also got to be cheap.
Rym: and I mean look at the display.
Rym: Part of the problem with LCDs and the technology we have is that they constantly have to be refreshed.
Rym: There's a refresh rate and unless your refresh rate is super high, even if you can't physically see it It causes eye strain eventually.
Scott: Yeah I mean look your computer monitor most likely is completely redrawing itself as in blank.
Scott: Draw everything again like 75 times a second, you know, it's it's constantly redrawing itself, right?
Scott: And that's you know, that's not when you talk about like FPS in games.
Scott: You think about vertical sync, right?
Scott: So it's like if you have a you're playing counter-strike and your monitor is 75 Hertz.
Scott: it redraws itself 75 times a second.
Scott: What's the point of having counter-strike do 100 FPS?
Scott: You're only seeing 75 of them.
Scott: So vertical sync says hey counter-strike Yeah, just make 75 FPS and I'll see all the 75 and it'll be locked in, you know, and it'll be totally cool.
Scott: That's a vertical sync.
Scott: is now if I'm reading a book if you refresh the screen at all Even if it's really fast, right number one that's using electricity to you know redraw and I'm usually looking at one Unmoving thing for a long time a page.
Scott: It's not like a game where it's moving all over the place.
Rym: It's actually a page of text very specifically because this is you know It's.
Rym: not only is it one unmoving thing?
Rym: But the biggest deal-breaker in the world for me and I feel like this Even if people haven't thought of it is the biggest deal-breaker for anyone.
Rym: there can't be any scrolling No, right or up down.
Rym: scrolling as opposed to page flipping is perhaps because even if people like especially people who are used to Reading books.
Rym: I feel like they're like I can read long documents on my monitor because I'm kind of used to it.
Rym: But if you're not used to that Have it.
Rym: scrolling and having text move and your eyes following it is gonna tire you out so quick.
Scott: Yeah, most of the things just flip pages, you know, they don't really.
Rym: I've never seen an e-book reader with scrolling But I see people having to zoom in and scroll just because or zoom in and then flip pages more often.
Rym: But that's just the side effect that a lot of people's eyes are really bad and they can't read the smaller fonts.
Scott: Yeah, handling fonts.
Scott: That's a software issue though.
Scott: That's not the hardware issue.
Scott: Yeah, but it is an issue.
Rym: Yep And but the display has to be high enough resolution to support a reasonable amount of text on page.
Rym: also big enough size to where?
Rym: I can turn the pages at a reasonable pace without scrolling or without having to turn the page constantly That's true.
Scott: If you have insufficient resolution, you know, you're gonna have to either move the text around or something.
Rym: It's also insufficient resolution means less capability for anti aliasing and all those things that make you look good.
Scott: Yeah, better looking fonts makes it a lot easier to read.
Scott: I mean you ever look at like.
Scott: I mean, I'm not gonna lie here right you look at a computer running OS X. Right, all the fonts look really great and all like.
Scott: the windows are really smooth.
Scott: It's not anything the Mac does in the hardware.
Scott: It's just got the same Nvidia chips.
Scott: Everything else has.
Scott: it's not anything special at the monitor.
Scott: They're just LCD monitors, right?
Scott: It's the rendering algorithms They use.
Scott: right.
Scott: everything you see in OS X is actually based on postscript or PDF or something similar to that.
Scott: you know the rendering system and Steve Jobs is always super anal about font rendering and all that shit and that's why everything's super smooth.
Scott: If you VNC to a Mac and on your PC everything in the Mac window will be super smooth All right, so and it makes you know, there's no lie It makes things a lot easier to read and it's a lot more comfortable.
Scott: and it does make you know Good typography makes a significant difference.
Scott: So you need a high resolution screen to get that on the e-book You know to to really make it a much more enjoyable thing and not have you go.
Scott: I fuck this.
Scott: I'm reading a paper book All right, so we got a. you know, you got to have a screen that when you push the button right now.
Scott: I just said we don't want the refresh rate, right?
Scott: We want the screen to not refresh right when you're just looking at one page.
Scott: that way it doesn't use any battery when you're looking at one page not doing anything and You're not gonna hurt your eyes because the screens redrawing itself.
Scott: But when I push the button to go to next page the next page has to be there instantly.
Scott: So it's like you need a really quick redrawing.
Scott: Otherwise the page would be like I'm turning the page.
Scott: Okay, you know you need to have it like click new page immediately.
Scott: So it's gonna have a quick refresh but has to not do it unless you push the button.
Scott: That's very very tricky.
Scott: We can't seem to manage that now.
Rym: Of course in terms of just other hardware and this is tied into the display because a lot of display technology either uses a lot of power or sucks.
Rym: Batteries also still suck.
Rym: Yes things gotta last an entire transatlantic flight without me having to swap batteries.
Scott: Exactly, I mean even swap or recharge or anything like that, you know, I mean Basically, I don't want to.
Scott: you know, if they want this is like there's a power outage, right?
Scott: I can read a book with like a candle or some shit, right but My Kindle runs out of batteries in the power outage.
Scott: It's not good.
Scott: Now I'm bookless so The battery's got to last a long time and as you know people, you know There's always advances in battery technology getting more electricity per battery and less less weight in the battery and and all this stuff less expensive.
Scott: but People seem to forget and you know Rym points aside all the time.
Rym: to is one of my favorite things to point out But I'll let you do it this time.
Scott: Yeah, is that a battery?
Scott: is energy in a brick basically?
Scott: or energy in a tube or something like that?
Rym: It's a controlled hand grenade.
Scott: Yes, if you want a battery that lasts longer laws of physics get in your way.
Scott: You have to.
Scott: you have to put more energy in a smaller space.
Scott: if you want it to be lighter and last longer and Etc.
Scott: You're gonna need to be more energy and less space.
Scott: more energy and less space means explode II right?
Scott: There's no way around this.
Scott: It's the laws of physics.
Scott: There's no way you can put a whole shit ton of energy in a very small space then, you know and not have it be dangerous It's gonna have.
Scott: it's no way around that and in a lot of ways that is holding us back.
Scott: There are in existence Batteries that are really freaking great.
Scott: They're just fucking really dangerous.
Scott: And that's why you don't have them in your laptop.
Rym: I Don't I'd be willing to accept.
Rym: actually personally I'm willing to accept the danger and even the way.
Scott: the danger isn't even like you Gonna hurt yourself with the mean.
Scott: we're already having problems like cell phone setting on fire Turns it into a bomb.
Scott: right that there's no danger to just if you use it normally and appropriately.
Scott: The danger is only if you're stupid or if you buy a poorly made Chinese junk battery and it sets on fire at the gas station.
Scott: There's no danger in.
Scott: you know, a well-made battery being used normally at all No, but you know, even if you put a lot of energy in there I guess too much energy could be a problem, but we could work that out.
Scott: That's a solvable problem.
Rym: even more I'm getting the point where size matters to me more than weight and I would actually be willing to accept a Very much more heavy small laptop or a very much more heavy Kindle If the battery just lasted twice as long.
Rym: like add a couple pounds to it, but make it dense.
Scott: Yeah, just if it's.
Scott: if it's.
Scott: you know, it doesn't.
Scott: I mean I already I put two batteries in my laptop.
Scott: that ain't significant.
Scott: That's pretty much all the weight.
Scott: if I take both batteries out It weighs almost nothing like like.
Scott: it weighs like maybe the weight of two pieces of paper.
Scott: It's that light.
Scott: the batteries are all the weight.
Scott: So Really if I'm putting two batteries if I'm putting two batteries in it, I'll put two heavier batteries in it.
Scott: It's still the same size You know, it's not any bigger.
Scott: It's just more battery life and like an extra pound or two, whatever It's not gonna hurt my shoulder.
Scott: It's already light enough.
Scott: big big deal.
Scott: Go for it.
Scott: No, actually, I guess like 10 pounds would bother me or five but not one.
Rym: but it would be like Dragon Ball.
Rym: It trains you it makes you strong.
Scott: Oh, yes my shoulder great.
Rym: Yeah, you'll have one big beefy shoulder.
Scott: Yeah But I was a big beefy lap.
Rym: I guess the third point like in terms of DRM honestly that is not as much of a concern to me as you'd think because a Lot of the things I want to read.
Rym: one of the reasons I want a device like this is that more and more there are long textual things Online that are free that I want to read at my leisure.
Rym: Yeah, like project Gutenberg, but I don't want to read them On my monitor.
Scott: Yeah project Gutenberg has like all these files I want to read but to read them on my monitor is painful, especially when they're too long.
Scott: I mean or plus.
Rym: I want to read them on the trains.
Rym: All right, I copy them to my laptop.
Rym: I got all these text files on my laptop.
Scott: I got to remember my spot, you know Even if I have a program that's made to help me read project Gutenberg files, you know.
Scott: And I turned down the brightness on the monitor and I'll adjust all that.
Scott: It's still not good enough.
Scott: I still have to scroll, you know, it's just it's not gonna work out.
Rym: But honestly, I'm willing to think it's too much money and I'm willing to pay what I pay for a paperback book for a DRM DB book.
Scott: see that's just the thing right?
Scott: It's weird because it's like I'm not willing to pay for Music, even though the digital music is cheap and DRM free but somehow I'm willing to pay for the digital book.
Rym: You know why.
Rym: what a reason I think is that with music they still haven't done what I want them to do.
Rym: Which is the you want?
Rym: every song the Beatles ever did organized hundred bucks fifty bucks.
Scott: Yeah, I think I think that's really what it is.
Scott: Is that Everything I buy in some way, you know, that's that's like media.
Scott: right is a lot.
Scott: for a little I buy a DVD Box set 30 bucks all of cowboy bebop, right?
Scott: I don't buy like some single DVD junk anymore, right?
Scott: Very rarely, I guess once in a blue moon, right?
Scott: I don't buy no, you know, like Comic book for four dollars.
Scott: I buy like, you know the omnibus.
Scott: It's like 20 bucks for like 30 comics, you know, and that's that's the way to get money for stuff these days.
Scott: So music they're not selling.
Scott: every song Beatles have ever done with the correct id3 tags in high quality For 20 bucks, they're selling one song for a dollar.
Rym: It's not even just that even if it's DRM free.
Scott: fuck that.
Rym: It's not even just the deal the Scott Johnson syndrome.
Rym: for me It's very simply the metadata is worth more to me than the data.
Rym: I can get the data for free.
Rym: I can pirate anything I want from anywhere at any time.
Rym: That's not the concern.
Rym: It's trivial for me to get any music I want.
Rym: What I want is the metadata and I'm willing to pay a lot for the metadata.
Scott: Yeah, why?
Scott: if the music is organized and is high quality and I don't have to sit there sorting it that's worth money.
Scott: I have so many unsorted mp3s and actually the fact that they are so disorganized is Preventing me from listening to a lot of download torrents.
Rym: like a while ago I downloaded a torrent of every rom Stein song ever including like Thousands of bootleg recordings from live concerts.
Rym: Yep, and you know what it is Practically useless to me in the form that I have it because it's so unorganized.
Rym: You can't figure out what to listen to what's what or even if it is organized It's always organized differently and in to make it conform to the way I already organized my music is impossible.
Scott: Yeah It's like this guy organizes his stuff by genre artist album and this guy Organizes by just artist album no genre.
Scott: and this guy does like, you know Just albums and this guy does like, you know by year and then by album.
Rym: This way even though I don't like iTunes very much.
Rym: Like I really don't like it just in general if Whoever offers what I want first will get my money.
Rym: if Apple was like, hey, we're doing this now.
Rym: You want every rock mononoff piano concerto ever performed by like these five people.
Rym: hundred bucks.
Rym: I will probably give more money to Apple than you could possibly.
Scott: I mean if someone actually did this I would pretty much sit for like an hour making a list of all the artists That I wanted and then go buy the complete collection of every single artist Even if it was like two thousand dollars or something like that.
Scott: and I'd be like.
Scott: and then I delete every mp3.
Scott: I had just boop gone.
Rym: Well, well, I would keep as long as I wear this I can Simultaneously, oh my god, I got to start distributing that mp3.
Scott: Yeah, you know any any any mp3 that was you know a record label whatever, you know.
Scott: But yeah with books, right?
Scott: I'm buying books now.
Scott: So as far as I'm concerned right now books are a good deal.
Scott: You got a whole shit ton of pages a big freaking book full of words, right and they're relatively cheap.
Scott: It's like five maybe bucks for a book on Amazon, right?
Scott: Yeah, and you get a whole book.
Scott: It's like hours and hours and hours of reading and it's high quality.
Scott: right on the Kindle The books are like one dollar and it's just as much reading Plus.
Rym: I actually really look forward to the kind of the rise of digital publishing of books because There is a barrier to entry to the mass market to small-time authors because getting a wide publication deal is very expensive.
Rym: publishing online with a DRM thing Cost you nothing.
Scott: Yeah me think about how many people.
Scott: you have written novels, right?
Scott: And then no publisher would say yes to them.
Scott: Most likely their book is crap, right, but even though their book is crap It might be the one that you like, you know, it's like there are only ten people in the world who would enjoy this book.
Scott: We're not publishing it.
Scott: Well, what if you're one of those ten people?
Scott: Well, if that guy puts that book out as an e-book and you got an e-reader hot damn You're gonna get that book and it's gonna be awesome.
Rym: when we get to the point where?
Rym: Someone publishes their book and then the technic or dutifully buys exactly one copy Yeah, yeah, I just this whole time I've been thinking about Martin Solanas and his books.
Scott: But yeah, think about you know, something like audible also right which has the DRM.
Scott: Why don't I do audible?
Scott: Well, number one, I don't.
Scott: I don't enjoy the audiobooks as much as the paper books.
Rym: I don't very specific circumstance.
Rym: Yes they gotta get the right person reading it and it has to be a book that does not benefit from the Phrasing and like the literary the word part on the page.
Rym: Yep as opposed to the idea part.
Scott: That also also.
Scott: I think that you know.
Scott: reading on the page is a more Significant intellectual activity that works the brain in a far better and different way than listening.
Rym: Well, my primary use for audiobooks are when I'm driving.
Scott: Yeah, but I just use podcasts for that and I don't need an audiobook.
Scott: But even if I didn't need an audiobook, right?
Scott: I'd say I had no podcast and I want it.
Scott: I was had a drive a commute, you know.
Scott: That would be a good reason to get an audiobook.
Scott: Why don't I do audible even without the DRM excuse of not doing audible?
Scott: there is so expensive.
Scott: it's like $15 for a book on audible For like five bucks.
Scott: I can just get the book.
Scott: I can get three books to the price of one audio, but you're not paying for the book.
Rym: You're paying for like James Earl Jones to read it to you.
Scott: Yeah, but I you know, it's as far as I'm concerned though.
Scott: It's the same, you know, it's the same thing.
Scott: You're not gonna do read the book and listen to the audiobook.
Scott: So why it's like?
Scott: why would I do that?
Scott: There's no reason to Unless James Earl Jones came to my house and read it.
Scott: That would that would be okay.
Rym: I think Cook me a little dinner.
Rym: I don't know if someone comes over to my house and reads to me.
Rym: I kind of want them to cook for me, too.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Scott: I'll read to you.
Scott: Will you cook for me?
Rym: But I mean there are things.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about the Kindle itself, but There are a lot of little things that I want that aren't necessarily deal-breakers like for one.
Rym: I want the ability to.
Rym: I want it to be a touchscreen so I can take a little stylus or something is built into it and Highlight a bunch of text and hit a button and it saves that text with an MLA and APA Citation and then we'll send it over the internet to my computer.
Rym: That'd be pretty cool uploaded somewhere.
Scott: That's a real good one.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: that that is something I've wanted for most of my life.
Scott: man If you did that the researchers would be like and students would be all over that You could just put all the textbooks on there.
Rym: The ripoff college textbook, I remember what like the biggest paper I ever wrote at RIT was this long like treatise on political communication.
Rym: There was like 15 pages.
Scott: You should have written a paper about citations with many citations in it.
Rym: The paper was 15 pages long.
Rym: It took me two hours to properly format and double-check all my citations.
Rym: I could have written like a five page paper in that time.
Scott: Yeah, I know right?
Rym: I Want the Kindle to be able to do that.
Rym: plus I realize how much more often I would quote things And they're people set up like delicious like things or they would share quotations.
Scott: Why don't we make a Firefox plug-in that does citations?
Rym: Let's do that.
Rym: That's really easy to make.
Rym: Yeah, that's really easy.
Rym: No, not just that though.
Rym: You need to have a server where you can share citations and tag them.
Scott: Oh Oh wait, I found something.
Scott: tations and quotes though.
Scott: Itro is easy to use Firefox extension.
Scott: How do you collect manage and cite your research sources?
Scott: It lives right where you do your work in the web browser itself.
Rym: I will check it out.
Rym: However, the Kindle needs to do that or I'm not that interested.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh something exists.
Scott: Someone beat us to it.
Scott: I wonder if it's good.
Rym: Yeah, I'm kind of dubious.
Rym: I feel like we could do it better whatever it is, but I don't know.
Rym: I'll check it out.
Scott: Yeah, it's got screencast.
Scott: We'll be all right.
Scott: Yeah, it's also looking free and cool anyway.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: also, you know like the user interface on these thing I mean the Kindle's got it right with the directly downloading wherever you are as long as this Wi-Fi going on Apple Taking take note.
Scott: Yeah Podcasts downloading a little weak actually Sony, you know Sony's ebook reader supposedly has a better screen.
Scott: the Kindle and I think that is true.
Scott: But also Sony's got a new like Walkman that actually does the podcast.
Scott: downloading properly doesn't have much else going for it.
Scott: It needs to be a phone.
Scott: But you know, they.
Scott: finally there is a device at the proper podcast support.
Scott: Hooray Took long enough.
Rym: I mean beyond that there's a lot of little things.
Rym: That would be cool Like some you know, Netflix has the.
Rym: you rate things you read and you can recommend things to other people.
Rym: I'd like a built-in network for that like the Kindle could.
Scott: probably Amazon reviews are on there.
Rym: Yeah but I use the Kindle and I feel like it could be done in a better way to encourage people to Review books quickly and recommend books to their friends and you could subscribe to the right.
Scott: Amazon reviews is not as slick as Netflix with their reviewing and recommending and sharing and suggesting plus that Amazon mostly Amazon suggestion engine is more because remember Netflix doesn't care about which ones you pick.
Scott: they get your money anyway.
Scott: Right, so they want you to help find things that you'll like that way.
Scott: You'll stay subscribed.
Scott: Amazon Right wants you to buy shit.
Scott: So there's subscription.
Scott: their recommender is trying to find things that you are likely to buy Not things that your friends like or things like that, you know, because that's not gonna make you buy more.
Scott: well, it might but you know Have we exhausted this topic possibly?
Rym: All right My plan is I'm probably gonna wait and wait until the Kindle 2 is out and I can hold one.
Scott: I hope they make sort of like a Kindle mini as in.
Scott: you know I pod many because I've always been more a fan of the mini nano type things than like the big ones, you know Like.
Scott: so if there was like I got a 4-inch screen like no like.
Scott: I want it to be the size right like the screen should be the size of a You know mass-market trade paperback, you know the runs they have.
Scott: now The page is almost as big as like the page in a normal hardcover book, you know, it's kind of big.
Scott: I'd rather have a smaller one, you know, that's like, you know, you know this size.
Scott: No one can see this Like, you know the size of like a piece of paper from the Hyperion book, you know That size is how big I want it to be that way.
Scott: I can just sort of toss it in.
Scott: You know, I mean the Kindle is pretty small, but you can go smaller people.
Rym: Of course, it has to be as indestructible as a Nintendo product.
Scott: Oh, of course I mean like books.
Scott: riggin beat the shit out of them all over the place and they they just keep keep on trucking.
Scott: Oh, that's another thing though Right is I?
Rym: the one thing with the DRM that does bother me can't just give books to other people when you're done with.
Rym: It's no secondary market.
Scott: You can't lend right?
Scott: I mean right now I buy a book.
Scott: everyone I know can read that book but with the DRM not so much.
Scott: so there needs to be something to do with that, right?
Scott: You know, I should be able to pass a book around.
Rym: Well, that's the problem with DRM.
Rym: is that companies realize that as there's so much media out there the second hand sale problem is becoming increasingly difficult to deal with because I Don't buy new books that often anymore because I'll go to like the strand which has every book I want to read ever for like four bucks
Scott: or more books than you can read ever.
Rym: Yeah, but any book I want that was written other than books that just came out today I can buy for like nothing at a used bookstore pretty handily yep, and video games books music.
Rym: everyone's having this problem and they're using the technological solution of digital distribution with DRM thus effectively.
Rym: in the end We're going to no longer have the right of first sale for any of our media And I don't know how I feel about that and I don't know what to do about it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that's really they're putting.
Scott: what they are doing is they're putting in danger Right the the continued existence of culture.
Scott: I mean like is.
Scott: a big problem is when you're researching old ancient shit, is that there are stone tablets?
Scott: They didn't really make it, you know, and their papyrus really fucking didn't make it, you know We don't had the papyrus and now we don't know about them.
Scott: right there needs.
Scott: well in the future Maybe our books will make it because we sort of put them in a safe place, you know.
Scott: Can we know how to preserve them?
Scott: and maybe some other things will make it?
Scott: DRM stuff ain't gonna make it to tomorrow if fucking someone turns the DRM server off.
Scott: So you're basically you put.
Scott: if you put some you know some song out into the world and the only form it's in is This DRM form.
Scott: that song might not be here It's gonna be lost.
Rym: make a requirement anything that will be distributed with digital rights management must be submitted to say the Library of Congress and Kept there in Such and then it will be released to the public the moment the copyright expires
Scott: in a non DRM way
Rym: Yes an archive there Otherwise forever and then
Scott: the Library of Congress should just put every single piece of material It has that is not copyrighted just online for free for everyone in the US.
Rym: Of course you realize.
Rym: what that will do is bring to full fruition the issue that I've been talking about for a long time that someday is going to destroy our current idea of the media market and the Competition of the past with the present.
Scott: Yep, if we actually that's the real I'm beginning to think that's the real reason.
Scott: They're extending copyright because it's not you know.
Scott: Oh, no Elvis will enter public domain and then we won't be able to make money off Elvis anymore.
Scott: It's oh shit.
Scott: All the books from the 50s are now free.
Scott: No one will have any reason to buy a new book because they can just read all the books from the 50s.
Scott: and now there Are enough books available and enough music available for free.
Scott: No one cares about new stuff anymore.
Scott: And then the 60s stuff will be free.
Scott: who cares?
Scott: They don't care that.
Scott: They mean they're making a lot of money on Beatles music.
Scott: But but it's a care more about the fact that oh shit now everyone just listens to Beatles music for free.
Scott: I remember.
Scott: no one cares about the new music it becomes.
Rym: It gets bigger and bigger because more media is created.
Rym: It keeps getting worse there.
Rym: Every day there will be more competition than there ever was before
Scott: Yep, so why is anyone gonna buy music ever all the music from the 80s and previously, you know as public as we go
Rym: on you say like look at movies that Modern move like someone might argue that modern movies do things that old movies couldn't do.
Rym: Yes, but all media hit a terminal point where the technology cannot make them better.
Rym: The only thing that can make them better is writing them better and in the longest term, you know If we go all as a movie in the final last question is that eventually everything will be written Statistically every combination typewriters.
Scott: Yes, Shakespeare comes out eventually.
Scott: So yeah, then, you know, what do you do when you know, let's say let's say copyright is we reduce it to 40 years Right.
Scott: So in 2040 right Everything every piece of artwork created in the 20th century will be free.
Rym: Which is why when our media than I could consume in my entire life if I dedicated my life to consuming media So why would anyone pay money for a 21st century piece of artwork?
Scott: when they could spend their entire life and be more than happy with everything ever from the 20th century for free?
Scott: and You know if they live to 2041 then all the stuff from the year 2000 will become free and if they live to 2042 Everything from 2001 will be free and so on and so forth.
Scott: So every year this year's worth of stuff will become free and without creating a new medium For artwork such as the feely's or something like that.
Rym: It's you got trouble now, I don't know what to do about that.
Rym: and that's not the topic of the show So I suppose we'll end it there.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta eat something.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.