Rym: It's Monday July 28th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk a bit about whether or not you were morally justified in stealing people's Wi-Fi.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: If you listen to last Thursday's show you know that us cooking dinner lately has been a rarity.
Scott: and since dinners in the oven right Now but it's only gonna be in there for like 10 minutes.
Scott: Let's record the news real quick so we can go down and eat it at the right time.
Rym: One thing about the whole dinner thing.
Rym: It's not so much that we don't cook dinner.
Rym: It's that Scott doesn't cook dinner.
Scott: Hey, I cook sometimes.
Rym: Yeah, you haven't cooked in a while not in a while.
Scott: No Cooking again in September.
Rym: most of these suggestions are They're not really that useful.
Scott: They're not things that we have not known about before.
Rym: yes It's more a matter of even those things take too much time Yeah, or they don't produce food that tastes good enough to be worth the time.
Rym: I mean sure I can cook a real quick meal of rice and something in like 10 minutes But I for all that I'd rather go hungry or just eat out.
Rym: yeah All right.
Scott: so check this out right.
Scott: there's been this big news today's.
Scott: oh my god There's a new search engine and compete with Google.
Rym: I think I have to redact that a little bit.
Scott: It doesn't eat with Google.
Rym: There's a search engine gasps.
Scott: There's been search engines since 1990.
Scott: God knows what.
Rym: of course It's funny how you think back through the early days of search engines, and it was like they all sucked.
Rym: well No, no, but the internet.
Rym: You know was barely usable without search engines.
Rym: They're all these kind of hacks But like one by one kind of like in Europe only at a much more accelerated pace one by one.
Rym: Every single search engine that was worth a damn would like Ascend to the top and then within three or four months be completely forgotten by the next one.
Scott: yep But anyway everyone's talking about.
Scott: the only reason this one's getting attention Alright is because it's written by ex Google people.
Scott: so they're like oh if these people left Google and made a new search engine Maybe it'll be better than Google.
Rym: wait left Google, or were fired by Google now.
Scott: They left Google.
Scott: I'm sure I'm pretty sure.
Scott: Uh-huh they were now.
Scott: I know that they were at Google at one point and no longer are with Google anyway.
Scott: So the search engine they made is called cool.
Scott: It's spelled c-u-i-l because they think they're so cool But they're not someone's shot.
Rym: actually noted something very important about cool But they made the critical mistake of branding a new product in that they named it something that you do not Automatically know how to pronounce.
Rym: yeah, Google is a stupid name, but you look at it, and you know exactly how to say yeah It's a typical marketing mistake, but that's not what kills them.
Scott: what kills them is this number one search results not so good.
Scott: All right.
Scott: number two the search results are look pretty interesting because they give you like them in columns with pictures And it's it's neat, but it's not helpful.
Scott: It's it's hard to skim that page to get the information quickly.
Scott: and the killer of cool the worst part about it the reason it Will not succeed it's slow.
Scott: the number one thing already sped up since this morning The only no Google is instant.
Scott: I push the button and BAM there it is.
Scott: if it's not that fast It's not worth point out.
Rym: I've been searching on this for the last few minutes, and it's been instant.
Scott: every time I clicked I wasn't instant this morning.
Rym: Yes, cuz everyone in the world was hitting it.
Scott: Yeah, well they need to be able to handle ahead everyone in the world hitting it.
Scott: You can't compete so that presents a problem.
Rym: I don't because if that is actually the case It'll be impossible for anyone to ever be Google.
Scott: I think it is.
Scott: until the world changes to where there's a new Paradigm besides the web search engine Google's gonna be the king.
Rym: here's the scary thing.
Rym: you know I was talking about all these different search Engines back in the day.
Rym: think of this.
Rym: I remember I used Yahoo for like Four or five months, and then I switched to Alta Vista because it was better.
Rym: for like six months.
Rym: Yeah, and then I went back to Google or not to Google.
Rym: I went back to Yahoo for another month or two And then I switched to Google and I've been using them for almost a decade.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I was that I remember I was using Yahoo But I didn't like it because it was just a directory and Alta Vista got all these pages.
Scott: And then I was like going a web crawler and you know like goes and Alta Vista And I was.
Scott: whenever I wanted to search for something I would like for a time I would go to every search engine seeing what came up.
Scott: You know the major ones at least Until eventually I would go to.
Scott: I went to Yahoo and Yahoo was working better than the others and at the bottom it said Powered by Google where it used to say powered by hotspot and hotspot was an okay search engine because it let you get real specific Like show me only SWF files and stuff like that, but Yahoo switched to being powered by Google.
Scott: so one day I was like huh What is this Google that powers them?
Scott: and I clicked on it and it brought me to Google and I said I can just use The Google.
Scott: why am I using the Yahoo to use the Google?
Scott: and it was the same search results that Yahoo was getting.
Scott: I was Like hey fuck Yahoo, and then Google ever since.
Scott: so the end?
Rym: yeah.
Rym: It's kind of interesting though one thing.
Rym: I mean it see while it's not as good as Google it's nowhere near as good or as useful as Google.
Rym: Google is like just the.
Rym: It's so transcendent for searching to the point that you use it without even thinking about it.
Rym: Yeah, but Most of the people who were complaining on slashdot and Fark and all these places We're doing these super generic one-word searches and their complaint was this and this alone.
Rym: It didn't give me the exact same list of things that Google gave me for the super generic search.
Scott: That's like the.
Scott: it's like the old argument Oh Linux the interface is bad is not the exact same as the wind.
Rym: or like the anime fanboy Argument.
Rym: when you're watching if you have the subtitles and the dub on they look at the subtitles.
Rym: They see that it's different from the dub and then decry the translation is being wrong.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, but I point out I search for something kind of specific.
Rym: I searched for RIT anime the old anime club that we used to run.
Rym: I used to run and Scott used to Infiltrate.
Rym: that's fine infiltrating as far as the shadow King shadow something Anyway, so I searched for it and actually all the things on the front page It shows.
Rym: the first link is the arti anime clubs home page with a picture of the arti anime club.
Rym: It's perfect.
Rym: The next one is the list all the arti anime club.
Rym: Third one is another page on the arti anime club.
Rym: It's got all these like.
Scott: really It's not gonna be stupidly off the thing.
Scott: The real test would be to search for like complicated things like I'm looking for You know, especially like the kind of things I search for when I'm at work.
Scott: I need a class a PHP class that helps me export, you know Excel sheets from you know, you're missing the point.
Rym: What I'm saying is that Google is good at that.
Rym: Google is good at searching for the specific unit of information you want irrespective of where you get that information.
Rym: You just want the piece of information.
Rym: But at least with a few searches and the anime club one's a good example.
Rym: It gives you kind of at a glance an overview of a topic of a semi-specific not ultra specific and not ultra Wikipedia for that most of the time.
Rym: but Wikipedia doesn't give it to you at a glance.
Rym: and honestly Wikipedia's quality in terms of editorial content has been dropping lately.
Rym: people grammars getting worse and worse.
Rym: I actually kind of gave up on editing for a while because I just couldn't deal with all the crap I had to fix.
Scott: the thing is I mostly I don't you usually use people write these big Wikipedia articles And I really think those big articles are only for the people doing like a research project and for the people.
Rym: When I go to Wikipedia, you want the simple English Wikipedia, which just tells you basically what something is as simply as possible.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I pretty much use it for But usually it also is I want like to find one specific fact about something that might not be just.
Scott: what is it?
Rym: You know, I usually that that's when you google for it and you'll find the Wikipedia page with that one nugget exactly.
Rym: But what this does is it gives you a nice overview and I'm looking and it links to GeekNights Because you know we used to be there links to anime cons and torque on and it's actually it worked really well.
Rym: The only problem the only problem is that the next two GeekNights.
Rym: It shows a picture of some Nokia phone.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not gonna be using the search engine.
Scott: That's all I can say.
Rym: I just I foresee that this search engine could survive because it could provide a service that is not a service Google provides.
Scott: I don't see it.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: There's a search for RIT anime on Google.
Scott: You'll find the same thing.
Scott: There's no reason to use this one instead of Google.
Scott: It's just more work.
Rym: actually know if you search for RIT anime on Google you find Links to all.
Rym: these is actually a completely different set of links for the most part and one of that Let's see.
Scott: The top link is the artsy anime club.
Scott: Yes, but what else do you need?
Rym: What if you're not?
Rym: what if you're just looking for an over you want to see like how what are kind of the websites about?
Rym: this thing Opposed to a specific piece of information.
Scott: I don't see why I would need to do that there either.
Scott: is not a time during my searching where I feel like There is a kind of search.
Scott: I need to make that I am NOT capable of making.
Rym: Well, I think the thing is you don't search for that kind of generic information.
Scott: There's no information that I currently cannot search for.
Scott: So what what need does this, you know, what problem does this solve?
Scott: Well, it's solving a non-existent problem.
Rym: Well, I think if it does solve anything at all I think it's providing an alternate kind of searching that I think some people are gonna like.
Rym: I think Do that.
Scott: Well, no one's gonna use this after you know It stops being paid.
Rym: because one other thing I can say and what if you hadn't kept interrupting what I would have finished is That Google gives you a lot of shit.
Rym: search results I mean Google's good like the top one will always be what you're looking for for like something specific.
Rym: But half the other links on Google will be the same thing on dig The same thing on all these other listsites on all these other aggregators and I didn't find any of that in cool.
Rym: Of course, I'm sure cool will eventually.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: That's what I found that I searched for me on cool.
Scott: It was like me on you know list all You are on the internet.
Rym: Maybe I'm in a lot of places But that's sort of like for like a club or something.
Rym: There's a Podcast going Google.
Rym: you find nothing.
Rym: but all these other websites that just have the same syndicated content.
Rym: It doesn't happen as much on cool yet.
Rym: So in some other news I kind of wanted to talk about all the business going on with software patents.
Rym: But I kind of want to wait until that.
Rym: we have more of a solid story there.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we talked about software patents enough times, you know saying they're bullshit is enough.
Scott: It's like a huge development.
Rym: Well, the development is basically that the USPTO has been very rapidly moving its stance toward just outright Devalidating all of them.
Scott: Yeah, it's a good chance But let's save the news until they do invalidate all of them.
Scott: Then we'll make a huge news out of it.
Scott: Like we could do a whole episode going.
Rym: But equally important here is that the FCC has been really there's been a lot of debate as to what to do about Comcast and you know and other ISPs and the fact that they've been kind of surreptitiously throttling peer-to-peer content.
Rym: Mm-hmm and They voted the.
Rym: you know, the five commissioners of the FCC have voted to punish Comcast.
Scott: I'm torn two ways on this quote.
Rym: the initial report on the vote said nothing about which way.
Rym: Oh wait, that quote doesn't have anything into it.
Rym: Never mind.
Scott: Great quote.
Rym: I realize the quote is just partisan BS.
Rym: I don't care about ya.
Scott: Do you want to tell me the two ways?
Scott: I'm torn.
Rym: Well me Why would I tell you the two ways you're torn?
Scott: All right, so the two ways I'm torn.
Scott: on the one hand Comcast is assholes getting punished.
Scott: Awesome, right?
Scott: I mean, come on as the obvious feeling to have right at this is Comcast was assholes filtering bit torrent Violating that neutrality.
Scott: the FCC is coming down on them.
Scott: That's protecting that neutrality weren't filtering.
Rym: It's not like they were saying I know I know but it's not like they were saying hey, we're gonna block these ports If you want to use our service, you can't use these ports or anything like that.
Rym: They were basically engaging in malicious behavior.
Scott: Yeah, we know what they were doing.
Scott: The thing is I'm torn the other way because I read this guy had a really great write-up.
Scott: I'll see if I can find the link.
Scott: some guy on the internet says it wasn't some guy I think was an actual like editorial in a newspaper.
Rym: Oh, so some guy.
Scott: Anyway, what he was talking about though was he was also supporting the net neutrality.
Scott: But what he said was this is sort of like the straw that's going to be broken and perhaps open a floodgate And another metaphor I can throw in there as well.
Scott: And that here we have for the first time Non-engineers Regulating the internet in some way.
Scott: every decision about how the internet works or how it's going to be run has always been done by engineers.
Scott: Another you know somewhere in the world, you know It's engineers that have come together and made the decisions about how networks will be run.
Scott: and here we have the first touch of government Bureaucracy of and you know politicians and those sorts of people get in their hands and now it's the FCC.
Rym: So it's a little bit engineering.
Scott: I disagree
Rym: because there's been a ton of legislation regulation about the internet and technology over the years by governments and not engineers and I would argue that a lot of the people who like what who have been making decisions about the internet are Technically engineers in the same sense that my job description.
Rym: It has the word engineering in it.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, you know There's some principle to the thing that you know once.
Scott: if the FCC can do this that means they can do other things We don't might not want them to do.
Scott: and that is just a little bit.
Scott: You're not so great.
Rym: your only argument is a slippery slope.
Rym: Then it's a logical fallacy.
Rym: it is it is slippery slope is only valid at all.
Scott: If you also have other evidence I know there's no evidence that it will you know slip down the slope.
Scott: But you know if we allow the government to do it opens a door less than it slips down.
Rym: What slope?
Rym: because basically?
Rym: I'm of the mind that a lot of what Comcast is doing amounts to among other things false advertise.
Scott: Oh, I see That's.
Scott: what I think is that Comcast should be punished but not by the FCC and a technological way But by you know, the criminal courts in a in a. that's not a criminal issue You know, they should be sued by the class-action lawsuit by the customers.
Scott: action lawsuits never amount to anything I know it's just wait for lawyers to get a lot of money If class-action lawsuits work.
Rym: I would take the opposite tack and say that I'm of the mind that this is the kind of thing the FCC Should have been doing all along and should be doing.
Rym: they shouldn't be censoring.
Rym: They shouldn't be regulating content.
Rym: They should only be regulating the means we get content the airwaves.
Scott: Yeah radio waves, which the same as the airwaves Yeah, but the other thing is I feel like the FCC should only deal with the wireless things and not so much the wired things.
Scott: Why?
Rym: that's an arbitrary distinction that you're making only because the wired things are more near and dear to you.
Scott: No, it's because if something's on a wire someone owns the wires and you don't have this issue where you need the government to step In yes
Rym: We tell
Scott: people how to use still
Rym: need the government stepping in because the regulation of
Scott: who
Rym: owns what wires where and who's allowed Or not allowed to put wires
Scott: Telephone wires, they're shared wires.
Scott: They're they're a public utility.
Scott: But right now, you know cable companies actually own all the wires that they put up.
Scott: It's it's an owned thing It's not a it's not a shared thing.
Rym: So it's sort of like, you know Civic they still use civic infrastructure they use the telephone poles and in fact cable modems and all these things are part of the reason why our telephone pole infrastructure is now on the verge of collapse because they're Well overextended as true.
Rym: Yes that that is why that that is actually the Specific point that I would make for the FCC being able to regulate this.
Scott: the other thing though Is that it's not all.
Scott: we're not com.
Scott: comcast specifically is actually is cable But you know not not every internet service provider is cable.
Rym: telephone don't use cable or telephone they use wire less And then the FCC gets it.
Scott: Yeah, but what if someone just gets a what is so?
Rym: it doesn't use wires?
Scott: Fiber that's not in a telephone pole.
Rym: So where do they put it?
Scott: It just goes to their neighbor.
Rym: how?
Rym: no You can.
Rym: actually you can do that.
Rym: Yeah, I'll tell you one thing though.
Rym: You're running pipe underground.
Rym: You got to do it.
Scott: Don't run copper Hell no hell.
Rym: no we learned a somewhat famous story at RIT Where to a company had two buildings on the same site and they wanted to have Ethernet between the two.
Rym: So they just had a conduit run, you know between the two buildings under and they just sent cat5 through the wire.
Rym: No, no, no, they send big old, you know coaxial cables.
Rym: No, all right All right media converters on both ends.
Rym: It was a big deal like, you know Like the internet was there's a bridge on either end and then stuff that had to go across went across this big high bandwidth Link.
Rym: All right One of the buildings got struck by lightning.
Rym: Oh Yeah Copper cable connecting the two underground.
Scott: not good bad idea.
Scott: Yes, could they can they solve that though with some sort of surge protector thing?
Rym: You're better off.
Scott: Wait, I mean you need a big one for lightning, but you know, you coulda it's possible.
Rym: Anyway, there's actually it's a longer anecdote.
Rym: I don't want to get into all the technicalities of it because none of you care.
Scott: No, no one cares.
Rym: It was actually part of an entire like one entire class worth of a case study of Poor decisions made by people who don't understand their amifications, huh?
Scott: I've never seen anything like that before in the.
Scott: you know, ITC s industry.
Rym: only every goddamn day Every way we're going to communicate will either need civic infrastructure public land right-of-way through private land or Regulation of the airwaves.
Rym: the only foreseeable place I could see no use for the FCC Would be quantum communication because it doesn't actually travel anywhere.
Scott: Or does it?
Scott: or can you just not be sure I?
Scott: Mean, yeah FCC.
Scott: We're gonna take you to court.
Scott: you violated some quanta the Quanta Communication Act of 2012.
Scott: Can you prove that I in fact communicated?
Scott: I where we have this level of certainty that there was communication occurring?
Scott: My follow I can tell you either if you communicated or what you communicated but not both.
Rym: My follow-on joke to what you said would have been but it's only Anyway bees of the day.
Scott: No, not the bees.
Rym: This is.
Rym: this is one of those rare things that's just so Perfectly formed and so hilarious.
Scott: just it's sort of like.
Scott: this is sort of.
Scott: it's good in the same sort of the same way That you can lift em.
Scott: Pokemon is good.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's such a simple joke, but it's executed flawlessly and The the mashup and just everything about it.
Rym: It comes together.
Scott: Same thing that's.
Scott: the one thing is that in the age of the internet, right?
Scott: We've sort of lost the format of like.
Scott: the quick joke, you know of like, you know Like.
Scott: why did chicken cross the road to get the other side?
Rym: dinner is nothing but quick jokes.
Rym: I mean real.
Scott: I mean incredibly quick.
Rym: How many YouTube video?
Rym: how many videos in College Humor if they're more than a minute long people just don't bother.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm saying I'm talking about this steak, you know a minute long.
Scott: That's that's.
Scott: that's quick relative But that's not like this is super quick.
Scott: We're talking about the fives the one-liner the five-second, you know where those jokes are.
Rym: go too far go to something awful.
Rym: The joke is a picture.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's that's a good one.
Rym: Those are in fact thriving on the internet.
Rym: I poke holes and everything you just said anyway.
Rym: Anyway, this is just.
Rym: I Laughed so hard when I saw that I'm pretty hard.
Scott: I wasn't expecting so much and I got way more than I expected because
Rym: it was like it was done really well Especially with the zooming in and the fact that it was done like obviously filming a TV Which gives it this kind of extra edgy quality, but
Scott: it was done well enough where it didn't matter.
Rym: Plus the fact that the comedic timing cuz it's like alright, it's really funny.
Rym: That's done really well, but then the exact Precise comedic timing of the second thing that happens at the very end of the video.
Scott: Yeah, if the timing and this was off it would not work at all.
Rym: What are those things where you know, you ha ha ha ha and just as you're about to stop laughing They hit you with the one-two punch and you laugh even harder I think as I saw it coming because I know how that works.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time you see it coming but then it hits and you still laugh for anyone.
Scott: It's a combination of this movie called the wicker man a movie.
Scott: I've never seen and know nothing about.
Scott: I think it has Nicolas Cage Okay, you can check IMDb for that and Megaman 3 hard man's level.
Scott: and well It doesn't matter if you've never seen the movie and it really actually doesn't matter if you've never played Megaman.
Scott: Okay, anyway, so I Don't know when you were a kid, right?
Scott: You would go to.
Scott: you know, there were.
Scott: there were these places called showbiz pizza.
Scott: It was a big chain in the in the old Midwest.
Rym: We had major magics, which was basically the same thing.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I think I went to one of these places but it was called something else.
Scott: But I remember it's basically go and play arcade games as a kid, right?
Scott: But really really shitty get really shitty pizza.
Scott: and there's an animatronic, you know band that plays music.
Scott: You know your birthday party.
Scott: They like all your friends in there and you go watch the animatronic animal.
Rym: one of those places was around here today.
Rym: I would probably go there regularly because it'd probably be the best arcade around.
Scott: Well if it had games like it did back in the day I mean nowadays to go to a Chuck E Cheese and all the games like crane games and toss the ball in the hole games And stomp the spider.
Rym: I remember playing crossbow at my major magics.
Scott: Yeah, you know these places don't have DDR and Mortal Kombat 2 anymore.
Scott: Anyway - yeah or virtual on.
Scott: So, you know those animatronic animals and I was a kid.
Scott: They scared the fuck out.
Scott: I was I didn't.
Scott: oh, they didn't really didn't scare me so much that run away But they were sort of annoying and painful to look at.
Scott: I didn't enjoy them at all.
Scott: And I wondered why other kids did enjoy them.
Rym: or if they even enjoyed them, you know It might have been at this kind of mass hysteria where kids are at a birthday party.
Rym: They see all the other kids losing their shit about the dancing.
Rym: We never lie.
Scott: I don't remember anyone losing their shit about it.
Rym: I remember seeing little kids jumping up and down and clapping and Jerry.
Scott: Yeah, I don't remember that.
Rym: But of course I remember usually my parents would make us sit there and watch the thing and as soon as it was done I would grab my tokens and make a beeline.
Rym: Exactly
Scott: It always felt like the kind of thing that adults thought kids would like but kids didn't actually like and they made us sit Or at all, I guess when I was a little bit older like maybe six It sort of felt like a thing that was for three-year-olds and I was too old.
Scott: I always felt too old for it no matter how old I was.
Scott: But anyway, some dude right he collected like a full set of these animatronic, you know Musicians and actually, you know, the place was called showbiz pizza But the animals were called.
Scott: the band that the animals comprised was the rock of fire explosion.
Rym: now I can say with almost certainty that I saw some of these exact same things.
Rym: that major man.
Scott: I've definitely seen some of them.
Scott: So this guy collected the full set of these animatronic animals like in his house Yes, I think like in his garage or something or like a rented space.
Rym: Anyway, not the animatronics.
Scott: He fixed them all up.
Scott: He set them all up.
Scott: The whole thing is pretty much in as working as well as it perhaps better than the day it was made.
Scott: he fixed the whole thing and what he does is you go to his website and You make a bid you pick a song and you offer some money and if someone else offers money for the same song that's a total money for that song goes up and Whichever song has the most money going for it.
Scott: He choreographs the animatronic animals to play that modern awesome song or maybe people think an old song I don't know and then he puts the video on YouTube and then you pay him.
Scott: and As Much as I hated these animals as a kid and thought they were stupid and didn't get it and everything I watch this now and there's something about it.
Scott: That's just really awesome.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I don't know what it is, but it like.
Scott: it feels great to watch these animals part of it Play modern pop songs.
Rym: I think appeals to the hacker and all of us because it takes is that Had those things you can bet we would be doing awesome things with them.
Scott: I guess it's sort of it's like I get the same enjoyment I get if I like watch people play rock band really awesomely, you know.
Rym: See there's more to it though because maybe for children of the 80s more so than anything else.
Rym: I remember that animatronics were kind of the symbol and icon of the economic prosperity of my child.
Scott: Well, that's definitely true because I remember right now a day when I was that young I didn't appreciate you know What the economy was good economy?
Rym: Children of the 80s we really came up like children of the 70s came of age in the 80s.
Rym: We were children of the 80s.
Rym: We came of age in the 90s.
Rym: in the 90s if you went to any mall in them in America We're at least outside of I guess the back ist of water.
Rym: Yeah, there were animatronics in every mall.
Scott: There's a mall over in Jersey on the other side of Tappan Zee Bridge called the Palisades Park, whatever right?
Scott: It's huge.
Scott: They built it sort of like at the.
Scott: yeah They built it at like the peak of economic awesomeness in the u.s.
Scott: Like, you know less than 10 years ago I mean the mall was huge.
Scott: this mall when I went to and it was new it had a Dave and Busters.
Scott: Right now only to have a Dave and Busters It had a Chuck E. Cheese Discovery Zone equivalent place with the biggest set of tubes and balls I've ever seen.
Rym: you know big ball pit lakeside ball when I was a kid near.
Rym: Not only did they have an arcade that was awesome and not only did they have like I'm not even done yet like multiple amusement park like Restaurants.
Rym: they had water slides in the mall.
Scott: All right, this wall this wall had a ferris wheel in it.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it had a rainforest cafe.
Scott: Remember that shit.
Scott: I remember that animatronics in there.
Scott: They had a Disney store full animatronics at Warner Brothers store full animatronics.
Scott: They had this NASCAR place.
Scott: you can go to NASCAR Silicon Valley Motor Speedway, and it was basically full-size NASCAR's with projectors in front of the screen and little tiny screens in the rearview mirrors and hydraulics lifting the things up and you paid 10 bucks to do like one track and it was a wreck.
Scott: it was a Replication of a real track and he drove just like a. you know, it's calibrated to be just like a real NASCAR.
Scott: I've had a business.
Rym: we've all had VR stuff.
Rym: I remember you'd go and ride like for five or six bucks like a VR roller coaster.
Rym: Actually a lot of them they had VR like first-person shooters where you and a bunch of friends would just play an FPS in the semi.
Rym: VR there's actually Really?
Scott: I kind of wouldn't mind doing that today and nowadays all those things are gone and only now can I appreciate that.
Scott: the reason We had all those things during that time period during the Clinton era It was because the economy was awesome.
Scott: and now the economy sucks.
Scott: We have none of those things, but at the same time the economy's sucking.
Rym: we we over the weekend We went.
Scott: those things are a waste.
Scott: We shouldn't have spent our money on them.
Scott: Maybe the economy wouldn't suck now.
Rym: Yes Oh, you always saw in malls Was that three rings like three concentric rings and you'd kind of crucify yourself in the middle and then it would spin you around Something a gyro.
Scott: Yeah, whatever it is.
Rym: Cuz the thing is that was actually exercise.
Rym: It wasn't just like a ride like you could actually control the thing by tensing muscles and shifting your weight.
Rym: Yep, I know this only because I did it a lot.
Scott: I don't call it a gyroscope, but it's a gyro.
Scott: It's a gyro something.
Rym: Let's just call it a da Vinci All right, so I'm of the mind that they're.
Rym: they're neither moral nor legal implications to just totally stealing someone's Wi-Fi.
Scott: I'm of the mind that there are no legal implications that I know of but you know, it's questionable.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I don't think there should be and I don't think there are.
Scott: but there might be legal implications.
Scott: but I think there is a Somewhat moral implication to just stealing someone's Wi-Fi.
Rym: I don't think morals should be a factor at all because in technology issues, we should only discuss the technology.
Scott: Well, if you only want to discuss the technology Wi-Fi works people leave them open you can connect to them But all the more there more is there.
Rym: there's a lot of people feel as though it is somehow a Crime or it should be a crime to connect to an unencrypted Wi-Fi.
Scott: Well, here's the only reason why I feel sort of in line with the moral argument of connecting to an unencrypted Wi-Fi That you just find a right.
Scott: All right So just any it doesn't.
Scott: First of all, there's a difference between you know One open Wi-Fi and another.
Scott: if I go to the park and there's a sign in the park This is free Wi-Fi here and I open up my laptop and I see one with the ESS ID of free Wi-Fi.
Scott: That's okay.
Scott: Obviously, it's okay.
Scott: if I go to hotel and it says free Wi-Fi and I connect to it It's obviously okay.
Rym: right now by the same token.
Rym: I remember one case.
Rym: we were out visiting our friend Pete Yep, and we drove way up and he wasn't around.
Rym: so we just kind of sat in this park next to there's like one house There and Scott notices that there's Wi-Fi.
Rym: Yeah, obviously coming from this one house.
Rym: Yep So we connect to it see that there's a computer.
Rym: we see that as an unprotected Windows share.
Rym: We made a text file explaining how to secure Wi-Fi.
Rym: We put it on the C Drive.
Scott: Yeah We did.
Scott: we did indeed but see here's the thing To you the best example I have and I said this in the forum But I don't think you know, everyone who's listening to this read that forum post right.
Scott: imagine for a second.
Scott: I think our opinion is largely shaped by the fact that we live in the United States.
Scott: Imagine for a second.
Scott: We were in Australia.
Scott: people in Australia when they buy internet access, right?
Scott: They get a limited amount of bandwidth, you know X gigabytes per gigabits per month.
Scott: And if they use that up, they have to start paying an exorbitant fee for every, you know bit they go over.
Scott: So let's say you have someone in Australia and they're dumb.
Scott: They set up wireless for their laptop.
Scott: They got that far but they were too dumb to set up.
Scott: You know the security on it, right?
Scott: Which is something you would definitely want to do if you had limited bandwidth.
Scott: because if someone random person used all your bandwidth now suddenly you can't use your internet without paying a crazy fee.
Scott: and You know if you go in Australia and you see an access point named links is one two three Odds are right.
Scott: being a technological person You know, the odds are a stupid person set that up and didn't know better, right?
Scott: And if you use that you know that odds are.
Scott: a person that's dumb like that is not the kind of person who's paying the Extra money for the unlimited bandwidth in Australia.
Scott: So if you use their bandwidth, you're actually taking significant stuff out of their wallet Without their explicit permission.
Scott: and in there I think there is a slight grounds for a moral implication that you probably shouldn't be doing that.
Rym: now.
Rym: the reason I definitely say there shouldn't be a legal implication and I Scott and I actually have argued about this a lot over the years
Scott: And
Rym: our opinions have kind of moved toward the center a little bit a little bit a little
Scott: bit
Rym: but basically I am leery of any time where in using a technology or engaging with the technological device that you have to have some sort of implicit or Subjective like.
Rym: you have to somehow Assertained the intention or the intent if I may Of the person on the other end that if I'm communicating with someone there's the information we're exchanging.
Rym: I shouldn't have to make some sort of meta calculation as to what they are intending to exchange.
Rym: Yeah, for example you did make that distinction.
Rym: You have basically broken the trust of protocols on the internet and made everything subject to legal action here.
Scott: Think about this for a second, right?
Scott: Someone has a web server, right?
Scott: I can ask that web server.
Scott: I can say get index study HTML and that web server sends me index that HTML.
Scott: It just does it.
Scott: there's no person making a decision on the other end.
Scott: What if someone?
Scott: Accidentally set up a web server and I'm using their bandwidth when I get data from their web server, right?
Scott: You know.
Scott: But it's implied sort of when you set up a web server on the internet that you want people to visit it.
Rym: now see the reason It's implied is because it's a specific Protocol.
Rym: the protocol is that if you want to accept these kinds of connections When a certain kind of request comes in then if you don't respond nothing happens, but the fact that I ask it Hey web server.
Rym: Can I look at you and it says hello Rym?
Rym: Here is some information.
Rym: Would you like some more?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And in that case if you if anyone ever argues that we should have to worry about the intent of the person who set up a technology then in that case Legally you could be in trouble for visiting a website just because someone put it online But they don't actually want anyone to look at it
Scott: even though they didn't set up the security on it
Rym: now.
Rym: That's why a lot of people use the analogy with Wi-Fi of the open door.
Rym: ah, well if someone just you know forgets to lock their doors that'll give you the legal right to steal everything in their house and The reason is it's not a good analogy at all with Wi-Fi.
Scott: This this Discussion is ripe for a million broken analogies.
Scott: pretty much all people do when they have this argument is throw analogies Like there's that analogies enough to like bury a city.
Rym: But it's like an analogy.
Rym: you see no But no, it's.
Rym: it's not like leaving your door open if someone walks in and takes your stuff.
Rym: It is much more analogous to you go to the store and you see a sign and the sign says Free lemonade come on in help yourself.
Rym: But you don't understand what the sign says.
Rym: But you choose to buy it anyway because you need something to patch a hole in your front in the front of your house.
Rym: There's a hole in your front in your house.
Rym: So you put it over the hole because you just you bought it to cover that hole But you can't read so you don't realize that.
Rym: on the on the hole now It says please come in making this algae way too complicated because that's exactly what it's like.
Rym: remember when you buy wireless access point You buy it because you want to.
Rym: you want to do something.
Rym: you have an intent in mind.
Rym: You want to have your internet around your house, but you're dumb.
Rym: So you don't know all the other things that this product does.
Rym: So I'm buying this sign to do one thing to cover the hole in my wall But I don't know the other thing.
Rym: it does the thing.
Rym: it explicitly does the thing.
Rym: it tells me outright that it does That.
Rym: it says all are welcome.
Rym: Come on in free lemonade Mm-hmm.
Rym: So in that case if I see a house with the door open and a sign that says free lemonade come on in.
Rym: I Believe that I'm perfectly within my rights to walk into that house unannounced and take some lemonade.
Rym: Yeah, now it's a little bit more dubious if I decide to also take the safe full of money.
Rym: Yeah, in fact you could argue that that is wrong because you were.
Rym: the sign explicitly said free lemonade But you're allowed to come in you're allowed to take the lemonade and you're allowed to leave and you're allowed to linger.
Scott: Well, well think about the situation where the guy What he did was he put up the.
Scott: the two people put something on Craigslist that said come to this address I'm giving you everything away for free and it was some other guy's house.
Scott: So it's as if the guy had a free lemonade sign in his house But he didn't put it up.
Scott: someone else put it up when he wasn't looking and everyone but at the same time.
Rym: What are the specifics?
Rym: the first person who showed up was the house unlocked?
Scott: It must have been.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: see because From what I read about that story I get the impression that people showed up and then broke in.
Scott: That's what if.
Scott: and then they were like angry when the guy said hey don't take my shit And then they waved the Craigslist papers in his face as if to see.
Rym: now that is two different situations because here's a not an analogy.
Rym: But take the example of a Cisco router that the company sets up like say I run joy Jojo Shabba do soft incorporated.
Rym: so I have a router.
Rym: now say I'm dumb and I don't set up my security, right?
Rym: So you can tell that to my router and it said it lets you log in.
Rym: now say I put a banner.
Rym: I'm smart enough.
Rym: I put a banner.
Rym: So when you get to the telnet screen It says clearly this router is the property of so-and-so.
Rym: you are not and no one is entitled to go any further.
Rym: Unauthorized access blah blah blah blah.
Rym: I Don't think you have the right to continue beyond at that point.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's been made pretty clear in the past.
Rym: But you can I know but you could not say by visiting this site you have hereby agreed to the following terms Not have known the terms before you arrived.
Rym: So that say someone will I you know I put up my lemonade sign and then someone walks in and goes to take my lemonade.
Rym: I think I have the right to say hey, who are you get the fuck out?
Rym: And then they say hey, but your sign says free lemonade to which I say well the signs wrong get out And then I think the person has to leave my button.
Rym: No.
Rym: No, this is this is my opinion the law.
Rym: It's pretty clear what the law says.
Rym: but my opinion regardless of the law is that in the Craigslist case?
Rym: If the owner of their property said to leave the moment those Craigslist people Craigslist people didn't leave.
Rym: they are now in violation.
Rym: But the person at fault is the person who posted the faulty thing in the first place.
Rym: in the case of the Wi-Fi The person who owns the house also posted the faulty sign.
Scott: Yeah, it's true.
Scott: However, here's the thing is that is It is commonly understood, you know that when someone sets up a website without security on it They want people to visit it.
Scott: That's sort of the default.
Scott: is that people want you to visit their websites.
Scott: when people set up Wi-Fi The default is you know, most people don't even realize that it's something other people are going to use.
Rym: But again, that's only because you're making assumptions.
Rym: You have to assume the it is an assumption.
Scott: However, I Found that it's mostly true.
Scott: people who set up Wi-Fi They don't know what they're doing.
Scott: people set up a web server know what they're doing generally say So it's like the reality.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I know the reality of the world is thus Even though I can't basing it on assumptions ruins a lot of things, but this brings up the more important point.
Rym: What about the old adage stupid should be painful is I think it should be pain?
Rym: I feel as though now obviously but on the other that's obviously it's a it's a sliding scale.
Rym: There's a is there's no black and white.
Rym: there is a line between moral and immoral.
Rym: now granted There should not be a line or a gray area between legal and illegal.
Rym: It should be a very clear line Yes, but in terms of morality, you know There's a fine line and I think that there's a certain level of due diligence.
Rym: in any situation Wi-Fi whatever any possible situation that a human could put themselves or others into There is a head in every case a level of due diligence for all parties.
Rym: that is required And I have the feeling that if you do not put forth that due diligence, then you do not have the right to recourse.
Scott: All right, but here's the thing right.
Scott: stupid should be painful.
Scott: I you know that that level of the argument I have to agree with the thing is stupid should not be deadly.
Scott: Well, no, no.
Scott: No, I'm just saying I'm just saying in this context stupid should be painful.
Scott: not it.
Scott: not as a general not as a general rule and for the universe maybe kind of itchy - right but Should it even if stupid should be painful if you are not stupid and you intentionally go about Dole ing out pain to the stupid.
Rym: Yes, that's That's morally questionable, but at the same time I don't think it is that unjustified to expect a do a level of due diligence of?
Scott: I click on WEP But they don't even know that much.
Scott: It doesn't mean it You know what?
Rym: I hate to say this but I'm of the mind more and more that with certain with technology if you cannot Function with the technology on it's on a most basic level and put forth the minimal due diligence That you have no business using seg technology.
Rym: and take the example of a car.
Rym: You don't need to understand the intricacies of a internal combustion engine.
Rym: You don't need to understand the chemical composition of automatic transmission fluid.
Rym: You don't even know have to know how to change your own oil.
Rym: I'm fine with that.
Rym: We're in a society where you know people need cars.
Rym: Not everyone needs to be an expert of cars But you need to know what the gas pedal does.
Rym: You need to know what the brake pedal does if you don't lock your car doors.
Rym: tough shit.
Rym: if someone steals it.
Scott: I know some shit.
Scott: if someone steals it All right.
Rym: If you leave the car Unlocked with the keys in it and the windows down and the sign says please take free car or even if it doesn't say free Car while it's still wrong to steal it The police are probably not going to care very much.
Scott: and the insurance so they don't care very much Even if someone steals it hardcore.
Rym: In fact, I'm not an insurance lawyer.
Rym: I'm not a lawyer But I would bet your insurance wouldn't cover it if that if you left the windows If you let your car unlocked and the keys in your insurance isn't gonna cover it They probably won't.
Rym: you didn't do your due diligence.
Rym: No, I honestly feel that encrypted that either enabling security or in the very least making the SSID say Private or something something any indication way.
Scott: So if the what if you?
Scott: what if you found a public Wi-Fi right and the SSID said private What if it was you know?
Scott: Like private Joe and his he was a private in the army or something and they would just.
Scott: he said I'll call it private.
Scott: Cuz that's what I am.
Rym: and see now this this is the sliding scale.
Scott: You're just sitting there and all you see is the word private.
Scott: Do you feel would you click on that?
Rym: See now me personally.
Rym: if I needed internet.
Rym: Yes Internet I'd break a web.
Rym: that's entirely different argument.
Rym: I need internet access and I and I find it I'll break the web.
Rym: It's not that hard to do.
Scott: need two laptops though.
Rym: Yeah, actually you can get away with one Can you?
Scott: I used to used to need two to make it easy.
Scott: But anyway, cuz there's
Rym: a bunch of exploits now where you can just basically get the server to dump a bunch of data at you
Scott: And she go I should get one of those things anyway Cuz most people using WPA now anyway those
Rym: Forgetting the legal argument which I feel private probably wouldn't mean anything because it doesn't explicitly say you can't connect.
Scott: Well, but this there's the other argument this with it with the wireless protocol.
Scott: There's nowhere to put a message before.
Scott: Yes You have to allow people to connect then do the thing that all the hotels do where they forward all your HTTP traffic to one Page that has the terms and then have the second level of connection with the Mac filtering in the whole business.
Rym: Yes, but you see there is still a facility.
Rym: It's called WEP.
Rym: Yep, there's also the argument.
Rym: I mean, you know I say implicit and explicit but Legal aside.
Rym: I think the only legal way to deal with it is simply if you don't protect your Wi-Fi It's open.
Rym: It's fair business.
Rym: But in terms of morality the more like if it says please don't use or private It's a little less morally justifiable to use it.
Rym: if it's a weapon cryptid It's about 80% morally unjustifiable to use it.
Rym: if this is WPA you're at about 99% but you won't break it anyway.
Scott: So yeah I think also in the United States the moral just the moral qualms are less because internet access is less Value, so it's still stealing on in principle in some way I believe legal term is not actually stealing because bandwidth is free and that's how I get.
Rym: it is trespass to Chatel, right?
Scott: But you're it.
Scott: the amount of damage is so small somewhere like the UK The amount of damage you will cause is much much higher and I think therefore the moral qualm while saint.
Scott: Well, it's the same moral qualm in principle.
Scott: It is far more damage that you are causing.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: it's like the difference between like, okay if you you know
Rym: have one
Scott: lock on your door But it's really flimsy and I sort of just open the door walk in spin around and walk out versus you know Open the door knock a bunch of stuff over and break it and walk out.
Scott: It's like okay in but in principle I did the same thing the breaking and entering.
Scott: but in one the amount of damage I did was get your floor dirty And in the other one the amount of damage I did was break things and it's just more damage.
Scott: So it's like if you're okay stealing a candy bar, but you're not okay stealing a car.
Scott: That's the difference between doing it in the US doing it in Australia.
Scott: at the same
Rym: time I'm kind of sad that you don't argue the legal aspect of it anymore because I have my killer point which is they're Broadcasting their wireless signal their radio waves into public property
Scott: where
Rym: I am and it's legal for me to what look at take pictures of observe Anything that I can see or hear from private from public property
Scott: and it is legal for you according to the FCC with your radio in your Computer to broadcast from that radio whatever signals you want.
Scott: Yeah So you're allowed to look at all the radio signals coming out in in the open air in public property and you're allowed to Broadcast these particular radio signals in public property.
Scott: thus and that level that's all you're doing.
Rym: So they're saying that it's illegal or it should be illegal to access someone's unencrypted unprotected wireless You know without having any sort of explicit Way of knowing not to is the same as saying that I could put a picture like a poster in my front yard But make it illegal for you to look at it or take pictures of it.
Scott: Hmm Well, I think the difference there is that you know taking pictures of the thing doesn't do any damage to you Whereas, you know when okay, sure you're broadcasting the waves themselves into the air.
Rym: But the result of those waves is also Exclusively defined by the protocol and you have allowed the protocol to make these decisions.
Scott: Yeah, what about that guy?
Scott: Remember that story the guys who were in the Home Depot parking lot and they got on the Home Depot Network.
Scott: Remember those guys.
Scott: Oh, yeah Yes, they got in trouble not just for the credit card ceiling that they were doing which is definitely a little but they got in Trouble for the infiltrating of the company network.
Rym: See what was that?
Rym: encrypted or not?
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: I don't think it was.
Scott: I think it was Home Depot being stupid and having open wireless access points on there.
Rym: You know store network, you know, here's here's another point now.
Rym: This is not to argue in favor of stealing things from people or doing bad or not.
Scott: Remembering that's.
Rym: There's also the point of due diligence is not shouldn't just be this thing that everyone has to do in order to kind of put Themselves above blame or like I at least did my due diligence.
Rym: Right, it's not my fight like there's nothing.
Scott: due diligence is usually now my insurance will help me out because I did the due diligence Yes, but it's also the.
Rym: I feel as though a lot of people have forgotten especially in America and in the West where you know Generally our lives are pretty good and personal
Scott: responsibility
Rym: But no, but just the fact that we live generally very affluent very well-off lives and a lot of people do but Everyone there's a certain level of due diligence you should do not because other people tell you to but because you only have one life and Even though people shouldn't do bad things to you A lot of people do bad things and you should take the due diligence Required to protect yourself from other people as best you can.
Rym: for example I don't I'm not a paranoid nutter runs around with four guns than a taser and a security system.
Rym: No, you're around six guns, but at the same time I Wouldn't go to sleep naked in the middle of Grand Central or not Grand Central in the middle of Central Park at night.
Rym: I Wouldn't just sleep naked overnight in a remote part of Grand Central Central Park.
Scott: assuming that that wasn't illegal.
Rym: being naked in public to begin with fine with it with a sock over my nuts, right?
Rym: Assume how it's legal.
Scott: I love that right?
Scott: Assuming that as legal in the first place, right?
Scott: You're putting yourself in incredible danger.
Scott: It's sort of an
Rym: at-your-own-risk
Scott: situation and it's like sure if someone comes and you know Mugs you or assaults you because you're naked in the park at night, you know on the one hand
Rym: Illegal the police should have protected you because they weren't there The police should follow up and all that but at the same time you could have trivially protected yourself.
Scott: You could have indeed.
Rym: So I just feel as though when it comes to technology The level of due diligence that is expected of people needs to be a little bit higher.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not saying it needs to be at the level of a technology professional But protect yourself a little bit.
Rym: know at least something if you're if you set up a wireless access point And you're 70 years old and you don't even know what it does or how it works That's no different than if I get in a car But I've never driven a car before and I just start hitting pedals and turning things on the freeway.
Scott: Yeah, and I mean a lot of Pete.
Scott: the other problem right is that there's a lot of people out there in the world Right who know enough about technology to be dangerous, right?
Scott: It's like an old person has no idea what to do with the wireless access point.
Scott: They don't even know it works.
Scott: They don't even know it exists.
Scott: They get their smart, you know grandkid to set it up.
Scott: The grandkid knows enough to follow the instructions and set it up But they don't know about web for WPA or Mac filtering or routing or net or anything.
Scott: They know just enough to be dangerous but they don't know really enough to get the job done right fully from beginning to end and that is why we have a lot of things like unprotected windows boxes.
Scott: and you know people.
Scott: they know how to install software and configure their computers But they don't know enough to watch out for malware how to tell the difference in malware and perfectly Okay where and that that that's really the dangerous situation that we're in now.
Scott: and I Don't really don't have a lot of confidence unless we start, you know, adding a fifth subject to all public schools in computer technology That anyone is ever and we have you know People being like me being paid enough to teach that class in every school
Rym: Now I would use is one I've been using for a long time and I think it's still perfectly relevant.
Rym: The internet and technology today is a lot like the Wild West one.
Rym: everyone says the one yes But think about it on a very on a more literal, you know, take the metaphor really seriously.
Rym: So there are laws Sheriffs, there are laws and sheriffs out there.
Rym: Sometimes the sheriff's are killed in cold blood But not only art like the movie 310 to humor or any of those, you know Western movies.
Rym: So there are laws and the laws applied just like the laws out in the east where there are police everywhere But at the same time there's not a lot of people to enforce those laws.
Rym: There's not a lot of people to help you out.
Rym: if someone else breaks those laws and if you don't carry a gun At the wall, you know, it's a shame.
Rym: if you get killed and your stuff gets stolen and the sheriff will say up That's a shame.
Rym: I wish I could have helped him.
Rym: I should have helped him, but I couldn't have.
Rym: I wanted to help him But at the same time you can't rely on the sheriff because there's only one sheriff and he's busy.
Scott: So and the deputies are corrupt.
Rym: You've got to carry a gun.
Rym: if you're on the internet, you've got to have at least a little bit of internet gun.
Scott: Well, I think that's the thing.
Scott: Is that unlike the Wild West the Internet's major fault is that in the Wild West if you were out there?
Scott: You knew it was dangerous.
Scott: The whole situation was dangerous.
Scott: The danger was apparent.
Scott: It was everywhere.
Scott: You knew that.
Scott: you know you had cattle.
Scott: you knew that they were gonna be.
Scott: you always thought that they were gonna be rustled any Minute.
Scott: now the internet looks perfectly safe.
Scott: It is totally unassuming.
Scott: It is totally there's.
Scott: no, you know, you could have.
Scott: you could be having your cattle rustled right now.
Scott: You wouldn't even know you had cattle Russell.
Scott: You wouldn't even know.
Scott: after your Russell your computer's sending out spam.
Scott: You still don't even know you don't?
Scott: it's?
Scott: everything is invisible to the average person.
Scott: They don't realize the danger.
Rym: They see a happy purple gorilla who says funny things and does a dance.
Scott: I see panditas Exactly, so we really I think you know.
Scott: on the one hand if we start Getting people to think the internet is dangerous as they should right They will start to fear it much like people fear guns today, you know Even though I guess guns should be you know.
Scott: But instead what we need to do is not fear the guns but instead have a proper level of respect for them.
Rym: Well that I think this her would be a healthy fear.
Rym: As in if I cuz you know, I fired some guns, but I never.
Scott: it seems like the General.
Rym: you shouldn't be afraid of the good like oh my god.
Rym: But if you hold a gun, you should have that fear of.
Rym: I hope I don't shoot anything unintentionally.
Scott: I will not shoot anything unintentionally.
Scott: I will not point this.
Scott: you have to be very aware and you know be very conscious of what it is and very serious and You have to you know have the respect for what's going on here.
Scott: You can't just be you know, taking it all willy-nilly like yeah, whatever.
Scott: It's a gun You got to be like, all right, you know, I'm not afraid of these guns like oh my god.
Scott: Everyone's gonna die.
Scott: It's a gun.
Scott: It's the end of the world.
Scott: but yet to you know take it seriously and respect the situation.
Scott: and I think that a lot of people in the u.s.
Scott: Now we're just I Think really our civil our society as a whole has lost healthy fear.
Scott: It's either Sensationalist nous awesomeness or sensationalist fear.
Scott: Everything is either crazy love or crazy.
Scott: Oh my god run away and we've really lost You know a lot of the ability to respect things on a serious level and and be you know, realistically cautious.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.