Rym: It's Thursday January 17th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is eat nice jinx personal.
Rym: Tonight we take dibs on shotgun.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So last night I had to engage in one of those semi-annual tasks.
Rym: that is Not so much something I want to do, but something that must be done.
Rym: You know insert innuendo here.
Rym: a man has a duty and every now and then you have to stand up and do your duty to the world.
Rym: and last night I Being the designated drain Oh doer had to buy that scary-ass shit and pour it down the drain while Scott watched from afar.
Scott: It was kind of interesting because it was like it used to be liquid, but now it's gel.
Scott: well No, no there.
Rym: You can still get the liquid.
Rym: There's three kinds.
Scott: There's the normal three one two three times.
Rym: There's the normal liquid which is like standard Drano and by Drano I mean generically everything takes that trademark acid in a in a jug.
Rym: no It's the opposite of acid the base in a jug.
Scott: yes alkaline.
Rym: So there's the liquid one which is like that the standard weak sauce.
Rym: And then there's the gel which is weak sauce.
Rym: still if you touch it They'll hardly burn you, but then then there's the gel which is all right.
Rym: I'm going down there, and I'm cleaning that out the gel.
Scott: I realized it's probably just as powerful But because it goes down slowly it actually sits there for longer burning more.
Rym: And then there's the foamer the one I use usually which is too dangerous chemicals that when you mix them together In the drain it goes foam foam foam foam foam foam foam foam foam foam foam.
Scott: I actually feel safer with that one because if you only one of them spills It's a little it's a I guess more.
Rym: Okay, what I think you would have to put forth quite a bit of effort to only spill one of them.
Rym: Yeah, I know plus It's scary because if the drain is really clogged and you put it down there it could just comes right back up.
Rym: And now I'm standing there, and there's there's Evil just sitting there all over it.
Rym: I'm like what do I do now?
Scott: It's very strange that I'm so afraid of that stuff right, but like in school in the chemistry lab I just feel like yeah boiling hydrochloric acid sure whatever.
Rym: Well there was Krenzle in my high school who we were told in the chemistry lab we had some Concentrated hydrochloric acid in a thing in a fume hood.
Rym: We're doing something with it And he's like.
Rym: now everyone make sure you don't get your head in the fume hood because hydrochloric acid will make you pass out pretty much immediately if you inhale it and Craig goes really, and then he passes out.
Rym: yep, yeah, but uh so Emily and Scott are been pretty much most sane.
Rym: human beings don't like to be around Drano And it's kind of a scary thing.
Scott: and for that tub it was backed up.
Rym: for whatever reason it is my duty.
Rym: I'm the one who has to do this every time it happens.
Scott: I would probably do it if you weren't here, and it needs to be done.
Rym: But I was here and we could have been not gonna do it.
Scott: if I'm not gonna do it It needed to be done for like a week and a half Basically that morning yesterday morning.
Scott: I took a foot bath when I was taking a shower.
Scott: Yeah an unwanted foot bath.
Rym: I don't like a nasty soapy dirty water Show me that.
Scott: but this morning I had to like spray my water feet spray my feet with water because they were so dry because the drain was flowing so nicely.
Rym: Yeah, Drano is some scary stuff, but it's my duty as a man, and I will continue to do it until the day I die hopefully not from Drano.
Rym: Thing is I never keep Drano in the house.
Rym: I always buy it and then use it right away, and then it's gone.
Scott: Yeah, that's definitely because the way to go I always remember as a kid too Cuz.
Rym: I think the only reason I'm not so afraid of is that as a kid my mom always made me do it So I kind of built up a mental immunity.
Rym: But even then I always was afraid like what if I'm doing dishes?
Rym: And I just grabbed the Drano by mistake and fart in the sink.
Rym: Oh Luckily you can't cuz.
Rym: those Drano bottles are also scary looking.
Scott: yeah Well kids is here's a lesson that you everyone should know right now.
Scott: scary like don't use it in the toilet.
Rym: You know it says don't use in the toilet, and they're not kidding.
Rym: Yeah They're not hitting.
Scott: I you know I was so afraid of it that I was never in a position to make that mistake But I won.
Scott: I could have made that mistake quite easily.
Rym: It's kind of like mixing ammonia and bleach.
Rym: Don't do it.
Rym: Don't even bother ice can.
Rym: why just don't do it?
Rym: you might die.
Rym: a lot of old ladies Die of that or at least used to.
Scott: don't do that.
Scott: Well.
Scott: They all they all died already.
Scott: You have a news over there.
Rym: I kind of do kind of this.
Rym: I could have talked about this on Monday But I'm gonna go from the more human side instead of the technology side even though the technology here is really cool And I think we're gonna see a lot of this cyborg ization and such in the future great in our lifetime.
Rym: But the gist of the story is that there is a man Oscar Pistorius a world-class sprinter And he wanted to compete in the Olympics.
Rym: hmm.
Rym: There's one problem.
Rym: He has no legs Unlike coconut monkey at least has arms, but he has no legs.
Scott: well.
Scott: Did he ever have legs?
Scott: I assumed so it was he a world-class spinner when he had the legs.
Rym: I don't he's a double amputee.
Rym: I didn't read the whole story.
Rym: the deal is though.
Rym: He has artificial legs, so they decided all right well Maybe we'll let you compete in the Olympics.
Rym: And then they decided after doing some testing that no because you're using artificial legs You are not allowed to compete in the Olympics.
Rym: now the reason Why the specific reason was not that it's dangerous or that it's unfair because he'd lose or it's because his artificial Legs are so much better than real legs for running.
Rym: He is faster and better than any human could ever be with these artificial legs.
Scott: Well what it was is that they measured.
Scott: you know in many trials that he could expend less energy To go just as fast as normal people you know or other sprinters You know.
Scott: so he could actually run as fast as the other people But it would be easier for him to do it than it be them for them to do the same speed.
Rym: now I recommend you check out this article just to see a picture of the artificial legs.
Rym: They're really cool.
Rym: Yeah They're pretty cool, and I don't know I have a lot to say about this.
Rym: I mean on one hand I always knew this day would come and I'm sure it will be coming more and more in the future Because we saw this even not in earlier times where Pitchers in baseball There's a common injury you can get if you're a pitcher in baseball and there's a surgery that fixes it.
Rym: I forget all the details so correct me if I'm wrong But I pretty much.
Rym: the deal is if you get this injury you can like pull this tendon back And then sew it down somewhere and it fixes it But as a result it also makes you a lot stronger for pitching.
Rym: So there were debates about is it okay if a pitcher just gets that surgery and they're perfectly fine?
Rym: Or what if they pitch badly to try and get the injury just so they can get the surgery?
Rym: yeah, and we're getting to the point now where there are prosthetics and Replacement parts for human bodies that are arguably better.
Scott: well better for some uses.
Scott: I'm sure his legs are not.
Scott: those legs are made for running.
Scott: I'm sure he has different leg.
Rym: shoes are made for walking.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure he has different legs for walking around and you know his life is not as easy.
Rym: See that's the thing.
Rym: I am sure that he would much rather have legs.
Scott: I'm also, but you know that you can makes.
Scott: you know we don't we're not at the point yet We can make a body part that is superior in all ways to the body parts We currently have.
Scott: but at the same time because the world we've made is a world that is designed for you know Human parts if we could redesign the whole world to make it more convenient for like you know Wheelchairs then all of a sudden people without wheelchairs would actually have a hard time.
Rym: Well, I think it's also just the fact that the technology is not there yet to make something that is overall completely a hundred percent better.
Rym: That the thing is though that is going to happen in our lifetimes.
Rym: There's very little doubt in my mind that we're going to see a point in our lives where there will be maybe an artificial eye Or an artificial ear an artificial hand that is better in every possible way Than what a human being naturally could achieve and at that point.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I find that really interesting.
Rym: I mean on one hand Definitely this is great for people who are injured But there are going to be people who will want to upgrade.
Rym: not kind of like with vision.
Rym: you can do this with glasses now.
Rym: You can get glasses if you have bad vision.
Rym: they give you 20/20 vision.
Rym: You can also if you want get glasses that give you 2010 vision.
Rym: I in fact did that.
Rym: I get.
Rym: my glasses now actually give me better than normal vision.
Rym: I paid extra for that.
Rym: It's an option you can do.
Rym: there are people with perfectly good vision who buy fancy designer glasses that let them see better.
Scott: Well night vision goggles.
Rym: Yeah, but I think I don't know.
Rym: I feel like a lot of people are gonna be very resistant to the idea of someone cutting off their hand and getting a better devil hand Luke Skywalker or Fry?
Scott: yeah, I think the real issue here as it relates to sports right is that that's the other half of this conversation.
Scott: Is that a sport is a game?
Scott: It's a competition right and the you know the steroids falls into this too.
Scott: They sort of haven't answered the fundamental question, which is we have a competition you're testing something you're testing You know especially a versus competition like sprinting right.
Scott: and the question is that they haven't answered is what are you testing right?
Scott: and you know if you're testing you know the ability of you know a Unmodified human body to propel itself with its legs and you're you want it.
Scott: you and faster is better.
Scott: well like then Someone who doesn't have an unmodified human body can't really enter that competition, but if the competition is you know?
Scott: Any human body how fast can you make it move by any means possible?
Scott: Rockets and whatnot.
Rym: is the way like look at f1.
Rym: people think like.
Rym: people think car racing is just car racing.
Rym: but look at the difference between like Le Mans or F1 or kart racing and like f1 for example.
Rym: you think oh, it's testing driver skill.
Rym: well driver skill is one part of it.
Rym: But the other part of it is they're testing car technology within a certain set of constraints.
Rym: Yeah, if they wanted to test just drivers there, and they would give everyone the exact same car.
Scott: Yeah, not only that but they're testing car technology and driver skill for driving incredibly fast on a complicated route repeatedly over Like an hour or so of time as opposed to Le Mans which is an endurance race.
Scott: They're testing not how.
Scott: also they're testing how fast but also how long can you drive?
Rym: or NASCAR?
Rym: Which is testing largely driver strategy and that sort of thing.
Rym: yeah, there's there's and in in sports I don't know.
Rym: I feel like there are two directions to go with sports in the future.
Rym: and the thing is it's easy to make delineations now because all right you can tell if someone has become a cyborg or not.
Rym: It's obvious that someone has a cyborg body part.
Rym: What are we gonna?
Rym: Do when these things are organic?
Rym: Do when you can just cut off your leg and replace it with a vat grown leg?
Rym: that is just better.
Scott: I mean you know I don't really.
Scott: you know I don't have a problem with.
Scott: if you know sports go this way or sports go that way really doesn't matter to me.
Scott: But if in any game you really have to define the rules And you know what if you whatever the rules are defined as that's what it is And if it turns out that people like a sport better with different rules, then the rules will change.
Rym: well You know what I think I think in the long run.
Rym: What's going to happen.
Rym: Is that their sports in terms of athleticism I think are eventually going to disappear?
Rym: And I think that what will happen is because if human bodies and the way we interact with the world becomes so mutable Then games will no longer be games of physical prowess on such a direct low level because that's not interesting anymore.
Rym: You want someone to run faster you make a running guy you want someone to throw a javelin you make a guy with one?
Scott: Really really really big, but maybe maybe as an f1 Whereas there is the mechanical component of who can make the fastest car it'll become who can make the fastest run.
Rym: Well, that's what I'm saying.
Rym: I think what's going to happen is we're going to see Competitions that are purely technical or purely you know looking at the aspect of what can we do within the constraints of the physical world?
Rym: And kind of like f1.
Rym: we're all right.
Rym: here are the constraints of this competition.
Rym: you can build a cyborg as long as you don't Break any of these rules.
Rym: go nuts.
Rym: and I think in terms of sports We will.
Rym: I think all sports are eventually going to become games entirely of skill and strategy and not at all of athleticism.
Rym: Yeah, I think that is the because I mean look at how many sports.
Rym: we've talked about this before.
Rym: but like baseball the strategy of baseball Has become so perfected that the who wins and loses comes down to such minute factors as in this guy is 1% stronger because he trained 1% more and as a result.
Rym: It's 1% more home runs or the wind.
Rym: Yes, and at that point I feel like games with more strategy and at like skill and talent involved.
Rym: like hockey though hockey Eventually, we'll have this problem to all game hockey.
Scott: I think we'll have the problem last.
Scott: well No football will also last a very long time.
Rym: Yes, because football is not completely exhausted.
Rym: and also they change the rules of football.
Scott: Yeah, they change them all the time you get.
Scott: every time football turns the referees don't even know all the rules of football.
Scott: Yeah, I could link you to some football rules, and we're not talking about soccer.
Scott: Sorry Europeans and other people not we're talking about a real sport.
Scott: I actually I can send you some rules from the NFL official rule book that you could not understand what they are.
Rym: dude I've been to football games for half the time.
Rym: something weird happens and the whole audience crowd is like what's going on?
Rym: I mean football is the only sport where the ref will come out and everyone gets quiet.
Rym: the ref says The rule was blah blah happened therefore Blah that doesn't happen in hockey.
Rym: in hockey something happens And then the ref scope mumble mumble mumble mumble and then the game just continues and someone's sitting in a box.
Scott: I know most of those crazy football rules, but not all of them.
Scott: It's really yeah, that's.
Scott: part of what makes football entertaining though is when crazy stuff happens like that.
Rym: You know I I've noticed that in any sport whenever something crazy happens It always seems like that makes it a lot more fun like hot.
Rym: Whenever a crazy fight breaks out that game is ten times more memorable.
Scott: Oh, yeah, all right, so my news here, right?
Scott: What do you got?
Scott: they did this scientific study?
Scott: Science involving neurology's.
Scott: you like those neurology.
Scott: I like fusiform.
Rym: Gyri all right.
Scott: Here's what they did.
Scott: is that they did here.
Scott: They took some wine.
Scott: You like wine right?
Rym: I do in fact like wine.
Rym: I could go on I could do a show about wine But I don't think you want.
Scott: they had a whole bunch of the wine and the wine was all the same.
Rym: Joke about whining instead.
Scott: Anyway, they had a whole bunch of wine.
Scott: It was all the same one and they put it in bottles and some of the bottles were $10 wine and some were $90 wine, but it's all the same wine.
Rym: I just see what they did there.
Rym: just different bottles right kind of like on Penn and Teller's bullshit.
Rym: But they had the hose water.
Scott: yep exactly, but this is a study and not just Dote hose wine.
Scott: yeah, so they had hosed dad all this normal wine And I don't know if it was good or bad or what I?
Scott: Imagine they must have redone the study with different wines because they're the professionals not me right and They had some of it.
Scott: was you know some of it.
Scott: people drank thinking it was cheap and some of it.
Scott: people drank thinking it was fancy right.
Scott: and What they did is they?
Scott: They like scan people's brains like for pleasure or something like that.
Scott: I don't know the details of that But I guess it was a percent signal charge in the mo FC is what they were looking at the mosque.
Rym: Yeah, it's my favorite part of the brain other than the fusiform gyrus yep.
Scott: And they have a little graph here, and there's a whole article that you can read.
Scott: and the little graph I don't know.
Scott: I like the hippocampus to write the little graph has has the x the y axis is the Percent signal change in the mo FC and the x-axis is time right and there's a little arrow and the arrow points to zero on the time track.
Rym: you know I'm just picturing a Completely made-up graph that doesn't say anything.
Scott: It's a son, but but the point at the graph here.
Scott: I'll read the the zero the God the zero on the graph.
Rym: What is the study find?
Scott: basically that?
Scott: You if you think the what if the wine is more expensive even before you drink it your pleasure will start going up and then after you drink it will go up even more.
Rym: and If now did it did that correlate with self-assessment of enjoyment and self-assessment of the wine itself?
Scott: Or was it just noted in the brain that the graph here is with Brain X?
Rym: so just the break because I'm curious because I can think of one explanation.
Scott: that isn't I know.
Scott: here's the second graph Which is the the ranking which which people said was better.
Rym: Do they coincide?
Rym: uh?
Scott: Pretty much yeah people said the more expensive ones were better.
Rym: Well, it's like that Dilbert.
Rym: the more expensive shoes are clearly superior.
Scott: the chart shows that people rank taste of a $45 wine higher than The same wine priced at five dollars and the same for a different wine marked at 90 and 10.
Scott: So I guess they had two wines.
Scott: one of them was $45 and five and the other one was 90 and 10. the got.
Scott: the original graph that I sucked at explaining Says this the text on that says this graph shows the activity in the brains pleasure center.
Scott: There's more activity with wine subjects think cost $90 a bottle than the same wine priced at $10.
Rym: well I remember two similar studies one where they took McDonald's wrappers and McDonald's logos and put them on food or didn't put them on food and Children ranked McDonald's branded food.
Rym: that was identical much much higher in terms of taste and quality.
Rym: and there was that beer study where they took a bunch of beer drinkers and they did you know a Double blind beer test and they found that most people couldn't tell it all and in fact often preferred beer that they had added vinegar To as part of the test.
Scott: Yeah, but basically I think this this this is from let's see Caltech Stanford great Yeah, so smart places is from.
Scott: I've suspected for a long time and there's been evidence but now I think there's a preponderance of evidence that suggests that the amount that people say they like something or You know do it in fact like something the amount of pleasure people get from something is Not entirely just based on the qualities the inherent qualities of that something.
Rym: It's just that the human brain is complex and all these sorts of factors even subconsciously can affect the way you perceive the world.
Rym: I mean look at the placebo effect.
Rym: You can if you believe that something will alleviate pain.
Rym: Oftentimes you will feel as though you experience less pain, even though nothing has changed.
Scott: Yep, and yeah, so I Do think though that you know the professional wine tasty people the real Professional wine tasty people not the people pretending.
Scott: but you know, they drink wines that are all just labeled ABCDEFG.
Scott: They don't know which ones are which or how much they cost.
Scott: So that's that's still a fair test there, but You know next time, you know, you see someone driving a BMW you're talking about how great it is.
Scott: Well, maybe if it was the same exact car, but it said like POS on it.
Scott: They wouldn't like it as much.
Rym: but by the same token if I was driving a Horizon, let's say a Plymouth horizon, but it had a Ferrari logo on it and I paid $100,000 for it.
Rym: I'm probably not gonna have a good time.
Rym: No, probably not You know.
Rym: I think what really rings true in the end is just Eat what tastes good to you and drink what tastes good to you.
Rym: and if you like the $5 wine Buy the $5 wine.
Rym: if you want to impress your friends say it was a $40 wine.
Rym: They don't know.
Scott: I think the real goal here is to just the to avoid marketing and avoid You know sort of like, you know getting preconceived notions of what if things are gonna be good or bad before.
Rym: the same time Get preconceived notions that things are expensive and good and then things will taste better to you.
Rym: if your brain is messing with you.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it.
Scott: just just have really high expectations of really cheap stuff and sudden maybe that's how Scott Johnson watches all those.
Rym: No, I think it's purely the dollar to unit fund ratio there because sure it may be a crappy anime But he only paid a dollar for it.
Rym: I know right Plus that's also the man who showed us cowboy bebop.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but hey the point is is that Yeah Expectations have a great effect on actual perceived pleasure in the end.
Rym: Anyway things of the day.
Rym: So what do you got for me Scott on this here Thursday thing of the day?
Scott: Well, there's a. you know, if a cartoon was made in 1938 that cartoon is in the public domain.
Rym: Uh, Yes, it is.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So here is a cartoon.
Scott: I think it is a merry melody.
Scott: if I if I man it's on YouTube I don't know how long it'll say on YouTube because you know while it is Public domain that you know YouTube and someone might complain and then you know without even asking questions.
Scott: They take it off Whatever, but it is.
Scott: this is like the highest quality YouTube video I've ever seen and it's a. it's called catnip College.
Scott: You can't go wrong watching a merry melody.
Scott: I haven't watched it yet, and I don't think I've ever seen it But it doesn't freaking matter.
Rym: Is it better or worse than I like to sing it in the moon?
Scott: I don't think it's as good as that one.
Scott: That's the best one.
Scott: Nothing beats that one but This one it can't be bad.
Scott: It's a merry melody I don't know.
Rym: I'm highly partial to the old Bugs Bunny versus that opera singer even though as a kid I loved it and then as an adult I saw it again.
Rym: All I could think was wow Bugs Bunny's an asshole.
Rym: Yeah, he is.
Scott: That's why I didn't deserve that.
Rym: That's why he's so great And Daffy Duck needed to be committed.
Rym: God damn.
Scott: Yeah he did.
Scott: What was your favorite?
Scott: We could do the show on Looney Tunes instead.
Scott: We could just cut it.
Rym: right now We'll save that one cuz I'd have to watch a bunch again.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: And also it's tough because I like a lot of Looney Tunes but at the same time the old Donald Duck versus Chip and Dale.
Rym: Okay My favorite cartoons ever.
Scott: You have to pick a single or old Warner Brothers cartoon a single one.
Scott: not not a character But like a single one, which one do you pick?
Rym: Apple core Baltimore.
Rym: That's your friend.
Scott: Isn't that Disney?
Rym: Yeah, it is, but it's so funny.
Scott: No, it can't be Disney.
Scott: Ah Pick a Looney Tune or a melody or something like that.
Rym: All right, I could pick one of those really old racist ones.
Rym: It's funny how they remade a lot of those not quite so racist.
Scott: Yeah, they did.
Rym: I'm kind of glad they did that.
Scott: Yeah, it's good.
Scott: Anyway, no, you didn't pick one.
Rym: Oh right now.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know you said the opera singer All right.
Rym: I'm thinking hiding in the stove I think the best line in that one because there was a similar.
Rym: there's been a lot of pair of Homages to that.
Scott: that's my favorite one.
Rym: Just the line a lot.
Rym: when he comes into the room and the other guys locked up and he says I know you've done it.
Rym: I don't know how you've done it, but I know you.
Scott: I think I think that's the other Mugsy cartoon.
Scott: that's not the same one.
Scott: It doesn't matter because that I wanted though is is up there.
Scott: It's way up.
Rym: that line is just one of the funniest things.
Rym: Yeah, it is So All right, so um, I Well, you know I went skiing last weekend and my neck is not broken.
Rym: I've determined it and I think most of my pain is gone.
Rym: So I don't think I permanently injured myself, but I remembered skiing and I remember thinking wow, you know It's really not easy for all my friends who don't ski Like it's kind of hard to show like what it's like to be skiing and I was just thinking about that Like man,
Scott: I'm sure someone is skied with a camera on their head.
Rym: I'm gonna find something.
Rym: but I stumbled upon this on College Humor and I figure this is also interesting because In the summer, you know when I can't ski because I plan to ski a lot from now on.
Rym: But I used to mountain bike a lot and I haven't mountain biked much in the last.
Rym: I don't know three years That's the right verbiage.
Scott: Shouldn't it be mountain bickin?
Scott: I haven't been Anyway.
Rym: So I also remember as a kid whenever I go biking cuz my mom like I come home cut up in it Like I have bruises and I come over like a broken helmet or I like my bike could be just completely destroyed.
Scott: My mom would always be like what the hell were you doing?
Rym: and I always thought like man, I should just bring a camera and show her and then maybe she understand like what it is that I do here, but I Saw this and I thought of that.
Rym: and here you go if you ever wondered what it's like to go mountain biking.
Rym: now I'm not talking like downhill mountain biking I'm talking single track with I guess intermediate to like the lower end of the advanced tricks.
Rym: I'll admit there are like five things in this video that there's no way in hell I could have done.
Rym: But if you ever wondered what it's like to go single track mountain biking like that check this out.
Rym: It's uh, It's super fun, and I highly recommend you do it if you like getting hurt.
Rym: It won't get hurt.
Rym: Actually, yes, you will.
Rym: Often when it comes I'll tell you what.
Rym: here's the secret.
Rym: if you skiing and mountain biking have one thing in common one very important Thing.
Rym: if you see someone who is good at skiing or mountain biking They are only that way because they have hurt themselves several times to get that good.
Rym: Yep Right.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So so shoddy Dibs no, I win now All right, so you got to talk about all these silly games that people play doorknob.
Rym: Yeah, I think we should because we thought these games are kind of this cultural heritage.
Rym: I don't know how it is in the rest of the world.
Rym: in Europe I'm sure they're similar games.
Rym: But in the United States here, there is a long and hallowed tradition of Adolescent males and to a lesser extent females.
Scott: They have different games some of them because I don't know Clapping games with the with the rhymes that I can't play.
Rym: I don't know how those work, but I have not known many girls who played doorknob as children.
Scott: No, not really yet.
Rym: It's weird how as a kid I never remember anyone teaching me how to play doorknob.
Rym: I never remember like thinking oh the game doorknob It was just like as far as I can tell as long as I was sentient if a kid farted and I said doorknob I had the unmitigated Human right to wail on them Pretty much.
Scott: I mean, it's so strange how there are these games and I remember that I didn't.
Scott: I wasn't playing the game forever.
Scott: There was a point at which the game sort of came into Daily protocol, but it's.
Scott: it's a game.
Scott: You're always Playing at least among your you know, close friend family company, you know.
Scott: And the game is always on you know, but it's not like.
Scott: it's not always on like you're always thinking about it.
Scott: It's just During.
Scott: certain events during the day can bring the game into into play, you know And it's you never stop playing it.
Scott: There's no winner loser or anything.
Scott: There might be a winner loser of the moment, but there's no there's no end of the game.
Scott: It's just this Sort of social rule you put into your life.
Scott: that doesn't really mean anything.
Scott: But you just put it there and it just for no reason whatsoever.
Scott: but somehow that rule and that Protocol spreads like a meme among everybody and everyone's plan.
Scott: even people you've never met before are playing the same game Slightly different rules.
Rym: these games spread long before there was an internet.
Rym: It's not like.
Rym: the internet allowed this to happen.
Rym: But yet somehow kids in the Midwest played pretty much the same games that kids in California played.
Rym: Yep, except pogs Yep.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So so the first game I think the most widespread game of all is shotgun.
Scott: Now shotgun is triggered whenever a group of people are going to get into a motor vehicle.
Rym: The thing is shotgun.
Rym: What I what I find interesting about is that it's one of the few of these games that serves a purpose.
Rym: It serves a very specific purpose and I've noticed a lot of people seem to play this game more When car space or cars are limited like when you're in high school.
Rym: you have the one friend who's 16 and has a car and You're cramming like eight people in that car.
Rym: You can cram an infinite number of people in the backseat and it totally sucks But only one person sitting in the passenger seat.
Rym: So sitting there is like this holy throne
Scott: and you know, since it usually happens when not everyone owns a car I mean if everyone owns a car then it's not really a big deal because you take enough cars to be comfortable and You know, but when there's only one person who's a driver that person's like, ah, I will always be comfortable But everyone else is like, oh shit.
Scott: Only one of us can be comfortable.
Scott: Who's it gonna be?
Rym: Yep Battle it's like when I was a kid in Michigan just because of the nature of the area No one ever played shotgun because pretty much everyone had a car.
Rym: I mean you could get a. you could buy for $300 you could buy a car that'll get you to school.
Scott: But you need because you know, not everyone's gonna be comfortable.
Scott: You need some protocol for determining who gets to be comfortable this time and you know There are many things you could arrange to make it fair.
Scott: But in the end everyone just plays shotgun, which is the game of shotgun.
Rym: now I remember that we had basically one car among the entire front.
Rym: Well, maybe one and a half cars among the entire front row crew when we were freshmen Yeah, freshman at least and sophomores.
Scott: We still yeah, we still suck.
Scott: We had more cars.
Rym: barely We had like two and a half cars.
Scott: Yeah, then we got more cars within a year, too Yeah, because we all had money.
Rym: finally Yeah, and then we lost all that money because we got cars and now we and now we have cars and money.
Rym: Yeah, I barely time.
Rym: I barely have a car.
Rym: That's true But it's funny how because I remember we were talking about board games a few episodes ago and I remember I said something about how you can tell the geeks or the board game nerds from normal human beings.
Rym: because If the geeks sit
Scott: around
Rym: and play a game made for three-year-olds called peanut butter and jelly Where you play down cards and make peanut butter and jelly sandwiches Within five minutes there's going to be an argument as to a possible race condition in the game That is ambiguously defined in the rules.
Rym: Yeah, and the timing considerations of peanut butter and jelly and I point out that I don't know within Two days of the crew front row crew coalescing into a body that had access to 1.5 cars We ran into the problem of how to deal with shotgun because you see we'd all be going somewhere.
Rym: We all walk outside and No, we had never really defined what the rules of shotgun were.
Rym: someone would just say it and eventually, you know It was such a high demand commodity that we'd all kind of stand outside the door and then suddenly everyone would yell shotgun Simultaneously and then there'd just be a fight.
Scott: So then what do you do?
Scott: it 80 because you know being gamers We all do the best we can to win the game.
Scott: every time we were paying attention where it's on our minds We want to win.
Scott: winning is important not even perhaps more important than the actual comfort you get by winning.
Rym: and I think that the It came to a head when we were sitting around in the house and someone was like, alright, let's go to the Blah, and I can yep, and then we all said alright, we got a deal with this.
Scott: So we came up with a bunch of rules Like if there was a tie then whoever touched the passenger side door handle first gets to be shotgun.
Scott: But if they pull that handle that's preventing the door from unlocking when it's supposed to unlock.
Scott: then they lose their shotgun privileges.
Scott: And after someone calls shotgun someone else can say not bitch to avoid sitting in the middle of the backseat.
Rym: Some people would go for the preemptive not bitch because they knew they wouldn't get shotgun.
Rym: But no one at no one ever goes for second place.
Scott: no, no, and then we figured out that you couldn't say shotgun until like some conditions where everyone is walking towards the Vehicle ride and the course was set.
Rym: We tried a bunch of different things originally like alright Everyone has to be outside.
Rym: So then we'd get into a situation We're like everyone's going outside and I go to get my keys and I walk out and I see everyone Standing on the edge of the door with a foot sticking out.
Rym: the doors is waiting.
Scott: Many times people would step the last person would you know hide in the bathroom or something or go actually go to the bathroom and Step out last and say shotgun.
Scott: as they stepped out.
Rym: Yeah, I mean everybody.
Rym: much people gamed it as much as they could.
Scott: That's that's how a game goes.
Scott: you game it.
Rym: I think the eventual like final rule was effectively that the group as a whole had to have come to a Consensus as to where we were going to go what we were going to do there and had begun Generally as a group making movement toward achieving that goal towards
Scott: the motor vehicle.
Scott: Yeah, and you know We were going to actually at when we got to the motor vehicle.
Scott: that was gonna be we're gonna go.
Scott: you could you know Cuz it might have been walking towards the motor vehicle then doing something else then going back to the car and then go.
Rym: Yep, if any - if there if there was any action to be taken between Moving and then getting into the car other than opening and closing trivial doors Elevators, I don't think they counted.
Rym: then it was all up for grabs again.
Scott: Yeah, so it was.
Scott: we got quite serious about that and then you know We only lost that seriousness as we got more cars and drove less.
Rym: Yeah, but that is.
Rym: I think shotgun is a time-honored tradition among college kids.
Scott: I think it's a time also the high school kids.
Scott: it's pretty much very important for and for people who are Putting a lot of people in fewer cars and you know People are wanting comfort now.
Rym: equally important among these games and there are so many different now this one.
Rym: Remember how I learned about it.
Scott: Oh really I don't.
Rym: I was watching a movie and I don't remember what movie But I've seen a lot of movies.
Rym: I was a little kid and it's a bunch of kids and they're about to go somewhere and something's gonna happen.
Rym: and Then suddenly one of them goes one two three not it and then they all go not it one kid goes.
Rym: Ah, man Yeah, I was like, wow, that's a really elegant way.
Rym: I didn't think that's a really elegant way.
Scott: I thought hahahahaha Basically when there's something that has to be done By someone like doing the Drano or taking the trash out or paying the check at the restaurant Right one person has to accomplish this task.
Scott: The task must be done by a member of the group right now, but no one wants to do the task.
Scott: You just go one two three Not it and you put a finger on your nose and the last the last person to put a finger on their nose has to Do it.
Rym: I think there are a lot of different variations on the game, but I think the basic game is determining.
Rym: It's the shortest straw game and that I like in Michigan.
Rym: actually I swear this wasn't racist but a lot of people would say nigs as opposed to dibs, but the etymology of that and I remember very clearly because playing Euchre Right, if you screw up the rules in Euchre like you play now This is also.
Rym: you can do this legitimately to cheat and if no one catches you then you can win.
Rym: But if you play a card that you weren't allowed to play and you're caught it's a renege, you know You've reneged on your deal now just because a lot of people in the Midwest pronounce things Horribly wrong.
Rym: It was renege.
Rym: Oh, man renege.
Rym: and because they pronounced it that way Renege and nigg eventually just meant basically not it.
Rym: or you suck or you screwed up.
Rym: So they basically it was just reverse not it.
Rym: Mm-hmm or reverse dibs not reverse not it.
Rym: That's dibs.
Scott: Yeah, dibs is the exact opposite of the not it game.
Scott: It's when everyone wants something but only there's only one resource and that many people desire and it's sort of the same game as shotgun.
Scott: but basically you just say it's usually like a Saving a seat for the future like hey, man.
Rym: I got two pork buns.
Scott: I got dibs, you know, there are two pork buns.
Scott: There are six people.
Scott: you say dibs.
Scott: now one of the pork buns is yours.
Rym: Now I noticed something really interesting about both these games.
Rym: is that we were talking earlier in the show about like what a sport tests.
Rym: It seems like what these games test is Who desires the thing the most and who has the presence of mind to get it?
Rym: But it's not presence of mind.
Rym: as in Like I say I got pork buns and suddenly luke is standing next to me and then suddenly both pork buns are in his mouth But instead it is you know Who who wants it.
Rym: if you really want it then you have the presence of mind.
Rym: whoever wanted it the most was thinking I really want that pork bun.
Rym: enough to think i'm going to say dibs Yep, or i'm going to say not it and I also.
Rym: there's two ways to play.
Rym: Not it.
Rym: the fundamental ways are either everyone says something and then whoever says it last has to do it or There's the surreptitious, uh finger on the nose, which is my favorite way.
Scott: Yeah, you just put your finger on your nose and you don't say anything.
Rym: and then eventually, you know like scott's got his finger on his nose and alex has got his finger on his nose and emily's got her finger on his On her nose and i'm sitting there and I go.
Scott: nothing has a finger in Rym's nose.
Rym: I see and I go and I look and I see pete doesn't have his finger on his nose.
Rym: Oh crap, and I put my finger in my nose And then pete looks around and goes.
Scott: Ah And he sees that everyone but him has a finger on the nose.
Rym: It's another presence of mind thing and I like it.
Scott: Well, you know these games in addition to being fun games of winning and losing and also sort of immature are.
Scott: there's social mechanics that You know resolve Situations in a way that everyone can agree upon and generally it works out because basically the person who wants something the most Will usually get it and the person who doesn't want something the most will usually avoid it.
Scott: So, you know out of a group of 10 people if there's something no one wants to do But one person really doesn't want to do it and one person kind of doesn't want to do it this mechanic arranges it.
Scott: So even though the one person kind of doesn't want to do it they'll usually end up doing it because everyone wants to do it even less than they do and You know it did.
Scott: it kind of works for keeping people happy and together without having a fight.
Scott: I mean, what's the alternative?
Scott: is you sit around and you discuss it for a while because you know.
Scott: or Everyone's fighting and yelling and hitting at each other.
Scott: I mean Or the mature solution where you just say yeah, i'll do it even though I don't want to okay mature.
Rym: Now of course these games can be distilled to the fundamental thing that is known among a lot of people of just The game.
Rym: and there's two, you know, that's the game where you're sitting around.
Rym: then suddenly someone says Ah shit, I lose because they thought of the game or I win which means oh they thought of the game and no one else Did they win?
Rym: Yep, and or there's a lot of like.
Rym: I remember the game in michigan that a lot of people play just because you know That was my childhood.
Rym: Everything I think of from childhood is from the midwest.
Rym: It was pediddle.
Rym: That's the stupidest name for a game ever.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: It's basically the cyclops game.
Rym: if you're in a car and you see Another car with only one headlight on you punch the roof of the car and yell for diddle And basically you win and everyone else loses because they didn't think of it.
Scott: But what about the game?
Scott: yellow car or like punch buggy?
Scott: Same game, you see like a volkswagen then you hit someone else.
Rym: Yep Or actually what we played was child molester and it was if you see.
Rym: Hey, if you see a conversion van with no windows in the back or one black circular window.
Rym: Yes, that has no company name and no commercial plates.
Rym: Ah And it has to be beat up and it has to be painted brown.
Scott: That just double points.
Scott: Yes There's actually a scary child molester.
Scott: ish car the car dealer outside that I saw it's it's for sale.
Scott: Yeah, it's a pretty scary looking car.
Scott: I don't know who would buy it except a scary person.
Scott: I think they should just whoever looks like a kid.
Rym: I think they should just arrest of a cow catcher.
Scott: No, i'll show you the car.
Scott: It's really scary.
Scott: I think whoever buys that car.
Scott: They should just arrest them.
Rym: Maybe it's a trap.
Scott: Maybe it is.
Scott: but yet I think the the game that is played the most the game We're trying to stop playing because unlike some of the other games.
Scott: It doesn't serve a great purpose.
Rym: I'm one of the few men In the world who has who has played the game for as long as I did and transcended it.
Rym: Yeah, scott didn't believe me.
Rym: He tried.
Rym: he didn't believe that I could do it.
Rym: I didn't believe I could do it, but i've done it.
Scott: i've mostly kind of gotten rid of it kind of But the game is doorknob.
Scott: now The game of doorknob does have a purpose and the purpose is to prevent the old situation.
Scott: because pre doorknob, right?
Scott: What was the situation?
Scott: it was whoever smelt it dealt it whoever made the rhyme committed the crime, you know Who farted bla bla bla bla bla doorknob.
Scott: the game of doorknob sort of encourages a few things.
Rym: first of all It slightly encourages not farting at all or holding your farts in until appropriate or or or totally farting And then getting away with it and watching your friend p get totally wailed out even though it totally wasn't him.
Scott: That's that can also happen.
Scott: But you know, it would have been so difficult to create a game that would actually discourage actual farting, you know among, uh, you know People.
Scott: So we made the doorknob game and we didn't make it.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's a game that just sort of came out of nowhere.
Scott: I mean and
Rym: it's not always farting I've seen kids play it where if someone swears or if someone says just a certain random word or just yeah
Scott: I mean i've been playing it sometime in high school like the game caught on I don't know
Rym: how
Scott: and it sort of still is Somewhat present a little bit.
Rym: if you don't know the rules of doorknob, it's pretty simple.
Rym: There is a condition.
Rym: the condition is always active.
Rym: if someone meets the condition Anyone who can see them can say the word doorknob.
Rym: Yep, and that is an indication you have put forth a challenge.
Rym: Basically, once the doorknob condition has been met and doorknob has been stated Anyone who is within sight at the time has the legal right.
Rym: as far as i'm concerned the moral imperative to Wail on.
Rym: now wail is the technical term we'll get.
Scott: punch them in the arm repeatedly and with to inflict pain.
Rym: Yes wailing on is a very specific kid thing.
Rym: that means punching other kids in the arm.
Scott: Yeah, you can't you know punching them in the face.
Scott: You're not.
Scott: you're not kicking them in the beans You're not twisting the nips.
Rym: It's whoa.
Rym: Oh Maybe we should talk about the the first rule of the front row crew.
Scott: It's not so much a game though that fits into the show, but it is the first lot.
Rym: Well, yeah, if anyone has a game that involves titty twisters, you are not cool people.
Rym: Well, unless you're into bdsm, then I guess that's okay.
Scott: I guess that's not really a game.
Scott: That's just sort of a.
Rym: Let me put it this way the first law ever ever passed by the front row crew and it was passed unanimously Was that no member of the front row crew shall ever under penalty of the same by everyone in the room?
Rym: Commits any act upon another front row.
Rym: crew members nipple in anger.
Scott: Yep So basically if I were to act upon rims nipple and anger and there were 10 people in the room I would Receive anger upon my nipples tenfold.
Rym: It was it was a quite.
Rym: It was you know, I for 10 eyes, I guess.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, no one no one does the titty twisters.
Rym: Yes now second base is totally okay.
Scott: Second base is an anger.
Rym: No now if you could somehow commit second base and anger That's just weird.
Scott: I guess.
Rym: yeah, I guess in A non-permitted I could see I could see a friendly like love punch with the right situation where you accidentally but even then That's not in anger that never happened.
Rym: Luckily.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah the game of doors.
Scott: Someone says doorknob you can.
Scott: then if you if let's say Rym farts I say doorknob That means I can hit Rym right now if Rym actually touches a doorknob not a door handle Not a door lever a doorknob.
Scott: if he touches a doorknob now he's safe.
Scott: I gotta let him go.
Rym: the way this game would usually work is there's a group of kids sitting in like a cabinet band camp And then you know someone rips one and then everyone just sits there quiet for a second and then someone Oftentimes it was Nardi when I was in band camp without even looking up would just say doorknob And then you no one ever hit it.
Rym: No if doorknob was called I don't think any kid ever would not fess up to it unless someone else stupidly fessed up to it.
Rym: But uh, pretty much one kid would just like Look at everyone and then suddenly just start running.
Scott: see now This is how.
Scott: this is why the game was so great.
Scott: it instead in the olden days I remember like elementary middle school before doorknob times it would be Who farted.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We don't know who farted.
Scott: they're not fessing up right but with doorknob, right?
Scott: If you fart and then say safety, no one can call doorknob on you.
Scott: So first it encourages people who fart to say safety and announce that they were the ones who indeed farted thus Preventing them from being doorknobbed and often it was kind of a safety.
Rym: as in.
Rym: what are you gonna do about it bitches?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: But then again, they just admitted to farting.
Scott: so you now, you know who farted And if it smells really bad, you know who to blame.
Scott: The second part is if they don't say safety because they're trying not to admit it Maybe they know it was really smelly or it was a really terrible one and they don't want to be known.
Scott: You get some ruckus when someone when someone says doorknob now They'll usually reveal themselves by running for the doorknob.
Scott: So in the end you find out who did it even if no one got beat up.
Scott: And most of the time the game of doorknob reveals the he who passed gas.
Rym: So, uh in van camp we uh, There i'm not gonna name names here But there was a person in the senior guy's cabin who was notorious for uh, letting them rip shall we say.
Rym: And this this this dude this uh, this drummer and bass player.
Rym: He had the the mighty flatulence He was proud of it.
Rym: In fact, in fact, he would whenever possible sit in wooden chairs that he could amplify it to the greatest possible effect.
Scott: Is he like whittling the chairs to create a sound channel?
Rym: Well the best chair to fart in if you want to make the noise are the wooden chairs.
Scott: they have like the kind of Sanding putting the snare drum under the chair for added effects.
Rym: He did fart on his snare drum more than once good god.
Scott: but uh Why don't you just play the?
Scott: uh, you know, the the butter phone in the in the van there?
Rym: What there's?
Rym: there's no such thing as a butter phone.
Scott: Yeah, there is.
Rym: it sounds like That's not a butter phone that's a butphonium.
Rym: So, uh And doorknob was the game we played but the dude would always sit right next to the door because he premeditated.
Rym: So one day he's sitting in the middle of the room We're all sitting around and and another unnamed person who is is famous from another story I told about bandcamp once about a bathroom and an overflowing toilet Sneaks over From the outside of the cabin and he removes the doorknob from the door to the cabin.
Rym: And uh one is ripped doorknob is called he saunters over to her with the door knowing that no one's even gonna bother And then he says where the fuck did the doorknob go?
Scott: and Let me tell you that was a good day.
Rym: Oh, yeah, because there was no doorknob within like a hundred yards.
Scott: Was this?
Scott: I imagine this is a large man.
Rym: He was uh, quite large.
Scott: the large men are known for two for the flatulence.
Rym: They're also known for not being able to run at all.
Scott: thus The game of doorknob has the the added bonus there and that the people who are typically more flatulent Are typically more threatened by the doorknobbing.
Rym: So, uh About six months ago, maybe seven months ago one day I farted I ripped one I was playing some game on the wii and scott says doorknob and I said don't you fucking dare i'm done with that game.
Scott: Yeah, the way the game of doorknob ends is when you basically fart you don't say anything and if someone calls doorknob on you You basically.
Scott: because when you're playing the game of doorknob, it's weird You don't consciously decide you just sort of have this rule of society built into you as like you have to actually think outside the box to act outside the rules of the game and
Rym: I mean It's definitely ingrained deep in the prime old part parts.
Scott: when I was at rit if someone called doorknob on me legitimately And they started hitting me I just couldn't fight back.
Scott: that wouldn't even come to me.
Scott: But the way to end the game of doorknob is to say if you hit me i'll break your face And thus nobody will call doorknob on you or try to hit you.
Scott: because well You're not gonna just cave into the doorknob because you're not playing that game.
Rym: You'll actually you know fight back cannot describe to you how difficult it was to not say safety that time.
Scott: I farted Yeah, because it was like you have to really have to consciously do it.
Rym: It's like we're sitting there.
Rym: we're playing like icy hockey or something and then Icy hockey.
Rym: Yes And then scott looks at me like you didn't say safety.
Rym: He just gives me this look and i'm looking at him right back.
Rym: Like are you gonna say it?
Rym: because I didn't say it?
Rym: I'm, daring you that was the end of that game.
Scott: Yeah, and so the game mostly ended pretty surprised.
Scott: The result is now people just letting him rip like all over the place Which is fantastic, I guess I don't know.
Rym: There's something about these games where they're.
Rym: They're fun and that's most of what I have to say about them.
Rym: Yeah, they're kind of like a rite of childhood.
Rym: They're a rite of passage.
Rym: Everyone plays them and every group has their own little like idiosyncratic rules about the games or special conditions.
Rym: And it's just.
Rym: it's great fun there.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely, you know, it's it's I guess It's something.
Rym: Is that all we got to say about that?
Scott: I don't i'm hungry.
Scott: I want to eat.
Rym: Yeah, uh, it's thursday.
Scott: I kind of have to do some dishes before I cook.
Rym: Yeah We've been uh busy lately shall we say busy busy But there's stuff coming.
Rym: swag is on the way and uh It's coming.
Rym: I gotta tell you when you guys see the shirt that we're gonna be selling as soon as we get them printed.
Rym: Uh, this shirt is so we should hurry up.
Scott: Isn't the katsukan real soon?
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Rym: But uh, this shirt is so high quality.
Rym: I don't think you understand.
Scott: We'll see how many people want it.
Scott: Hopefully all of them.
Rym: the hint Is pockner and that's all i'm going to say.
Rym: great This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the rss feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and rpgs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tom foolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in itunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night All right.
Rym: So, uh, you might notice the show's still going.
Scott: emily just reminded us of the one game We forgot which is the perhaps the game i've played the longest just playing this in elementary school the game of jinx where If you say the exact same thing at the exact same time as someone else One of those two people or more multiples of people may call jinx
Rym: In which time you cannot say a word until someone says your name.
Rym: if you don't know how jinx is played Watch I think it was season one or two with this.
Scott: Let's let's do an example.
Scott: Let's both say, uh, You know, hello at the same time right one two three.
Scott: Hello jinx jinx jinx double jinx.
Rym: I don't know There's different I forget the exact right.
Rym: I think scott won that one because uh, He said jinx again before I thought to say it again, right?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So because uh, basically now Rym is jinxed but scott just said my name.
Scott: so it doesn't matter ah shit But if I didn't if I had not have said the word Rym He would have been jinxed and he would have been unable to say anything at all Until I said Rym and then he would have been able to talk again.
Rym: now, uh There was an episode of the simpsons where lisa has all of her.
Rym: uh girly friends stay over and do girly things and among the girly things they uh They basically just torment bard and they jinx him.
Rym: and there there's a perhaps the perfect example of How ingrained these games are because this interaction has probably happened between many young boys and their fathers in the course of life.
Rym: Bart is trying to get his dad to say his name.
Rym: His dad won't say his name.
Rym: So finally he says ah dad say my name.
Rym: Why i'm jinxed and he just punches him.
Rym: Bard's dad punches him right then and there.
Rym: Oh, what'd you do?
Rym: that for rules the jungle boy?
Scott: Yeah, he was he was jinxed and he was talking.
Scott: so he got hit.
Scott: That's That's how the game works.
Rym: So, yeah, we couldn't let this show go without talking about jinx.
Scott: Yeah, I can't believe I forgot that one.
Scott: Uh, if there are any others we have gravely forgotten.
Scott: or if you have local variations or maybe games that are you know That you play that we didn't mention because we don't know about them.
Scott: And so forms are for people but only the always on games.
Rym: don't tell me about punch for punch or uh bloody knuckles or quarters.
Rym: There's gonna be another show about that at some point.
Scott: Yeah We're talking about the games that are just sort of always on.
Scott: you're always playing them.
Rym: They're not the game that the third graders taught you about when you were in first grade exactly.