Rym: It's Tuesday January 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight We talk about those house rules.
Rym: y'all be rolling with.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Man, I don't know if tonight's episode is going to top last night's.
Scott: Oh last night I was the best episode of GeekNights.
Rym: I think I think that really is pretty much our triumph.
Rym: It's it's over.
Scott: after this I mean you can always tell when an episode is quality because it's so easy to do.
Scott: the episodes that are hard to do are Usually bad and the easy ones do are very good and it was like four hours long.
Scott: So Good time.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: So yeah today you can just forget today's episode.
Scott: It's not worth it.
Rym: Yeah, it is New Year's Day.
Rym: So you're lucky.
Rym: We're even doing an episode today.
Scott: You're real lucky.
Scott: We're just we got some time to kill and we're sort of waiting to for stomachs to settle and maybe eat dinner and go to Bed cuz you got to go to work tomorrow.
Rym: Well, really the only reason this is happening is that I have 12 fluid ounces of Red Bull right here.
Scott: Oh, yeah, cuz someone brought those to the party and they didn't drink them.
Rym: Oh, he drank one of them.
Scott: That's about all a man can drink.
Rym: So, uh, this is kind of important.
Rym: So I figured I should talk about this in the news, but Xbox Live it's down.
Scott: Wow, they killed a sold so many Xboxes on Christmas that all those people trying to sign in totally destroyed The the system there.
Rym: I think there is in fact a relevant penny arcade from some number of years ago.
Scott: Yeah, something like that, I mean the we didn't.
Scott: we had similar problems.
Scott: I mean I tried to go to the we store.
Scott: You know the we shopping channel on like Christmas Day or the day after Christmas and he wasn't working.
Scott: It was not going.
Rym: so think of this.
Rym: think about how many weaves have been purchased in the last I don't know four months.
Rym: pretty much every single one of them was a gift.
Rym: They all turned on at about 7 a.m.
Scott: Christmas Day and a large percentage of them went online Though not all of them because a lot of people, you know, can't set that shit up Of course, so we thought we had some problems later, but it turned out.
Rym: the wireless router just crapped out.
Scott: Yeah, just I reset the wireless router with the button.
Scott: that didn't help but unplugging it and then plugging it back in that work.
Rym: You know, it might not have helped that we had like 12 laptops in the house.
Scott: pretty much It's like we own one Mac.
Scott: but yet when people come over to visit us that are more max in the house than anything else and we're nerds with a Lot of computers like we got like five or six computers in this house, but goddamn
Rym: We really need to set up that Scott Johnson slash katsu computer in the living room to keep them busy.
Scott: Yeah I think we should.
Scott: really we should get a computer set up in the living room for people to use and Also, anyone who doesn't have a laptop should get one and I'm working on it.
Scott: You see I think we need to get a higher quality wireless access point.
Rym: remember I was going to buy your laptop only with a better processor and pretty much better everything else But the power went out.
Rym: Yeah, and I didn't and now I'm waiting for that better laptop.
Rym: That's not out.
Scott: I think anyone who wants to buy a laptop should wait exactly two months.
Scott: then you will.
Scott: Well about a month maybe but February is the month to buy laptops.
Scott: Let me tell you it's just a race.
Scott: Can I hold out whose January is when all the shits gonna go down and then in February when you're gonna be able to buy all the shit.
Rym: so I can say one thing though Microsoft is actually going to Refund the money for all the time down for the people who pay for Xbox Live.
Scott: No, that's nice of them at least.
Rym: Well, I don't get a refund for the time the we shopping channel was down, yeah Well, if anything you should probably pay Nintendo for the fact that you're not using their stupid wireless.
Scott: Actually, I bought about punch-out from them today, even though it doesn't have Mike Tyson in it.
Rym: But is it otherwise exactly Mike Tyson's punch-out?
Rym: I didn't look.
Scott: Yes, it's otherwise exactly Mike Tyson's punch-out and other than the fact that Mike Tyson is replaced with mr Dream who I assume is the exact same thing as Mike Tyson only looks different.
Scott: Ah Yeah And the word Mike Tyson has been removed.
Scott: well, obviously I played and I was fine.
Scott: I got.
Scott: I lost a bald bull twice, but I you know, I rematched him and got.
Rym: no you got to remember He goes but doom but doom but doom and on the second and a half of doom you punch him in the gut.
Scott: Yep and then After that was the second piston Honda fight and oh, that's like the first hard fight in the hole.
Scott: Yeah, he took me out.
Scott: He took me out and I couldn't you think you're ready for him Thing.
Scott: I told he does it twice.
Scott: Yeah, I totally forgot the order of the guys.
Scott: So I kept thinking the next guy was gonna be soda Popinski and he's way late in the game.
Scott: He was I think he's after that second piston Honda.
Scott: But yeah, I really wanted to get to sort of Popinski cuz he's hilarious.
Scott: His head is shaped like a bottle of soda pop.
Scott: All right, so what kind of what was your news wasn't it?
Scott: Yes, it was All right, so I got a double news here ready.
Scott: So in this glorious New Year's week, or I think the week before the New Year There were four game for new games for the Wii released in the u.s All right only four games.
Rym: You know what, you know four games they were I do but I think I'll let you Tell the world.
Scott: Well, the first one was called Kawasaki four by four quad bikes.
Rym: Oh those Kawasaki four by four whatever games cuz they have things like that in the arcade.
Rym: Let me tell you those are some great games.
Scott: Yeah, then they got classic British motor racing Monster trucks with an X colon off-road.
Rym: I think the X is better a little bit classier than the Z you see in games like cats or dolphins And the best one rig racer - where you race in big rig.
Scott: Wow rig racer Okay, so Yeah, four shitty racing games are the only games that come out for the Wii in the last week of the year.
Scott: What does this tell you?
Scott: it tells you the Wii is the system that's getting a lot of crappy games for it and only a Few good games.
Scott: and you know what?
Scott: Sounds a lot like the ps2 to me.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: I mean people always talk about how many great games there were for the ps2 and that is true.
Rym: There are a lot of great games like games that will go down in history as some of those great games for our time on The ps2.
Rym: but you know what?
Rym: 99% of the games on the ps2 are worthless.
Scott: yeah, you go to the store GameStop or whatever.
Scott: you look at the shelf for ps2 games and You see a row that has all those great games that people, you know We'll talk about forever.
Scott: and then you see 20 rows of games that are complete shit.
Scott: and you know People would never trash talk the ps2 for that.
Scott: But when they look over at the Wii and DS shelves and they see all these crap games.
Scott: You know, they trash talk the Wii and DS for that and it's like what the hell man?
Rym: well not everyone.
Scott: a bunch of crappy games for a system is a sign that the system is doing well because it means that This there's so many consoles out there that you're still gonna make plenty of money Even if you put out a shit game with you know, mediocre sales.
Rym: I mean remember when the GameCube was out and then bit by bit the third parties started abandoning it.
Rym: I mean there weren't a lot of crappy games for the GameCube just because there weren't a lot of third-party games.
Rym: and Generally third-party games on Nintendo systems pale in comparison to actual first-party games on Nintendo systems.
Scott: Yep, and everyone always says, uh, you don't want to make third-party games for Nintendo systems.
Scott: If I'm not gonna talk about that now, that's that's a separate topic.
Scott: But anyway, yeah that ps2 with all its crappy games, you know When the ps2 came out a long time ago the year 2000 cuz remember we were at RIT and there was that casino night.
Rym: We're young and we were gonna pool all our money together to try and win it.
Rym: But it wasn't enough and we didn't win.
Scott: well cuz we bet it all on black.
Scott: We had a big pile of money.
Scott: if we bet it on black if it would have come up black We would have won a ps2, but it didn't.
Scott: so we didn't win a ps2.
Rym: Oh, yeah we had a 48% chance of getting a ps2 and then Much like when Bart and Milhouse got radioactive man number one, there would have been trouble as we tried to walk home.
Scott: There would have quite been some trouble.
Scott: and that was like that casino night at college was like right after the ps2 came out.
Scott: That was like ps2 on day one.
Scott: So what games would be a played?
Scott: I don't even know what the release games of the ps2 were.
Rym: Well, someone had because there weren't even that many ps2s at RIT as nerdy as the school was there just weren't enough.
Scott: Well after a couple years there were plenty.
Rym: Yeah, but when they first came out I remember there was some robot game that was really pretty.
Rym: it was one of the laws one of the Enders.
Scott: That was a release game.
Rym: I believe but then I played it.
Rym: It wasn't so great.
Scott: Well, it was actually not a bad game, but it was very short.
Scott: It was basically like a robot tech demo kind of thing.
Rym: But any oh a launch game tech demo kind of like Luigi's Mansion.
Rym: Yeah, not actually much of a game.
Rym: Yeah, Scott beat it.
Scott: for some reason it basically zone of the Enders Luigi's Mansion equivalents for their respective consoles.
Scott: But I mean I know got.
Scott: maybe Nintendo made Luigi's Mansion and said wow This is just sort of a short tech demo.
Scott: and they said it's okay Sony put out that zone of the Enders.
Scott: We're all right.
Rym: I do point out.
Rym: However, that one of those games has general beauregard and one does not.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So speaking of that ps2 with its piles and piles and piles of crappy games Quite a bit of build-up to your news.
Scott: It is quite a bit of build-up to my news the ps2 which came out in the year 2000.
Scott: So it was now eight years old.
Rym: Well, I didn't believe what you told me.
Rym: cuz you know Scott was secretive.
Rym: sometimes when he thinks he has a good news He won't tell me what it is.
Rym: He'll just kind of say I got something.
Rym: Just let me.
Scott: yeah Because how what good is it if we discuss the news beforehand?
Scott: because if it's an amazing news You're gonna have to say something about it before the show and then that ruins it.
Rym: So he's trying to verify it and when he told me what it was, I Actually didn't believe him and I told him to continue verifying.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So the ps2 came out in the year 2000.
Scott: Yep, the DS came out in the year 2004. all right, so it's four years of Ps2 existence with no DS existence.
Scott: So it's four versus eight.
Scott: basically In Japan, we're not talking about the rest of the world talking about Japan only here.
Scott: Total all time since the history of the universe, you know existed.
Rym: There have been more dear might have been game consoles in pre-human civilizations, you don't know that.
Scott: that doesn't count.
Rym: They might have been called the DS.
Scott: It doesn't count in Japan.
Rym: you specified the wide window not me.
Scott: Yes, there have been more DS is sold than ps2 sold ever.
Scott: That you think.
Scott: all the ps2 sold for eight years and all the DS is sold for four years more DS is sold.
Rym: Well, I mean it goes without saying that Nintendo has pretty much been for as long as the portable gaming market has existed.
Rym: Nintendo has basically had a monopoly on it.
Rym: The fact that the PSP still exists is amazing.
Scott: It is amazing indeed and they're actually, you know, a few interesting PSP games.
Scott: Yeah, but uh, I still wouldn't buy.
Scott: it's not worth it to buy a PSP But if you got one at least it's something to do.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, that's it's absolutely insane.
Scott: the ps2 the most successful Craziest biggest selling most hit games Console that has dominated the world for eight years and is still selling This portable system outsold it.
Scott: I think though there's a bit of cheating going on here and I got to point this out or ideas like Yeah, think about it.
Scott: people DS is very likely to replace them with DS lights.
Scott: people with ps2s Not very likely to replace them with slim ps2s.
Rym: not very likely to replace them with ps3s.
Scott: No, not very likely to replace them with ps3s either.
Scott: so yeah DS lights definitely sort of fudged those numbers a bit because you you pretty much got to take the DS fat sales and subtract them from the total sales leaving a Small percentage.
Rym: and then but at the same time the fact remains that the the DS is pretty much the number one gaming Platform in the world outside of South Korea.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much at least in places where it is sold and You know PC gaming doesn't have a strangle.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we can't count South America where the Sega Genesis still has a strong lead Also, I think you know in Europe, I think DS is broke.
Scott: I can't really figure out exactly how popular DS's are in Europe.
Scott: I assume they're kind of popular but places where mobile phones are just so crazily popular like that Of course, it's it's weird cuz Japan the mobile phones are also crazily popular.
Scott: So I don't know.
Scott: but yeah Yeah, I don't think in Europe.
Scott: It's that big.
Scott: I think there's more mobile phone gaming in Europe than there is DS gaming.
Scott: That's just the vibe I get.
Scott: I had to figure it out.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But
Rym: yeah, though I think part of it I mean while Nintendo always has the best portable is partly because they seem to always They understand that portable games like the actual games you play on a portable console Cannot be the same games you play at home because you can't have a game Where you're on the train going somewhere waiting for the doctor and now you have to spend 10 minutes finding a save point Waiting for loading time.
Scott: This is this is Sony's mistake still which I think I talked about this when the PSP first came out.
Scott: Is that look now they're making it so you can like play ps1 games on your PSP via your ps3 and it's like, okay But none of those ps1 games are actually games that are designed to be portable.
Scott: They're not.
Scott: they're not good games to play on the go.
Rym: Yeah, it's basically just a Sega Nomad and we know how that ended.
Scott: Yeah, Gran Turismo is not something you can play while you walk about town and get on the train.
Scott: It just doesn't work.
Rym: I think part of the the PSP is getting games like Pat upon and I think they might have realized this.
Scott: I think they're just what Sony has done.
Scott: is I think ever since Katamari They realized the way to to try to get those gamers and keep them in is to get these Exclusive games that are sort of quirky in a Katamari way.
Scott: that might you know be a smash hit on every gaming site.
Scott: Of course portal sort of took that away from them.
Scott: Well portals the best video game ever made and that's why they've been paying You know to get things like the Pat upon and they paid a lot of money to the person who made flow to get flow on the ps3 and all that stuff.
Rym: so things of the day.
Scott: Oh Yeah.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: I just realized something extra about my thing of the day just now.
Rym: Oh, did you?
Scott: Oh I did Alright, so, you know how some people make off those knockoffs of PSPs and DS's and stuff like that.
Scott: Yes And you know you go and you go to the dollar store and there's something that looks just like a PSP But it's a dollar or the V. Yeah, and you buy it, but it's just that it just looks like a PSP.
Scott: But really the games it plays are like Tiger LCD games and it's mostly to trick grandmas who don't know any better.
Scott: You know, oh my son wants a PS my grandson wants a PSP.
Scott: Oh, there's one by.
Rym: these are the same like the game Like cats or dolphins gay or dogs.
Rym: these games that Nintendogs sold crazily so they made What looks like on the surface the same game.
Rym: because grandma doesn't know.
Rym: she knows that little Susie wants that dogs game Game with the dogs and she goes and she sees dogs only $20.
Rym: It's got Nintendo on it and she's Nintendogs $35 and then little Susie gets probably one of the worst games to be made ever.
Scott: Yep So most of those things.
Scott: there's some funny videos.
Scott: I think we're things of the day in the past where a guy makes fun of them.
Scott: Those those are pretty good.
Rym: I love when they open the V and see what was inside.
Scott: That was a good one.
Scott: But anyway, one company has done something I think is pretty cool.
Scott: They made this thing.
Scott: It looks like a PSP.
Scott: It's actually pretty close to a PSP and You know the idea of it is remember back when you're a kid, you know, someone had that.
Scott: You know gum and it looked exactly like double mint gum, but when you took the stick of gum, it snapped your finger.
Rym: I remember that or the and it really only hurt buzzer in the palm.
Scott: Yeah it only really hurt if you're a little kid with little fleshy fingers and if someone does it to you now you just like.
Rym: See the problem was it always, you know, it looked like gum kinda.
Rym: but at the same time No, five-year-old ever knew how to properly present that gum in a manner where I would not immediately be suspicious.
Scott: I knew how to present that gum in a manner.
Scott: You had to conceal the fake packaging with your hand and only allow the stick of gum to be pointing out.
Rym: Actually, what you do is you take a real stick of gum and you put it under the fake stick.
Rym: You pull it out put it in your mouth in view of someone and then you say oh, hey you want some?
Scott: It's a good one.
Rym: I was the master of conning when I was five years old.
Scott: Yes, because he is easy to con five-year-olds.
Scott: Yes mind of a ten-year-old.
Scott: so Yeah, so they they got this thing.
Scott: It's obviously to anyone who's ever seen a PSP this is not a PSP, but it's pretty close and you give it to someone and they try to play it and Nothing actually happens on the screen.
Scott: It just shocks them.
Rym: how badly we talking like electrocution.
Scott: I assume it shocks that you ever.
Scott: you know We've talked about that shocking roulette thing right.
Scott: Someone at my old job had it and Shocking roulette is actually a really good thing for almost any gamer to have.
Scott: what it is?
Scott: It's a little box and has four holes and everyone puts their finger in one of the holes.
Rym: It's reminiscent of a thunderball.
Scott: Yep, you push a button on it and one of the four fingers will get electrically shocked and the other three will not.
Rym: what better Way to determine who goes first in a game of tigers and Euphrates.
Scott: I can think of no better way none.
Scott: So that's a shocking roulette.
Scott: So this I assume shocks you in a similar manner to shocking roulette, you know illegal non deadly But possibly painful and surprising shock, you know good for a gag not good for hurting anyone.
Rym: now is those things are never.
Rym: I mean It's.
Rym: I'm not saying they need to actually cause harm But they need to cause a little bit more pain than they do.
Rym: Mm-hmm Now we can fix that.
Scott: you thought that PSP was good.
Scott: I clicked on a link and I see something else Here.
Scott: they have you know, those laser pen keychains.
Scott: Yes They've got a laser pen keychain.
Scott: that also shocks people if they try to use.
Scott: So you can be like ooh laser pen want to play with my laser pen yet.
Scott: Oh, it hurts even better than that.
Scott: They got a fake iPod.
Scott: listen in music doo-doo-doo, hey you want to hear what do you want listen to something?
Scott: Okay, hey shock.
Scott: It's good stuff.
Rym: Except usually you just hand them the headphones and not the iPod.
Rym: I know but you know now unless maybe it shocks you in the ear.
Rym: Oh That would be hardcore.
Scott: That would be hardcore, but possibly lawsuit action could be quite quite.
Scott: Yes It's also a really fake looking iPod.
Scott: They may I really wish people made these things.
Rym: look at least the laser pen looks exactly yes because I'm sure Sony is perfectly okay with you making a product on the market that looks Exactly like their product only instead of allowing you to play enjoyable games like pat upon it fucking shocks you.
Scott: What if we just made some sort of add-on for the PSP where we put a thing on a real?
Scott: Shocker the PSP shocker.
Scott: you give someone your real PSP and they try to create and they get shocked.
Rym: you Know that way.
Scott: it would be really easy to fool somebody because they would actually you'd have a game running on there.
Scott: And if you're if you know how to if you were the person who installed the shocker like there is maybe a hidden like child Safety switch.
Scott: so you put your finger on it while you're playing on the secret button behind the PSP.
Scott: So you don't get shocked.
Scott: You're like you're playing the PSP.
Scott: then you give it to someone and they don't push the secret button on the back of the PSP While they're playing and they they you know, it shocks them.
Scott: and there you go.
Rym: Good time You seem to have a lot of plans ready to administer the shocker.
Scott: Oh everyone better beware.
Scott: There's a lot of shocking coming through.
Rym: Yeah, I think the studio audience might have leaked into the microphones a little bit.
Rym: This is actually for the first time in a long time We actually have a live studio audience that is greater than size and then one.
Rym: usually it's just Emily like playing her DS And listening to us idly or Alex downstairs on his laptop and you might think he's downstairs.
Rym: How can he hear you?
Rym: We're pretty loud pretty loud, but I Remember one time Emily went out for a walk while we were doing the show and it was summers.
Rym: I had my windows open.
Rym: she could hear us like way further down the block that you should be able to hear us.
Rym: awesome Yeah, but I did not give them a microphone.
Scott: you got thing of the day over there.
Rym: Oh, I do in fact now up.
Rym: Emily showed me this actually last night and this was kind of amazing.
Rym: now the story here is that there's an advertising agency whatever and They wanted to grow their companies like commercial CG department like just make it better.
Scott: Yes, you can make cool CG commercials and people would pay to make them and you make money.
Rym: now You could send them off to a school or one of those I don't know classes things, you know, like go off on a business trip and learn how to do whatever but instead they just said alright guys make a short film and They made a short film.
Rym: The film is called one rat shorts, and it's kind of amazing.
Scott: It's kind of amazing But the only problem I can find with this film is that the lab is a terrible terrible lab.
Scott: not in I guess also In what it does.
Scott: but What kind of lab has event that goes directly to the outside maybe and a door that goes directly to the outside?
Rym: what they're testing?
Rym: Because I note that the rats were up on treadmills.
Rym: They're testing the effects of the environmental air conditions in an average office.
Scott: It's a terrible Non-scientific laboratory, what do you want?
Rym: I do better laboratory.
Scott: Apparently.
Scott: I want to be able to maintain my believability.
Rym: apparently the Protocol for failure if the system fails is to let all the rats free turn off the lights and open the front door.
Rym: Yep But I'll warn you this film is really good.
Rym: It's an incredibly well animated like.
Rym: this is some damn good 3d.
Scott: Yeah, they must have had some really good people working at the advertising agency to begin with and they probably brought some good people in.
Rym: It's one like ten short film awards.
Scott: Yes, pretty But I'll warn you they're gonna get a lot of business from people who need ads and I think that anyone who buys ads for Them is gonna end up with amazing CG commercials.
Rym: It is one very sad and two Very kind of frighteningly reminiscent of portal.
Scott: There are many similarities between this this short film and portal and I would not bet against someone who said that the people who?
Scott: I've made this video.
Rym: We're also playing portal though I can't say that I'll quote the art director for this.
Rym: One of my favorite short films which I saw as a child was the red balloon.
Rym: I think the melancholic and innocent spirit of that film inhabits one red short.
Scott: I think he should.
Rym: I think he actually based it on portal.
Rym: I think he needs to watch tales because I the red balloon is not a I. I Did not enjoy the red balloon.
Scott: No, but I think he needs to watch.
Rym: you ever seen the red balloon.
Scott: Yes balloon Yes, he needs to watch tales from a street corner.
Rym: Not the good balloon who fights air power.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Audience.
Scott: audience.
Scott: audience raise your hand if you seen tales from a street corner Okay, so maybe we should watch it.
Scott: I don't know I could always watch that.
Rym: It's really good.
Scott: It's really sad.
Rym: doesn't give you the moral you think it's gonna give you.
Scott: it's amazing.
Scott: Anyway, we did show about it.
Rym: So we were playing, you know, it was a weekend.
Rym: We got all our board gaming in.
Rym: since we had the whole crew here We rubbed out a quick T&E.
Rym: Scott won.
Scott: I won.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Who won?
Scott: It's got one.
Rym: You know, what's funny though?
Scott: How about who won the previous T&E?
Rym: Oh Scott has won two games of Tigers and Euphrates.
Rym: I believe It's pretty impressive.
Scott: I believe.
Scott: objectively you could call me the reigning king of Tigris and Euphrates.
Scott: Two rivers two rivers.
Scott: who can take that?
Rym: I will point out that If you were the reigning king of that region of the world, it's not gonna go so well for your civilization.
Scott: You want to play some Amun Ray.
Scott: I'll take the Nile too.
Scott: Nile next stop.
Rym: Have you ever won Amun Ray?
Scott: No No, not in a meaningful game, but Nile next stop.
Scott: Let's go.
Scott: Oh shit floods.
Rym: So we're playing all these games and we played one of those cheap ass games that we've got a while ago And we've been oh, yeah we did
Scott: a show on apples to apples and one of our listeners suggested to us to play big idea, which is a similar game.
Scott: and We I finally after having owning this game for weeks and weeks and weeks New Year's I was finally we I think we played the Game three or four times.
Scott: I was surprised I was able to get people to play it.
Rym: Yeah Correctly captain Bob wonder pants.
Scott: I was very tired and Such over the New Year's with the partying and the loudness and the waking up early and the going to bed late.
Rym: So we yes because Scott didn't have to go to work on Monday.
Rym: Anyway wasn't?
Rym: I had to go to work.
Rym: So yeah, he had to wrangle the Visigoths and I did for once.
Rym: I wasn't there and he had to handle on his own and They're not even out.
Scott: It's very headache to wrangle them.
Scott: We'll see cuz they're loud.
Scott: You like you go into the living room.
Rym: Oh, they're loud.
Rym: We're not loud at all.
Rym: We don't make noise.
Scott: is the difference between the loudness of one?
Scott: Conversation with a loud talking person and being in a room where there are just like 30 people talking.
Rym: It's like ah my head.
Rym: I love the front row crew.
Scott: That's great.
Rym: But the games like the concepts there and I think my powder decadence was quite delectable.
Scott: I liked my.
Scott: what you called the permanent gasoline.
Rym: permanent gasoline is good.
Rym: I think the best invention There were.
Rym: we won't get into that.
Rym: We're gonna do the show another time.
Rym: Yes, but after the game the game was fun, but it wasn't her.
Scott: Yeah, basically, it's a game of trying to sell products but there's also this investing thing and the only reason the investing thing is there is because The point of this game is to sell products and be funny.
Scott: The investing thing is there's that you have some way of determining the winner and the loser and The investing thing kind of works, but it's kind of shitty and it's not fun.
Scott: It's just kind of tacked on.
Rym: now Of course after the game ended we do what we do with every board game we own or ever play which is analyze it Seriously in great detail.
Rym: we spend quite a bit of time talking about how the game could be made.
Scott: I took this silly little cheap-ass game when we analyzed it as if it were.
Rym: that's like when Corbin was trying to play that PB&J game with Luke and Gabby back at RIT.
Rym: this is a game made for five-year-olds and The rules weren't exactly clear.
Rym: So I remember a long argument where Basically, they Corbin Oh Colin not Corbin Colin Colin was arguing with Luke about a race condition that occurred in the game as to what if I play two PBJ's before you play your one.
Scott: a game for five-year-olds people Arguing about the rules rules lawyering in.
Scott: it's like rules learning in Candyland.
Scott: That's what was going on here.
Scott: I recorded that we'll talk about if I go down the chute and then up the ladder - I had to.
Rym: Well, if you go down the chute and go up the ladder, there's nothing wrong with that.
Rym: Yeah, I know because there's no chute that goes to the place where the same ladder went.
Scott: I know but I'm.
Scott: you know what I'm saying?
Rym: Yeah, but that can't happen.
Scott: See, I'm just may see.
Scott: see this is exactly what's going on.
Rym: So Earlier in the weekend.
Rym: We had a bunch of people over and we needed to play another game.
Rym: And what better game to play than Gloria Mundy simply because he doesn't?
Rym: Bob is probably my favorite character in Futurama.
Rym: That isn't bender.
Rym: Yeah And also especially isn't but Except you eat nism, but man, so he comes up a lot.
Rym: He just lately for some reason.
Rym: I don't know why but That game is also a game that had a lot of potential but actually playing it is not that fun.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it the basic concept of the game of you're running away from Rome because you're all hedonism and the Goths are going To sacrum no matter what is a good concept and also the game mechanics.
Rym: each individual game mechanic is like solid gold.
Scott: Yeah, I mean playing the resources.
Scott: Yep It's good stuff But the way the game works out largely because of the costs of the buildings and the way the buildings work and the way the Goth works the game ends up not being so fun and there's not a lot of strategy or tactics.
Scott: That's meaningful Of course, I won that game too.
Scott: I had a fist full of resources rocking on regular running away to Carthage.
Rym: Yep, so, uh, you know we played that game.
Rym: then we talked for a while about how that game could be made better and we Realized what can we talk about?
Rym: but house rules and making games better augmenting games you already own and play now.
Scott: Here's the fundamental question here.
Scott: right is what defines a game?
Scott: What makes one game different from another game?
Scott: You know when I mean if I change let's say rules exactly I mean if I let's have a game of baseball, right?
Scott: What if in baseball I say four strikes you're out?
Scott: Is that still baseball?
Rym: Well now because baseball is defined by the lexicon of the rules exactly.
Scott: So when you take monopoly and you say landing on free parking gets you money.
Scott: That's not monopoly anymore.
Scott: That's something else.
Scott: That's monopoly with free parking money monopoly with a house rule.
Scott: Yep, and It completely changes the game to a different game.
Scott: now I'm not saying that you know just because a game is changed that it's bad.
Scott: You know I mean if you have a game that is bad and somehow Taking some of the rules of that game and adding some other rules that you make up or figure out Creates a newer better game.
Scott: That's awesome.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with that, but a lot of people, you know, they sort of have these house rules like no, this is the way you play monopoly with the money on the free parking and the free jail whatever's and the BS and That's.
Scott: you know, they're not trying to make a game better.
Scott: They're just changing a game with random house rules.
Rym: Well, one thing I've run into a lot is that especially with the like monopolies of probably the best example of this I think that most people in America who play monopoly play it wrong and Don't realize it because they've never in in their entire lives actually looked in that rule book.
Rym: No, they learn from someone else to learn from someone else because everyone I've ever met other than people at RIT Who are really hardcore into board games didn't do the bidding didn't even know there was bidding in that game and For some reason thought that if you land on free parking you get all the money that was given to the bank From all those taxes and things.
Rym: Yep, and Taking out the bidding pretty much takes out the whole game.
Scott: It's not that even though if you follow the rules of monopoly, it's still a terrible game.
Scott: In fact, if you take if you play by the real rules, it's even less fun.
Scott: if that's possible.
Rym: You know, I find it very fun to play it with the real rules once per year at best kind of like say I haven't played it in like a few years.
Scott: So do you want to play it with the real rules?
Rym: I think we should play a game of Monopoly with the whole crew as I have a really fancy Millennium Monopoly set with the real Official exactly what the original rules said.
Scott: rules, you know, I would do that, you know, it sounds good.
Scott: Plus I like that set is really fancy and I like to fiddle with it because the money is really shiny whatever but Why would I do that when I could play one of the other hundred awesome better games that I have when I know that's not So well,
Rym: the thing is playing Monopoly like that is okay.
Rym: It doesn't take that long as long as you don't let the Ken Nicole Situation.
Scott: that was x-men monopoly.
Scott: That's completely different.
Rym: It's the same stupid game.
Rym: I know I know I mean we were playing Monopoly and it was really fun for like 10 minutes.
Rym: then everyone like it.
Rym: everyone suddenly went Oh, wait a minute.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: Monopoly sucks.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This sucks.
Rym: Luckily everyone bankrupt Except Ken and Nicole.
Rym: and like alright, let's just quit and play something else.
Rym: and Ken says, alright Yeah, if you forfeit then I win and we'll play something else.
Rym: and then Nicole says well, no you quit I'll win and then we'll play something else.
Rym: and I think four hours later one of them won.
Scott: If I didn't even think it was possible.
Rym: Well, we pretty much ignored him and played another game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Alright, so house rules.
Scott: We're gonna talk about house rules.
Rym: I think so.
Scott: Alright, what house rules you want to talk about?
Rym: I don't see how to.
Rym: I guess we could talk mostly about how to not suck at making house rules because a Lot of people just kind of make house rules without thinking about it.
Rym: and we talked about this before with mods and games and changing the rules of a game how you can Really take away any actuals.
Rym: You can ruin a game real quickly by changing the rules without thinking.
Scott: Well, a lot of people I think what they do like.
Scott: look at Monopoly, right?
Scott: They add a house rule to make the game.
Scott: It's it's like when they're playing the game.
Scott: there might be something they want, right?
Scott: For example, you'll be playing Vinci and you will really want to have three things for your civilization instead of two.
Scott: like man I like my barbarians revolutionary civilization, but I wish it was barbarians revolutionary livestock breeding.
Scott: That would be awesome.
Scott: so they change a rule to be where you have three things instead of two or You'll be playing Tigris and Euphrates right and so many times during the game.
Scott: you'll say man I wish I had three actions instead of two.
Scott: So they'll say man.
Scott: We all want three actions, don't we?
Scott: Yeah Okay, let's play with three actions and they don't actually think about will they make this game a better game a worse game?
Scott: They just think it'll be more fun because they'll be getting what they want sort of like the same reason.
Scott: People cheat and counter-strike, you know, it's like man.
Scott: I wish I could do this.
Scott: That would be great.
Rym: I wish I could shoot everyone in the head and not get shot in the head with my TMP and be Everyone in the head Yeah, and if you don't really.
Scott: but if you ever cheated a counter-strike you realize that after a while It just it's not fun.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: That's never not fun.
Scott: I think that's only fun because there's real people on the other end.
Rym: Yes, exactly Have we done a show on griefing specifically?
Scott: I don't know Because we probably should otherwise.
Scott: because uh on one hand I think we've definitely discussed it.
Rym: I hate griefing and I hate griefers because I want to have a serious game.
Rym: But on the other hand, I Really?
Rym: Really enjoy griefing people online that there's a reason why I spent there was a period of about two months when out in FARC I never posted unless it was trot to try to start a religious flame war and I succeeded about two-thirds of the time.
Scott: Okay, I don't think I know.
Scott: I'm pretty sure we've discussed griefing on the show before but In oh six twelve twenty dubs and subs.
Scott: my thing of the day was I don't know what this thing of the day is But the thing of the day was gross genitals grief grief, and I'm gonna click on it.
Rym: What?
Scott: I don't know what the hell this is.
Scott: Great.
Scott: I have no idea what this thing of the day Are you sure that was the word?
Scott: Oh, no, it was the time we talked about griefing because it was the time I clicked on it.
Scott: The penises in the Xbox live penises and say in Second Life.
Rym: Oh, yeah penises.
Rym: It's always penises.
Rym: Why is it always penises?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Okay See ya when you want to make a house rule, right?
Scott: Generally, the first thing you have to ask yourself is is this game not fun?
Scott: Because if the game is fun don't change it There's nothing wrong with it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean Actually, you know, I've noticed something.
Rym: it seems like most games that have house rules that people use just kind of willy-nilly Are generally bad games to begin with.
Scott: yeah Cuz I mean if the game is fun to begin with there's not gonna be anything that Frustrates you or makes you feel bad while you're playing the game and you're not gonna think to change anything.
Scott: So when someone changes something like house rules a monopoly which I think is evidence that most people realize the monopoly is a bad game and don't have fun with it that they feel the Need to have to change it because you know, like they want to play it but some you know Cuz maybe something about it is fun, but it's not completely fun.
Rym: I've noticed that most people's house rules seem to Oftentimes add a very large element of randomness or some sort of just like oh the crazy thing can happen The games up in the air until the end.
Rym: Oh, man.
Scott: Yeah, it's very hard because it's very difficult to think up.
Scott: You know a really good rule.
Scott: I mean it takes a lot of time and a lot of thinking to design a balanced and quality board game.
Scott: You know then or any kind of game and coming up with a house rule just sort of randomly is almost never Unless you put a lot of thought into it going to make the game good.
Rym: Yeah It basically comes down to the utility of the game.
Rym: utility is what you want what you're getting out of playing this game And if you're not enjoying the game You have to alter your utility or alter the game to provide the utility you want.
Scott: Yep for example in the game the big idea game.
Scott: right the utility of the game is We want people to make we want to encourage people to do two things.
Scott: number one We want people to come up with funny products to sell and sell them.
Scott: Well high priority booze hammer yep, and the second thing we want to do is we want people to have an incentive to vote for the Funniest and best products and the people who you know pitch the best products.
Rym: cuz what in the end?
Rym: we just want to be entertained Yep But the games utility is get the most money and the mechanic to get the most money is to basically Ignore What the funny things are.
Rym: you actually don't really want to have the funniest thing because you'll make a lot more money having like The second or third funniest thing that maybe one person invests in and then you pretty much roll dice and it's totally random.
Scott: Yep So what we did is we said hey, why don't we do this?
Scott: Obviously, this is a different game because we're completely changing the rules.
Scott: But everyone makes a funny product and tries to sell it.
Scott: then everyone votes for one product that's not their own and they have to vote.
Scott: they can't withhold their vote right like you can in the normal rules and Whichever product, you know for every person who votes for your product you get one point.
Scott: So if six if five people vote for mine, I get five points.
Scott: All right, so you want to make something funny to get lots of people to vote for it now For all the people who you know voted for it, right?
Scott: They get money too.
Scott: So if I vote for something and Rym votes for something then we each get one dollar.
Scott: that way Voting for the thing that everyone else votes for gets you more points.
Scott: so there's an incentive to vote for the thing everyone else votes for and There's also an incentive to make the thing that everyone's going to vote for.
Scott: and that's all that's all there is very easy now.
Rym: Luckily, this is an incredibly simple game incredibly simple.
Scott: So it's why it was very easy to come up with house rules.
Rym: In fact, it was easy to come up with a lot more complex schemes and basically make a much larger game out of it.
Scott: That was not necessary because all of it detracted from An excuse.
Scott: the only thing you need is an excuse to make funny products and sell them now.
Rym: number two Say you decide to have a new house rule or try someone else's house rule.
Rym: You really have to go into the first couple times you play Expecting the game to be broken and being a kind of cognizant of how it might break.
Rym: so you can try to maybe fix the house Rule make it better.
Rym: maybe realize it's not the best house rule that sort of.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: Like if you come up with a house rule play the game and if you see that, you know The person who you know is sort of doing stupid things ends up winning.
Scott: Something's wrong or like.
Rym: if I make a house rule I don't know the Harkonnen get a hundred spice instead of ten at the start of doom and you notice that I get and then I get pissed because the guy playing the Harkonnen wins and it feels unfair and cheap.
Rym: Well, you were playing kind of an asterisk game anyway, so it's not like you can really.
Rym: Yeah, actually this is probably the most important thing when it comes to house rules.
Rym: If you ever play like say you have house rules good used all the time like in D&D We roll d30s instead of d20.
Rym: Oh Whatever.
Rym: or our burning wheel d4s.
Scott: Oh Think about that.
Scott: You couldn't mix you couldn't succeed on anything.
Scott: You could barely ever.
Rym: How's white shades become a lot more important than they sure do?
Rym: but uh alright.
Rym: so you've been playing with this house rule like in settlers roll the robber and Everyone has to bribe the guy who rolled the robber.
Rym: and now like that's what you have to do You.
Rym: uh, if you ever play with anyone who isn't in your little crew you'd better tell them about the house rule before you start playing because otherwise I Guarantee this.
Rym: I've seen this happen way too often Especially in like gaming clubs or large groups of friends not so much in the crew because we're kind of anal about our board game rules.
Rym: You'll be halfway through the game.
Rym: Someone will do something under the Misapprehension that the rules are not the way everyone else thinks they are and then the game is totally broken.
Rym: There's gonna be an argument and someone's going home crying something like that.
Scott: There's also a problem of people who have a house rule and they play the game a certain way to the point where it sort Of becomes natural and then they go somewhere else and play the game say at a gaming convention And they sort of naturally play it with their house rule forgetting.
Rym: That's not how that happened at the world settlers tournament at uber con several years ago.
Rym: Really in the first round, right?
Rym: The first round is version ups.
Rym: I won like 10 to 6 to 4 to 4 like something crazy.
Rym: and I remember on the first round like right away robber comes up and I'm like, alright bitches I'm about to throw the robber down and two of the players say no, it's in the first four rounds.
Rym: You can't do that blah blah blah.
Rym: We got to just reroll.
Scott: You called the judge over.
Rym: I said, uh, that's not the rules.
Rym: called the judge over.
Rym: He said it's not in the rules.
Scott: and Yeah, yep, you got to remember what's a house rule and what's a real rule?
Scott: Make sure you read your rule books because I give you you know This might happen a lot with things like magic the gathering and stuff like that where you know Be aware of what the real official rules of a game are even if you don't play by them So that you know when you play that game in public because you're probably gonna want to if you like the game That you're not being stupid because you will get laughed at and put okay show kind of short Not as good as yesterday's show.
Rym: Like we said, yeah, I'm what can you do?
Rym: That was a triumph?
Rym: I know I mean for all of you who are still alive.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of people here hanging out being bored while we're making a show and you know We should go and you know dinner and all that kind of other stuff and then go to bed early So, you know and clean all this crap out of the house.
Rym: Oh great work tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's alright.
Rym: We got a lot down actually and just for the record because we did some of the final planning.
Rym: We said this before but it's gaming day.
Rym: It's the new year So we're gonna say it pretty much straight up.
Rym: Scott and I are going to be at PAX.
Scott: We're going to pass her no matter what it will happen.
Rym: We will be there.
Rym: I can't promise we'll be doing any shows or anything.
Rym: We might.
Scott: I'm working on that, but we will be at packs Guaranteed 100 unless something happens such as the plane crashes We know I before then if both of us die We both lose our jobs and have no money.
Rym: if we both lose our jobs and have no money We're kind of fucked anyway, so we'll just road trip across the country with whatever we've got left.
Rym: Maybe and then after packs Mexico maybe.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.