Rym: It's Wednesday March 5th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about graveyard Kitaro.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I'm sure many of you noticed the lack of a show last night.
Scott: I Wonder why that was?
Rym: Well that our fault or perhaps did something happen.
Rym: stay tuned tomorrow And we'll tell the story of what exactly we were doing last night.
Scott: Oh good, so we can just ignore that and I'll talk about something else right now.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know I had a good day though.
Rym: I mean we had a good dinner last night all things considering, but today at work I was you know we're dealing with a vendor and vendors often take you out to lunch, so Instead of going to my normal lunch.
Rym: It's somewhat one of those like euro cafe or whatevers or limerage pizza We went to the capital grill, and I had some steak and let me tell you that was one of the best steaks I've ever had in my life.
Scott: She got a lowercase grill far superior.
Rym: the thing is though the steak was amazing It was.
Rym: it was simple to smaller, but it tastes better.
Rym: It was like this sirloin something But all they seasoned it with was salt pepper and a whole bunch of sugar And then they beat it with that and then they seared the outside black, but the inside was watching them.
Rym: Well, they told me what they were gonna do and then they did it.
Scott: uh-huh they could have been doing some secret stuff in that Kitchen.
Rym: I'm pretty sure it was pretty simple.
Rym: But the thing is the steak was pretty good like that was a really damn good steak, but we also ordered some mashed potatoes and This might sound weird, but those were far away by perhaps an order of magnitude the best goddamn mashed potatoes I've ever eaten in my entire life.
Rym: I doubt that I'll ever eat mashed potatoes that good again.
Scott: What if you just go back there?
Rym: I don't know if they could replicate it.
Rym: They were too good.
Rym: It was.
Rym: it was really kind of crazy.
Scott: The chef was like god damn I was off and like yeah But yeah, I can't feel too bad though.
Scott: I had a rocky road cheesecake today.
Rym: Oh a cheesecake.
Scott: rocky road cheesecake.
Rym: The thing is you but you didn't get to that I got was so sitting there right one this place.
Rym: when you walk in now I think this is a little silly But they have these little boxes like cages on the wall And there's names on them and each box is a little bit of stuff.
Rym: And if you're someone who eats at a place like this often You get a box and you keep your personal wine collection in there.
Rym: some people have like books and stuff in there But I just found that silly.
Rym: but our table, you know, we're trying to talk and we're enjoying our food but directly across from us is a gigantic is a gigantic portrait of the most Glowering angry bald bull looking motherfucker I've ever seen.
Scott: ball ball.
Rym: You look kind of like bald bull.
Rym: imagine this like eight foot tall portrait original oil painting of bald Bull, you got a bald bull sticker and like put it up there staring at you angrily.
Rym: And the thing is I kept looking at.
Rym: I was trying to like lean over and read maybe Who it was.
Rym: so I could look him up because all the everything else was kind of happy.
Rym: There was big smile in pictures, but this one portrait and no we're walking out and I didn't say anything about it.
Rym: You know, it's a business lunch or whatever.
Rym: and my boss leans in and he says So, uh, that was quite an interesting portrait that was glowering at us the whole time.
Rym: Wasn't it?
Scott: He did if you would have said something about bald bull.
Rym: Oh, that would have been like times 10, but still yeah.
Scott: No, another interesting thing that happened to me today in addition to my rocky road cheesecake.
Scott: It's doo-doo.
Scott: No, no, not any doo-doo.
Scott: No was when I was in the train coming home I was pretty tired and I was playing some Phoenix Wright 4.
Scott: Well, I guess it's not Phoenix Wright 4 It's Apollo justice one, but you know what?
Scott: I mean ace attorney for whatever gakuten saiban.
Scott: for there you go Take that one, right?
Scott: So I'm playing it.
Scott: I'm on episode three already, right and I got so tired I like dropped it into my lap Again.
Rym: But maybe that tired.
Scott: but in addition there was a guy sitting next to me on the train and I you know He's a businessman.
Scott: He's got a pile of papers.
Scott: So I you know, I look take my eyes and I glance over at his papers.
Rym: Thank you.
Scott: Well, he was a lawyer.
Scott: I could tell from his papers.
Scott: Definitely a lawyer some sort of patenting lawyer.
Scott: He had a patent there.
Scott: He was looking at The patent was from Yahoo, I think and I don't know.
Scott: I couldn't read what the patent was about.
Scott: I'm sure it was a bullshit software patent because you know, all software patents are bullshit pretty much and in this patent was The entire Like because like at first he was just like, you know the cover page and whatever, right?
Scott: but then after you know I look I played Phoenix Wright again, and then I look back and he was reading the RFC for FTP.
Rym: Huh?
Scott: The entire RFC for FTP was pasted I guess for reference.
Scott: within this patent as in the patent must have involved FTP some.
Scott: So they put the entire RFC in there I've and he was reading it.
Rym: I've never read the RFC for FTP.
Rym: I've read other are.
Scott: if she was reading me He was.
Scott: he wasn't reading every word of it But he was definitely reading that RFC which implied to me that he didn't know what FTP was.
Scott: These were some.
Rym: probably there's a good chance that maybe that was actually someone else had recommended that perhaps this RFC Was prior art that invalidated the patent or so.
Scott: I could have been something I don't know but that I was glancing over at a guy and that's you know.
Rym: Plus I've read RFCs before and the thing is it's funny But the only are.
Rym: I read RFCs a lot in college at university where I had to know these things But now that I'm in the real world even in enterprise IT.
Rym: I don't need to read RFCs.
Rym: There's nothing in an RFC.
Scott: I need you know when you need to read an RFC.
Scott: Oh, you know what I read.
Rym: I read white papers.
Rym: Yeah white papers.
Rym: Tell me what I need to know RFCs.
Rym: Tell me things that I don't care about, you know.
Scott: You know when you read an RFC when you want to make a see that that's when you read.
Scott: C is for cookies.
Scott: good enough for me.
Rym: Anyway, since it's anime manga comics day I got a quick news here.
Scott: Cookie starts with C.
Rym: Just cuz.
Rym: we've talked about this a lot and came up in the late show at Katsucon.
Rym: This comes up a lot now.
Rym: But you know the anime industry is having some trouble and there's a lot of blame going around a lot of this blame going toward people downloading fan subs instead of buying anime.
Rym: and I Want to make it very clear because I don't want to talk about this a lot that In at no point whenever I talk about any of this stuff Am I ever trying to be an apologist for people who download fan subs or illegally pirate or whatever?
Rym: But at the same time I don't think that the anime industry would be doing much better if they somehow Eliminated all the piracy in the world.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of this.
Rym: they're blaming these people.
Rym: But those people may be wrong in a lot of ways But at the same time those people are not the cause of the industry's problems, but all that aside There's an interesting little blurb here on the animators Network.
Rym: Here's a quote.
Rym: I'll read the quote then I'll explain who said it and why.
Rym: perhaps if so many fans weren't getting their anime from illegal file sharing sites or unlicensed streaming sites We might have expanded our UK catalog more quickly as it stands now.
Rym: However, we have a better shot at growing our business with lace than maintaining an overseas branch.
Rym: Yes, it turns out that John Ledford who is pretty much mr ATV who is that the CEO of a TV films is going to wear lace Instead of distributing anime in the UK.
Rym: you heard it here first.
Scott: Oh, I'm sure that will sell lots of anime.
Rym: That'll sell lots of something.
Rym: now Lace, you know that was kind of a lame joke.
Rym: lace refers to a company that will.
Rym: Looks like they're going to kind of outsource their distribution or whatever to the UK to this other company.
Rym: Okay, no one really cares.
Rym: so I'm not gonna really go into it further, but It's starting to bother me that the anime industry and I'm seeing more and more of these kind of Semi-official off-the-cuff statements pretty much directly blaming piracy for the state of the anime industry.
Rym: maybe it has more to do with the fact that They're really marketing a lot of anime at the people who are the least likely to have the money to buy the anime.
Rym: They're marketing the shows that are the least likely to be bought on DVD and are more likely to be watched on TV.
Rym: But oh, they're not on TV in the US because we don't have that sort of model over here.
Scott: And they're on Adult Swim, right?
Scott: Look at this.
Scott: They they show kids shows on Adult Swim, right and So who likes the shows?
Scott: Well kids.
Scott: kids are watching Adult Swim Of course kids without money kids without money kids you don't need and they try to the episode of Naruto again.
Rym: So they're not gonna buy the DVD.
Scott: and then they bring a bunch of other shows out on DVD Which are for kids and they try to sell them to kids who have no money.
Scott: Maybe you should take a look over at that HBO where they have Adult shows and adults have money.
Rym: There's also the problem that I'm sell them to adults of course, the anime industry is very secretive here, but there is definitely a lot of evidence that the majority of the money is made in merchandising and If you go to anime conventions nowadays, well, they pretty much always.
Rym: 90% of the merchandise is for those shows that have the same problems as before.
Rym: it's for like three or four shows But in addition a lot of it is really kind of classless kitschy Crappy little crap tchotchkes that I don't know.
Rym: I'm willing to spend 40 bucks on an old Leiji Matsumoto movie poster.
Rym: I'm not willing to spend four dollars on a PVC poorly made of a character from a show.
Rym: I don't like.
Rym: yeah, pretty much I Show about this.
Rym: we've talked about this before, but I'll talk about it again.
Rym: I'm sure Even if this is right, this is true And you know you're losing money, and you're not able to expand because of people downloading fan subs and such Snarky comments like that are not the professional way to go about this.
Scott: No not really really.
Rym: I mean, I don't know.
Rym: if you're a businessman you should I don't know have a press release with some sort of formal statement Like a professional businessman and not like some schmuck I Just don't like.
Rym: but anyway.
Rym: What do you got in the news Scott?
Rym: I don't want to talk about this anymore.
Scott: I don't really.
Scott: I don't really have any news.
Scott: so don't you know, but what I do have is You know vertical the company that publishes all the awesome manga.
Scott: well They don't publish all the awesome on good, but all of them all the all the manga They publish is awesome.
Scott: You know one of those logic.
Rym: You know Socratic things all right.
Scott: You know they bring over the Tezuka's and they bring over the keiko taka me is you know what not right?
Scott: But one manga they're putting out is this goo in saga manga, and I talked about it I think is a geek bite a few weeks ago.
Scott: I don't remember exactly when.
Scott: Basically, it's a manga side story to the longest series of fantasy novels in the history of the world.
Scott: There's like a hundred plus novels in this series about the leopard-headed king in his kingdom and whatnot.
Rym: yeah, Tolkien wrote what five?
Scott: Haha Right anyway.
Scott: There's a three volume Manga side story to the goo in saga called the goo in saga manga.
Scott: the seven magi Right and vertical published all three volumes in English.
Rym: yeah, we did.
Rym: Scott did a yeah geek bat big big bite.
Rym: I want to say geek back.
Rym: I know I'm a cuz I hadn't read it yet, but I'm gonna read it soon.
Rym: Maybe we'll do a kind of more thorough review at some point.
Scott: It's not the greatest manga ever, but it's a good manga, and it's a fantasy manga.
Scott: There's not too many of them.
Scott: it's a somewhat serious fantasy manga and More than anything it really makes me want to read the goo in saga itself.
Rym: You know because hear that vertical translated bring it out.
Scott: They did.
Scott: they brought out five or something volumes of the goo in saga.
Rym: Ah wow they're like a magic genie.
Rym: I write.
Scott: I say there are a hundred something volumes of the goo inside.
Scott: It's fine.
Rym: Think think about how long it'll take you to read him.
Scott: Yeah, I know right, but anyway so Vertical.
Scott: you know I kind of met their Publicist person at the New York and a festival and we talked it up.
Scott: And then they sent us an email a little while ago, and they were like hey some of our editors listen to GeekNights And we want to we like you.
Rym: so Shout out to you guys cuz you guys are like my personal heroes of bringing manga out.
Scott: Yeah, so then I'm like hey Don't you remember us?
Scott: I met you at the New York and her festival, and they're like oh, yeah, we did meet you.
Scott: So they're like we want to send you some stuff, and I'm like all right you can send us stuff But you know that like I can't guarantee.
Scott: We'll review it, and I can't even guarantee.
Scott: We'll say anything about it I can't?
Rym: we have like the worst industry relations in the world.
Scott: well cuz pretty much You know we won't.
Scott: we refuse to sell out, and I feel like it would be dishonest.
Scott: You know at least if I'm not gonna sell out right I'm gonna make it clear to the person sending me free stuff that I am not giving them any Guarantees of a good review of any review at all of anything right you know.
Scott: But I did say we might.
Scott: if they send us free stuff at the very least We'll give it away as a prize right?
Scott: so I of course already buy every manga vertical publishes.
Scott: No, I'll probably continue to do so.
Scott: so I have here the entire three volumes of this manga.
Scott: It's the whole manga.
Scott: there are only three volumes of it.
Scott: volume three is the final volume, and I have all three.
Scott: They sent him to me So we got to give them away to somebody.
Scott: huh now.
Rym: We've done come now.
Rym: I was thinking fast, and I've just got decided that by and large contests on podcasts are largely worthless.
Rym: They're usually not that entertaining.
Rym: They're usually kind of laying.
Rym: they always end up with some sort of Boring raffle with the drumroll at the end.
Scott: yeah, so I was thinking well We just keep these things and then we'll give them away.
Scott: and like a convention or something right you know cuz we can give away For like the anime match game or something like that.
Rym: I don't know yeah, but the thing is after katsu-kan We've actually got some time before the next convention.
Scott: Yeah, and I was like oh, it's a great I'll just do that, but then there aren't any more conventions for a very long time.
Scott: There's many many months going by so these books are to realize precious space in our house.
Rym: I've saying that means that I'm gonna wake up tomorrow.
Rym: It's gonna be August and we have three conventions in four weeks.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: We do have three conventions is four weeks.
Rym: You know any conventions.
Rym: We're gonna.
Rym: Have one summer comes do.
Rym: Why do we do this?
Scott: so anyway?
Scott: We need to think of some way to get rid to give these away?
Scott: What do you what do you think Rym?
Rym: ah we could have a contest to come up with the way to give them away?
Scott: No, that's too lame.
Scott: I think we're gonna keep it simple.
Scott: right now.
Scott: You have to write and email us.
Scott: GeekNights at front row.
Scott: crew calm right write an essay about why?
Scott: I should mail you these manga for free now.
Scott: Keep in mind most people Entering the contest we have on podcasts.
Scott: Do not follow the directions.
Rym: I'll say this now.
Rym: Dave and Joel actually wow I haven't listened to them in a while actually yeah.
Scott: But anyway, they're actually their latest episode was high quality.
Rym: Oh really see it wasn't any matter of.
Rym: not low quality It's a matter of.
Scott: I haven't had headphones since I sent my headphones back to get repaired now But their latest episode was well above their average the the one about like the wolf cannon or whatever.
Rym: It's pretty high quality wolf cannon.
Rym: Yeah Something like that, but I remember they talked about when they had a contest before that.
Rym: whenever you enter a contest And there's rules They're always the people who break the rules on purpose because there's the chance that the people being judges look and say wow That guy had the balls to break the rules plus one.
Rym: well.
Rym: I'm gonna tell you right now at GeekNights Their disclaimer is times infinity for us if you break the rules you're not gonna win no matter how cool You are.
Scott: yeah, if you send in the best reason ever for why I should mail you these manga But it's like one poorly spelled Unpunctuated sentence you ain't getting shit in fact.
Scott: I'll just be rate you on the show and call you out sure you want him to say why they want the manga.
Rym: maybe should Get him to write some sort of literary like a treatise on I don't know Tezuka, and then we can publish that.
Scott: no I think we'll just keep it simple something people don't have to research for.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I like the high bar yeah, but anyway you have to write an Essay and it which means it should be long enough to where me and Rym would consider Okay, that's an essay and not just a paragraph.
Rym: you need at least the middle school equivalent which is five.
Rym: introductory paragraph body paragraph body paragraph body paragraph.
Rym: Conclusion.
Rym: I want a thesis statement.
Rym: a lot of people say you should start with a global statement.
Scott: if there are any any at Spelling or punctuation errors that are egregious You automatically lose.
Scott: you have no chance to survive.
Rym: so I'm gonna say this style counts.
Rym: I gotta I gotta get this out here because I'm a student of the lively art of writing School of writing.
Rym: if you don't know what that is it's a book.
Rym: I Demand that you buy it and read it and learn how to write from it.
Rym: however if you decide to start your essay with a Global statement and narrow in on a thesis.
Rym: I'm gonna tear your essay up as in.
Rym: I'm gonna print it out and then tear it up Alright, so Basically think about this.
Scott: This is a really easy contest when you get right down to it because your reason for wanting these manga Will only come into play if you and someone else both Follow all the rules of the contest.
Scott: if you make a submission that doesn't break the rules and satisfies us You will probably win.
Scott: It's really easy.
Scott: Just follow the rules and win pretty much guaranteed.
Scott: If not enough people submit entries and or all of the entries are bad Then I'll just hold on to these or I don't know what I'll do, but yes.
Rym: We I'm gonna.
Rym: we reserve the right to Defer awarding prizes.
Scott: well if there's no valid entries.
Scott: I can't give away the prize.
Scott: Yeah, yeah Well, I guess it's like if you had a raffle and nobody bought a ticket.
Scott: You don't give the car away To nobody.
Scott: well you give it to yourself.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know you give it away.
Rym: You give it away to Joey Jojo Shabbatou from Clifton and That just means you don't give it away, and then you auction the same car off next year.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway Yeah, so that's that's the deal.
Scott: I'll repeat this probably next week and maybe the week after.
Scott: The deadline is pretty much When I feel like it.
Rym: So yeah pretty much the sooner the better.
Rym: cuz if a good one comes in we're gonna end the contest right then maybe maybe.
Rym: And now.
Rym: well I got it one last time.
Scott: we got email to eat nights at front row.
Scott: crew calm.
Scott: the subject should be something like goo and saga Contest or manga contest or vertical manga giveaway or anything like.
Rym: and seriously again a big shout out to all the people at vertical listening right now because One you know it's not a shill because we kind of sing the praises of them all the time regardless.
Scott: That's probably why they like us because you know if you don't believe us go way back and listen to like some episodes about like Apollo's song and stuff.
Rym: well Yeah, you know if there was a podcast where all they did was periodically say man GeekNights is so awesome I'd probably really like that podcast.
Scott: yeah But go back and listen like the Apollo song episode and you'll see we were shilling them before they sent us free shit.
Scott: the free Shit has absolutely no Influential effect on our liking of them or the things they make.
Rym: but I got some real news here And this is kind of.
Rym: this is important news actual news.
Rym: I have a lot to say about this, but luckily it won't take long because well I have a lot to say regarding it.
Rym: the actual news story here is pretty simple But we were at katsu kana recently and as you may be aware Scott and I are our kind of epic panelists in that If you look at a list of the numbers of panels events like guest appearances and whatever we've done at conventions It's kind of frightening.
Rym: We did like six things at katsu kana and Every convention kind of handles panels differently, and I'd always been of the mind for pretty much as long as I've been going that Otakon Should by all rights have far and away the best panels from fans of any convention.
Rym: They have the biggest pool to draw from.
Rym: they're like this mega epic gigantic amazing convention, and they've had good panels.
Rym: There's always good panels at Otakon.
Scott: Well go to any convention There's good panels, but he much the Otakon never quite seemed to reach their full potential.
Scott: Yeah, you would think that you know Otakon so big so awesome.
Scott: every panel should like completely blow your mind, right?
Scott: Right because they don't have any.
Scott: you know they actually have less panels in quantity than some other conventions because you know they dev You know they don't go over all the overnight You know and stuff like that.
Scott: so they have just as many panels as say katsu kana or ConnectiCon or something like that.
Scott: But they have a much bigger pool of people.
Scott: Shouldn't and a bigger money and bigger everything.
Scott: shouldn't?
Scott: the panels be better You know in aggregate than the panels at other conventions, and they were a little bit kind of yeah, but at the same time Remember our our start in paneling.
Rym: well our second start our first start was at a convention I shall not name because that was the convention with the midget prostitutes worst convention ever.
Rym: But the second anime counter.
Rym: we ever went to Otakon 2002.
Rym: We went to the anime club summit found that the people who were supposed to run it weren't there.
Rym: So we pretended to be them and ran the goddamn panel.
Rym: yep Yeah, that was professional.
Rym: But last year there's kind of a shake-up in the Otakon panels department and the people who took over did kind of an awesome job Of fixing everything and as best as could be expected from anybody.
Rym: now of course after Otakon I gave them a kind of long Semi tirade of.
Rym: here's how you could make panels a billion times better at Otakon now Not only if they implemented in some form pretty much everything I suggested though I'll bet they came up with a lot of this on their own.
Rym: I'm not going to claim that I am the reason for all this by any stretch but they actually went beyond and thought of things that I never would have thought of and Panels at Otakon 2008 are pretty much guaranteed to be the best panels Otakon has ever had.
Rym: they have completely redone this Pretty much.
Rym: if you were stupid you will be unable to put forth a panel or even be considered Because I'm gonna break down the rules here.
Rym: first off.
Rym: They have an official form.
Rym: you have to fill out to get a panel at Otakon now in this form is Amazing.
Rym: you gotta give your real name your real address your email address the names and addresses and contact info of every other panelist the name of your panel a 100 word or less description of your panel?
Rym: is it an 18 plus panel?
Rym: is it an industry panel?
Rym: Have you ever presented this panel before?
Rym: yes at a previous Otakon yes at some other pack convention?
Rym: No, but I have been a panelist before.
Rym: If you have or you say you have You have to give the names of the conventions and the names of the panels.
Rym: they can check and make sure you're not lying.
Rym: You have to write a short paragraph of why this panel should be accepted You have to state all the equipment and technical stuff you need and you have to numerate pretty much everything about this panel.
Rym: That's the first step.
Rym: that is the lowest barrier to entry right there And that is asking more than pretty much any anime con has ever asked before Mm-hmm.
Rym: now in addition to that a lot of cons give you free badges for doing panels.
Rym: never con has done it differently Some kinds of kind of lacks.
Rym: I remember one con.
Rym: I won't name it cuz I like this kind of lot But we I pretty much walked in on Friday to the ops area and said yeah, I'm a guest Can I have my badge?
Rym: and they handed me a blank guest badge and a marker?
Scott: Oh?
Rym: Yeah, and I and part of me thoughts.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and I need badges for my roadies.
Rym: Yeah, there's like nine of them isn't poor kids?
Scott: when you're going to convention is time to volunteer right?
Scott: Confidently just walk into ops and say I get well grab a go to reg.
Scott: Just take a program right.
Scott: look for the name of a guest who doesn't have their picture in the program Name.
Scott: that is the same gender as yourself.
Rym: You know what.
Scott: go to con ops and say I'm so and so I need a badge.
Rym: When you walk out with confidence and see what happens when you walk up to the to the ops and you walk up to the person sitting there and you say Hi, my name is Greg Ayers, and I'm here to be a guest at the fact.
Rym: They're going to beat you.
Scott: Yeah, you had to pick someone who's picked like a webcomic.
Scott: They won't know what the webcomic guess looks like.
Scott: yeah The thing is I'll say you got to be really key can't be like nerdy.
Scott: you got to be like yeah I'm so and so come looking for how do I get my badge?
Rym: see the thing is I?
Rym: Also, have a sneaking suspicion because I've seen people attempt this sort of thing before.
Rym: It's almost like the staff at most.
Rym: cons can sniff out if you're legitimate or not.
Rym: Regardless of how you act I could.
Scott: I could probably get a badge at any con.
Scott: I guarantee it.
Scott: Any anime convention in the United States?
Scott: I think I could get a badge for free without having just showing up.
Rym: I think Otakon would take the most work, and they're probably anime.
Scott: expo might be a little difficult But any other ones?
Rym: now you know what.
Rym: there's one exception to that the New York anime festival.
Rym: You cannot get a fake badge to that car.
Scott: I guess not.
Rym: I didn't really try.
Rym: But actually a non kind of showed up out of the blue to come to the con with us.
Rym: He wasn't like a guest or anything.
Rym: He just came to like chill with us.
Rym: So uh we're walking up, and we have our like guest badges and a nonth is with us.
Rym: So I pull my usual art.
Rym: enough carry this thing for us And you're our roadie, and we're walking in and there's this big guy standing at the escalator And he looks at my badge, and it says guest and he looks at Scott's badge.
Rym: It says guess and he looks at the nonth who is buried under a heavy thing.
Rym: He's carrying and the guy says well Where's your badge?
Rym: Yeah, I held up my bad guest badge and say hey.
Rym: He's our roadie.
Rym: He's just carrying our stuff in.
Rym: where's his badge?
Rym: He's he's like.
Rym: Where's this badge?
Rym: god damn it, so we had to go get him a badge.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but yeah, I don't try to scam badges from cons.
Rym: unless it's the con that shall might not be named, but anyway Uh Otakon now base don't try to do it like for evil But try to do it.
Scott: just see what happens for funny.
Rym: if you actually there's
Scott: a difference
Rym: I'll say this if you actually get a free badge doing that I Would recommend that pretty much right after they give it to you tell them what you did and hand the badge back Cuz there's a small chance that they'll laugh and then give you a free badge.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good move.
Scott: But anyway also, they'll go oh shit, and they won't.
Scott: then a real guest will come in and say where's my badge.
Scott: They're like need to see some ID.
Scott: Be like it's.
Scott: it's like the guy who flew over from Japan ultra-famous.
Rym: Yeah, it's like a kirakami.
Scott: Yeah, he says where he says where's my badge.
Scott: They'll be like need to see some ID.
Scott: be like Oh Rims thing of the day reference my it's coming.
Rym: It's coming.
Rym: He'll kick you apart, but All right real briefly.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into the rest of this, but the final issue Here is that they're not gonna give you a free badge just because you get a panel at Otakon.
Rym: they will give you a free badge before the con if you have presented at Otakon before and They have an indication from whatever, you know past performance commentary emails that you actually Ran a good panel.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: Otherwise, you do not get a free badge.
Rym: However, if you run a really good panel, you will be given a refund after the convention If you do not show up to run your panel or you run a bad panel.
Rym: They do not say this outright, but it is heavily implied.
Rym: You will probably be blacklisted forever.
Scott: Yeah, they don't say anything like that But that is my can imagine.
Scott: why would they be asking all these sorts of information and tracking it if they weren't gonna do Something like that or at least keep the option available I'm sure like if they really needed a panel and you would run one before and you know, you know They'd be like, all right.
Rym: We'll throw them in it like, you know crack it on Sunday or something, but so pretty much Otakon my hat is off to you because this is such a good system like is it one?
Scott: I'm gonna be very interested at the quality of the panels but also at the variety of the panels because I Have a suspicion that certain kinds of panels that pretty much anyone who would run them would do a bad job And I think that the kinds of panels that people who are good at running panels are interested in will start to dominate the convention.
Rym: Yeah, plus I mean I've already submitted God like seven panels and I've got about nine more.
Rym: as soon as I get the rest I'm not running seven panels.
Rym: You know, I wouldn't be too opposed to running events all day Friday and Saturday at Otakon.
Scott: However, however, that's not gonna happen.
Scott: I here's how only if there are other people's depends like I could just be sit down only if I did not have to run anything on Sunday.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, but things are they.
Rym: this is a good system because it's gonna also encourage like new people can still try to do panels You can still kind of break in but you have to be at least a little bit professional And if you do a good job you get rewarded.
Rym: if you a bad job You're done.
Scott: Yeah, it'll let them sort of have this cycle going of new people who are potentially good come in They try to run a panel if they do a good job.
Scott: Hooray.
Scott: We have a new good pen.
Rym: I think this is also going to lead to panel dynasties which could be really good because if there's someone out there who runs an awesome freaking panel and Every year they run a different awesome freaking panel You don't you get free.
Rym: that's like the best thing that can happen to a con Especially if they get the reputation like oh every year at Otakon on Saturday night They show the violent movie or they have that guy that does that panel about that thing.
Rym: but anyway things of the Why you gotta be doing that, all right, you know giving it away every now and then when I get bored I just type Hokuto no can into YouTube and watch a couple of head explode ease and I was doing this the other day.
Rym: cuz Scott and I were talking about it kind of out of the blue and We watch one video.
Rym: It's him versus the colonel, which I I like this.
Rym: I like that clip mostly because of the absolutely piss-poor animation but There was one of those related links in YouTube and I clicked on it.
Scott: related links on YouTube is the best thing ever.
Scott: That's I gotta say and I had never seen this fight before.
Rym: however Before you watch my thing of the day I would recommend that if you can you try to watch the second episode of Hokuto.
Rym: No, can.
Scott: yes, I watched.
Scott: if you watch the second episode of Hokuto no can.
Scott: let me explain what happens in the first episode.
Scott: He beats the bad guy by doing what?
Scott: Right in the second episode what he does is he puts his thumbs into the bad guys temples And he says after I pull my thumbs that well after I pull my thumbs out You will die seven seconds later, and then there's fucking digital timers.
Scott: He pulls his thumbs out a digital timer appears on the screen and counts down By tenths of a second from seven down to zero and when it hits zero dudes head explodes.
Rym: So after you even if you don't watch that at least you know what happened.
Rym: because in this video Ken Shiro is doing something and this guy is pissed at him, which is off in the plot of a Hokuto no can episode and This guy comes at him like I'll get you How dare you turn your back on me?
Rym: and Ken Shiro does the thing that I love it when characters do in any show?
Rym: Where they turn around on someone like that, but they don't hit him or anything.
Rym: they just look at him like well He does.
Scott: he sort of hits him like no no no not even paying attention.
Rym: Well after that when yeah, I'll get you.
Rym: yeah He's about to get him.
Rym: and then Ken just turns around and just looks at him like what are you gonna?
Rym: Do and the guys like oh shit, and then and Ken's like go ahead.
Rym: So he does the same thing that Dut-dut to the temples.
Scott: he puts his thumbs in Ken Shiro's temples like he's gonna kill him, and then he says You're already dead.
Rym: He says it but Watch this because I did not expect what was going to happen and of all the possible things that could have happened This was by far the most epic thing and the funniest thing that could have happened.
Scott: This is all the Hokuto.
Scott: no Ken you need to see because this is pretty much the highest point in the show that there could possibly be.
Scott: this is This is actually.
Scott: I would consider this a high point of anime comedy.
Rym: Then it seems like a lot of the high points of anime comedy or unintentional.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: it could have been intentionally funny I Think the when he says the oh more whatever How many seconds will I die in ten ten seconds all right?
Scott: I'll count it down for you.
Rym: kind of answers like oh ten.
Scott: Yeah, he's like all right.
Scott: Well.
Scott: Let's count it down shall we?
Rym: I should watch it again.
Rym: In fact.
Rym: I'm gonna watch it while Scott does this thing of the day.
Scott: no Let's watch it after so I can just do your thing today.
Scott: All right, so you know and you ever seen him I'm watching it.
Rym: Do you think of the day?
Scott: This is not good.
Rym: Just do it.
Scott: No all right, so You ever watch like an old movie like.
Scott: I don't know Monty Python the Holy Grail or the Pink Panther and they have those sort of.
Scott: you know those kinds of movie openings Sort of like the Rocky and Bullwinkle TV show opener.
Scott: You know a movie that it's got like a little swing in music and sort of like bright colors.
Scott: You know that kind of thing.
Scott: well.
Scott: generally a lot of 60s movies opened like that.
Rym: any movie that has a clever or a cool Opening I always just feel better about overall.
Scott: alright, so these guys what they did.
Scott: I don't know who they are, but they basically took Star Wars and they made an opener for Star Wars.
Scott: That's in that 1960s movie swing and opening style.
Rym: this is pretty hot.
Scott: It's pretty hot.
Scott: That's all I got.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I couldn't find any better things of the day whatever.
Scott: This is the best thing I saw.
Scott: so so watch it all right Rym.
Scott: stop watching the hook done.
Scott: Okay, but he's it's about to blow up five.
Rym: Four just gave it away three anyway.
Scott: So all right, that's what we're talking about today.
Scott: Yeah, let me let me introduce.
Scott: you want me to introduce.
Rym: I'll say this though for those of you are looking for the rest of our katsu gan covers Do we got another hour or so?
Rym: we record that when we have time?
Scott: alright, so In Japan you know it's very strange because there are many animes and mangas out there And it seems like there's a lot that are you know popular in one place and not popular in other place right for example?
Scott: One piece crazy popular in Japan and Italy not so much in the u.s.. Right didn't didn't do so well here But there's reasons for that right yeah at one piece was not good I don't know Ken crazy popular in Asia not popular here at all.
Rym: No, I don't.
Rym: I think that everyone who watches and likes hokuto.
Rym: no Ken watches it on a semi-ironic level.
Scott: Maybe of course there are people who flat-out deny that they do that.
Rym: yeah, but I don't know.
Scott: I Watching it seriously, I I can't say that it's good all right, but son like detective Conan, right Super so crazy popular in Japan right like.
Scott: they're on almost 500 episodes of detective Conan.
Scott: You know what and they put you put it on TV in the u.s.. Flop.
Rym: You know what scary GeekNights is catching up to that.
Scott: I guess there's there's many GeekNights as there are detective Conan almost.
Scott: So you could have watched every detective Conan instead of listening to GeekNights.
Scott: is that what you're saying?
Rym: You probably should have to?
Scott: oh yeah, but the 12 movies.
Scott: I think we have to catch up with that.
Scott: We need 12 nice movies.
Rym: We'll get started on the first one as soon as we get that camera right.
Scott: another one of these things That's crazy popular in the Japan and spit relatively unknown in the u.s.. Is Kitaro?
Scott: right and it's it's tricky because this hakaba kitaro and gigi gay.
Scott: No kitaro, and let me explain from talking to Japanese Person and reading Wikipedia and anime news network I believe you mean Wikipedia.
Scott: that inside joke is only relevant to you all right Wikipedia a Japanese person and Anime news network.
Scott: I am now going to tell you all you need to know about Gigi no kitaro and hakaba kitaro, and then we are going to talk about the latest in the Kitaro saga.
Scott: all right, so This was a manga called hakaba kitaro.
Scott: all right And the manga was from 1959. there are nine volumes of it.
Scott: That's it right.
Scott: It was a popular manga.
Scott: Then they made a TV series called gigi gay no kitaro based on the manga But it wasn't super based on the manga right it was a little bit based on the manga.
Scott: It was like the same characters the same kind of setting right, but it's much more like a kid-friendly show because you know it wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't as serious and as didn't have some of the things the manga hadn't it right?
Scott: and Gigi gay no kitaro was a lot more like a Monster of the week kind of plot structure.
Scott: you know every week There's a different sort of monster going on and we deal with it.
Scott: And then the episodes over.
Scott: it was a lot more kind of happy and silly and and you know for kids.
Scott: And that was a 65 episode TV series from in 1968 and 69. this is old shit man old shit.
Scott: Then they made another TV series in 1971 and 72.
Scott: Then they made another TV series.
Scott: you see where this is going.
Scott: there are like five different.
Scott: gigi gay no kitaro TV series is right.
Scott: it wasn't like one ongoing thing like detective Conan Which sort of just never stops or one piece which never stops.
Scott: It's they made a TV series.
Scott: They ended it.
Scott: It was crazy popular.
Scott: They made the second TV series and so on.
Scott: it would be like a big Oh got through third fourth and fifth seasons.
Scott: right Now there are also a live-action movie.
Scott: There's another live-action movie.
Scott: I can't tell if there's any.
Scott: there might be some anime movies.
Scott: Yeah, there's anime movies a whole lot of them.
Scott: There's a PlayStation game.
Scott: There's all kinds of stuff, right?
Scott: but the thing we're gonna talk about now is a Brand new TV anime.
Scott: you see there is currently a gigi gay no kitaro TV anime, right?
Scott: But there is also It started in January of this year a hakaba kitaro Anime.
Scott: hakaba kitaro anime.
Scott: now that what makes this hakaba kitaro anime special?
Rym: is that Dracula?
Rym: the fourth?
Rym: Is really really really a lame, dude?
Scott: Well, is that unlike gigi gay no kitaro, which is bait which is sort of a you know a kid-friendly version of the story.
Scott: Hakaba kitaro this anime series we're going to talk about that is currently available on fan sub is pretty much a direct Port is very very similar to the original 9 volume, you know hakaba kitaro manga.
Rym: now before we go any further I will say this if you're one of those anime fans who feels like you're bored or you're one of those people who isn't really an anime fan and you're just you know You listen to Wednesday because you can't get enough of GeekNights and you just you really really need it Especially since we didn't do a show last night due to the the incident.
Rym: but This is one of those shows that's different.
Rym: It's not like the stereotypical Anime looks different.
Rym: It feels different.
Rym: It's got such a different vibe that if you're looking for something that'll I don't know kind of push the envelope of what you watch As anime, this is one of the shows you should check out
Scott: You know, let me let me give you a couple interesting facts here just to get us started here, right?
Scott: All the gay gay gay no kitaro TV anime have the same opening and closing song, you know They might change the singers or rerecord it, but it's like the same openers and closers, right?
Scott: That's like the theme of the show Hakaba kitaro has a new opening song, which is awesome.
Rym: It's called Mononoke dance.
Scott: Well, it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: yeah, it's Mononoke dance, but it's like Mononoke dance.
Scott: You can play it.
Scott: I have the mp3.
Rym: Well, you know what I'll say this.
Rym: I'll say this We'll put it at the end as like a stinger.
Rym: No, but not only do I really like the song but the opener is is one of those openers right?
Rym: Oh, oh man this show it's so Rocking it's.
Scott: it's all stylized in like, you know The style of the original manga and it's totally funky and awesome.
Scott: the closers a little and it's just sort of a calm closer.
Scott: You know what though it is rare to have a show with good closers It is it is but the opener to this show rocks the house.
Scott: now something else interesting about this show Is that the voice actors for Kitaro the main character and his father sort of the secondary character?
Scott: His name is made Ama.
Scott: Oh, yeah G made Ama, right?
Scott: Cuz he's an eyeball.
Scott: Yeah, you see where he's not just an eyeball.
Scott: He's an eyeball with a tiny body.
Scott: He used to be a mummy used to be a mummy.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: their voice actors for the in the new hakaba kitaro show are the sort are the Original not these super original voice actors But pretty much like the fate the people the voice actors that are like famously associated with these characters.
Scott: You know like the I think they're from like the second TV series.
Scott: So it's sort of like, you know, they're coming back, you know from the olden days to reprise their roles as Kitaro.
Scott: So it's like if you had what our big Kitaro fan you'll watch this and you'd be like, oh the good voices are back.
Scott: Yes, that's the right voice instead of like, you know Where you would maybe seen that the of the newer giga no Kitaro series have been like, oh, who are these voice actors?
Scott: They don't sound the same.
Rym: well, I can say one thing the the the woman who does the voice of Kitaro Masakawa Nozawa is Famous for being in fucking everything.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much Kitaro doesn't really say that much in the show though, but the voice acting is really excellent though All right.
Scott: So, let's see.
Scott: What is this show about?
Scott: Let me try to sum this up a little bit here, right?
Rym: Well, I mean there's the funny way to sum it up.
Rym: The first episode is about an asshole who throws a baby and then goes to hell Kind of on purpose because he's not that bright.
Rym: Yeah, well basically This ticket will take you to hell whatever.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'm going to hell.
Rym: What'd you expect dude?
Scott: Yeah, the show is about this this.
Scott: this basically the story is this you have the earth, right?
Scott: But sort of supernatural ghosty monster hell kind of stuff is real.
Scott: Okay, and there were these people called the ghost tribe that used to live on earth and they still live on earth.
Scott: But they went.
Scott: humans normal humans came along they persecuted the ghost tribe and the ghost tribe went to live underground.
Scott: The final members the last remaining members of the ghost tribe which are Kitaro and his parents.
Scott: Well Kitaro's parents, right?
Scott: They come above ground to try to seek help because they have some disease.
Rym: now You know in pursuant to all this they go to a hospital and One way or another they end up making some ghosts kind of hang around in the house.
Scott: Yeah, but they're scary supernatural powers.
Scott: They mess up some stuff at the hospital.
Rym: So then kind of the other the main ish character guy has to investigate it.
Scott: He's not.
Scott: he's not the main character He's the main human character.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, you know what he sorrows.
Rym: the main character He's kind of like a lame not that bright kind of jerkish master Keaton like that seems to be his job Sort of I guess not easy.
Scott: He's definitely not a master.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: No, he's Technically a bachelor.
Rym: I guess not from a good school.
Scott: No, but basically, you know, this guy goes to investigate he finds the ghost people whatever we're just sorry.
Scott: and So stuff happens and I could give you all the details.
Scott: But he sort of ends up with Kitaro right and and Kitaro is born and you know Raises Kitaro and Kitaro is like the last ghost kid right the last member of the ghost tribe.
Scott: So he sort of lives like a human life in the human world Doing you know interacting with the humans yet.
Scott: He's a ghost tribe person.
Scott: He has supernatural stuff like.
Scott: he can go to hell whenever he wants and he interacts with all these other ghost tribe people.
Scott: And he's sort of creepy.
Scott: and you know, he's got his dad the eyeball hanging out with them telling him what to do.
Rym: I think that we should just not even explain the eyeball.
Scott: You just watch it and see no just his dad the eyeball.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: It's not just an eyeball There's more parts to it, but not as many as you might expect
Scott: right and basically every episode There's sort of some sort of supernatural, you know related troubles, right and by some crazy coincidence Kitaro gets tied up in them and maybe solves them in some sort of way.
Scott: but Unlike some other, you know, it's.
Scott: it's very strange in that Sometimes you have an anime like Gundam seed say right where there's a big Story and each episode is just like a chapter in the big story, right?
Scott: Sometimes you have an anime like cowboy bebop where the episodes are largely I mean, they're related a little bit right as a little thread that goes between them, but they're largely episodic.
Scott: Sometimes you have a show like Voltron where yeah, there might be a big story But pretty much every episode just stands alone.
Rym: But instead this show kind of follows this thread where each episode just kind of picks up from the last episode But yet doesn't rely on it and that if you hadn't seen the last episode You pretty much would it wouldn't matter.
Rym: like not seeing the previous episode doesn't matter at all.
Rym: But yet Everything kind of follows along in this chain that just goes off into infinity.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: There's no really big overarching plot Like.
Scott: there's no mega boss or giant conflict that needs to be resolved.
Scott: The conflicts are within each individual episode But little details from one episode usually carry into the next episode and maybe sometimes even More than one episode out.
Scott: for example in one episode Someone steals a lot of money from someone else and the next episode they use that money and it's like oh He's using that money and somebody makes a comment about the money.
Scott: You know in one at the end in one part of an episode near the end Something happens that something is the total is the main focus of the immediately following episode.
Rym: Now this show in a lot There's a lot of I mean.
Rym: what I like about it is that there's a lot of kind of black humor and a lot of times It'll be kind like a silly.
Rym: You're really kind of off the wall.
Rym: thing will happen, but it's kind of Surrounded by and part of this if you think about it actually happening.
Rym: It's really horrible Yeah, but yet it ends up with a tiny Representation of some Anka singer popping out of a tree and then wandering off to go get drunk.
Scott: Yeah the thing it.
Scott: I think the reason I like it so much is it reminds me quite a bit of the bug boy in which You have this sort of the bug boy.
Scott: You sort of have the horrible horror Aspect right because I mean these are horrible monsters doing monster things, you know people dying You know blood diseases all sorts of nastiness, right you have sort of the silly like the gross kind of horror.
Scott: But the gross heart is also comedic grossness.
Scott: cuz you got like a guy like, you know spewing bad breath into someone's face And then they pass out.
Rym: Well, that's sort of gross funny scary at the same thing the thing with Dracula the fourth and the eyeball Was the funniest one yet?
Rym: Yeah, it's a good one or just regular the fourth cuz he's.
Rym: He's lame tries to be so intense and like arm Dracula, but he's just really Really lame and pathetic.
Scott: Yeah, and then you know, you've got like other stuff going on like when they go to hell.
Scott: It's actually pretty scary down in hell I don't know.
Scott: I think that guy who kind of greets people coming in the guy who Gries guy the guy who greets people coming to hell is the best character in the show kind of like hey He like holds his thumb out like he said chucking Like hello.
Rym: And then I mean then there's uh, the rat man Nesumi or Toko who is Raman's Eve.
Scott: He's bad.
Scott: I don't like him.
Rym: He's not so evil so much as he's just a complete jerk.
Scott: Yeah, I don't like the rat man.
Scott: He's just he's an ass, but he's really smart.
Scott: He graduated from Monster University Which is you know, apparently only really smart people can graduate from Monster University.
Scott: I got some gas going on.
Scott: All right, great.
Rym: That's just what.
Rym: are you sure?
Rym: you're not Nesumi or Toko?
Scott: Maybe maybe anyway.
Scott: And the other thing though is the show also has plenty of like cuteness going on.
Scott: I mean Kitaro like if you look at his character design, you just look at it you say wow It's really easy to take that character design and it really was just a little change in the facial expression.
Scott: It can go from like horror to cuteness in a very Quasimodo kind of way, you know very easily and I think it's it's very apt because as the show is all about is he got Comedy, you got horror.
Scott: You got cuteness all sort of rolled into one with this very distinctive stylings And I like it.
Scott: I like it a lot and maybe you like it.
Scott: Got anything else to say?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: we could talk a little bit about the animation in the style The way the show is put together it and I really like the like.
Rym: the effect and the way this seems to play out is that it almost feels like every scene as you're watching is a panel in a comic or in a manga that is then Animated as much as it would be animated and then the next kind of when the camera cuts It's like it cuts to the next panel and you're going panel by panel in a comic and then Animating like what would have been going on in each panel.
Rym: that might sound strange But you'll see what I mean when you watch it.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like.
Scott: one of those things we're like, you know that one scene in flcl where it's like.
Scott: You know, they it's sort of like a manga moving around.
Scott: It's not like that No, but it's definitely like storyboarded like they might have just used the original manga as storyboard.
Rym: It's like, you know, sometimes you say a manga is cinematic.
Rym: I'd say the reverse of this that this show is Mongomatic.
Scott: maybe.
Scott: I think a really large reason that that Comes across is because they apply.
Scott: so I don't know what it is because they're not an expert on these matters But some sort of filter where it looks like a lot of the backgrounds are like sorta.
Scott: It looks like like a watercolor Painting or like a. really it it's like if you took a really old manga where sort of the pages got discolored But they were in color.
Scott: It looks like that like they made everything look like some sort of like water damaged Painting almost and it really changes the atmosphere and everything and it's it's actually really cool and nothing else looks like it But it doesn't really interfere either.
Scott: It's like they apply some crazy filter to like the show at all times You know, usually that really stands out like a sore thumb and makes it sort of annoying to watch.
Scott: But here you really only you don't even really notice it.
Scott: It's so subtle yet.
Rym: It's so effective and also in terms of like the plot and the way it progresses the This is one of those shows that cuts right to the chase right to the interesting part.
Rym: like this will sound strange, but there's an episode the last one we just watch actually where someone plants a blood tree in someone's arm and The like the hint at it like oh the tree was planted in his arm.
Rym: now a normal show you'd expect like There's gonna be this sinister.
Rym: He's got a lump and he doesn't know what to do and he goes to the doctor and the doctor doesn't know what it is And this thing is kind of festering and growing and then it comes to a head.
Rym: and oh my god.
Rym: the next scene is.
Rym: the guy looks at his arm and there's a tree growing out of it and he goes ah And then the next scene he's at the doctor and the doctor's like I don't fucking know but you're gonna die.
Rym: And then it just it just goes straight away.
Scott: Yeah, it's really crazy because usually like it almost seems like the show The the pace is so fast that you would be like, oh, there's not enough exposition to make a decent show here.
Scott: But at the same time It's very weird.
Scott: the pace is quick But it doesn't leave anything out.
Scott: But at the same time you have to really pay attention because sometimes you know Like everything everyone says is meaningful every moment is is you know, so full and they don't waste anything.
Scott: Everything is quality and everything matters.
Scott: So you got to pay full attention to what's going on pay full attention to every word everyone says but it zooms right through the plot and It keeps you really interested all the time because there's always something new happening all the time.
Rym: Yeah, I like that And I think we can leave it at that.
Rym: I mean, I don't want to really walk through the plot or what happens now.
Scott: We don't need to do that.
Rym: All I have to say those I think my favorite thing is still when the two vampires fight Yeah the east versus West Dracula versus the Chinese vampire and then Especially when the rat man walks over after it's all over and how he kind of reacts to all that.
Scott: My favorite is Jen.
Scott: My favorite part is pretty much any time.
Scott: Hell is involved.
Scott: It's mean in the first episode Guitar goes, you know He goes to hell like to have a good time and then later on when hell comes back into play Really funny stuff happens with who goes who stays in hell?
Scott: who leaves hell?
Scott: what happens to people going to hell?
Scott: How you get in and out?
Scott: I just I'm a big fan of the G Goku.
Scott: What can I say?
Rym: Yeah, all right, so once again tomorrow we'll explain why there is no episode.
Rym: Yesterday and this weekend or at some point we'll record the rest of our Katsucon 2008 coverage.
Rym: But I can sum it up The Khan was pretty damn awesome Other than the fact that we both got sick and all of our staff got sick.
Scott: What do we still have to talk about?
Rym: We didn't actually talk about the Khan.
Rym: we talked about all of our craft at Katsucon and then we stopped Alrighty, then.
Scott: Yeah, it was a nice hotel room.
Rym: the end and stay tuned.
Rym: We're probably going to be doing events at Connecticut Otakon anime next.
Scott: Maybe are we doing anime next really?
Rym: I submit it.
Rym: I haven't finalized anything yet.
Rym: Maybe gaming for hope.
Rym: We're probably not gonna make anime Boston this year, but we're gonna shoot for it.
Scott: Isn't that this weekend?
Rym: Yes We're not gonna make it man.
Scott: We never make it to anime boss.
Scott: That's a big con to like.
Scott: if I looked at a map of the no, it's not this weekend It's March 21st and 23rd.
Scott: So two weekends.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much that in necco con are the only big cons in this area.
Rym: We don't do stuff.
Scott: is necco con that big?
Rym: It's big enough.
Rym: It's it's big enough to be worth caring about.
Scott: Well, it's November 7th.
Scott: Oh wait Okay.
Rym: Yeah, we could.
Scott: Yeah, you could Let me look at the guest list.
Scott: But anyway, we're done with this episode.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: *JAPANESE LANGUAGE*.