Rym: It's Thursday November 13th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight Thursdays.
Rym: change it up.
Scott: Let's do this Stayed home today Went to work I'm gonna stay home tomorrow too, and I don't even have to use days or anything.
Rym: see I actually have too many days.
Rym: I got to figure out exactly which days I'm taking.
Rym: I'm.
Rym: I think I really think I'm gonna take off like every Wednesday in December and then like the last two weeks of the month.
Scott: yeah I guess like this of this work that I'm I need to do that needs to get done pretty soon.
Rym: I'm in that boat.
Rym: I'm behind on every project.
Scott: I had I should probably do.
Scott: It's just one work.
Scott: It's not a bunch of projects one thing I'm supposed to do but and they're like yeah, you know you can work on it from home.
Scott: You got the VPN working right.
Rym: ah you know what I've actually been working from home a lot lately.
Rym: because it's like I'm at work.
Rym: Alright I can either go home on the 410 train And then if I have another hour work to do I can just do it at home in the comfort of my house in My Aeron chair with food and drink and music and I can be mostly naked Or I can stay at work take a crappy crowded train home get stuck in traffic on my way back.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just not gonna do it until Monday.
Scott: I'm gonna instead do what I did today, which is spend most of the day working on GeekNights shit Website and such.
Rym: see I don't.
Rym: actually I really don't feel that I've been working a lot of extra hours this week But I don't well actually for the last like month.
Rym: But I don't feel bad about it because I still work fewer hours than a lot of other people Not just in my company But just in general like people seems like a lot of people we know will put in a lot of overtime with no real benefit.
Scott: yeah, I don't know why.
Rym: I mean if it's a choice between Do the overtime or you lose your job, and you're not in a place where you can easily get another job quickly well I mean this.
Scott: the thing is there's a lot of people out there right who?
Scott: Actually get paid hourly and make overtime money in those people if they've got nothing better to do.
Scott: You know if they're just gonna go home and play NS Or if they're just gonna go home, and you know play World of Warcraft or something I mean think about this if you work two hours of overtime Even if because of that you have to eat dinner like you know at a restaurant or a takeout place instead of eating dinner At home you still make enough money to make back that.
Scott: and Unless you're doing something after work.
Scott: You're not really losing anything.
Rym: But you're forgetting something because remember there was a time a time when we were in college a time When I often could not afford food.
Rym: I could not afford food.
Rym: I had a job.
Rym: very often the the the manager would come out and say something to the effect of Hey if someone wants to go home right now they can and I would be the first one out the door.
Rym: well The boss would say hey anyone wants him overtime And I'd be hell no and then I'd go home and realize that I didn't have any food or money to buy food.
Scott: The thing is is that when in those in those times when you left work immediately it was summer in College and awesome.
Scott: so the time you weren't spending at work was time of awesome.
Scott: So I'm talking about someone who if they leave work is gonna go home to a family they hate or go home to a TV.
Rym: No, I posit this to you if you're good if you're one of those people who's going home to the family you hate There is a far bigger problem in your life than working overtime.
Scott: This is true, but at least under overtime is understandable If you are that person if you are a salaried employee like ribbon I and Your pay doesn't change depending on how many hours you work.
Scott: That's simply a matter of either work and get paid at work.
Rym: and don't guess the critical part cuz that IBM.
Rym: No, I wasn't gonna get promoted.
Rym: just cuz the way IBM was nothing was gonna happen to me.
Rym: good if I worked 60 hours or 10 Hours, so I just did my job and that was it the hospital.
Rym: I don't want to get into how poorly managed they were but now My bone it.
Rym: basically I'll probably just get a much bigger bonus because I've been working late And I kind of need that for a down payment on a house.
Rym: So it's about the right time.
Scott: Yeah, I my pay does not change based on how many hours I work.
Scott: So I just work and I you know, I get all the work I need to get done on time and actually that's it You know.
Rym: one cool thing about when I worked at that hospital is it?
Rym: I was a salaried employee But I still logged my hours and the way they handled overtime Was that you had to work thirty seven and a half hours a week and that was really the only Requirement as far as like payroll.
Rym: and all those people were concerned and a lot of people worked a lot of extra hours.
Rym: A lot of them didn't log the hours because their bosses told him not to.
Rym: but that's just cuz they were dumb.
Scott: But I would log ever if there was our logging which never has been for me.
Rym: I don't think it was the dumbest thing because they they do this.
Rym: they'd like log.
Rym: they'd work hours that they didn't log.
Rym: But then their boss would let them take like a week off which was more vacation time than they'd get.
Rym: just had to do it Like kind of secretly.
Scott: Oh, that's how they were.
Rym: Basically everyone in the company did all these like secret deals with their bosses to like hey Can I just work late tonight and then skip Monday and Tuesday?
Scott: I wish I could do that.
Scott: That'd be awesome.
Scott: I'd go for that a lot.
Rym: There were a few people who worked the four ten hour days a week.
Scott: if I if I was a boss of people.
Scott: Basically, I wouldn't care if people showed up at the office unless there was a meeting at the office They had to be at.
Scott: I wouldn't care if people stayed home.
Scott: All I would care is this is the work it needs to be done on this time and That's it.
Scott: If that happens you can do whatever you want.
Rym: many a lot of jobs.
Rym: you.
Rym: there's concurrent work with other people So you really got to have people around at the same time or else the works not gonna get done.
Rym: And if it's if you don't get the work done Do that because then you're leaving it All right, so you and me are on a project and we got to get it done and you're like, yeah Let's work all day Monday and finish it.
Rym: I'm like, fuck you.
Rym: I'm working Friday and then we don't get anything done.
Rym: We won't get fired great.
Scott: Yeah, that that was our fault for being dumbass.
Scott: isn't not working together?
Scott: Nah, nah, but that way if some it would be apparent very very quickly.
Scott: if someone was not capable of working You know freely and awesomely and if someone isn't that's not the kind of person I want working for me.
Scott: Honestly, I kind of like having the schedule now at least just because I commute on the train People who needed to work together would use you know technology to schedule the times they needed to be together.
Rym: No Because that member at college that never worked unless the professor set it up had no one ever worked together properly on things.
Scott: Oh, we did.
Rym: You're the only ones.
Rym: I don't think I ever in the history of my time at RIT had a meeting with a group for a class whereupon Everyone in the group showed up.
Rym: I've never Once it happened.
Scott: there have been groups that I have been in where there were people not showing up But at least one or two other people always showed up and I have had groups that were like the perfect best groups where everyone Showed up and was awesome all the time.
Scott: Most of you I guess you know.
Scott: But the best group actually was when I took the XML not the XML class the ad hoc networking class Because it was basically me a guy I was in a group with before who was awesome and two graduate students who were awesome.
Scott: It was just four awesome people, you know, cuz I'm awesome.
Scott: Also see the.
Rym: I guess the problem I had in IT was that the one time I was in a really awesome group.
Rym: Everyone was so awesome that no one wanted to do the work because it was boring work.
Scott: Oh, see we you know, this is a high-level CS class of you know, hard awesome work.
Rym: Yeah And that class only the last couple labs were high-level.
Rym: the first couple labs were like Here is how to deal with like running cables through walls and cut and dry wall.
Scott: This wasn't a. this is wasn't a situation of labs.
Scott: This is a situation of the whole class is one project.
Scott: You basically spend the entire quarter making it and every single week you have to present where you're at and such.
Scott: So, you know, I basically did all the front heavy work and then went ah for the rest of the quarter.
Scott: Well, everyone else did the top heavy.
Rym: But anyway, you do make a good point.
Rym: Remember those days?
Rym: Yeah, what about days in those summers where we lived at RIT?
Rym: We had nothing to do.
Rym: No responsibilities You had like one like summer half.
Scott: I had class I had the the the third But they basically be the calculus three.
Scott: Yeah calculus three for the third time Three by three.
Scott: Yeah, see I took calculus in high school.
Scott: So when I got to RIT, they made me take calculus one two and three.
Scott: So the calculus one.
Scott: it was so laughably easy because I had already taken calculus in high school.
Scott: That was like they give me problems like, you know derived the old way and I'm like, I already know You know annex to the n-1.
Scott: I can't even my brain won't even do it the old way anymore because I know the new way.
Scott: this isn't gonna happen.
Scott: but I got like, you know an a and then it was calculus 2 which was like.
Scott: But ti 89 was able to pull me through calculus 2 and then calculus 3.
Scott: I just didn't understand what they were saying And I didn't understand what they were saying again.
Scott: And then I took it in the summer and I got to see which was you know, good enough to graduate Outstanding and I got the same degree that someone who got much better grades got and probably a better.
Rym: I at least had the requirement of if I didn't maintain a 3.4 one IBM would never have hired me because they required a 3.4.
Scott: Well, I already yeah, I already knew that I did not care to work at any place.
Scott: You know The only places that look at the GPA and stuff and actually cared are big companies.
Scott: Like if I wanted to work at Intel, yeah But I.
Rym: yeah, I only work at big companies because more and more I work in a company IT for small companies.
Rym: It's not fun and doesn't pay.
Rym: well and you it you're.
Rym: I mean if you're the IT guy for a small company They're not hiring more IT guys.
Rym: You're it you're on call.
Rym: You're the only one never go on vacation.
Scott: I guess if I was it and it's I guess if I was IT I would like to work at the bigger company because that's what the big iron is.
Scott: but being CS It's better to work at the small company.
Scott: Everyone's just chillin chillin hanging out having a good time Relax, no big faceless, you know Policies and things getting in the way Just do it.
Scott: However, it's supposed to be done.
Rym: And yeah, I definitely agree Of course now I get.
Rym: I get the benefits of both because there's only like a hundred people in my company But everything is run like it's a big company.
Rym: So we still have all the like enterprise stuff, but there's only a hundred people.
Scott: Yeah, we just bought and things are getting.
Scott: you know, they're slowly getting weird but we're seeing how we can do.
Scott: and you know, the boss who used to be you know, the Tech partner is now the New York tech manager and he's he's looking out for us.
Scott: He's all good.
Scott: So as long as we have the defenses up, well, we'll be alright.
Rym: So anyway Tonight we decided you know, it's Thursday and remember way back.
Rym: We said we were taking Thursday shows.
Rym: We're just gonna change it up go crazy.
Rym: We're gonna do all the cool weird stuff on Thursdays.
Rym: We're gonna break format and Yeah, Thursdays ended up being two newses.
Rym: We didn't care about and then a main bit that usually devolved into well what we just did.
Scott: Yeah, well, I think you know, the problem is we just when you have a you know People talk about creativity, right and it's like when you have some sort of focus or limit on your creativity It's much easier to come up with something.
Scott: For example, if someone says, you know come up with a cool video.
Scott: It's like uh But if someone says come up with a funny video game video It's like huh, you can actually you have something to build off of it actually can think and I think Thursday in Thursday it was not a do.
Scott: this Thursday was a. don't do tech don't do video games don't do anime don't do comic.
Scott: So and don't do science.
Rym: and I remember for the longest time it was either we did a food show Yeah, or we talked about a movie We just watch.
Scott: so it's very very difficult.
Scott: even when we decided to you know in throwing away the format of Thursday made it even harder to come up because now we even Have less direction.
Rym: So we did.
Rym: the best we could come up with is I think every Thursday.
Rym: now This isn't.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: the reason we're not doing this stuff in the experimental feed is because the experimental feed is going to be reserved For the really out there stuff.
Scott: Yeah, basically we came but we've always had a bajillion ideas the experimental feed and never done them because we don't have time for that.
Rym: Shit, but we're getting there.
Rym: I've actually got I've got several things recorded that eventually there's gonna be regular content in there and You know, I'm.
Scott: as soon as this website is ready our ability to do more crazy shit will be greatly enhanced.
Rym: But and shit just got real.
Scott: it got real.
Scott: You should see some of the features that are.
Scott: at first.
Scott: It's the website's pretty much just gonna just list the episodes and link to the mp3s and that sort of thing.
Scott: But you'll see it's features will slowly grow on to it like a like a like barnacles.
Scott: only good because barnacles are not so good.
Scott: Sometimes they are are they really?
Scott: Oh never.
Scott: No, I mean even if you're a whale you want some armor.
Rym: Probably not whale armor whale armor.
Rym: Yeah, how about a giant whale?
Scott: What do you?
Scott: all whales are giant.
Rym: now, I don't think you understand how giant.
Rym: the one that went to the moon was very large Back down the map.
Scott: It was how did he get there?
Rym: It was bigger than the city on the map by far.
Rym: It was like the size of four city squares.
Rym: The big whale take it to the moon.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not armor.
Scott: You Need the paladin anyway.
Rym: So we decided for now.
Scott: what we're gonna do with Thursday is For now meaning for today and we'll see what happens.
Rym: Well now for now in the general sense, there's two.
Rym: there's two for now's.
Rym: for now number one general sense.
Rym: Thursday we're going to try out formats of the show and Bits and all those things because we got a lot of bits that we never really incorporated into the show.
Scott: We're still gonna talk about books too on Thursdays.
Rym: yeah, yeah, but pretty much I think the best way to go forward with Thursday is to Everything like we have.
Rym: we can have a multitude of formats because right now GeekNights says the one format, you know news news thing of the day main vid Thursday can be a different format like every time to match the content of Whatever.
Rym: we're talking about that.
Scott: Thursday Yeah, and we'll probably steal things from other shows and try to remix them and combine them and some people might notice us stealing and Some people might not.
Scott: and you know maybe we'll try to come up with new stuff and mix it with the stolen stuff and and formats that work will then be a retconned into Monday Tuesday Wednesday show.
Scott: Yeah, we'll try to party.
Scott: We'll try to be like the Japanese steal ever steal everyone's ideas and then make them ten times better.
Rym: Isn't the old strategy to steal from the Forgotten Masters exactly?
Scott: Gonna steal from someone steal from the Forgotten Masters Because then it appears as you're great as a master, but no one knows you're stealing.
Rym: But anyway the for now of right now is whenever we can't come up with a topic for a Thursday Then what?
Rym: basically these two things?
Rym: if we can't come up with a format for a Thursday Then what we're gonna do is just like pick a topic and force it and if we can't come up with a topic We're gonna pick a format and force it.
Rym: so tonight we couldn't come up with a topic.
Rym: so we decided to force a format and The crab people I came up with was I'll have a topic.
Scott: people know what crab people is.
Scott: We keep saying it.
Rym: I don't think we should tell them.
Rym: All right, or should we?
Scott: I know if you don't know what crab people is.
Rym: You're not cool It's a crab people.
Rym: It's now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right So I guess you could have crab people II then it could be an adjective people.
Scott: I people I multi-pass.
Rym: Yeah, quite really Honestly, yeah, really?
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Well, there were like nine jokes and okay anyway, so Scott's got a topic.
Rym: I've got a topic and inadvertently we didn't tell each other what the topics are.
Rym: So one if the topics end up being the same topic I don't know what we'll do because I can't imagine that being the case All right, but I don't know.
Rym: should we flip a coin?
Rym: I got a C a d6 over there.
Scott: I rolled roll your d6.
Scott: All right, I got evens means you go first.
Rym: evens mean I go first.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right, here we go.
Scott: You could be lying.
Rym: It's a one.
Scott: No, it's not good.
Scott: I could roll again.
Scott: I Don't know then.
Scott: What's the point of even rolling if it's just We're not gonna obey the dice.
Scott: what's the point of using it?
Rym: That's always been the way I flip coins whenever I need to make a decision that I flip a coin for And I urge anyone who has to flip coins when you're not playing a German board game To use this method.
Rym: I say with me you're not playing a German board game Because if you're playing a German board game, you're flipping a coin.
Rym: It should actually be random.
Rym: if it's not random Don't flip a coin.
Rym: But anyway, if you're gonna flip a coin to figure out what to do flip the coin and if you immediately in any way balk at the result choose the Opposite answer from what you flipped and don't look back.
Scott: Yeah, cuz that means you know, it's like.
Scott: it's like if you're flipping a coin It's because you don't know what you want.
Scott: But if you flip the coin and you get a result and you feel like you don't want that like you're like I don't want to do what the coin said then do the other thing, you know Just don't then just do.
Scott: the other thing is obviously you didn't like the one you got.
Scott: Yes, but don't lie to yourself.
Rym: Don't be angry with or for the coin.
Rym: Just just go with the opposite.
Rym: Yeah, you don't have to do whatever the coin tells you to do As long as you promise to protect both children and coins.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Okay enough of this cavalcade crap.
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: I guess they're barking and you're going first.
Rym: Well, I assume you're not talking about Martin Martin Luther King jr.
Rym: Estate.
Scott: no, okay Is that what you're talking about?
Scott: I'm talking about really?
Scott: Yeah Cuz it came up What.
Scott: well, there's one thing I know about Martin Luther King jr.
Scott: Estate and that is his wife.
Scott: Coretta Scott King died Relatively recently like months maybe a year something to go due to Randy BS due to well do Well, yes, she had cancer and she could have easily.
Scott: I mean, you know, there's no cure for cancer There's no magic.
Scott: cancer goes away and you survive right but many many people Survive all types of cancer because they go and get chemotherapy and radiation therapy and all sorts of other Painful medicines in hospitals that she could have easily gotten just by going to a hospital.
Scott: You know, she's Coretta Scott King Martin Luther King's wife.
Scott: She could have gotten them.
Scott: that do you know?
Scott: she even if she didn't have the money which you know Obviously she had the money and she could have gotten the money easily Right.
Scott: She could have been you know, good chance of survival not like a guarantee but good chance very good chance.
Scott: instead She decided to go to Mexico to see some Randy bullshit clinic not real medicine doctor and she died To no one's surprise.
Scott: who knew that she was going to get fake medicine?
Rym: Yeah, but that's not what I'm gonna talk about.
Scott: Okay, because I guess if she hadn't done that with the question of the estate even be a question right now She'd probably still be alive.
Rym: Uh, I don't the thing I'm gonna talk about.
Rym: I don't think you know the the fullness of the state of the state of Martin Luther King.
Rym: jr.
Scott: I'd know I did not.
Scott: I know nothing of this.
Scott: I didn't even see it on Google News Really?
Rym: This is one of those things is gonna make you really really angry.
Rym: But anyway, because I rolled a one Alright, I guess you have to go first.
Scott: Well, I know we're talking about.
Rym: That was simply a preview.
Scott: Oh, well, I was just gonna talk about how Rym is stupid.
Rym: All right, go for it.
Rym: No, that's I'm waiting.
Scott: No, I basically copped out and You know, I was gonna write a long post in the forum that I stopped earlier.
Scott: So I said aha what an easy way to do that - what a way to foot.
Scott: what an easy way to fill up The show.
Rym: Wait, did you write like a quarter of the post in the forum and then close the window or the tab?
Scott: No, I did a okay cuz I don't like two paragraphs and then ctrl-a and pushback space and then close the tab.
Scott: See, I usually close the tab when I balk But basically I just said hey, you know what?
Scott: Uh, cuz that was so easy.
Scott: I've already thought of two paragraphs.
Scott: I'll save it for right now.
Scott: What you know?
Scott: nice cop-out.
Scott: basically what I was gonna talk about is cuz you know, people were talking about this.
Scott: You know, there was the regular old bailout of the the mortgage companies and the banks, right?
Scott: And now they're talking about, you know bailing out the auto companies.
Rym: and there was I in the state of California, which really you realize the state of California's Current deficit is now more than the GNP of more than a hundred countries.
Scott: Whoa, and You know New York State actually just said, you know what?
Scott: We're gonna have to cut back the spending because we don't have any money which is the first Thing I've seen about cutting back spending as opposed to you know, getting more fake money.
Rym: First thing you do.
Scott: Yeah Back the spending on education and Well, it depends.
Rym: I mean you cut back spending unless that's not an option.
Rym: I mean if your choice is either run at a deficit or stop sending kids to school You should probably run at the deficit.
Scott: or you know, no, but yeah, but they're not not sending kids to school They're just make getting schools less money.
Rym: So no new textbooks this year, you know, that sort of thing I went to like one of the richest schools in Michigan outside of the fancy boarding schools and we still had like Nine-year-old textbooks beating the hell out.
Scott: Yeah, me too.
Scott: I went to you know, relatively, you know, big-money high school.
Scott: I mean it was in the wealthiest County in the wealthiest state in the entire in the wealthiest country in the world.
Scott: You know wasn't the wealthiest town But it was a wealthy town.
Rym: man talk about silver spoons because I went I lived in like the fourth or fifth Wealthiest suburb in the country and that's per capita though You know, they're like you can like places like Beverly Hills have mad monies.
Scott: But then there's still like Monaco where there's also a lot really really low money.
Scott: Yeah We'll have to compare the Fairfield County, Connecticut is just you know average big monies all around.
Scott: no low monies.
Rym: We'll have to compare the gross to the per capita.
Scott: and then there's a small area in Westport, Connecticut.
Scott: That's just huge monies.
Scott: like famous people.
Rym: I lived in the Mushroom Ring of Prosperity around the decaying center.
Rym: That is Detroit.
Scott: Yeah, yeah But anyway, so the whole the main thing that's going on right now is the question of you know Bailing out the auto companies Ford GM mostly those two right.
Scott: and the situation is this see these really big companies.
Scott: right, the big companies are ran are run incredibly inefficiently are incredibly stupidly and They're losing money, you know, and they have cash right in their wallets.
Scott: But their wallets are slowly emptying and in a certain number of months their wallets will be empty Unlike say Google or Microsoft who have giant wallets that are not emptying.
Scott: So even if they start being unprofitable They're gonna be around for a long time.
Scott: The car companies might just run out of money.
Scott: Yeah, and if you look the US already we have you know The airplane companies and Amtrak and them and most of the X.
Rym: not a good example, but for a lot of reasons I don't get into it.
Scott: The point is is you have one Amtrak.
Scott: the point is and that is that whether you support them or not the you have these Transportation related companies where if the government just didn't give them a bunch of tax money all the time They're incredibly unprofitable and inefficient and would go out of business and all those people wouldn't have jobs and it would be the end.
Rym: Yep, now but at least in the case with the transportation things they provide it's kind of like the government is subsidizing this service.
Rym: that is at least in the government's eyes or Possibly the lobbyists eyes a net boon to society.
Rym: in a bit of perfect world Amtrak and failing airlines are at least a boon to.
Scott: I think you know Ideally right as people always talk about, you know, the old socialism capitalism divide, right?
Scott: And it's I think the way you have to handle it Which is something that is pretty obvious and just people don't say it often even though smart people all know it Is that there are some things out there?
Scott: there are some services which there's no reason to profit from them either because a It's a necessary thing that is impossible to profit from you know, because it's just a losing deal be because it's something where you if the influences of you know profit invaded into that service.
Scott: it would you know provide a you know a Negative effect on society as a whole, you know things like, you know medicines and you know transportation You know public transit and things like that.
Scott: Really having those things be for-profit private companies is not is not gonna work out.
Rym: Yeah, kind of like for-profit prisons.
Rym: bad idea Exactly exactly, but the point I was just trying to make is that at least with like the airlines and you know These sorts of things Amtrak.
Rym: It's a direct boon to society.
Rym: It's a direct boon to the people that's being subsidized.
Rym: but with the auto industry It's like this indirect boon because the old the boon to society is primarily that Towns and cities that otherwise do not have any sort of enough jobs to maintain themselves Have jobs like cities exist because these auto companies exist to create jobs.
Rym: But it's like this indirect thing because we're creating them through this for-profit enterprise.
Rym: And then the boon is the secondary effect as opposed to the primary effects.
Scott: Yep, you know cuz like, you know if we pay money to keep say, you know American Airlines in business, right?
Scott: What does that mean?
Scott: Well, it means that American people can get from here to there, you know quickly.
Scott: if we didn't do that You wouldn't be able to get everywhere.
Scott: You'd only be able to get to the profitable cities.
Scott: You wouldn't be able to fly to.
Scott: you know, North Dakota, you know.
Scott: But now because you know the government subsidizes these airlines you can fly to North Dakota Which is I guess useful for some people especially those who live in North Dakota, even though it doesn't exist.
Scott: and they don't exist.
Rym: But that's been a thing with Scott for a long time.
Scott: I've never been there.
Scott: I've never met anyone who is from there.
Scott: We met people at RIT were from there Someone who said they had a friend who is from there.
Scott: That's not good enough for me.
Rym: Okay, do we have to go there?
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Cuz I mean I remember Iteration.
Scott: I bet we'll just drive north from South Dakota We'll enter Canada and you'll be like see Scott we went through North Dakota and I'm like, aha sure remember that Plan alpha of desert bus involved going through North Dakota.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah anyway, so You know with the subsidizing the airlines you get that sort of thing where now we can you know have Transportation for people in North Dakota.
Scott: We did not have before subsidizing the airlines and the auto companies.
Scott: All that does is You know keep all these people in their jobs.
Scott: There's no other reason to keep you know subsidizing auto companies other than these people won't have any jobs because we can get cars from Japanese companies European companies or Even other American companies that are not, you know, we can get that are not Ford or GM, you know There there's at least one other.
Rym: well, but there's all it's.
Rym: it's really difficult to talk about companies in that sense because the auto industry is really really incestuous a lot more than people realize and Companies make engines for each other and there's all sorts of overlap.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah I mean you go to go to the actual Ford website like the Universal Ford website and you'll see all the logos of all the different things that are actually forward.
Scott: Aston Martin is actually Ford Mazda's actually Ford.
Scott: it's like there's a whole bunch of things that are actually Ford besides Ford and basically everything else is GM, but So it's not a problem with us not having enough cars.
Scott: There are plenty of cars.
Scott: We don't really need more except for you know, people like to buy new ones, but there's you know the demand for cars.
Rym: Yeah, I can't think of one possible Boon indirectly for creating these cars by hat by making sure that there are a lot of domestic cars available.
Rym: It drives the price of foreign cars down because if there were only foreign cars and a limited number of domestic cars Then over time the price of cars would go up because there's no competition internally and there's no incentive for foreign companies to offer lower prices.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But that's Such an indirect.
Scott: the other thing is that the foreign companies, you know would end up still competing with each other for you know The because the supply of cars might fall under the demand and then you would have these, you know They would all compete over, you know by the you know, the French car no by the Japanese car No by the you know, whatever car that you know.
Scott: that competition would drive the prices down.
Rym: But I guess I would argue that having the domestic mark the domestic production at least stabilizes car prices.
Rym: Yeah, it's in in a short-term way Yeah, I think yeah, but I think that's what stabilizing does it makes things less prone to change in the short term exactly.
Scott: So the thing is.
Scott: the major problem here is I actually on the one hand I say man We should just let those car companies go out of business.
Scott: They were poorly managed, right?
Scott: They were spending their money like stupid.
Scott: they you know, we're not.
Scott: you know driving up demand for cars.
Scott: You know spending way too much money in advertising not enough on making newer better cars building a whole bunch of SUVs.
Scott: You know, they I point out something really sad that I learned they did right, you know ever since Roger Rabbit way back in the day It's just been bad for no Something really bad today.
Rym: remember when gas prices were going up and up and up and like SUV sales Collapsed and they lost money on the SUVs.
Rym: Yeah SUV sales are way up.
Rym: Now the gas prices are back down.
Rym: Yeah I think the FARC headline was as more proof that people never learn from their mistakes and never look to the past for guidance.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I still understand why people buy SUVs, but that's not what I'm talking about.
Scott: So on, you know going by that I feel like we should let these companies go out of business.
Scott: They're not a company like, you know Amtrak where or American Airlines.
Scott: So they provide where they're providing something that is can't be profitable, but it's sort of necessary infrastructure in a way.
Scott: But But It's not because I didn't want to say but They're not providing any a necessary infrastructure kind of thing.
Scott: And if they went out of business, they're just wouldn't be nude GM cars, they wouldn't you know, but By letting them go in the wrong place.
Scott: Yes, but by letting them go out of business, right?
Scott: All of these unskilled laborers will lose their jobs not just unskilled.
Rym: there are a lot of highly skilled laborers, too.
Scott: Yes, the thing is right is that you don't?
Scott: it's it's like if we let the companies go out of business.
Scott: You don't feel bad for the highly skilled laborers.
Scott: They would get new jobs, you know, well the executives could get new jobs.
Scott: It depends.
Rym: the executives are not highly trained labor.
Rym: Most of them.
Scott: No, no, no, but it's like.
Scott: but like you Don't have a choice of like, you know, cuz the reason the company's doing bad is not because of the factory workers It's because.
Scott: well who may
Rym: well part of the problem why the American car companies are doing so poorly is because of the workers but again indirectly because of the benefits that were paid and Promised due to the unions back when the car industry was very profitable are still liabilities today and pensions and health care And things are so much higher for American car companies and other car companies, which I'm not arguing against.
Rym: I'm saying that's kind of how it is.
Rym: That is one of the primary reasons they're having so much trouble.
Scott: Well, here's the thing right.
Scott: and when the economy is bad the companies, you know in bargaining with unions Should have a lot more power and they should be able to just say look pensions are gone You're screwed.
Scott: now either you do what we say or you're gonna have no jobs in this bad economy.
Rym: Screwing the pensions only hurts all the old people who were promised the pensions and that's how they're retiring.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, but either either hey, you know, we screw the pensions and they can't retire on that.
Scott: But you know now, okay, so I get your social security.
Scott: Well, no the other doing it.
Scott: the way we're doing it is basically saying here you can have your pension But now we're gonna tax it all the way from you to give the money back to your company So it stays in business.
Rym: Well, no because the the tax is funding.
Rym: This would be coming from you and me not from the people living in Detroit.
Scott: Yeah, that's real fair.
Rym: We are paying for that.
Rym: It's got we and by we I mean people living in like New York and Major urban centers and the quote-unquote blue states.
Rym: now I'm not trying to make a value judgment here by any stretch.
Rym: But we basically fund the existence of many places in the rest of the country And I'm fine with that for a lot of historical and societal reasons, but that's kind of how it is.
Rym: Anyway, so how is this any different?
Rym: Well the thing here, I guess it's different because Michigan's a blue state.
Scott: the thing is right is We're entering a situation where what do we do about the fact that there is you know in a world where we don't yet Have in a world.
Scott: Yes, we we all know we all know that someday, right?
Scott: We'll invent some sort of nanotechnology diamond age type replicator technology and even people who don't want to work.
Scott: We're able to live at some subsisting level doing absolutely nothing and you know, they'll be able to eat and have some sort of protective shelter and clothing and Then you know the the people who want to do things will do things.
Scott: people don't want to do anything Just won't do anything and we'll just get the bare minimum that is provided for effectively no cost by technology however, we are not yet at that point, but We are approaching a situation where there is less demand for unskilled labor in the world.
Scott: Then there is a supply and the only way people have of making a living in this world of you know Getting anything beyond nothing is with their labor.
Scott: That's all someone has is you know, their skills their work.
Scott: and if there is no demand for work, then what are people gonna do?
Scott: To just get food and a shelter?
Scott: if their work is worth nothing?
Scott: Now then we don't yet have a technological solution that lets them live You know at a minimum level for free and they have nothing that anyone wants from them and there's nothing they can do now Even if we skip over that part.
Rym: and you know The kind of longer-term scenario even in the short term.
Rym: Feel bad for the engineers and the highly skilled workers too in these situations because it's coal miner syndrome where I'm a coal miner I work in the coal mine in the coal mining town.
Rym: if the coal mine closes I Have to leave because there is no other coal mine for me to work in and coal mining is my skill The engineer.
Scott: I think a problem today is a lot of people refuse to leave.
Scott: they just sit there.
Rym: But at the same time if you have a family, it's I mean the way America is it is very very difficult if you do not have a lot of money or If you have a family to just pick up and leave.
Rym: it takes a long time.
Rym: It takes a long time to sell a house.
Rym: takes a long time to buy a house.
Rym: if you pull kids out of school That's usually not good for them.
Rym: You know during a year or something.
Rym: It's difficult to put down roots in a new place.
Rym: It's difficult to get a job somewhere else.
Rym: I mean if you lost your job You probably don't have that much money to go flying around all the different cities going to job interviews That aren't even guaranteed.
Rym: new jobs like giving phone interviews Yeah But no company does that with the and not that many nice companies will fly you out for a job interview and also all the places That have jobs like New York.
Rym: You can't afford a house.
Rym: You're gonna have to live way way outside and commute like crazy, and it's not.
Rym: it's a bad situation.
Rym: get some roommates Yeah, but if you have live someplace crappy yeah, but if you have a large family that makes it even more difficult.
Scott: Yeah, well you know you've.
Scott: well There's you know that's a separate issue that we keep discussing of people having families that you know they but this situation I mean these are people who?
Rym: Could afford their family and we're doing well and head plan for the future.
Rym: But they've been slowly put into the situation where there is no easy way out where the planning was for.
Rym: not because Factors they have no control over fucked them that is true.
Scott: However.
Scott: You know there are some factors in which you know for example I You know know how to program computers.
Rym: yes because you were born with a silver spoon.
Rym: To go to one of the most prestigious.
Scott: Let's say right nobody needs computer programmers.
Scott: every more someone writes a program that writes every program That's ever needed, and we don't need computer programmers anymore.
Scott: There are things I can do.
Scott: I have other skills that I can sell that are worth something.
Scott: I you know.
Scott: I could get a different sort of job in some other industry that would be at a similar level.
Rym: However, I would argue that the main reason we have that luxury and the reason we have so many Skit like marketable skills outside of our primary skills is that we grew up in relatively affluent wealthy middle-class to offer middle-class Lifestyles are?
Rym: we didn't have to work that much?
Rym: But if we're in we could skip.
Rym: we didn't have to work for most of our lives And when we did.
Rym: it was trivial work.
Rym: we had a lot of time to pursue varied interests.
Rym: We went to universities which got us a lot of well-rounded skills.
Scott: You're a coal miner right.
Scott: you may have not had an opportunity in your life to go to college and to learn all these things earlier In life, but if you were at a point in which you know you're a coal miner in a town and you coal mine But you're doing well you can afford your family.
Scott: You're doing okay.
Scott: You're responsible right now.
Scott: You could learn new things Right now if you didn't have you know the ambition to you know or or the forethought to say I?
Scott: Could learn something else just in case the coal mine goes under because you you know.
Scott: you know you're in a precarious Position even if the coal mines doing really well.
Scott: You know that if the coal mine goes away You're fucked.
Scott: so but at the same time knowing that as you're saying time while you're good You should do something to make sure that you know you're okay in the future.
Rym: at the same time one If you're raising a family and working full-time you might not have the time to reasonably do that or at least not do it quickly.
Rym: I mean a lot of people probably saw the writing on the wall.
Scott: Hey, this isn't going so well, but you got to do something before the writing is on the wall.
Rym: Yes, but even then by like even the long-term like all right.
Rym: I see problems a decade down the road.
Rym: go to night school Yeah, but if you're also are taking care of the family life is hard.
Rym: Yeah, well see the other problem here is that if everyone affected by these economic troubles had done this then there still wouldn't be Enough jobs forever.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: It only works because most of the people in these situations either can't or don't take advantage of these ideas.
Rym: if everyone did Everyone's right.
Scott: if every coal miner went to night school Then we'd have a million people who learned some valuable skill and thus the supply of that Particular skill would be high and the demand would be less than the supply.
Scott: and you know the people already getting paid to do whatever Those coal miners learned how to do would get paid less.
Rym: Anyway, and the whole thing would yeah, because we should try to wrap this up at least somewhat reasonably quickly I actually have what I think is a really good idea on how to deal with this situation.
Scott: Oh, dude I was
Rym: inspired because you happen to pick a topic that I read a lot about in the last week Because earlier in the week I I found a Wall Street Journal laying on the ground like in continue
Scott: to intentionally make companies inefficient Thus requiring more human labor.
Scott: No, no.
Rym: I'm talking about like what could the government of this country do like right now to make the situation To make the best of the current situation not talking about what could we have done in the past not talking besides
Scott: public works
Rym: But right now like specifically what could we do?
Scott: Hire all the let the car companies go out of business and hire all of them to build the bridges and the roads?
Rym: No, the power lines because actually there is a nice article about.
Rym: Basically the Democratic Party and Barack Obama are kind of taking a gamble in that They're pushing for action to be taken and there he's kind of taking a big role in this already Even though he's not president yet, but he's a senator.
Scott: He can still Senate.
Rym: He's not taking the Senate in role.
Rym: He's taking the president in role That's true, but he can still.
Scott: you know, if he's taking the president in role and you know something You know is required some legislation moving through you can go to the Senate and vote.
Rym: Yes Control the House and Senate so we can't anyway and Bush vetoes it.
Scott: Well, yeah, don't wait.
Scott: No, don't the don't the new senators and House people not go in until the next session or whatever.
Rym: But we already control this business.
Rym: just we control it more anyway.
Rym: One of the ideas and I'm the idea wasn't this but I expanded on this idea.
Rym: Here's what I would do were I the president and I would do it by.
Rym: you know Getting Congress on board and you know Executive orders and all the different ways The president can pull strings and press releases and speeches to get people on board with this.
Rym: But I would one bail out the companies if they agreed to my terms.
Rym: The terms would be yes, you will be bailed out in return.
Rym: we will either get.
Rym: the government will either get a controlling interest in the company or He got.
Rym: the board of directors will be replaced or Added to by government regulators who will basically sit on the company.
Rym: Make sure that you don't waste any of the money we gave you.
Rym: make sure that the end goal which is to make sure jobs are available in these places to prevent the average people from being screwed happen and basically take over the companies halfway as the government and force the companies to do what's in the best interest of the country and Part of that would probably be not paying out these bonuses and all sorts of.
Rym: you know minutia that I don't want to get into now and I can't think of a better way to handle it than that I Would.
Rym: just bailing them out encourages them to do the same bullshit to us in the future.
Rym: Yeah, not bailing them out screws a whole lot of people in a way that I'm not willing to do.
Scott: The problem is right is even if the government took over these, you know Let's say the government took over Ford in that way, right and they they did all.
Scott: let's assume the best possible situation.
Scott: Right did all the right things?
Scott: they you know.
Scott: every single person who's getting paid a lot of money is now getting paid poop and you know We're just making sure everyone still has jobs and we do everything we can to you know, try to make it profitable.
Scott: Maybe right now all the taxpayers own this unprofitable company that slowly loses money for everyone all the time instead of you know, just losing money for this set of shareholders.
Scott: and It's you know, it's we got.
Rym: that's why one way to go about it.
Rym: Instead of having the controlling interest like owning the stock in the company is Having government people on the board who can veto anything stupid the company tries to do.
Rym: basically It's just so.
Rym: the government still doesn't have the liability beyond the bailout But at the same time the government has the control to force the company to act in the best interest of the nation.
Scott: Yeah, but even then when is the government gonna?
Scott: you know, we got to have some anything like that.
Rym: Yes There's a lot of minutia.
Rym: I've thought them all through.
Rym: I don't want to spend 20 minutes.
Scott: Anything like that needs some sort of phasing out deal where you know, we let it go.
Rym: That is very clearly part of the plan.
Rym: I could tell you my specific idea, but yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I'm just.
Scott: I'm more interested in not you know, the particular very specific government right now solution But in sort of the entire world society solution of you know.
Scott: Right now we have an account.
Scott: the world Economy basically says if you provide labor you'll be you get something.
Scott: if you don't provide labor you get nothing.
Scott: But there is less demand for labor than there are people who will provide it and thus they're people who no matter what they do There's no one who wants, you know to feed them.
Scott: Basically, what do we what do we do as that ratio?
Scott: Changes and technology is not yet solved it even though it may in the future just an alternate system of distributing scarce resources.
Rym: Simple done.
Scott: Yeah, what system would that be?
Rym: So anyway things of the day.
Scott: Oh and the things.
Scott: they in the middle bears playing hockey.
Rym: I'm not going to explain to you whether or not this is real.
Rym: I simply want you to observe the spectacle of Bears playing hockey.
Scott: only this could only be in an old Russian video in what I can only assume is a Russian circus.
Scott: You must be All right, so, you know for much of my life, you know being at least Jewish by birth and whatnot.
Rym: You know it as opposed to Jewish by injection.
Scott: Yeah, it has been very apparent that you know Despite there being gourmet chefs and iron chefs that the the greatest chefs in all the world are Jewish and Italian Grandmas, right they can out cook anyone, you know you get.
Scott: you know, fancy guy went to culinary school from France.
Scott: Whatever, you know get someone's grandma up ins and they got nothing right?
Scott: It's it's just well known.
Scott: It's it's a fact.
Scott: That's how it is.
Scott: So I was wondering why aren't the old Jewish and Italian grandmas on the TV cooking shows?
Scott: Why are at these culinary people?
Scott: Why why don't the grandma's open up the restaurants?
Scott: They just cook for the family.
Scott: They never open up a restaurant or anything, you know, they could rake it in.
Scott: who wouldn't want to go, you know.
Scott: It's like this amazing special treat to get like, you know Grandma's food maybe three times a year somewhat something like that.
Scott: If you could just go and buy it whenever you want it all man's it would be amazing.
Scott: And I had a much simpler idea of.
Scott: you know, why doesn't someone just you know?
Scott: Make a YouTube or something of their grandma cooking.
Scott: and You know, I had that idea for many years much like I had the idea for dig for many years.
Scott: Well close to it.
Scott: Everyone had the idea to make slash.
Rym: See you avoided that.
Rym: you would have been the one.
Scott: you would have been the man Everyone in the whole world knew wanted a slash dot where the people where the users voted.
Scott: Yes, but now we see one person did it and everyone else.
Scott: but it's just going.
Rym: fuck I know because now we see what we Have wrought and we despair.
Scott: that is true head is true because dig made me lose faith in all forms of internet democracy, but You know the idea to had just videotaped grandma cooking has been around for a while and no one did it until Just now.
Scott: some guy did it and that's my thing of the day.
Scott: It's a let's see feed me.
Scott: Bubby is the name of the video this.
Scott: Yeah, Bubby is the Hebrew word for grandma.
Scott: so and he's he's got his Yiddish grandma and she's cooking it up.
Scott: and it's a video.
Scott: and Some of the videos are loading a little slowly when I tried to watch them downstairs, but they work.
Scott: So just you know, pause it let it load up and learn how to cook Traditional Jewish grandma food, which is you know, the best food there is.
Scott: so, you know, why watch Food Network?
Rym: I don't know alright, so, uh Martin Luther King jr.
Rym: I'm gonna read the bed because you don't know about this.
Rym: This is I'm curious to see your reaction, but I'll start by reading the FARC headline.
Scott: Well, how I don't know.
Scott: first of all, he wasn't that really rich.
Scott: so how does he have a big estate?
Rym: I'm going to start by reading the FARC headline and I'm going to work from there.
Rym: Hopefully I will elucidate all That can be elucidated.
Rym: illuminate all that can be illuminated.
Rym: all this and more as I'm in an illuminated manuscript Free at last.
Scott: Thank you God almighty.
Rym: We're free at last.
Rym: Licensing and registration fees still apply.
Scott: Okay
Rym: basically The story is that the Martin Luther King estate is a rigidly controlled Copyright trademark machine and if you want to have a picture of Martin Luther King or quote his speeches or do anything Anything at all and they go after people who use up You know all their rights to parody and such too and they do anything they can to force their trademark and copyright rights.
Rym: You need to pay the estate of Martin Luther King jr.
Rym: To use his speeches.
Rym: his likenesses.
Scott: You can't put I have a dream on YouTube without paying money.
Rym: Ah, that is correct You can't.
Scott: what about the federal government?
Scott: shouldn't the federal government have to pay?
Scott: they got Martin Luther King Day Shouldn't have to pay for that holiday.
Scott: Basically, it's infringing that holiday.
Rym: they forced people to pay to license the likeness of Martin Luther King jr.
Rym: and all of his words and anything depicting.
Scott: if it's Martin Luther King Day and I draw a picture of Martin Luther King and put it outside my business saying Isaac Newton Ferris jr.
Rym: King's nephew and head of the nonprofit Is his name really Isaac Newton?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Oh my god Head of the King Center in Atlanta said the estate is entitled to hundreds of thousands of dollars in licensing fees maybe even millions due to Merchandise depicting Martin Luther King standing next to Barack Obama that is being sold on the streets throughout this nation.
Scott: Well, that's that's just not true.
Scott: He's gonna go to court and lose because now they win these all the time.
Scott: Well, you can't treat you.
Scott: It's someone's it's the picture of a person.
Rym: They trademarked Martin Luther King jr.
Scott: You can't trademark what a person looks like especially if they're a stork or famous person.
Scott: They did you can't.
Scott: How did they win in court?
Rym: They just win.
Scott: All right, so I'm Trey, you know, so wait Yes, anyone is allowed to you know, take like photographs in public, right?
Scott: Right, am I right?
Rym: roach realizing the value of his ideas King himself Copyrighted well registered the copyright of several of his speeches during his lifetime after he died.
Scott: Do you can copyright his speech?
Scott: You can yes.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So all mine all of his speeches are copyrighted.
Rym: That's fun not in the public domain.
Scott: Maybe so.
Rym: but well, yes, it's so.
Rym: he's not that old remember.
Rym: basically nothing enters the public Don't ever?
Scott: if sure right the speech itself is not entered the public domain.
Scott: I could not print it in a book right?
Scott: However, he was in public right when he gave speed.
Scott: There are certain speeches he gave in public places where he could be videotaped Publicly and if you appear in public and are videotaped by just someone standing there They own that video even if you're in it and you have no say whatsoever.
Scott: Yes, however That's why you know the news can just go out with video cameras and put things on the news.
Rym: however most of these things or at least a lot of the ones that you see have Ended up being falling under the copyright or in the very least have ended up with this group being paid royalties or other.
Scott: Yes, that's also right.
Scott: It's just if you a picture of Martin Luther King.
Scott: Well, I'm sure there's a picture of him somewhere and that picture itself was taken by a photographer And that photographer owns the rights of that picture and I could just be like no I'm.
Scott: I'm making a likeness of that picture and the photographer is letting me.
Scott: I'm not making a likeness of Martin Luther King.
Rym: I can tell them on whatever I want.
Rym: The legal issues around this are extra complicated But many people have tried to fight against these people and lost over the years.
Scott: Why are they losing?
Scott: This is ridiculous.
Rym: So what what they're doing now?
Rym: quote Ferris says he expects to announce deals in the coming weeks to license some items featuring Images of Martin Luther King jr.
Rym: And Barack Obama that are going to be sold in the King Center and on websites and things alongside recordings of speeches postcards calendars mugs bearing images of King and other licensed merchandise.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I guess they want.
Rym: you know It's so weird that someone Scott the estate even sued CBS over their you their sale of a video documentary on Martin Luther King that happened to include excerpts from the.
Rym: I have a dream speech.
Rym: Well as much as I like Martin Luther King and the appeals court ruled in 99 that the speech was in fact covered not public domain and Eventually CBS settle out of court for a large amount of money.
Scott: what the hell wusses.
Scott: no one fights for anything.
Rym: Well, because the court basically said CBS you can't win this anyway, they It's weird.
Scott: It's like everyone likes Martin Luther King.
Scott: He's totally awesome.
Scott: I guess success.
Scott: I can think of people who don't like the KKK doesn't like him, but everyone else likes it.
Scott: and You know, the thing is it's the Martin Luther King's, you know foundation or trust or whatever these people are.
Scott: It's their job to guess make people like and know Martin Luther King even more.
Scott: But they seem to all they want to do is make people not like Martin Luther King.
Scott: They want to make it, you know, keep them out of the textbooks Keep them out of the schools.
Scott: Keep them out of the t-shirts.
Scott: make it so no one sees them No one hears them and no one likes.
Scott: and if that's what they want Maybe we should just stop talking about Martin Luther King.
Scott: Let's not put his picture anywhere.
Scott: Let's not talk about him Let's not put up his videos or anything.
Scott: Let's just pretend like you did because that seems to be what they want right just like the record companies, right?
Scott: Oh, you know, sure.
Scott: We want our job is to make everyone like this music.
Scott: We're gonna do that by making sure nobody hears it.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: If that's what you want fine No one will listen to your music and we won't like it anymore.
Rym: But I'm surprised you didn't know about the long-term issues with the fact that the can never heard of this before ever.
Rym: the King Estate is one of the most.
Scott: very surprised that they haven't won in court.
Rym: The King Estate is one of the most aggressive pursuers of copyright actions in America outside of the RIAA.
Scott: See this comes back to what you know, Lawrence Lessig and Cory Doctorow and all those people always say about copyright.
Scott: is that this you know, this copyright.
Scott: and then there's this culture.
Scott: and These people are using copyright not to you know, get the temporary monopoly to incentivize creative endeavors but to actually Strangle culture and to remove things from the culture.
Scott: The record companies are removing their music from the culture.
Scott: the you know The King Estate is trying to remove Martin Luther King from the culture.
Scott: I know that's not probably their goal in their mind, but by aggressively You know trying to enforce these copyrights and trademarks and things.
Scott: That is the result of what will happen if they get their way on those issues is Martin Luther King will be More removed from the culture than he is now where he is very much a part of the culture.
Scott: Now one thing I say the best solution is to just let the people dig their own graves.
Rym: the the article that slash shot the specific article that slash shot links to is Pretty bad and actually has some inaccuracies in it.
Rym: So I wouldn't go by that but this is something that's bothered me for as long as I've known about it.
Rym: But as Scott said, I think the relevant quote here is to promote the progress of science and useful arts By securing for a limited time to authors and inventors the exclusive right to the respective writings and discoveries.
Scott: Yep, I mean this is remote.
Rym: the progress of science and useful arts Yeah, that is the.
Rym: that is the only reason we have copyright law according to the Constitution.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: It's there.
Scott: Well, that's it's actually enumerating the powers of Congress.
Scott: So it's actually Congress has the power to promote the you know, useful arts, etc.
Rym: It's although Congress has the power to grant inventors and artists exclusive rights in order to promote the progress.
Scott: Yes by making laws and yes the whole right.
Scott: Anyway, the thing is right.
Rym: I would argue that any law that doesn't clearly show to promote the progress of science.
Rym: Do you is unconstitutional?
Scott: Yeah, well, that's the thing.
Scott: Do you remember the Grokster case?
Scott: Yes that we lost.
Scott: yeah in the Grokster case, right or was I forget what?
Scott: or was it that Sonny Bono?
Scott: but there?
Scott: I forget exactly.
Rym: They're like eight cases Sonny Bono, but basically they went to the suppose the one where you lost and they're right.
Rym: Yes, you can.
Scott: you can extend it the Sonny Bono.
Rym: You can't extend it anymore after this.
Scott: Well what that wasn't it easy That was the next one.
Scott: that wasn't it either.
Scott: basically what it was.
Rym: timeline of this shit.
Scott: Listen that the Sonny Bono Copyright Act extended copyright from I guess What was it 75 years to 99 years something like that, right?
Scott: And they went to challenge it in the Supreme Court.
Scott: and the Supreme Court says, you know Well, you know the the law says limited right that the Constitution says limited times.
Scott: So when they argued at the Supreme Court, they said look because they keep extending copyright every time it's about to expire.
Scott: It's effectively Unlimited and even though there's this particular law has a limit of 99. by keep making these extensions It's effectively unlimited and therefore unconstitutional.
Scott: That's the argument they made us.
Rym: But I remember this that the Supreme Court basically said that if they continue to do it No No what the kind?
Scott: what they said is look they extended to 99 and they had a reason to extend it to 99 because of all The recent things that have been going on on the internet and whatnot, right?
Scott: There was a reason for this extension.
Scott: We don't see, you know, some sort of trend of infinite, you know extension.
Scott: That's exactly what I was saying No, no, they didn't say don't extend it anymore.
Scott: Well, they said was if there becomes a trend of extending it with the purposes of making it infinite Yeah, they said, you know if there is a further extension if there's no reason for the further extensions and whatnot then maybe Maybe then they won't be allowed.
Scott: but you know, they didn't rule out any further extensions either, right?
Scott: They said if there is more extensions without reason then maybe this argument would work.
Scott: the problem is they no one has tried to make the argument based on the first part, which is Promotion of the useful arts and sciences.
Scott: Are you?
Scott: no one is not that I've seen not in the Supreme Court anyway Not in a big case that was all over the internet geek news.
Rym: But maybe in the past, I mean copyright has been extended many many many times and that's true.
Scott: And I think I remember I'm not sure about this But I think I remember someone saying, you know, one of those big lawyers maybe Lessig or someone else Saying after that case we should have argued the useful arts and sciences instead of arguing, you know the limited You know time and you know, and I just don't know, you know I think if we made that argument is presented well that we would totally win.
Scott: like look we have a situation where software patents are Actually doing the opposite or promoting useful.
Rym: Here's why it wouldn't work.
Rym: because the argument against that is that they are in fact promoting and they have a Equally sounding valid argument and no one on the Supreme Court understands the issue.
Rym: No, no one Involved.
Rym: I would say that no one involved in the judiciary Understands what the issue is with software patents.
Rym: No, I would argue that not a single judge in the world actually Understands why we don't like software patents.
Scott: No, but if you went to zoom in court explain, you know, they're not.
Scott: you know, some of the judges are not good But they're not stupid people.
Scott: They if you explained it to them.
Scott: They're smarter than Ted Stevens.
Scott: They could maybe figure it out and some of them would probably get to be in your favor.
Rym: But then again if remember they if they don't understand the issue Then someone on the opposite side will give an equally valid sounding argument against you.
Scott: Yeah, it's true but I think that you know you could.
Scott: it's a much better chance of Winning an argument about.
Scott: is this promoting the useful arts and sciences then winning the argument?
Scott: Is this limiting and I think clearly.
Scott: here we have a situation where Martin Luther King that is estates Aggressive, you know enforcement of their copyrights is actually not doing the opposite of promoting useful arts and sciences.
Scott: It is removing Martin Luther King a very important and beloved person from the popular culture.
Scott: It is preventing people from being creative and using his likeness to create new arts and sciences.
Scott: It's actually causing an overall decrease in The promotion of useful arts and sciences and you could demonstrate that you know just by showing look There've been more, you know, all these things pulled off a YouTube were useful arts and now they're gone because of this thing.
Scott: yet Them themselves are not, you know doing an equal.
Scott: so in some, you know This is demoting useful arts and sciences and therefore no good.
Scott: No one's made that argument as far as I know not a lawyer.
Rym: I'm kind of hungry Before we wrap this up.
Rym: I do want to point out and we're gonna talk more about this.
Rym: We're gonna make a little audio bit or something about it whenever we get a chance but there'll be a link in this post to a post in our forum, but The long story short is that a very good friend of ours a member of the front row crew is now a teacher.
Rym: The school does not have enough books in their library for like kindergarten through third graders.
Scott: Do we have any kindergarten through third grade books?
Rym: So what we are asking what we are putting out to you if anyone is interested in helping these kids out in this school Where they're soliciting donations for chapter, but earlier I'll read a quote.
Rym: We need books that are appropriate for grades K through 3 early readers stuff picture books graphic novels like owly for instance Easy chapter books DVDs CDs audiobooks, etc.
Rym: Any books that speak to about minorities and other cultures are a big plus since we want the library's contest because versus for students population Blah-blah-blah-blah-blah.
Rym: if you're interested at all and helping these kids There's an address linked to in the forum.
Rym: You can send these books.
Rym: They will be much much appreciated.
Scott: Man that's always so weird Just like that like schools today like don't have libraries and I was a kid.
Scott: my elementary school Had a big-ass library middle school big-ass library high school double big-ass library and there were two town libraries.
Scott: He had so many fucking libraries.
Scott: every freaking school, you know and sure the elementary school had older books and the middle school had a little bit newer and the high school had newer and Then school had a gigantic library that I don't think any students ever used.
Rym: we had a card catalog.
Scott: Well, we had card catalogs in every library, you know.
Scott: That was only slowly replaced with computers.
Scott: now dial in dial in directly my modem.
Scott: I'd call the library's modem on the phone and search the library to see what books are there.
Rym: in middle school we had a multimedia server that had 20 CD drives in it and You could access multimedia stuff anywhere in the school from that one server.
Rym: Except more than two people used it at once it totally slowed down and stopped working.
Scott: But yeah.
Rym: But actually, you know, I'll read the whole thing.
Rym: As some of you know I recently started teaching kindergarten third grade art at a charter school in the Albany New York area.
Rym: The school is an entity as an entity several years old and moved into its brand new building in August.
Rym: The upside is that the facility is amazing and the students and teachers love it.
Rym: I even have an LCD projector that is mounted on my ceiling so that I can show images from the computer via plugs in the On my desk.
Scott: RIT styling.
Rym: Yeah, you know, we were really spoiled going to RIT.
Scott: Yeah, the hell is at RIT, right when you're just RIT student and RIT is the only place you ever, you know Gone to college right you go.
Scott: Oh man RIT.
Scott: It's all bricks.
Scott: It's ugly.
Scott: It sucks, right?
Rym: Every single classroom had a gigantic perfect projector.
Rym: We had Elmo's and like all the really oh my god Like the facilities of like all this technology everywhere.
Scott: and it's like not until you go to like a state school Do you realize?
Scott: wow, you don't have anything.
Scott: it's like you have one projector for the college.
Rym: I would at IBM.
Rym: I remember my first day on the job at IBM and I went to this big meeting.
Rym: It was like yeah come to this meeting.
Rym: It's like the monthly blah blah blah meeting and it's important but you can kind of get a feel for all the stuff we're working on.
Rym: and they had a Transparency projector and that was it.
Scott: RIT didn't have any of those.
Rym: I know we had Elmo's.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh my god We're almost.
Scott: I guess some teach I guess like maybe one or two teachers had the transparency but not you know.
Rym: You know, it might be worth it to buy an Elmo because think about the things we could do at panels with an Elmo.
Scott: It's all you.
Rym: I'll see how much money they are Anyway, and it's skip skip skip which has been used in projects regarding owly Dragons and textures on them and Kiki's delivery service Mm-hmm.
Rym: the downsides that when they left the old building that they shared with another's charter school with whom they were affiliated They left the library behind.
Scott: So then why didn't they bring the library?
Rym: because the other school it was the other schools library.
Rym: they couldn't just take it.
Scott: Oh, I get it.
Rym: So I'm gonna say this While it would be funny to send them a road sick of doji Do not send them a road sick of dough.
Scott: Why don't they just you know sort of like save up a you know, a bunch of money and solicit donations and then just buy You know the penguin classics collection.
Rym: That's a good idea.
Scott: It's just instant library.
Scott: Of course elementary school kids couldn't read any of those hard real books, but you know, all right Instant library say if you have Donations send them here.
Rym: if you want to do a separate donation drive to buy the penguin books collection for some other school in The future that's a really good idea and we'll do that later.
Rym: But for now send books for kindergarten through third graders that do not involve over fiends to the address linked to in the forum.
Rym: I Swear to God.
Rym: if any of you send them a road sick of doji, I'm gonna cry.
Scott: Realize you send them a road sick of doji They're just not gonna give it to the school and we're basically getting free copies of a road sick of doji for us.
Scott: Yes, in fact, is there a neurosica?
Scott: doji manga?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Oh, oh, by the way, I've read it.
Scott: the cheapest Elmo's $692.
Rym: that's less than I expected.
Scott: That's that's the cheapest one.
Scott: that basically does like jack and shit.
Scott: It's a camera on a stick.
Rym: Yeah, but how?
Rym: how far have Elmo's come?
Rym: Alright, he was a long time ago.
Scott: It's basically this is the cheapest one is a camera on a stick and then a surface to put your stuff on.
Scott: the fancy Elmo's Right the like are very very expensive like $3,000, but they have many many fancy features.
Rym: That's still not that bad.
Scott: Alright, if you want to pay the $3,000, it's all you.
Rym: I'm looking to it I can.
Scott: the fancy one is a built-in monitor.
Rym: I feel like an Elmo at a gaming con at some sort of like burning wheel panel would be boss Maybe.
Scott: yeah, they're definitely good for gaming things.
Rym: Alright, you know, they'd be really good If I was running a game like show someone how to play a board game.
Scott: we could just put the board game on the Elmo and then Of course, you know, we could just put a webcam on a stick for like 40 bucks Yeah, and then no reason to buy the Elmo.
Rym: actually we should.
Rym: we need to.
Rym: we need some sort of ceiling mounted camera for filming port Games.
Scott: Well, you just take a camera put it on a stick aim it straight down Put a white surface under it put the thing on there and then connect it to directly to a computer and you get.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row.
Scott: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.