Rym: It's Monday, December 7th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about putting your technology on life support how to ring the most out of it.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So it's uh, it is finally too cold for me to just go running outside Like I usually do I really.
Rym: I push it later into the season, but it's just too cold.
Rym: I guess I could put on a bunch of like spandex and gear and go out there and a hat but That's a pain.
Rym: So I've moved to ride my bike to nowhere like you've been biking to nowhere.
Scott: Yeah, bike to nowhere.
Scott: You should do it.
Scott: if you I guess your bike to nowhere isn't gonna be Swift compatible.
Scott: We can't bike to nowhere together.
Rym: Oh hell no plus the kind of biking I'm doing is Mostly either on it for an hour doing intervals the whole hour or like spin class type stuff.
Rym: So I'm watching Netflix shows.
Scott: It does that.
Rym: Yeah, but that's all I do Hmm.
Rym: So what I'm doing is I'm watching like.
Rym: I'm watching shows that I'm interested in but not super interested in.
Scott: But aren't there shows you're super interested in that?
Rym: you haven't watched shows I'm super interested in.
Rym: I'll watch like.
Rym: I'll sit down like with dinner or like with a drink and watch is a dedicated event.
Rym: But this is like I'll watch a whole episode of the old unsolved mysteries while I'm biking.
Rym: So I started watching the Queen's Gambit and it's pretty good and it portrays chess very accurately Which I'm very happy about.
Rym: I can't I am.
Scott: it's hard to portray chess Inaccurately, right?
Rym: Yeah, this is not too much to it but I guess I just noticed a trend in the last like five or five fish years where When there's a show on like one of these streaming services Like what are those shows that's made in the modern pipeline?
Rym: Like not a broadcast TV show and it portrays like games of any kind For whatever's changed.
Rym: They're definitely getting someone who knows at least one thing about the game That's gonna appear to make sure that they don't portray it completely stupidly.
Rym: and I've just noticed that generally in media Which is a big change from like 10 or 15 years ago We're like if a video game appeared in a show, it would always be like super fake II.
Scott: Don't know if people remember this but it was a big deal.
Scott: for a very short amount of time there was a TV show that For some reason decided to have the characters on the TV show Playing that runner there must have been some nerd on the cast of the show or the staff or some of the production staff Something like that that there was a scene in which the the people on the show are playing netrunner.
Scott: I don't think fantasy flight had anything to do with it because There were some Netrunner friends I had in New York who are basically like went there Right to be extras in the background playing netrunner at the netrunner tournament and also to consult them So that the dialogue of the very brief scene Was not, you know way off the mark.
Scott: so you can probably on YouTube search I forget which TV show it was.
Scott: it was some live-action TV show and you can hear some TV actors saying netrunner words playing netrunner cards And maybe see some people I know in like one second of footage in the background or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yep
Rym: I just remember back to like the 90s the 2000s like a video game would be in a show and you'd see like and like an Adam Sandler or someone just like Randomly mashing the shit out of a controller and they'd show a fake video game on the screen.
Rym: for like a second Times have changed.
Rym: So it's Monday.
Rym: It's tech news day.
Rym: We can't quite do a tech news round up.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Here it is.
Scott: It's on.
Scott: It's on YouTube.
Scott: It's it's the.
Scott: the title of the video is billions netrunner Taylor and Oscar Langster at S3e5.
Scott: so I don't know I found it.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, so whatever that that's it.
Scott: That's the scene.
Scott: It's one minute and 35 seconds long.
Rym: Alright, so some Monday you got any news.
Scott: Yeah, so let's start with this tiny news, right?
Scott: We all know apples m1 chip.
Scott: We've talked about it to death.
Scott: the rumor You know seems like a true rumor.
Scott: It's not an outrageous rumor.
Scott: It's more like a thing.
Scott: That would be common sense.
Scott: it's like yeah, I figured that out for myself, but now people are Officially rumor ring it.
Scott: Yeah They're they're rumor ring a specific more specific detail.
Rym: There's a difference between yeah, that makes sense versus I heard specifically they're doing it Exactly.
Scott: So the specific thing that people are saying is that obviously they put the m1 into the MacBook Pro and Into the Mac mini.
Scott: well that leaves your iMac and your Mac Pro, right?
Scott: And maybe oh and they also put it in the MacBook Air, right?
Scott: So at least the iMac and the Mac Pro still running x86, you know They're gonna get ARM chips next round, right?
Scott: It's like obvious.
Scott: But the rumor the specific rumor is that probably the Mac Pro is gonna have some ARM chip with possibly 32 cores High performance ones in it.
Scott: That is going to.
Scott: if true and if the single core performance on that is quite strong I think you could finally cuz.
Scott: up until now the Mac Pro has always been a bad investment.
Scott: money wise right cost a fortune.
Rym: and Even though it is quite strong and as it is it are stronger than the market when it comes out.
Scott: Not all aspects are some of them But if you look at it when it comes out like the day it comes out if you put it right up against Build your own Intel PC at home Right, it not only is like not too far ahead of that.
Scott: performance wise if it's ahead at all And it's way ahead of it.
Scott: price wise it's like oh I could buy two computers of GT 3080s assuming I could get one instead of buying one Mac Pro.
Rym: Yeah, 3080 MSRP not that expensive for how powerful it is, right exactly?
Scott: So but if that chip has 32 high performance cores in it That may.
Scott: that's taking like enterprise hardware and putting it in consumer tech, right?
Scott: There are existing like arm server CPUs you can get like I forget what they're called There's like the end something or whatever.
Scott: that are really ridiculous CPUs that you're never going to buy because there's nothing you could run on them at home.
Rym: that makes sense for you Yeah, and usually those kinds of chips have a way lower clock speed because they're doing a very different kind of task.
Scott: yeah, but the point is if You could get that kind of like, you know enterprise power onto your desk then the five to $10,000 price range of the Mac Pro with that chip in it begins to make sense.
Rym: Yeah, anyone who actually needs Ludicrous performance and at that point like the only thing we're really lacking here is the ability to put our real GPU in one Of these m1s, right and at that point you also Begin to stop caring about the fact.
Scott: the major downside of the Mac is that it does not run all software ever created.
Scott: Yeah, right which Windows does.
Scott: but if Apple can push performance hard enough, right?
Scott: We're already seeing that they can run old x86 OS X apps with their Rosetta Sometimes, you know faster or almost as fast as they did on x86.
Scott: Yeah, you could just emulate a whole goddamn Windows PC.
Scott: Just right and not even give a shit call me.
Rym: when like a premier like CP a hundred percent CPU No GPU possible effect renders faster on one of these m1s Then I could see you I had.
Scott: I can see a future years from now where even the windows person It's like well all these pcs suck ass.
Scott: I'm gonna buy the Mac because it's the most powerful PC on earth.
Scott: Yeah, and then I'm in a virtual machine.
Scott: I'll put Windows 10 and it's gonna be faster than any Windows 10 PC you've ever had.
Scott: in a virtual machine You can just play counter-strike in it you.
Scott: it's faster than counter-strike on the windows.
Scott: It's natively and that's the end of it right and you run all your software ever.
Rym: I'm still just very cautious here because these benchmarks are synthetic.
Scott: All benchmarks isn't?
Scott: they are.
Rym: But for example, what kind of like stutter latency is there in the emulation layer?
Rym: What about like very CPU intensive that require a high like?
Scott: there's a lot of unknowns around gaming in particular Yes, but what we're seeing is that in the arm?
Scott: Architecture world where it's especially not, you know mobile CPUs and also the server CP.
Rym: You know the vast majority of computing usage like gaming is kind of an edge niche case.
Scott: We are seeing big Performance gains right like 20 30 percent, you know generation on generation right like they're moving Whereas x86 is not moving, you know AMD's making some gains.
Scott: Intel dropped the ball a few years ago.
Scott: Yeah But it's like x86 is not, you know getting the rock up the hill.
Rym: Yep It's tricky though because that said there was an era.
Rym: now the difference was no one was moving off of x86.
Rym: But remember back when there were alpha chips You could run Windows NT at like 500 megahertz and a normal like x86 chip could only run like hundred.
Scott: Oh the power PC like chips from yeah.
Rym: Yeah all those eras.
Rym: There was also the era where Intel just like today hit this long plateau.
Rym: the Pentium 3 Pentium 4 era together were not impressive to anyone But at that time the they were surpassed Momentarily by changes in technology.
Rym: But then they basically whatever they were up to either it was skunkworks R&D or some product managers said oh shit I guess we got to start like advancing again.
Rym: They suddenly just blew everyone out of the water again out of no.
Scott: Yeah, there was you know, they're very various reasons for that.
Scott: But yes, it's true there could all there's never ever in any technology area.
Scott: Right.
Scott: think that any one company or platform is like the winner forever We're talking about it could become the winner because it's currently not the winner.
Rym: x86 lasted a long time.
Rym: what we don't know now is if x86 Can continue to scale on hardware or if the paradigm shift to a different instruction set is the only way?
Rym: To take advantage of modern material science.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, so it's like, you know in Apple right came they died They came back.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like it happens, right?
Scott: It's like, you know various companies, you know They.
Scott: they look like they're the biggest deal in the world and then they go away.
Rym: But that's what I wanted to come back.
Scott: and sometimes they don't.
Scott: Intel's Google can die.
Scott: Facebook can die.
Scott: Everyone can die.
Rym: I mean my face died.
Rym: Yeah, but Intel has been weirdly quiet in this whole scene with Intel chips not getting materially.
Rym: You need to read.
Scott: you need to read about the organizational internal difficulties that Intel has had Disaster going on for a while.
Rym: Part of the reason why I have is that I've had recruiters come after me from Intel.
Scott: Yeah, you know don't work there.
Rym: No Recruiters anyway, but it was interesting.
Rym: recruiters were from Intel.
Rym: it's not good, but the question I have is either Intel has R&D that is not public Or Intel does not have R&D that is not public in regard to addressing this competitor in their space and I don't know which of those is true.
Rym: and It's gonna be a material because I gotta buy to build an HD PC Probably before I can get an m1 that'll run Windows and let me put an Nvidia GPU in it.
Scott: I say this every time but watch out the Nvidia CPU is coming.
Scott: Yeah, well would not be surprised if the all Nvidia computer comes.
Scott: I'm like half betting on it.
Rym: for someone like me The all Nvidia computer is almost a dream in the same way that the win app OS was a dream in ancient times.
Rym: Computers unstable run win app.
Scott: It'll actually stabilize it All right, so I thought that'd be a one-minute news, but we've recorded for 13 minutes a lot to say about it.
Rym: You want to talk about your pornhub thing?
Rym: Oh Yeah, so actually pretty big deal.
Scott: Well, so this is old news right?
Scott: is that?
Scott: you know, if you're in the porn business Specifically, right?
Scott: Obviously if you're in the drug business you have even it's even harder, but yeah Opioids apparently, but if you are selling sex Right, whether it is a you're doing it morally and correctly and legally or not.
Scott: It's very hard to collect money right.
Scott: American Express, right will not let you Use them like.
Scott: they will not let you accept American Express cards if you're running like, you know Even a legitimate perfectly legal, you know sex business.
Rym: now This is porn website like.
Rym: sex work should not be criminalized like this whole Exactly.
Rym: This whole space has a lot of buried leads and assumptions that shouldn't necessarily be assumptions Exactly.
Scott: We I support the decriminalization of sex work.
Scott: This is what and I this is basically what sex workers have said that I see on and follow on the internet, right?
Scott: They want it to be decriminalized not legalized.
Scott: Right, which is different right from being decriminalized.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The shortest version of the argument I've seen is that Legalizing it is a danger now primarily because of capitalism and that people will be forced into it if it is a legal profession.
Rym: But if it anyway if it's decriminalized but not legalized then people can do it safely.
Rym: But a welfare agency couldn't say well you didn't take that porn job.
Rym: So we're not gonna pay you.
Scott: Yep regardless the the payment industry is the primary barrier for Legitimate Sex workers, especially on the internet.
Scott: They need to collect money somehow.
Scott: They need a payment processor to get money from.
Scott: To consenting adults happen to be using the internet.
Scott: they want to do this, you know, I got no problem with it, right?
Scott: So it's hard because if you set up like PayPal, it's like PayPal will just be like no Yeah, it's like we're gonna can't count your patreon patreon.
Rym: a huge percentage of patreon money is porny stuff.
Rym: But that's part of why patreon doesn't make it easy to find that porny stuff through their own tools to avoid problems.
Scott: This isn't.
Scott: this is less of a problem for major major porn sites Like say pornhub probably the biggest porn site that I know of right, you know, it's the one everyone knows.
Scott: Yeah So pornhub you could use, you know visa MasterCard on pornhub to buy porns, right?
Scott: until now Or did they threaten to cut them off?
Scott: They did cut them off but basically there were investigations allegations perhaps a lot of truth to You know the that pornhub, you know, they let you just upload porn to pornhub, which I think was a mistake.
Rym: Yeah, I mean they've take every problem YouTube has and multiply it by porn.
Rym: That is a problem for you as a business.
Scott: That's the way a lot of porn sites are operating these days.
Scott: is they just let everyone upload porn and then they take down the stuff?
Scott: That is you know, not supposed to be up there like, you know the child porn Sensual pornography, which is the heart of this article.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Scott: So obviously pornhub not doing a perfect job of removing that stuff from its own service.
Scott: So that's why they're getting cut off right.
Scott: so MX and not MX.
Scott: MX isn't okay with any of it.
Scott: They don't do they don't they won't even.
Scott: but on MasterCard and visa We're like, hey, you know, we will let you accept, you know, take money for porn as a legal law-abiding business.
Scott: But it seems you got some child porn and perhaps revenge porns and other porns.
Scott: You shouldn't be having on your website.
Scott: so we're gonna cut you off and you can't make money.
Scott: and that not only you know that even if that correctly harms People who are uploading that shit that shouldn't.
Scott: you know, that's no good right that those people some of them She didn't be in jail some of those people, you know or punished by some System that is, you know a fair justice system or whatever that some brought to some justice.
Scott: somehow those bad people The perfectly good porn stars that are consensual adults just sex working as they should be I get hosed by this right there like this huge industry, right?
Scott: It's like a few bad people, you know uploading some child porns, right?
Scott: It's even worse than that because Everyone else doing it normally gets ruined.
Rym: is that like?
Rym: porno's argument here is that there are the Visa and MasterCard are applying a double standard to them because they primarily work in the space of pornography.
Rym: but non pornographic sites like Facebook and Instagram have Way more illegal pornography on them than Pornhub does Pornhub?
Rym: that is not doing a great job and should not be letting people Upload the way that they do like that is a. that is a dangerous and risky business model.
Rym: But even Pornhub is doing a way better job than like Facebook is.
Rym: Yep, why isn't Facebook cut off?
Scott: Because they're not a. there's a social stigma like the whole thing against porn, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, sometimes the bad kid in class is the bad kid in class.
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: I remember there was um, remember a pup named Scooby Doo.
Scott: It was always red herring the.
Scott: yeah Right, and they'd be like they'd always accuse him.
Scott: every single episode was never him.
Scott: It was an adult in a costume every time.
Rym: but sometimes it's like gog manga vre where the bad kid is the bad kid Who did the bad thing.
Scott: so they're always looking at you know?
Scott: It's like he was a bully and he was a jerk and no one liked him.
Scott: and you know You don't want to be his friend, but it's like.
Scott: was he actually committing all those crimes?
Scott: It's like he didn't get one.
Rym: I think in one episode he did Did not commit this one crime that we were actively engaged in.
Scott: Right, it is.
Scott: I mean it is.
Scott: what about ISM to say well other people are doing it too, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well, you're it's like yeah.
Scott: Well, if you did this you should be punished for it, right?
Rym: You should face the consequences, but the fact that visa MasterCard would never ever Cut Facebook off is a problem.
Scott: No, cuz they make so much money.
Rym: Facebook the kovat the kovat denial stuff the election stuff.
Rym: Facebook arguably has caused more harm to American society Than a thousand porn hubs combined yet.
Rym: Facebook is totally safe here and Facebook has more illegal pornography than pornhub does.
Rym: That's the plan.
Scott: I think that you know somebody.
Scott: I'd really like to see somebody set up.
Scott: I think they're.
Scott: they do exist, but they're not from what I'm.
Rym: That's like.
Rym: we'll let it all go.
Scott: yes, yeah, it's like.
Scott: people have done this.
Scott: there are payment processors that do this But some of them are a little shady not you know, I'd love to see someone set up a major awesome Trustworthy payment processor that will do this.
Scott: the problem is Suddenly now as that payment processor you're put in the place of all right, you're gonna police everyone fairly payment processor Or are you going to police any shit except around money laundering and things?
Scott: because that's the thing is if you are If you aren't policing anything, then I don't want to run that business.
Scott: I don't want to send money be responsible sending money to like Cloudflare Cloudflare For like.
Rym: there's that whole debate of should they host Nazis like.
Rym: no fuck you don't host Nazis Nazis, right?
Scott: That's right.
Rym: There's a side line.
Scott: now you've got a. you're on the hook.
Rym: there's a side story.
Rym: I don't even dig up a link but parlor the place where shitty people go to have their only shitty people social network.
Rym: Apparently the problem they're having is that because they're so aggressively free speech, and there's no like blocking tools.
Rym: It's filled with nothing but ads for pornography.
Scott: now That makes sense.
Rym: yep that that it is, but it's not just because the spam is not blocked because of free speech.
Rym: it's actually worse than that.
Rym: the Companies are advertising to the kinds of people that they know will use that service.
Rym: Mm-hmm right-wing not job shit bags basically.
Rym: so there's a whole ecosystem of like Awful pornography spam aimed at awful people who use parlor destroying the platform.
Scott: Why don't we go there and post some spam?
Scott: I?
Rym: Do not want to engage with parlor.
Rym: Nice heuristic in your life.
Rym: if someone you know uses gab or parlor as a shelter social network You should probably never speak to them again.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Scott: So you could also?
Scott: Scam them out of their money.
Rym: You probably could.
Rym: there might feel like if I was gonna make a pyramid scheme that it parlor is Exactly where I would sell it gonna form a cult.
Rym: that is the first place I buy ads.
Scott: Okay, bye.
Scott: I'd start your call by buying it.
Rym: I mean I feel like that's how you do it.
Rym: That's how Scientology got their start I guess.
Rym: so uh in some other really really unfortunate and sad news the our SIBO observatory if you weren't paying attention to this is Gone.
Rym: it collapsed.
Rym: It's dead.
Rym: We lost it.
Rym: Thank you America for our money fixing that.
Scott: we spent our money armoring police instead.
Rym: Yep, basically our SIBO was an incredibly good like I'm not gonna explain everything that this radio telescope Did.
Rym: this was one of the more important?
Rym: Scientific apparati that humans have ever created in our entire history.
Rym: It's in Puerto Rico.
Rym: It is a gigantic radio telescope.
Rym: I'm not gonna explain our radio tele telescopes work because that is a huge topic.
Scott: I do know how we now have other ones right do but that doesn't mean you know We don't have that many and each one gets used a lot and is super important.
Rym: Yeah, let's be clear here our SIBO was not obsolete.
Rym: RS SIBO's budget was cut to the point that they couldn't do enough basic maintenance.
Rym: It started to run into trouble and it got to the point to where it didn't make sense to continue To maintain it with the budgets that they had.
Rym: considering all the competing priorities mm-hmm and it thought there was a plan to decommission it and try to save whatever technology we could out of it.
Rym: and The lack of maintenance was so severe that it actually just collapsed on its own before they could even Salvage components out of it.
Rym: There's a Sad video of this happening.
Scott: In fact, they knew that it was going to mess up right?
Scott: It wasn't like it was sabotaged.
Scott: They would have they inspected it and we're like, yeah, this thing's gonna fall down any day.
Scott: Now these cables are all messed up is this is not gonna work out.
Scott: It's going down and then sure enough a few days later.
Scott: It went down.
Scott: That's how smart they were.
Scott: I mean people who work at a radio telescope are probably pretty smart at least at some things right at least about radio telescopes.
Scott: So they knew it was it was done for.
Scott: but what could they do about it, right?
Scott: They didn't have the money to fix it.
Scott: It was you know to fix up.
Scott: It's it's huge and heavy and Fancy and unique, you know fixing it is a huge endeavor that requires a lot of money.
Scott: if you don't have the money It's like well your hands are tied.
Scott: There's nothing you can do.
Scott: You just gotta they.
Scott: they abandon it basically so that no one would be around in case it fell.
Scott: and so no one was hurt.
Scott: And it fell when it fell beyond.
Rym: now a lot of nerds like to argue that oh We got a fun NASA to go into space with humans.
Rym: and like they like they have these very specific things They want to fund.
Rym: but stuff like this is probably way more important to scientific discovery and understanding space than the flashy things that nerds tend to gravitate to.
Scott: I Mean my I always I sort of say that but I just say hey look fund nerdy things Right - after you funded all the more important things but nerdy things deserve quite a bit of funding.
Scott: nor so than guns.
Scott: do at least and Fund them sufficiently.
Scott: Yeah, the boring and boring Right, we have too many right on the right and the left or every politician, right?
Scott: They're all trying to micromanage right saying, you know, even JFK was micromanaging when he said NASA go to the moon.
Rym: Yeah, you probably should not have tried to go to the moon at the time that we did.
Scott: In fact is that he's doing it because of the Cold War and because if you know non, you know other reasons, right?
Scott: You know my policy would be you know give huge budget to science and arts and education and you know everything and then The people who run those things will decide on the budget.
Scott: I'm just deciding I have decided only that science is super important and I will let scientists Decide the rest.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Rym: There's a thing.
Scott: not try to direct them and say no no boring telescopes rockets rockets are excited.
Scott: It's just a thing.
Rym: that's bothered me more and more as I've started to notice it more and more but there's a lot of nerds and geeks out there who will almost performatively Express their like love of science, but in practice, they don't give a shit about science They care about like Elon Musk specifically for some reason,
Scott: right?
Scott: They care about things that have the Science aesthetic.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Science is cool is the best way to like a cool.
Scott: They like a cool rocket.
Scott: They don't like actual science.
Scott: What's actual science, right?
Rym: statistics and Boring shit, you know doing?
Scott: yeah, it's like they don't actual science.
Scott: They don't like that's hard work Yep, they just like the aesthetic of science.
Scott: and you know.
Scott: and even when it comes to believing in science, okay They don't believe in like superstitious Nonsense right, but they'll probably believe in you know, something like, you know sounding better When the science doesn't support that
Rym: or a hyperloop they're really into hyperloop when we already have trains that are better than that Dude, like come on
Scott: Bullet train.
Scott: Let's make it happen.
Rym: So a news that happened today, so I haven't fully like this.
Rym: I've noticed something this year.
Rym: There's been a lot more news that happens like the day we're doing a show that we haven't had a chance to read up on.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: for tech We all the Apple days happened like, you know the day after we did a show because they're all on Tuesdays.
Rym: But uber there was this thread a long time ago about.
Rym: uber is exploiting workers For his business model like we know they've been doing that since day one.
Rym: They're devil cars But their long-term play was to also invest in self-driving cars to eventually not even have to exploit workers and just fuck Everybody over like that was their plan.
Scott: That way, you know on the one hand that's Bad because it puts the drivers out of work in a society without socialism, but it's good.
Scott: It's good because it means well, you're not being exploited.
Scott: you can you know, if we had socialism You could just stay at home and do nothing.
Rym: What a waste of a human mind to force them to drive a truck around the country further for their entire youth.
Scott: like yep Driver is the number one occupation.
Scott: just driver in the United States the number one job driver of things Whatever it is that includes truck drivers cab drivers, you know everything.
Scott: now.
Rym: the listener Apparently really like the statistics TDM and failure.
Rym: That is what science is.
Scott: That's it is the sciences.
Rym: but so that's what we all kind of assumed uber was doing and lyft sort of made a name for itself as They're still exploiting.
Scott: But no, they're the same they're not better.
Rym: but they sold the image of we're not going to do self-driving cars.
Rym: Uber is gonna automate.
Scott: you were just selling the image of we're less evil.
Rym: Oh, no there.
Rym: Yeah, they sold it.
Rym: That's not real.
Rym: They're equally bad.
Rym: But uh uber apparently just sold its entire self-driving unit to some some Aurora company.
Scott: Well, I wonder if this is a you know A lot of companies have sort of bailed out of the self-driving car game because it turns out it's not Progressing as fast as they thought right?
Scott: I think there's a few reasons.
Scott: The reason number one uber did just successfully get their law passed in California to exploit workers further.
Scott: also, if you vote, California That uber paid for Uber is now trying to get similar, you know legislation passed in other states and places.
Scott: don't let them.
Scott: You know, luckily we don't have some easy stupid referendum system like California does so they can't pull that same shit in New York.
Scott: But they're still trying.
Scott: Yeah But also so they since they have that law in place now that's gonna be very hard for Californians to remove.
Rym: They don't need to replace the workers they can just keep exploiting them legally without a threat from the courts and also they can sell all this to some other company who will deal with all the problems of actually getting self-driving cars to the mass market?
Scott: and also Self-driving cars while a good thing and while a possible thing are even today Right such a long play.
Rym: There are short plays or things that you can't like.
Rym: uber would not make money on as quickly as they'd like to.
Scott: They're not a short-term play and it's you know, a short-term Stock market, right?
Scott: They don't give a shit if you're gonna do something that won't turn profits for 20 years, right?
Scott: You're not allowed to do that.
Rym: Yeah, but even more I'm thinking This I feel like companies like uber.
Rym: by selling by basically offloading this to some other company to figure it out They'll reap the same benefits if that technology comes to market regardless.
Scott: Yep, there they weren't.
Scott: they weren't never looking to sell self-driving cars to other people.
Scott: the way like, you know A car company is now.
Rym: I'm curious to see because I just read this news.
Rym: I Know professionally a lot of people who have quit capital markets jobs to go work for uber on the self-driving cars Feel like those people all made a terrible mistake because uber does not need a massive Engineering division if they're just exploiting workers with a rideshare app.
Scott: Well, I've also seen you know Just from an outsider that you there's already been.
Scott: I thought I think there was some battle over some employees that switched Companies who are working in.
Rym: so yeah, there were a bunch of people.
Rym: people switch between these companies But maybe they have IP.
Rym: there's non-competes and lost.
Scott: There is the people who work on.
Scott: this is generally like a short list of places to work on this one problem and it's The same set of people who are experts in that area and sort of everyone in those, you know places knows Which ones are ahead and which ones are behind.
Scott: and if you're behind it's like why even bother to continue?
Scott: They're gonna beat you to market.
Scott: their thing is gonna be better than you and if you try to Workers you're gonna get sued.
Rym: I think non-compete agreements are 100% bullshit, but they're still gonna bother you.
Rym: It's hard to fight them, right?
Scott: but it's like why release the Sega Master System if you already know the NES is Development, right?
Scott: It's like you can just stop.
Scott: then you don't have to bother - it's actually a good thing Right.
Scott: don't bother to release to goes all the way through with this and release a piece.
Scott: Oh my god You know, there's a funny story waste your time and resources when someone else is already doing it better.
Rym: There's a funny story about the 45 record like, you know The two competing formats of records not the old era with like the old 78s or whatever But the 45 and the the regular old 33 and a third, right?
Rym: Yep, so supposedly, I don't remember all the details of this the new record format was coming out and the industry did like a demo of it and The company that developed the 45 had not announced anything yet and basically realized.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: Someone already made a better record.
Rym: What the fuck are we gonna do now?
Rym: But the other thing that's interesting is the CEO of uber is joining the board of this company.
Rym: So part of this is definitely shuffling money and investment around.
Rym: a lot of the same players are still involved in everything But anyway things Of the day, so this article is a little long, but it'll go into the detail.
Rym: If you read this article, you will understand what this person did.
Rym: They made a tweet.
Rym: that quote tweeted itself a Tweet.
Scott: that quote treated itself.
Scott: So they tweeted out like hello.
Rym: Yep But that hello tweet was a retweet of the tweet that said hello.
Scott: So they had to do this with the API.
Scott: There's no way to do it with.
Rym: they did it with the API.
Scott: So they in between they were like it was like tweet tweet ID one quote tweet tweet ID.
Rym: So basically they reverse engineered a lot of how tweet IDs work and Figured out a way to guess the tweet ID of the tweet You're about to post.
Rym: so you could then incline it in the tweet.
Scott: I see.
Rym: But the way they did it was really clever and there's a lot of really really fun side effects where you could do clever Interesting shit.
Rym: if you read this it is possible.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I'm not gonna mess with this because it seems like too much of pain in the ass and it might be goatsy But you could theoretically tweet something today that in the future will become a retweet of a tweet Meaning someone will treat them.
Scott: quote tweet.
Scott: You just quote tweet some ID of a tweet.
Scott: That's way out in the future.
Scott: You know what tweet.
Scott: you don't know what tweet that's gonna be.
Scott: It's like the current highest number tweet is a million.
Scott: you quote tweet tweet to million.
Scott: a million tweets.
Scott: from now Suddenly your regular tweet becomes a quote tweet of a tweet that didn't exist when you tweeted.
Rym: Yep, so if you do it, right and you can maybe predict like how far out that tweets likely to be.
Rym: You could basically have a quote retweet where someone would tweet something clever and then notice that wait a minute.
Rym: How did rib retweet me four years ago?
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: So, uh, you can read this article that actually explains it all in excruciating detail.
Rym: It's not actually that complicated and it's pretty fun.
Scott: Okay, so yeah, uh, so here's a video from Chinese television.
Scott: for some reason the only Chinese television that seems to make it to at least my sphere of media consumption is Always people doing like wacky Guinness Records sort of.
Scott: you know silly type things I get.
Scott: I Don't not sure if like this is what they show on Chinese television a lot or if this is just the thing that People who aren't from China show.
Scott: that being on Chinese television.
Scott: right that share, right?
Rym: TV gets pushed pretty hard too.
Scott: So right But anyway, yeah, so CCTV is Chinese state television.
Rym: If you didn't know as Wikipedia will warn you if you click on this link exactly.
Scott: But that doesn't really matter because this is just a video of a dude jumping off the ground Like a meter in the air almost right so it looks close to a meter.
Scott: that's already a pretty good standing jump.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: I can't do that.
Scott: Can you do that?
Rym: I Have not tried in my adult life.
Scott: I come close.
Scott: I mean I might like, you know get near the top.
Scott: It's it's it's not.
Rym: you know, I think I could.
Rym: I'm gonna try this later.
Scott: a lot of people it's it's not the easiest.
Rym: Yeah, I've been really Really working out my legs.
Scott: It's not the easiest but you're not jumping though I am Okay, well it's not the easiest.
Scott: I'm sure many people can do it but not most people regardless.
Scott: What's more amazing is that on top of the two?
Scott: He's not jumping onto a platform either.
Scott: He's jumping under two sticks, right?
Scott: So that's hard.
Scott: But now he's jumping under two sticks.
Scott: on top of each stick our little cushions.
Scott: and each of those little cushions are Two eggs and you can tell they're real eggs.
Scott: because he keeps messing up and the eggs break all over.
Scott: Right now I'm faking it.
Scott: This is not fake.
Rym: now That is I don't know if it if he messed up on purpose to like increase the drama or if it is just that hard.
Scott: I'm sure it's not easy, but it's not a fake thing.
Scott: Like they're not fake eggs.
Scott: It's not some trick, right?
Scott: It's simply a matter of the fact that a. eggshells are stronger than you think they are.
Scott: They can support the weight of an entire hand easily.
Rym: Well, I mean kids in point.
Rym: put an egg in your hand and try to just crush it.
Scott: Yeah eggs are stronger than you think it's like an arch right they have.
Scott: they have quite a lot of strength in them You know, they've evolved to be strong so that they don't break under the weight of animals sitting on them, right?
Scott: Or attacking them or trying to eat them or whatever.
Scott: But also if you evenly distribute your weight right across that a couple eggs.
Scott: He's not doing one egg each, right?
Scott: He's also doesn't appear to be that heavy a person.
Scott: It'll be much more difficult for a heavy person to do this But it's not a heavy looking person, you know, he can stand on less egg someone, you know for me I'd probably need more than two eggs per foot to stand on that without breaking them, right?
Scott: But if you evenly distribute your weight across them, no one egg will break Right, the jump just sort of makes it more dramatic and exciting You know to get it and we've got
Rym: to tell the landing right to not put too much force like put more force than his Body-weight on it.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Yes So, you know regardless of Chinese propaganda TV the great job.
Scott: egg jumping person awesome.
Rym: In the meta moment, I have not lit the tale of Genji signal.
Rym: I'm still reading this political book.
Rym: Okay Our Bunch of panels are on YouTube.
Rym: Pax just posted a video that we've never uploaded.
Rym: We ran a version of the 40 tabletop games You should play at Pax unplugged last year and it happened last year.
Scott: It wasn't it several years ago.
Rym: No, it's 2019 and they put it in.
Scott: I thought this one was from like 2017.
Rym: I think this was from 2019.
Rym: Maybe 2018.
Rym: I have a database I can go check.
Rym: Okay, but anyway it's a panel we didn't record because packs had live streamed it on one of the packs channels from PAX Unplugged and They're doing reprises of popular panels.
Rym: So they did a premiere live stream meaning a panel that has never been on YouTube before But is fairly similar to a very similar battle with the same name.
Rym: We've done before with only minor changes.
Rym: It's now on YouTube.
Rym: You can watch it.
Scott: All right Pax announced they're gonna try to have a Pax next year.
Scott: We are not gonna go unless it is like super safe.
Scott: If it's not safe for me to go to like a crowded metal concert and I'm not going to a Pax.
Rym: Here's what I will say and I think you should apply this to your life, but this is the gig night standard.
Rym: We will not attend any convention that requires masks.
Rym: Has COVID related attendance limitations or has any social distancing measures?
Rym: because if any of those three things are true It is not safe to have a convention in the first place.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And it's.
Scott: if it's not, you know, there's a.
Rym: If a convention does not have all three and COVID is still going crazy that is obviously we're not attending that con either.
Scott: As much as I want to go to a con your life is your life.
Scott: You're not gonna if you die You're not gonna go to any other con ever.
Scott: if I just survive Another what - even if I have to go and survive for two or three more years, right?
Scott: How long did the Spanish flu take?
Rym: How many more Pax's will you get if you live to 70?
Scott: right if I just make it through that if I just got to Survive then I can go to 20 30.
Scott: How many more Pax's?
Scott: Yeah I'll be all right if I go to one.
Scott: if I go to the know you could go to five Really working at it.
Scott: All right, if I'm so desperate for a Pax I go to one with masks and all sorts of protocols and then I get friggin sick and die.
Scott: Well, that's my last packs.
Scott: Hope you enjoyed it.
Rym: so to be clear it if Masks are required if social distancing is required or if there are COVID related attendance caps do not under any circumstances Attend any conventions for the love of God or Satan or whatever.
Scott: We I will not intend a high attendance Event of any kind until it is as safe as it was in 2019 2018. just go and not even think about it.
Rym: Yep, if I have to wear a mask then I'm already.
Rym: I'm still in like personal lockdown in my life, right?
Scott: Of course, you know even in you know now I think there might be one good positive Which is that by you know masks used to only be a thing in certain cultures and places around the world.
Scott: Yep, maybe now when people are you know regular sick, right?
Scott: They just have a cold they have.
Rym: you know something like that like still like don't go to a job if you're already like.
Rym: if we're already at a con and we're sick and We have to do a panel like I'll wear a mask Like before I go to the panel, I mean I can not gonna lie.
Scott: I didn't do that before but you know what for the rest of my life.
Scott: That's probably how I'm gonna do.
Scott: Normalized people should wear a mask when they're sick But yeah do not attend a con now on until I'm old, you know, whenever if I'm sick I'll probably and I go outside where there's people I'll wear one which I didn't do previously.
Rym: probably should if I was wrong But so long as things are requiring masks do not go to things All right, other metamode.
Scott: one mother metamoment.
Scott: So the It is currently December 7th, right the advent of code 20 is happening.
Scott: Yeah, it's a. Basically if you don't know about it's been going on since 2015.
Scott: I met the person who created it once for like a 30 seconds when they checked out a game at the PAX East tabletop library.
Scott: But it's basically a little puzzle contest where every day from December 1st through December 25th They put out a little puzzle and you solve it and type in the answer and then if you're right or you're wrong and it.
Scott: There's a little competition aspect to it, but you don't have to worry about that part if you don't want to.
Scott: Regardless I am recording videos of myself Solving the puzzle each day.
Scott: I didn't upload all them to YouTube because some of the videos came out shitty.
Scott: But I live streaming and also so I'll probably do one right after this show.
Rym: So I'm looking at a seven.
Rym: that actually looks pretty fun.
Scott: What's today?
Scott: today's day seven?
Scott: I didn't do it yet.
Rym: Oh the one about the rules for bags like encoding the rules of this game, basically No, okay.
Scott: I'll be doing that after this.
Rym: I'm just I just.
Rym: I just went to the site so I could put something on the screen and this one actually looks interesting.
Scott: They're all.
Scott: they're all pretty interesting.
Scott: So the nature of these puzzles is like you could just solve them by hand or whatever.
Scott: But they're structured in such a way that you're unless you're gonna get an answer.
Scott: You can't get the answer from someone else because everyone has a unique input file And it calculates to make sure your answer matches your input file for you specifically.
Scott: But you could steal someone else's code and run it on your input to get the answer.
Scott: That's cheating.
Scott: I kind of right who cares?
Scott: but if you're gonna solve it yourself You're probably going to have to enlist the aid of a computer and you're going to have to use some sort of programming language.
Scott: But I've seen people do it in Excel.
Scott: I've seen people do it in bash script.
Scott: I've seen people do it.
Scott: I'm like web-based interpreters of various kinds.
Scott: You know you can solve it using pretty much any computer tool you want.
Scott: I'm just using Python because that's the what I know the most and it's the easiest.
Scott: But yeah, it's.
Scott: it's a lot of fun.
Scott: You can go back and do the old years if you want to.
Scott: Good times even for a Jew doing some Advent
Rym: All right, so this was the idea we had for a show like suddenly We're trying to figure out what to talk about But it's related to things we're doing in our lives right now And actually we have a long history of this and it's a topic.
Rym: I think well you'll find interesting and the idea is When and how do you extract?
Rym: Value longer from technology be it software or hardware that you've got like?
Rym: is it worth it to keep an old TV for as long As possible until like the last piece of it is unrepairable?
Rym: How long you keep running that Pentium 2 before you give up and actually throw it away?
Scott: right and now this is something that's very important in an era when a Repairability has gone way down for a lot of things.
Scott: So things break and it's like well I guess I had to throw it out and buy a new one.
Scott: right if you could somehow keep it going Then you could.
Scott: it helps the environment.
Scott: It helps your wallet it helps So many things.
Scott: for you know There's always you know nerds.
Scott: on the one hand we love to be on that bleeding edge like ooh.
Scott: There's something newer faster better stronger.
Scott: I want to get that.
Scott: but if what you have is still perfectly good or even if it's not perfectly good for your nerdy use case It's still good for something.
Scott: Yeah, it's not useless it.
Scott: You know.
Scott: It's like if you can keep it functioning And maybe find a new purpose for it.
Scott: Maybe you know keep it going.
Scott: That's great Especially since you know like I said waste, but e waste is like even worse than just regular old wastes.
Scott: It's all toxic Yeah, and it's like you know some kid probably had to like mine rare minerals from some you know Trash-dumb for something to build.
Scott: that it's already super bad Capitalism to make the thing in the first place if you waste it to buy a new one.
Scott: now You've doubled that super bad capital yeah.
Rym: But even still there's that there's a very personal thing to like directly to you as a user of technology Around and I used to say this a lot my whole life whenever I had a computer.
Rym: Every day.
Rym: that I can continue to do what I do on a daily basis with my existing computer Saves me money Because I got more value out of the computer I built or bought and I get one day further into the future when technology gets better and cheaper.
Rym: Mm-hmm I held on to some computers Probably honestly way longer than I should have remember the era where like my computer would crash randomly trying to record GeekNights because I was Unwilling to buy a new one.
Scott: Yeah But not only that Right do you?
Scott: do you make your your shit lasts?
Scott: Longer right?
Scott: you get more use out of the same thing But the time it takes to replace a thing and can recon in especially a computer But also other things.
Scott: get used to a new thing.
Scott: learn a new thing could help.
Scott: you're a new thing set up a new thing Right it's time that you're not using the thing Right.
Scott: you're not you know getting the productivity out of it.
Scott: you're doing some meta work of setting up your environment and configuring shit and Learning and that's time where you're not producing.
Scott: so the longer you can if you get a setup the longer you can make that setup.
Scott: a productive setup that continues to function well without having to Completely mess with it and redo it or replace things is More productivity from you another day.
Scott: you could just podcast.
Scott: if Rym buys like a new microphone It's like well podcast gonna take an extra hour.
Scott: today Rym bought a new thing.
Rym: Yeah I gotta calibrate everything and figure out the pipeline and set the line levels and all that now.
Scott: But if we just use this to set up we have another day.
Scott: It's like oh, it's another day that we can.
Scott: you know don't know it's funny.
Rym: We're saying this I'm looking at.
Rym: I got the audition screen here recording this episode of GeekNights right now.
Rym: I threw together a hacky like pipeline to handle you being a remote But I never templatized it.
Rym: so every night.
Rym: We do the show.
Rym: I just open the old file save as and continue Well templatize it today.
Rym: I actually am planning to templatize it this week because I just templatized the other shows like the Disney show.
Scott: So okay, so the first.
Scott: so let's talk about ways to accomplish this.
Scott: How do you get more blood from the stone right now.
Rym: some of this involves planning a little bit in advance especially with computers.
Rym: with computers?
Rym: Whenever you buy or build a new computer at least look at how upgradeable it is.
Rym: Where in the cycle of technology advancement is it right now?
Rym: does it have two slots for RAM or four slots for RAM?
Rym: Like those are things that if you look at that early that is how I have milked computers for so long in my life.
Rym: I'll buy something and even if I'm trying to save money it has four dim slots.
Rym: I'll buy one stick of RAM to stick in it so that later I can buy a second large stick as opposed to buying four small sticks And then I have to buy all new RAM when I want to replace it.
Scott: little things like that add up All right, so the first thing you want to do is go and listen.
Scott: We've done two episodes of GeekNights on computer maintenance.
Scott: We did one in 06 and we did one in 2020. right so that's just for computers.
Scott: But the general topic of maintenance applies to everything right.
Scott: everything that you have in your whole house from like Sharpening your kitchen knives to you know just cleaning shit watering your plants.
Rym: Yeah, if your computer's full of dust.
Rym: It's slower than it would otherwise be Right.
Scott: maintenance takes time and it takes effort But it pays out.
Scott: right you're get you get back for your investments.
Scott: the next time you're spending an hour Cleaning and it feels like oh man this sucks.
Scott: I hate doing this right.
Scott: you just bought yourself Right like who knows how long you know in something in some other department of something not breaking something not needing to be replaced something Not needing it's not getting all gross and gummed up.
Scott: right?
Scott: you you know you lubricate some motor.
Scott: It's like that's what you just you.
Scott: okay you wait you spent.
Scott: You know even if you spent a long time on that You effectively just purchased a motor that you because the one that you're not going to have to purchase because the one you just Lubricated is gonna work that much longer.
Rym: yep You know what case in point the trumpet that I'm playing like every day during this quarantine.
Rym: I've had that trumpet since 1995 and you know what.
Rym: I maintain it.
Rym: I oil it.
Rym: I clean it.
Rym: I like take it apart and run snakes through it.
Rym: I replace parts on it.
Rym: Buying a trumpet that expensive every like five or ten years would have been a big problem.
Rym: But that trumpet is completely fine.
Rym: it'll last another 50 years the way I'm maintaining it.
Scott: Another way to make sure things last a long time is to buy the right thing to begin with.
Scott: now This has a problem in that it's sort of a privilege of people who have a lot of money.
Rym: Yeah, I buy a four to five thousand dollar computer every like seven to ten years.
Scott: well It's not just buying something That's way strong and way ahead of the curve so that it doesn't become Obsolete because it's so powerful and new right like buying a 4k TV before they're a thing and that way you just have one Right.
Scott: that is a thing But it's also buying the right thing.
Scott: so I think my bicycles are a great example of this right.
Scott: so the bicycle that I bought when I moved to the city In like 2010 right I just sort of went in the bike shop, and I bought like a four hundred ish trek $400 ish trek whatever right and The two choices were like one that was slightly small and one that was slightly big.
Scott: So I took the slightly big one because I had like a more upright sitting comfortable sitting position because it was bigger right And it wasn't bad.
Scott: You know I rode that bike a long ass time.
Scott: I made it work a long ass time.
Scott: I repaired it several times But because it was a little bit too big that can't be fixed right.
Scott: It was slightly the wrong thing.
Rym: It's in its just like a computer.
Rym: you buy a motherboard that is not upgradeable.
Rym: It was probably the wrong thing.
Scott: Right it was the wrong thing for me.
Scott: It didn't fit.
Scott: I kept using it.
Scott: Regardless I made it last quite a long time, but then the bicycles that I bought now Yeah I spent more money and time and research right getting ones that are exactly right and are ultra high quality.
Scott: these I expect to last forever until unless they break or something bad happens to them.
Scott: right they'll last my whole life.
Rym: I assume now that the privilege thing like the this gets tossed around a lot But it's very worth remembering.
Rym: it cost very fresh.
Rym: it quote from We're I think disc world ring world without disc world stuff.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I've never actually read any of those books I'm only familiar.
Scott: eventually.
Rym: I know I know that Terry Pratchett wrote disc world But there's that Vimes next Economic fairness where if the cheap boots are affordable, but they wear out every couple of years No one poor can afford expensive boots, but expensive boots last forever.
Rym: It is more expensive to be poor exactly and that is that applies to technology to like Trying to keep using Adobe like cs4 in the mind.
Rym: I know people are using cs4 to this day.
Rym: That is causing more pain and anguish and difficulty than the cost of buying new software.
Rym: But that's what you got in some cases.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't I mean, it's like yeah They had.
Scott: the thing is you know it's like they got choices.
Scott: They can keep using what they got which costs pain anguish and difficulty and time or they can use this other thing that will save Them pain anguish difficulty and time but cost money,
Rym: but
Scott: when you're poor you have time you have pain You don't have money, so that's what you're.
Scott: that's all you have.
Rym: and computing in particular both software and hardware.
Rym: You can get a lot of value out of both software and hardware if you are have and are willing to spend the time To the point that you can save terrifying amounts of money, but if you have money those things are a waste of your time exactly.
Scott: So Yeah, getting the right thing to begin with putting in lots of research figuring out knowing yourself knowing what you're going to use things For right what their purpose is you know exactly what you what your needs are yep?
Rym: What does the video card do like?
Rym: that's a very specific example.
Rym: if you're not a gamer?
Rym: Or you only play like simple games that don't require like a crazy GPU, and you're not streaming But you want to watch 4k stuff on a TV you can get like an Intel i7 which will Integrated chips will just play 4k video.
Rym: fine And that's enough that while the i7 chip is more expensive than the other Intel chips You don't have to buy a video card for your use case.
Rym: You'll save yourself a ton of money.
Rym: that thing will last forever Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean you know I look at for example a case where maybe I didn't Sort of buy the exact.
Scott: I sort of did and didn't buy the exact right thing and like the camera department right.
Scott: so I have like a pile of cameras.
Scott: I Basically need at this point zero more cameras.
Scott: I haven't bought any camera stuff in a long ass time, right?
Scott: I mean this year because I haven't gone outside, but anybody last year either I don't even you know I guess since it's been a long time since I bought any camera stuff And I don't need any more because I finally figured out you know.
Scott: ah these are the cameras.
Scott: these I find myself using a lot right I you know I needed to know.
Scott: You know myself more, but I see other people in the camera world who are buying all new stuff constantly, right?
Scott: They're constantly selling all their stuff and buying all new stuff selling all this stuff buying all new stuff switching all over the place.
Scott: And I'm like Do you it's like they must not know and they just like buying stuff, which is true.
Rym: Don't mean they might be a camera hobbyist like their joy in life is play with this lens for 10 minutes Sure.
Scott: But you know if you I feel like if your goal is to use the thing You're at some point you're gonna figure out What's the right one for you, and then you'll be able to stick with that one for an absurdly long amount of time.
Scott: Yep, right I bought cameras that are older than me that are still good.
Scott: if I had bought them when they were new I could Still I could have been the original purchaser and still had them.
Rym: which leads us to sort of point two Which is a little more directly relevant?
Rym: Irrespective of if you have money to buy the right tool in the first place brand-new whatever tool it is that you're using.
Rym: Learn how it works like fully learn how it works.
Rym: learn it enough to recognize What's wrong with it.
Rym: a normal person has a TV that doesn't work anymore, and they throw it away.
Rym: Someone who knows a little bit about TVs might realize that certain kinds of TVs like one set of capacitors Will like fail and the backlight doesn't work But the TV is fine And they can repair that TV for like a small amount of money like 20 bucks and the TV is fine again.
Rym: Computers if you know what part of your computer broke you can replace just that part.
Rym: that's a lot of people there have probably been.
Scott: Think about how much stuff has been thrown out every year Simply by people who don't know better.
Scott: And there's also a lot of cases right where people throw stuff out and people who know better are actually by policy or by law or other things Unable.
Scott: I read it because a good example I was reading about this if you were best buy is like actually one of the places in the US where a lot of e recycling happens Because they'll just accept You know electronics there to be recycled.
Scott: a lot of the best buy best buy.
Scott: employees happen to be nerdy people who know some stuff Right, and they see someone bring something in.
Scott: that's perfectly good and working and they want it.
Scott: But if they take it they will be fired and in big trouble.
Scott: So I don't and that stuff just goes to who knows where.
Rym: but you Especially if you are like a nerd or you have free you have time But not money.
Rym: if you have a thing where you need to learn this level of detail just for your own productivity or hobbies or entertainment You could have a side hustle on repairing things for people and That's a way to get more money to buy a better tool Mm-hmm.
Rym: I have done those kinds of things in the past at high school.
Rym: I would fix other people's computers for cash.
Rym: You know what fixing them entailed in most cases fucking nothing.
Rym: Nothing was wrong with the computer.
Rym: Nothing at all.
Rym: I Charge the same price no matter what and I would just hand them a computer bag and say it's working.
Rym: now Mm-hmm, like I remember I fixed someone's computer once.
Rym: this is a rich family that drives happen to do know their computer Wasn't working.
Rym: The monitor was broken and I went to fix it.
Rym: They didn't know what resolution was or how to change it.
Rym: This giant monitor had like 640 by 480 outputting to it.
Rym: I Right clicked in Windows.
Rym: I fixed that and they paid me 40 bucks.
Rym: Okay in the year Sure.
Scott: So another way, right?
Scott: So, you know now we're sort of into like this, you know Reduce reuse recycle situation, right?
Scott: So, you know you make a thing last longer, but you can also Reduce right.
Scott: so reduce means waste less shit.
Scott: But actually when it comes to technology right buying less stuff Could actually mean that the few things you did buy get used a lot more Which means they might break faster.
Scott: So I've found that sometimes Depending on what it is like with shoes, for example, right if I have Two shoes for two different purposes again, you know privilege of being able to afford two shoes at once.
Scott: Both shoes last longer because like I have an inside.
Scott: It's em at the office.
Scott: I haven't worn it in a year.
Scott: I got like an inside only shoe with the office, right?
Scott: Having that that shoe lasts forever.
Scott: It never touches anything.
Scott: That's not carpet.
Scott: Yeah shoe store, right?
Scott: It's like that shoe lasts so many years but that shoe Takes removes all the indoor carpet walking from my outdoor only shoe.
Scott: the outdoor only shoe Yeah, it wears out faster than the indoor only shoe, but it gains a much longer life Right.
Scott: So just by buying that one Extra shoe once Right over time that actually adds up to like more than one pairs of shoes worth of wear Right by being a carpet only shoe.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So if you sometimes if you buy more than one thing Right, especially the kind of thing that wears with use Maybe you might want to get more than one.
Scott: a good example.
Scott: I might think of is I do this?
Scott: I know a lot of people have like a joy con drift, right?
Scott: I swap my joy cons Between two sets.
Rym: I started doing the same thing.
Scott: Neither one is drifting yet But I switch.
Scott: I just swap the joy cons once whenever I think about doing it.
Scott: And so that means you know, both of them are still working.
Scott: So it's you know, not wearing one out with a ton of use, right?
Rym: So we've gone on a while.
Rym: So I think let's end on a very practical note with a computer specifically Not max because that's a different world but with regular old computers desktop workstation type computers.
Rym: What are the things you can do specifically to bring as much blood out of that stone as possible?
Rym: And the first thing it comes down to low hanging fruit.
Rym: What are the cheapest things you can upgrade that will give that computer more performance an old computer usually uses?
Rym: older slower RAM.
Rym: You can probably buy that RAM a real cheap Probably if it's still available.
Scott: sometimes occasionally there's an ultra-rare RAM.
Rym: Yeah, if it's too old it gets more expensive.
Rym: again.
Rym: There's a diminishing return at that point.
Scott: Well, I mean the RAM from Mac Plus was super cheap.
Rym: But like my previous computer it had six dim slots because it was weird like it was a weird Trichannel thing that didn't last that long.
Rym: But what that?
Rym: and well what that meant was.
Rym: I bought for like five bucks each a pile of two Gigabyte dims and I filled it with them.
Rym: They got 12 gigabytes of memory.
Rym: It cost me like 25 bucks plus shipping and that literally let me use that computer for another year Before I really had to get rid of it.
Scott: The other thing is when it comes to computers computers are general purpose devices.
Scott: They can do a lot of different things Right.
Scott: So a lot of people they just have a computer and having a second computer seems kind of useless to them Like they'll just get rid of the first computer when they get a second one, right?
Scott: Okay, your computer is so old.
Scott: It won't do the things you need to do with that anymore.
Scott: It won't run the newest Photoshop.
Scott: It won't play the newest games.
Scott: It's really slow and your brows the web, right?
Rym: It's like my behind is an HD PC.
Scott: Might be fine as an HD PC.
Scott: It's Mike there.
Scott: It might be fine.
Scott: It's like doing a pie hole in your house.
Scott: Yeah, even though it's big and loud because it's a desktop.
Scott: It's like just hide it in a closet somewhere.
Rym: Oh, here's a higher-end example.
Rym: So my current computer with the 1080 GPU I have and everything else going on.
Rym: I cannot handle three simultaneous OBS's and an nginx or like.
Rym: I cannot do a Very complex streaming environment with a lot of sources and destinations on one PC.
Rym: I could make a PC strong enough to do that But that would be a lot more expensive than buying a second cheaper computer With a very cheap video card and offloading all those other streams to that other computer Mm-hmm, like a lot of streamers.
Rym: instead of building a god PC to stream and play their 144 Like refresh rate FPS is competitively They'll just buy a second cheaper computer and all that computer does is stream.
Rym: that allows them to save money on In the end because two good computers are way cheaper than one extreme computer.
Scott: And by learning right by learning a lot about the computer, right?
Scott: You may be able to find ways, you know uses and ways to breathe new life into it, right?
Rym: You know, where is the bottleneck?
Rym: if you know where the bottlenecks are?
Rym: You know what to upgrade or you know that that thing isn't feasible.
Rym: to upgrade it lets you make these decisions.
Scott: Or seemingly even if you don't upgrade it even in its unupgraded state It still might have a useful purpose if it's not broken.
Scott: Yeah You know.
Scott: or there might be some way to you know.
Scott: Make it like nicer to use considering what year it is like how I upgraded my GBA screen, right?
Scott: It's like yeah, and I get it the GBA kind of useless.
Scott: I can just emulate all these GBA games on another platform.
Scott: This thing is you know could have thrown it out or I upgraded the screen in it.
Scott: I put new battery in it now.
Scott: It's like the nicest handheld.
Scott: I have it.
Scott: Just you know any plays anything up to GBA games.
Rym: Yeah, sometimes you can even use this to wrap around gamers.
Rym: I had a computer that bit by bit all the USB slots one by one had Mechanical like that shorting issues where if anything was plugged into them the computer was more and more likely to crash.
Rym: So it got to the point to where there's only one USB port that worked.
Rym: that was the GeekNights computer that kept crashing.
Rym: Okay, but I didn't want to buy a new computer yet because the computer was still more than capable of doing everything I wanted to do with it including producing GeekNights.
Rym: So what I do?
Rym: I bought a USB hub and I plugged it into the last functioning USB port Mm-hmm, and I just unplugged inside of the computer all the USB headers that were having these shorting problems And I got another like year and a half out of that computer.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, but you know whatever your old thing is right.
Scott: so you know maybe you've got a laptop right that you had in college And it's been in the closet, and you haven't touched it right and it's like okay if you try It's it can't it's.
Scott: maybe it's a MacBook.
Scott: It can't run big sir.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: it's so old the newest OS X won't install on it right.
Scott: It's just really really sad and kind of man right.
Scott: What do you do with it?
Scott: It's like you would never use it instead of the computers you have and use now.
Scott: right.
Scott: But maybe because you don't care about it that much Maybe you can use it when you go like you know out in the woods, and you might get damaged.
Scott: You won't.
Scott: so I care so much right Maybe you can use it.
Scott: You know it's like it can still word process right.
Scott: Maybe it's comfy to go use it for some typing.
Scott: you're just gonna do some typing You know go take that one out somewhere if it gets something happens to it or whatever.
Scott: It's not cheap old computer you know.
Scott: maybe you want to try to like the key.
Rym: there is that knowledge.
Rym: you have to learn a Lot more and a lot of different things that you might not expect.
Rym: you need to learn about your hardware about whatever it is You're using in order to have a lot of these options.
Scott: We're talking about yeah, maybe you got an old We.
Scott: well guess what you know.
Scott: you can install that all we You know.
Scott: they people are you know hacking their wheeze installing special OS's players.
Rym: Remember an RIT when the capacitors were a problem and like computers are all dying.
Rym: So my computer had the bad capacitors.
Rym: I could not afford to replace that motherboard like I got to have any money, but I underclocked my CPU the Athlon case 7800 and The computer with the leaking capacitors was more stable and that bought me time to save up money to buy a new motherboard.
Rym: But I knew that Underclocking it would reduce the stress on the problematic component.
Rym: due to research without knowing that I would have just been fucked.
Rym: My computer just would have crashed every day, and I would have been screwed.
Scott: oh Maybe you like me.
Scott: you just replaced your phone right.
Scott: well Maybe your old phone.
Scott: you could use it for a cool project.
Scott: remember that guy who would like Put the phones with the booby traps in the.
Scott: oh yeah, yeah mail into people.
Scott: right.
Scott: It's like a phone is like a camera and a computer in a little tiny package with a battery and everything and radios.
Scott: It's like you can have a lot of fun with the phone.
Scott: if you've got a new phone and your old phone still functions Your old phone could at least be a cool backup phone or give it to someone else.
Rym: That's what I'm literally doing now.
Rym: I put my SIM card in my new phone my old phone.
Rym: I still keep I still power it on.
Rym: it works on Wi-Fi.
Rym: That's the house phone Mmm.
Rym: I just like leave it.
Rym: in fact You know what I've seen some what I always wanted to do.
Rym: I never did this because we never had any reason cuz everyone know as the smartphone.
Rym: I just wanted to take old tablets and smartphones Put a generic account on them and just leave them out like on the coffee table like hope you want to browse the web while You're hanging out like just that's the house phone.
Rym: Just hanging out for anyone to browse the web on.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they're not that you have anyone visiting now.
Scott: Yeah, okay with creativity, and you know like there are purposes for New stuff or old stuff or stuff.
Scott: That isn't your primary stuff anymore.
Scott: Okay, so you know figure it out, and you'll be helping.
Scott: You know yourself the environment your wallet.
Rym: well.
Rym: look if I had been more diligent You know what I could have done with that old computer.
Rym: I could have tried to replace those capacitors.
Rym: It was only six of them Mmm.
Rym: I was too much of a power facing it.
Rym: anyway You know this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our Website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and The patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Mardi Grady and Link Eiji.
Rym: Graham Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: now.
Rym: go through the last year or so of podcasts and make Rym saying Clinton Walton ran from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Chris mid gift dread Lily Tenebrae just like a dude guy.
Rym: Chris Reimer Finn Shervin Von or and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: and now I leave you with Super.
Scott: she's a. She's like you have.