Rym: It's Wednesday, November 11th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We are reviewing the anime Deca-Dence.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know, it's been a thousand years since March and like the date doesn't mean anything to me anymore.
Rym: Like it never matters what day it is.
Rym: Like I gotta look like Oh, what fucking day is it when I'm gonna say it?
Scott: It matters if it's a Saturday or a Sunday.
Rym: It matters what day of the week it is.
Rym: It does not matter what the number is on the day.
Scott: No, because the calendar only matters for special events and if all special events are canceled then why does it matter what the calendar day is, right?
Scott: It's not gonna be packs.
Scott: It's not gonna be a holiday.
Scott: You know, it's like oh, it'll be Thanksgiving, but you won't be doing anything.
Scott: So what does it matter, right?
Scott: It's just another Thursday.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Do I have to work from home or just stay at home?
Rym: But I noticed just now that today is 11/11, which there's a holiday not that it matters to us especially in America people barely celebrate Veterans Day or Armistice Day.
Scott: We have a different Veterans Day.
Rym: But Armistice Day has a weirdly tragic story.
Rym: I've learned a lot about World War One because I'm weird.
Rym: I may not like that.
Rym: And World War One is a complex tapestry of bullshit that I do not want to get into right now.
Rym: There's a lot of complexity to what the hell was going on in World War One.
Rym: But the thing that's always struck me is that Armistice Day was on the 11th hour, the 11th day of the 11th month.
Rym: And that wasn't a coincidence.
Rym: The powers that be kind of did that on purpose because it was a cool number and people literally died because of that.
Rym: And I don't know how many people know that.
Rym: but if you're ever in a position where you are prosecuting a defensive war against an aggressive and belligerent enemy and you have an opportunity for peace and you delay the opportunity for peace or at least a truce in order to make a cool number appear somewhere.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: Like do the right thing.
Scott: The fact that these people had already been the people who had the power to end the war, right?
Scott: We're also the people who chose to start the war.
Scott: So already fuck them.
Rym: Well, it's complicated because on one hand a lot of powers were culpable for starting World War One.
Rym: But on the other hand, I will stand by.
Rym: In fact, the last time I was in Australia.
Rym: I ended up getting into an argument with a bunch of strangers about this topic.
Rym: But I would say that Germany was primarily culpable for the continuance of World War One due to their continuing territorial aggression and then their unwillingness to exceed the fact that that did not work.
Rym: But anyway, Armistice Day is a day and that's literally the only interesting thing I can think to talk about in my life since nothing's happened since Monday.
Scott: Nope, not really.
Rym: Yeah, so let's get right into some anime news.
Rym: It's actually really, it's news that needed to come.
Rym: I'm glad it came.
Rym: I was worried that it wouldn't come.
Rym: Like I was actually kind of worried about this but Katsucon has finally, correctly, canceled for 2021.
Scott: Oh, finally.
Scott: Oof.
Rym: I won't share any rumors of any internal things in detail because they're just rumors.
Rym: But basically it is notable that Katsucon waited so long to cancel when other cons that happen around the same time canceled a while ago.
Rym: Like I'm surprised it took this long.
Scott: I'm not, I mean, you know based on what I know, I'm not surprised.
Scott: I'm just.
Scott: It's hard, I guess it.
Scott: can you be disappointed if you expect, it's like if you if it met your low expectations.
Rym: Yeah, like I kind of stopped going to Katsucon when the staff thing happened, but that was so long ago that Katsucon has had much drama that I will not go into.
Rym: But that drama was like a decade ago.
Rym: We never even attended the new reformed Katsucon.
Scott: No, no, I barely know what's going on since that drama with Katsucon all those many many years ago.
Scott: But it, you know, because of that incident, right, I now in my mind give Katsucon a reputation for being a drama, you know, infused con, right?
Scott: And this piece of information, you know, the the whispers that I've heard through who knows what grapevines that, you know, they were doing their best to try to make their event happen instead of, you know, if I ran a convention, I would be doing my best to not make it happen.
Rym: Yeah, like the biggest danger right now are these conventions that are nonprofits where the state that they're in is a shitty state and won't like order them to cancel.
Rym: and thus they're because of stupid laws and stupid contracts.
Scott: MagFest, which is in the same exact building as Katsucon, right?
Scott: It's literally the same place.
Scott: Very close to the same time.
Scott: You know, it held back a little bit.
Scott: They tried a little bit, but then they're like, okay, no, right?
Scott: Most of the people that most of the staff I think that I am aware of were like, yeah, no, if you have it I'm not coming if you have it, right, etc.
Scott: So they didn't like Katsucon, look how long Katsucon held out until literally today.
Scott: So they decided to cancel.
Rym: They did issue follow-up statements.
Rym: They said, I'll skip through a lot of this, "Please know that there were many logistical and legal steps to take before we could announce
Rym: this.".
Scott: That is true.
Scott: That is not incorrect.
Rym: Yeah, and we've talked about this a bunch of times.
Rym: I'm not gonna go deep into it again.
Rym: But for all of you out there who are disappointed that a con's canceled or who are mad that a con is not canceled yet, the thing to bear in mind is that contract law and like the way this works in America is really, really stupid.
Scott: And I'm sure it works stupidly in other countries as well.
Scott: Every country on earth has contracts.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But American contracts, like in particular, part of what's going on is that America did not handle COVID well.
Rym: That is the understatement because Republicans were in power.
Rym: But as a result, not only is COVID not calming down to a steady state, like it's rising everywhere in the world, but it is rising at a catastrophic rate in America.
Scott: Maybe we saw that coming.
Scott: We were like, you know, in the summer, we were like, "Yeah, it's gonna way be bad when it gets cold
Scott: again.".
Scott: And we were right.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: A lot of things opened up.
Scott: I didn't want to be right, but we're right.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, the tricky part is a lot of people are saying, "Oh, we'll just go
Rym: online.".
Rym: Like, "I'm just trying to go
Rym: But I got to tell you, I've been involved in a lot of online cons up to this point.
Rym: They're doing their best.
Rym: However, online cons do not present a compelling story for most of the people who would attend a con.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Online cons do, you know, are a thing, right?
Scott: But basically, they're just, you know, even if you do all the best stuff that you can do at the online con.
Rym: You can have a bunch of panels and some discords to hang out in.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You are not making something that replaces the in-person con or serves the same purpose.
Scott: You are just, you know, doing what.
Scott: you have a company and you're doing what you can with your resources, plus the internet, to make money and engage your audience.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you are not replacing the thing you actually do.
Rym: And that's why, like, I think I hope God's Gun does try to do something online.
Rym: I like that cons are doing this because they're basically doing it, one, to keep their brand afloat, two, to give their staff something to do, and three, just to, like, do something for the community they work with.
Rym: Like, hey, if you run a con, usually you're running it because you want a cool thing to happen.
Rym: Why not do the coolest thing you can do under the circumstances?
Rym: But it is basically impossible to charge any amount of money for an online con, except in rare circumstances.
Scott: It depends.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And online cons do cost money to run for a lot of reasons.
Rym: So we'll see what happens.
Rym: But I just don't think there's going to be any cons in 2021 the way America is going right now.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: So at least the other thing that I can say is I was scrolling through all these tweets.
Rym: Very few people are mad about this.
Rym: Everyone seems to be taking this the right way, which is actually very heartening compared to how some people reacted to other cons being canceled last year.
Rym: Well, last year, earlier this year.
Rym: God damn it.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, so tiny news here, right?
Scott: So we did a GeekNights episode on season one of Beastars, which is an AA anime, Beastars is great.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Scott: And season two, we knew was coming eventually, but now we know it's coming January 5th, so January 5th.
Scott: And you know how Netflix do.
Scott: every episode is going to be there all at once.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So on January 5th, you'll be able to watch all of Beastars season two.
Rym: I'm excited.
Rym: I like this giant snake guy we're looking at here.
Scott: Yeah, we haven't.
Scott: I was wondering about, you know, those kinds of animals.
Rym: But especially because this snake is gigantic.
Scott: Yep, yep, yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Other tiny news, right?
Scott: So there's an anime called Venus Wars that was a big deal in the U.S.
Scott: in the 90s, late 90s.
Scott: It was, you know, it was a sci-fi channel.
Scott: Was it actually on sci-fi?
Rym: It was on sci-fi network.
Scott: I'm pretty sure because I remember it was one of those few anime that were dubbed in the U.S.
Scott: early.
Rym: I rented it from Blockbuster and copied that VHS tape.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: How notable and good is it really?
Scott: Right.
Scott: If it wasn't for the fact that it was one of those few anime that was distributed in the U.S.
Scott: in those days, would it even be known today?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It's interesting.
Rym: I really liked it as a kid and it was good, but it basically doesn't have an ending.
Rym: like it's a kind of one of those real war stories.
Rym: like take a little bit of Akira aesthetics, not the crazy stuff, but just like the bike stuff, coupled with some little bit of mech stuff, but more like big tanks and make it a Red Dawn situation.
Rym: A bunch of punk kids trying to fight against this occupation.
Rym: like it's kind of a real war story, but the end just doesn't fucking go anywhere.
Rym: Like this movie just ends on nothing.
Scott: So anyway, did we ever review it?
Scott: No, we thought we talked about reviewing it several times, but we only had a video CD that we got for free at a con somewhere.
Rym: The only mention on our site about Venus Wars is in the out of date.
Rym: I forgot this existed about Rym page.
Scott: Anyway, so why is Venus Wars make your about Rym page?
Rym: When he was nine, he saw his first anime, Vampire Hunter D, Robot Carnival, Project Echo, Venus Wars.
Scott: OK, anyway, so by this show, Sentai Filmworks has license rescued it from wherever it was.
Scott: So it's going to be available to watch again easily soon.
Scott: Now, I don't know exactly what actually like.
Scott: I'm glad I got the article and read it.
Scott: So, you know, regardless of whether this thing's any frickin good or worth watching in the year 2020, it does have a significance to the history of anime in the United States only and may be worth the time it takes to watch a single movie just to know what the deal was.
Scott: But yeah, it's going to be easy to do that soon or maybe even now.
Scott: Click on the article, get the date.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, it's got a few like really good iconic scenes.
Rym: Like there's a scene with the reporter and her camera that's really tense.
Rym: But yeah, just don't expect this movie to end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In some other news, we got a good news, bad news here from maybe the best anime distributor/publisher.
Scott: I don't know what they count as.
Rym: And why are these two news on the same page?
Scott: Because they're both discotheque.
Scott: Discotheque made two announcements.
Scott: It was a single press release in discotheque announcing two things they're doing.
Scott: So the first thing discotheque is doing, we'll do bad news first, right?
Scott: Is there is an OAV, an OVA, kind of not super old, but kind of old one.
Scott: And they're releasing, they're re-releasing it and it is called Kiss X Sis.
Scott: And you're probably thinking, listen to the name of that anime and thinking about what is an anime called Kiss X Sis about?
Rym: Well, it's either Hunter X Hunter, like Hunter X Hunter kind of situation or it's incest porn.
Scott: It is absolutely incest porn.
Scott: This anime is so bad.
Scott: This is like, you know, we make fun of a lot of animes, especially when we're judging animes about like, we're like, we get a whiff and we're like, stay away from this.
Rym: It's like, you know, I feel like I say Kiss X Sis sometimes as like, oh, this is going to be a Kiss X Sis situation.
Scott: This is worse.
Scott: I think Kiss X Sis is worse than like Chubra.
Scott: This is like, oh, for sure.
Rym: Chubra is positively tame compared to this bullshit.
Scott: In fact, there are things that are just like, you know, actual hentai, right, that are less distasteful than Kiss X Sis, right?
Scott: Because you have an actual hentai where like people are having consensual sex.
Scott: You know, it might be drawn in a way to subjectifying people and has other problems with it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not perfect.
Scott: But Kiss X Sis is this dude has two sisters, literal sisters who want him to pay step sisters.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I'm pretty sure these people are too young, I'm guessing.
Rym: I mean, it's anime.
Scott: So I have not looked into that many details.
Scott: I just know enough.
Scott: And that's all I know.
Scott: And that's enough to know.
Scott: this is the worst thing ever.
Scott: Why are they bringing this back?
Rym: But I guess they like the ad copy, like the copy from the press release, like specifically calls it out as a taboo breaking love bloom.
Rym: Like, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that's what it is.
Rym: They know what it is.
Rym: They're marketing it.
Scott: And that so having to be aware of the existence of Kiss X Sis is the price we have to pay for a discotheque.
Scott: to also announce they are re-releasing one of the best Lupin movies, the Miyazaki one, the one that's not like any other Lupin movie.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: But it's still amazing.
Scott: The most famous one, Castle of Cagliostro is getting released again this time in on a UHD Bure, which is 4K Bure.
Scott: So you can wait for someone to rip that.
Scott: And basically they had, you know, unlike a lot of other things, they try to re-release where they can't get like, you know, Project Aco, we can't find the material.
Rym: We're literally using this laser disc.
Scott: Exactly right.
Scott: It's not one of those situations.
Scott: This is like they have this.
Scott: They have all kinds of material from this.
Scott: In fact, it's going to include original like Japanese seven point one audio that they have for ultra surround sound and shit.
Scott: So this is probably going to be all indications, the ultimate home release, like you cannot beat this short of going to a theater and maybe even going to a theater with film wouldn't be as good maybe as what they are about to release, like the ultimate edition of this anime.
Scott: So I wouldn't.
Scott: I personally don't buy physical media, but, you know, if you do or if you can get a pirated rip of this or whatever, it's coming.
Scott: And that's that's exciting.
Rym: Yeah, I think we would give it a rewatch.
Rym: We're living in an era where a lot of anime is getting remastered and rereleased basically at the best possible quality that is possible, possible, possible, possible.
Rym: I said that a bunch of times.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So that's that's an excellent news.
Scott: And I just want to mention this one other thing.
Scott: I don't know if you've ever judged this show.
Scott: I've never seen it.
Scott: I don't know if there's a manga about it.
Scott: I think there might be.
Rym: I don't think we judged it because I would remember this title.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I basically well, I think we might have seen the title in Japanese, but basically there's an anime, maybe manga.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I have to go to Wikipedia and Google it.
Scott: I didn't do that before the show.
Scott: I'm sorry.
Scott: But there's an anime that's coming.
Scott: And all I know about it is the synopsis of the plot and the synopsis of the plot.
Scott: It doesn't seem like it's going to be a great all time anime.
Scott: I'm not going to lie and be like, oh, this is going to be amazing.
Scott: But the concept of the show seems so fun that I just I'm going to like.
Scott: it makes me want to go check it out.
Scott: So here's the show is called in English, Suppose a Kid from the Last Dungeon Boonies Moved to a Starter Town.
Scott: So this is obviously, you know, one of those shows where the world is a fantasy world that works like.
Rym: it's basically basically Takumi from Initial D.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's a. it's a world where it's a fantasy world.
Scott: It's not a video game thing, but it's where the world works the way an RPG works the same way as like Delicious and Dungeon, where the world works the way an RPG works, even though it's not.
Scott: it's not about real people in the real world going into a game.
Scott: It's just a world that works the way a game works.
Scott: And in this world, there's this tiny little kid, right, who's mad weak.
Scott: He's he's so weak compared to like all his friends and family.
Scott: He's just so sad and weak.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So he leaves his home and he goes to like the starter tutorial town of the world.
Scott: Wherever that is.
Rym: Let's go to Canaria and I'm going to figure go fight Garland.
Rym: That's a basic moves venture for parties level one to three.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He moves to to Canaria, right, to parties one to three go.
Scott: And it just turns out that where he comes from is a village that is sitting right next to directly adjacent to the most dangerous final boss dungeon in the entire world.
Rym: Like basically the tomb of horrors is right there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So he was the weakest kid in his town, so weak that he left.
Scott: And moved away because, you know, everyone else is so much stronger than him.
Scott: And he goes to the tutorial town, but in which he is basically God tier.
Scott: But he looks like a little kid.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So just that concept is such an anime manga concept.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: it's like if you just told me that plot, I would say that plot is definitely an anime plot.
Scott: There's no way that that's something else.
Rym: I love the whole thing.
Rym: The title of the anime is, quote, Suppose a kid from the last dungeon booties booties moved to a starter town.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: And it's like, wow, that seems like, you know, not going to be the greatest show, but it seems like it could be a lot of fun if they don't spend too long on battles.
Scott: That could be a really fun show.
Rym: It has a little bit of a concept.
Rym: It could be like Goku, though.
Rym: If anyone remembers, it could be.
Rym: I like Goku.
Scott: So I'm right.
Scott: So I'm kind of interested based on just the concept alone.
Scott: I want to.
Scott: I think I'm like, you know, I want to give this show a chance to see what the deal is.
Scott: It might be funny.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So in another I tell people it exists.
Rym: Another small news.
Rym: If you didn't see, as we know, HBO is bringing out one by one hour long Adventure Time continuing specials set throughout different.
Scott: Did we do an episode?
Scott: We did an episode of the BMO one.
Scott: Yeah, we did.
Rym: So the next one is coming.
Rym: The Marceline and Bubblegum won Obsidian.
Rym: We they just dropped.
Scott: I thought that would be the final one, but I guess not.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The final one is supposedly just Finn and Jake again.
Scott: Yeah, I thought that, you know, I thought it wouldn't be shocked if they make more after these four.
Rym: They seem to be doing well.
Scott: We'll see how many people, you know, they'll do whatever they want to do.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But Distant Lands, Obsidian.
Rym: We have the trailer for it.
Rym: And remember in the beginning when Marceline first gets introduced and she's like, oh, I was on vacation and it shows like hula hooping in some lava.
Rym: Pretty sure the place with the lava is the place that they go to in this one because there's the lava and the dragon and like the crystal glass people.
Scott: But the fact that they're together means it's not.
Scott: it's not a story about Marceline's vacation.
Scott: It definitely takes place after the end of Adventure Time based on the trailer.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Based on the trailer, the end of the TV 90 percent, it takes place after the end of the show or it takes place possibly during that brief era where Marceline and Bubblegum were like dating.
Rym: But like the Candy Kingdom wasn't fully formed.
Rym: It's not clear.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think that's what it is.
Rym: Pretty sure it just takes place at the end.
Scott: Yes, I'm pretty sure it takes place after the end of the TV show, unlike the BMO one, which takes place.
Rym: Well, spoiler to say when that one takes place.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: But the BMO one was great.
Rym: So I'm actually really excited about this one.
Scott: The trailer for this one actually makes it look like it's going to be, I don't know, I want to say better, but like it goes harder.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: Like it starts with like Marceline and Bubblegum are definitely in a committed direct relationship.
Rym: Like they're not dancing around that like they had to in this one.
Scott: This one's good.
Scott: This one's going hard.
Scott: So if you're an Adventure Time fan, it's good news.
Rym: I mean, they're going to fight a dragon.
Rym: There's a very like direct narrative here.
Rym: The BMO one was very like interesting and told a story around the edges.
Rym: This one, I think, is just going to be a direct.
Rym: Marceline goes and fucks up this dragon via confronting trauma in some fashion.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: OK.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: So I'm going to continue my tradition of using non things that don't match the GeekNights' day for a thing of the day.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I found out about this like a while ago.
Scott: Actually, and it was just so interesting.
Scott: Apparently, people say that there are some authors and writers out there, prominent ones, most notably the Game of Thrones guy, although I don't know if you can call himself a writer because what has he written recently?
Scott: The R.R.
Scott: Martin, whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Old beard guy.
Scott: who do?
Scott: who still to this day do their writing, not with, you know, pen and paper.
Scott: They're not going that old school.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Not with Microsoft Word, like some new one, but specifically word perfect for DOS.
Scott: Where are or some sort of older word processor from that exact that brief period of time when word processors were still complex, you know, complex and fully featured there, you know, beyond text editors.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But not ridiculously full of features, which I guess around happened, maybe like maybe Microsoft Word.
Scott: ninety five, maybe was around the time where they really went like, you know, ridiculous with the word processor and cluttered it up with.
Rym: I remember working like writing documents in these early eras of word processing.
Rym: In fact, I remember writing an essay on an actual noncomputer, like a word processor where the screen was like four rows of base.
Scott: I tried to go look for like.
Scott: I tried to go look to see if anyone still made one of those or be if you could get old ones.
Rym: Someone I saw some people are making some modern ones, but they're running like Raspberry inside of or something.
Scott: Yeah, they're not actually, you know, anyway, the point is, is that, you know, do you?
Scott: actually it's a lot of hassle, right, to go do that.
Scott: We need an old DOS computer.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: so here is a project actually that, you know, it's called.
Scott: what's it called?
Scott: Word perfect for DOS updated, updated.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's a whole set of instructions whereby you can.
Scott: Get word perfect for DOS 5 1 6 6 1 or 6 2 to run on a modern computer, and they even have tools where you can like convert between Doc X format to word perfect format to get your files saved and loaded back and forth.
Scott: You can print you can you can get the clipboard will work.
Scott: You can copy and paste into it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can.
Scott: they have all this stuff working.
Scott: It's pretty impressive.
Scott: I didn't feel like going through the hassle of doing it.
Scott: But it really appeals to me in a strong way, not because I want to use specifically old as word perfect for DOS,
Rym: but
Scott: the though that exact time period, the word processors that came out then right were had like this exact feature set of, you know, having enough features that word type, you know, typing is, you know, lovely and pleasant and you're not like missing anything.
Scott: But there isn't a whole bunch of stuff like getting in the way.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Rym: I know personally, you know, I would argue those things don't get in the way of anyone with basic discipline, but maybe.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: I just know that psychologically speaking, right.
Scott: If I go to type something like, you know, I'm writing like, you know, essay long, a long form text of some kind.
Scott: If I do it in a text editor, that's no, you know, like Vim.
Scott: It's like that doesn't cut it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Vim doesn't, you know, format text and do it directly in LaTeX.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You can't do headers or anything.
Scott: You know, I could do it in LaTeX if it would, you know, but LaTeX only looks that way after you're done typing it, not while you're typing it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, you have to type some, you know, if you're using like Lex or something, you got to type in the weird language or whatever.
Scott: It's not that's not pleasant either.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if you're going to use like the newest, newest Microsoft Word.
Scott: Or even Google Docs, you got to try to type a long thing in Google Docs and it's actually not, you know, it sort of gets in the way a little bit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, you type in and you get this formatting and it's popping up with like spell checks and all, you know, it's like.
Rym: what fucking word do you have set up?
Rym: I don't have any of these problems.
Scott: Anyway, the point is, I'm just saying psychologically speaking, right, is, you know, there's less, you know, my mind is less focused on just the content of what I'm writing because it's being distracted in some way.
Rym: I know, I'm just giving you shit, partly because the person who made this website is definitely like you and like has particular, did you click on the link they have for, quote, the fact why some people use a DOS error word processor?
Scott: No, I did not.
Scott: I did not read that.
Scott: What does it say?
Rym: Oh, if you click on that, it says everything is explained here.
Rym: If you click on that, it takes you to the XKCD about how DOS is fine.
Rym: And that's it.
Rym: It's a very, but I guess what you're missing is that there are modern applications that are designed for things like I am writing a novel or an essay that are limited to the functions you would need that are useful for that specific purpose, like chapter outlines or plot outlines or citations.
Rym: There are, but otherwise minimal and focused on the content.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: The other thing is that just the aesthetic of, oh, I would argue with you on the aesthetic.
Rym: It's partly nostalgia.
Rym: Like we grew up through all these areas.
Rym: Like Scott, I literally grew up through like I wrote essays on a typewriter, mechanical, a mechanical one.
Rym: We play you could plug it in because it would automatically do character turns.
Rym: But otherwise, they're just a mechanical typewriter.
Rym: And every era of word processors we've used.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So like I wouldn't personally use this project, mostly because it's too much of a hassle to.
Rym: Also, did you read the fact at the bottom false positives from antivirus software?
Rym: Do not email me if you get if this says if if your antivirus tells you this is malware, use other software.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But I would really love for somebody to to like write a piece of software that was basically a clone of word.
Scott: perfect for DOS, except for Windows 10.
Rym: You know, it'd be fun.
Rym: Make it as a game instead of word processor.
Scott: What do you mean as a game?
Rym: You make the word to make you start an old word perfect and the game happens in there as you try to make a document.
Scott: Oh, so it's like you pull a frog fraction.
Rym: Yeah, you pull a frog fractions, but it stays with that aesthetic to the end.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So that, you know, if this interests you in any way.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you if you just imagine like, you know, if you're doing some writing and you think, man, it would be really nice to write it with, you know, a word processor a lot like an old word perfect.
Scott: Well, here's how you can.
Scott: here's how you can do it on your modern computer.
Scott: That's neat.
Rym: So I just did an anime thing.
Rym: I don't know how many of you have actually ever watched the old Speed Racer, like the like Speed Racer, but a couple episodes a long time ago.
Rym: Speed is kind of a gigantic dick like he is mean.
Rym: He is cruel.
Rym: The show is if you've never seen it, it's probably not what you think it is.
Rym: But one thing that really stands out in this video sort of encapsulates it is that speed kills.
Rym: a lot of people like with guns, like speed will just bust out a gun and murder a whole bunch of people that happen.
Scott: They're bad guys.
Scott: Yeah, there are bad guys.
Rym: He's killing, quote, bad guys.
Rym: There's other videos that highlight other horrible things.
Rym: Speed is done.
Rym: But I think this video really encapsulates like the mood of what Speed Racer is really like to watch it.
Rym: But it's a compilation just of him using guns, except one point where he murders someone with his car instead of with the gun.
Scott: And it's I mean, you know, Wacky Races is pretty similar, right?
Scott: In Wacky Races, you've got, you know, the bad guys, right?
Scott: And they're intentionally running people off the road.
Scott: But then it's like Yogi Bear, but he runs people off the road, too.
Rym: I would like I would watch a like modern reboot Rocky Wacky Races type thing.
Rym: Bonus points if you want to watch that.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, Metamoment, the biggest news we got because we don't have cons, there's no new panels to upload or anything, but we are or we did.
Rym: We published and officially activated the new GeekNights Community Code of Conduct.
Rym: I recommend you read it because if you're listening to this and you're interacting with us in any way, this code of conduct applies to you.
Rym: It will not be a problem for you unless you're a bad person.
Scott: If there is a digital or physical space in which we are organizing the community and so social activity, then this rule applies.
Scott: And if you do not abide by the rule, you will be evicted from the space to the best of our ability.
Scott: So you should read it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: If you think you are not a bad person, but you think that we should make some changes to this, it's in GitHub.
Rym: I know this is the Wednesday GeekNights, but trust me, GitHub is not that hard to use.
Rym: But you can submit changes to our code of conduct and we will review them.
Scott: And you could just also just contact us using any means of communication whatsoever to tell us what you think about it.
Scott: Positive, negative, change this, change that, you know, comment, whatever.
Scott: It's always subject to change.
Scott: It's not perfect.
Scott: So, yep.
Rym: And we'll continue to evolve it as time goes on.
Rym: But speaking of community, remember, we have a forum.
Rym: We have a legacy forum, like 12 years of like old posts from the old forum, which was really, really high volume compared to the new forum.
Rym: Partly because forums aren't as common anymore.
Rym: Like they're not as used as they used to be.
Rym: We got a Discord.
Rym: We got this YouTube stream right here.
Rym: There's a million, million places.
Rym: Actually, there's like seven places you can interact with us.
Rym: But we're in all those places.
Rym: Just find us.
Rym: Type GeekNights into whatever text box is in front of you.
Rym: And unless it's WordPerfect on MS-DOS, it'll probably take you to one of those places.
Scott: Yeah, we're on the Twitter, Facebook, freaking Spotify.
Rym: Don't contact us on Facebook, please.
Scott: No, but there is a page there.
Rym: It is technically still there.
Scott: Yeah, I posted on it once and was like, hey, does anyone see this?
Scott: And people saw it.
Scott: Yeah, I guess so.
Rym: And otherwise, the the GeekNights Book Club books, even the tale of Genji, I think I might just start reading it again every time I poop.
Rym: Oh, so watch out if I if I continue this trend for the rest of the week, then you're on notice.
Scott: I'll tell you.
Scott: I'll tell you what.
Scott: As soon as you read.
Scott: The first person, right, if you read a page of the tale of Genji that you have not read before or I read a page of it that I have not read before, immediately message the other person and say, I'm reading it right this second.
Scott: And that way, you know, whoever writes it, as soon as you receive the message, well, now you don't need to send because that's where we will know what I read.
Rym: What I read was I skimmed through what I had read already to remind myself where I was.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, you know, we will that we will know exactly who started reading again first.
Scott: And the other person will then have the hot, you know, the fire on the ass.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But you're on notice, the fire's not like, yeah, I've only done this twice.
Rym: That's two poops worth of reading.
Scott: The point is, if one of us finishes it and the other person is not yet finished or not even started continuing reading it, oh, then every time we get to them at a moment.
Scott: Right.
Scott: For example, if I finish it and you haven't and you haven't even started, I'm going to be like, I've finished the tale of Genji, but still hasn't read any since.
Scott: And that's going to be bad.
Rym: So shame is a powerful motivator.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So as soon as one of us starts, the other person has to also.
Rym: So, yeah, otherwise, let's go right into it.
Rym: Decadence will avoid for the beginning, at least spoiling anything about the show, but will spoil a little bit.
Scott: So that's very difficult.
Scott: But here, so we judge.
Scott: we judge this show for the Crunchyroll Expo.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know if that made the cut.
Rym: I think I might have edited out for time, like our review of the show at the time.
Scott: We said this looks like a proper noun laden, sort of, you know, tropey, very anime kind of anime.
Scott: That's I think that's what we said.
Scott: I don't remember clearly.
Rym: But I remember the result was, regardless of those details, that this show is probably fine, but probably not great.
Rym: This is a show that I will not watch unless there is buzz about it.
Rym: If other people are talking about it, then I will watch it to see what the drill is.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And that buzz.
Rym: Behold, there was buzz, buzz, like bit by bit, like one of our like.
Rym: someone on Twitter was like tweeted something that I follow, I follow them and they were like something something decadence.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: I was like, oh, all right.
Rym: Wasn't that the show we judge?
Rym: And then our friends use the Natalie over the other guy we're hanging out a few weeks ago and they were like, oh, if you watch Decadence yet, oh, I'm not even I won't say anything.
Rym: They refused to say anything about the show until I had seen two episodes.
Scott: OK, so Decadence is an anime and it's only 12 episodes long.
Scott: That's the whole damn show.
Rym: Yeah, I'm going to finish it.
Scott: So you can think of it as a four hour movie, which is actually not significantly longer than like, I don't know, Lawrence of Arabia.
Scott: It's like it's basically the same.
Scott: So you can just think of it as, you know, one thing that you're going to watch all at once or break it up into two parts, whatever.
Scott: It's really not long at all.
Rym: Yeah, I've only watched four episodes.
Rym: Scott's watched the whole thing.
Rym: But what I'll say is that I see why people were acting the way they were about this show, why everyone who mentioned it to me always said the same thing.
Rym: Oh, watch a bunch of it.
Rym: Then let's talk about it.
Rym: The show is not about what you think it's about.
Scott: Yeah, so it is a 12 episode show.
Scott: It does not appear to have been based on a manga of any kind.
Scott: It was directed by someone, Yuzuru Tachikawa, who I've never heard of.
Scott: They might have done something else.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It was done by Studio Nut.
Scott: I don't know what else they did.
Scott: And then it's a Funimation thing.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: They did storyboards on Arslan.
Scott: OK, the legal way to watch it in the United States would be on Funimation or Hulu and the illegal way would be to pirate it.
Scott: And those are the only ways you're going to see in the U.S.
Scott: right now.
Scott: I don't think it's on a DVD of any kind or a Booray.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think so either.
Rym: It wasn't on any platform that I had like easily set up.
Scott: So, yeah, I also don't know if it's dubbed.
Scott: I watched it subbed.
Rym: Yeah, I don't really watch dubbed anime.
Rym: No, you can't.
Rym: I just don't.
Scott: OK, so it's really hard to talk about the show without spoiling, because this show is heavily laden with anime tropes.
Scott: I'm going to list so many tropes that get to the point where I list all the tropes it has.
Scott: But one of the tropes it, of course, has is our favorite terrible secret of space where, you know, there is like all these questions constantly there in your face while these other things are happening and they're answering other questions.
Scott: But there's these big questions like what's really going on in the world?
Scott: How does this world darker than black?
Rym: What's outside that wall?
Rym: What's the key of the twilight?
Scott: Right.
Scott: The characters are in the dark about the what the truth of the world that they live in.
Scott: They don't understand the reality that they are under and neither do you.
Scott: But it will be revealed to you before it is to them.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Now, some shows the end of the show or at least the end of a season or like the middle episode of the show will be like, here is the answer to the terrible secret of space.
Rym: And if it's the end of the show, that's the plot or it happens in the middle.
Rym: And that sets the stage for the final arc of the show.
Rym: This show kind of reveals the secret, like so by the end of the first episode, you rims only seen four episodes, right?
Scott: So they reveal quite a large secret of space in episode like two, one that would have been sufficient.
Scott: That would be right.
Scott: One that would have been a normal anime show.
Scott: ending reveal of that's how the world really works.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there's only 12 episodes.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So they reveal like a bombshell in episode two and then they continue to bombshell.
Rym: By episode four, I had been hit with a second bombshell and Scott's already telling me before the show.
Rym: Oh, you haven't even read anything yet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, for example, in episode nine, I'm going to you know, in episode nine, they do a thing.
Scott: There is a climactic event, right, that occurs in episode nine.
Scott: that would normally be in another anime, the end of the show.
Scott: It is so climactic.
Scott: That's like, oh, well, Dave, Dave, that's got to be the end of the show, right?
Scott: There is three more episodes left.
Scott: That is a 12 episode show.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: Twenty five percent of the show remains after a climactic event that would end any other normal and like Evangelion, like the third impact.
Rym: Happens.
Rym: And then there's still five more episodes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the only way in a show such as this where literally you're getting, you know, anything you discuss whatsoever is going to spoil.
Scott: not, you know, tons.
Scott: I don't care about spoilers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Personally, but not going to spoil it for you because you're going to go watch this, I guess.
Scott: Yeah, I would only discuss the show in a non spoiler way if I only speak in generalities and nonspecifics.
Rym: Yeah, I guess we could.
Rym: at the very end, we'll see how we want to approach it.
Scott: The problem is, is I can't, you know, I have to.
Scott: if we go to spoiler territory, I got to let you take the lead.
Rym: Well, I guess I'll put it this way.
Rym: So when I start watching the show, it looks like a pretty standard anime.
Rym: I was getting some Fullmetal Alchemist vibes in terms of like the rough like level of quality, like what the characters are like, like it just felt like that kind of show.
Rym: And I was getting into it like if there had been no terrible secret or space at all, I think I would have been interested in the show anyway.
Rym: I might have actually kept watching.
Rym: So then at the end of the first episode, it like cuts to a scene that is really weird looking, like a very different style, and it doesn't explain anything in the episode ends.
Rym: And you're like, wait, wait, what?
Rym: What was that?
Rym: And then episode two backs up and explains what the deal is with that, which is already a bigger, terrible secret space than most anime will ever have.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Rym: And then it just keeps going from there.
Rym: And what I like is that the characters cross all these like these like weird demarcations of what the show looks like and is about.
Rym: And the characters are themselves pretty compelling and interesting.
Scott: Yeah, I'm trying to think of how we can explain the two styles and how significant they are to the show without spoiling it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So imagine you had an anime that took place on two planets.
Scott: It's not this, not this one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And one planet was drawn in an art deco style by one set of artists.
Scott: And the other the other planet was drawn in an art nouveau style.
Scott: Right.
Scott: A completely different art style.
Scott: Doesn't even match.
Scott: You think they're two different shows, but they're actually just two different places in the same show.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Two different sets of characters who live in the different places because they're two different alien races.
Scott: And they're just drawn completely differently.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like you hired, you know, you know, you know what, you hired Studio Ghibli to draw the first planet and you hired, you know, to draw the second.
Rym: Keklos.
Scott: Keklos does that.
Scott: Yeah, you're right.
Rym: The different the Spartans are drawn differently than the, you know, you've got the stop motion and Greek statues and then you've got the Yamashibai.
Rym: look in 2D like limited animation characters.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So that's what's going on in this show.
Scott: Is that there are two sets of characters kind of.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they're drawn in completely different art styles.
Scott: The main characters that you're going to start to see at the start of episode one are drawn in a sort of generic anime kind of way for 2020.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: They look good though.
Rym: Like they're good character designs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And these other characters are drawn like cute little cartoon characters.
Scott: They look like they're from like a kids show or something.
Scott: You know, they're very like.
Scott: they're toys that you would buy at like the kid robot store or something.
Scott: But they are.
Scott: it's almost like a Roger Rabbit only instead of live action plus cartoon.
Scott: It's cartoon plus different cartoon.
Scott: And they're, you know, together in the same story.
Scott: And it's kind of I think for a person who's not an animation person that just the visual contrast there, I don't think I think a non anime person that have a hard time just seeing past that.
Rym: Yeah, I could.
Rym: I could definitely see that.
Scott: I could see someone taking the shows and taking the show seriously, because like the story of the show, it's not a silly story.
Scott: It's a serious sci fi action.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like the like the opening scene like that set before you actually start watching the show almost feels like a scene out of like Jurassic Park.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: In terms of what goes down and why.
Scott: And then especially the kid robot style characters, if they are doing something very serious, but just the way they look, it's not like Oh, kaburagi that voice, the main dude's voice is a very good voice.
Scott: Yeah, it's not.
Scott: You'll notice there's a lot of voice actors in this.
Scott: You've heard before there's them, you know, in every studio trigger anime, there's usually like a really loud, like squeaky, small, usually female, you know, female character.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: It was like, you know, that character is that voice actor is also voicing a similar character in this show, even though it is not a studio trigger joint.
Scott: So, yeah, but yeah, seeing the characters with the not serious cartoony art style engaging in serious drama, I think will be a miss for a lot of people who are not anime animation people.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Also, because the character interactions like it actually has a surprisingly low anime attacks.
Rym: otherwise, like the characters are normal, like the characters interact in interesting ways.
Rym: The voice acting is really good.
Rym: There aren't like weird fan service bits.
Scott: Yeah, that's literally the.
Scott: I think the only thing that's an anime text is that.
Scott: OK, so the other thing about this show is that it is like I said before, it is laden with anime tropes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the first trope you see immediately is, of course, the trope of, you know, there are secrets in this world, precursors, you know, whatever.
Scott: Obviously, it's terrible secret to space.
Scott: There is this thing that has become popular.
Scott: I think Attack on Titan made it popular where you fight using some sort of backpack that has like a weapon attached to it.
Scott: There's been at least.
Rym: Yeah, there is a big Attack on Titan vibe when they're actually fighting with the big monsters outside of the city.
Rym: It's got the trope of we're in a we're in a ship or of some kind and it's us against the world with like a man center in the ship and like deploy like almost like a gundam kind of gundam.
Scott: Well, it's more like Macross, right, where the people live inside the giant robot.
Scott: that is enormous.
Scott: But the giant robot also transforms and fights and it has, you know, a bridge and it's it now has.
Rym: we have to change things because the the most powerful punch is one punch, man.
Rym: That doesn't count.
Rym: The most powerful punch, that's not one punch, man.
Scott: Up until this point had been the big oh, big oh, or I guess Mazinger also is a rocket punch.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I think, but the this is the.
Rym: this is the big oh, I imagine if the Macross ship did the big oh punch is what happens.
Rym: It does.
Rym: I imagine that because that's literally what happens.
Scott: The Macross ship has the the Daedalus attack because its right arm is actually just like is it a battleship or an aircraft carrier?
Scott: And it's called the Daedalus, right?
Scott: They attached it to the Macross.
Scott: It's not an alien ship like the Macross is.
Scott: And then it punches the alien ship right in the front and then they open the bay in the front of it and all the robots are just like launch all their missiles after they punch inside the hull of the enemy.
Scott: Anyway, Macross spoilers.
Rym: Yeah, there's a. there's a big fight where you start out like a gundam or Macross fight where there's like, you know, that trope where there's people in like a command center shouting orders like open the thing, do the thing, communicating with each other.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This show, OK, this show also has the trope of a Godzilla movie.
Scott: There's basically there's an episode where they're fighting a very large monster like Godzilla sized.
Scott: And you know how in a Godzilla movie, there's always that part where Godzilla is sleeping and you're waiting and then and then they're preparing and doing all this stuff and then wait for it to wake up again.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It is like there's an episode that's basically a Godzilla movie.
Scott: The episode.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, it's like I could probably keep going on with this more and more.
Scott: It's like you're going to see in this show basically so many other anime just like incorporated together.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, like these key pieces of just well trodden territory.
Scott: But then what they do to just, you know, to make this not just another anime is each and every one of those normal old anime things are a obviously combined into one show, which is interesting.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But B, like we said, with the constant, you know, pushing to the next terrible secret of space after the previous one and, you know, going further is they push each and every one of those troops like farther than you could have imagined it being possible to push them.
Scott: So it's like if I took a lemon and it's like everyone knows.
Scott: a lemon tastes like.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I squeeze it all out and you look at that lemon and you say that lemon is bone dry.
Scott: That's the Godzilla movie lemon.
Scott: We've seen everything we could see from a Godzilla movie.
Scott: There is nothing left to get from there.
Scott: And we know what it tastes like.
Scott: It tastes like lemon.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Decadence comes over and grabs this dry ass lemon rind and squeezes it.
Scott: And what comes out is still just more lemon juice.
Scott: It doesn't taste any different.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But like a whole extra glass of lemon juice comes out and you're like, what the fuck?
Scott: How did you get?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like that guy slapping the hood of the car.
Scott: I can fit X whatever here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like somehow they've taken this old hat trope.
Scott: Of normal old anime stuff, stuff you've seen before, stuff you know so well and they haven't changed the way it tastes.
Scott: It's the same old anime.
Scott: They just got more out of it.
Scott: And it's like, oh, wow.
Scott: Look at that.
Scott: How did you do that?
Rym: In fact, you know, another thing it does.
Rym: that I appreciate, because Big O did this sort of retroactively, all the little detail, like background details, like really minor stuff.
Rym: Utena did this too.
Rym: Anime looking things that you might just ignore in a show like, oh, they just drew that thing that way because it's anime that seems to always end up mattering.
Rym: specifically.
Rym: Like there's a scene in the very beginning where the girl is like, I want to I want to be a fighter out fighting the Godalls like those people over there.
Rym: And you see those people and they have like radically different colored skin for everyone else.
Rym: And they're like like neon hair and they just kind of look crazy.
Rym: And the explanation you're given is that, oh, they're part of this warrior case, like they're a different type of person.
Rym: And it is true that they're a different type of person.
Rym: But that is a spoiler.
Rym: But that detail is just like two seconds of screen time.
Scott: Well, at least at that point in the show, I can definitely tell you that is as someone who's seen the whole show, I can tell you there is I mean, other than, you know, your suspension of disbelief because you're watching a fictional anime and a fantasy sci-fi world.
Scott: Other than that, it is extremely tight on terms of plot holes and every single thing you see matters and make sense.
Rym: I really appreciate that in a show.
Scott: And there are.
Scott: no there's not a lot of loose thread hanging at the end.
Rym: I was not left at the end with any questions of like, hey, what about the something something like at the end of Fullmetal Alchemist, the original show, we were like, all right, so now what the fuck?
Rym: You didn't answer like any of my questions.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That will not happen with this show.
Scott: The the negative thing I can say about this show is that being 12 episodes, it's good.
Scott: It moves right along.
Scott: It moves maybe.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It doesn't feel like it's going too fast.
Scott: It's just like steadily hitting really hard constantly.
Scott: But the characters, other than the two most main characters, all of the other characters are not given a lot of time and or development.
Scott: Ones that get time early, get almost no time late.
Scott: Ones that get time late are not given time early.
Scott: So it kind of changes over the show, which characters are getting more time and all the characters, other than the main ones, basically have like one thread that's theirs is very shallow and is, you know, resolved.
Scott: But it's like, you know, I guess in episode one, it's like the main character, the girl has like a friend in school or like it's orphanage school.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so that's a side character, that school friend from episode one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That school friend from episode one, you see briefly a few times when they interact a few seconds here and there.
Scott: And then the plot with that character is wrapped up in a couple scenes of drama.
Scott: And then that's pretty much it.
Scott: It's and you get pretty much that amount of stuff from each character.
Rym: Which is a shame because, you know, going back to the sort of Full Metal Alchemist energy, what I like about that show was that the side characters were all great and got a lot of screen time.
Scott: And you start to like, well, I had more episodes and more manga pages to work with right here.
Scott: Each each side character is very one note.
Scott: Like, here's their deal, their deal, you know, the first one.
Rym: Yeah, they.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: Here's their deal.
Scott: They get a scene maybe right where you you write to maybe show you who they are.
Scott: And then at some point their deal gets sort of resolved.
Scott: And any other time you see them, if they do get more screen time, they're just sort of being who they are.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So like loud guy who likes to fight.
Scott: It's like, yeah, he's got a scene that wraps up his shit.
Scott: He's got an introduction scene and every other scene he's in, which is quite a few.
Scott: He's just being a loud guy who likes to fight.
Scott: You know, he is not developing or have any, you know, interesting things going on.
Scott: And there's several characters other than the two main ones.
Scott: But all of the other ones just sort of follow that thing.
Scott: This is a show that is not about.
Scott: at least it's about the two main characters and it's about the plot of the world.
Scott: It's not about the other characters.
Scott: They're just sort of filling in, you know, where characters are needed.
Rym: Yeah, which is fine, because what I've seen so far, the world is plenty of meat.
Rym: It's like a Thanksgiving buffet where I can't eat everything.
Rym: It would be too much if it had everything, unless it was just longer.
Rym: But then it might not hit as hard in terms of the density of the terrible secrets.
Scott: Yeah, I think if you made this as the thing is like the show is weird and that if you made it longer, you could give respect to those other characters, some of which could become really interesting and awesome characters if you did like having like just an episode where the main plot doesn't advance.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But they go fighting some bad guys or something and you spend that time, you know, developing or learning about some of these other characters in the show.
Scott: But by having every episode be a heavy plot episode.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It moves along in a different way.
Rym: Well, you know, look at Attack on Titan is a good example of that, because that's the opposite of this in that it really, really, really focuses on the characters and like them doesn't move along.
Rym: And the terrible secrets of space come like once every season.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: So, yeah, I think that's the balance that they struck here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I think if it wasn't 12 episodes, I don't think I want to watch the whole thing, you know.
Rym: Unless imagine if it was just 12 more episodes of continuing secrets of space somehow.
Scott: That I don't think that could happen.
Scott: You could do more episodes, but I don't think it ends pretty solidly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: At least.
Scott: I think if you wanted to continue this, I guess this isn't spoilers, you would have to go to a far away place in the same universe.
Scott: You could not really do much more writing in the same characters, same place.
Scott: After the end of the show, you have to go to like, you know, another side of another planet, another galaxy, something, you know, something else.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Anyway, so what would I say about the show as a whole?
Scott: I don't think it's actually like an A anime.
Rym: Yeah, I wasn't feeling that even from the beginning because I've seen some A anime recently.
Scott: Yeah, my feeling is like this is a B plus anime, but because it has unique qualities and because it is so short, only four hours long for the whole series, that I think it's actually worth, if you're an anime fan, right, an anime person, there's a lot, you know, if you've already seen the top tier animes, you got four hours to do nothing.
Scott: You're stuck at home all the time.
Scott: Why not watch this?
Scott: It's perfectly enjoyable.
Scott: I don't regret spending four hours on it.
Rym: B plus is the level of like a scrapped princess.
Scott: Like pretty good show.
Scott: Like this is better than Scrap Princess for sure.
Rym: You didn't even watch all the Scrap Princess.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: How far did you even get into Scrap Princess?
Scott: A four or five episode.
Scott: I don't remember it that well.
Scott: The point is, you know, this is a show that's well worth watching.
Scott: It will not become a legendary anime of all time.
Rym: I feel like we might talk about it in a panel someday on the terrible secret of space or like the mid-season.
Scott: I think it has.
Scott: I think it has a lot of.
Scott: I don't think it has the kind of staying power where it's going to be a show that is like must watch like everyone's putting it on their lists.
Scott: But I think it's a show that will sort of, you know, it will come it will come back up.
Scott: People in discussions.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It will have some relevance and be brought back up.
Scott: And someone who's you know, if any if you're into anime any deeper than you just watch Akira and Ghost in the Shell and Miyazaki movies, if you're on the next level where you're like an anime fan, this show should be one that you that you watch.
Rym: Yeah, absolutely.
Rym: I'm going to.
Rym: I'm definitely going to finish it.
Scott: And because it's it's you know, it's kind of hard to surprise an anime fan who's seen many animes, right?
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I'd like kill la kill at that point.
Rym: I'm even like, all right, nothing really surprised me here.
Rym: I'm just into this.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So you got four hours decadence, you know, enjoy.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the GeekNights Patreon patrons are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Green, Graham Finch, you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: I pulled up to the house about seven or eight Clinton Walton, Redfield, Ryan Perrin, Chris Mink of Dread, Lily Tenebrae, just like a dude guy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin Von Harlan, a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: But now on this Wednesday, where very little happens to us in these covid times, no one's tried to fight me since this weekend.
Rym: So we'll see the next time someone fights me and I have something fun to talk about.
Rym: But anyway, now I leave you with...
Scott: Wake up, wake up, wake up.