Rym: It's Thursday, April 9th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about chili, the food, coming to you live from our remote quarantine pipeline studios.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, the funniest thing about this quarantine for me, like, just the fact that we're not going out and everything's shut down, is that I'm not eating out.
Rym: Like, I now realize- How much fucking money I spent eating out on, like, a monthly basis.
Scott: Yeah, you spent a ton, especially on booze every time you ate out.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But also, I'm finding that because we're cooking, we're cooking much healthier food than I normally eat in my, like, day-to-day life.
Scott: I'm like, I don't know if I'm cooking healthier or not.
Scott: Yeah, we're definitely cooking healthy, and- I think part of it is that the cooking is perfectly normal and healthy, but the baking, right?
Scott: It's like, "Oh, I can just bake a banana bread, and then I'll bake
Scott: it.".
Rym: We kind of had the revelation of, "Why don't we just start baking a shit ton of
Rym: cookies?".
Scott: Yup.
Rym: We even got a bunch of craisins left over that we can use to make, like, craisin shortbread cookies and everything.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: But because I'm not eating, like, snacks and garbage when I'm out, and we're not eating out all the time, and I'm still, like, exercising like normal, I've lost three pounds since this started.
Scott: I don't know if I've lost any.
Scott: I guess because I'm not exercising, because basically it's, like, the time that I would exercise, like, say, commuting to work, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Instead of, you know, being like, "Well, I have all this free time now.
Scott: Let's, uh, you know, let's go for a bike ride before or after work," right?
Scott: I mean, I would like to do that.
Scott: The problem is, you know, A, weather, but, you know, weather's been okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Is that that time has been spent just waking up later.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: No, I literally-- I just wake up at-- I used to wake up at seven.
Scott: Now I'm waking up at, like, nine to ten.
Rym: Every night I look at my, uh, work calendar-- I don't set an alarm anymore.
Scott: I just wake up whenever the hell.
Rym: Every night I look at my work calendar to figure out when my first meeting is, and I wake up eleven minutes before that meeting.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So it's, like, that's the time.
Scott: And the thing is, you know, my building has a little gym in it, uh, and I was actually literally finally about to use it.
Scott: Like, "Well, I'm trapped inside.
Scott: I might as well actually use this gym that I would never otherwise use," right?
Scott: And I was about to go use it, and they closed it.
Rym: That sucks.
Rym: They're keeping ours open, but our building only has, like, 150 apartments, so there aren't that many people who would use it.
Rym: And they have rules about, like, there's two treadmills, only one person can be on either of them at any given time, and all that stuff.
Scott: I'm just saying, just as I was like, "Alright, I find that I'll use this damn gym, Miigaw, because I'm trapped inside.
Scott: I would never otherwise use a gym if it wasn't such an extraordinary
Scott: circumstance.".
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Okay, we'll close that gym right before we use it, and it's like,
Scott: "Pah!".
Rym: I mean, look, I'm a crazy runner.
Scott: Like, I exercise-- There's a sauna in there.
Scott: I could be in that sauna, like, as soon as my work is over.
Rym: I, uh, like, crazy run, but I hate running on treadmills.
Rym: I hate it to a degree that is palpable.
Rym: But, what else am I gonna do in the winter?
Rym: Like, it's either that or nothing.
Scott: But yeah, they closed it, so.
Rym: Yup, that sucks.
Rym: It's getting warm out, though.
Scott: It's gonna be sunny-- It's like, the governor ordered gyms to be closed, so we're closing it, and I'm like,
Scott: "Okay.".
Rym: Uh, so technically, as far as I know, the governor only ordered, like, public gyms to be closed.
Scott: I'm aware of that, but that's not what, you know, the building did.
Scott: what the building's gonna do.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Our building's different for now, but we'll see.
Rym: Hopefully they don't close it on me, 'cause that's-- The one thing I got rid of when we moved to this building 11 years ago is I got rid of all my weights, because there's weights down there.
Rym: Now I don't have any weights.
Scott: The only way to do weightlifting-- When I moved here, I got rid of my-- I got rid of-- It was kind of broken.
Scott: I mean, it wasn't broken.
Scott: It worked, but it wasn't, uh, great.
Scott: The thing where I could ride my actual bike in place.
Rym: Yup, yup.
Scott: And, uh, yeah, good luck buying one of those now.
Rym: Oh, God, right?
Rym: I wanted to buy-- I thought about buying new free weights, just, like, during this crisis.
Rym: Yeah, they are gone everywhere.
Rym: Those are impossible to get.
Rym: I should just try to buy something heavy, like two buckets, and just start using that.
Scott: Right, even if I were to buy one of the fancy ones that goes with my bike computer, right?
Scott: Like the, uh, it's like, okay, are these in stock anywhere?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: They're a thousand dollars anyway, right?
Rym: It's like-- Yeah, I found the thing-- the crazy expensive versions of a lot of these things are still in stock, but even now, I don't really-- Ooh, the certified reconditioned ones.
Rym: Ooh.
Scott: But they're still a fortune.
Rym: Yeah, that's a problem.
Rym: Even outside of a crisis, things like that are a fortune.
Rym: There's a lot of things.
Rym: I thought, oh, maybe now's the time to buy, but then I look at the price, and I'm like, you know what?
Rym: Even-- I think I can still wait.
Rym: I think I can still hold out.
Scott: Yeah, $1,200.
Scott: It's like, yeah, I could just buy another bicycle.
Rym: So what do you got news-wise on this lounge episode of GeekNights?
Scott: Sure, it's sort of thing of the day adjacent, but it's also news adjacent, right?
Scott: The date on this is what?
Scott: April 8th.
Scott: Yeah, this is from yesterday.
Scott: So sometime on Wednesday, which I guess, you know, today's Thursday.
Scott: Is that Wednesday for astronaut's time?
Scott: Oh, okay, never mind.
Scott: It was sometime yesterday.
Scott: There's some space action going on, right?
Scott: Oh, no, the launch is Thursday at 1.05 local time.
Scott: Oh, did the launch happen already?
Scott: Anyway, Russians launch in a rocket to send some Americans and two Russians into space, right?
Scott: Like you do.
Scott: So they were in quarantine, which you do when you're an astronaut anyway.
Scott: It's not an unusual circumstance.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I'm sure they did not bring coronavirus into space.
Rym: Yep, that's part of what being an astronaut or a cosmonaut is.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure they didn't do that, but there's a story here about.
Scott: apparently when you go to space in Russia at Baikonur, I never knew how to pronounce that name of that place.
Rym: Don't even, Cyrillic, I can't read at all.
Scott: It's the place of the, it's basically the Cape Canaveral of Russia.
Scott: If you've never heard of it before, that's like their place, right?
Scott: Where they launch all their rockets.
Rym: Yeah, in Kazakhstan.
Scott: Yeah, whenever you launch from there, apparently it's mandatory that the day before launch when you're in the cosmonaut quarantine hotel, you must watch this movie like they make you watch it.
Rym: That's kind of amazing.
Scott: Right, it's mandatory.
Scott: It's always the same movie.
Scott: It's an old Soviet film from the 70s called White Sun of the Desert.
Rym: Oh, I want to see this now.
Rym: Is this like the Soviet one?
Scott: This is my news.
Scott: It's on YouTube with subtitles.
Rym: Is this like the Soviet Lawrence of Arabia?
Scott: It looks like Lawrence, I thought that the movie was Lawrence of Arabia, but apparently it's not.
Scott: It's White Sun of the Desert.
Scott: It's a, um, but yeah, I am freaking watching this movie as soon as I get the chance.
Scott: It's on YouTube for free with subtitles.
Rym: Hey, there's our next Thursday show.
Rym: Next Thursday, we're going to review this movie.
Scott: White Sun of the Desert, two weeks from now, everybody.
Rym: GeekNights Movie Club, let's go.
Scott: I don't think it's actually going to be that good.
Rym: Yeah, but looking at these stills, it looks like the kind of movie that I will enjoy.
Scott: Oh yeah, but, you know.
Rym: I like, like, a really long, extremely dated, like, drama piece.
Scott: Anyway, uh, here's a movie for you.
Rym: Oh, it's got some Western action.
Scott: And then after you finish watching it, you'll be cleared to go on the Soyuz.
Rym: The guy with the bolt-action rifle, like, firing from under his horse.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I love that shit.
Rym: I've been off and on on a Western kick over the last few years, but I've kind of run out of Westerns to watch.
Rym: So I've got to dig deeper into, like, older, weirder stuff.
Rym: So, uh, my news, if you don't know, Fark is a website, F-A-R-K dot com.
Rym: But the best way to describe Fark is it is Internet 2.0. before Internet 2.0 was really a thing.
Scott: And it hasn't changed, so it's like going into the past of the Internet, but there's still people there?
Rym: Like, you know that thing, and the reason I'm bringing this up, the reason I think this is newsworthy, is not, like, I like Fark, but it's not just because I like Fark.
Rym: And I think Fark is actually moderately important, but I think it's important in a lot of the same ways that, like, something awful was important.
Rym: Or even 4chan in the early days was important, that it was kind of foundational to how the Internet culture formed.
Scott: Yeah, good, important being separate from good or bad.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: There are a lot of important things that are not good, and a lot of good things that are not important.
Rym: That is a lesson you need to learn in life.
Rym: But Fark, for a lot of reasons, was and is to a degree still important.
Rym: But the deal with Fark is that there was nothing like it.
Rym: And when it came out, it was sort of like a revolutionary idea of how to do a community online, centered around news and current events.
Rym: And somehow, while Reddit and 4chan and something awful and YouTube and all these other places descended into- Well, Slashdot was very Fark-esque.
Rym: Oh yeah, Slashdot was too.
Scott: I'm pretty sure Slashdot was older.
Rym: But Slashdot is also in the category.
Scott: And then there were many, many sites that tried to do the same thing, like Dig and whatnot.
Scott: Fark is older than Dig, obviously.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Remember Memepool?
Scott: Right, right, exactly.
Scott: Well, Memepool was a little slower, and I think it was one person?
Rym: Yeah, Memepool was a blast from the past.
Rym: That was a product of its era.
Scott: But it basically is these sites that would be aggregators of news that were manual aggregation to a large extent, but not editorial.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And also somewhat crowdsourced the aggregation, but not to the extent where, say, Reddit does.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Where it's completely automated, right?
Rym: But distinct and, in many cases, overlapping communities.
Rym: But just to look at Slashdot versus Fark as an example, Slashdot, as the decades went on, has become increasingly old, embittered, MRA, white, shitty, Nazi shitbags.
Rym: The people who use Slashdot are awful people today.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, it's the worst old white guys in tech culture, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And everyone else in the tech scene who was checking Slashdot, because that was the tech news site of the day, has left, and those are the only people who are still there are the ones who are old bad white guys.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But Fark is unique in that that never happened to Fark.
Rym: Fark has younger people and older people using it.
Rym: In terms of online communities that are centered on broad topics and just topical news, look at any generic Reddit and it's a goddamn shit show.
Rym: The only good Reddits are the hyper-specific ones, or the ones that have very communities around a particular thing.
Rym: But Fark is one of the broader large internet communities, and it's kind of amazing how much of a local culture it has in an era when there really aren't that many websites anymore.
Scott: Well, I think it's simultaneously broad, but also not.
Rym: Yeah, it's like a niche.
Rym: take on people who are interested in policy and pay attention to weird news.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Fark is about the news, which is huge.
Scott: Like, any news goes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the kind of news that Fark actually cares about is actually a specific subset of news.
Scott: It just looks broad because that slice slices across the whole watermelon.
Rym: Like, you think Florida Man.
Rym: Florida Man, like, that meme partly came directly from Fark, but Fark is where you see the Florida Man of the entire Earth.
Scott: Right, so for example, right, on Fark, Fark will very, very much enjoy news about injustice, right?
Scott: But you'll see news about injustice from every country, every place, every kind of injustice.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right?
Scott: You know, it enjoys a wacky news, right?
Scott: Something that's, you know, a man eaten by, you know, a tiger bites a dude's foot off in a submarine or something.
Scott: Something crazy, right?
Scott: It's like, but it'll do crazy things from everywhere.
Scott: So it's really, Fark likes a few specific things.
Scott: It also just posts the biggest news story of the day.
Rym: But that's another thing is it's like this community and it's just like all fun and games.
Rym: And it hasn't descended into Nazi hellhole like a lot of other communities have due to a really robust system of moderation that a lot like.
Rym: I'm really kind of amazed at how relatively civil the conversations are in Fark to this day compared to almost any other broad community on the Internet.
Scott: Well, I think that's because, you know, Fark is sort of like, you know, all the other ones have some, a greater idea of like openness.
Scott: Whereas Fark is more along the lines of a Craigslist, right?
Scott: It's owned by one guy.
Rym: He just gets to say, he can just be like, no Nazis.
Scott: Because Craigslist is owned by Craig, Fark is owned by this Drew guy.
Rym: Yep, Drew Curtis.
Scott: It's just owned by a guy.
Scott: They run it right there in charge of it.
Scott: You can comment there, you can post content there, but it's run by the guy.
Scott: There's not, there isn't this expectation of, you know, culturally and in the community wise, there isn't this feeling of, you know, I have rights to post here, right?
Rym: They will ban people if they need to be banned.
Rym: And the other thing is Fark was actually really ahead of most of the rest of the Internet in terms of community safety tools like blocking and shadow banning and automated moderation.
Rym: Like Fark really pushed the envelope in a lot of this stuff.
Scott: Well, because unlike the other places, say like Reddit, right?
Scott: They're outsourcing that stuff to the, you know, to the community.
Scott: Like here at Reddit, you start your own subreddit and moderate it, right?
Scott: Slashdot is like, hey everyone, up and down vote stuff to moderate and report for us.
Scott: We don't want to, right?
Scott: Whereas Fark is doing it themselves and when you have to do something yourself with your own company and your own money, you build tooling.
Rym: Yep, and you also by having a strong community.
Scott: There's less motivation to build tooling when someone else is doing the work for free.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So I read Fark.
Rym: I've read Fark for like more than 20 years.
Scott: Your whole life?
Rym: Pretty much my whole adult life I've been reading Fark daily and like I like this community.
Rym: I like the people in it.
Rym: I don't like all the people in it, but whenever I encounter a shitty person, I use those tools that still exist and they disappear forever and I just never see them again.
Rym: But Fark is in trouble because the reason why we keep saying things like, you know, that common theme, there used to be more websites.
Rym: Independent websites like CollegeHumor, like places where people would like make a community to make content have been vanishing for all the late capitalism reasons.
Rym: we talk about a lot on GeekNights.
Scott: Well yeah, because if you're getting your aggregated stuff through a Twitter feed or a Facebook feed or any of those other Instagram, right?
Scott: When you are in those places, you're largely staying in those places.
Scott: Those do a lot of embedded content.
Scott: You have a Twitter thread rather than a Twitter with a link to a blog post, right?
Scott: Things like that, whereas Fark, since it hasn't changed, is still almost all the posts on there are, you know, even on Reddit, it's like you go to a subreddit.
Scott: Yeah, some of the stuff is a link somewhere, but a lot of the posts on Reddit are.
Scott: I uploaded a video to the Reddit.
Scott: I uploaded the image to the Reddit.
Scott: I wrote a text post on the Reddit.
Scott: That's the post, right?
Scott: Whereas on Fark, everything is a link usually to some local newspaper or local TV station.
Rym: Fark actually is a significant source of how people find real news, especially during a crisis.
Rym: I remember during on 9/11 or during the hurricane in Louisiana and all that, Fark was in some cases hours ahead of the regular news media because Fark is a wide community, so there are people who are on the scene of fucking anything that happens around the world.
Rym: I see stuff on Fark sometimes before I see it on like a Bloomberg terminal.
Rym: It's kind of amazing.
Scott: And also, there's a lot of people who use Fark and don't credit it appropriately.
Scott: I remember when I was in college and I would do a short drive from, you know, our apartment to the one parking lot I was allowed to park in.
Scott: I would sometimes, you know, in those days, we didn't have podcasts, so I would still have to listen to local radio guy.
Scott: And I could tell, 100% guaranteed, no question, there was no doubt in my mind, local radio guy, literally, he might not have even known that he was doing this because his writer or his producer was doing it, but basically getting stories from Fark, probably printing them out and handing them to him.
Scott: And then that's what they would discuss on the show is they would go through the wacky stories on Fark like, "Hey, did you hear a Florida man did this?
Scott: Hey, did
Scott: you?"
Scott: Right?
Scott: And I was like, "Those are all the headlines on Fark right now.
Scott: Open up Fark.
Scott: He's literally going down from the
Scott: bottom.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: There are still lots of people out there producing other content in that exact same way.
Scott: There are definitely still local radio, zoo shows that are just going down Fark.
Rym: So why am I talking about Fark so much?
Scott: Because their listeners don't know Fark.
Rym: Partly because I'm old and the Fark demographic is definitely a little older.
Rym: When it comes to politics, people seem to know more in there than the general population.
Scott: Fark is not doing great at getting new people because it's such an old thing.
Scott: Not like it's advertising.
Rym: But it does still grow.
Rym: There are people younger than me there.
Rym: More of them than you would expect.
Rym: The reason I'm talking about Fark is that somehow Fark has survived so long and they're on the verge of failing now between the virus and ad revenue dropping and subscriber numbers dropping for a lot of reasons.
Rym: Fark is actually running out of money and might have to shut down by the end of the year.
Scott: I don't understand why you could just cut back.
Scott: It's so cheap to run.
Rym: I think there's a bunch of plans.
Rym: This is kind of new news.
Scott: I don't see why you'd ever have to shut it down.
Rym: It uses a terrifying amount of bandwidth, for one.
Rym: And our support staff that have to keep it all running.
Rym: It also has developers because it's a little janky and needs people to continuously update and fix things that are broken with it.
Scott: If it's so old and it's been developed for so long, wouldn't it be just fine?
Rym: It's got some issues.
Rym: You can read some of the details.
Rym: I don't want to take the whole show and make it the Fark show.
Rym: But basically, you know, GeekNights has the newsletter.
Rym: That's just whenever Scott feels like it, he writes the newsletter.
Rym: Drew Curtis has been doing that in Fark for a long time.
Rym: I just get this email from Drew Curtis every now and then that just talks about, "Hey, here's the deal with Fark," or "Here's what I'm thinking today," or whatever.
Rym: And he's explaining that.
Rym: here's all the reasons why we're in trouble.
Rym: A website like this is very hard to continue to run in the modern world.
Rym: One of the dangers is litigation risk.
Rym: Sites like that get sued all the time.
Scott: Mmm.
Scott: Doesn't he have insurance of some kind?
Scott: Oh yeah, but-- We just talked about that, don't you?
Rym: Basically, if you are someone who has never used Fark before, I recommend just going and poking at it.
Rym: It might not be for you.
Rym: I'm not saying you should use Fark, but just go look at it.
Scott: Because if nothing else-- You're probably benefiting from Fark indirectly without knowing it.
Rym: But it's also a time capsule into a different kind of internet.
Rym: It is a lot like what the internet was like in the early to mid-2000s.
Scott: I think you'll be surprised if you do go to Fark that you'll go there, read it, and like an hour or two later, you'll see a lot of the things that were on there appearing on your Twitter feed.
Scott: Like, "Oh, what?
Scott: I already read this somewhere.
Scott: Where did I see
Scott: this?".
Rym: But there's basically the other thing that I just want to point out.
Rym: If you read Fark and like Fark, what I would recommend, much like with important news sites, they have a subscription service that does give you a bunch of stuff.
Scott: I thought they had two.
Rym: Well, they have one that removes ads, but ad blockers work.
Rym: They've never stopped ad blockers from working because they're not evil, they know.
Rym: But two, you can pay for total Fark.
Scott: It's not that expensive.
Rym: I'm paying for it now.
Scott: You could pay for it because you want to pay for Fark.
Rym: But don't use it.
Rym: If you use it, it's like serotonin straight into--.
Scott: The thing that they give you that you're paying for is not a thing you want.
Rym: It's a thing that you want if you work in a job where there is no actual work and you're literally just sitting at a desk reading Fark all day.
Rym: That is the kind of person who pays for total Fark and uses it.
Rym: But if you use Fark at all, that is a way to give them money.
Rym: And if they get enough subscribers, they can probably continue to run for a long time to come without getting bought out, shutting down, or having to make the kinds of compromises that sites like Slashdot have made that have turned them into hell holes.
Rym: So I care a lot about Fark, so I'm just putting this out there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Rym is basically Fark the person.
Scott: If you read a lot of Fark, you'll turn into a Rym.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Fark.
Rym: Poop Report.
Rym: Not that I've read Poop Report in a decade, but... But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So check this out.
Rym: There's a video in this tweet.
Rym: It's from South Korea.
Rym: I haven't researched this or looked into the deal with it yet, but it's a highway.
Rym: And in the middle of the highway--.
Scott: Oh, I've seen this.
Scott: It's real.
Rym: There's a median.
Rym: And in the US, when there's a median in a highway, it's just grass, usually.
Rym: But this highway in the middle is a really good, really wide bike lane.
Rym: But that's not notable because Australia has stuff like that.
Rym: You can just ride.
Scott: The ones we saw in person in Australia were on the side of the highway.
Rym: Yeah, they are in the middle in some cases.
Rym: I've driven a lot more in Australia than you because I've been there.
Scott: You saw middle ones?
Rym: Yeah, I saw middle ones, too.
Rym: God, I've been to Australia a lot of times now that I'm thinking back.
Rym: But anyway, so here's one in South Korea.
Rym: But the cool part about this is that the bike lane is in the middle.
Rym: It's aimed at commuters and long-distance cyclists.
Rym: The entire thing is covered, protecting you from the rain and the wind.
Rym: And you're completely isolated from traffic because the roof is just miles and miles and miles and miles of solar panels.
Rym: Holy shit is this awesome.
Rym: This is what the United States needs.
Rym: I'm so sick of this fucking country.
Scott: That's my thing of the day.
Scott: Other countries do smart, basic ideas, and the US doesn't do anything.
Scott: We're no longer a country that does the best stuff.
Scott: we haven't been for quite a while, and people are just seeing it more and more every day.
Scott: They're like, "Yeah, the United States is not great at stuff because you kept electing people who don't spend money to make nice
Scott: things.".
Rym: And now, over the last three months, we've moved from being just kind of a shitty, falling-behind country to actively harming the rest of the world.
Rym: More so than when we overthrew peaceful socialist governments to replace them with dictators in the '70s, but I digress.
Scott: I mean, we had stuff, right?
Scott: We didn't pay to take care of the stuff, so we had a real fragile thing, and now a pandemic came along and broke it.
Scott: So now it's like, before, we had stuff that was just fragile and shitty.
Scott: Now our stuff's broken.
Rym: Well, what made America so powerful?
Rym: Much of the rest of the industrialized world got bombed that one time when we didn't get bombed, and we were just there, ready to profit from it.
Rym: That's the main reason the US was so prosperous for so long.
Scott: Pretty much, yeah.
Scott: So what do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: So hot!
Scott: Yeah, so hot.
Scott: So I posted this in our forum, which you should join.
Scott: But since there's a coronavirus going on in South Korea, which Rym just mentioned is all smart, at least smarter than other places with regards to that, they were shutting things down.
Scott: The K-pop scene was shutting down way before anything was going on in the US, like several weeks before we did anything.
Scott: I was at PAX East, and there were K-pop groups performing their songs to empty rooms because they were like, "Nope, no more crowds.
Scott: GG.".
Scott: That's it.
Scott: So if you don't know, K-pop people, one of their things that they do really well is they post lots and lots of video content constantly to keep their fans well-fed and give them all kinds of things constantly.
Scott: As opposed to, say, J-pop, where if you're not in Japan, you're getting something never, and you have to pay for it.
Scott: So they're running out of stuff to post, obviously, because everyone's locked in somewhere, usually not with video equipment or video editors.
Scott: So here on the JYP channel, they reposted an old video that I'd seen before, but the one that I saw before was not as complete and was not as good quality as this.
Scott: So what this is, a video of the person, the JYP, who's an interesting person if you look him up.
Scott: He's written many hit songs over the years, and one of the hit songs he wrote, one of the biggest hits was "So Hot" for the Wonder Girls, the song he wrote.
Scott: And in this video, he shows you exactly how he made that song.
Scott: He's only like two to four measures of the song, like the main part of the song.
Scott: He shows you exactly how he made it piece by piece, instrument by instrument.
Scott: And it's only a small part of the song, but basically, that's the song.
Scott: The song is that over and over with a little bit of this and that.
Rym: You know what it's like?
Rym: It's like, what's a 2Mix song?
Rym: There's a duh duh duh duh duh duh duh duh duh, then just repeat that forever.
Scott: Right, but it's fascinating, I think, to someone who is, if you're not a songwriter, you're thinking, "Okay, I understand conceptually how you write the song, but really, how do you write a
Scott: song?".
Scott: Like, how?
Scott: Right?
Scott: After you watch this, you will never ask that question again.
Scott: You will say, "Oh, that's how you write a song,".
Scott: and then you'll hear him do a little bit of the ways into it.
Scott: You'll be like, "I can do this.
Scott: I could be a
Scott: songwriter.".
Scott: And then you'll be like, "No, I
Scott: can't.".
Rym: One thing I love is seeing different artists process for writing songs, because it's all over the place.
Rym: Writing a symphony is very different from writing a pop song.
Scott: Well, yeah, this is the pop song process.
Scott: And it's also great to see in this video, because he's got a Power Mac over there on the side or something.
Scott: Oh, wow, yeah.
Scott: This is from, like, you know, 2000... I guess the song came out in 2000?
Rym: Oh, look at all those synth boxes.
Scott: Yeah, the song is 10 or 11 years old, maybe, I think.
Scott: It's at least 10 years old.
Scott: And then he must have made this video after the song became a hit, so this is probably a 10-ish year old video?
Rym: Oh, I see both the audio and the MIDI cables coming out of that keyboard.
Scott: Yeah, he's basically just got, like, an old Mac, probably a Power PC Mac, I'm imagining, and a big old keyboard, right?
Scott: And a bunch of digital instruments.
Scott: he can switch the keyboard to, right, with some MIDI.
Rym: You know, actually, I've realized something sad.
Rym: As of when I got the new audio equipment and set up this whole new pipeline, I now have, in my apartment, zero ways to connect MIDI devices to my computer.
Rym: There's no way to do it right now.
Rym: That's the end of an era.
Scott: I mean, if you're not writing songs, I don't think you need it.
Rym: I haven't written songs since music theory class in RIT or, like, high school.
Rym: And the songs I wrote sucked.
Scott: Yeah, well, the song he wrote was an all-time hit.
Rym: In the meta moment, we ain't reading shit, 'cause we don't have commutes, so stay tuned on the book club.
Rym: We are streaming a lot.
Rym: Follow us on YouTube and go to the GeekNights official/unofficial Discord.
Rym: Scott and me soon will just be streaming random games in there sometimes.
Rym: We're hanging out online, doing as much as we can.
Scott: Before mentioned GeekNights forum.
Scott: Actually, there was a problem with the forum.
Scott: It wasn't sending emails.
Scott: I fixed that.
Scott: Which means some of you may have gotten a flood of emails that were in the backlog.
Scott: I'm sorry.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: You might have noticed, we're seeking comments.
Rym: We are writing a new, clarified code of conduct for the GeekNights community as a whole.
Scott: Oh, yeah, we didn't actually pub--oh, we did publicly announce that, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but I just want to remind you all, like, you can contribute to this.
Rym: It's just in GitHub.
Rym: I would love to hear your feedback, because we're two, like, middle-aged white guys.
Rym: We need a lot of help to write a good code of conduct, because we definitely have blind spots.
Scott: Right, and I don't just want to steal someone else's.
Scott: I want it to be one that's appropriate for our community and our beliefs.
Scott: Even though I have stolen from many masters from other communities.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: I went around and read a whole bunch of them to take what they were doing.
Scott: that was good and put it into ours.
Scott: But, you know, we need feedback.
Rym: And part of it is we don't--.
Scott: If you go to the forum, there should be a stickied post about the beta, you know, draft of the code of conduct.
Scott: And you can go to the GitHub, and you can communicate with us however you're most comfortable with.
Scott: You can email us, you can post in the forum, you could make an issue on GitHub, you can make a pull request on GitHub.
Rym: Yup, try to find me on Discord and send me a message, like, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, you can DM me on Twitter, you can do whatever you want to comment about this code of conduct, because it's not in state yet.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But when it is, it will apply to not just our forum, even though that's primarily what it's for, it's also for literally every single GeekNights community thing.
Rym: Including the live stream on YouTube, which we are streaming right now.
Rym: We are streaming shows again, so if you stop paying attention to the YouTube channel, pay attention again, because there's 14 people watching this right now.
Rym: People are starting to come back.
Scott: Right, but if you were to say-- if we were to have a gaming meetup in the city or something, the code of conduct would be applying to that event as well, right?
Scott: So, if you ever-- if you're listening to GeekNights, if you ever want to participate in our community in any way, this is relevant to you and your interests.
Scott: And we want to make sure that, A, it is not something that is onerous and ruining your fun, if you're a good person.
Rym: Yup, but if you're a bad person, we 100% wanted to ruin your fun.
Scott: We wanted to make sure you have a bad time, because of this code of conduct.
Scott: But also, we want to make sure that literally anybody on Earth who is a good person will see this code of conduct and they will feel safe enough to join in GeekNights.
Scott: Not be afraid to come to GeekNights community events.
Scott: We want you to feel welcome and safe at any GeekNights thing, no matter what your situation is, if you're a good person and not a bad person.
Rym: So, speaking of good and bad people, let's talk about Chili.
Rym: I can't believe we haven't done a show on this.
Scott: Well, so the thing with Chili, the food, right, is that I think because of the culture of the Chili cook-off, right?
Rym: Yeah, which I'm a big fan of.
Scott: Right?
Scott: There's this sort of-- unlike other foods, right, Chili has competition sort of built into it.
Scott: Whereas, I guess barbecue does a little bit, but it's really-- Chili is like the forefront of food that's competing.
Rym: Well, competing not-- There's also pie, pie contests.
Scott: You know what I'd say?
Rym: There's contests for all these things, but Chili has a lot more, like, people will just kind of do a Chili cook-off on their own and sort of self-organize.
Rym: Like, my work had a Chili cook-off recently, just randomly.
Rym: Like, all the engineering teams were like, "Let's make a Chili cook-off.
Rym: Fuck it, let's
Rym: go.".
Scott: Right, you know, the county fair will have contests for pies and things like that, but the Chili cook-off is really the preeminent American food competition.
Rym: Also, Chili is one of my favorite foods.
Scott: Right, and that culture of competition around Chili, I think, results in this particular food being-- giving people very strong opinions about the right way, the wrong way, the better way, the worse way, what makes it good, what makes it bad.
Scott: Like, how to score a Chili, right, on a cont-- I'm unwilling to talk about the true origins of Chili.
Rym: I don't care about the debate of whether or not beans are traditional.
Scott: I think the internet just says it came from, like, you know, working class, you know, Latinx people in Texas or something, right?
Rym: I mean, Wikipedia, in Spanish, the word "Chili" from the Nahatl "Chili" refers to a chili pepper.
Rym: Mm-hmm, yep.
Rym: There's the cowboy stuff, beans are not beans, but whatever.
Rym: Really, what we're talking about are braised dishes that involve some combination of chili powders and--.
Rym: And then beyond this, this could be an "or" list, obviously.
Rym: Beans, braised meats, other, like, onions, celeries, tofu's, but usually it's like a chili con carne with braised meat, tomato, and onions and stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, usually, but, yeah, it's just, it's a stew, right, and the stew is usually red and spicy and has a bunch of stuff in it, and it's such a wide variety of different things, meaning, like, this minimal, like, common factor that they all qualify as chili, right?
Scott: It's like, you can get a turkey chili with bean, you can get a vegetable chili, you can get a chili that doesn't even need tomato going on, you can get a chili with just, like, basically ground up, it's basically just your scooping ground up bits of meat that have been spiced and sauced lightly, right, or heavily.
Rym: There are people who are already taking issue in the streaming chat with our inclusion of beans.
Scott: Yep, well, deal with it.
Rym: Yep, because when it comes to chili, I am not a purist at all, and I fucking love almost any kind of chili.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, a
Scott: lot of, like I said, a lot of people have these no true Scotsman arguments of what is chili, what is not chili, and you know what, I don't give a shit, I just care that it is delicious, and if I have to say the word chili to have someone bring that food to me so that I will eat it, then I will say that word, and I do not care.
Rym: Well, the same person is saying that tofu is bad, not because it's vegetarian, that's awesome, but because it's also beans.
Scott: Tofu is beans, that is correct, but it is also delicious, and I would welcome a tofu chili that is tasty.
Rym: But I think the main reason I like chili, my feelings on chili are primarily that the power of chili is that it's real hard to fuck up.
Rym: Even if you suck, you will make an edible, satisfying chili.
Rym: Like, you have to really, really fuck up to make a chili that I wouldn't eat.
Scott: But, if you're good at it, get chili mix at the grocery store, get the cheapest one, buy a meat and follow the instructions, and like, get a can of sauce, and you'll have a chili that is food.
Rym: And even if you mess it up, if you just let it sit long enough simmering, it'll eventually taste good.
Rym: But, at the same time, if you understand the fundamentals of cooking braised dishes, then you don't need a recipe, like, you can just make any kind of chili and it'll always be good, not edible, but like, good.
Rym: Because, there's not that much to it.
Rym: There's a chili recipe I've used for most of my life that basically is just how to make the three stages of preparing a chili, and I know what kinds of ingredients to put in at what part of the chili cooking process, and by following that rubric, I can make chili out of fucking anything.
Scott: Well, I think that's also, right, that wide birth, girth.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: No, birth, as in B-E-R-T-H.
Rym: We ain't talking about Gandalf.
Scott: Yeah, the wide birth of things that could count.
Rym: That is an inside joke from a long time ago.
Scott: The wide birth of things that could count as chili is also what leads towards, you know, back into that, you know, competitive scene.
Scott: Right, because it's like if chili was one specific, like if you have a cheesecake competition, it's like, you can't have that much variety where things are still cheesecake, it's like different toppings, different flavors, how smooth is it, right?
Scott: It's wide, but it's like, it's not chili wide, right?
Scott: You can have chili with different meats, different sauce, different spice, hotter, less hot, bean, no bean, throw some vegetable in there, don't put some vegetable in there.
Rym: I like to use a primarily celery base.
Scott: A looser chili, a thicker chili, right?
Rym: It's very stew adjacent too, but I think the distinction is, chili, all chilis are stews, but not all stews are chilis.
Rym: I feel like the line there is just stew is put a bunch of shit in a pot, chili is put a bunch of shit in a pot, braise parts of it, and use at least some amount of chili peppers.
Scott: Alright, so some of my favorite chilis.
Rym: Stu Leonard's chili?
Scott: Stu Leonard's chili, so if you don't know, this is a grocery store, you may have mentioned it on GeekNights before.
Scott: It is, I guess, Ripley's Believe It or Not says it's the world's largest dairy store.
Scott: It was owned by a guy, Stu Leonard, who got in trouble for tax evasion, and his son took over who got in trouble for something else, and I think his son is out of jail now?
Scott: I don't know who's running the store now.
Rym: When I met you, you would not shut up about this fucking Stu Leonard's, and I'd never heard of it.
Rym: But then I went to it.
Scott: Of course, if you were not from Michigan, you wouldn't hear of it.
Rym: No, but then I went to it, and I understood from that point on why you talked about it so much.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, the way people talk about Trader Joe or Whole Foods, that's because they haven't been to Stu Leonard.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Well, like, maybe with roller coasters, the way people talk about Six Flags or Disney World, that's because they ain't been to Cedar Point.
Scott: But anyways, Stu Leonard, among the other things it has, which are off topic now, is that they make a lot of their own foods, right?
Scott: So, one of the foods you can buy there is their award-winning chicken chili with beans.
Scott: It comes in, you know, a plastic takeaway container.
Scott: It's like a quart or whatever.
Rym: It's so good.
Scott: It's so good.
Rym: Every time.
Scott: There's a video on YouTube that shows you how to make it.
Scott: But I don't think you would make it as good as it is when you buy it at the store.
Scott: It's just refrigerated there in a plastic container.
Scott: You take it home, you pour it out on top of something.
Scott: Some rice, maybe just a bowl of it.
Scott: On top of anything.
Rym: For years, any time Scott and I drove within like 10 or 15 miles of Stu Leonard's, we would always deviate and go get some of this.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Why wouldn't you?
Rym: And it's just like a solid chicken chili.
Rym: Chicken chili is really underrated chili.
Rym: It's harder to make.
Rym: well because you can kind of burn the chicken if you braise it the wrong way and it'll be kind of tough.
Scott: Well, I think one thing I've learned cooking chicken lately is I've pretty much, you know, it's like I already like dark meat better than white meat.
Scott: That's not new, right?
Scott: But basically now I'm like, I've realized, I've sort of taken that thing I already knew, which is dark meat is better, and just been like, wait a minute, I know dark meat is better.
Scott: I've known that for a super long time.
Scott: Why don't I go all in on that?
Scott: So whenever I make chicken, almost any chicken thing I make, I'm making boneless skinless thighs.
Scott: Or getting boneless thighs and removing the bone, right?
Scott: And just, you know, so if I was going to make a chili, I would just go all thigh.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Because you can make a chili with just like ground like white chicken, but you got to braise, you got to be careful with the braising.
Scott: Like you got to use more oil, you've got to like really- You got to spice that chicken to basically, you know, really season that chicken and keep it juicy.
Rym: And you really got to deglaze.
Rym: Like deglazing is important for like a beef chili, but with a chicken chili, if you don't deglaze, you're like all.
Rym: the flavor is just going to be stuck to your pan.
Scott: Yep, yep, yep.
Rym: But that's, you know, the key to making a good chili.
Rym: for me is the process of like.
Rym: the first thing you have to put into that bowl is you braise whatever meat you're going to use.
Rym: If you're using tofu or something like that, that isn't like a primary meat, you don't put that in right away, you put that in way later.
Scott: You braise the meat- It's not a meat that's going to give off a lot of delicious fat when you braise it down.
Rym: Got to put that oil in there.
Scott: You got to add some oil, right?
Scott: So if you get a tofu, you got to go with sesame oil.
Scott: maybe, go for Asian style chili with the tofu, I don't know.
Rym: Ooh, I've never used sesame oil before.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: You can make an Asian style, Asian fusion chili.
Rym: What I tend to do is I'll braise either cubed chunks of beef or ground beef and then I'll set it aside and without cleaning out the pot, I'll put in a bunch of oil.
Rym: And usually, as much as I like to make the traditional like just a pile of onions for the base, I actually tend to use primarily celery, like one onion and two hunks of celery, like big hunks.
Rym: And then I just braise that down until it's like unrecognizable mush and the whole pot is covered in fond.
Scott: Yeah, it's a lot like making curry, right?
Scott: It's like I'm making curry from scratch.
Scott: and I think, you know, all the really difference with the curry is that curry is like, okay, I take some onions, right?
Scott: Disintegrate them down into nothing, right?
Scott: Get your braised, you know, boneless, skinless thighs in there, right?
Scott: You know, whatever.
Scott: And the thing with the curry is that you go with water and then you put in, you know, your, what's the word for it?
Scott: The butter flour.
Rym: Oh, the, yeah, I know what you're talking about.
Scott: Yeah, you take butter and flour and you cook them together and you make whatever it is.
Scott: There's a word for it.
Scott: The roux?
Scott: Yeah, the roux, right?
Scott: And then you add the butter flour and then your spice, you know, whatever your curry spices are in with the butter flour.
Rym: But what Scott just said, that's mistake number one.
Rym: When you make a bad chili, a lot of times it's because you put the garlic or the spices in way too early when you're still cooking the base stuff and you burn and fuck up the spices and the garlic.
Scott: But I was saying, that's the difference between curry and chili, right?
Scott: So curry is like, you know, you got your water, right?
Scott: And then you roux it up.
Scott: With chili, it's like, you're not really putting too much water going on there.
Scott: You're definitely not making a roux with butter.
Scott: No, no, no, no.
Scott: No, no, no, no, no, right?
Scott: You're going with something tomato based maybe or, you know, some kind of, you know, maybe like some kind of stock or something, right?
Rym: Recently, that's made my chili way better.
Rym: Like recently, like in the past five or six years that when I was younger, I didn't understand it's made my chili so much better.
Rym: I realized you don't add the tomato until way late in the process.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: The acid in the tomato kind of fucks it up and makes it harder to like make the meats.
Rym: Like it causes all these chemistry problems in the chili.
Rym: The other thing I learned to do better was instead of cooking the garlic, because I like to put a ton of garlic in.
Rym: Instead of cooking it separately, what I do is after I've made the fond and I've got all the vegetables, I make a little hole in the middle of the fond and I put some oil in the middle of that hole.
Rym: And I put all the garlic there and cook it by itself in the middle of the hole for like two minutes.
Rym: Then I mix it all together and then I deglaze.
Scott: Oh, you could do that.
Scott: It really depends on if you're looking to keep the garlic in there.
Scott: It's like you're maybe getting little niblets of garlic.
Rym: Or do you want it to be a paste that just causes garlic flavor?
Scott: You could do that too.
Scott: Or you could just take a whole head of garlic, right, chop it in half down the middle, toss it in, skins and all, right, and then you just got to get it out.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Before you serve it.
Scott: And that'll really...
Rym: Use it like you use a bay leaf.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You'll get a fucking ton of garlic flavor into that, you know, whatever you want.
Rym: Though I'll admit I've found that if I want that kind of chili, using a bunch of granulated garlic has the exact same effect.
Rym: You can't taste the difference.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I'm saying like that's a, you know, usually I think the put the whole head of garlic in.
Scott: You could do it with the chili.
Scott: It'll be good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I think, you know, usually you're not.
Scott: you're not pouring a chili through like a strainer, right?
Scott: The way you would say making like a chicken soup.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You don't want to have to fish it all out.
Rym: I've done that a couple times in my life.
Scott: But you could, you know, but you can.
Scott: You can put a little string on it and then you can get out.
Rym: But for those of you who might not know a lot about like better cooking techniques, the fond, what we're talking about there.
Rym: So imagine you have a bunch of celery or onions or stuff in the pot and you're cooking a whole bunch like over kind of high heat.
Rym: This brown crust has formed inside of your entire pot now, like everywhere.
Scott: Assuming you don't have some nonstick.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I don't think you can make a particularly good chili in a nonstick pan.
Scott: I don't think you could either.
Rym: Because you need that fond.
Rym: The fond will form.
Rym: Normally, like when I was younger, I always thought that was me fucking up and like cooking too hot.
Rym: But then I learned the secret of deglazing.
Scott: Right, so it's like the Maillard reaction happens.
Scott: Like you put an onion in a pan, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The onion starts to brown because of the Maillard reaction, right?
Rym: That brown is not bad.
Rym: That is pure flavor country.
Scott: That is the delicious part.
Scott: But some of that brown will just like come off the onion and be stuck to the pan.
Scott: So it's like, OK, I got this piece of onion.
Scott: It's grilled and heated nicely.
Scott: So it's got, you know, browning and it tastes great.
Scott: But some of the browning fell off.
Scott: It's on the bottom of my pan.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: You got to scrape that shit up.
Rym: And scraping it is real hard.
Rym: That's why you deglaze.
Rym: Use something like alcohol and you put a little bit of it in and it'll basically just melt all the fond into your food.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, for example, a lot of, and this isn't just chili, a lot of food cooking.
Scott: this happens in, right?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Deglazing, like hook that up.
Rym: And there's whole sets of instructions and techniques.
Scott: A lot of times, you know, like I'll like take some chicken on the skinless thighs, right?
Scott: With some olive oil.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They brown up nicely.
Scott: And then it's like, OK, let's throw in all this other stuff and a splash of cooking wine.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or some vinegar or sherry or brandy works really well.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or even sometimes, depending on what you got, water can do it too.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And suddenly all that stuff that was on the bottom of the pan comes right up and absorbs in.
Scott: And there you go.
Scott: So you can even, for example, like say brown some chicken, take the chicken out of the, your chicken's done now, take it out and then make a sauce.
Scott: And, you know, while you're making the sauce, all the stuff gets incorporated into the sauce.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I've done that a few times.
Scott: And then you would pour that sauce over the chicken out of the pan and your pan should look clean, but you still need to clean it.
Rym: For my basic chili, I usually use like a brown ale or a red ale, like a beer, and I'll basically pour half a can of beer into the fond and use that to deglaze because that adds a really nice flavor and all the alcohol obviously evaporates.
Scott: Another thing you can do, right, is like a lot of people, I think, when they make chili, right, they're like, you know, you got to worry about the actual chilies, right?
Scott: Where the name comes from.
Rym: So I just use chili powder, but, or in the state after I get the onions and the celery down, then I'll do that again with a whole bunch of peppers that I've chopped up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I think the real pro technique is to get dried chilies, right?
Scott: Because the dried chilies, if you're not growing, if you're not growing your own, if you're looking at dried chilies, there are so many more available varieties.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Especially if you live in like a city, right?
Scott: Like I could go to the Mexican grocery and get a shit ton of different chilies, all crazy kinds, but they're all dried.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So you can rehydrate them, which is totally easy to do, right?
Scott: You can get fresh chilies and like roast them down a little bit on a sheet pan in the oven.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right?
Rym: Especially, don't use poblanos in particular, roast them first because they will not break down fast enough if you cook them in the pot by themselves, the skins thick.
Scott: The other thing, well, yeah, well, you roast them and you could take the skins off.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: There's a whole technique about that.
Rym: It's like, look it up.
Rym: It's a crazy technique with plastic bags, but it works.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You don't always need a plastic bag.
Rym: The plastic bag just works so well.
Rym: It's so easy once you learn it.
Scott: You cook things to get the skins to peel off.
Rym: Yeah, but it depends on the pepper too.
Rym: Like a lot of the peppers I use, you don't need to do this.
Rym: You can just cook the whole pepper chopped up.
Scott: But the other thing you can do is you can take those, right, and throw them in if you've got a blender or a food processor.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Right?
Scott: So you get all your actual, you know, chilies, right, blend it up real good that way, and then they go in with all your meats into your stew pot.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So after that, after you get the meat- If you just throw a bunch of chilies in a pot, that's not going to work out as well.
Rym: So I have to get the meat in.
Rym: I let it cook for like an hour, maybe longer.
Rym: Like, chili just gets better the longer you let it cook.
Rym: Like, that's just, that's the magic of chili.
Scott: It depends on certain things, right?
Scott: So if, you know, you've, you know, you might want to like, you know, say you're going real fancy, you want to do more like a barbecue chili.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So you can use that long chili cooking time as like a slow cooking for the meat to get it to be, you know, very barbecue tender, fall apart.
Scott: Like a pulled pork situation.
Scott: But maybe if you've, you know, got like a ground beef and you browned it already, you don't need as long a cook time there.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But after all that cooking, then is when I add the tomato and if there's beans or tofu or anything, I put all that stuff in.
Rym: Like, so it's cooked for an hour.
Rym: Then I put all the tomato and everything in for like 10 more minutes of cooking.
Scott: Because the thing about eating the chili, right?
Scott: The most important part.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is you could just put it in a bowl and eat it with a spoon.
Scott: Isn't that, that's perfectly acceptable.
Rym: My go-to is put it over rice or have croutons on top.
Rym: Those are my two main ways.
Scott: I feel like you have to add some kind of bread, rice, grain thing.
Rym: It just makes it a complete meal.
Rym: It tastes, it feels right.
Scott: But I never want that grain to be a, uh, if the chili is next to the grain, right?
Scott: Then the grain could be special.
Scott: So for example, I could have a bowl of chili with a garlic bread next to it.
Scott: I could have a bowl of chili with a cornbread next to it.
Rym: But if it's chili in a bread bowl, that's just gotta be some plain ass bread.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: If the chili is touching the bread or the rice or the grain, right, in any way, top or bottom, side, then that bread has to be plain as hell because it is just a bread vehicle, a wheat train, right, with meat passengers.
Rym: Chili in a bread bowl is like literally like one of my top 10 favorite foods on earth.
Scott: It is an extremely convenient way to eat chili because you don't have to think about the bread part or the bowl part.
Rym: Every time I ski, ski resorts are famous for having fucking garbage food.
Rym: Even fancy ski resorts, the food is just garbage.
Scott: Oh, but they're also famous for having warm food because people are fucking cold.
Rym: Yup, but every ski resort, even the shittiest one, has fantastic chili.
Scott: Yeah, even someone who's not a great chef can make a chili.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: My dad was a fireman and part of the reason I was so obsessed with chili is because we ate chili a lot because firemen in firehouses, like they'll go on rotation for like a week at a time, they all take turns cooking because they're living in the firehouse, they make chili like 80%
Scott: of the time.
Scott: Chili is like the stereotypical fireman, right?
Rym: Like firehouse chili is a thing, like that's a kind of chili.
Rym: Put some cayenne pepper in it.
Scott: And they'll even say things like, you know, five alarm chili, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Or, you know, I can't think of a single firehouse on earth that doesn't have their own chili cook-off.
Rym: Oh, 100% and their own chili recipe.
Scott: I've never heard of one, at least in the United States.
Rym: And because I ended up, because my dad was a lieutenant and he ended up being like the deputy chief, so as a kid and growing up, I met a lot of like, I went to a lot of different like firehouses over the course of my life.
Rym: And the one thing I remember is that every one of them had the one guy who made the chili for that firehouse because he was the best.
Rym: Like everyone had like one guy.
Scott: That's the guy who's entering the competition at the end of the year against the other firehouses.
Rym: My memory may be a little faulty, but I'm pretty sure 100% of the chili guys had full mustaches.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: I mean, you can't make a chili.
Scott: You gotta grow the mustache first before you can make the chili or else it'll turn out like shit.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: My chili got worse when I shaved off the mustache.
Rym: That's one problem.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: The other important component of eating the chili, not always, but for most chilis, I want to have a cold thing.
Rym: Either a sour cream or a cheese to mix into it.
Rym: Well, okay, so mixing in I'm not too big on because that can dilute- Well, you put it on top and I only mix it in right as I'm eating it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That can dilute the power of the chili.
Scott: If I do a sour cream, then what I want to do is I want to sort of like, you know, get a little chili on a bread and then put a sour cream and then eat that.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: I like to put a blob of sour cream on top of the chili bowl.
Scott: I'll even do that just like in the house, not even chili, but like if I'm eating chips and salsa, I'll just get sour cream and I'll dip the chip in the salsa and then in the sour cream.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But I think if you're doing cheese or any kind of dairy, I just get the bowl of chili ready.
Scott: So if we're doing the bread bowl, right?
Rym: If you sprinkle it on the top, make a layer like a French onion soup.
Scott: Top, top sprinkle, right?
Scott: I get the cheese grater, I get the block of cheese and then I go right on top of the bowl, right?
Scott: No mixing, right?
Rym: And I don't use a fancy cheese.
Rym: I use like Monterey Jack or cheddar.
Scott: Oh, no, no, no.
Scott: I use the regular old just cheddar cheese, you know, rectangle from the grocery store.
Rym: Monterey Jack is a good choice.
Scott: It could be a sharp one, but you know.
Rym: But if your chili is particularly powerful or good on its own and you don't want to even like compromise at all, you just want that cheese like texture and flavor, Monterey Jack is not a bad way to go on a chili.
Rym: No, no.
Scott: I think, you know, nothing fancier than Laughing Cow should be going on.
Scott: No.
Scott: And I think most of the Laughing Cow varieties aren't even chili appropriate, I don't think.
Rym: So in terms of the other bits of chili, and I think we've gone on for long enough about chili, when I cook it, I usually use a beef broth instead of water because that just makes the chili way more flavorful without me having to fuck with it.
Rym: Like that works pretty well.
Rym: Sometimes I'll make, but if I don't want to mess up the flavor, I'll use a vegetarian broth or I'll just use water and add enough salt to the water to make it as salty as broth, but to not add any flavor.
Scott: Yeah, I'm still not an expert on this.
Rym: I know that stock comes from like, you know, bones and broth comes from- We made some the other night, I can show you how to make broth.
Scott: No, no, no, but I'm saying is like, you know, it's like.
Scott: I know this stock versus broth, right?
Scott: But it's like when would you, you know, when do you use one and when the other?
Scott: Or is stock just better?
Rym: You know what, in terms of chili, I found it doesn't matter.
Rym: I've used all different kinds of stocks and broths and like even my saltwater technique.
Scott: Because I get the feeling that like, you know, when I hear like chefs, I've never heard them say it directly, but I get the feeling whenever I watch cooking programs that stock is just better than broth, fuck broth, right?
Scott: That's like the vibe I get.
Rym: All right, I just googled it.
Rym: What's the difference between stock and broth?
Rym: The terms stock and broth are used interchangeably and you can substitute one for the other within recipes.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: There's slight difference in their preparation, like that's it.
Scott: All right, well, anyway, if you go to the grocery store, you'll definitely see the same brand selling in a carton, right?
Scott: Stock and broth of the same animal and they're two different products.
Rym: But seriously, like you can get away with just water and salt if you put enough good ingredients in there.
Rym: And in terms of tomato, I either use fresh crushed tomatoes, like from a, not fresh, but like from a can, but like crushed or diced or honestly.
Scott: If you got tomato, can is the way to go unless it's that one moment of the year where tomato is in season.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Tomato paste, however, you can't tell the difference.
Rym: Tomato paste, like if you're chili.
Scott: Tomato paste is from a can.
Rym: Yeah, but tomato paste is fine compared to like a big thing of diced tomatoes and way easier to work with and you can store it longer.
Rym: and tomato paste is just like magic.
Rym: If a chili doesn't feel quite right, or you kind of messed up the flavor profile, more tomato will just make it taste more like generic chili and save you.
Rym: Tomato paste is like tomato concentrate.
Scott: Yeah, I mean tomato paste is literally tomato concentrate.
Scott: If you need tomato sauce, just take tomato paste and water and look, you got tomato sauce.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: That's how it works.
Scott: That's the point.
Rym: In terms of the spices, I tend to, the one thing I really don't deviate from is I tend to mostly just use chili powder.
Rym: A shit ton of cumin.
Rym: I love cumin.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: We got, Amanda was making a chili today and she's like, "I bought this giant cumin, but look, it's running out.
Scott: I make so much
Scott: chili.".
Scott: It's like, we never buy big things because there's not a lot of people and we don't eat that much food in New York.
Scott: You don't have a lot of storage space.
Scott: We don't like to buy big, you know, we like to buy small amounts.
Rym: Only now am I buying big things.
Scott: Right, but she's like, "I bought this big cumin,".
Scott: and it's like, "I never want to buy a big
Scott: thing.".
Rym: Cumin's so good.
Rym: Like, however much cumin you think you should use in a chili, just use three times as much.
Rym: It'll be fine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We use so much cumin in the chili that the big one was the right purchase.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And then I either use smoked paprika or cayenne pepper, depending on what kind of kick I want to give it and all the rest of the flavor.
Rym: I just want it to come from my ingredients.
Scott: Yeah, they're pretty similar-ish.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Mostly depends if I want it smokier versus, like, spicier.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's the thing is you got to mix, you know, the great chilies, you're mixing together different chili flavors.
Scott: You get, like, a fruity pepper and a spicy pepper and a smoky pepper.
Scott: Get all three or balance them in some way.
Rym: Or don't balance them and lean in heavily to one and make a very, like, specific kind of chili.
Rym: Habaneros are real good for flavor, but do not try to make a chili with just habaneros.
Rym: You'll be in for a bad time.
Scott: Whichever one of the peppers you lean into, the rest of the chili has to sort of contrast.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So if you got, say, you know, if you go in, like, the extra, like, on fire spice, like a real tangy kind of spice.
Rym: Don't also go heavy on chipotle in that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Then you might want to come back on it and go maybe more, you know, with some dairy on that, right?
Scott: Or, you know, maybe a sweeter tomato to go on the other side.
Rym: Like, one thing I really like to make is instead of using a lot of chili powder, I'll get, like, three or four pounds of rainbow peppers, just, like, random sweet peppers.
Rym: Chop them all up and I'll braise those down just like I would with the celery and the onion.
Rym: And then for a kick, I just add a bunch of cayenne pepper.
Rym: That works real well.
Rym: And it makes, like, almost a sweet chili.
Rym: So you get this contrasting sweet and spicy.
Rym: Last thing about chili?
Scott: Yeah, because we got to end the show.
Rym: Yep, and I'm getting hungry, so.
Scott: Is that, oh, well, you've been talking about chili.
Rym: I know, I'm getting real hungry.
Rym: I want some chili.
Scott: I ate food already.
Rym: I think we're going to get a Baroness burger tonight.
Scott: Ooh, exciting.
Scott: Is that, unlike a lot of other foods, chili is good all times.
Rym: Oh, yeah, breakfast chili, Bob, chili omelet.
Scott: Breakfast chili, lunch chili, dinner chili, all appropriate.
Rym: Late night snack chili, you'll get heartburn, but fuck it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then, not only that, but all seasons.
Scott: Summer chili, winter chili, right?
Scott: I'm cold.
Scott: I want to eat warm chili.
Scott: It's summer.
Scott: Let's go outside and have a chili cook-off.
Scott: And also, I have chili at the barbecue.
Scott: Made too much?
Scott: I'll have a chili dog.
Scott: I'll dip my hot dogs in the chili in the summer.
Rym: But in the middle of winter, cooking some chili?
Rym: All right, now there's a bunch of humidity in the apartment.
Rym: Everything smells good.
Scott: Oh, it's dry because the heat's on.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But you make humidity.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's never a time where it's not chili season, because everything you're using in the chili is meat, which it doesn't have a season, right?
Scott: And canned vegetables and dried peppers and all these, you know, beans from a can, right?
Scott: All the ingredients going in the chili.
Scott: So, almost none of them are fresh and seasonal.
Scott: All dried, preserved meats.
Rym: Like onions and celery in particular.
Rym: It does not have to be good onions or good celery.
Rym: Usually, when I use celery, it's because we have too much celery.
Scott: You can always get a good onion anytime if you live in a place that has food.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, that's one of the greatest things about chili.
Scott: That even other, better, not to say chili is the greatest food on Earth, you know, it's a great food for sure.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's not my number one.
Rym: It's just in my top ten.
Scott: No.
Scott: But it's like other, greater foods are often seasonal in some way or time-based, right?
Scott: I wouldn't eat the delicious steak dinner for breakfast.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Don't steak and eggs.
Scott: But you don't- You could have a country fried steak for breakfast.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But if you make steak and eggs, you're not making a filet mignon steak and eggs.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But chili is appropriate at per every meal, in every season, in every time, in every place.
Rym: The other main property of chili, the last one that's real important that you didn't touch on- The real last one?
Scott: I already did the last one.
Rym: There is a last, last one.
Rym: You're coming over the last, last- It's impossible to make too much because you can just freeze it and thaw it.
Rym: Frozen chili, recooked, just tastes better.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's made of preserved stuff.
Scott: Just preserve it again.
Rym: And as long as you're careful with the temperatures and, like, If you freeze chili that you made, thaw it and cook a bunch of it, don't finish it, you can just refreeze that shit and it's good again.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, it's not- What's wrong with it?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The only problem you can have is if you don't do right food safety and let it sit out too long because you'll slowly increase the bacterial load.
Scott: If you leave it in the fridge too long or you let it sit out too long, it's okay until you see something growing on it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So here's the secret.
Rym: If you make a lot of chili and you want to freeze it or get into your fridge, don't just put it in the freezer.
Rym: It'll actually mess up the rest of your freezer or fridge because it's so hot.
Rym: And if you let it get cool to room temperature naturally, that usually works.
Scott: But it's not super safe unless- It'll be sitting in the danger zone for a long time.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Way too long.
Rym: Meaning if you freeze it once that way, do not do that again.
Scott: But- Usually just separate it into individual serving containers and freeze those.
Rym: Well separate it into individual serving containers, but then what I do is I seal those containers and I put them in a cold water bath to bring their temperature down rapidly before I put them in the fridge and then the freezer.
Rym: That really minimizes the time it's in the danger zone.
Scott: Putting them in the containers is going to already cool them off a whole bunch because- Remember I
Rym: worked at that shitty restaurant at RIT, so one of the things I was actually responsible for was taking the chili and the hot saucy, the meaty hot sauce stuff that they had down there.
Rym: And doing the quick cool before we then staged it into the fridge and then the freezer.
Rym: That was literally my job.
Scott: Yeah, but I think that the individual containers is key because if you have a giant bucket of chili in the fridge or the freezer- What, are you going to chisel out and split that up?
Rym: That's not going to fly.
Scott: Right, you've got to heat that whole thing up when you want chili again.
Scott: If you've got individual containers, you can just pop one out and chili anytime.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: My god, next week I'm going to make some more chili.
Rym: Actually no, next week I'm going to eat all the chili in my freezer.
Rym: The following week I'm going to make more chili.
Scott: I have a fridge full of chili right now.
Scott: I'll probably eat one tomorrow.
Rym: Alright, stay safe out there and eat some chili.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the GeekNights Patreon Patrons for this episode are in order of how much they love us or how much money they give us.
Rym: Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Grenier, Just Like a Dude Guy, Kajar Taubjian, Link Iji, You Hold the Key to My Heart.
Rym: She said, "You're moving with your auntie and uncle in
Rym: Bel-Air.".
Rym: Clinton Walton, Jay Bantz, Rin from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openletter, Nicholas Brandow, The Thirst for Hydrated Ganon, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Finn, Sean Klein, Thomas Hahn, Shervin Van Horl, Sean Yeager, and a whole bunch of people who don't want me to say their name.
Rym: We're continuing to truck along, continuing to do the show remotely.
Rym: We're setting up something to be able to stream simultaneous video feeds from our two houses.
Rym: Stay tuned, we'll see what we can do with that.
Rym: We're going to be testing some pipelines this weekend.
Rym: But now, I leave you with a song from the year 2000.