Rym: -It's Monday, November 9th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: -I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, there is a new president of the United States, but more importantly, we are talking about the Hypertext Transfer Protocol.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, we knew that Joe Biden had become the president, like, the week, like, before the weekend.
Rym: Like, we already knew, but no one had called it officially, except decision-based.
Scott: It's one of those situations I always talk about, where Rym brings the news on the show, and I'm like, "We knew this news already.
Scott: This isn't
Scott: news.".
Scott: And Rym's like, "No, but now that it's officially confirmed, it's a different
Scott: And I'm like, "I knew that last year.
Scott: That was just, I knew that my whole
Scott: life.".
Rym: Well, I mean, in this case, if we didn't have an electoral college, we knew, like, the night of the election.
Rym: 'Cause the popular vote is, like, it's a landslide in the popular vote.
Rym: Like, they're still counting.
Rym: It's crazy.
Scott: Millions more people.
Scott: If we had to, if the good people and the bad people had to fight each other... We win.
Scott: ...and the non-voters and ineligible voters just didn't participate...
Rym: Biden won by, like, four... ...we would destroy them.
Rym: ...four million already, and it's projected to hit, like...
Scott: At least four million people.
Scott: And it's gonna be, like, seven million.
Scott: It doesn't matter how big your army is at the beginning.
Scott: If you're outnumbered by four million, you're in deep shit, right?
Scott: I mean, even a billion, an army of a billion versus an army of a billion plus four million is in deep, deep shit, right?
Scott: Because the billion versus the billion fight, right?
Scott: But four million of those billion are being double-teamed.
Scott: So they've only got, assuming everyone's equal strength...
Rym: Or, or, actually, that's not, that, you know, what you're talking, you know how you're talking?
Rym: You're talking how people would lose wars in ancient times, and even medieval times, and even all the way up to World War I. Because the real use of that extra four to seven million is not to double-team.
Rym: No, no, no, that's not how you do it.
Rym: No.
Rym: Those are the reserves.
Scott: Oh, okay, so...
Rym: The attrition battle comes down, both sides are almost depleted, and then cavalry and Gandalf the White come over the horizon.
Scott: Well, that's how we did, and it worked.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But, uh, the official official was delayed for, basically, bullshit reasons, but it was delayed.
Scott: The official official official will be when the House certifies the slates of electors, which is, like, next month, or when that is weeks away.
Rym: There's actually a bunch of different steps, uh...
Scott: That's the final step, though.
Rym: Well, yeah, the final final final step is Inauguration Day.
Rym: It is possible...
Scott: That step is, that's just simply ceremonial.
Scott: The only one that matters is the certification.
Rym: So, a point of order, it is possible if the Electoral College can't, like, get its shit together on Inauguration Day.
Rym: What do you think happens if the Electoral College just doesn't vote, and Inauguration Day comes?
Rym: I'm just curious, trivia bit, then we'll get into the show.
Scott: I mean, I know a lot of the scenarios, but I don't know that scenario.
Rym: That scenario is actually really complicated, and there's debate about it, but the best guess is that there is, the current president is no longer the president, and you just follow the 25th Amendment.
Rym: So, you say, "Well, president's not the president anymore, nor is the vice president.
Rym: The next one in line is the Speaker of the House, who is still the Speaker of the
Rym: House.".
Rym: They immediately become the acting president.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I'd be fine with that, President Pelosi.
Rym: But, something happened to me that had nothing to do with the election.
Rym: Because on the day with the official announcement, Emily and I were hiking in the wilderness, we were in a valley, no cell signal, just enjoying the world, not thinking about politics.
Rym: Just birds were singing, it was beautiful.
Scott: Yeah, birds don't know.
Rym: We crested a ridge, and suddenly, my phone starts buzzing.
Rym: Emily's looking at her watch, because her watch is buzzing.
Rym: We must have gotten like one bare bar of data, cresting this ridge, and the first thing I see is a text message, I don't even have data yet, from our friend Scott Johnson.
Scott: Text messages are going to get through much more readily than anything.
Rym: I think we've talked about on GeekNights why the text will always get through, or won't.
Scott: No, actually it won't.
Rym: It won't, but it'll get somewhere.
Rym: It might just be in a rotating buffer in a cell tower for years, never going anywhere.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: And I get this text, and he's like, "Pretty sure you're in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: We
Rym: won.".
Rym: I wanted to be the first one to tell you, and he was.
Rym: So the next day, I go out to run, and I'm on Randall's Island, just doing my half marathon like I do every weekend, and this dude tried to have a fistfight with me.
Rym: Nothing to do with the election.
Scott: You're running.
Scott: How long are you near a person if you're running?
Scott: Were they also running?
Scott: Right?
Rym: So get this.
Rym: I stopped on Randall's Island.
Rym: I was about seven and a half miles into the thirteen mile run.
Scott: Where on Randall's Island did you stop?
Rym: Near ICANN Stadium.
Scott: Okay, over by the stadium.
Rym: And because the cops were gathering there for some reason, I was like, "What the fuck is going
Rym: on?".
Rym: Because there were so many cops there, and they had all the riot police gear, and all the sergeants were lined up, and it looked like the sergeants were all addressing the police, and they were holding the riot helmets.
Rym: And I was like, "What fucker is this?
Rym: Gonna tweet just in case some shit's going down.
Rym: What's going
Rym: on?".
Rym: So I stopped, take pictures, can't really figure out what's going on.
Rym: I tweet about it.
Rym: And then I'm walking toward the bridge to get back on the RFK to do the rest of my run.
Rym: And I'm looking at my phone, and suddenly this guy on a bike who is riding on the sidewalk stops in front of me suddenly and starts yelling at me to get out of his way.
Rym: Now, there's a bike lane in the street.
Rym: Also, you're an adult.
Rym: You shouldn't be biking on the sidewalk, but whatever.
Rym: I ignore him.
Rym: I just kind of laugh and keep walking.
Scott: There is a very brief area there where they put a tiny strip of, like, bike/walk.
Rym: Oh, this is way past that.
Rym: Way past that.
Scott: Well, it's right at the entrance to the bridge.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But where we were is way, way, way past that.
Rym: There's that really narrow, like, a little over, like, barely two feet wide, old sidewalk.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I don't know why this dude's biking.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: He yells at me, and, like, I get out of his way, and I kind of laugh and just keep walking.
Rym: I didn't even flip him off yet.
Rym: Like, I didn't even, like, do anything, because, you know, I was going to flip that dude off, but I didn't.
Rym: I was still just, like, laughing, like, whatever, because I was in the middle of my tweet.
Scott: How do you flip someone off when you're holding your phone?
Scott: You've got to put the phone away, then you get the thing.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: So, before I can even flip the dude off, because I start laughing a little bit, he starts following me, yelling at me about disrespecting him.
Rym: And then he starts threatening to fight me, and wants to, and he's throwing slurs out, and he, like, he's about to punch me.
Rym: So, I, like, back off, like, fast, and I start recording him, because, you know, if he's going to fight me, like, I'm going to have to deal with the police at some point.
Rym: So, I have the camera up, and I'm like, "I got video, dude.
Rym: What the
Rym: fuck?".
Rym: And he keeps, and now he changes his tune.
Rym: He still wants to fight me.
Rym: He's aggressively chasing me, but he's yelling, "Put the phone down.
Rym: Put the phone down, so we can settle this like
Rym: men.".
Rym: And I'm just like, "Fuck you.
Rym: Leave me alone.
Rym: I'm videoing you.
Rym: I'm going to call the
Rym: cops.".
Rym: Like, what the fuck?
Rym: Now, I don't actually want to call the cops.
Rym: I just want this dude to go away.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Because if I call the cops, like, he might get shot, and, eh, I don't really want that to happen, even though this dude is a super piece of shit.
Rym: So, I do something I have done multiple times in my life, and the reason I'm telling this story, and taking some time to tell it, is that this works.
Rym: So, this dude, clearly, like, he's getting to the point where he's about to, like, try to punch me and take my phone to get rid of the recording, or to not have a recording of him fighting with me, because I guess he thinks he's going to win this fight.
Rym: I don't think he realized that if it had come to a fight, I was going to kick him in the nads so hard.
Scott: That's what I would have done.
Scott: That's exactly my plan, as well.
Scott: I have to hit you.
Rym: So, I put my phone up, like, I fucks with it, and I act like I'm on the phone with 911 while I'm backing up from him.
Rym: I'm not actually on the phone with 911.
Rym: I'm, in fact, still recording video.
Rym: So, and I'm like, "911?
Rym: Yeah, no, this guy's threatening me.
Rym: Yes?
Rym: Yeah?".
Rym: And I'm, like, doing this whole bit, and the dude keeps trying to act like he wants to fight me, and he's still following me, but as soon as I start describing his appearance in detail, and where he is, to nobody, he starts to back off a little bit, and obviously is frightened, but his machismo is still too up, and he doesn't want to, like, admit that he lost.
Rym: So, eventually, I'm like, "Yeah, he's got a tattoo on his right leg.
Rym: Yeah, he's still following me.
Rym: Yeah, I can stick
Rym: around.".
Rym: And then he starts to back off, like, at that point.
Rym: Like, I think he realizes that he thinks I actually did call the police.
Rym: They're on the way, and he's in trouble.
Rym: So, he starts to leave slowly, unrelatedly.
Rym: I could not have timed this better.
Rym: An ambulance is going by, like, way off in the distance, and it runs a red light, and it blips its sirens.
Rym: while it runs the red light, and I can see this, because it's way behind him, but he's still looking at me.
Rym: When that siren goes brrrrp, I wave.
Rym: I wave, like, "Hey, cot," like, whoever, and he fucking books.
Rym: He is gone so fast.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I didn't actually call the police, because whatever.
Rym: I think I scared that guy enough.
Rym: It works.
Rym: That's the end of my story.
Rym: That's just what happened to me, randomly.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So, uh, you got any tech news?
Scott: Uh, there is.
Scott: There's a tiny tech news.
Scott: So, I don't know how many people are aware of this company, uh, called Sling, right?
Scott: Uh, I've been aware of them since, like, the mid-2000s, because my boss at my first job out of college was, like, a very early customer of theirs, and was bragging because he thought it was just so cool, their technology.
Scott: So, what the Sling box is, if you don't know, is you, for some reason, buy cable or satellite television.
Scott: Why the hell you do that?
Scott: Um, and you connect this box up to it, uh, I guess, after your cable box or whatever, in between your television, and what you can do with this box is then, on any of your other devices in the world, right, you would run the Sling software, like a little application.
Scott: And what you do is you connect to your own television, right, your own cable that you're paying for is rebroadcasting itself over the internet to you and only you.
Scott: So, it's like you're, you're not pirating the television because you're paying for it, right?
Scott: But, like, when you watch pirate television on the internet, you're watching someone else Slinging to a million people, or whoever many people are pirating and watching, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Now, this is a legal stream from yourself to yourself.
Rym: As far as I can tell, the legality of the Sling box stuff was never, like, fully determined, but it seemed like it was working.
Scott: But no one cared because it wasn't taking money away from cable companies, and they weren't even offering a competing feature?
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It feels like it was in the spectrum of, like, using a VCR.
Rym: Like, you're shifting to yourself.
Rym: So, eh.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you paid for it, you're paying for the Sling service on top of that from another vendor, and you're streaming your own cable to you live, right?
Scott: And, you know, of course, you know, it's like it's your own cable.
Scott: So, like, let's say Rym is at home and I'm using Rym's Sling, right, because he shared his Sling account with me.
Rym: Because that's what I would have done if I had a Sling, that's what I would do.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So, Rym is watching the hockey game, and I'm watching the hockey game, right?
Scott: But then, you know, the hockey game's over, and Rym switches to Owl House, right?
Scott: Well, guess what?
Scott: I'm watching Owl House now.
Scott: The cable box can't be on two channels at once.
Scott: It's not, like, you're streaming literally whatever the cable box is watching.
Rym: That's how they get you.
Rym: In fact, in the old TVs, you kids might be too young to remember, TVs got this feature, picture in picture, and it was a big deal at the time.
Rym: But to make it work...
Scott: They needed two cable boxes.
Rym: Yep, you either had to have two cable boxes, or you had to have a splitter before the cable box, and then only the non-premium channels would work in the picture in picture.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, so Sling was a pretty cool thing for people who weren't super technologically advanced, a way to pay money to get this feature.
Scott: Obviously, very technologically advanced people would use a computer with a capture card and some open source software, right, to set up a DVR kind of situation.
Scott: I think DVRs also really made Sling largely unnecessary, right, because you could just record whatever it is that you were...
Rym: I feel like Sling was used primarily for sports.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing with Sling is that it doesn't save you money, it costs you more money, right?
Scott: People want to move toward...
Rym: Yeah, Sling sold this, this wasn't like a little prod, like, you buy their hardware.
Scott: Yeah, you get the hardware, you pay for the service, and it has a subscription.
Scott: The point is, Sling is dead, RIP, rest in peace.
Scott: They're shutting it down, they're not making any more Sling products, they're discontinuing all their service, and I think they said two years from now, everything that people have will just be bricked.
Scott: So, the end of Sling is here, not really surprised.
Scott: I'm more surprised it lasted this long.
Rym: I didn't know it was still around, to be honest.
Scott: I think it's at least 15 years old, right?
Rym: When you sent me this news, I was literally about to respond with a slowpoke gif, and then I saw that it was actually current real news from today.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: Breaking news on GeekNights here.
Scott: Even so, their technology did work incredibly well, even in the earliest days.
Scott: That boss I told you about, who was like my boss at my first post-college job, who was showing it off.
Scott: I remember him having Sling set up at his house, and he would watch, he had a, you know, like, this is Blackberry era, pre-iPhone, 2004, 2005, and he had, what is it called, Windows CE in those days, I think, right?
Scott: So, I think he had a Windows CE-based smart, you know, PalmPilot thing, and he could watch the Sling video on that.
Scott: And he also, also in the office, at the time that I was there, they upgraded the whole phone system in the office.
Scott: So, we all got new phones that were all, you know, VoIP phones that were hooked up to software on the computer and, you know, everything, right?
Scott: And it's all Windows XP, right?
Scott: So, but the, he, on his desk, because he's a CTO, right, got the fanciest model of VoIP phone, right, to put on the desk.
Scott: And that model of VoIP phone ran Windows CE, and he installed the Sling app on it, and he watched TV on the VoIP phone in 2005, right, ish.
Rym: That is, that is a similar energy to that time when we were in college, driving to PenguinCon, and we had an access point in the car.
Scott: Right, the point is, Sling was an impressive technological feat of, like, video encryption, you know, from point to point over the internet, you know, with quality management, lag management, and such, right?
Scott: But just as a useful consumer product, the price they charge, you know, not worth it, they didn't make money.
Scott: But yeah, a notable, interesting thing.
Rym: Yeah, this fact doesn't fuck around either, it's like, question, will Slingbox be releasing any new products?
Rym: Answer, no.
Rym: No, we're done.
Rym: What about support?
Rym: Fuck you, is basically what it says.
Scott: So, I mean, on the one hand, I wouldn't never use their products, because I would never pay for cable anymore, but on the other hand, I sort of, like, you know, respect what they did.
Rym: Yeah, they got away with it.
Scott: It's a little sad, it's a little bit sad to see them go, but also, indifferent.
Rym: Yeah, well, because it's kind of like, it's one of those situations where if you or I, like you alluded to earlier, wanted to do something like this, we'd just use some open source software and the extra PCs we always have lying around and just, like, make it happen.
Rym: But normal people don't really have that.
Rym: Most people don't just have, like, an extra computer laying around, or five.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, in some other news, we do a lot of technology news on GeekNights Mondays, but very rarely do we do science news, partly because we're not experts in a lot of scientific fields, most scientific, all scientific fields.
Rym: Almost all.
Rym: I'd say I'm a lay expert in, like, a handful of areas I have deep hobby interests in.
Rym: But anyway, you know, we have not done, I don't think ever, in the 15 years we've been doing GeekNights, an arithmetic news.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Not, you wouldn't think- Did someone solve one of the problems?
Rym: The, uh- Yeah, I'm not talking, like, maths, like, general math, like, theory of math.
Rym: I'm talking pure arithmetic.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: Like, how to multiply two numbers together.
Scott: Well, I know how to do that.
Rym: There has been a relatively recent advancement from April of this year.
Rym: What?
Scott: In how to multiply two numbers together in a- Are you sure this isn't one of those things where someone way long ago in, like, India or Persia already discovered this, and someone rediscovered it, and they're pretending like they invented it?
Rym: No.
Rym: In fact, in 1960, a Russian mathematician basically finally, like, for millennia, it was- I'm quoting the article here.
Rym: For millennia, it was widely assumed that there was, in fact, no faster way to multiply numbers than the way that we all know.
Rym: The way you all learn.
Rym: The way I multiply numbers.
Rym: To this day.
Scott: Memorize it.
Rym: Well, for times tables.
Rym: But, you know, you take- You have two numbers.
Rym: You take the bottom number, and you multiply every digit of the bottom number by every digit of the top number.
Rym: And then you just do that, adding powers of ten as you go down.
Rym: You carry everything.
Rym: That's how you multiply.
Rym: For thousands of years, no one came up with a faster or better way to do it.
Scott: Pretty sure that in other countries, they teach the children to multiply it with a different way.
Rym: No, that way.
Rym: That way is the fundamental way.
Rym: Times tables and small ones, maybe, but multiplying two numbers with a large number of digits- Isn't there a way you can do it?
Scott: by drawing, like, lines, and then drawing lines across the other way, and then circling the intersections, and then grouping them?
Rym: Yeah, but that's not faster, and more importantly, it's not faster computationally.
Rym: All those methods require n to the two time, n being the total number of digits of the two numbers.
Rym: Give or take.
Rym: So, in the '60s, a Russian mathematician basically said, "Yeah, we're pretty sure there's no faster way to do
Rym: it.".
Rym: And this other guy just recently found a way.
Rym: After a week of searching, I guess?
Scott: What's the way?
Scott: How do I do it?
Rym: You can read this article.
Rym: This way is legit.
Scott: Can we make computers change to do it this way instead of the way they do it now?
Rym: Yes, the only reason this is interesting- Binary computers, not quantum ones?
Rym: This way is not really faster for a human to do, because very rarely will a human multiply two very long numbers by hand.
Rym: Very rarely are you going to multiply two 20-digit numbers by each other for funsies.
Rym: And the methods outlined here, you can go to this website, it's pretty straightforward, but basically, it makes the computational time to multiply two numbers together be linear.
Rym: That's a big deal.
Scott: Big if true.
Rym: This article does a really good job of explaining it.
Rym: I cannot paraphrase this article, because I am not up on modern theory of math or modern arithmetic or any of this, but if you read the article, it will explain it at a level of detail that you will understand, and it has a very good visual diagram of how this works and why it saves time.
Scott: I'd be very interested to see someone take an FPGA or something and set it up to multiply that way, instead of with the existing circuits, and see not only how much faster it is, because computers do a lot of multiplying, but also how much power it saves.
Rym: You can read the article to see all the details.
Scott: I don't know how many more transistors you'll need, because I haven't read anything.
Scott: I don't know anything about it.
Rym: There's a great quote here.
Rym: Except in the context of doing multiplication.
Rym: And this article made multiplication interesting to me.
Rym: Anyway, things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: So, much like many people do, when you discover a thing, sometimes you fall down some sort of hole on YouTube and consume all of that thing, right?
Scott: And then when you're a nerd, you just gotta tell someone about that thing, right?
Scott: So it all started.
Scott: I was watching some worthless K-pop video, right?
Scott: Where Seulgi from Red Velvet was answering stupid questions, because those are the only kind of questions you're allowed to ask idols, right?
Scott: And someone asks her a question, and they say, "Hey, when you go to the karaoke, what song do you
Scott: sing?".
Scott: And you're thinking, "She's probably just gonna say, might not even give a specific answer, because it might be
Scott: controversial.".
Scott: What if she mentions a singer who got in trouble or something, right?
Scott: And the song she says is "Bakwa" by Lee Jung Hyun.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Have you ever heard that song in your life?
Rym: No.
Scott: Yes, you have.
Rym: I should clarify that.
Rym: Almost definitely, I've heard it.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So, when I heard that, I was like, "What?
Scott: Is that that song?
Scott: Is it that
Scott: song?".
Scott: And I looked up, and yes, it was.
Scott: In the year 2000, when we played Dance Dance Revolution, the mix that was available at the time was third mix.
Scott: And it was well known, right?
Scott: Because fourth mix came out shortly thereafter, and then fifth, and then we sort of played less after that.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean, I play a lot more now because of COVID, but anyway.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: It was well known that there was a special third mix.
Scott: The Korean third mix.
Rym: Oh, shit.
Scott: And in the Korean third mix, there were two of the songs from third mix had been removed, but I think maybe six or eight songs had been added.
Scott: And one of those special added songs in third mix Korean was indeed
Scott: "Bakwa."
Scott: "Bakwa!"
Scott: "Bakwa!".
Scott: And it was that song.
Scott: So now, now that I find that for some reason I've been listening to K-Pop shit for almost a decade, it had never known, right, what the hell that song was or who the hell sang it, right?
Rym: I never thought about it.
Rym: It was the song I played because the third mix Korean machine was 25 cents for five songs in
Rym: "Wildwood."
Rym: Right.
Scott: So there was also another song in third mix Korean,
Scott: "Wah."
Scott: Right?
Scott: *sings* That is also Lee Jung Hyun.
Scott: So now I'm like, well, who the hell was this Lee Jung Hyun person making these songs in our, you know, mid-2000s techno dance style, right?
Scott: This person, Lee Jung Hyun, is a ridiculous person.
Scott: The Koreans have been keeping secret from everybody, right?
Scott: So she's like, I think she's like 40 now.
Scott: So I guess then she was like 20-ish, right?
Scott: She's a really tiny person, like a little tiny person.
Scott: And singing, I mean, she sings like a drunk person at a karaoke, right?
Scott: It's like, she doesn't have a lot of range.
Scott: But she can sing with the range she has, right?
Scott: Dancing, it's like, does she have a lot of dancing technique?
Scott: I mean, more than we do, right?
Scott: But not like the K-Pop people you have today.
Rym: Not the height of the craft that molds these people into entertaining machines in the year 2020.
Scott: No, not even close.
Scott: But when she dances, she's like a drunk person at a karaoke.
Scott: She's just like so excited.
Rym: You know what that gives me a similar energy to?
Rym: Captain Jack.
Scott: She's pretty much Korean female Captain Jack.
Scott: But another comparison would be, I think someone said, "Ah, Lee Jung Hyun, Korea's Lady
Scott: Gaga.".
Scott: And the reply was like, "No, no, no, no, no, no.
Scott: Lady Gaga is the US's Lee Jung
Scott: Hyun.".
Scott: So she obviously doesn't have the musical talent of Lady Gaga, who actually can really sing and play instruments and write music.
Scott: But in terms of every different song she has, she's got a totally different aesthetic and different stage going on.
Scott: Like one stage, she's wearing weird alien stuff.
Scott: And another stage, it's like disco time, right?
Scott: Every single time she comes back, she's got something ridiculous and some kind of gimmick going on.
Scott: It's just too fun.
Scott: And obviously if you're a DDR type person, you're probably going to enjoy most of this person's music.
Scott: So I went and I watched, there's not that many of them because her career was in the past mostly.
Scott: She's mostly an actress actually.
Scott: She's actually popular in China and Japan as well.
Scott: I guess they weren't telling us either.
Scott: But the point is, my thing of the day is the best single performance of Lee Jung Hyun that I could find.
Scott: The one that is the best one of this song called "Micha," I guess.
Scott: M-I-C-H.
Scott: It's a Korean word.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But yeah, if you like that sort of thing, if you go to YouTube, there's an hour long video.
Scott: that's like every single song she did, at least every title track worth listening to.
Rym: Oh no, I just went into my NAS to check on something because I have every DDR that was ever officially released for StepMania, obviously.
Rym: I have 3rd Mix and 3rd Mix Plus.
Rym: I don't have 3rd Mix Korean.
Scott: No, you're missing 8 songs.
Rym: I'm missing those 8 songs.
Scott: However many it is.
Scott: They might have been in later mixes though, I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I got it.
Scott: I feel like Wah might have been in 5th Mix.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Once I hit after 8th Mix, I kind of lose track of what's where.
Rym: And a lot of old songs like re-emerged in like X2 or X3.
Scott: But yeah, so it only took 20 years to figure out who this person was.
Scott: And then they have earned the right to be a thing of the day.
Rym: It was funny, as soon as you said "bakwa," the whole song played in my head.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And a lot of the other songs, I'm not sure if they were in DDR, but they have this ring of familiarity.
Scott: And I can't tell where I've heard them before or if I've heard them before.
Scott: Because they sound like 2000s techno songs.
Rym: Which is actually some of my favorite aesthetics.
Scott: Yeah, but some songs, she switches up the genres too.
Scott: There's one song, she was just punk rockin' on stage.
Scott: She doesn't care.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: So my thing is a very short fiction.
Rym: This is a science fiction story, narrated with a little like, animatic-looking animation on YouTube.
Rym: It's 3 minutes and 42 seconds long.
Rym: And, you know, we've reviewed a lot of different science fiction over the years.
Rym: Like, we talked about some Bradbury and some Heinlein and in the book club at some point we'll talk about in the future different science fiction.
Scott: Old 20th century white guy sci-fi.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But there's a lot of non-white guy sci-fi and a lot of different kinds of science fiction.
Rym: Some of my favorite science fiction stories are the ones that almost have a sort of form as function.
Rym: Where they're written in an odd way or they're very very short, like micro-fiction is something I'm a big fan of.
Rym: And this is a story.
Rym: It's titled "My Job is to Open and Close
Rym: Doors.".
Rym: It is 3 minutes and 42 seconds long, including the credits.
Rym: And it is the story told from the perspective of an AI whose job is to open and close the doors on a spaceship.
Scott: Oh, so I thought it was going to be the grocery store door opening device.
Rym: Oh, it's that kind of device, but it controls the doors on a spaceship.
Rym: But it's written from the point of view of an AI that has to figure stuff out based on what it knows about the world.
Rym: And the story is good, like.
Rym: it's 4 minutes long, not even, so like, spoilers, whatever.
Rym: But basically, the thing starts and a person goes into the airlock and hits the button and the AI is ready to open the door.
Rym: But the AI is like, "Wait, the person is not wearing a helmet.
Rym: Does that
Rym: matter?".
Rym: And that's the story.
Rym: Like, what's going on?
Scott: Of course.
Scott: I mean, that was sort of obvious.
Scott: that's where that story was going to go.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: The story is really well framed, partly because of the way it's told.
Rym: Like, the AI will interrupt itself to try to figure things out about humans or the world, but does not have all of the necessary information to figure these things out and is trying to make a path toward a decision point.
Rym: It's just really, really well done.
Rym: Like, this thing is great and I encourage you to listen to the whole thing.
Scott: If you don't have an attention span for that, I don't know what to tell you.
Scott: That's my style.
Scott: I'll check that out.
Rym: You'll like it.
Rym: I think you'll like it a lot.
Rym: In a moment, we actually have some really important meta news.
Rym: We've talked about this off and on.
Rym: If you don't know, there is a GitHub repository where we have been workshopping a new code of conduct for the broader GeekNights community.
Scott: Yeah, if you have a community on the internet these days, you gotta have a code of conduct.
Rym: Now, we had one a long time ago, but I kind of just wrote it and then Scott added a bunch of stuff to it.
Rym: And we're two white dudes with money, so clearly there are blind spots and biases that we wouldn't have thought about.
Rym: Like, we thought like, "Oh, we should ban Nazis,".
Rym: but there's lots of other types of behaviors that we wouldn't have thought about unless someone reminded us or prompted us or pointed at us and said, "Hey, what about
Rym: this?".
Scott: The point is we tried to strike a balance between accepting input from many sources and also hurrying our ass up and getting it done.
Scott: We probably didn't balance that that well, but whatever, it doesn't matter.
Rym: We solicited feedback, and more importantly, we got a lot of implicit feedback from people complaining about what we had put forth, and that actually led to some of the parts of this policy.
Scott: Anyway, we can't change the past.
Scott: This is the present.
Scott: We now have a code of conduct.
Scott: It is now 100% in force.
Scott: So if you want to participate in any GeekNights community, whether it's an obvious one like our forum or our Discord server, or if it is even just an official GeekNights meetup at some future when we can have conventions again, or replying to us on Twitter.
Scott: It's like if you violate our code of conduct by replying to the GeekNights account on Twitter, the GeekNights account on Twitter will block you.
Rym: Now, this does not apply to my personal Twitter.
Rym: My code of conduct is if you annoy me, I block you.
Scott: Yes, these are official GeekNights spaces, and you can read the code of conduct to get all the info, which you should, but you should also come participate in our spaces.
Scott: This is not like we now have rules and our spaces don't come.
Scott: It's like, no, we now have rules in our spaces.
Scott: Therefore, if you have not come, or maybe if you have left, or who knows, please come.
Rym: Even if it seems obvious, it's important to state out loud why a community exists and the parameters of engagement within that community, and we have codified it.
Rym: that was difficult to do.
Rym: It took a while to write this thing.
Scott: And if you want to, if you have any suggestions, if you come and look at it, and you maybe still see some problems even though it's been thought about so heavily, it will never be perfect and continue to be edited as the world changes forever.
Rym: And because this is GeekNights Mondays, I want to point out, it is in GitHub.
Scott: Or at least as long as GeekNights exists.
Scott: It is in GitHub, and if you want to- That's right, make a pull request.
Rym: Yeah, make a pull request.
Rym: If you have never used GitHub before, or Git before, and you don't think you're a technologist, you're listening to a Monday GeekNights, let me tell you, there is no lower stakes, zero consequences way to learn how to use Git than trying to submit a change to our code of conduct to me and Scott.
Scott: Yeah, you don't even need to know how to code.
Scott: It's a text, right?
Scott: Yeah, like the worst case scenario, Scott doesn't- You can even just submit an issue.
Rym: There's issues and bug tickets there.
Rym: Scott doesn't accept your merge request.
Scott: Yeah, you can submit an issue.
Scott: You can just email us.
Scott: You can DM us on any platform, right?
Scott: You know, as long as you don't violate the code of conduct while doing so.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But we're pretty excited about this.
Rym: We think it'll help codify this as time goes on because the GeekNights community is very fractured due to the fact that the world is different.
Rym: Forums are old.
Rym: Mostly old people use forums.
Scott: The Discord community- I guess most other things like podcasts, Twitch streams, any sort of content creator, a YouTube person, people don't set up forums these days.
Scott: It's like they have their YouTube, their Instagram, their Twitter, and whatever, and that's what they have.
Rym: Maybe there's a subreddit that they may or may not control.
Scott: They might have a Discord server or a subreddit.
Scott: People don't have forums in separate places these days, right?
Scott: Maybe they have a Facebook page.
Scott: I don't know what people have.
Scott: I do think forums are important.
Rym: I think it's a lost art that we need spaces like that that are a little more slow, a little more thoughtful, longer posts, more dense content, that kind of thing.
Scott: Yeah, but I think actually those people, because they don't have the forum, they're very active on all those other platforms whereas we are less active on those other platforms.
Rym: We are more active on the GeekNights Discord than we used to be.
Rym: I'm in there occasionally.
Rym: Scott's in there a lot.
Rym: I'm trying to be in there more as I have time.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: maybe we should try to be more active on all of them instead of just, I don't know, but regardless, they are now all governed by not only the codes of conduct on the respective platforms themselves, but also ours, at least as far as interacting in the space that GeekNights can control.
Rym: Yep, and the last thing I'll say about it is when you read it, one thing that is explicitly called out and it's relevant to the bit we talked about in the beginning, it is honestly like we don't fuck around with our terms of service.
Rym: You're not allowed to support the American Republican Party if you engage in any of our spaces, like at all.
Rym: That is literally written in our code of conduct for a reason.
Scott: Well, if somehow there's another big switcheroo like there was decades ago...
Rym: Oh, we'll update it if it changes.
Scott: We'll update it and we'll switch it around and be like, "Oh, the Democrats are the Nazis now.
Scott: Things
Scott: changed.".
Rym: But right now, the Republicans are the Nazis.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Otherwise, Tale of Genji, we'll see if we start reading it when it's cold.
Rym: I actually started reading again a little bit this weekend because I had a poop that took longer than usual.
Scott: What a big poop.
Rym: It was.
Scott: You ran out of things on your phone?
Rym: Well, partly because Twitter was just a sea of celebration to the point that I couldn't keep up with it and I actually broke my rule of read every tweet and just let it wash over.
Rym: I'm gonna re-engage with Twitter in a couple days when things calm down a little bit.
Scott: I got a new phone coming on Friday, I guess, so maybe I'll read on there.
Scott: It'll have such a nice screen.
Rym: Alright, so before we get into the main bit, someone who's in the stream right now just asked us for a link to the Discord and since they're active and on the stream, I'm gonna post that right now.
Scott: Yeah, if you go to our website, person watching the stream at frontrowcrew.com, you'll see there's all kinds of stuff going on there.
Scott: The website needs a big update, but all the information is still there and in the news about the code of conduct, there are links to the forum and the Discord.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm gonna send a link to the Discord right now just to this person because they seem cool.
Rym: Since we just said let's engage more with the people who are using these places, there's people in this stream, I will engage with you.
Scott: The code of conduct does apply to you people in that YouTube live chat.
Rym: Weirdly enough, this is like a random aside, YouTube is where I've had to have the least heavy hand in moderation.
Scott: Well I think as YouTube, despite YouTube comments being a shithole, YouTube does have an automatic filter that other spaces don't have.
Rym: But the other thing that's going on there is that the people who comment on GeekNights' videos in particular tend to be like 90% great.
Rym: It's not just that there aren't bad people there.
Scott: You're not gonna end up on how to win at Carcassonne as a recommended video next to a Nazi video.
Rym: We are definitely niche content when it comes to that.
Scott: Yeah, if for some reason Nazis were into Carcassonne lately, we'd be in trouble.
Rym: Alright, I have posted all those things to you in the stream and now we're gonna continue with the show.
Rym: Think of the day, think of the day, alright.
Rym: So, can't believe we never talked about this.
Scott: Or we did and you deleted it.
Rym: Oh yeah, of course I deleted it.
Rym: So the next GeekNights' Monday we're gonna talk about web browsers, which was our first idea.
Rym: But we realized in the old days, the Monday episodes of GeekNights, we would do these foundational series where we'd do a Monday and that would set the stage for the next Monday and the next Monday and the next Monday.
Rym: We'd be like, here's how binary math works, now we're gonna talk about transistors and we get up to computers.
Rym: So, HTTP is one of the most important things in the modern world.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: So I mean, it's just a protocol for computers to talk to each other.
Scott: It's a pretty high application level protocol.
Scott: It's not like, you know, it's on top of TCP.
Scott: So it's like computers connect with TCP and using that connection that's already got so many layers underneath it of stuff going on, right?
Scott: You're then going to use the TCP connection to speak the HTTP protocol between two computers to exchange information, right?
Scott: And this is an important protocol because not only is this how web browsers and web servers talk to each other using this protocol, but also because so many applications have been built upon the web, pretty much so many applications these days, even ones that aren't web browsers, are now speaking HTTP as a means of communicating with each other and avoiding having to code networking stuff, which sucks to code,
Rym: right?
Rym: Yeah, like you hear people talk about web APIs.
Rym: Like a lot of times, even like APIs will basically just act similar to how a web browser would work, hitting some random endpoint.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, and maybe it's the late 90s, early 2000s, you want to make a video game that's like turn-based, right?
Scott: And you want to have it be networked.
Scott: So what do you do?
Scott: You have to make a special server.
Scott: You have to come up with your own protocol, right, for how your game and the server are going to talk to each other, right?
Scott: You got to, you know, invent all this stuff.
Scott: And that's what games did in those days, right?
Scott: But now you can just be like, well, I'll just run a web server, right?
Scott: I'll run a web app, a web server, and then my video game that's running on someone's phone or on their switch or whatever is just going to make an HTTP connection to my web server and talk to it like it's a web page.
Scott: And we'll use that to send high scores or whatever logins, you know, just do it all the web way because all that stuff is already cookie cutter.
Scott: Save a bunch of effort.
Scott: So it's important to know how the HTTP protocol works to understand how a lot of the Internet works.
Rym: And you don't even, it's not even complicated.
Rym: Like we can pretty much explain the whole thing if we skip over like a few technical details.
Rym: And it's also not even that old.
Rym: It is less than 30 years old.
Scott: Yeah, it's not that old.
Scott: It's literally the web, right?
Scott: When someone says the web, they don't mean the whole Internet.
Scott: The Internet's bigger than the web.
Rym: They mean the WWW.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: The part of the Internet that is talking HTTP as opposed to talking any other protocol is the web.
Scott: And the rest of the Internet that's not speaking in HTTP is not the web.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: This is like Ted Nelson, Tim Berners-Lee Internet that we're talking about.
Scott: Even if you have part of the Internet that isn't talking HTTP, for example, an IRC server isn't talking HTTP.
Rym: Or if you're in a web browser, you type ftp colon slash slash.
Rym: That's not HTTP.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But people will make things like web-based IRC clients.
Scott: And now you have, you're speaking HTTP and something is translating that to IRC.
Scott: And you're talking an IRC, right?
Scott: So that's a thing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So HTTP, I think that the history lesson I do want to talk about, though, is what it actually stands for matters.
Rym: It is the Hypertext Transfer Protocol, because it was designed to allow people to build hypertext interactions.
Scott: The original design for the web, right?
Scott: The original World Wide Web, it was HTTP and HTML, the two pieces, right?
Scott: And the idea is that you have HTML, the Hypertext Markup Language, which is a way to make a document and a document with links in it.
Scott: And you could click on the links.
Scott: That would take you to other documents.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You realize links were called hyperlinks.
Rym: We call them links now because this history doesn't matter to most people anymore.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the idea of that having documents that link to each other.
Scott: Well, if the documents link to each other, you need some protocol for requesting the other document.
Scott: You have one document, you click on a link, you need to get the next document that you just clicked on the link for.
Scott: You can't download every document in the world to your computer at once.
Scott: You need to do it one at a time.
Scott: So HTTP and HTML go together.
Scott: You have the web browser, which takes HTML and turns it into a document that you can read.
Scott: But it also is speaking HTTP to web servers to get you more documents when you click on links or type in URLs into the browser.
Scott: And that's still basically how the web works.
Scott: However, the original design for the web was such the web these days is pretty much read only.
Scott: All of the writing is sort of done in not the original way that was intended.
Scott: The original way that was intended is that, you know, you would be like post to a web page to create a new document.
Scott: You would make a post HTTP call to create a document.
Scott: You would make an update call to update a document in place.
Scott: You would make a put document.
Rym: Imagine a world where Scott is running a web software.
Rym: I'm not going to say web server or web browser because those kind of came later in a lot of ways.
Rym: So Scott's running a web thing.
Rym: I'm running a web thing.
Rym: I have some documents.
Rym: Scott has some documents.
Rym: I just send a request to Scott's thing to create a new document on his server and it just appears.
Rym: And then I link to it from one of my documents.
Scott: I'm on Rym's.
Scott: I do a get to get a document from Rym.
Scott: I'm reading it.
Scott: I make some changes to it.
Scott: I send an update request via HTTP to Rym and his document updates.
Rym: Imagine the world wide web as originally envisioned as literally every web browser is a web server and everything is Wikipedia.
Rym: Literally everything.
Scott: Pretty much.
Scott: That was the original idea for the web.
Rym: Now it turns out spam and shitheads mean that doesn't work, but it was a noble idea.
Scott: Yeah, it can work in certain cases, but it didn't work.
Scott: So the way things actually happen is that most of the time when using the web you're making a get request.
Scott: You make a TCP connection to a server.
Scott: You send literally the letters "get" in ASCII, followed by some path.
Scott: Like get index.html.
Scott: Get /geeknights/2020-1109/something.mp3.
Scott: It's real simple.
Rym: You can do a packet capture and understand web traffic with your human eyeballs.
Scott: Yeah, you can just open up your terminal and type telnet space google.com and then type get forward slash and the HTML of google.com will just appear.
Rym: And if you do that on a simple website, you can probably read it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So that's what happens.
Scott: You send a get request and the web server sends back the document or whatever it is at that URL.
Scott: And then it's up to you.
Scott: You've now received that document.
Scott: It's up to your computer to decide what to do with it.
Scott: If there includes JavaScript, maybe your web browser will run the JavaScript.
Scott: Maybe not.
Scott: Maybe some of it.
Scott: Maybe not some of it.
Scott: There's HTML.
Scott: It's going to render it.
Scott: How's it going to render it?
Scott: There's instructions on how they would like you to render it, but it's up to you.
Scott: They sent you documents and what you do with them is now up to you.
Scott: And when you post these days, you're still sending data to the server, but the server isn't updating the document at the URL that you posted to.
Scott: It's, you know, probably performing some, you know, validation and computation and putting that data into a database and using that data in the database to then render and automatically generate documents.
Rym: Well, same with gets.
Rym: When you get, you very rarely get back like a file or a document that is stored somewhere.
Rym: You get back a dynamically created file at like created at the time you made the request.
Rym: Your request caused it to exist just for you in that moment.
Scott: Or at least part of it, right?
Scott: You make a get to Reddit.com.
Scott: They load a Reddit homepage.
Scott: that's your Reddit homepage.
Scott: You know, you make a Google search, they create a Google search result.
Scott: That's not, you know, it might be a global Google search result if you were like using private browsing or something, but it's probably a Google search result customized for you that the server generated, you know, ran some code when it got that request.
Scott: And then the code created an HTML document to send back to you that wasn't just sitting on the server waiting.
Scott: Although there are many static websites still out there, which literally are just a bunch of files and you request them and you get the files as they are on the disk and no computation is really happening.
Rym: One way why this was very important and different from how things were done previously, like you look at how Gopher and things work, like other methods to share documents or information was that, like Scott pointed out, it's sort of this two way thing, but it's also hyper generic, as we discussed.
Rym: But the third way it's really important is or the third thing that's interesting about it is that it is completely stateless in that once you complete a transaction, it doesn't matter that you have completed that transaction.
Rym: The server doesn't know that it was you that did shit.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: So if I make a post right with my username and password.
Scott: Right.
Scott: OK, well, OK.
Scott: And then the server sends a response and then that's it.
Scott: We're done.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It can't it doesn't.
Scott: if I then send another request like, OK, you know, get me my user profile.
Scott: It doesn't remember anything about the previous request at all.
Scott: It's a brand new request.
Scott: So how the hell does it know that I'm logged in, not logged in?
Scott: How how is the state happening?
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's every single request is brand new from the void.
Scott: Doesn't know anything about what happened in the past.
Scott: How do we carry the state over?
Scott: And that's we.
Scott: there's extra features that are built on top, which is basically cookies and headers.
Rym: Yeah, that's where like a lot of these things came from, because the protocol is so simple that it doesn't actually do very much.
Rym: And 90 percent of the logic you see in any web interaction is at a layer above HTTP effectively.
Rym: Like example, JavaScript, JavaScript, the data transfer, like, you know, a lot of URLs have like a bunch of random gibberish at the end and a bunch of like like that is your request in many cases directly.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: New kinds of files, CSS files that were invented.
Rym: In fact, early HTTP actually initiated a complete TCP connection for each request and then terminated that connection after the response came back.
Rym: They added the idea of a keep alive later.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And now they've got newer things like HTTP three slash quick web sockets.
Rym: That just came out.
Rym: That is like 2017, 2018.
Rym: Like that is brand new.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: it didn't literally just came out.
Scott: But in terms of the scope of the entire web.
Scott: Yeah, it just came out.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: In terms of like being used widely to actually check this out.
Scott: Web sockets are the WebSockets is like how Jackbox works.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: 2015, 2.0, 2018, 3.0.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, yeah, let's talk about the HTTP headers for a bit.
Scott: So the HTTP headers are.
Scott: is, you know, if you're just opening up your terminal and typing get forward slash, you know, it's like, well, that's all you're sending to the to the server.
Scott: But your web browser is sending a lot more information besides.
Scott: just get and the URL.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's sending all of this extra stuff like here's my user agent.
Scott: Here's, you know, the the kind of format I would I want to get from you.
Scott: I want to get this kind of content, you know.
Scott: Oh, and here, you know, I also here's a bunch of cookies.
Scott: Here's the things that I remember about the last time I visited this website.
Scott: And, you know, just all this that your browser sends a lot of extra just meta information.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'm visiting you.
Scott: And the reason I'm visiting you is because my user clicked the link on this other site.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Someone clicked a link on front row crew dot com.
Scott: I know that you're Google dot com.
Scott: I'm just telling you this is who sent me here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's just your browser just sends all this extra stuff and all that extra stuff.
Scott: The Web servers can now use that extra stuff and often do to make a decision about what to send.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, oh, you're using IE, I see.
Scott: I will send you different HTML so that it renders properly.
Scott: Oh, I see that you have included a cookie that you have saved that cookie.
Scott: Let me check my database here.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That is a cookie belonging to a valid logged in user.
Scott: So instead of sending you a login page, I'm going to send you, you know, the settings page.
Rym: Some of them are setting and just not like they don't mean anything anymore.
Rym: Like no one ever sends them.
Rym: Some of them have been sort of appropriated to do something different from what they originally intended just by consensus.
Rym: Some of them are used, a lot of them are actually used for performance reasons.
Rym: Like even in the early days, there's one.
Rym: I pulled up the list.
Rym: I was looking for it.
Rym: If on modified since, like that's an example that actually makes sense.
Scott: People use that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: A lot of them control things like caching, you know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But here's this example actually makes sense.
Rym: If on modified since basically says only send the response if the entity I'm requesting has not been modified since some previous time.
Rym: So I might send a get that says if unmodified since some date and Scott's web server just wouldn't respond.
Rym: And then I know.
Scott: Well, it responds.
Scott: It sounds like there's like a code for it, but it's like two oh something.
Scott: And it's just.
Scott: there won't be any actual data in the response.
Rym: I only get a header back.
Rym: I don't get the payload.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: But I know.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Nothing's changed.
Scott: You don't need to reload your page.
Scott: Just stay where you are.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So thus, Scott does.
Rym: I don't know if I keep that five in virtually through my system, but I'm using this if unmodified since Scott doesn't keep sending me the payload.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You're on the night's home page and you keep reloading.
Scott: Well, your browser is still making requests and getting tiny, tiny responses, but it's not actually reloading the page.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Then we upload this episode.
Scott: Suddenly you're going to get a real response and then you keep reloading.
Scott: And then after that, you're not getting real responses anymore.
Scott: You're just getting the tiny response again.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But yeah, all these headers, like you can send, you can put any header you want with any name and put any content in those headers that you want.
Scott: But it's just that we've come to agree over time, you know, between browser makers and web server makers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, these headers are going to have sort of codified behaviors and we're just sort of going to agree among us that this is what they'll mean.
Scott: And this is what you should do if you see them and you see these values in them.
Scott: And it's just sort of like these, you know, codes and rules you've come up with because you can make a header of anything.
Scott: So it's just.
Scott: it's just up to, you know, the community.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And various consortiums of people working together to agree that we'll do if these headers mean this, do things this way.
Scott: And if you follow those rules, things will function properly.
Scott: And if you decide to do it a different way, things might function not as users expect.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And sometimes you can always intentionally not do or do extra things based on what you see when you're talking in HTTP.
Scott: And that's up to you.
Rym: Like, for example, I might my server might say, oh, if the user agent string is foo, I know that that browser is broken and I'm going to serve different HTML to prevent there from being a problem.
Rym: But there's no standard around that.
Scott: So on my Web browser might say, well, if you see any, you know, HTML that looks like this, that's an ad.
Scott: So don't do this.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Because the big the way HTTP is used and the way HTML are used is that it's just a way to transfer basically these documents back and forth.
Rym: But it doesn't say none of this says anything about what to do with that data once you get it, because it's completely stateless.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, yeah, that's you know, if you really want to see the exact details about HTTP works, it's really not that scary.
Scott: If you just Google for like if you use HTTP to Google for how does HTTP work?
Scott: or what HTTP packets look like?
Scott: or, you know, what HTTP headers looks like and how they're formatted.
Scott: It's very straightforward.
Scott: You can understand it even if you don't understand anything else.
Scott: And all you got to know is that Web browser sends one and then the Web server sends one back.
Scott: And that's pretty much all there is to it.
Rym: There's only nine methods and most of them are never used.
Scott: Some of them are used these days.
Scott: They're still all available.
Rym: There's things that are used for weird reasons today that were never used for their original purpose.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I think the original purpose was to use all nine.
Scott: The hypertext world we were discussing, the Wikipedia world, right?
Scott: That never came to be.
Scott: So what happened is for many, many years, people were literally just using get and post mostly and really not using the other ones very much at all.
Rym: The head was used a lot for performance reasons before we had was used for debugging.
Scott: You know, you just want to see the headers, things like that, you know, things that normal people wouldn't be like delete patch.
Rym: But like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But nowadays, with the advent of like restful APIs, though, because those functions still exist and the code for them was still there, just slumbering.
Scott: People took advantage of those extra functions and have now used them to develop various APIs for different applications.
Scott: And so those are now being used in various ways, especially restful APIs, not so much other kinds of APIs.
Scott: But they're still heavily underused compared to get and post.
Scott: It's pretty much just if you can get and post, you're good.
Rym: And people misuse them like in the original specs, like get was one of the functions, one of the methods that is defined as it should not change anything.
Rym: You should be able to call this as many times as you want and nothing will ever change.
Rym: But I know there are definitely applications out there that will change their own state based on a get request.
Scott: Yes, that is because they're mostly that happens because of query parameters.
Scott: You make a URL and at the end of the URL, you put question mark A equals B, X equals hello.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And what happens is when the Web server receives that, they remove that part from the end of the URL and they break that into parameters.
Scott: And now whatever program is running on the Web server is free to interpret those parameters as it wishes, and it might do instructions.
Scott: So the most common use would be like for a search query.
Scott: Yeah, it'll be like, you know, you go to front record dot com slash search slash.
Scott: question mark Q equals water in the ceiling.
Scott: And now you're searching for the episode about water in the ceiling.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Stuff like that.
Scott: But most of the time you'll be doing for stuff like that, you'll be doing a post.
Scott: And the same exact query parameters that when you do a post, those same as a query parameters that would be would be in the URL are now in the body of the post.
Scott: You can't visually see them in the browser, but they're basically just in a different part of the HDV packet.
Scott: They're still there.
Scott: They're still the same format.
Scott: And the Web server will interpret those.
Scott: And that's considered to just be a better idea to not mess up someone's URL bar.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And to use the correct command.
Rym: It is definitely like.
Rym: it's kind of like when you see a Web site that has like really, really, really ugly overloaded URLs, like it's a sign that maybe it's not the most sophisticated system.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's other issues.
Scott: For example, let's say you're going to a form to purchase something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The Web was never intended originally for commerce.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like most of these functions are supposed to be idempotent.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You go to fill out your credit card information and your address and everything.
Scott: If you put that in the URL, which will totally work, by the way.
Scott: If someone writes their web, their eShop that way, their e-commerce platform that way, then now not only is that URL being sent over the Internet, like sort of unencrypted, I guess if using HTTPS.
Scott: We'll talk about HTTPS, I guess, finally at the end.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's still going to be like in your browser history, your credit card number just hanging out there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's not great.
Scott: So you want to put it in the post body when you fill out forms on the Web.
Scott: It's in.
Scott: That's a post.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You push the save button, the submit button, you know, the add to cart.
Scott: Check out button.
Scott: That's making a post request and sending all the information in the form to the server for processing in a not visible, you know, better way.
Scott: If you ever see your credit card information, your username, your password in the URL bar, change that password to something else and get the hell off that.
Scott: And if you're using that password anywhere else that you shouldn't be, change it and get the hell off that website.
Rym: I have never seen that except on malware sites.
Rym: I was poking at to see what the malware was going to do.
Scott: I've seen it back in the olden days.
Rym: In the old days, I saw it a lot.
Scott: The extreme olden days, extreme olden days, late 90s.
Rym: Not common these days.
Rym: So I guess the last piece.
Rym: Notice there's no log in, log off, any of that.
Rym: That's all handled by applications.
Rym: There's also no encryption or security of any kind in anything we've said so far.
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: Nada.
Scott: So if you have access to a network and you can, you know, read the packets on that network because it's your router or something, you can see all the HTTP traffic going back and forth and you can see, oh, this person visited this website and this is what came back.
Rym: They typed this password.
Scott: This is the kind of porn they like.
Scott: And since HTTP is so easy to understand, you can just read it with your eyeballs pretty much and understand what's happening.
Rym: I have done this troubleshooting problems in my life.
Scott: And if you use software to make it even easier to read, well, now you can really see everything.
Rym: So HTTPS is basically the way to wrap this whole exchange in an encrypted channel, basically.
Scott: So what happens is before you start talking in HTTP, you make an encrypted connection with the web server.
Scott: And there's a whole schmageggy that goes on here.
Rym: It used to be SSL.
Rym: It's TLS now.
Rym: And TLS, the exchange that happens, is actually very complicated.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: But what you have to know is the important part for users to understand is the certificate signing issue, right?
Scott: So there in the world, there exists the certificate signing authorities, right?
Scott: CSA.
Scott: You might have heard of these.
Scott: Verisign is a big one, like maybe the biggest one.
Scott: But there's others, some small, some big.
Scott: Let's Encrypt is like the hot one, which you should probably be using.
Scott: And what they do is they're basically saying, look, we're a certificate signing authority.
Scott: You trust us, right?
Scott: We're basically a house of trust.
Scott: That's all they exist for.
Scott: And what they do is they verify that their customers who are coming, who own websites, who run websites, are who they say they are.
Scott: So if I have a website and I want my website to be secure, I go and I say, hey, hey, hey, trust house.
Scott: No one trusts me.
Scott: I'm just Scott.
Scott: They trust you, though, because you're a giant organization.
Scott: I want you to tell everyone that I'm trustworthy.
Scott: And they say, oh, well, we're going to have to come and investigate.
Scott: Are you trustworthy, right?
Scott: Are you who you say you are?
Scott: And then they say, OK, we talked to Scott.
Scott: We figured it out.
Scott: Scott is who they say they are.
Scott: This Web server is definitely owned by the person who at this domain is definitely the person who just came asking us to sign their certificate.
Scott: So I make a cryptographic set of keys.
Scott: They basically put a rubber stamp on my cryptographic set of keys.
Scott: And then I now have a number, literally a number, in a file on my Web server.
Scott: And that number mathematically proves with cryptographic levels of no doubt that the trust group has said that I am trustworthy.
Scott: So then when you come to our website, before we start webbing and you start sending me your name and password and stuff, we send back, we do a little math between each other to arrange for some cryptographic keys between us.
Scott: And because I have that cert from the trust house and your Web browser also has a cert from the trust house baked into it, your OS probably has some baked in as well.
Scott: I know Windows has a huge list of them.
Scott: Your computer trusts that group.
Scott: That group trusts me.
Scott: Now your computer trusts me.
Scott: Now you verify.
Scott: you basically assume that I am who I say I was and not an imposter trying to set up like chase dot com.
Scott: That is not actually chase dot com.
Rym: Yeah, but it's just our friend Chase.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: I didn't make a fake Chase Bank Web site, you know, to try to trick you into typing your bank password into something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then you now know the top left of your browser where that little lock icon is, is going to be locked and not unlocked or red or have a skull and crossbones.
Scott: And you've ever clicked on that thing.
Scott: It's going to be nice and green and happy.
Rym: And you keep clicking until it shows you the details.
Rym: You can actually see like the details of that certificate, who signed it, when they signed it, how strong it is, everything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it serves these two purposes.
Scott: One, the Web site you're visiting is the Web site you think you're visiting.
Scott: It's not an imposter.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And two, now that you trust them, you you do a key exchange and you create a temporary set of symmetric keys with which to encrypt all of the HTTP that you are now going to speak at each other.
Scott: So if anyone on the rest of the Internet decides to try to look at what your conversation is, try to look at the credit card you're sending to Amazon, try to see the password you're sending to the forum or discord or whatever, you know, your secret messages to your lover, whatever that will be encrypted and no one will be able to read it.
Scott: Tough cookies.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's beyond the scope of this show.
Rym: But as of now, the way this is done is is secure at the time of the transaction.
Scott: And if you're using the newest correct ways and everything is set up properly and your browser is not been tampered with and there's so many caveats.
Scott: But if you, you know, under normal circumstances, you're good if you see the green light.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Modern TLS is incredibly powerful and it's complex to the point that I cannot explain the full handshake without referencing a guide because it's actually way more complicated than SSL was.
Scott: If you want to learn that, YouTube videos.
Rym: If you want to learn that, there will be a job for you forever.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Greenia, Graham Finch, you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: I pulled up to the house about seven or eight.
Rym: Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perry, Chris Midgiff, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, just like a dude guy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Chirping Ron Horrell and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: And now, I leave you with...
Scott: Celebrity Jeopardy.
Scott: We've got three wonderful celebrities playing for charity.
Scott: Let's meet them.
Scott: Sean Connery.
Scott: Hello.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Connery, it's your turn.
Rym: I'll take movies for 400.
Rym: The answer is John Travolta learned how to dance for this 1977 hit movie.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Connery.
Rym: That would be George.
Rym: No.
Rym: Jaws is incorrect.
Scott: And please answer in the form of a question.
Rym: Sean Connery, it's still your board.
Rym: I'll take swords for 400.
Scott: It's actually not swords.
Scott: Swords.
Scott: These are words that begin with S. The answer is Popeye is this sort of man.
Scott: Sabre.
Scott: No.
Scott: It began with a bloody S. All three celebrities are $800 down.
Scott: The hell if I'm going to pay you a bloody $800.
Scott: Please rest assured, Mr.
Scott: Connery, this is for charity.
Scott: It's not your own money.
Scott: And it is still your board.
Scott: I'll take movies for 200.
Scott: This racing movie with Dom DeLuise told us that, yes, cannonballs can run.
Rym: Sean Connery.
Rym: I'll not pay this fine I've incurred.
Scott: It's unjust.
Scott: You don't have to pay that Jerry Lewis.
Scott: Okay, let's just move on.
Rym: Bert, can you please pick a category?
Rym: Pick swords.