Rym: It's Tuesday December 15th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about the fantastic hypno space outlaw.
Scott: Let's do this All right, so you know these days stuck inside.
Scott: It's getting colder.
Scott: I'm like double stuck inside I guess like yeah like.
Rym: I got one last hike in this weekend because it was weirdly warm on Sunday like Mercishly warm, and I feel like that's one.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it used to be.
Scott: well try not to go outside, but it's warm.
Scott: I'm gonna go outside if I can kinda right now.
Scott: It's like I don't even want to go outside.
Scott: It's gold.
Scott: So I've been.
Scott: you know all the stuff that you have lying around your nerdy house those nerdy things that you never get around to Like the old Apple computers you bought or acquired somehow in the late 90s And then have just carried around with you and kept in the closet and never used.
Scott: It's like huh well.
Scott: Let's have fun with those.
Scott: right we like computers.
Scott: So I managed to get all sorts of.
Scott: you know there are all sorts of new things Available that weren't available a long time ago to make these old computers easier to use right like things to adapt MicroSD cards to speak to.
Scott: you know old Apple floppy interfaces and things like that.
Rym: yeah I remember how trouble it was to mess with those Apple things like back at RIT when you were messing with them.
Scott: Yep, so the Apple to GS is actually doing great.
Scott: the memory expansion card that it already had and it works.
Scott: It has one megabyte of RAM.
Scott: It seems that all of its parts work.
Scott: The screen is actually pretty unbelievable.
Scott: It works super well, and the image is super clear.
Scott: that old crazy RGB monitor stuff like a special thing is not VGA.
Scott: So yeah, everything's good in that department.
Scott: Just the keyboards not you know the most fun to type on.
Scott: The Mac Plus has like is like an up-and-down right.
Scott: so the Mac Plus is like You know is an old Mac.
Scott: the kind that you know was at the built-in monitor right with the floppy under it, right?
Scott: And it totally works.
Scott: Not don't need to mess with the floppy drive because like I said I got other tools to.
Scott: you know avoid that.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it'd be broken anyway And I don't have any floppies that will work in it.
Scott: to begin with the screen is actually kind of got an unbelievably clear Image.
Scott: it's working so well and The mouse works right.
Scott: oh the the Apple to GS problem Is that the have a mouse for it.
Scott: that works, but it doesn't have a ball.
Scott: So I'm like sticking my fingers in the.
Rym: oh no That is that is so work optimal.
Scott: I'm working on solving that one Egg and then get the ball out of there.
Scott: yeah the So on.
Rym: so fun fact if you open that thing up.
Rym: You know how that thing works.
Rym: It's actually an optical mouse Mmm.
Rym: Those rollers are not.
Rym: what do you think those rollers are doing?
Rym: Let me make sure.
Scott: the Apple mouse spinning a piece of metal with a gear.
Rym: no Well it is, but that piece of metal is spinning a wheel that has markings on it, and there's probably a light in there.
Scott: That's.
Scott: I haven't opened the mouse to find out.
Rym: I'll check if the Apple to mouse was actually that this is like a third-party mouse.
Rym: Oh, so you don't have the original.
Rym: yeah most mice from that era were technically optical mice because that was the only way to make it Accurate.
Rym: you'd have like computers 1986.
Scott: yeah anyway The point is the Mac plus.
Scott: I upgraded it from one megabyte of RAM to four megabytes.
Scott: in order to do that I had to take out the motherboard right swap for swap for Sims.
Scott: I guess I didn't even know if they're dims or whatever they're.
Scott: you know memory sticks, right?
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I don't know what they are.
Scott: I bought them on the internet.
Scott: They worked.
Scott: They were cheap.
Scott: They were like a couple bucks.
Scott: But I also there was a resistor on the motherboard and if the resistor is in the computer Thinks the memory chips are small.
Scott: so I had to remove the resistor.
Scott: So I basically unsoldered one of the two halves of the resistor and pulled it out.
Scott: So it's still stuck in there, but you know it's not it's not connecting.
Scott: So that way if you ever want to put it back in right you can.
Scott: it's still sitting there.
Scott: Then right.
Scott: so in the back.
Scott: I have this thing that you know converts from SCSI to micro SD.
Scott: The problem is is that the Mac plus does not provide what is known as SCSI termination power.
Scott: So I don't know how many people know, but SCSI the old SCSI interface To my RIT computer.
Scott: right it was used by mostly PCs.
Rym: I mean mostly by Macs, but also some PCs and PC anything like ultra high-performance extremely expensive option.
Rym: Right
Scott: you could use it for printers hard drives various other devices And the way it worked is you could actually daisy chain Several devices together so you have one SCSI port and you could plug cable a to device one And then you connect from the back of device one to the back of device two and then from the back of that device to Your printer to the back of another right and so on.
Scott: and as you set this little dials on the back of all the devices So you choose which number they are.
Scott: so this is device one two three four five six however many you can support And then all these devices will be able to communicate with the computer Even though at the end of the day all of those signals are going over.
Scott: What's basically?
Scott: one cable Right it's a lot of pins on Inside.
Rym: there's a bunch of like parallel nonsense And I used to remember I used to know intimately all the details about SCSI work.
Scott: But yeah this one only has 15 pins actually, but it's still the same functionality is still there.
Scott: So like you know if your printers if you have three hard drives in a printer when you print Right those electrical signals go all the way down all the hard drive cables and back and the hard drives are doing stuff at the same time.
Scott: right anyway.
Scott: so Scuzzy termination power.
Scott: there was some electrical phenomenon.
Scott: I don't fully understand it, but well the way It's been described is that The signals would like bounce off the end of the chain, and you would get sort of like an echo off the end.
Scott: So there needed to be some sort of termination right to prevent that echo from Bouncing off the end of the chain of cables and like messing up all the data.
Scott: So some devices would provide termination power and some would not right.
Scott: so If for example you know you have a Mac plus here the Mac plus does not provide it.
Scott: So that means that like you plug a hard drive in that hard drive has to sort of do it itself Right to be have a terminator at the end of some kind otherwise it would just wouldn't work.
Scott: so this little device Obviously you can plug in a USB cable to it to provide that power you know to get the termination.
Scott: But it would be much nicer if you could just stick this in the back of a Mac plus and be good to go right With no having not having to go get your micro USB cable and another power outlet or whatever a battery or something right.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: So in order to there happens to be Right the Mac plus if you take the motherboard out.
Scott: right next to the SCSI connector in the back There are these two holes where it looks like something should go and nothing's there.
Scott: And it just so happens.
Scott: if you take a diode and put it in that spot Then suddenly you'll have SCSI termination power.
Scott: They added this feature to the Mac plus and never enabled it with a single dial.
Scott: They could just put one diode in every Mac plus.
Scott: They didn't.
Scott: and back in the day this Mac plus cost like a fortune right to buy one new.
Scott: You know they couldn't add one diode to it's like.
Scott: come on.
Scott: I bought 50 diodes for like $2.
Scott: I'm not.
Scott: I'm sure they were more expensive in 1986 whatever, but not that expensive.
Scott: So I did that.
Scott: that worked.
Scott: the memory upgrade worked everything worked.
Scott: It was so great.
Scott: this Mac plus is running like Quite.
Scott: amazingly and also quite amazing that you can get the Mac plus to run Mac OS like 75 which came out and like you know the like which is like many many years newer than the computer itself.
Scott: It really makes me think about how old iPhones run the newest iOS.
Scott: So it's sort of the same thing like the super old Mac would run like a Mac OS that came out so many years afterwards.
Scott: The problem is the keyboards not work.
Scott: I don't know why the keyboards not working.
Scott: I don't remember if it was broken before or after I did all this stuff.
Rym: Oh, no That's the worst because if you knew they know it worked at some point then it's a different calculus.
Scott: Then did it work right.
Scott: so I took my.
Scott: I took my meter my multimeter.
Scott: luckily if you take the if you open up The keyboard case this it is easy access.
Scott: because though the keyboard connects to the Mac plus with like old Telephone rj10 right and it's only four wires Five volt ground clock and data, that's it.
Scott: four wires for the keyboard on an rj10.
Scott: So the problem is is that there's basically no other keyboards in the world that like do rj10 except this one stupid keyboard for the Mac.
Scott: That's the only one.
Scott: There's a lot of adapters out there where that will let you use this old rj10 keyboard with Another interface.
Scott: it's like on a. you could use it on a newer computer.
Scott: There aren't a lot out there to use a ps2 Keyboard.
Scott: you have to like make something with an Arduino in order to use like a ps2 keyboard and convert it to use the rj10.
Scott: It's also not standard rj10.
Scott: You can't just grab a phone cable.
Scott: I think the wires don't line up straight.
Scott: They think they're.
Scott: you know, they're.
Scott: the pin outs are different on either end I forget.
Scott: but anyway, I tested the pin outs and everything seemed right.
Scott: So I'm thinking the keyboard might be broken.
Scott: but getting a new keyboard for this is actually not the cheapest.
Scott: So it's kind of sad that like I upgraded this Mac plus all the way and like without a keyboard it It's kind of sad, but once it works we can play Carmen Sandiego or some shit.
Rym: Ah, yeah the fellows We can't even do like.
Rym: like.
Rym: we could set up a show where we like fuck with it and do something semi-live But we can't even like media.
Rym: I can't go play with this thing.
Scott: No, what's really sad is like you just open up an emulator.
Scott: it just works better and way faster.
Scott: Emulator is just better in every way this.
Scott: How much reason is there to actually use the old computer versus the emulator?
Rym: Yeah I guess the only reason to use the old computers for the aesthetic of having the hardware there or if you're doing some sort of Hardware verification of some behavior that's different.
Scott: Yeah, something like that or like.
Scott: I actually set a virtual box.
Scott: I installed Windows 3.1 in VirtualBox and It's just way better than having a DOS PC.
Rym: I don't need to go buy a 486 Alright, so there's a lot of gaming news like a ton and we're not gonna talk about everything.
Scott: It's been so long since we did a Tuesday show and it feels like there was so much gaming news But I can't remember anything that happened before today.
Rym: So let's just talk about what happened today Yep, or things that happened recently and there's a cluster.
Rym: There's like three story.
Rym: Well, there's really like five stories, but I want to condense them all into issues around cyberpunk 2077 Right.
Scott: So I gotta start with saying that like this game was announced and it was like such a huge announcement People were so hype over it, but I'm like, wait a minute.
Scott: This is based on cyberpunk 2020 the tabletop RPG.
Scott: I thought that was like an obscure thing that only tabletop RPG people and like netrunner players knew about.
Scott: you are correct.
Scott: The original Android netrunner was.
Scott: I mean Android netrunner was based on the original netrunner and the original netrunner used the intellectual property from the Cyberpunk 2020 RPG.
Scott: right, but I don't.
Scott: actually I actually don't know people who've played it.
Scott: It's like people know of it.
Scott: But like if people have played it, they don't talk about.
Rym: I mean the only cyber punky RPG I ever played was second edition shadow run and that is a shadow run.
Scott: I've heard of people playing.
Scott: I'm.
Scott: cyberpunk is like a thing people know of every art tabletop RPG people know about but people didn't play.
Scott: Right, you know, yep, but so I was very surprised to see that the cyber the the to my knowledge first ever video game based on this property was like triple a mega game of like Untold proportions.
Rym: I mean, I honestly didn't even think about it as being based on that property.
Rym: Not like that didn't even cross my mind.
Rym: All I thought was cyberpunk is a very generic term for a particular kind of cyberpunk is a very generic term.
Scott: but to my knowledge the only thing that like titles itself as like Cyberpunk the game is that like I'm pretty sure if you tried to make another game called Some cyberpunk like that was the name of your game that like art alsorian would come after you with the trademark lawsuit or whatever.
Scott: I mean that especially if you did cyberpunk followed by a year, right?
Scott: Cuz the original was 20/20 and this one's 27/7, right?
Rym: I just want to point out that that is the.
Rym: the Wikipedia page for this game does not mention this at any point.
Scott: Okay, interesting But I'll be that it's not.
Rym: what you miss is that it wouldn't have mattered.
Rym: either way The hype machine for this game was running at possibly the maximum.
Rym: I've seen a triple-a video game studio run since like the era of giant ARGs.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen.
Scott: you know, we've seen big games get big hype but like like Yana Reeves doing the stuff like this game Pulled out all the stops, but also this game was on it's on every platform.
Rym: Well, there's a big asterisk next to that now Right.
Scott: Well, it's on it's.
Scott: you know, it wasn't just.
Scott: it wasn't an exclusive.
Scott: I don't think it's on switch Is it?
Scott: I don't think so, but it's on PC xbox.
Rym: Better on the switch than it seems to run on the ps4 Maybe but the point is it's on like everything right?
Scott: So they're trying to get as many people to buy this game as possible.
Scott: It's not some exclusive, right?
Scott: So yeah huge huge deal.
Scott: then there was while it was being developed.
Scott: There was all sorts of controversies coming out.
Scott: They were crunching the team big time, right?
Rym: Yeah, that's one issue that we need that in general I could came up in this game for a lot of reasons But the video game industry is broken as shit.
Scott: in the triple-a space in particular There was also issues where not only were they crunching they kept delaying.
Scott: so it's like if you're delaying Right, you know, everyone's already buying the game.
Scott: Just pull a half-life.
Scott: 1.
Scott: It's ready when it's ready.
Scott: Why do you got to be like this?
Rym: Yeah, well, especially because I've won is legendary.
Rym: We're gonna climb it now where if you announce a triple-a game that appeals to like a particular subset of gamers, you know exactly who I'm talking about.
Rym: if you tell them a release date a Scary percentage of them will plan their lives around that date, which cool you can be into a thing.
Rym: But then if that date changes they will not only flip out, but they will start harassing your developers.
Rym: They'll start sending you death threats Like it's a problem almost to the point that like if I was a triple-a studio Even if I didn't have the philosophy you and I have of do it the way valve release games I wouldn't give release dates just to avoid that harassment.
Scott: Yeah, like anyway.
Scott: So they delayed the game and they crunched the team at the same time To make this game and so the game finally comes out, right?
Rym: Yeah, and there were a number of controversies along the way that we talked about in the past.
Scott: Well, so the actual release of the game was rocky.
Scott: It wasn't just like here.
Scott: it is it like Some people got it.
Scott: reviewers got it, but reviewers only got the PC version, right?
Scott: So reviewers only got the PC version.
Rym: They didn't get the console versions and it turns out the conversations don't fucking work, right?
Scott: Well the reviewers got Gave it bad reviews.
Scott: Well, not bad, but like sevens.
Rym: They gave it its I they gave it accurate Reviews and of course remember I refer to those gamers earlier.
Rym: Yeah, if you give any game that they're excited about a score of less than nine point eight, they'll send you death threats Right.
Scott: So it's like there's these people who for some reason have never played this game Assume they can't possibly have anything wrapped up in the intellectual property.
Scott: It's not like it's Right.
Scott: I don't understand.
Scott: they were just like somehow had become in in love with this game where they're like getting super mad That someone gave it a bad review insulted even though they've never played it.
Rym: I think about that sending a death threat to a developer for a game reviewer.
Rym: Yeah to a reviewer and a developer the developers for the late the delays and the reviewers for talking about the game Of a game that you have not played.
Rym: that does not have a franchise history.
Rym: That isn't even out.
Scott: Yeah, it does have a history.
Scott: But I just questioned whether the people who are sending the death threats have any involvement in the history whatsoever.
Rym: So but one of the issues that happened specifically was they wanted this wide release so they released it.
Rym: You can technically run it on an or an x-bone like an actual Xbox one Xbox or a PlayStation 4 and Reviewers didn't see that as far as anyone can tell and people bought it.
Rym: They played it on those consoles and it went about.
Scott: as they don't have a ps5 or an Xbox series.
Rym: Nobody has a ps5.
Rym: The only thing harder to get than a ps5 is a 3080.
Scott: She's like look what I got and I'm like who cares?
Scott: I mean actually I have a computer.
Rym: I could if anyone I I could get a ps5 I did like any time But all I want is a 3080. if someone out there can get me a 3080.
Rym: I'll do swaps ease.
Scott: No, you're traded fee.
Rym: I'll even pay the difference between the MSRP.
Rym: But a lot of people got ps5s because they had connections But ps5 is not nearly as sold out as 3080s are obviously but there were a lot More ps5.
Rym: it is not.
Rym: we would be remiss to not point out that you and I and the people we are friends with in The gaming industry are more connected in a sense that it is easier to get something like a ps5 through No matter how many people I know.
Scott: if I wanted one the way I would get it is just go to a website like everyone Else and just go to Amazon and be like bye and wait.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of people I know got it By talking to someone who worked at a company who had extras or pulling shenanigans.
Scott: I would not do that getting a review Console pre streaming edition of a console.
Rym: a lot of streamers got him early Mexico PlayStation.
Scott: Well, they don't have any on Amazon.
Rym: So yeah, but yeah anyone out there if you can get me a 3080 I will die will get you a fucking ps5 and it'll be a good time.
Rym: so now they they're issuing refunds and apologizing and vowing to rebuild trust after they basically had to admit that this game just does not run on those old consoles because they Radically underpowered for a game of this scale really just built the way it was and designed the way it was like
Scott: They crunched and they delayed and the game still.
Scott: the console ports Basically are buggy and crashy and non-worky.
Rym: Well, a lot of it is just that the the console port the consoles are not powerful enough to even run the game.
Scott: So like textures, you know I You know for you just make your software more optimized and also scale back on your.
Scott: you know, right It's like.
Scott: yeah, Mike my computer is weaker than someone who has a 3080.
Scott: But if I bought this game, which I never will you turn the settings down I can do settings down.
Rym: The problem is got your computer's no settings.
Rym: your computer compared to any current generation console like not the ps5 Like let's say that's next-gen because they're coming out right now Your computer is infinitely more powerful than a current generation console That's true.
Scott: But a console release at least in theory right is like consoles historically have always been less powerful than PCs.
Scott: But that's because when you release software for a console that software is usually running like exclusively, right?
Scott: You don't have like 10 web browsers open eating.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: like look at a look at it and also and then look at a PC game that was released the same year
Scott: All right, and also because you're releasing a game for the console You know exactly what chips are in that machine and you can optimize your code At least if you bother to go through this effort.
Scott: and because you have to write if your game doesn't need it Or if you don't have the budget or time for it, you don't do this, but you can optimize specifically for those chips that you know are in the console and you know will work right and Make the same software just run better, even though the hardware is using less power and is weaker, right?
Scott: But whereas on a PC you would make a PC release of your game Unless you want to release the source code of your game and have everyone compile it on their own computers You're releasing an exe file and that exe file has to run on who knows how many different computers with different chips in them AMD's Intel's who knows what the fuck people have in their computer.
Scott: It has to work.
Scott: And so, you know this we have things to make this better than it used to be.
Scott: in the DOS days We had to like, you know code for every sound card and make people choose their sound.
Scott: Yeah, now you just have DirectX.
Scott: it's a lot easier But you still have to.
Scott: you know You can't optimize as much and therefore since this exe is less optimized people need a more powerful video card Right in order to run that software a more powerful CPU to get the same performance.
Rym: So all that aside the thing I want to talk about the most is something that was just kind of ridiculous and egregious.
Rym: so cyberpunk 2077 has a kind of extreme Epilepsy triggers.
Scott: Oh, yeah, which apparently I think people are speaking about one part in particular When you put on the glasses in the game a character puts on the glasses, it's at least based on the description.
Scott: It sounded like a character was putting on the glasses.
Scott: They live style.
Scott: The glasses were very blinky blinky, but they were blinky blinky.
Rym: It's not even just like they were blinky blinky.
Rym: They happen to be blinky blinky in a way.
Rym: That is particularly extra dangerous to photosensitive people like some That style guide say avoid this pattern.
Rym: if you're gonna do blinky blinky don't use red and white.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I think there was you know on Twitter I don't know the people who were tweeting.
Scott: they could have been fake obviously who knows.
Scott: but the people on Twitter were like people with Epilepsy who were saying yeah The blinky pattern was basically almost identical to the blinky pattern in the glasses The doctor has when the doctor needs to make you have an epileptic seizure on purpose for doctor reasons.
Scott: I'll make sure that you know, right and it's like.
Scott: it's almost like someone took those glass almost as if someone took real life.
Scott: Make someone with epilepsy have a seizure tool and turned it into a part of the game Like you would not be like.
Scott: we don't know if this was malicious intent But like you would not be.
Scott: based on the smell is that rates are?
Rym: Indistinguishable when they?
Scott: yes, right, but based on the descriptions I read you would not be Perhaps out of line and have being very sus.
Scott: It's us.
Scott: We'll see how.
Rym: it's even worse than that.
Rym: There was no warning in the game except in the EULA.
Rym: The game didn't.
Rym: even you know most games like it.
Rym: every NES game had a giant warning on it.
Rym: That was like hey if you have epilepsy don't play this game like.
Scott: yeah Nintendo loves to put warnings.
Scott: They even have warnings like hey, don't break your TV with your remote, right?
Scott: Yeah you know, they always have health and safety warning on fucking like.
Rym: there was no warning in game and Even if let's say like there are use cases for that kind of effect but if you know anything you don't make the effect like This specific pattern.
Rym: that is particularly dangerous.
Rym: this implies that nobody in their entire team Making this game over 500 people at any point talked about epilepsy or Accessibility or anything like.
Rym: this is all they were just.
Scott: they were just crunching to get it done.
Scott: They were just crunching to get it, you know done done, right?
Scott: They weren't?
Scott: all those other concerns go out the window, right?
Scott: That's what happens with that sort of culture of work is like just get it done.
Scott: We care about making money first, right?
Scott: What can we cut away?
Scott: You're right.
Scott: We can cut away man.
Scott: Okay, don't spend time optimizing the console don't spend time On the accessibility right.
Scott: that's not needed to put it on the store shelf.
Scott: Don't do it.
Scott: We're working around the clock.
Rym: Yeah, et cetera, but even worse.
Rym: then they not only that warn people.
Rym: There's no option to disable it.
Rym: Like it's like we're not saying that games can.
Rym: I think they did?
Scott: They did put out a patch to do something about.
Rym: yeah, they're doing they're doing stuff But this level of omission from a company like a project this big is particularly egregious.
Rym: This isn't some like indie developer in their basement making something for fun.
Rym: who doesn't know better Like there's?
Scott: no this is someone who spent all this money on marketing obviously instead of actually development.
Scott: Yep, right Make everyone want to buy a thing.
Scott: who cares what the thing is, right Gabbo?
Scott: So the final nail for this at least the the final nail I'm aware of and I don't know exactly which Content is causing these rumblings, but I have seen and read many many rumblings And from people I do know who they are so I'm inclined to believe them that there is Significant transphobic content in this game.
Rym: Oh, yeah There's.
Rym: there's that.
Rym: there's also the fact that the game is kind of like Procop pro capitalism like it's literally the opposite of cyberpunk.
Scott: It's not what cyberpunk is.
Scott: Yeah, exactly I don't know.
Scott: and it's like I know, you know, I only know these meta things about this game.
Scott: So basically, you know my opinion beforehand right was like like I was saying I didn't know people cared about cyberpunk 2020 or knew about it except table top RPG people.
Scott: Why is this triple-a?
Scott: enormous right?
Scott: and my you know my feeling at the time of the big announcement was like I'll maybe I'll buy this in a steam sale one day when it's ten five dollar, right?
Scott: It's a one-player game.
Scott: This is timeless.
Scott: I need to play it now.
Scott: It's not multiplayer, right?
Scott: Whatever My feeling now is I will never play this game.
Scott: Even if it's zero dollars fuck this game.
Scott: Yeah, this is obviously the biggest shit show we're gonna be.
Scott: you know, it's not a Duke Nukem Forever shit show but it's almost worse cuz Duke Nukem Forever was just Mismanagement and it's also this is like this is actually, you know harmful.
Rym: Yeah Well, it's also almost worse because it is still pretty broadly popular and it's doing fine.
Rym: Like they're gonna make their money.
Scott: Oh, yeah, they're making big money.
Rym: Cuz you know Duke Nukem a lot of people lost money because of all those problems like that was a different situation.
Rym: here They are like this game is going to continue to reward the broken Aspects of the games industry at the triple-a level almost to the point.
Rym: I've said this before on GeekNights.
Rym: I've said it in panels of hacks.
Rym: They'll say it again.
Rym: I Don't think triple-a games can be made ethically in the current world like full stop.
Rym: I think it's impossible.
Rym: And that resonates with that tweet.
Rym: you see it makes the rounds like every few months.
Rym: it makes the rounds the tweet that says something Like I want to see shorter games with worse graphics made by people who work less hard, and I'm not kidding.
Scott: Nope, I agree with that like the game.
Rym: We're about to review.
Scott: Yeah, it's more fun to play links of the past randomizer than like, you know, like do maternal right?
Scott: I played do maternal.
Scott: That was fun.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: I paid I buy did buy it when it came out.
Rym: Yeah, I bought it when it came out.
Rym: It was good.
Scott: I had a lot of fun with the previous doom and the previous doom and the previous doom and the previous Every doom You know, but you know what?
Scott: I played it once I beat it and I was done even breath of the wild.
Scott: I played it.
Scott: I played it longer than I played do maternal But I played it I beat it and I was done.
Scott: links at best randomizer.
Scott: I'm you know a game that's 20 years old.
Rym: part of that your years older.
Rym: your predilection has become become increasingly esoteric.
Scott: I'm just saying links at best randomizer is 30 years old.
Scott: I think almost You know link to the past is almost 30 years old.
Scott: the randomizer isn't?
Scott: That's that gets more replay value than any of those things, right?
Rym: so saying that someone made me feel even older than when you brought up scuzzy and I remembered buying a scuzzy car to make My new cable modem work because previously the cable modem was plugged into an ISA scuzzy card and it wasn't fast enough.
Rym: Mm-hmm ISA anyway it's in some other news.
Rym: we can go through this stuff kind of quickly.
Rym: so we get to the main bit.
Rym: but Nintendo there is a ton Relative ton of little indie games having remakes or releases on the switch.
Scott: Yeah, Nintendo had a big announcement today as of this recording December 15th, and they announced a pile of indie games they're releasing and they also Added some more Super Nintendo games to the Super Nintendo app and whatnot.
Scott: But anyway, so the games they added were Among us obviously right the biggest hit of 2020.
Scott: I think that's a great game to have on switch.
Scott: It's an easy port.
Scott: They're gonna.
Scott: they're gonna make money on that price on it for five bucks I imagine because that's what it costs on Steam.
Scott: Maybe they charge more for it on switch.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: No, it's five bucks.
Rym: I just checked.
Scott: Okay good But yeah, it cross plays too.
Scott: So if you maybe you know, it's like do I need this?
Scott: Will I buy this?
Scott: probably not but you know what I have among us on my PC You know, maybe you want to sit around with your friends and play among us, you know You don't want to use your phone.
Scott: the switch is probably better experience.
Rym: Yeah, the problem Here's the one problem I have the I can say like at that use case I can see like maybe I just want to lay On the couch and play among us while I'm on the discord instead of doing it like on my PC.
Rym: usually it's not that case because I'm the one hosting the game, but When I'm at a con I imagine for a second.
Rym: Hey, we all have switches.
Rym: What if we just busted out in among us while we're all like sitting in line for the Omega thon?
Scott: But yeah, you could do that now.
Rym: I've never successfully gotten the switch to play a local multiplayer online.
Rym: wife our local Game at a convention in my entire life.
Scott: This would obviously use the internet right?
Scott: You'd only they say local local Wi-Fi.
Scott: Oh, they added that good job.
Scott: We'll see if it works for any player online or via local Wi-Fi.
Scott: So next see they spelunky and spelunky - obviously legendary platformy roguelike II.
Scott: ish game, right?
Scott: If you haven't if you don't know spelunky, well, you know, it's on switch now.
Scott: They're fun of them.
Scott: Yeah, they're hard grind really hard.
Scott: Grind stone is a game that I played when I had a free trial of Apple arcade.
Scott: I played it on my iPad.
Scott: It's like a little kind of puzzly game, but it's not like micro transaction II.
Scott: Right and it's sort of like one of those almost like a pattern recognizing one.
Scott: Do you remember that?
Scott: What was that one on?
Scott: the?
Scott: was on the GBA or the DS?
Scott: I think was DS.
Rym: Remember that game that was on the GBA or the DS.
Scott: Yes It's on the DS and I think it was like a might and magic and there was like you will line up the monsters of The right color.
Rym: I know exactly what you're talking about.
Rym: It was a it had a name was here was a might magic like special something something like that.
Scott: But the point is it's not.
Scott: the puzzle isn't like that puzzle But it's that same kind of game where you're optimizing like your next lash of heroes.
Rym: I think is it yes?
Scott: So like you're this little Viking warrior, dude And like you optimizing like what your next move is gonna be on this grid of like monsters and things, right?
Scott: So it's actually a pretty fun game.
Scott: I got bored of it after a while But I occupied my pre bedtime gaming for like a few days.
Scott: a good toilet game.
Rym: I say I kind of want to play clash of Heroes again.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: It was actually real.
Scott: go Calico is a game I saw at PAX East.
Scott: I think maybe I saw it.
Scott: maybe at magfest also I don't remember but it's basically a game where you're building a Cat cafe right.
Scott: so it's a little neko Atsume not microtransaction II right and if you look at the trailer It's like you're going around the woods riding cute animals and then arranging your cafe.
Scott: This game seems to be like way good.
Scott: I might get this kid.
Scott: And then the long-awaited right super meat boy forever that we have seen at Various conventions in its, you know pre-release state pretty much forever.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's apt that they called it forever too.
Scott: Like I said, this is much like do do come forever.
Scott: It's in development But yes, it's finally a real full-on sequel to super meat boy.
Rym: more new super meat boy thousands of levels and many different characters.
Scott: Yep, it's gonna come out on December 23rd And I think the only console it will be on at the time will be the switch.
Rym: I think it might be on PC at the same time also Perfect for that so I can play forever try to get trying to finish a level so I can watch the replay and go to Sleep.
Scott: it will not be on Expones or PlayStations at least not immediately.
Scott: It will only it'll be on switches and I think possibly PC on December 23rd this year the for real.
Scott: It's actually You know done done.
Scott: here it comes more meat.
Rym: yep, there's a bunch of more games in the list.
Rym: you can check it out?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's all the games on the list, but I don't know anything about those.
Rym: looks pretty good a happy game.
Rym: I don't know if I've heard of it or not But it's described as a psychedelic horror game set in a bizarre dream world and this game.
Scott: sure some of these games are great I'm just don't know them.
Rym: Yeah, but the image of it looks particularly good and weird in a way that jives with me Very nice.
Rym: the switch is also getting an anime watching app to watch Funimation, but not crunchyroll anime.
Rym: But that doesn't matter cuz crunchyroll is gone.
Rym: We'll talk about that next week on Wednesday.
Rym: Yeah There's so much so everywhere yep.
Rym: Yep wait till next Thursday.
Rym: We could we could do a whole show just on what Disney announced.
Rym: We don't need to do that There's one like ten more Star Wars shows literally literally ten.
Rym: But yeah this the app will let you watch anime on your switch if your switch is your device.
Rym: I feel like this is mostly aimed at kids who don't have an HTPC or a PC or a tablet and Want to watch anime at home or on their house?
Rym: but anyway things Of the day, what do you got?
Scott: What was my thing of the day?
Scott: It was the right?
Rym: Yeah, okay?
Scott: So my friend we were having a discussion and someone linked this to me a friend.
Scott: There is a YouTube channel called ordinary sausage and my thing of the day is just gonna be one of their videos although the whole channel.
Scott: I watched some other videos in the channel and they were okay But this one was the best one.
Scott: and what this channel is is there is a person and this person has Sausage making equipment.
Scott: right.
Scott: they have you know sausage wrappings, right?
Scott: They have a grinder with which to grind up things to put into the sausage And they have I guess I don't know what the device is called a sausage press where you squeeze You know you put your sausage wrapping on the end of the pipe you squeeze whatever your filling is and it goes into the sausage Which you can then twist off and seal.
Scott: and then of course they have a stove with a frying pan on which to cook sausage.
Scott: and all they do on this channel is take things that Are you know some more unusual than others and they put them into the sausage, right?
Scott: If it needs grinding they grind it.
Scott: if it you know needs mushing they mush it right and they just make Sausages of various things.
Scott: and here they make a sausage just filled with oil Just oil.
Rym: the best about the videos where they pour oil in the pan to then cook the oil sausage.
Scott: yep.
Scott: So for another example of video on this channel that was actually like you know a less ridiculous one is.
Scott: they made a McRib sausage.
Scott: They took an entire McRib sandwich You know bread and all ground it squeezed it in and actually they gave that five stars like and I could understand Yeah, that could be a good sausage.
Rym: It'd probably be better than just a McRib.
Scott: Yeah, maybe but you know that's what.
Scott: that's what you have here.
Scott: And also I just want to give this isn't thing of the day worthy because it's sort of cheating.
Scott: But I just want to mention this video.
Scott: There's a video how to make fried water.
Scott: There's what they did is they took water, and they used some sort of this Chemical that you get from algae.
Scott: It's like something something out.
Scott: sodium alginate I think they said, but there's other varieties other different alginates like semi.
Rym: solidify the water right.
Scott: what it does Is it allows you to form a membrane around the water so basically like a little water bottle right?
Scott: That's sort of like goopy.
Scott: it almost looks like a jellyfish blob right.
Scott: and then they took that jellyfish blob Floured it breadcrumb you know egged it breadcrumbed it right and then fried it in oil And without getting it to pop and thus making fried water And that I thought that was mildly interesting, but also sort of cheating right.
Scott: And also when they ate it they sort of like didn't just pop the whole thing in their mouth They squirted the water out, so that's why they don't get they're not thinking that a status cuz they're Yeah strong the oil sausage commits the oil straws.
Scott: it is much more powerful and Terrifying.
Rym: do not eat this Yeah, so yeah You know I'll go.
Rym: one of my things today was the worth the kids channel because they may other than big top burger.
Rym: They've made many recent delightful Meme-able animated shorts like Palpatine's journey like just solid channel making great content and all the content though most of the things they uploaded had sort of Like a similar aesthetic style of writing style of humor, and that's cool.
Rym: Say like.
Rym: the animation looks similar like I'm down for that But that meant I couldn't just keep using them as a thing of the day.
Rym: over and over again goes against the GeekNights code.
Rym: Today they uploaded something very different from what they've done up to this point.
Rym: It looks like stop-motion animation And it's a music video to just a straight-up song dried up old bones by Tom Willett.
Rym: Okay, the skeleton in the desert But it's particularly where they can.
Scott: were they commissioned by this person to make the music video?
Rym: for oh, no if I if I if I Am correct I've Tom Williams who I think it is he was like in the 70s.
Rym: Okay, but I don't know if it's the same Tom Willett.
Rym: I did not do any research on this.
Scott: I'm not and it's not a person I know about
Rym: but the video is extra great because it's just he's singing this country kind of song about us being a bones died In the desert and all his friends come to check him out like the desert spider and there's a cute desert spider kind of dancing next to him and his friend the snake who's dancing and it's clearly a rattlesnake who is Warning him away, and it's just really cute and fun and good, and you should watch it.
Rym: hmm in the meta moment Can't go anywhere.
Rym: We're still here.
Scott: obviously I have not received the book signal.
Scott: What signal out there in the sky?
Rym: yeah, actually I was playing a hypnospace outlaw.
Rym: I was also working on stuff.
Scott: See ya most of the stuff you know.
Scott: I said earlier in the in maybe weeks ago that yeah I'm gonna have these huge vacation.
Scott: well obviously you know.
Scott: I think I also mentioned the huge vacation was decreased.
Scott: But after this Friday the huge vacation is back on its.
Scott: I'm gonna have I think 16 days of no work in a row.
Scott: that includes the weekend days.
Scott: I will accomplish Something.
Rym: we'll see.
Rym: I actually have most of next week off because I had a bunch of vacation days I have to use before the end of the year.
Rym: I lose them.
Scott: What I have accomplished is I am There's advent of code which is an annual Computers sort of a coding sort of competition thing friendly.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just live-streaming myself solving these coding puzzles every night until I guess Christmas which wouldn't be the last ones To stick on your keyboard.
Rym: so we get some ASMR Scott.
Scott: Well, I've actually worked hard to get rid of the keyboard noise.
Scott: But you know if you go to my YouTube There's a few of the first three or four.
Scott: so I uploaded to YouTube.
Scott: the rest are.
Scott: might the twitch VODs might still exist Might not who knows.
Scott: But yeah, you can come and see me do those usually every night ish Eastern time whenever I you know I'm done working.
Scott: I get around to it.
Scott: You know.
Scott: So that's the thing I'm doing right now.
Scott: And also, I'm still streaming myself biking, but I haven't biked in a little while.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: Maybe I'll bike today after dinner.
Scott: But the problem is I need to do the puzzle also.
Scott: I think that's sort of what's you know.
Rym: do the puzzle while biking.
Scott: It's too hard.
Scott: I can't do that.
Rym: So yeah watch our stuff on the internet.
Rym: we live stream this.
Rym: there's like 20 people watching this live stream right now.
Rym: There's a vibe.
Rym: There's a pretty rocking chat going on right now.
Rym: Join our discord.
Rym: there's links on our website.
Rym: Read our GeekNights community code of conduct because it is I think very good and also very specific About things you are not allowed to do in the GeekNights community.
Scott: So come and participate in our community and just make sure that you abide by all of those behaviors and You know do not conduct yourself in a way contrary to the code and everything.
Scott: you'll have an awesome time with awesome people.
Rym: Yeah, there's good people in there.
Scott: All those all those think about all the parts of the internet that you do engage with community.
Scott: wise you know They're all shitty right.
Scott: well.
Scott: We can.
Scott: we're trying to make a good one over here.
Scott: So you know it'll be better with you in it.
Scott: So let's talk about Hypno space outlaw Alright, so again at PAX long long ago.
Scott: Maybe a magfest.
Scott: who remembers This
Rym: is one of those games where I saw it Like I walked over and I looked at it and all I thought was I don't need to even play this now or talk to Those people I'm just gonna play this game Someday when it is rare
Scott: was.
Scott: there was a Siri.
Scott: I can't remember.
Scott: I don't know which ones came first or anything like that But there was a. there was like a trend of games that that where the user interface of the game looked like an old computer.
Rym: There were multiple indie games that did this effectively right.
Scott: well the oldest one that I personally remember playing was uplink Which is didn't really look like an old computer, but it was still a game where you're ostensibly You know you.
Scott: are you using a computer that has an interface that wasn't the uplink interface wasn't anything like a normal Windows.
Rym: it was like thing right.
Rym: movie hacking like you were playing a movie exactly doing movie hacking But then there were other games.
Scott: You know all right other notable games like.
Scott: Emily is away.
Scott: the user interface Looks exactly like a little instant messenger.
Scott: It's obviously a well instant messenger for Windows 95 right but You know it obviously doesn't say Windows 95 on it or a well as to message on it right But you basically it's.
Scott: Emily is away is like a visual novel But you're basically chatting with people and making dialogue decisions through what looks like ale instant messenger, so hypno space outlaw is About this sort of never really existed, but yeah it totally existed.
Scott: late 90s online service much like prodigy AOL CompuServe right.
Scott: however It is none of those right.
Scott: It's sort of all of them and none of them.
Rym: Yeah, because it's also like an internet simulator where you have like a computer that you're running with like browsers.
Scott: right you have a computer.
Scott: Right you can run hypno space software on this computer, but the thing is hypno space is not just like a normal internet service From the late 90s although it is the late 90s, and it has late 90s vaporwave aesthetic to it
Rym: But it's more
Scott: just less
Rym: vaporwave and more true to what that aesthetic was in its time.
Scott: Both I think.
Scott: yeah But hypno space is an internet service.
Scott: You can only use while you're asleep, so you would go to sleep.
Scott: It's like up time for bit like you go about your day right which isn't part of the game at all.
Scott: Go about your day, and then at the end of your day It's time to go to sleep, and it's like well You're gonna waste eight hours of the day if you just sleep.
Scott: sleep like a normal person right.
Scott: so plug in hypno space And your body will sleep, but you can have productive hours Doing hypno space shit.
Rym: And it's kind of like how I actually used computers because I would go about my day Be like midnight, and then instead of going to bed.
Rym: I'd sit down in front of my computer I'd dial in to like Wow or whatever and I'd be online all night.
Scott: But imagine if you also got sleep right so it hit no space right?
Scott: you know in the Realistically speaking you're not actually going to sleep right?
Scott: your character is going to sleep into hypno space.
Scott: yeah But you're sitting there, and you have this mouse.
Scott: You know keyboard based user interface.
Scott: that looks a lot like a late 90s online web service.
Rym: like to the point.
Rym: It's so spot-on like there's a browser.
Rym: It's basically got a win amp installed as an application.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they put a lot of effort into this making it complete.
Scott: It's not one of those things where it's like oh Yeah, you can only click on a few things, and it's mostly just pick.
Scott: you know a background.
Rym: everything works like When we start the game.
Rym: it does a little like bios load, and if it says like hold B It for by if you do that.
Rym: There's a fucking BIOS.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you know you could.
Scott: There's like a search engine.
Scott: you can search.
Scott: you can find things when you search.
Scott: you can click links.
Scott: They work install software that get install software.
Scott: you can remove software.
Scott: you can get viruses.
Scott: you can play music.
Scott: You can download more music and add it.
Scott: it's like they have just created so much content that it feels like an complete Internet service right yep, so how is this a fucking game?
Scott: isn't it just like a you know just a You know sort of like a sandbox where you explore all the content that they made?
Rym: Sandbox, I think I still would have enjoyed it.
Scott: Oh, I probably still would have also for quite a while But not as long as if it was a game because basically the game on the one hand reveals to you a great story But also Forces you to explore the content that they've created.
Scott: right.
Scott: so by playing the game You're sort of forced to follow this path along which you are seeing all the great stuff that they made.
Rym: yep You're basically playing someone who for whatever reason volunteered to be a moderator in Hypno space.
Rym: So you have a special version of the software in some ways.
Scott: It's almost Like Pokemon snap only you you control the vehicle right where it's like.
Scott: you know they've created all these wonderful Pokemon for you to see and enjoy watching them right along the sides all these web pages songs you know Places in Hypno space right emails things for you to see and do And you're going along enjoying them right, but you're charting your own course.
Scott: But you also definitely have a target that they've given you of where you want to get to right.
Scott: And what's really amazing is that?
Scott: All this content even though it's all kinds of varied random stuff it really feels Like the drama and the social aspect.
Scott: right.
Scott: there's these fake characters.
Scott: They're obviously not real people right, but they're really made.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: you know there's the chowder man right and you go to the chowder man's webpage, right?
Scott: And it's like then you'll see a comment on another web page from the chowder man, right?
Scott: It's like there's all these characters that they've made up.
Scott: who have are the other people in Hypno space?
Rym: like the first job You get as a moderator is there's a report of this kid Zane is harassing people.
Rym: so you're like I'm gonna find him.
Rym: you find Zane's web page, and it's amazing.
Rym: But then you fuck around and like look for like all right who is he harassing?
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: You gotta kind of like do some detective work And you find all these other people who have interacted with Zane in some capacity And like you can solve the puzzle.
Rym: It's almost like a puzzle game like the puzzle in this one was find some reason to ban Zane like.
Rym: that's what they want you To do and you've reached trivial to find a reason to ban Zane.
Rym: you find his secret web page, and he's a little piece of shit.
Rym: but Then you find all these other people and you find all this other interesting stuff.
Rym: That's also kind of relevant to the Zane situation.
Scott: Mm-hmm Such a just a punk kid.
Rym: he's a punk kid doesn't know better and the people he's harassing are also kind of harassing him And it's like this right.
Rym: They're all teenagers right.
Scott: This is what I was trying to get at.
Scott: is that all this content They've made has a second level and this well has multiple levels.
Scott: But the the second level is that it's even though it's very random stuff Right it's.
Scott: you can see.
Scott: it feels like you're a part of a real internet community That is developing and you can.
Scott: you're experiencing the drama between the people much like you experience drama if you're the part of something like a live journal community or a tumblr community or any of the.
Scott: you know a Forum on the web somewhere or some IRC channel and you see you have characters that you know based on their internet names and the drama That plays out between them and their different personalities.
Scott: This is totally believable.
Scott: you could have put this on a web page and people would believe it was a real forum.
Scott: Yeah, and it wasn't just a piece of art right the imitating life because it is the thing that is so amazing about this game.
Rym: It's like Scott.
Rym: I grew up in the era where the internet was like very much like this.
Rym: pretty much this game For us is also deeply nostalgic like I would interact with things and see things that I Specifically recognize as touchstones of the way I use the.
Scott: I had real web pages that you could if you could somehow find them.
Rym: Oh, I made some pages that look a lot like pages in here.
Scott: Yeah the oldest web pages of For my old days that I still have are like from 2000. if you could find my ninety nine ninety eight ninety seven like earlier web pages You could just paste them into hypno space outlaw as no changes.
Scott: No, you could find my geocities page.
Scott: You can just paste it right in.
Rym: and when Scott I first became friends in RIT I remember we showed each other our geocities pages because geocities was still up.
Scott: It was yeah.
Rym: If only we thought to back that shit up.
Scott: I Mean I tried.
Rym: yeah, I mean I could have just downloaded the.
Scott: I backed up.
Scott: I do have backups going pretty far, but not just like just a little bit past.
Scott: I can't get.
Rym: yeah, but anyway for someone who did not grow up in that era like you might miss like there's references to like Specific technology things that you might not notice that wouldn't matter.
Rym: but for a younger person who didn't grow up in that world I think this game is equally compelling because it's almost like a Simulation of a previous era.
Rym: it is very true to the feeling like if you play through this game You will feel the kinds of things that we felt when we were young interacting with a very different internet.
Rym: It's very true to that feeling.
Rym: it's very true to that experience and That is kind of amazing.
Rym: like that shows that the people who made this game really Understood like what the internet and what services like prodigy pre-internet were like Mm-hmm.
Scott: so yeah, there is a greater.
Scott: It is sort of a visual novel situation where there is a greater plot right that you are discovering.
Rym: It's a pretty good plot to like.
Scott: it does have an ending at some point although after the ending you obviously can load up Hypno space and just sort of.
Scott: you know poke around all the content You know to see everything a freely as you would like And is because of the way the interface is.
Scott: there's tons and tons of hidden stuff.
Rym: Like so it's so free It's you know and so fully featured, but the gameplay loop like if you want to think about like what is this?
Rym: What are you doing in this game?
Rym: It comes down to you're a moderator.
Rym: You get emails and dispatches from like the people who run the company who are like like deal with this report like there go find This problem.
Rym: There's some malware someone uploaded like go find it and like tell us where it is.
Rym: we get rid of it and You can click on links.
Rym: You can follow people's stuff install their software and even to search type of word and You can solve a lot of things with clever human intelligence.
Rym: the game has like no rails really Except a few very specific rails based on certain plot events like when you get to the image map.
Scott: Yep But also you know depending on certain choices right the game might be easier or more difficult to you.
Rym: Like if you get a virus and it's it'll be bothering you all the time Yeah, but move it like the way to solve an early puzzle is to kind of get a virus on purpose.
Scott: Yep Professor you are you gonna pay money for the virus remover?
Scott: It's like you can buy software.
Scott: Yeah in this like there's like this e-commerce like you can get money in the game and then go and there's things to buy with The money right, but there's like a little bit like I won't spoil stuff about this game because there's a lot in here.
Rym: But what I will say is that professor helper was obviously malware.
Rym: But no shit.
Rym: the task I had was Find like this anyone who's using this cash app that like we don't allow on our platform to transfer money and get rid of it.
Rym: And it's obvious that this malware is using that cash app to steal money from people.
Rym: So I installed a malware and then the malware gives me pop-ups that link to the cash app.
Rym: that let me find.
Rym: the people who?
Rym: Are scamming.
Rym: but now I've still got malware.
Rym: So I reported the malware which I was not tasked to do.
Rym: like you could report malware I reported it.
Rym: They rejected my report and the CEO of the company starts bitching at me for reporting it because he's trying to make a deal with that company.
Rym: The other thing is very true in this game that I found really fun Is that the two people who run merchants off like the company that runs all this they are to a T Exactly how people who ran those 90s internet startups were like.
Scott: it's a very Steve Jobs Wozniak kind of do right.
Rym: one of them right incorporates others and has like a modicum appearance of ethics.
Rym: and But I'm saying a modicum here.
Rym: There's a lot going on.
Rym: Not just right.
Scott: That's the tech guy.
Scott: There's a technical guy.
Scott: a technical guy clearly has some sort of morals and ethics right wants things to work a certain way Etc.
Scott: and then is the business guy.
Scott: and the business guy is just like get it done Right.
Scott: do they do this?
Rym: business guy types like?
Rym: Ceos typed for real in that era and many still they were people who made this game did an amazing job.
Scott: They are really masters.
Rym: Yeah, and the game also has a nice good meta commentary.
Rym: like the very first task you get is They tell you about this character and they're like there's.
Rym: there's effectively like copyright claims about this character.
Rym: So bad like go ban anyone and delete anyone who's using this character without permission from this company And it's this ugly goldfish thing.
Rym: So uh start poking around and of course the first thing you're gonna find is this like six year old girl's fan page with the fan Art she drew and you feel real bad about it as you delete her page and get her in trouble Mmm, like that's the kind of stuff this game makes you do or ask you to do and maybe you approach the problem a different Way, and there's.
Rym: there's a lot of paths to solve problems Mm-hmm, and it's hard to say more without spoiling things like.
Rym: the game's not that long.
Rym: It'll take you Five or six hours to beat it Seeing most of the fun stuff along the way Maybe like seven or eight hours if you like really poke around and like dig into side quests.
Rym: I can't imagine this game being more than ten hours long.
Rym: Even if you like read every page.
Scott: Yeah, I know if you just want to beat the game it will not take you long at all.
Scott: in fact, there was a speedrun of it at the Previous GDQ that I think was like they found out it was a world record like after the fact.
Rym: Oh someone in the chat's already like gums.
Rym: Your grouper is not ugly.
Scott: Yeah, it does not take.
Scott: You know, it doesn't take long if you just want to beat the game.
Scott: but if you want to explore deeply all the content and like really read everything and and you know Scan everything and dig deep and find secret stuff then you can spend quite a bit of time with this You know and you can always go back to it and I think they added more to it since I've played it So I might I might go back to it and have another look and just enjoy.
Scott: You know the various songs.
Rym: when I got it what I what I found a site that had pirated music And I went to it.
Rym: it looked like Exactly, like the website I used to download mp3s from before Napster and when I clicked on a song it was a broken Fucking link.
Rym: all of the links were broken just like it was back in the day.
Rym: Yep You should like.
Rym: this game is a I would say like if you were Enthusiast of interesting game experiences like you should play this game.
Rym: Do not think this game is only for people who are nostalgic for this era.
Rym: That is the opposite of true this game.
Rym: No, we'll let you are Yeah, like this game will let you experience that era in a very true way.
Scott: I think pretty much anyone who is a person of the internet is a person who will enjoy This even if you're not a person of games, right?
Scott: Yeah, I think this is this is really just an entertaining piece of software for any Internet II person.
Scott: right a person who engages online Right will enjoy this.
Scott: a person who doesn't understand internet and is you know, not an you know.
Scott: A person who like reads tweets or you know does any internet communities?
Scott: I can imagine you might have a hard time like connecting with what this, you know game is saying.
Rym: Yeah I can imagine like a pre internet person like someone who grew up before the internet existed.
Scott: right nothing to do with like Computer skills, you'd be very good at computers and just not.
Scott: a person who like socializes online or engages in.
Rym: you know internet You know like you got to get into the mind of a 13 year old punk kid to solve some of these puzzles.
Rym: Right, right.
Scott: if you're not the person who shares things online or you know consumes things shared by others online You know reads comments that sort of post comments.
Scott: This game might not you know ring anything for you, right?
Rym: I guess the last thing I'll say is that the one of the things I really appreciate is that the game the only way to learn how to play this game is to start playing it and you have to run like the Tutorial software in the game on your game computer and it is identical to the tutorial software.
Rym: I had to run for a lot of things in school through much of my childhood Right down to the CG animation of going through a door.
Scott: Yep All right.
Scott: So hit no space outlaw came out a while ago.
Scott: It's an a-plus game.
Scott: I don't know what it costs.
Scott: It's worth it.
Scott: Even at the full price I would say.
Scott: but I did buy it in a sale at some point and I'm sure you can get it in a sale.
Scott: I'm pretty sure you can get it from Steam or itch.io and maybe other places too.
Scott: I think it actually come out on switch and even came out on switch.
Scott: I think it's on a lot of platforms.
Scott: I think came out a lot of platforms.
Rym: now There you go, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot-com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patreon is for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Marty Green.
Rym: yeah link eg a fresh dot net slash tilde Rym slash podcast - beta Grant Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: now.
Rym: get through the last year.
Rym: so podcast and make Rym sing.
Rym: Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Chris midkiff dread Lily Tenebrae Just like a dude guy Chris Reimer Finn Shervin Von Harl and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: So now at least on this Tuesday, I leave you with something that would be fitting in hypno space Oh.