Rym: It's Tuesday October 20th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about Star Wars squadrons.
Rym: It's out.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: you may recall we were gonna do this show a couple weeks ago, but Horrible water came up out of my sink and that was an odyssey to deal with.
Rym: it is now dealt with but I had to Deal with it, but this past weekend.
Rym: I wanted to go out hiking Which like that like hiking in the remote wilderness Much like biking in the middle of nowhere is a decent hobby to have in the middle of a global pandemic Like stay away from people be in the middle of nowhere This time and
Scott: everyone has the same idea Away to the woods.
Scott: There's no people there.
Rym: They do have that idea But the vast majority of people will never get more than a mile away from a parking lot or a trailhead.
Rym: So you just go somewhere remote get to a hard trail and you won't encounter any people.
Scott: Yep, that's what happens when I go.
Scott: biking is like I'll go out into the who knows where and As soon as I get I'll encounter like, you know bike paths that are like your trails separate from the road And if I'm near the road or near the end There'll be people and then you just go a bit and it's like no more people.
Rym: Yep Like on the South County ever away you're going and there's that one park where there's a big parking lot.
Rym: There's a million people on the trail just there get even a half a mile past.
Rym: that nobody.
Scott: Yeah, it's like people only go so far and then nope They did like that's.
Scott: as far as I go they turn around and the density just like drops off precipitously.
Rym: Yep, which you know, I thought my whole life I've thought about that like that was a thing that my kid brain even noticed when my family would go hiking.
Rym: But I thought about it a lot when we first moved to New York again.
Rym: like it came back into my brain because I noticed you I run over the I've run a lot and I wrote over the bridges and I always started counting like.
Rym: I noticed that I pass a lot more people near the two ends of the bridge But I pass a lot fewer people in the middle of the bridge.
Rym: Mm-hmm, like I think some people start walking up the bridge and just turn around and walk back.
Scott: Mm-hmm so much.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So anyway, the one thing about hiking out in the wilderness is that if you have good charts and trail maps And you know how to orient here like that's one thing.
Rym: But if you're going somewhere where you don't know the trails like you need a trail map And I've realized that a lot of people are the trails can just be really well marked.
Scott: So the map is just inherent in.
Rym: well marked is only good for a little baby short hikes though Because if you want to go a long distance, you're gonna have to cobble together a route.
Rym: Nothing is well marked if it's that long or some things aren't like the Appalachian Trail very well marked and you can spend months Hiking that thing.
Scott: Yeah, but there are still areas like there'll be gaps where you're sort of not, you know, yeah Yeah,
Rym: but the point more is that if you want to plan a long hike that gets you back to your car Because you don't you can't like it's not like I could do hiking where we go up with a bunch of people and we leave Cars at both ends of a big hike because we can't go with people.
Rym: that defeats the whole purpose.
Scott: So oh you could go to with with one person to one end another person with the other end And then you just when you pass each other on car keys.
Scott: That's keys.
Rym: That's actually not a bad idea.
Scott: So you don't have to retread your your.
Scott: your hike would be the same length But you would be seeing twice as much territory because you yep and it avoids the problem that I was trying to avoid of.
Rym: usually when I do that trick you Together drive up in a bunch of cars and leave cars at places But that defeats the point of avoiding people with kovat.
Scott: So that's not just have to be very clear about where the other car is.
Scott: You can find it because I didn't park it and that makes you be like, where is the other car?
Rym: But The problem with hiking and cobbling like making a route to do a loop like.
Rym: I know I want to hike like 20 miles.
Rym: So I go and look at maps.
Rym: There aren't really online maps of trails.
Scott: Yeah, there are in New York State.
Scott: Every trail has like a map website a PDF.
Rym: they do.
Rym: they have a map website or a PDF?
Rym: Yeah, not.
Rym: Yeah, those are usually incomplete Or more important they're pretty zoomed.
Scott: they're zoomed out mostly.
Rym: I hike a lot.
Rym: A lot of them are incomplete or they have a map for one particular trail system.
Rym: But we hike far enough to.
Rym: we're actually gonna cross through multiple trail systems.
Scott: So you gotta get multiple PDFs.
Rym: you need three different maps.
Rym: But that makes it difficult to plan your route in advance knowing that you have to make a big loop and get back somewhere When you can't like.
Rym: you can't like put it into a GPS tracker and it just shows you the route You can't.
Rym: you have to like line up the maps figure out where this trail system is that trail system starts.
Scott: No, why don't you make an app that fixes that make a hiking app make the hiking Strava and make money?
Rym: So someone did.
Rym: it's called all trails.
Rym: So I tried it out.
Rym: Just doesn't fucking work.
Rym: It costs money doesn't work at all.
Rym: Like get the.
Rym: you're this website and it is really good for free.
Rym: Like.
Rym: I'm poking around on it and it shows you like every goddamn trail on earth.
Rym: You just can't use it on your phone like remotely.
Rym: but looking at a website like that's how I figure out Where to go get real trail maps and do the real work, but You have to pay to like get access to like the details and download to your phone.
Rym: So I try to sign up for an account.
Rym: their account sign up just doesn't fucking work on the website.
Rym: It's just like you can't make an account.
Scott: you make an account Never make you any app that doesn't suck and make money yeah, but it was.
Rym: it's fascinating to me that this service exists where there's a phone app and if you pay for it and Like use it only on your phone You can make an account and it seems to work.
Rym: But they have a website that does the same thing.
Rym: the website just does not work.
Rym: There is no way to actually make an account on this website It's just.
Scott: it's probably like two people working there if any people.
Rym: Yep, if I just made it set it up and then called it a Day, yeah I noticed that a lot with apps where there's like a lot of the biking apps are kind of shitty like that, too.
Scott: I mean most of the but I mean pretty much every crappy biking app is dead.
Scott: The only one that survives that's kind of meh is like ride with GPS, which is sort of like this very weird With GPS, but there's no reason to pay for it.
Scott: But it's like it had and it's all this.
Scott: it's like really garbage II kind of 2000 style app, right?
Scott: But it has these features.
Scott: Basically, it's it's almost like its purpose isn't actually to be used.
Scott: Its purpose is to like be the data transfer point for other apps, right?
Scott: So for example Like I for navigation I use my actual biking GPS device, right?
Scott: To load if I want to go on Google Maps and I make a route on Google Maps and I want to load that map into my GPI biking GPS device I basically use a website that converts a Google Maps URL for directions into a special file a route file of some kind.
Scott: if we have the extension is and then I go to ride with GPS and I import the File and I cannot I and then I send it from ride with GPS to my device And then I delete it from ride with GPS because I'm not paying for it.
Scott: So it's like I don't have too many features there and it's like it's really just like this data transfer conversion Cloud syncing thing.
Rym: so total aside.
Scott: No one actually uses it I think for to do their actual navigation total aside more businessy.
Rym: that type of service the like Take data from one thing and move it to another thing.
Rym: That is probably like the hottest actual industry in the world right now.
Scott: Yeah, that's like that's where they.
Scott: they basically make all their money because they're like the the sort of central, you know app for You know bike routes, right?
Scott: Even though their actual app is kind of garbage.
Scott: They're like, you know, you want to make a route and share it.
Scott: It's like you do it on there, right?
Scott: It's like they're just the Google Drive and everyone else makes word processors.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: They're just.
Scott: they're just like a dropbox for one specific data type And that's that's pretty interesting.
Scott: it's similar to how if you're a DJ there's like the record box.
Scott: It's like you might.
Scott: who knows what you know, DJ thing you're using, right?
Scott: You might just be using a pioneer.
Scott: You know DJ set up in the club, right that doesn't connect to a computer It doesn't have to connect to a computer.
Scott: You just connect a USB stick full of songs, right?
Scott: But you use record box to prepare all of your tracks and the cue points and all that stuff in advance And that and there's also Serato and some other competitors.
Scott: But it's like record box is the one that can prepare your files on the USB stick to work with like any Possible DJ equipment, right?
Scott: So there's sort of like the ride with GPS of DJing.
Rym: Yeah, it's interesting like on one hand.
Rym: I don't like.
Rym: whenever I see a niche like that I think wow I could do it so much better.
Rym: But then I step back and think do I actually want to be in that business?
Rym: and the answer is always no.
Scott: Well, they've ordered that.
Scott: the problem is that they've already done so much work You know and solved all these problems and you would have to resolve all of those before You could start competing on them with the features that they're failing on.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they got all these fundamental things right in that it works, right?
Rym: Well, there's a barrier to entry for competitors in that niche, right?
Scott: It's like they're already handling all the data formats.
Scott: They're doing all this.
Scott: the the core like back-end work correctly of you know Setting things up and it's like people are doing it now using those apps successfully.
Scott: So you not you have to basically perfectly beat that core functionality and Then you can start being like, okay their UI sucks.
Scott: They've never tried to improve it.
Scott: Now you can beat them there, right?
Scott: Yep, but you have to match them where they already are from starting from nothing.
Rym: So anyway getting some actual gaming news.
Rym: so the problem here is not new but the news is more that it's becoming a growing problem and People are noticing it and it's starting to actively antagonize the chess community.
Rym: Basically people are aim botting the shit out of online chess like everyone's cheating because right well Well chess has become more popular online because people are stuck at home.
Scott: Yeah, people are playing more online chess and They're cheating.
Rym: Yeah now It's funny because part of the reason why there's so much outrage about the chess cheating compared to like counter-strike cheating Is that there's this odd perception among just like regular old people that people just cheat at video games.
Rym: That's just what they do.
Rym: But somehow my chess that is a more pure engaging exercise of the mind and the.
Rym: I think it's just.
Scott: I think it's just the culture of Cheating like you're only cheating yourself.
Scott: Like what's the?
Scott: what's the point?
Rym: but counter-strike is the same way like cheating a counter-strike.
Rym: That's not like you can join an e-sport.
Rym: You can't actually play in a tournament if you're a cheater because they'll catch you.
Scott: Well, I think what it is is if you cheat a counter-strike, what are you gonna get for it, right?
Scott: You're super high rank in steam Right something like that, you know, there might be drops and who knows what right?
Scott: but if you cheat at chess The chess ranking system unlike say the counter-strike one actually has like matters, right?
Rym: I would argue the counter-strike one does matter in that not as much as the chess one, right?
Scott: if I go online I'll play chess and I use the AI helper to be to beat grandmasters, right?
Scott: It's like being a chess grandmaster is a huge fucking deal, right?
Scott: It's like they're not.
Scott: You can't cheat your way into that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, but here's the thing counter-strike.
Rym: What do they really get?
Rym: because people don't really cheat just to get the rank high up.
Rym: Usually we know why they cheat because they're griefing for a lot of reasons.
Rym: They're often antagonizing the other players They're having fun like.
Rym: But the interesting thing about this article is that the article talks about not just oh people are cheating and we'll talk about the details That in a second, but the people who are cheating are Sounding and acting and talking and trolling and griefing the same way.
Rym: counter-strike cheaters do.
Rym: they're posting vile chat and like Harassing people when they get caught and disrupting games and it's literally the same crap that happens in video games.
Rym: Now like to a tee right down to like the post cheating catch harassment mmm, and The fascinating thing about chess is that on one hand it's impossible to differentiate Effectively between a player who is very good and a player who is cheating.
Rym: because unlike counter-strike Where you could see that a human could not possibly have like tracked a by a head Through a wall with their mouse that they could not see and then gotten the headshot on the first frame.
Rym: It was shootable.
Rym: Chess is just a turn-based game.
Rym: There's no difference between the cheater and a skilled player.
Scott: there's also no technological way to detect a chess cheating because it's just like You're just making your moves.
Scott: Your cheating app is off to the side.
Rym: It's not My counter-strike.
Rym: cheat has to be on my computer fucking with my code in some fashion Unless we build the robot they're playing.
Scott: you could play chess on your phone and have a supercomputer next to you That's telling you what move to play and how are they gonna know through the phone?
Scott: The phone is this thinks you're playing chess.
Scott: It doesn't have any connection physical or electronic connection to the cheating computer.
Scott: The cheating computers is a monitor that tells you what move to make Responding to someone on the stream.
Rym: I'll get to that in a second.
Rym: someone paid money to say words to us.
Scott: Why don't you have something better to do?
Rym: That'll be.
Rym: that'll be a news at the end of this.
Rym: what?
Rym: what they said, don't worry.
Rym: Okay, he's nothing bad.
Rym: but uh, the prop the cool part is it Effectively is actually trivial to catch chess cheaters.
Rym: Because while it is true that chess is meta is stagnant and that humans will probably never Bring anything to the table in chess again Unless we change the rules of chess or play chess in a different format like a eyes will always be humans forever, but that's done.
Rym: Yep, a eyes The only way humans can get better is by playing more and more like a eyes.
Rym: So you can't even do something like if a human does stuff that is very similar to the weird things that only a eyes do.
Rym: They're likely cribbing from an AI and we can catch them.
Rym: That doesn't work because grandmasters are literally studying a eyes and trying to learn the AI techniques Mm-hmm.
Rym: So and those AI techniques even worse almost always lead to draws like that's the the end game of chess.
Rym: Everything's a draw.
Rym: that that's the fundamental.
Rym: we've talked about this a lot on GeekNights But I'm gonna cheat at chess, right?
Scott: All I want to do I'm probably gonna be able to win unless the other person is also cheating right up.
Scott: Why set your at?
Scott: you're helping AI that you're using to cheat with.
Scott: don't set it at grandmaster level.
Scott: set it like Less than one master like not even master.
Scott: You know what that's like.
Rym: pretty good level.
Rym: It's like the counter-strike cheat that just moves your mouse a little bit before you like when you click before it fires.
Rym: So you're like get a little bit of an aimbot but not a like pistol shot from across the map.
Rym: aimbot Not a. I'm in your spawn with a knife somehow before the match started cheat Mm-hmm.
Rym: Oh god, imagine the chess cheater who's just like I just keep moving my pawns.
Rym: You can't stop me.
Rym: Here they come.
Rym: But the way they're detecting them is basically if Someone is too good.
Rym: Like if they're master or grandmaster level.
Rym: if they're playing at that level in any chess app 99% of the time they're cheating because the community of people who are actually that good is so small
Scott: small
Rym: and nobody is Going to join one of these chess apps and start playing at that level without having been noticed by the real chess community before that.
Scott: So basically it's like so to compare it to counter-strike.
Scott: It would be like rather than saying.
Scott: Well, we saw you aimbotting.
Scott: It's like look your kill death ratio is like a hundred to one.
Scott: Nobody is that good.
Scott: We can just see that.
Scott: we just know that you're cheating just by that.
Scott: It's like when you're playing pac-man and you look at the leaderboards just for score and you see a score That's like a billion and it's like nobody can get a billion.
Scott: That's.
Scott: I don't even need to see what you did when you played pac-man.
Scott: I know that you're cheating because nobody can get that score.
Rym: so you can actually move at least with chess cheating to above a certain line like above an egregiousness of chess cheating.
Rym: You could do a guilty until proven innocent model for people who are costs Exactly, and that seems to be what they're doing and I bet it'll work What I write.
Scott: they're smart enough to be chess grandmasters, they're smart enough to figure this out exactly as best possible.
Rym: But what's interesting is what about all the people who are cheating at a lower level?
Rym: Like I don't think you can stop that the way you can in a non turn-based game.
Scott: I don't think you can.
Scott: but I think it also doesn't matter because there's nothing to be earned by cheating.
Scott: Like I said, if I was gonna undetectedly cheat by just slightly improving my own people do that all the time.
Rym: That's that service.
Rym: It's not a news.
Rym: people were paying for that destiny cheat that just made them better without getting them caught.
Scott: Yep, and it's like sure do that and it's like but it doesn't win you anything in life.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: You know, you're not gonna.
Rym: well, what's in a tournament like that?
Scott: and get and win a money prize?
Rym: well, even better.
Rym: what I've realized is that unlike counter-stroke cheating with this chess cheating if someone cheats a little bit, uh, It doesn't matter because I'm playing online.
Rym: It's I might as well be playing against an AI.
Rym: Anyway, it doesn't matter that I'm playing chess against a human anymore.
Rym: Mm-hmm, like chess a eyes are just fine.
Rym: Pick your pick how difficult you want it to be.
Rym: if a human is augmenting themselves with an AI They're just playing like that slightly harder AI or a human who's at that level.
Rym: So it actually doesn't matter at all.
Scott: It doesn't actually disrupt my experience in any way because you can't create disrupts their rankings because the serious non cheating people are also playing Serious truly competitive chess online.
Scott: and now suddenly you look at the grandmaster rankings and it's like, okay We see everyone all the real grandmasters are there on the same site, too.
Scott: Ah, and it's like suddenly this randos mixed in there.
Rym: But those randos will get weeded out by the.
Rym: you're not actually a grandmaster guilty until proven innocent.
Rym: What if someone is Then they'll get.
Rym: that'll get sorted out pretty quick.
Rym: There's a lot of ways to solve that problem.
Rym: And if someone just gets lost in the woods like lost in the weeds, they're the edge case.
Rym: that sucks.
Rym: But just like counter-strike you might get banned when you're not cheating because he did something.
Scott: It also messes up the the person who maybe truly is a grandmaster, right?
Scott: And now because I mean because they might get eel they're using elo, right?
Scott: They might get elo'd out by the cheaters and not rise.
Rym: Seems like they don't really like.
Rym: those grandmasters are not playing in the tournaments with the people who might be cheating and vice versa.
Rym: This is mostly affecting regular people playing chess Whatever and enthusiasts where it wouldn't matter.
Rym: if you see if everyone cheats to get to like a certain level that's below the threshold of cheating detection Then you just have to naturally get better enough to get above that on your own.
Scott: I Think it's just clear that it's not just chess.
Scott: But basically any online game and with with the advent of The computer right perfect information games.
Scott: I think are not long for this world.
Rym: Yep, so like that you play them out and chess is basically it could be played out But you can read this article to see more info.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: I do have a news a tiny news.
Scott: So Sega's anniversary is going down.
Scott: and what they doing for their anniversary?
Scott: I don't know if it's almost over They're on Steam.
Scott: They got some tiny free games and they put out one game a day and you just had to click and grab it while it Was still available before it goes away.
Scott: and then you've got the game forever.
Scott: And some of these games are cute.
Scott: there was like a. there was like a Streets of Rage side scroller But it was Yakuza themed combining two Sega franchises.
Scott: They were just giving Sonic the Hedgehog 2 for a PC just for free and I guess if you you know, whatever You just emulate it, right?
Scott: But one of the games was golden axed as in the past tense you got axed, right?
Scott: And this is apparently some prototype Golden axe game that never.
Scott: it was never released.
Scott: way back when when it was made and Because they didn't like the prototype They just made it and didn't release it and it was you know, sort of a more bloody Gory kind of golden axe right like, you know, you chop someone's head off at the axe and blood spews or whatever.
Scott: I didn't play it, but that's what I heard.
Scott: Yeah And they're.
Scott: they're like, you know what.
Scott: we'll dig this thing out of our vault and we'll release it to the world.
Scott: Hey everyone, it's gonna be buggy and janky We know but you know what.
Scott: it's free for you.
Scott: and as to celebrate our anniversary and I think that's pretty cool I wish I'm sure Nintendo's got a lot of stuff in the vault I would love to play janky like vertical slices of Nintendo concepts that never made it.
Scott: I mean, I know right.
Scott: so if they released that for an anniversary of Sega, that would be awesome.
Scott: or Nintendo, right.
Scott: so What happens?
Scott: is somebody?
Scott: the person who largely was responsible for golden axed Right comes out on Twitter and tells the real story about how.
Rym: basically, you know typical game industry story Executives who don't know what the fuck they want Seven day work weeks to force this game to get like this vertical slice to get right.
Scott: They overwork this dude a zillion hours to crank this thing out.
Scott: You know, he didn't make what they asked for.
Scott: They didn't even know what they wanted.
Scott: Given the runaround then they never even released the thing.
Scott: It's like a dark memory for this, dude.
Scott: And then they had to go and say oh, you know like insulting it when they released it like oh, it's all janky and buggy and broken right.
Scott: and he's like Opened up the old wounds here.
Rym: on one hand work for hire Like I think this guy's right in this case because the crunch problem.
Rym: But if I made something janky for my job and at some point the company released it For free or prepare whatever and admitted how janky it was like that's work for hire.
Rym: That's what happens when you're working for someone else like.
Rym: that's not that big a deal.
Rym: But the fact that they did this for something that they also forced this dude to work to 14-hour seven day weeks to make that is the problem that the Crunch is never ever justified in the video game industry.
Rym: if that means a bunch of triple-a studios go bankrupt.
Rym: Fuck them That's right.
Scott: And that thing is the crunch.
Scott: it's like, okay, we made you work super overtime or nothing release, right?
Scott: It's like it.
Scott: may you know, it might barely make it.
Scott: All right, so let's think of a case where crunch might make sense.
Scott: All right, let's say you and I follow 13 is happening right now.
Scott: We need the astrophysicist to work.
Scott: Yeah Engineers to stay on the clock to save the astronauts live.
Scott: that's acceptable.
Rym: game 7 of the Stanley Cup.
Rym: I work for the Rangers.
Rym: They're like they're in it.
Rym: Like that's the curl.
Rym: you're gonna work as long as that overtime takes.
Scott: Yeah, but even then and the lead-up is something more, right?
Scott: But even in that case compared to the people's lives are on the line.
Scott: Apollo 13 case Right the Stanley Cup while very very important is not life and death.
Scott: So if something more important comes up like, you know some major you can leave you don't.
Scott: there's no reason to you know Hurt yourself.
Scott: Yeah, you work really hard.
Scott: You might work a few extra hours But there's no reason to sacrifice your body or your life or true anything for the Stanley Cup.
Rym: Like there's a reason why there's a concussion protocol, even if the player wants right play We don't let them right.
Scott: you push yourself to your limit in that case and then stop, right?
Scott: There's no reason to go over.
Scott: Here's a video game.
Rym: you and I you and I are making tribes 2 - and Yeah, like for summaries like we got.
Rym: we work extra hours to get it done because it's a we were passionate about it.
Scott: We're not working but we're not good.
Scott: There's no reason to hurt ourselves or sacrifice our bodies.
Scott: or you know.
Scott: Even if there's some sort of deadline like we're back in the day where we have to push CDs or something Yeah, and we need to get it to the CD manufacturer the gold copy by a certain time or otherwise.
Scott: You know the.
Scott: the game will have to be delayed by several months and then you know problems, right?
Scott: Okay, that might justify a little bit of overworking but hopefully we didn't fuck up to begin with and we're on time also as we didn't manage anything poorly previously.
Rym: in Functional like sane industry is the way that works is if you work a lot of extra overtime to get something done You either get a bunch of extra time off or compensation the video game industry.
Rym: Usually you just get fired and your game comes done.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: That's right And you know, but for a game that is never released for a prototype for a demo There is no reason to have.
Scott: you know, I mean there should.
Scott: I guess it would be unreasonable to work on a prototype You don't even know you're gonna make for several months.
Scott: That would be kind of ridiculous.
Rym: Well that actually is common and fine, but it's not common and fine to do that for several months with crunched hours.
Scott: Right, but I'm saying it's like, you know, we don't even know if we're gonna do this thing.
Scott: Am I really gonna pay someone for months to make a prototype?
Scott: It's like just make it crappier and make it faster.
Scott: That way we can decide sooner whether we want to keep going with it.
Rym: Well that I always go back to a philosophy I've had in careers and like think everyone should follow in their whole life.
Rym: if someone's paying you to do something you can like And it's rich.
Rym: It's not crunch.
Rym: Like it's normal 40-hour workweek.
Rym: It's their money.
Scott: yeah, sure, but Why I'm saying doing that is silly but to crunch on a thing.
Scott: You're not sure is gonna be a real thing.
Scott: Yeah, where there is there it's like there's no deadline because you didn't even make it.
Scott: so it didn't matter whether you did it or not.
Scott: That's really kind of effed up.
Rym: Yep, like this could have just been delayed a couple weeks and that guy could cost you.
Scott: The point is it costs you nothing to play golden axed.
Scott: So it doesn't benefit Sega really in any way.
Scott: So go ahead and install golden axed and try it out.
Scott: I didn't try it out yet, but I clicked on it on Steam.
Scott: So I have it.
Rym: Oh, yeah I didn't click on it on Steam.
Rym: I guess I could.
Scott: I don't know if you There's like.
Scott: there's a. you have to check.
Scott: There's a. there's a brief window.
Rym: I think yeah, I'll go check out whatever I like.
Scott: you can just play regular golden X. It's probably way better.
Rym: So let's play arcade like golden X again.
Rym: I'm good times with that game.
Scott: You'll like golden X. We don't like any of you don't like streets of rage.
Rym: I think the part of it was.
Rym: I only like golden X when I was kid.
Rym: kid brain and fantasy was more important to me than street fight.
Scott: All right, so thematically sure that was pretty much it right around on the animals in golden access.
Rym: I was like 11 Also my main memory of golden X. we were kicking that game's ass and we were taking turns putting quarters into it and Someone kicked the machine and we knocked the plug out.
Scott: And to this we never figured out who kicked it out At least the D&D one and River City Ransom of actual RPG elements.
Scott: golden X is just walk sideways and hit things.
Rym: Honestly, the D&D one was I as a kid.
Rym: I remember it being better, but there's only one arcade that had it so I didn't get to play it as much.
Rym: There's two D&D ones Yeah, the one where you could take the path to fight the red dragon Both of them or you could go the other side.
Scott: It's both pretty sure that's both.
Rym: Yeah I don't remember which one switch at all.
Rym: It was a. it was a Cocktail cabinet and it was in a pizza parlor.
Rym: They also had an afterburner machine.
Scott: We played the whole game at RIT.
Scott: We beat it.
Rym: I vaguely remember that one of them.
Scott: I forget which one it was one of.
Rym: don't remember which one it was.
Rym: So anyway, it's a blast news.
Rym: a while ago.
Rym: We talked about how Facebook requiring Facebook accounts on oculus VR Oculus
Scott: Yes was
Rym: causing problems and that a lot of VR developers were Reconsidering their plans to release stuff on that platform and a lot of gamers are like getting rid of their headsets Or planning to get rid of their headsets.
Scott: So I did see some people a lot of people on Twitter buying like, you know quest twos with various Reactions positive and negative.
Rym: Yeah, the quest two is good hardware.
Rym: I'll say that for it.
Rym: But
Scott: I saw some complaints about the hardware aspects as well and some positive things, you know,
Rym: yeah But apparently it is interesting because the split I see is People like me and people are more close to the games industry are generally more down on the oculus quest to people who are Less into gaming and this is their first VR.
Rym: They don't really know or think about it.
Rym: they just get it have a Facebook account don't even think about it.
Rym: totally fine and At least for now the lot like steam just works with it.
Rym: Everything just works.
Rym: But the problem a bunch of people are having and upload VR is an article about.
Rym: it is a lot of people bought it.
Rym: Who don't have Facebook accounts?
Rym: Not because they're like me and they hate Facebook because they're young and they never thought to make a Facebook account Mmm, so they go to make a Facebook account.
Rym: Facebook has a backlog of Creating new accounts because they require proof of identity and all that nonsense.
Rym: Like they'll lock your account out if they think it's suspicious and that I never provided that you have to do for a new account.
Scott: You have to do that.
Rym: There's all sorts of nonsense in Facebook.
Scott: You can't just make a Facebook account and then you're good.
Rym: So Facebook accounts can get disabled if they're reviewed and Facebook isn't sure that you're an actual individual, right?
Scott: So that that's what I thought is that it was a post.
Scott: It's not a pre thing.
Scott: It's a post thing that you.
Scott: they may give you your account and then you know You verify your email or whatever people are getting they might disable it.
Rym: People are making new accounts that are getting disabled pretty or pretty quickly Because they only made the account for Facebook VR and they don't use it for anything else.
Scott: That makes sense.
Rym: Yeah, so if that happens and you don't like send them photos and do all the stuff You have to do or even if you do it and they don't believe you your accounts just disabled permanently Fuck you, and now you cannot even boot your quest to.
Scott: Yeah, it makes sense.
Rym: Yeah, and there's a huge huge story here of a bunch of people who basically returned them or Had to charge back their credit cards or otherwise could not use their oculus quest to because Facebook either disabled their account or wouldn't let them access an account.
Rym: They hadn't used in a long time and they're just fucked.
Rym: Mmm, I just it'll be interesting to see what Facebook does about that.
Scott: I Did they care that much?
Scott: Yeah oculus is not a large part of their money.
Scott: Yep, and as much as they know the actual number of people this happened to is probably small in the grand scheme.
Rym: Well, especially considering the the demographic that I think would likely be hit most by this are young people who don't even like care about Facebook or think about Facebook.
Scott: and where did those people get that much money?
Scott: to buy VR from?
Rym: their parents probably bought it for him.
Rym: maybe VR is pretty hot right now because people are stuck at home.
Rym: It's actually selling way better than it was previously.
Rym: Maybe I mean it is we have numbers.
Rym: It's not hmm.
Scott: Yeah, where's your where these number?
Rym: But anyway Things of the day.
Rym: the listener made this video.
Rym: It's what a link to this video it is.
Rym: they took the panel we did at the crunchyroll Expo and they They made a super cut of it.
Rym: So they cut it down.
Rym: They distilled our 59 panel to 59 seconds is a 59 second distillation of our judge anime by its cover panel And it's actually pretty great and pretty funny.
Rym: This is worth watching.
Scott: Okay, I know who the listener is by the way, but I'm telling yeah, I've just used the listener.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Scott: So yeah my thing of the day.
Scott: so the Pusheen Channel.
Scott: they Pusheen much like yeek nights is on every single internet channel.
Scott: They got Instagram.
Scott: They got the Twitter.
Scott: They got the YouTube.
Scott: they got pretty much everything.
Scott: Pusheen has an account and they post there and what Pusheen does.
Scott: pretty much every week or so.
Scott: They'll post something and they'll make like a new Pusheen content and they will format that content for each platform Especially so that like, you know on YouTube It'll be a video and then you'll go to Instagram and you'll see like a single animated gif.
Scott: That's basically the same content is a video.
Scott: Yeah, and it's sort of like these four panel cute Pusheen's.
Scott: however For Halloween and to promote their Bousheen, which is sold out I don't know if it'll come back in stock at any point.
Scott: They have made a full cute animation of Bousheen in the haunted house.
Rym: the skeleton is great.
Scott: Yeah, and it's it's only on YouTube.
Scott: I did not see this on any other Bousheen platform.
Scott: so Go to the official Pusheen YouTube channel and watch this tiny cute Halloween animation that is high quality.
Rym: It is tiny and cute.
Rym: in the moment The book club book is still the tale of Hanzo because we're just not reading books right now.
Rym: Stay tuned But I don't know.
Scott: I've been I've been feeling a book reading mood, but it's telling me to read Like fantasy sci-fi novel and I'm like no if we're gonna read any.
Scott: I still haven't read anything.
Rym: But if we do read something I was about to say you read any fiction that is not the tale of Genji.
Scott: Fuck you That's right, I got to read that one.
Rym: I can't read the tale of Genji.
Rym: I just don't have time to read anything.
Rym: I mean I do too, but it's You know, yeah, I'm not the only thing I'm feeling to read like.
Rym: I want to read a bunch of stuff including this.
Rym: But the only things I'm actually reading are still nonfiction right now for a lot of reasons.
Scott: and read the internet.
Scott: That's what I read.
Rym: Yep, but another meta moment.
Rym: Danny the listener on the stream paid $4.99 to make sure Your five dollars.
Scott: you could do something better with those five dollars.
Scott: He wants to know like any Democratic campaign for credit for anything.
Rym: Well, this is a question that gets asked a lot on the YouTube channel.
Rym: I keep trying.
Rym: we got disrupted on doing and following up on this.
Rym: Will the utenna series continue?
Rym: Now the answer is yes, like we do want to continue it, uh We just got to actually do it with our remote setup.
Rym: Mmm, you want to do it this weekend.
Rym: want to record one?
Rym: No, you want to watch one this weekend?
Scott: Yeah, I don't remember which one we're on.
Rym: We're in Black Rose.
Rym: Yeah, I know that We're actually just getting to another good duel.
Scott: Isn't every duel a good do holder?
Rym: Well, no, cuz the Black Rose has a bunch of non-dual episodes before the duel.
Scott: Oh, yeah every other episode, whatever.
Rym: All right, if you want to know maybe I'll just do one by myself.
Scott: this weekend He's gonna make videos by yourself.
Rym: I'd be pretty easy to do.
Rym: The only reason it's hard is that both of us have to watch it and then we have to record it together Which because of kovat takes the same amount of effort as recording an entire goddamn panel.
Scott: It's not like yes makes no effort.
Rym: I do ten of videos take a lot of work to do more work than even a panel Yeah, but the pre-production of a new ten up before kovat only took about Twice as much effort as a podcast like.
Rym: we just have to sit down and like record the thing and then the rest of the Is me spending a few days like editing and futzing with it, but now the pre-production.
Scott: they're also you know While I'm sure our utenna content was very good or at least good ish, right?
Scott: there are people who do exactly that way way way better than us.
Scott: go check out empty movement on Twitter and Like.
Scott: they are way more Utenna expert than we ever will be.
Scott: you can why you don't need to come to us for that.
Scott: You can go to someone else for that like.
Scott: so they're a hundred percent utenna all the time.
Rym: Yep, listeners have basically said in our YouTube channel Effectively the thing we do that's different is that we go for a really long time about an individual episode With no one else.
Rym: does that not really Like?
Rym: we go way clips get copyright strike.
Scott: So that's a problem.
Rym: Yep, I did.
Rym: I did get around that because the last one we uploaded where I did.
Rym: So I made some changes to how I did the clips.
Rym: I got far fewer copyright strikes.
Scott: That's okay didn't?
Rym: actually?
Rym: I actually fought all the strikes and won.
Rym: It was just a pain in the ass and I had to open myself up to significant legal liability, but so far it worked.
Rym: Okay, I will try to.
Rym: basically it's at this point.
Rym: it's a matter of is Scott willing to do it cuz I'm ready.
Scott: You're right.
Scott: You're just gonna push this on me.
Scott: Well, if you want to do all these all these months slash years.
Scott: you haven't done anything and now you're gonna play.
Rym: I actually did edit together a bunch.
Rym: I pulled all the clips out.
Rym: I wanted to talk about for the next episode of utenna.
Scott: I do actually have that.
Rym: four years ago I did that actually a bit before PAX East and I thought oh after PAX East then things calm down and I can work on Stuff and then the world got weird.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: You could in the time it takes to wait for us to do this You could just watch your tennis several times and then nothing we could possibly tell you would be new information.
Scott: You would have learned everything that we would tell you.
Rym: What's sad is all those videos keep getting comments and like people keep finding them and like they get to the last one And that episode that one has mostly comments saying oh, where's the next one?
Rym: Did they die?
Rym: What happened to those two guys?
Scott: Even though there's a whole YouTube channel full of content.
Scott: What happened to those?
Rym: Oh, the the people who watch the utenna videos tend to not be subscribers to the rest of our stuff.
Rym: They're like a sense.
Scott: I can see that but usually on YouTube like I'll click on you know, the channel Underneath the video to see what helps that.
Rym: now a subset of them are watching these streams and they actually ask this question a lot In the stream, this is the first time someone paid money to ask the question.
Scott: Dude, take your five dollars and do something.
Scott: It's too late.
Rym: I got it's too late.
Rym: I got the five dollars.
Scott: Well, it's mine to donate.
Scott: I'm gonna donate the five dollars.
Rym: You want you want your two you want your 249?
Scott: after taxes well before taxes No, Google paid me the whole five dollars so I could donate all of it.
Rym: No, it's 5050.
Rym: We gotta split that money.
Scott: No, you're gonna donate your 250.
Rym: I will.
Rym: I will use it to produce the utenna video You.
Rym: Otherwise we don't have any cons coming up like for a while now.
Scott: none of anything coming up.
Rym: Yep It's uh, the elections coming.
Rym: vote for Joe Biden like seriously don't vote for a third party.
Rym: That's yeah.
Scott: I'm always tired of people who are like, you know You get like.
Scott: there are people who are like vote and it's like.
Rym: it's like no Don't vote like seriously.
Rym: don't vote unless you're voting for Joe Biden like.
Scott: vote for Joe Biden or don't yep.
Scott: And actually don't don't just vote for Joe by.
Rym: yeah, there's no don't remember.
Scott: You are eligible to vote in the United States of America and you do not successfully vote for Joe Biden go fuck yourself.
Rym: We uh, uh, if you haven't read the GeekNights terms of service Which we're still evolving like we're trying to work on that more.
Rym: I got I got some more changes I want to put into the get repo but anyway
Scott: It is
Rym: actually against our terms of service to be a member of the American Republican Party and interact with us on social media Like I'm not joking because we consider it a here.
Rym: So yeah, but for Joe Biden.
Rym: We can fix the problems that Joe Biden will cause a lot more easily if he's the person we're fighting.
Rym: Think of it that way.
Scott: He's kind of a pushover, right?
Rym: Yeah, also Just platforms pretty good.
Rym: He actually adopted a lot of Bernie's stuff and a lot of Warren's stuff.
Scott: It's it's better than Literally kill everybody.
Scott: Yeah, kill everybody.
Scott: the platform if you care about other human beings.
Scott: Yep But black don't care about other human beings go fuck yourself.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Star Wars squadrons.
Rym: This game pretty good like spoilers.
Rym: It's worth 40 bucks like actually it's only 40 bucks.
Scott: surprised That it's 40 bucks.
Scott: 40 bucks with no microtransactions and no DLCs so far.
Rym: Yep, everything you can possibly unlock in this game is entirely Inside of the game like that's it.
Scott: Just play the game.
Scott: so get stuff.
Scott: everything that they said on paper coming up to the leading up to this game Despite it being an EA published game.
Scott: It was made by motive in Canada.
Scott: I think right I knew some.
Scott: I Tangentially am acquainted with some of the people that worked on it.
Scott: kinda I think you know at least one Former GeekNights listener worked on this game.
Rym: It's fun when I notice a game that comes out and like some of the people who made it or tweeting and the people I follow Cuz they're games people and every now and then it's like oh that person follows me - oh wait.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I know who that is But anyway so it is the spirit not spiritual actual successor to X-wing TIE fighter And X-wing Alliance which came out 20 years ago.
Scott: So 20 years after X-wing Alliance we get Star Wars squad.
Rym: all we need is the Pokemon MMO to come out and Scott and I are in fact the profits of this era Of game design, that's right.
Scott: So this game is a game in which you fly inside one of eight Star Wars star fighting ships.
Scott: for you know, either it's you get X-wing you got your a-wing You got a Y-wing and you got this weird support thing.
Scott: I don't know the hell that is.
Scott: Yeah the you wing Doing it or I never heard of a you wing anyway, and then the Empire side you got your tie fighter You got your tie interceptor my boy.
Scott: You got your tie bomba and You got this other this fucking.
Scott: I don't know what the hell it is.
Rym: Yeah No, they don't have a b-wing cuz that would be opie.
Rym: There's no tie defender you nerds like that.
Rym: Let that go.
Scott: Yeah, it's fighter interceptor bomber and Weird thing.
Rym: So here's the deal with the game.
Rym: first off It has a single-player campaign that is like five to ten hours worth of content.
Rym: Like it's not I played the entire thing.
Scott: It is a single-player campaign.
Scott: It has a plot.
Scott: It has characters.
Scott: It's mildly interesting.
Scott: Yeah, it's not too shabby.
Rym: the missions are pretty fun, right?
Scott: Some of it.
Scott: It's some of its fun.
Scott: Some of its frustrating.
Scott: you can sort of tell that the purpose of it is really Training to teach you to play this game by introducing things, you know mission by mission, you know to get you up to speed.
Scott: You know, it's it's a long tutorial in disguise.
Rym: Yeah This is not like tie fighter where you literally have like dozens and dozens and dozens of missions and branching nonsense and secret objectives Like.
Rym: it's not a campaign.
Scott: No, it's it's.
Scott: you know, not that it's less than 20 missions.
Scott: Maybe even less than 15.
Scott: It's the same missions no matter what you play both light side and dark side.
Scott: You have two characters actually some missions your one character on the light side and someone sometimes you're an imperial character doing the other side You know, it flips back and forth mission to mission as you go forward And you see that you see what one character is doing.
Scott: you see what the other set of characters are doing how they interact with Each other, you know, it's worth a playthrough.
Scott: But is it worth $40?
Scott: I don't know about that, right if that's all you want to do I don't know.
Scott: $40 is too much.
Scott: wait for the price to go down to at least 20 because that's basically One day of entertainment and I figure a movie can cost up to $20, you know sometimes.
Scott: so that's a good Deal.
Scott: if you've paid 20 bucks and just play this game in a day Yep, live a Star Wars movie like fight for five to ten hours.
Rym: Maybe play through a couple times put it on a higher difficulty But then you'll run out of steam.
Rym: this game is really aimed at if you want to do multiplayer Which frankly was my literal dream from the moment?
Rym: I first played that x-wing game with my flight stick when I was a kid until today when I can finally realize it and in terms of that They got it like 90% right already.
Rym: and most of the complaints I have are Bug fixes primarily and they fixed a lot of them.
Rym: Yeah, they're fixing bugs like at a steady clip already Hmm.
Scott: So yeah, so this is a game where I think that the story of the game is that you know in the grand scheme When you zoom out, it's kind of perfect.
Scott: right when you zoom in a little bit more It's like, you know, okay, they got all the fundamentals exactly, right?
Scott: It's a Star Wars game.
Scott: You can play in VR even.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you're in the ship.
Scott: You have all the controls the complexity of the game.
Scott: It's it's more complex than an arcade, you know situation But it's less complex than like a true flight sim, which is exactly in the exact right spot.
Rym: You want it to be Yep, and don't worry in this review.
Rym: We're gonna get into some details of what we mean by that specific state.
Scott: It is a skill based Right multiplayer free space shooting game.
Scott: It is not a game where you pay to win.
Scott: It is not a game where you grind to win.
Scott: It's nothing like that.
Scott: It's literally a skill based, you know high skill cap game meaning if someone's good, they will just fucking destroy you.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Exactly, which is happening to us.
Rym: We are our squad Not the finest.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: So those fundamentals are all there.
Scott: they're all in place.
Scott: you pay for the game once you can play it forever.
Scott: There's no subscription.
Scott: There's no nothing right.
Scott: what they got wrong is the game.
Scott: It feels like what they did.
Scott: is they had like a checklist of things like we need to do all these things to release?
Scott: And they did all those things.
Scott: they completed the list 100% and then they released and they did not Spend the extra six months of polishing it until there wasn't a single scratch.
Scott: and there's lots and lots.
Scott: not lots and lots but a nice handful of Tiny niggly bits and rough edges that are not polished away.
Scott: Some of them were major bugs that have been fixed but there are still you know rough edges because it feels like they finished it and pushed it out rather than Really making it super awesome, which is probably why it's able to be $40 and not who knows how much.
Rym: now The cool thing is all all the polish issues are Things that are easily fixed and seem like they're being fixed mostly as bugs or minor improvements post release.
Rym: quite a few have been fixed in and I think a lot of the rest of them will too and I would Say that the majority of the problems are in the tutorials and the menus.
Scott: Yes, for sure.
Scott: Also, you know despite the fact that it's a good thing There's no DLCs or microtransactions or any other kind of bullshit like that.
Scott: It is somewhat of a negative in that it doesn't look like there's ever going to be more content for this game.
Rym: This is the whole game the end which so I'm good with because all I want is to get good at The skill of the game.
Rym: like I don't want more shit here.
Rym: I don't want more characters.
Rym: I just want I'd be okay if at some point they added like more types of competitive formats.
Scott: Yes, it's it's good and bad right?
Scott: It's good in that.
Scott: This is the game.
Scott: get good at it, right?
Scott: We would just taught.
Scott: we spent a whole bunch of the show just now talking about it.
Rym: You don't want to get good at it.
Scott: There's no expansions for chess, right?
Scott: But if you're the kind of person who seeks novelty, right and you're not in it for Deep, you know going deep on the game that exists and getting really good at it.
Scott: You just want to.
Scott: you know, you will.
Scott: you will even if you play multiplayer Probably get tired of this game.
Scott: Once you've played and all the ships and all the formats and all the maps and there's like there's nothing more for me.
Scott: You if you're the kind of person who wants like Smash Brothers where there's more maps more characters more more more This game is not for you.
Scott: It will run out on you.
Scott: Yeah, but only way you can get more replay out of this game is personal skill development like a fighting game that doesn't have too many characters to choose from.
Rym: and the thing is that is something that.
Rym: That's what I personally seek out of games, but that is not what most people seek out of games.
Rym: So you really need to understand and think about this.
Rym: if you are you the kind of person who plays Counter-Strike?
Rym: Gets mad that you're ranked load Everyone's better than you and then go and play overwatch and then get mad because everyone's better than you.
Rym: Guess what's gonna happen in this game?
Scott: Also, are you the kind of person who's maybe good at Counter-Strike and you play dust and then you play Italy and I don't even Know what maps they have these days?
Scott: right and then you get around and you're back on dust again, and then you're on dust - and you're like dust again.
Scott: Right, you're not interested in playing dust for the hundredth time because you feel like it's so boring.
Scott: You've done it a hundred times.
Scott: Yeah versus someone who's like, I don't care what map it is I will become the master of.
Scott: you know, I need to play dust a hundred more times.
Scott: to these things about it I haven't perfected.
Rym: I mean, I would go to servers that were just dust only because I wanted to just play dust.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: So if you get bored by the same content over and over regardless of your skill advancement, you're gonna get bored By this game because it's only a handful of maps and eight ships.
Scott: Yep I've customized the ships a little bit But it seems like that some of the customizations are just better and there's not a lot of choice going on there though.
Rym: Part of that is the relatively small player base and the lack of matchmaking data is skewing that like.
Rym: But I think there will be some minor balance tweaks as the game goes on and I think also these.
Scott: so it doesn't appear that There's actually An organized competitive scene yet.
Scott: so there's sort of a lack of a Universal meta or at least a visible one.
Scott: that like you can you right you?
Scott: I guess we had to join some.
Scott: maybe I can go Find like a subreddit for this game and see what people are saying.
Rym: Yeah The other thing I'd say is the community seems pretty good and chill like we were playing a match the other day.
Rym: mostly mostly We're we're the jerk like.
Rym: I hate when people do this in overwatch and I hate that I'm doing it in this game.
Rym: I was only doing it in this game because the in-game voice wasn't working great when it first came out but I Hated an overwatch.
Rym: when I join a game and there's a group of people who are on my rando team But they're doing their own voice in discord.
Rym: So I can't talk to them or hear them because this game Absolutely requires you to coordinate with your teammates.
Rym: You literally have to be like calling for fire support and like calling out targets and constantly communicating or you're just gonna get crushed.
Scott: Yeah, I kind of wish that Like I have turned off the voice chat.
Scott: just cuz I don't want to hear anyone yelling awful stuff, right?
Scott: But I do wish I could turn it on because I'm hoping maybe you know, like when I played PUBG, you know There were times where I would play like the team PUBG where like throws you in with a team of four people randomly Right, and I would occasionally get in with a good group and they would teach me something.
Rym: Oh, but this game to scojo.
Rym: while we were playing he was both in our discord and in the team chat And oh we were getting wrecked like way more than usual.
Rym: Like we've been doing better that session and then we're just getting fucking destroyed.
Rym: We couldn't figure out why.
Rym: and then he explains to us that the other people on our team Actually explained to him the glitch that the other team was exploiting and why we were losing.
Scott: Yep, there's that lack of polish yet again, right?
Rym: But like in overwatch, I'm always in the voice chat with randos.
Rym: I play with randos 90% of the time and you know what?
Rym: Maybe one and every hundred games to someone say something even remotely.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: Next time we play let's just not use discord.
Scott: Let's use the in-game channel.
Scott: See what happens All right.
Scott: Yeah, cuz let's talk about how the game actually works.
Scott: So there's a dog fighting mode.
Scott: The dog fighting mode is literally just shoot other people.
Scott: see who gets them, you know kill the other people a lot great.
Rym: And the cool thing is I play it a lot.
Rym: The meta is all over the place.
Rym: Sometimes I join and like everyone's in interceptors, which you might expect like ooh the super fragile super fast.
Scott: You're not trying to destroy capital ships.
Scott: Why would you use a bomber in a in a shit in a fighter on fighter?
Scott: You know dogfight the interceptor and the a-wing should be like the only ones you should see out there, right?
Scott: right But no people bring out the x-wing.
Scott: they bring out the Thai bomber.
Scott: They were you know, it's like And it's like.
Scott: yeah, it's not necessarily a bad choice.
Rym: Yeah, because the ships are pretty well balanced like they you they're.
Scott: No one brings out the support ship though in the dogfight there some people do.
Rym: I don't know if the support ships are necessary in The meta or if they only exist to give people who are not as good at the rest of the game something to do and engage With kind of like how Team Fortress 2 had the healer.
Rym: that really wasn't fun compared to overwatch where the healers.
Scott: That's a problem.
Scott: I think you can do a whole episode of V nights about how support roles in games like You know exist to give people like a non murderous task and also a lower skill cap task.
Rym: But that's the fact that we tie the non murderous and the lower skill cap together.
Rym: I think is the problem I like.
Scott: I think you just make they should make the support high skill, too.
Rym: Yeah, that's what overwatch does.
Rym: a lot of games do that now like there are low skill attack characters and high skill support characters Like they've separated you can you have two separate sliders in every character on skill cap.
Scott: aren't the low skill ones just worse than and for competitive play?
Scott: because the high skill ones Balance out the higher skill difficulty with more power and numbers to a degree.
Rym: Yes in the top tiers of the meta the lower skill characters just don't get played.
Rym: But there are very high skill cap characters in every type Right.
Scott: So I think that that exact thing is also what happens with the cut the ship Customizations in Star Wars squadrons, you'll look at for example Like you're choosing which hole to put on your tie fighter Yeah, and one of them will be like well if you use this hole you can turn faster But you'll go slower or something like that and it's like alright, whatever.
Scott: and then there'll be another one that I'd be like Oh, you know what?
Scott: This one is just better but Piloting will be more difficult and it's like well I can Counterback that more difficult piloting with my skills by getting better.
Scott: So this is just better than the other options.
Scott: and so all of those are the options that trade numbers for numbers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Oh shoots faster, but shoots less accurately does more damage, but shoots less often, right?
Scott: It's like the highest DPS one is the best one.
Scott: It doesn't matter that those trade-offs don't matter, right?
Rym: It's unless you're not perfectly skilled.
Scott: Sure, of course.
Scott: But once the idea is that if you play enough your skills will balance out You know the the weapon or the the armor that's like yeah, okay It's you know, it does more damage, but it's hard to aim.
Scott: Well, I can aim better.
Scott: So that's just the best weapon, right?
Scott: And and I think in the end those are going to be the only Equipments that are used on all the ships are those ones that give just more numbers with the skill trade-off.
Rym: Yeah, I'll just be better now if skill if at some point they did add more modes.
Rym: Nothing else in the game like more scenarios for combat.
Rym: I think some of those options become more viable because of situational stuff.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep, but the dogfighting mode super super fun.
Rym: And if I have to give you any advice, I'm we're trying to follow this advice.
Rym: But the game's real hard.
Rym: The skill cap is up in the stratosphere.
Rym: It's up in space It's up by the stars.
Rym: like I cannot do what I'm about to say, but learning the rudiments of Like World War 2 era dogfighting like the basic techniques of like how to shake a tail how to call out like attacks.
Rym: That stuff actually works and can help you be good at this game.
Scott: You literally.
Scott: how do you know it works if you haven't been able to do it because I have played games with randos where they?
Rym: Do call outs.
Rym: they're not doing like that.
Rym: schweebs that might just be too hard But what they are doing is like I got a tail and they ping the tail and someone on the team will acknowledge that ping And disrupt it to save them and they'll do this reliably and I've seen I
Scott: don't even have the situational awareness to know We're like all my teammates are and like dude And I wanted to come help you.
Scott: I would spend like a minute finding you.
Scott: I then you're dead Scott.
Rym: all you have to do.
Rym: if I ping a target then You'll get.
Rym: it'll give you an audio and a visual indication saying like Rym ping to target.
Rym: if you acknowledge that ping It'll turn your targeting computer to point out whatever I pinged.
Rym: You do not know how the game works.
Rym: did you not like?
Scott: I mean I could there.
Scott: that was though actually the one thing in the whole The entire like story mode.
Scott: there was one point because it's the story modes is tutorial right.
Rym: yeah It makes you do everything one by one like it makes you do everything once.
Scott: the acknowledge ping is the one thing I never successfully did.
Rym: oh you do all.
Rym: you don't have to do anything except click whatever button you bound to acknowledge ping and whatever.
Scott: I don't know what the fuck but I still know what the fuck button it is and I when I looked when I had that on the screen during the tutorial slash story I went to the settings to figure out what button it was and like.
Scott: I Couldn't figure out which button it was and I pushed buttons, and I didn't it.
Scott: Let me.
Scott: it said I acknowledge the ping But I couldn't tell what I did to acknowledge it and I couldn't see on the screen the indicator of Anything that looked like a ping or an acknowledgement, and I still have never seen one.
Scott: So I didn't know what it looks like or sounds like.
Rym: so that is it Aside but it's a an annoyance I had.
Rym: the hardest part of this game was setting up my hot ass for it because there's a lot of things to bind.
Rym: There are no defaults.
Rym: if you have a real joystick like there's no default that makes sense.
Rym: You'd really have to customize it to your specific joystick and Due to the nature of modern joysticks like my joystick combo here has like 48 buttons and That's too many buttons.
Rym: Yeah, because I'm not using a lot of them because a lot of them I don't need for a game like this.
Rym: I needed about 16 to bind everything that I.
Scott: that's a good number.
Rym: Yeah, but Try when I'm playing the game the first time I tried to just dive into it and there's no default.
Rym: so everything's just nonsense.
Rym: It would be like hit button 27 on joystick to it.
Rym: I'm just like.
Scott: that's an example of the lack of polish, right?
Scott: You know is that like?
Rym: like a polish game would have come with a profile for every popular hot ass set up?
Scott: Yeah, even with my gamepad which is actually the default set up.
Scott: So I'm playing with a gamepad and it is actually way better than I anticipated for real game pads.
Rym: Like you can play this game fine If you can't get a joy.
Scott: it has to be a modern gamepad that has two analog sticks for face buttons a d-pad start select And two L's and two R's.
Scott: but if you have all that you are good to go with this game.
Scott: Like I don't see myself buying a stick because I'm not playing this game enough.
Scott: I'm playing or spending all that money and Giving up all that space.
Scott: But gamepad is way better than I thought it was gonna be.
Scott: but even then it would be like hey press this button and I'd look down at my gamepad and be like It says to push X but I push X and it's not it.
Scott: It's actually Y or it's actually a or it's actually something else, right?
Scott: So but I guess the moral if I was using an actual Xbox controller and not this SN 30 Pro Plus.
Scott: I think it would have been absolutely correct But I'm not so.
Rym: so this is a game.
Rym: I guess what I'll.
Rym: the important part of that is you have to approach the first time you boot this game The way you would have approached the first time you turned on a DOS game in the old days.
Rym: meaning Yeah, you go to the menu before you do anything.
Rym: You look at the control customization.
Rym: You just go down the list like sitting in front of your keyboard joystick, whatever it is you're using.
Rym: You make a guess at what everything that you could bind does and you bind it to something that feels like it makes sense.
Rym: Then try to play the game.
Rym: You'll run into like three-quarters of those were terrible decisions.
Rym: Now you understand your remap everything again.
Rym: after you go through this process like four times You'll have everything bound to something that makes sense.
Rym: Then you can play the game.
Rym: You got no way around Yeah on the gamepad.
Scott: I see no need to rebind anything.
Scott: I'm just sticking with the defaults and they're perfectly great.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: I would still you have to go into the settings and figure out what the hell button they're actually talking about.
Rym: Now the game does something good.
Rym: it supports people who don't have a ton of buttons because a Lot of things can be bound to a combo.
Rym: like you can bind ping and again ping and act to hit a button to ping Hold that button to act like you can do things like that or you can bind them to separate things.
Rym: Binding them to separate things only makes sense.
Rym: If you're using a big-ass joystick, like I have all these toggle switches So all my targeting computer stuff at the bottom of my throttle I'm like flicking switches to do all that stuff and it feels great.
Rym: But if you don't have that you can overload buttons on your joypad to make sure you can do everything you need to do.
Rym: That's actually a really good design decision But I think so.
Scott: the main so the main mode right we talk about the dogfighting mode right the main mode of this game is his fleet battle and the fleet battle is They set up a map and on one end of the map.
Scott: Is this MC 45, you know?
Scott: Alliance yeah, Mon Calamari crews are looking thing Yeah, and then the other end is a star destroyer normal one.
Scott: and then there are two sort of capital ships, right?
Rym: You know frigates basically, yep to frigates or to uh to like other types of ships, right?
Scott: And then each side has sort of like this mini Ship.
Scott: right.
Scott: in the case of the good guys It's the Corvette the very Corvette that you a very first ship you see in Star Wars.
Rym: So one that you have to slay is on the one with the auto turrets that you fought with when you were playing tie fighter Exactly.
Scott: And on the other side the the Empire has this Reaper ship, which is like a little mini star destroyer.
Scott: It's like a triangle guy little triangle guy.
Scott: And then everyone.
Rym: I think that's just the assault ship.
Scott: It's a little triangle guy.
Rym: that is a little triangle.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, everyone launches out of the capital ship and it takes a while.
Scott: It's like fly out to the you know battlefield, right?
Scott: And you start shooting stuff and if you destroy enemy stuff you get points.
Scott: if you destroy an enemy human You'd get a lot of points.
Scott: That's like a lot.
Scott: It's big-time.
Rym: Yeah, there's also a bunch of a eyes flying around like just random.
Scott: There's just like garbage tie fighters and x-wings just flying around randomly controlled by AI.
Scott: They don't do much and you actually don't even notice them unless you seek them out.
Rym: But if you shoot them you got a couple points like it's not nothing and they do come after you like they will actually like Attack you and if you're doing dumb stuff, they'll really attack you a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, if you fly too far like if you fly out near the enemy frigates, they will just destroy you basically instantly.
Rym: It's sort of like an instant kill zone just like an old tie fighter like you get too close to like a rebel capital ship.
Rym: You're just done unless you were right.
Scott: It's like you could survive out there But really you shouldn't see you sort of there's.
Scott: only so far you can go away from your capital ship.
Scott: That's safe and you start scoring points.
Scott: the other team scores points and whoever scores more points you'll see at the top of the screen this is bar that goes back and forth and It'll give one team the advantage.
Scott: so if you have the advantage it will now be safer for you to go further out.
Scott: and So now you can start attacking their capital ships to try to destroy.
Rym: so it's a lot like nidhogg You start in the middle and you're trying to push all the way to the other side and destroy the enemies thing.
Scott: your mood There's like this instant kill zone sort of DMZ line and you're by scoring points killing enemies blowing up ships.
Scott: you're moving that line towards the enemy and when you get hit the line moves towards you and You eventually you destroy both their capital ships, right?
Scott: both of their frigates whatever and The line gets pushed all the way back to their capital ship and then you can start destroying that.
Scott: you have to just.
Scott: it has Individual systems to destroy right?
Rym: It's like it's got less though.
Scott: Like it's not like in the old shields It's you know, it's a pain in the ass But you eventually you can take it out and when you take it out you win and that's that's how it works.
Rym: So it's sort of a back-and-forth push but the damage you do to those ships is permanent.
Scott: So yeah, the only thing that's not permanent.
Scott: Is that the Corvette and the Reaper?
Scott: the smallest?
Scott: non?
Scott: It's the smallest.
Rym: It's not the Reaper.
Rym: You call it a Reaper.
Rym: The Reaper is the support ship on the Empire side.
Rym: Oh, what?
Scott: Oh the Raider the Raider.
Scott: Ah, it's very similar.
Scott: They both in start and end with our Raider.
Rym: Anyway, I don't play those support ships on either side at all.
Scott: No me either but the the you can if you push your advantage your whichever side sort of is currently like on the attack will have it like if the if the rebels start attack pushing a Corvette will spawn out of nowhere and start attacking and you can sort of fly with it and defend it because it will do a lot of damage if you can keep it alive.
Scott: and Meanwhile, if you are being attacked by the Corvette you want to take that thing out quick?
Scott: Yeah, because that'll give you a lot of points and sort of flip the field and then the Raider will come out and you can Attack with the Raider.
Rym: now think about this, too.
Rym: You might all be like star fighters when the match starts But once you get on the offense, you might have like someone switch like flies back to the hangar switches to a y-wing Mm-hmm.
Rym: Like you can switch ships is the equivalent.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, if you fly back, so there if you're for if your frigates are still alive They have healing zones in them that you can go into to heal to get repaired on the battlefield.
Scott: Yeah, and as long as you're not dead, you can always go back to your capital ship.
Scott: You just can fly as fast as possible right into the hangar and it'll just suck you in perfectly every time And then you can spawn a brand new ship in perfect quality.
Scott: Even if your capital ship is on the brink of death.
Scott: Yeah, just come right out with a brand new thing good as new.
Rym: generally like Killing the humans who are playing like dogfighting with the humans and taking them out is the general thing to be doing Except when you have specific objectives along the way, you just got to coordinate with your team.
Rym: the experience itself Just feels like you're in a Star Wars movie like the actual fighting when you don't run into glitches and it's just working even if You're getting wrecked by the other team.
Rym: It just feels Really really immersive and tight.
Rym: like.
Rym: the environments are really good.
Rym: There's a bunch of different maps that this happens in.
Scott: the only Boring one of the maps is not so good.
Rym: The boring one is the red mist one because it's just a big open field with some mist you can theoretically fly into But at the top and bottom, yeah, but the other ones like there's a big space station.
Rym: You can actually get inside the space station.
Scott: The space station was the best one I love.
Rym: I was chasing a y-wing and he like went into the space station trying to get away from me.
Rym: So I just flew to the other side of the space station and came around and like headed him off and it felt so good.
Rym: We lost cuz we suck.
Rym: but that one moment was so sublime.
Rym: I don't think he expected the only thing about.
Scott: the only thing about the game that doesn't feel Absolutely, perfect is the feeling of speed.
Rym: You're the only person I've ever heard complain about this.
Scott: No one else has a problem.
Scott: I've been complaining about it.
Scott: So what happens is you're.
Scott: you can be even in like an a-wing right with the fastest engine.
Scott: You turn it up to full speed and you don't feel like you're going that fast.
Rym: Yeah, I do.
Scott: I don't know where you get there so far away at least at the start.
Scott: Let's say you spawn out of your capital ship.
Scott: You are so far away from the action that it like.
Scott: it takes you just forever to get over there.
Scott: It feels like forever, right?
Scott: So it's like it's sort of like going beep beep beep, but then see you are actually going fast.
Scott: It's just that the distance is so great and you're in wide open space.
Scott: It wasn't feeling fast as soon as you get near things.
Scott: It feels way too fast.
Scott: It's like this exponential thing right where it's like you'll be a thousand whatever units of distance They're using to you know to measure in this game.
Scott: Yeah, it tells you your range to your current target, right?
Scott: So be targeting so another an enemy TIE fighter and I'd be like, oh the enemy TIE fighters 1500 something's away from you.
Scott: And you're like, okay, you start flying towards it.
Scott: It'll be like 15 14 13 10 9 8 7 6 or 3 year.
Scott: It's exponential right?
Scott: So and that's what the speed feels like.
Scott: It's like when you're far away It feels like well I guess I'm gonna spend the next minute of this game getting back into the action and then once you're in the action It's like too fast too fast too fast.
Scott: Like you're going past the.
Rym: I wonder part of our difference, right in Perception might be specifically because I am playing in VR.
Scott: It could be the VR could definitely because modify the process.
Rym: I wasn't played in VR, but I'll talk about the VR a little bit because a brilliant thing about this game is VR headset for the cockpit of a vehicle in space is like the ideal use case for a VR headset and much Star Wars by supporting that.
Rym: the fact that the game works equally well on a desktop with a monitor or a VR headset and it supports pretty much any modern VR headset.
Rym: the fact that both are supported equally is great.
Rym: The caveat is they do not let you ever have a third-person view.
Rym: You are always first-person view.
Rym: that is by design.
Rym: They've talked a lot about why they made that have third-person view even without VR.
Scott: It's just yeah, there's only one camera.
Rym: That's it first person the end, but I will say the cockpit the VR.
Rym: the only part that doesn't just work are glitches early on that they've mostly fixed now or Configuring your shit because it's really hard to configure your shit in VR before you've configured your shit.
Rym: Bind all your stuff out of VR before you try VR the first time or you will not be able to even open the menu Because you can't even see your keyboard.
Rym: It's not like you can like use your mouse Mmm, so I bound everything before I went in.
Rym: but once you get VR working it is The best way I could describe it is intense.
Rym: It feels very Very real.
Rym: it is Terrifying to crash into something like in a way that like I wince like physically.
Rym: I react like I'm in a car that's about to crash but the moment when you're sitting it like the cockpit visibility of the x-wing is Nuts.
Rym: you turn around you see r2 like sitting behind you.
Rym: He's reacting to stuff.
Rym: Like when I'm flying into VR I'll literally like a like the enemy jukes to the left and I look left out my window and like Plan like kind of zoom around them and see them and come back around.
Rym: I would say that VR also makes you better at the game.
Rym: It is a better experience for competitive play and is a more immersive experience.
Rym: It is the best way.
Scott: the abilities just look right?
Scott: It's like I could technically look using like the right stick or something.
Scott: Yeah, right, but it's you know, I guess if you have enough if you have enough hot ass, you know, I guess.
Rym: Well, like my joy, my hot ass actually has a little Like gamepad stick that my thumb can just use on this.
Scott: I thought you could use that for looking around inside the cockpit and it didn't practice.
Rym: You're never gonna do that with a joystick.
Scott: that just feels weird But so but yeah, the VR gives you a greater field of view, which is a competitive advantage No doubt, but you can really.
Rym: if you're gonna play with VR You really need a hot ass.
Rym: you could possibly get away with a game like a joypad like a gamepad of some kind But I do have a sort of lose.
Scott: you could I mean the gamepad would be just fine even in VR But you would lose the immersive aspect Yeah, and the immersive aspect like.
Rym: I cannot stress enough how real and intense and good it is.
Rym: This gets into another thing that they did well in the old like x-wing tie fighter type games X-wings and tie fighters didn't really feel that different.
Rym: like the game kind of felt the same no matter what ship you were flying in.
Rym: This like a tie fighters are felt like the Imperial ships are very very very different from the rebel ships like Completely different skills some different things to do feels different to fly every single ship.
Scott: You know all.
Scott: there's only eight ships, but there are eight very different ships.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I feel like if they had included a tie defender or a b-wing.
Scott: It's like you know would they where?
Scott: what else could they do?
Scott: that would be feel that different like cuz.
Rym: they know the x-wing game.
Scott: It might be different strategically.
Scott: Yeah, wouldn't you know be different?
Rym: you know feeling like you play la wing it doesn't actually feel different from an x-wing in this game.
Rym: You're flying x-wing you feel like you're good like you got this game And then you try an a-wing and you'll immediately crash because holy fuck is it fast?
Rym: Yeah, it's too fast But the and the visibility is a big factor to like the x-wing.
Rym: the rebel ships in general have great.
Scott: You can see everything.
Scott: it's like you have a big glass dome.
Scott: You know see the whole world and you fly and then you fly a tie fighter And you're.
Rym: it's like you're looking at a peephole at the world and in VR It's funny because you look around and you see just like the inside of a tie fighter.
Rym: I'm like lead.
Rym: I literally am like leaning forward in my seat to try to look down between my legs when I'm chasing someone Mm-hmm, but also gameplay is very different.
Rym: Here's a. I'll give one example that drives home how like.
Rym: Well, they designed the game itself irrespective of the polish problems Though a big aspect of the old games was you can divert power between shields and weapons and engines in this game.
Rym: But it was very fiddly like plus or minus a pip like you tune it constantly through the game.
Rym: in this You generally go between put it fucking all in engines or all in weapons or all in shield Yeah, and pips are still there, but it's like.
Scott: do you really it does like, you know to sit there fiddling with the pips It's like no you're rather an engine mode shield mode.
Scott: If your ship has shields or weapon mode, but the three modes the difference is Radical.
Rym: if you put it in engines you're going like twice as fast.
Scott: you put it in and when you're in engines your boost will Start charging and you can use the boost.
Rym: Yep, or you put it in weapons You just had like.
Rym: your lasers are just better and stronger and recharge You get near a capital ship or it's like you have to.
Scott: you know It's like you sort of have to like switch to weapons when you before you start shooting then switch away from it.
Scott: But if you switch to weapons when you're shooting someone fast They're getting might get away from you.
Scott: So you have to keep it in engines and then you're shooting them but you're shooting them weak sauce and hit them more.
Scott: You know, you gotta you gotta figure it out, but the Thai fighters don't have shields No shields, but instead they have a thing.
Rym: they can do that.
Rym: No, the rebel ships can't do.
Rym: you can still divert power between she or not between shield between weapons and engines.
Rym: That's the normal thing.
Rym: You can also Shunt power separately from the charging and no rebel ships can do this.
Rym: so you can just take your engine power and Transfer it into your weapons instantly like take all your boost and turn it in a laser or vice versa.
Rym: That is really like.
Rym: I'm not good at that.
Rym: We mostly fly rebel and I'm still like trying to learn how to do that effectively in a Thai fighter.
Scott: I'm still not even entirely sure like the exact details of like how it works.
Rym: Real simple.
Rym: if you hit the button to shunt into weapon It takes all your boost away and puts up that equivalent amount of energy into laser.
Scott: charge instantly Okay with no loss Okay, but it does it like what happened does it?
Scott: but in future energy that I'm generating the charging is there.
Rym: the charging is independent of the shunting.
Rym: Okay, so if I tell it so charge.
Rym: so what I often do in a Thai fighter now I tell it I put it in engine mode all the time and anytime I need more lasers.
Rym: I don't tell it to charge lasers.
Rym: I just shut my boost into my lasers directly.
Scott: So I have to add way to do it.
Rym: So my left thumb is on a stick to change the engine charging like that Like what's charging and my right thumb on my hot ass is shunting power?
Scott: Mmm, so the shunting button the button that you use to shunt at least on a gamepad by default if you're in an x-wing That has shields.
Scott: that button Instead does shield directionality.
Scott: so you can put your shields forward or back or neutral When you're going in when you're going in like, you know on an attack run you put your shields forward Yeah, and then you shoot and then you turn around and you're running away.
Scott: Right because the big strategy of this game is that when you die the enemy team scores a lot of points.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want to die.
Rym: You can get back home Even if you're out of action for a while doing it.
Rym: It is so worth it.
Scott: more important than killing is not dying because you die.
Scott: you give them points to give them the advantage.
Scott: So just go out there do any amount of damage.
Scott: you go back and heal instead of dying Even if you have one health left, that's actually good.
Scott: If you have one health left, right you make it back and survive.
Scott: Right, that is great.
Scott: So you put the rear shields on and when you run away and you're all good Yep.
Rym: So what I've got those bound to is on my my joystick.
Rym: My main one has one two, three four hats.
Rym: So one of those hats is for charging the engine stuff on my throttle.
Rym: I have three more hats.
Rym: so one of the hats on the throttle is for Redirecting the shields and the other hat is for shunting energy.
Rym: and the shunting energy.
Rym: I made those directions match the charging directions on the other hat.
Scott: yeah, the gamepad just the default controls are to have the shunting and the shield directions on the same button because They're this when you're in what a tie fighter you're never gonna have shield directions, right?
Scott: and so that's the same button for either way and it's the same user interface on the screen.
Scott: the only difference is that the Shunting is like left and right and the shields are up and down and there's more things like that.
Rym: but the the moral of that is pretty simply just that the ships are Very different from each other and require very different skills and have different.
Scott: you have to get good at all the ships, right?
Scott: it's it's and it's not like say You know other asymmetric games you can specialize in one thing.
Scott: be like, I'm like I play guile.
Scott: I mean Samus.
Scott: It's like no.
Scott: No, you got to be good at all fucking eight of these ships Or like.
Rym: right now Julie I'm practicing hard with the a-wing.
Rym: I'm getting pretty good at it Like I am good at the a-wing and I did it.
Rym: I did a decent job in our last game of keeping people off of you guys like it was working out.
Rym: I got a lot of kills But I go play the interceptor the equiv the red.
Rym: the Imperial equivalent of the a-wing is the tie interceptor.
Rym: That's their interceptor.
Rym: I'm just a garbage baby at it, even though it's the interceptor.
Rym: It's so different from the a-wing that I can't fucking fly it.
Rym: Yep, that is what's making this game great.
Rym: that is where I'm finding.
Rym: a lot of the fun I'm having is just every decision you make in the game matters a lot.
Scott: So I think if you are who should buy this game if you have a VR headset Honestly, like just get this game because this is oh, yeah, cuz there's like what other game you're gonna get.
Rym: Yeah, no game if you're a VR like this game is just don't buy a VR headset or just for this game No, but if you already have a VR headset, this is a must-buy game.
Scott: Yeah, even if you just you're really tutorial if like us you really like the old tie fighters x-wings and whatnot.
Scott: Then you got to get this game.
Scott: if you're a Star Wars fan who is fast Fantasized about flying Star Wars ships.
Scott: Yeah get this game.
Scott: If you're so rich that $40 means nothing to you get this game.
Scott: Yeah, if you really like getting competitively good at a high skill game And you want to do a space shoot a game you can get this game.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to do the single player of this game and not are interested in multiplayer I would wait for it to be cheap.
Scott: Yeah Then get this game.
Rym: if you get really salty when you don't get Rewarded by just playing like if you need like loot boxes and nonsense to keep you playing a game you do unlock some Skins and things.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but you don't get anything that helps you with the game.
Rym: Nothing progresses in a meaningful way unless you get better at flying.
Scott: That's it, right.
Scott: You can play this game for a year.
Scott: And if you don't get better at it, you'll still be ranked trash.
Rym: yep, if you Struggle with that in other games do not get this game because you're gonna this game Unlike a lot of other games that are high have high skill caps in competition.
Rym: This game basically gives you nothing if you are bad at it.
Scott: But yeah, if Star Wars and skill-based Competitive multiplayer are not for you.
Scott: This game is not for you.
Scott: Do not get this game.
Rym: Yep This game will have a bad time If you hot asses and joysticks are just sold out and really hard to get it.
Rym: You do not need one to play this game.
Scott: Like Scott said the gamepad is way better than you.
Scott: like I figured gamepad was poop I was gonna do mouse and keyboard.
Scott: No gamepad, you know with two analog sticks a modern gamepad is Totally legit at this game way.
Scott: But they did a way good job of gamepad support because I think the game got console releases.
Scott: Yeah, so only played the PC version, but I assume the console ones are the same as the experience I'm having only on a television.
Rym: I recommend if You're serious about the game getting a full-on hot ass like hands-on throttle and stick Because it just may probably help at least a little bit But I don't think it helped.
Scott: I think the difference is less than I thought before playing Yeah, but it's obviously that it just from playing with the gamepad.
Scott: It's obvious the hot ass would be better Yeah, but I previously thought it would be a lot better.
Scott: and now I'm saying it's probably Moderately or maybe even just a little better.
Rym: I think it's a lot better at very high skill, but I am NOT that.
Scott: Yeah, well, I think they did.
Scott: there was recently.
Scott: that's an example of a bug fix They recently fixed like the dead zones on actual joysticks.
Rym: Oh, yeah, they basically made joysticks way worse than they fixed it.
Scott: But they fixed it now, so it's all good.
Rym: Uh, but the hot ass is definitely a lot more fun.
Rym: But yeah, but if you can't get a hold of one more immersive It's fun enough with a gamepad until you get your like pre your back order of a logitech thing I personally recommend the side tech or logitech.
Rym: I guess x56 Stick and throttle that one actually was.
Scott: I think there's two.
Scott: there's two logitech models.
Scott: I think that they currently make there's like a super high-end one and a super normal one.
Scott: I think the normal one's gonna get you there.
Scott: Yeah, because this is not a full you don't need the super fancy extra expensive.
Scott: Just get the regular expensive.
Rym: I only got the more expensive one because one it will.
Rym: I found a place I could buy it and the other the cheaper one was out of stock and I really wanted it as fast as possible.
Rym: and two I'm also planning to get deep into Microsoft flight simulator and I did need all those toggle switches for that.
Scott: If you're doing Microsoft flight simulator, then yeah, you're gonna want but you don't need foot pedals for this game.
Scott: Most no, they won't help you that much.
Scott: because yeah, so there is an X. there's an x56 hot ass 50. there's an x52 and an x52 professional.
Scott: The x56 is 250 dollars.
Scott: The 52 is 150 and the 52 Professional is 200.
Scott: You'll be fine with those 52s for this game.
Scott: They are gonna get you there.
Scott: They'll probably even get you there for Microsoft flight simulator.
Scott: but if you get really serious that yeah, you're gonna need that x56.
Scott: and also It seems like they make a lot of other stuff like this.
Scott: actually if you're doing flight simulator.
Rym: Oh, they make like you stop panels of switches and buttons that mirror real cockpits.
Scott: They've got flight instrument panels They got rudder pedals.
Scott: They got yokes, right?
Scott: They got all that kind of stuff.
Scott: They got you know The throttle quadrant that has the three separate things, you know on it, right?
Rym: Yep, I mean the x56 does have a dual throttle.
Rym: dual throttle does not do anything for you in Star Wars.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Scott: the x52 is the one for Star Wars if this is your game, but oh, you know, it's on $50.
Scott: So are you playing $150?
Scott: You better really fucking love this game, which I think I do like.
Rym: it's real fun I guess the last thing I'll say is I'm glad that they definitely leaned into the yes This is the successor to those games because they added all these little touches.
Rym: Like you can go into the hangar and look at your ship.
Rym: There's a briefing in the game like they tell it like you get a briefing room in competitive.
Rym: There's a briefing room.
Rym: You can like sit with your team and plot before you fight The two stormtroopers that stand by the hangar in TIE fighter the whole time and don't let you in until you like register your name.
Rym: They're fucking standing there if you're playing in VR and you look behind you.
Rym: Yeah, all those little touches are there and I think all the polish issues are gonna get resolved within another three or four months.
Rym: They'll have resolved all those issues.
Scott: We'll see how much they continue to work on.
Scott: the game Definitely feels like a game where they made it they released it and they're do they like cut down to a skeleton crew to like Barely get it through its release period
Rym: and I wonder if they pushed it to get it out early because of kovat and people Are stuck at home -
Scott: who knows they're either going to Real see big numbers on it and then put more people on it and try to expand it or they're gonna be like, okay Original plan.
Scott: right where this game is now.
Scott: it is what it is.
Scott: We'll keep these servers on for some period of years and then turn them off the end.
Rym: Yep, maybe re-release it or do something in the future.
Rym: Like there's a lot of things they could do but I Guess the last complaint I have now and this will hopefully also resolve itself.
Rym: The matchmaking is not great.
Rym: You will get matched against people who are Infinitely better than you and you're just gonna have to deal with.
Scott: yeah, they improved it, but it's still man You're.
Rym: the matchmaking is not great But we can always get together with some of you like our squad versus like a squad of the listener.
Rym: That could be fun.
Rym: Yeah, sure.
Scott: I Did notice though that after they fixed so-called fixed the matchmaking what was happening is we kept getting matched against the same people over And over.
Scott: Yep, which is bad people are in your skill range play.
Scott: Oh, these people are still in your skill range.
Rym: play them again because there was one of them.
Rym: I won't say they're handling kids.
Rym: They're listening or like because there aren't that many people at that level.
Rym: Maybe they always flew the bombers.
Rym: They were kind of bad.
Rym: So I knew they were bad.
Rym: So every time I saw them I made a point of going out of my way to kill them because they were an easy kill And we kept playing games and they kept being against us.
Rym: So I kept like ragging on this one poor player for like two hours across games and I felt bad but kills the kill.
Scott: Well, it actually feels late but it's 730 because it's the shitty time of year.
Scott: God damn it.
Rym: GeekNights It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: Oh, no, it's recorded at night again for once.
Scott: I've talked enough about this game.
Scott: I don't use anything more.
Scott: You can really learn about it because it's not really that big a game, right?
Scott: It's its depth is in the gameplay not in you know, the stuff there's like so many maps.
Rym: There's a lot more that could be said but it's at the level of detail of.
Rym: let's talk about specific loadouts Let's talk about specific strategies.
Rym: That's not the kind of show.
Rym: GeekNights says go find some Star Wars squadrons podcast for that.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights that took us a little longer to record than normal for a bunch of reasons.
Rym: Yeah, there we go.
Rym: I'm stalling it for time before this thing loads Slower than usual.
Rym: All right, Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Greenia, Graham Finch.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart.
Rym: I Whistled for a cab and when it came near Clinton Walton, Jay Vance, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Farrand, Chris Midkiff, Dredd, Lily Tenebrae Just like a dude guy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin von Horl, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names The two things we're gonna try to make progress on now that we're past.
Rym: our set of online conventions Are not the tale of Hanzo But one.
Rym: I'm gonna try to finish reading that Castlevania book to you all because that was fun and I want to pick that up.
Rym: Again, I can still do that voice and two.
Rym: we're gonna make the utenna the next utenna episode.
Rym: I did get that pre-production partially done before COVID and we've just been gonna busy and lazy.
Rym: If Scott doesn't want to do it, maybe I'll put out a preview video.
Rym: That's just my half of it, but I'll get something out for you in the next month or so.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: But now I leave you with something that I wonder if you've ever encountered anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime anime (x7).