Rym: It's Wednesday, August 19th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about the Devilman manga and the Gibi-ate?
Rym: Gibi-ate?
Rym: Gibi-er?
Rym: The anime that's coming.
Rym: Already out partially.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So, I'm doing the podcast, you know, a little differently today.
Scott: for anyone who might be watching on the YouTubes, right?
Scott: It might look a little different because I'm standing looking into a much higher quality camera with maybe better, different, similar audio, I guess.
Scott: But yeah, we tried to set up technology to do panels remotely, right?
Scott: And, you know, it's pretty easy to podcast remotely because it's only audio, right?
Scott: So you could just slump over your computer.
Scott: You don't need to, you know, have.
Scott: you could just use a webcam if you want video, right?
Scott: It doesn't need to be good.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And like, you know, when we live stream the podcast, we started just live streaming like the production of the podcast.
Rym: And when we first started it, you see, I'm just like slumped over my desk.
Rym: Scott is like laying on his back with his eyes closed like that's how we do the show.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So to do a panel, we need like high quality video.
Scott: And if we're separate, right?
Scott: This creates a whole host of problems.
Scott: At least we don't have to live stream it, which is good, right?
Scott: I can just record video of me and audio of me.
Scott: Rym can record video and audio of him.
Scott: But we also need to communicate with each other at the same time.
Scott: We need to be able to, you know, have some talking going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So it's like, OK, I plug a microphone into my camera and I talk at it.
Scott: But then how does Rym hear what I'm saying?
Scott: Am I going to have two microphones, one for the computer?
Scott: And then I need to wear headphones so I can hear what Rym is saying.
Scott: So now I'm being recorded with headphones in my ears is not right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So in order to set this up is ridiculously complicated.
Scott: So I set it up and we're testing it out for a podcast before we use it for a panel.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Basically, we recorded one panel already.
Rym: So if you want, if you go to the Crunchyroll Expo online, like somewhere in that schedule, judge anime by its cover.
Rym: That was like version one of our recording panels remotely pipeline upcoming at the Penny Arcade Expo.
Scott: That was a worse setup than this.
Scott: This one's a better setup, I think.
Rym: This one's a lot better setup, but I'll tell you all the secret.
Rym: If you watch our Crunchyroll panel, it sounds like we're doing a good back and forth, like we're doing a normal panel thing.
Rym: I could only understand about 50, maybe 60 percent of what Scott was saying.
Rym: I just couldn't hear Scott.
Scott: We were communicating.
Scott: I had Discord on an iPad in front of me.
Rym: I had Discord in front of me on a laptop and a shitty webcam pointed at me just out of frame.
Rym: So Scott could hear me.
Scott: Rym was hearing me because I was yelling at the iPad and the iPad built in microphone was picking me up and sending it over to Discord.
Scott: And then I was hearing Rym because I had headphones that were Bluetooth connected to the iPad and disconnected at one point.
Scott: So now the new setup, I managed to get my computer, like my computer, my camera to output not just video, but also audio over the HDMI cable.
Scott: And that's picked up by the capture card.
Scott: And then on the computer, I have a whole bunch of crazy nonsense that somehow sorts everything out between Discord, recording software, OBS, all kinds of nonsense.
Scott: And then the camera can also is recording video and audio too.
Scott: So, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I just cannot express to you.
Rym: Like it's interesting because I'm talking to a lot of people in the games industry because a lot of people are having trouble making their panels in this current environment.
Rym: But think of this.
Scott: They're experts on the thing they do.
Scott: They're not experts on cameras and video and audio.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Scott and I, like we've done GeekNights by ourselves for 15 years.
Rym: So like if we wanted a video, guess what?
Rym: We're both learning Premiere.
Rym: We want audio, guess what?
Rym: Audio engineers, fancy microphones.
Rym: Like we've basically been doing everything ourselves.
Rym: So, kind of pretty well positioned.
Rym: Meanwhile, I was like coaching literal industry professionals who like their job is to give lectures at conventions and they are struggling to like record themselves talking for 20 minutes in OBS.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They're not camera people.
Scott: They don't know how to use a camera.
Rym: Like do you think Jon Stewart, like you watch the Daily Show for 20 years, do you think Jon Stewart like could just set up all those cameras and make all that like nice color grading and everything happen for a home podcast?
Scott: No, he has no idea probably.
Scott: Yeah, he might, but probably not.
Rym: But usually the talent is like when someone's called the talent, on one hand, you might think, oh, yeah, like they're the person who's like the star.
Rym: But that also means like the stage crew front, like back of house, front of house, all the people who are like dealing with them, when they refer to the talent, it means those are the people who literally can do nothing but be on stage.
Rym: And our sole job is to make them look like they know what they're doing.
Scott: I think it's just the general philosophy of like, you know, if I have a problem, I Google, I read things, I follow instructions.
Scott: I learn how to do something, right?
Scott: There's a lot of people who just don't want to learn, don't care to learn, don't try to learn.
Scott: They have a narrow focus, not a broad focus.
Scott: They only learn in their area.
Scott: They don't learn other areas, right?
Scott: All that sort of stuff.
Rym: Yeah, like you know, I learned audio engineering.
Rym: I was making mixtapes when I was like in middle school and they sounded like butt when I played them in the computer, like in the car.
Rym: So then I wanted them to sound better and I learned about equalizers and it just went down a rabbit hole from there.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: So yeah, I guess that's the thing.
Rym: But anyway, that segues into some news because there actually has already been a couple of like online anime conventions and things.
Rym: I think like there was OdaQuest, I think happened last weekend.
Rym: I saw people like talking about it a little bit, but I didn't really see that chatter until Sunday when it was like mostly done.
Scott: Yeah, so basically all I, I don't know details.
Scott: All I see is on Twitter, people who are deeper in the anime scene than we are, right?
Scott: Are being like, hey, there was an online anime convention or maybe more, there's at least two, but maybe more than two.
Scott: And those online anime conventions somehow, you know, got high quality Japanese guests to appear online at their convention, right?
Scott: So they must have paid the money.
Scott: And so the content at these online conventions was like interview with amazing director with a translator online.
Scott: And it's like, there's tons of these like an amazing amount of content that's like, you know, not been available before because a lot of those things would happen at anime cons in rooms that weren't streamed or recorded or uploaded.
Scott: We're now put online where anyone in the whole world could see them, not just people who could go to an anime con.
Scott: Maybe, I'm sure it wasn't free, but I'm sure it also wasn't 50 bucks.
Scott: And a whole bunch of this stuff happened, but seems like no one knew about it.
Scott: Even people who were like, would have like loved to do.
Scott: it only found out afterwards or not at all.
Rym: Yeah, this was like powered by Anime Central, like a serious thing that I kept hearing about it like vaguely.
Rym: And I thought, oh, I should see like, maybe I can submit a panel or something.
Rym: And then when I actually went to look at it, it had already happened.
Rym: Like if the event had happened and I just missed it.
Scott: Yoko Kanno was in this thing.
Scott: We just missed all this great anime stuff.
Scott: Yoko Kanno.
Rym: Yeah, right?
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: But like, there's another convention happening.
Scott: It's like, oh yeah, we had the greatest online anime con and we didn't tell anybody.
Rym: There's like another one happening this weekend.
Rym: That's like, I think, Magfest, a bunch of other content putting something together.
Rym: But like, I never saw like a call to panels.
Rym: I never get like, I didn't get press releases.
Rym: Like, I don't know what's going on here, but I feel like a lot of online cons are the people who are running them.
Rym: And we're not saying this happened with these particular cons because I don't know the details of why these particular cons didn't pierce our bubble.
Scott: Because I don't know anything about them.
Scott: How can I know what to criticize if I don't know anything?
Rym: You want like, I think what happened is that like us, like, you know how I find out about a convention to appear at or something because I get a press release because I'm on mailing lists like industry mailing lists and I didn't get shit about this stuff.
Rym: Meanwhile, most larger anime cons in the US at least have a history of not advertising.
Rym: Like, they never have to advertise.
Rym: They kind of assume people will show up because they have a bad, like, they run out of badges to sell, they fail.
Rym: So, it kind of just worked out that way.
Rym: Like, advertising would almost make their situation worse rather than better.
Scott: But also, I have seen some cons advertise and they usually advertise on like cheap local media, right?
Scott: Because they're local events where people come visit from around town.
Scott: You know, it's like you try to get the townies to come.
Scott: If you're trying to advertise to the internet, that's very difficult.
Rym: Most of the people who go to conventions in general, not just anime conventions, but also gaming cons and everything else, they all go for a lot of different reasons, mostly to hang out.
Rym: Like, there's a lot of stuff they want to do with these cons.
Rym: And at most cons, the guests and the panel content are not actually the biggest draw.
Rym: Like, that might surprise you, but kind of sadly true.
Rym: But I feel like, and again, not saying that this con did that, but I think this happened in a lot of instances, they kind of assumed that the people who go to the con in person would be interested in engaging with their content online.
Rym: And thus, they assumed that number, our normal attendance number, is probably like a nice baseline number of who would come to the online version because the online version is free or cheaper.
Rym: But the reality is, I think the majority of the people who go to conventions are not interested in the online versions of these conventions.
Rym: Like, I think about how many people interact at cons, they're mostly hanging out with their friends, like in anime cons, they're mostly hanging out cosplaying and running around yelling at each other.
Rym:  Going to room parties, stuff like that.
Rym:  Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: Plus, you have to consider, right, it's like, you know, GDQ is happening right now.
Scott: It's like, if I'm turning on, you know, my computer to watch something, everything in the world is competing with GDQ.
Scott:  Yup.
Scott:  That's a tough cut, that's a tough cut.
Rym: Oh my god, that Zelda 2 reverse boss order run, once I realized it was also a glitch run.
Scott: I didn't realize, I was like, reverse boss order, how are they going to get to the Thunderbird first?
Scott: They have to be doing like the second to last boss first so that they can.
Scott: then eventually, are they going to go from dungeon one through the end and get all the items, then go back and beat the bungeons in reverse, then I'll go to the final dungeon.
Scott: It's like, nope, Thunderbird first.
Rym: Yup, it was like, it was one of the glitchier, like it is up there in terms of glitch runs with like the Final Fantasy 4 staircase run.
Scott: Pretty much.
Rym: But so yeah, there's probably some online anime cons, but I don't know, the only one we really know about and are performing at right now is the Crunchyroll Expo.
Rym: And other than answering questions added, I don't think I'm going to go, like I'm not going to go to other online content from most of these cons, because again, like you said.
Scott: No, I really, you know, if these cons want, you know, if you're, if you're having online con and your online con is literally just a bunch of videos, right, for people to pay and watch, don't make it like some live event.
Scott: Just put the videos up on YouTube, even charge money for the videos if you want, but just put them up there for all time so anyone can come and see them whenever.
Scott: And then people will come and see them whenever.
Scott: Or if you're just like, all right, today for six hours, there's going to be video content on this one TV channel, temporary television channel, limited time only, then it's gone.
Rym: It's like, I don't even watch GDQ live usually.
Rym: Usually I'll watch the VOD on YouTube, like later that day or the next day.
Scott: I'll watch some of it live, but not much, right?
Scott: Just a little bit, whatever.
Scott: Like I watch it during lunch.
Rym: But like whatever you do with online cons, if something's live, there's got to be some interactive reason for people to be there live for it.
Rym: Even if it's like a Discord where all the people watching the channel are like interacting and there's some reason to do that interaction, you got to have some reason.
Scott: I just find it sad that suddenly, right, it's like all this amazing anime con type content has been created.
Scott: And where is it?
Scott: And who knows about it?
Scott: It's like a sad situation of like, no, why?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So in some other news, that's actually a pretty big deal.
Rym: A bunch of shitty piracy sites for manga and anime are now gone for good.
Rym: KISS anime and KISS manga are dead.
Scott: So now like we're never been against piracy, right?
Scott: It's like, if you want to watch something and you know, you can't afford it or it's only on like one service, you don't want to set up for that service.
Scott: It's the only thing you want to watch on there.
Scott: You know, yeah, there's plenty of legitimate reasons that I will never tell anyone like, don't pirate, right?
Scott: You're poor and they're charging 20 bucks.
Scott: So many valid reasons to pirate something.
Scott: You know, I'm never going to go say don't pirate.
Scott: What I don't like is the other side of piracy, which is where, you know, not someone who wants to watch something goes out and watches it by any means necessary, but someone who takes a bunch of stuff, a whole bunch, and then sells it to make money, even though they didn't make it, nor do they have rights to sell it, right?
Scott: So if you go, you know, we're talking like, I don't, you know, someone goes and buys a bootleg, you know, CD in the nineties.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Someone has a bunch of bootleg CDs in the nineties and sells them on a street corner.
Scott: Not okay.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So we're talking about a situation here where if you go online and you search for various anime or manga titles that you want to watch, right, for the many, many years, including today, you know, Google, the highest results, many, many results in the front page, sometimes even the first result would be illegal sites.
Rym: Which causes a weird third problem that I never even considered until this occurred.
Rym: It's been occurring for a while now, but the problem of someone doesn't actually realize they're pirating now.
Scott: Of course, they just go to Google.
Scott: They say, I want to read this manga and the top link, they click it.
Scott: They can read the manga.
Scott: It's right there, surrounded by advertisements.
Scott: It looks legitimate, but actually it's a pirated site that took scanslations or whatever, or just scanned in the actual manga or something like that.
Rym: Some of these services even just charge money for access, like selling it like it's a full-on thing.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, oh, no one's going to make a legit one.
Scott: I'll just make an illegal one.
Scott: And it's like, all right, though, you know, it's like one thing for Pirate Bay, right?
Scott: It's another thing for someone to go out and do this.
Rym: So I've encountered so many anime weebs who literally thought KissAnime was a legitimate site.
Scott: Right, so that's a big news is that KissAnime, one of the larger of these pirated, not legit, you know, watch anime sites is gone, bye-bye.
Scott: For reasons.
Rym: Yep, now what is interesting in the anime world, more so than other areas of piracy, like I don't see hockey fans making this argument with the pirate streams, like when Reddit NHL streams went down, but I do see this with American anime fans specifically.
Rym: There's a specific sort of like weird entitlement of, I have a right to watch this content no matter what, coupled with a like the official release is broken or wrong in some way.
Rym: Like they always make an excuse.
Scott: The first one, I kind of agree with, right?
Scott: I believe that if there is art, right, that all humans sort of have a right to view it.
Scott: If you have some art, like let's say you have some painting and you just keep it locked up and you never display it and no one can see it, you know, fuck you.
Scott: We should go and take that painting from you and hang it up in a museum where people can see it.
Rym: But we do need a way to compensate artists so that art continues to be made.
Rym: We have not solved that problem.
Scott: The current system is the correct one, right?
Scott: So, you know, there's...
Rym: Oh, yeah, we need massive copyright reform.
Rym: We need public funding for the arts, et cetera.
Rym: But the fact that the anime fans will try to make a dual moral argument of one, I have a right to this content and two, my excuse is and they'll make up some shit like they translated the subtitles wrong in the official release.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: If you're going to pirate stuff, well, one, they're usually wrong about that.
Rym: Like, all I'm saying is if you're going to sail the high seas, do not pretend you were doing anything noble, just sail.
Rym: Like, just be a pirate.
Rym: Don't try to pretend that you're taking this moral stance because Funimation censored the titty stuff in your anime when they actually did no such thing and you're literally making shit up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But also, you know, if you have a legitimate reason for why you're pirating, right, it's like, why make up the bullshit reason or tell yourself a bullshit reason?
Scott: They probably actually believe that reason.
Scott: That's why they say it.
Scott: But just say the real reason.
Scott: The real reason is I'm a teenager with no fucking money and I like anime.
Scott: I want to watch a lot of it and I have a lot of free time.
Scott: I can't possibly afford to buy legitimately the amount of anime that I want to watch.
Scott: So I'm going to pirate it.
Scott: I'm not going to lie.
Rym: The only reason I didn't pirate anime in middle school was that there was no way to do so.
Rym: But I did get fan subs, which is very close to piracy.
Scott: The only difference is those things were literally not licensed back then.
Scott: That is a perfectly legitimate reason for pirating in my eyes.
Scott: They're overcharging and you can't afford it.
Rym: All right, go ahead and pirate.
Rym: On one hand, society is broken and we need to fund this stuff.
Rym: But two, sites like KissAnime are basically the bottom of the barrel because they are both extracting money as a rent-seeking middleman to enable that piracy and denying money to the creators.
Rym: So they are skimming off the top.
Rym: They are just leeches.
Rym: If you're going to pirate all this anime, there are other ways to pirate it.
Rym: And the one thing I'd say is that if you live in America, go learn how to pirate things.
Rym: if you're going to pirate things.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Learn how to pirate things without giving money or on some shady-ass website.
Rym: Yeah, and the only other advice I have on that before we move on is don't pirate software.
Rym: It's all malware.
Rym: 100% of it.
Rym: You might think you know a way to pirate it.
Rym: You're wrong.
Rym: I guarantee there are ways to pirate software and you do not have access to them.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: All right.
Rym: In some other related news, not like semi-related, because it's related to weeb anger, a bunch of animation studios in Japan have basically taken a bunch of classic family kids-type anime and they put it all on a Japan-only YouTube channel just free.
Rym: Like Future Boy Conan, Black Jack, Astro Boy, a bunch of old Takahata stuff.
Scott: See, this is what Japan needs to do more of.
Rym: Oh, Japan only though.
Rym: It's not yet available in the rest of the world.
Rym: Only Japan.
Scott: Oh, they fucked it up.
Scott: Ah, no, no, no, no, no.
Rym: So, nerds are all seeing that and saying, "Oh, well, they fucked it up," because that's what would normally happen.
Rym: However, they did issue a press release saying, "The plan is to add subtitles in English and Chinese and open this channel up in the
Rym: future.".
Rym: The channel's brand new.
Rym: Give us a minute.
Rym: Jesus Christ, basically.
Scott: There have been a few recent legitimate services like Retro Crush, which you can just go get, where you can watch a lot of... They've somehow licensed a large, somewhat large number of old titles, right?
Scott: I guess really cheap licenses, things no one wants to watch, things no one wants to pay for, and managed to put them up on a free service.
Scott: I'd think there's ads or something.
Scott: You know, they get their money some other way.
Scott: And there's actually a lot of good old stuff.
Scott: It's just stuff that most people don't give a crap about.
Rym: Yeah, and there's not enough demand to make a formal overseas release.
Rym: You're never going to make money selling this.
Scott: No, no, no.
Rym: But it's also an important part of culture and history.
Rym: And even the article notes, no one pirates this stuff either.
Rym: It's not even really pirated that often.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: So, the people who own the content, especially if you own it on YouTube, cost you nothing other than the administration of the YouTube channel.
Rym: You're not even paying for bandwidth.
Scott: Yeah, but we could do a whole show about how Japan, this huge country with tons of money, one of the bigger economies in the world, has this huge media empire of music, movies, -That they're slowly advocating on.
Scott: anime, manga, novels.
Scott: And they say that they have this government program, Cool Japan.
Scott: They want to make it popular around the world to get some soft power around the world and spread their culture.
Scott: But what do they do?
Scott: is they always keep everything close to the chest.
Scott: Even when they have bands that tour the world, the band will release a different CD in Japan that has more tracks on it.
Scott: And they won't even put those tracks on Spotify anywhere else.
Scott: And it's like they'll publish a manga and they won't let it go over to any other country translated.
Scott: You ever seen a Japanese... They go on YouTube and they aggressively take everything down.
Scott: Meanwhile, South Korea, a tiny country with a lot less money than Japan, all their TV shows, all their music, everything free on YouTube, free on Spotify, free everywhere in the world.
Scott: They're just constantly putting out tons and tons of free content everywhere, just spreading it all over the place.
Scott: And oh, what do you know?
Scott: K-pop took over the world and J-pop, no one gives a crap, right?
Scott: So that's the story of Japan's media non-empire.
Scott: I think if Japan did somehow flip the switch and just put everything Japanese translated online for free, Japanese culture might actually take over the whole earth.
Rym: Well, you take a subset...
Scott: It's sort of a danger in the other scenario.
Rym: You take a low-risk subset of content that's hard to monetize both domestically and internationally and start with that.
Rym: This is actually a very positive step and I think this is a carpenter of good things to come.
Scott: But... It's still way too little, too late, even if it's a toe in the water.
Scott: Hey, it's a start.
Scott: Meanwhile...
Rym: Also, because despite all of this, anime is having this fandom and monetization renaissance in America right now.
Scott: Because people are stuck at home right now.
Scott: They got time to watch anime.
Rym: However, the internet shouty men who like to talk about anime, like the people who are not going to listen to a show like this to learn about anime, their narrative on this, the way a lot of people reacted to this news was really weird.
Rym: And I think it's the same kind of people who tried to justify their use of kissanime.
Rym: They basically tried to frame this as, and this was a big enough argument to where I saw real media people debunking it, that this was Japan striking back at Funimation and Crunchyroll for censoring anime and trying to push anime toward Western taste.
Scott: Japan doesn't give a crap about that.
Scott: Japan loves censoring stuff for the West.
Rym: You know what it is?
Scott: They'll even say, "Please censor this for the West.
Scott: We don't want you to see crazy
Scott: Japan.".
Rym: The weebs seem to think that, they know that Tim Apple makes every decision for Apple, so they seem to think that Mr.
Rym: Japan is personally mad that their titty anime wasn't carried by Crunchyroll.
Scott: Yes, there's a Mr.
Scott: Japan who controls everything.
Rym: Because their titty anime was taken off of Crunchyroll, they think and they made up this narrative that Japan is trying to bypass Crunchyroll to get to the world with their titty anime, which is...
Scott: This is just a thing that happens everywhere, right?
Scott: People see a thing happen, right?
Rym: And they mold it into whatever narrative they've already set forth in their head.
Scott: They come up with whatever explanation matches their existing beliefs, they tie it in, and then they say it, because it makes so much sense to them, they say it as if it was true, and then other people believe it as if it was true because people start to spread it, and then suddenly it's a rumor, right?
Rym: Well, case in point, half the apocryphal stories from anime in the 90s and early 2000s came from someone who was given a panel at some con that wasn't recorded, they made some shit up.
Rym: that sounded plausible, someone saw that panel, they then, years later, do their own panel, and they reference what they saw in that first panel, and now you've got people literally making shit up about the anime industry.
Scott: Well, I mean, about everything, right?
Scott: And I think that the solution to this is-- You don't see it in the games industry as much because a lot more of the panel-- You see it in the games industry.
Rym: Not as much.
Rym: I think because the bigger game cons, more of their content was recorded earlier, so there was, like, people had less room to make shit up, and there were fewer fans doing panels without some sort of credential check.
Scott: Or it could just be that you're paying attention to the English games industry in English, so people, it's hard to make stuff up when the people who, you know, right?
Rym: There's a lot more people to call you on it, but, like, American anime fandom, English-speaking anime fans, all went to those conventions, so everything that sounded plausible was taken as truth, even in the wider industry discourse.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I just think about, you know, I'm not even talking about, like, within nerdy industries.
Scott: I'm talking just about, in general, discourse of anything, right?
Scott: You know, rumors come to be when the original source of the information doesn't reveal all of the surrounding details, right?
Scott: If you come out with something and say, "Oh, yeah, we're delaying this product," right?
Rym: It must be a conspiracy.
Scott: Well, it's like, well, people start to think, "Why are they delaying it?
Scott: What was -- Mm, what
Scott: happened?".
Scott: You know, right?
Scott: It's like, if I'm delaying a product, I should say, "I'm delaying this product because every -- Here's every single detail.
Scott: I ran out of money, and I need to find another investor to get this much because I had to let this person go, and that person had the skills to get us through this next phase, which isn't done yet,".
Scott: right?
Scott: Tell everything, right?
Scott: No, I don't think that works.
Rym: There's no reason to keep -- Scott, as a product manager, I've found that that doesn't work because if you tell everything, a significant subset of people will assume you are lying or covering something up anyway.
Scott: It's their problem, but it's still way less people.
Rym: Case in point, this article we're talking about, they said in their press release, "We're making English
Rym: subtitles.".
Rym: Like, that's in the plan, yet people were still just lying about it online and saying that this is just another example of Japan being closed.
Scott: 'Cause people only read the headline.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: Whoever wrote the article about the press release probably didn't, you know, anyway, frame it correctly.
Rym: I feel like even if Mr.
Rym: Japan said out loud -- Like, him and Tim Apple got together on a stage, and they were like, "Look, this is not in --".
Scott: Tim Apple's the number-one secret keeper.
Scott: He's the secret keeper.
Scott: He doesn't tell you anything.
Rym: Think about this, though.
Rym: Imagine if Apple said, "Oh, iOS 14 is delayed because of
Rym: X.".
Rym: I feel like half the people who care about Apple News would immediately assume that because they revealed more information than usual that they were hiding something.
Scott: Well, they could just --.
Scott: That's the problem, is that they've been keeping secrets for so long.
Scott: It's like a reverse wolf cry, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You have to never keep secrets to begin with.
Scott: Build trust, right?
Scott: By keeping secrets all the time, you don't have trust.
Scott: So now if you suddenly turn right and start being honest, you know, you got problems.
Scott: You got to be honest and completely open from the get-go, right, to have your correct reputation.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So anyway, last and least, do you want to talk about this Leiji Matsumoto thing?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So they're publishing this book.
Scott: It's $45.
Scott: So I do not blame anyone who doesn't want to buy this book.
Scott: It's only for extreme nerds.
Scott: But basically --.
Scott: I guess if you're doing research -- -You know, yeah.
Scott: In Japan, right, people -- I mean, everywhere in the world, not just in Japan, but people write essays about things.
Scott: It's a thing people do, right?
Scott: You know, write essays on stuff, book reports, you know, reviews of books in newspapers, all kinds of stuff, right?
Scott: But it's like when a topic is very local, right, you know, you're only going to find, you know, people expounding and deeply investigating something that's local to them, right?
Scott: So if you wanted to learn a lot about, I don't know, some Belgian rock band, right, you're probably -- if they're super popular in Belgium, I bet you'd find a lot of articles and deep information about their history and who they were in Belgium, in a Belgian library.
Scott: If you could read, you know, right, you could read their material.
Scott: You could find out a ton of information on them.
Scott: French.
Rym: Yeah, French or Flemish.
Scott: The point is, if you're in the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: you've discovered that band, you go to the Wikipedia page, you're lucky if it's got one paragraph, you're lucky if any of your music's on Spotify, right?
Scott: You just -- it's hard to learn about them, right?
Rym: I remember as a young anime fan, I found out about 2Mix.
Rym: I was like, "What is
Rym: 2Mix?".
Rym: I couldn't find anything in English.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So Japan, which has this media that keeps everything close to the chest, people want to find out about it.
Scott: You know, Leiji Matsumoto is someone that has a lot of fans around the world, especially in Italy.
Scott: He's got a ton of fans in Italy.
Scott: And, you know, if you want to learn about Leiji Matsumoto, there's actually tons of material people have written about him and his works in Japan, in Japanese, right?
Scott: It's just not really available.
Scott: No one's republishing that in English, because who cares?
Scott: There's not a lot of English.
Scott: People who speak English or other non-Japanese languages, they care to watch Leiji Matsumoto's anime, right?
Scott: But do they really care to read essays about Leiji Matsumoto?
Scott: Probably not.
Scott: So when someone translates, or gathers and translates a pile of essays about Leiji Matsumoto in a book, that book costs $45.
Rym: It doesn't say how many pages it is, but that information is not actually revealed yet, but it has 60 photos in it.
Scott: Yeah, so Helen McCarthy and, who's this, Darren John Ashmore, right?
Scott: I think they have compiled and translated a whole mess of Leiji Matsumoto essays so you can learn everything there is to know about Leiji Matsumoto.
Rym: "Previously unexplored biographical and bibliographic
Rym: detail.".
Scott: Short of actually meeting and knowing the person himself, or being the person himself, a book of essays is about as close as a complete stranger is going to get to knowing someone and what they're all about.
Scott: So this book's coming.
Scott: If you got $45 and you're a really big Matsumoto fan, buy it.
Rym: Or if you're putting together a panel for an online anime con on Leiji Matsumoto, this would be some really good source material.
Scott: Yeah, but I have a feeling that the author should probably be doing that panel, not you, a reader of the book.
Rym: Your panel, if you're citing a book heavily, should cite at least multiple books and have a narrative based on the citations across those books.
Rym: I feel like there will be people who will buy this book and do a panel to base solely on this book, though.
Scott: But what it does mean, though, is that don't go read this book and just turn the book into a panel.
Scott: What you should do is realize that once this book comes out, there are those people who are going to pay $45 and read it.
Scott: And the authors themselves, you're going to be able to get some of that learning without buying and reading the book yourself because people are going to be reading it and then repeating what they have read in other relevant venues.
Rym: Most of the history books I read will cite primary sources, but I don't usually go back and read all of those primary sources.
Scott: Of course not.
Scott: So yeah, book's coming out, so there's going to be a lot of Leiji Matsumoto biographical information available in English sometime soon-ish.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So you probably saw with the last Star Wars movie that there was a funny little animation of what Palpatine was up to during the last movie.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: You didn't see that?
Rym: It just pops out of the... Because it basically starts at the end when Vader throws him -- spoilers, I guess -- Vader throws him out of the ship and he goes flying off into space through that chute or whatever, and it shows like, "How do you end up in that
Rym: chair?".
Rym: And Yoda shows up and it's like this cute funny thing.
Rym: That channel is the same channel that made Big Top Burger and that has made a ton of short, desperately funny animations.
Rym: So what I'm linking to now, but I recommend you watch this whole channel, is titled "Frasier and Niles Become Demon
Rym: Lords."
Rym: It's just a short animated clip of Frasier Crane and Niles Crane from the show Frasier.
Scott: How many listeners know what that is?
Rym: You would be weirdly surprised how well-known Frasier is.
Scott: Like, I know it exists.
Scott: I would see beginnings or ends of Frasier episodes when I was watching other television programs.
Scott: But it did not look like anything I ever wanted to watch.
Rym: Oh, you would not have liked Frasier.
Rym: You would not have watched that show.
Rym: However, it is popular among a lot of webcomics.
Rym: people.
Rym: People our age who ended up making webcomics and got famous, they all have weird encyclopedic memory of Frasier for reasons I don't actually understand.
Scott: It seems like a super white people show.
Rym: Oh, God, yes.
Rym: This show is about a radio-- a pop psychologist, radio star, and his brother in Seattle.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Like, that is what this show is about.
Scott: And they become demon lords.
Rym: So in this animation, they become demon lords.
Rym: But this whole channel is just delightful, and I recommend you watch every video on this channel.
Rym: So what do you got?
Rym: All right.
Scott: So I feel like Thundercats are making a move lately.
Scott: I still have to go watch that Thundercats Go show that came out.
Scott: I got to figure out where it's--.
Rym: Oh, I want to watch it, too, because everyone said it's just Teen Titans Go, but for Thundercats, which you want to sell something to me.
Rym: That is exactly what I want.
Rym: I want the Teen Titans Go version of every popular media.
Rym: And the more it angers people who like that original media, the better.
Scott: But this video got posted on YouTube, like, just a few days ago, not very recently.
Scott: And it's the Thundercats opening, except it's the exact same-- It's just not a parody or anything.
Scott: It's the exact same Thundercats opening as the original, only computer-generated graphics instead of hand-drawn.
Scott: So somebody basically just CG'd the opening instead of-- And it's not the most impressive you've ever seen, but it's like, "Oh, all right.
Scott: Pretty good.
Scott: Pretty good
Scott: job.".
Scott: What makes this a thing of the day is that this was made not by some famous CG animator person, not like some Pixar person in their spare time.
Scott: Obviously, if it was, it would look way, way better than it does.
Rym: Well, if you raise the question, I thought I'd have a go at learning how to use 3D animation software.
Scott: I thought I'd go have a go at learning to use 3D animation software.
Scott: And you didn't do Pixar level, but look at that.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Look at that.
Rym: Not too bad.
Scott: So this thing of the day is not-- And it's got hundreds of thousands of views, by the way, more than any GeekNights episode, right?
Scott: Or GeekNights anything, for that matter.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The GeekNights YouTube channel has like two million-ish views, I want to say.
Scott: No.
Scott: Does any single video on the GeekNights YouTube channel have as many views as this?
Rym: A couple hundred thousand is like the max.
Rym: And those are not GeekNights episodes.
Rym: That's dumb shit I made.
Rym: Like The Simpsons to handle the Brexit, or Gooney's Game of Thrones type shit.
Scott: So the point of this thing of the day is obviously, if you want to have a go at learning something new, right?
Scott: Just pick a project, finish it.
Scott: It could even just be something like, "Oh, yeah, remake the Thundercats opener in
Scott: CG."
Scott: And just upload it.
Rym: Yeah, just do it.
Scott: And look at that.
Scott: You know, don't be like, "Oh, my crap is bad.
Scott: I'm not going to upload
Scott: it.".
Scott: This person-- You know, if I was this person, I'd be looking at what I output, and I'd be like, "This is back in.
Scott: I'll upload this.
Scott: Look how crappy this
Scott: is.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: But, you know, look what happens.
Scott: So, you know.
Scott: And they've never CG animated anything before, right?
Scott: They just learn from nothing.
Scott: Just like I learned cameras from nothing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's good stuff.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: Meta moment, I guess.
Rym: Doing GeekNights from home.
Rym: We're a little bit busy trying to get panels uploaded, but it shouldn't disrupt us too much.
Rym: So look for us at the Crunchyroll Expo, and look for us at the Penny Arcade Expo Online, with Judge Anime by its cover, and where is the finish line?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Any other meta things?
Scott: The Book Club book is still technically-- I can't even remember-- The Tale of Genji, the oldest novel to ever be written in human history.
Rym: We only stopped reading it because we're stuck at home and don't have any time to read like we normally would.
Scott: I had a feeling.
Scott: I had this feeling in my gut, like, "Must-read fantasy novel," right?
Scott: Or sci-fi novel.
Scott: Because it's summer, and it's like-- But there was no beach to go to to read one, and I still haven't read one.
Rym: Actually, I should check.
Rym: I hope a new R. Scott Becker book didn't come out, because I definitely don't--.
Rym: It's not like I'm going to read anything right now.
Scott: Well, maybe.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: So, yeah, just type the word "Geeknights" into Google, and you'll find our stuff.
Rym: Come to the forum, but more importantly, find somewhere in the forum a link to our Discord, the official unofficial, but, yeah, it's official, Geeknights Discord, because it's hopping more and more.
Rym: We've been playing train games with the listener, so you could join us and play some weird train games and stuff.
Scott: I will give you personal train game teaching lessons.
Rym: Scott literally trained the listener in how to play 18XX, 1846, and then we played it together, the three of us, and it was a good time.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, come on down to-- If you have never-- If this is somehow the first Geeknights thing you've ever seen, you don't know who the hell we are, just Google for "Geeknights" and find us.
Scott: We're, like, you know, a lot of stuff.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The only thing that won't show up that much is our website, because we're working on it.
Rym: Don't worry.
Scott: I'm working slowly.
Rym: Yeah, bit by bit.
Scott: If you know somebody who is really good at HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and wants to work on the Geeknights website, contact me.
Scott: Yeah, we'll pay.
Scott: If you know someone-- Yeah, we're paying money for this, obviously.
Scott: Good money.
Scott: So, if you know someone or are someone, right, contact me or refer them to me, and we'll get talking.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And if you want us to appear at a panel or something, like, if there's a convention, and you want us to, like, be at that convention online doing panels, contact me, and we'll sort out those details.
Rym: Also, if you think you are the kind of person who should be a guest on Geeknights, because you made a game or an anime or something, like, we're working out.
Rym: We got a pipeline set up.
Rym: We're going to do some interviews soon with some people, but email me.
Rym: I'll take care of that.
Rym: Maybe we'll make it happen.
Scott: Yeah, but not, you know, people who are just shamelessly shilling their stuff, right?
Scott: We're not interested, right?
Scott: We're interested in, like, actual human beings.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: We get a lot of those requests that we don't respond to.
Scott: Not those, you get random email, like, so-and-so that doesn't even know who you are wrote a book and sent an email to every podcast in the whole world trying to appear on podcasts.
Scott: It's like, no.
Scott: So-and-so who saw you at a convention once is working on a video game.
Scott: It's like, yes, okay.
Scott: Let's do it.
Scott: So, yeah.
Rym: Wow, Scott, I've been watching and reading a lot of different manga and comics and animation lately, so we figured we each talk about something we've read or watched recently, and I have to avoid talking about Kipo because I've talked about it in the opening part of the show, like, four or five times, and it's great, but I think I'll just have to wait for Scott
Scott: to watch it.
Scott: I don't remember you talking about it even one time.
Rym: Ah, okay.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: You should watch it.
Rym: It's actually pretty good.
Rym: It's short, too.
Rym: There's two pretty short seasons.
Rym: It's just on Netflix.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's a pretty good show.
Rym: It could theoretically be in the Giveyate universe.
Rym: That actually tracks pretty well.
Scott: Uh-oh.
Scott: All right, so which way are we going to talk about Giveyate?
Scott: first or Devil May?
Rym: We could do Givyater because it's...
Scott: So,
Rym: in the not yet published Judge Anime by its Cover panel, this was an upcoming anime, so we judged it, so if you want to hear what we thought it was going to be like, check us out at the Crunchyroll Expo, but based on the images that we saw, to paraphrase what we said, it looks like a bunch of characters who are very anime in a Fist of the North Star-looking world fighting demons together.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That's not immediately bad.
Rym: Yeah, and I figure, like, the way we looked at the show, the worst-case scenario is it is just a shounen fighting show, meaning it'll be four episodes of good stuff, and then it'll just be shounen fighting till the end.
Rym: So, uh, I actually watched the first two episodes of this show, and you know what?
Rym: It's all right.
Rym: It is, but it took a twist.
Rym: I'm going to spoil something.
Rym: It is more like Gasaraki than I expected.
Scott: No, that's a positive for me, but probably negative for everyone else in the world.
Rym: Right?
Rym: I feel like you, me, and our friend Pete are the only people on Earth who watched Gasaraki to the end and thought, "You know what?
Scott: I like that
Scott: show.".
Scott: Alex watched it, I think.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't think Alex liked it as much as we did.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: I don't know if anyone liked it except us, our little group.
Rym: All I remember is that that show is 24 episodes of buildup for a payoff that for some reason hit with us but did not hit with anyone else on Earth.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But there was a moment in that show, I guess spoilers, because who's watched Gasaraki?
Rym: None of you are going to watch Gasaraki if you haven't already watched Gasaraki.
Rym: Gasaraki just goes and goes and goes, and then there's an episode, like episode 13, where the opener's different, and it's just a different fucking show.
Rym: That happens in the middle of the first episode of Gibiate or Gibiate.
Rym: So Gibiate starts with a girl, and she's in an apartment in a Mad Max world, and she's got a camcorder.
Rym: It's funny because you see the camcorder, and it says it's a 16K resolution camcorder, clearly near future style.
Scott: Cool.
Rym: It's like the year 2030-something, and she's like, "I'm making this video.
Rym: I don't know if anyone will ever see it, but I just want people to know that I was here and that we
Rym: tried.".
Rym: And you get this story of like, there was a virus that appeared, and it turns the Gibi-er virus, and it turns people into Gibiates, which are basically zombie monsters, like giant animal monster that attacks people, and that caused an apocalypse and destroyed the world, and there's humans left over trying to find a cure for this disease.
Rym: Like, that's the plot.
Rym: Like, five minutes in, the show then cuts to the year 1600, like Tokugawa, and these samurai, and there's these two samurai on a boat, and one of them's like, "Oh, I know who you are," and the other one's like, "Oh, yeah, I know who you are, too,".
Rym: and the first one's like, "So, why did you get
Rym: exiled?".
Rym: And then, like, he tells his story, and the other one's like, "Oh, yeah, so I got exiled because of...".
Rym: and he tells his story.
Rym: So, we've got a ninja and a samurai on a boat in, like, 1600, leaving Edo because they have both been exiled for reasons, and there's a whole, like, backstory and plot there.
Rym: And that's where the show starts.
Rym: But, basically, those two characters...
Scott: It actually kind of makes me want to watch it.
Rym: So, that did make me want to watch it, and I do kind of want to watch more.
Rym: However, I looked online, just to get a link for this episode, because there's, like, seven episodes of the show out so far, and the show has mostly one-star reviews, and people seem to absolutely hate it.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Like, the reviews are resoundingly bad.
Rym: on every website that I've gone to, and the crazy part is, they're even, they're, like, the reviews are all, like, one-star.
Rym: Like, the majority of the reviews everywhere for this anime are one-star.
Scott: Every review is either going to be one-star or five-star, right?
Scott: Maybe sometimes four-star.
Scott: Two and three basically don't get used very often.
Scott: Especially, two is almost never used.
Rym: On Crunchyroll, six-fives, seven-fours, nine-threes, thirteen-twos, thirty-four-ones.
Rym: On MyAnimeList, there's, like, five-thousand reviews.
Rym: It's the same distribution.
Rym: Almost all ones.
Rym: But, the show's not that bad.
Rym: Like, the show's not great.
Rym: Like, maybe in the later episodes, like, the show Peter's Outer gets boring or something, but this is not a one-star anime, for the love of God.
Rym: This show feels so anime.
Rym: It feels like Fushigi Yugi or, like, whatever the show's like.
Rym: It feels like the show that would be the one everyone's cosplaying as and popular at an Otakon where the nerds like us are like, "Oh, that show's overrated.
Rym: I'm not that interested in that
Rym: show.".
Rym: Like, it feels like that kind of show.
Rym: I can't understand why people hate this show so much.
Rym: They mostly say it's boring, so it might actually be good.
Scott: Oh, maybe.
Scott: You did say it was Gasaraki-esque.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: But, uh, yeah.
Rym: So, based on what I've seen, I'm actually gonna keep watching this show.
Rym: Like, it's... I'm intrigued by the premise a little bit, and I want to see why we have these samurai from 1600 in the year 2038 fighting a disease that causes humans to turn into monsters.
Rym: And...
Scott: Well, I imagine that you will, uh, you know, the samurais will be somehow near the origin of the disease, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And you'll see the disease's effect all throughout history.
Scott: And that way, you know, setting up a story like that allows you to create new content at any point in history of like, "Oh, here's gibiates in the 1800s.
Scott: Here's gibiates in the 2030s," right?
Scott: It's like, you have a huge span of time.
Scott: You can just make up some characters in a different setting and throw in the gibiates and you're good to go.
Rym: I mean, Madoka Magica did that in a certain scene near the end where we saw a series of vignettes from different magical girls throughout history.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: So yeah, this show seems like, I feel like this show's gonna end up being like a three-star okay show.
Rym: And I really don't understand the weird vitriol in the reviews of the show because I have seen way worse shows that have higher ratings than this.
Scott: The only thing I can think is since you've only seen two episodes, something could be coming up in an episode up ahead that you will be like, "Oh God, one
Scott: star.".
Rym: Yep, it seems though like most of the complaints are that it's boring or people don't like the CG of the monsters because they look weird.
Rym: That seems to be like the only things people are actually saying about the show.
Rym: It's boring and I don't like the way the monsters look.
Scott: Okay, should I talk about Devilman now?
Rym: Yeah, let's talk about the Devilman.
Scott: Alright, so who published this here?
Scott: Alright, Seven Seas.
Scott: So Seven Seas published these two volumes, the classic collection Devilman by Gonagai.
Scott: So it's two big-ass books collecting literally all of the original Gonagai Devilman manga, right?
Scott: It's just two books, that's it.
Scott: So if you perhaps watch the amazing, excellent anime Devilman Crybaby, which we did talk about on this show I think?
Rym: Pretty sure we did.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I don't think we finished it when we talked about it, but we did talk about it.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: I finished it.
Scott: You can go back and read the original Devilman manga now in English, no problem.
Scott: So I read the whole freaking thing.
Scott: And first of all, it was a lot more similar to, I was under the impression watching Devilman Crybaby that it was quite a large departure from the original Devilman, right?
Scott: With only the base sort of intact.
Scott: No, the original Devilman is much more in line with Devilman Crybaby than I had any idea.
Scott: Interesting.
Rym: That actually makes me want to read this manga.
Scott: It should.
Scott: Something else, even though it's big books, there's only two volumes of this.
Scott: So there's actually a second manga called New Chin Devilman.
Scott: New Devilman, right?
Scott: And in that separate manga that is not part of the original Devilman series, Devilman goes on adventures throughout history to fight demons in various places.
Scott: So it's like, go to Rome and fight demons or whatever, right?
Scott: And normally, I guess originally that was published separately, but here they've been sort of combined and mixed together a little bit, the chapters.
Scott: So you're reading and you're going through the story and suddenly it's like Devilman in Rome.
Scott: And it's like, what's going on here?
Scott: And then the next chapter goes back to the plot again.
Scott: And you're like, huh, what's up with that?
Scott: Why was that random chapter in here?
Scott: But I researched, yeah, when they published these two giant volumes, they interspersed Shin Devilman chapters in it.
Scott: So that's a thing.
Scott: And that is making these books fatter, right?
Scott: So the parts of these books, the parts of these books that are just regular.
Scott: Devilman is still most of it, but not all of it, right?
Scott: So the original Devilman manga is not long.
Scott: It's not very long and it contains basically almost, pretty much that whole story you saw in Shin Devilman.
Scott: If you haven't seen Shin Devilman, watch it or read this first.
Scott: I don't think it matters too much.
Scott: It contains the whole Devilman storyline.
Scott: It's such few chapters and that lets you know the pace of Devilman is fast.
Scott: It is a fast story, right?
Scott: It blitzes through, right?
Scott: If there's a fight, it's self-contained.
Scott: in one chapter, Devilman beats some evil demon, boom.
Rym: So it's the literal opposite of One Piece or Kaiji.
Scott: Oh yeah, Devilman just blitzes right through the enemies.
Scott: He's just charging towards the, it's like he's in a rush to get to the end, right?
Scott: And because it's so short, it's constantly referenced, the whole story stays with you the whole time, right?
Scott: You're not like, we're reading One Piece, you'll be like, you know, the events of the beginning of One Piece, right?
Scott: And like sort of start to like not be as relevant when you're a hundred volumes in, right?
Rym: But there's like four pieces now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Throughout the whole story of Devilman, every time they add something new, all the previous things like continue to be carried along right up to the end, right?
Scott: So it's a very well-constructed story and that like every single thing they add is, there's no like wasted, even though it's going fast, nothing is wasted or extraneous or unnecessary, right?
Scott: It's like every step in the plot has meaning and relevance and continues to have meaning and relevance right up to the finale.
Scott: Of course, if you don't know, Devilman is pretty extremely and not safe for life.
Rym: Yeah, it's not like apocalypse zero level, but it's but it's close.
Scott: So on the one hand, visually right, it's not visually disturbing, even though there is lots of gore and violence and sexy, gory violence right?
Scott: It's like I don't get nauseous looking at the illustrations of Devilman.
Scott: They're actually pretty awesome.
Rym: True, because apocalypse zero is gross in that way too.
Scott: Right, but what is being depicted is horrifying often frequently, but I think in a way, you know, obviously it's going to guy, right?
Scott: That's what going to guy's all about.
Scott: But at the same, you know, sex and violence, but at the same time, I think it serves the story because it's about like literal demons, right?
Scott: And it's like, it's hellish, literally hellish.
Scott: And it's like, yeah, that's the kind of shit that's going on in hell, right?
Scott: Crazy.
Rym: Well, you know what, like an eccentric family, like when the, when the one character goes to hell for a little while and hell is hellish.
Rym: Hell sucks.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's, you know, this is a hell on earth scenario here, right?
Scott: So it's I don't think it's in a, it's not inappropriate sex and violence.
Scott: It's just be aware that it's there.
Scott: Don't read it if you don't want to see that.
Scott: Don't have children read Devilman in, I guess, I don't know how old children were supposed to be reading Devilman in Japan.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, that's the thing.
Scott: But yeah, it is, you know, if you can get past the extreme sex and violence and also, you know, sexism and things.
Scott: It's actually a pretty compelling story.
Scott: You can see that same, most of that same compelling story in Devilman Crybaby and I guess this is the original Devilman anime as well, I assume also has the same story.
Scott: I haven't watched that.
Scott: But the only thing that really stood out to me as kind of meh is that there's a storyline towards the end where Devilman goes around the earth collecting the other Devilmen and creating like a fighting force of Devilmen to fight the demons, right?
Scott: Because before then he's all on his own, right?
Scott: And that was, you know, the pace of the thing is so fast.
Scott: That felt sort of like a rushed insert thing.
Scott: It wasn't meaningless or wrong.
Scott: It just felt like it was like the manga was about to end and rather than end it, they came up with this idea of a way to extend it a little bit more, right?
Scott: And then they threw that in there and then they ended it.
Scott: So that was, because it's like they add a bunch of characters that get barely any screen time, right?
Scott: And it's like it's kind of a little bit awkward in there.
Scott: But yeah, if you don't know, I'll just summarize the story pretty quickly.
Scott: There's a kid and his friend and his friend is basically like, "Hey, let me show you something
Scott: cool.".
Rym: Hey kid, want to see a dead body?
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: that's the start of the story, right?
Scott: Hey kid, you want to see this cool thing?
Scott: And then he's possessed by not just demons but like the most ridiculous powerful demon there is, right?
Scott: And he finds out that like, yeah, actually that there's demons on Earth and they're trying to come back and get rid of all the people.
Scott: But because you've been possessed by a demon, you can fight back against them with their own, you know, fight fire with fire.
Rym: You know, that's very similar to the plot of Evangelion.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, I guess in some ways yes, but in some ways no.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, in the sense that I guess if you haven't seen Evangelion, somehow what are the Evas made of?
Scott: Yeah, but sure.
Scott: But yeah, Double Men is a classic of Gonagai, you know, popular, you know, super important manga anime for the history of anime.
Scott: If you've never experienced any Gonagai, this might be the one to experience.
Scott: I'd say like you can go for Mazinger Z to get a Gonagai experience, but you won't understand the sexy violence of Gonagai if you do that, right?
Scott: Not that there's none in Mazinger, but you know, this is really like I think the core of who Gonagai is, right?
Scott: Is this manga.
Scott: So check it out or not.
Scott: And it's only two volumes.
Scott: You can probably get them at the library, return them.
Rym: I just search for it on Amazon and Amazon itself is sold out.
Rym: You can only buy a used Okay.
Scott: A hardcover, I guess.
Rym: Is there a softcover version?
Scott: I have two hardcover volumes.
Rym: I do not believe they are there for sale for like 50 bucks each used on Amazon.
Scott: Oh, can't have mine.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: These are mine.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So that's that's Devilman.
Scott: Is he man or Deville?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at Front Row Crew dot com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce having the nickel, Marty Greenidge is like a dude, Guy Jartobshan, Graham Finch, you are the key to my heart.
Rym: She gave me a kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Rym: Clinton, Walt and J. Banch from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Nicholas Brandow, Chris Midkiff, The Thirst for Hydrated, Gannon Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Finn, Sean Klein, Shervin Von Harl and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their name.
Rym: Yep, we put together a new pipeline for the PAX panel.
Rym: It's looking pretty good.
Rym: This is still more of a pain in the ass than we anticipated, but we're getting better at it.
Rym: So for now, I leave you with something that is very relevant to what we just talked about today.
Rym: [music].