Rym: It's Tuesday June 16th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about our favorite and deadest genre the free space shooter.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Yep, still uh still stuck inside Mm-hmm playing a lot of like little indie games watching a lot of cartoons playing a lot of overwatch Riding a lot of bikes that don't go anywhere writing panels for conventions that aren't happening Building of a backlog of panels for next year.
Scott: I actually cleaned out just about everything on my task list.
Rym: So like how many my hopper is like my hopper.
Rym: literally it's open.
Rym: There are more than a hundred things in that list.
Scott: My list is now all like, you know projects to you know.
Rym: Yeah, it includes projects.
Rym: it has things like get those and like make a pipeline for those anime YouTube videos.
Rym: Like do the next episode?
Scott: I don't have anything left.
Scott: that's like, you know urgent thing you have to do.
Scott: Call the get this bill.
Rym: Oh I cleared my decks this weekend.
Rym: I did I didn't pay my taxes yet because I still got time but I did like everything else.
Scott: Yeah clean the house.
Scott: You know all those things.
Rym: I did a bunch of digital housekeeping like I went into patreon and like all these different services and like Checked and updated settings and linked stuff and like fixed a bunch of configuration options.
Rym: I did.
Rym: I think I was bored at one point during work last on Friday where I actually ended up doing the thing where I looked at All the emails.
Rym: I got an unsubscribe from a bunch of stuff.
Scott: Oh, I just unsubscribe constantly.
Scott: Yeah, I'll get a job at junk mail and the physical mail.
Scott: I unsubscribe from it immediately and put it in their cycle bin.
Rym: They were emails I just started getting mostly because of donations I've made.
Scott: so I get any.
Scott: I I will.
Scott: I will make a donation Immediately get an email response to that and then an unsubscribe on that email.
Scott: Yeah, I'll get.
Rym: It's like look you're getting my money.
Rym: Like trust me emailing me is not going to change.
Rym: I'll get Asian.
Scott: I'll do something like a I'll make a donation or sign a petition or something and get a Text message and then in I will immediately type unsubscribe and send that text.
Scott: 99% at 90% of the time at least you get an auto reply like you've been removed.
Rym: Yep All right.
Rym: So there's actually a crazy amount of gaming news to the point too much too much gaming like we even considered just instead of the topic Just doing a gaming news roundup, but we'll wait on that.
Rym: because while there's
Scott: a lot I think the thing is even though it's a lot of news Most of the news there isn't much to say about other than it's a thing
Rym: or There's too much to say to where that really would be its own show if we actually wanted to talk about it.
Scott: Alright, so let's blitz through a bunch of tiny news is right.
Scott: So Sega is gonna make this tiny game gear.
Rym: I'm alright, so it's funny.
Rym: I'm really excited about that, but I'm really only excited about it because I was one of those kids who had a game gear.
Rym: I'll be I'm like as much as I love my game gear as much as I think that console Gem fire on it.
Rym: Well, we'll see.
Rym: It's the gem fire was not a game gear game.
Scott: Oh, what was the game gear one?
Rym: Uh, well, this is well the good game gear games were Sonic 2 Crystal warriors, that's the one crystal warrior.
Rym: I don't know if that.
Rym: I didn't see the game a list yet They didn't.
Scott: I got confused.
Scott: cuz crystal and Jim, you know, oh no, okay.
Rym: Anyway, there is a game list.
Rym: now when they?
Rym: when I first saw the announcement there was no game list.
Rym: Oh my god, it comes with a mini a little magnifying glass.
Rym: You could use to play it.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: columns is okay shinobi.
Rym: That was actually okay.
Rym: Last Bible special not good Demon Slayer.
Rym: Not good.
Rym: Not good the Shining Force games.
Rym: Uh, Okay, it has like none of the good games, all right, whatever Next news.
Scott: So Pokemon the sword and shield has a DLC, right?
Scott: But there's a different DLC for the sword versus the shield what?
Scott: So and so, you know other Pokemon games in the past they would be like, you know gold silver crystal, right?
Scott: Well, they're not doing that.
Scott: They're basically just gonna give you DLC to sort of right.
Scott: give you new stuff.
Scott: Some people some people with shield accidentally bought the sword DLC and vice versa.
Scott: Nintendo's not refunding you.
Scott: they're just saying tough shit.
Rym: That's actually pretty egregious.
Scott: Yeah, that's all there is to that news like well, yes the people made a mistake.
Rym: That is like.
Rym: that is a very easy mistake for a normal person to make.
Scott: why is it not the same DLC for both?
Scott: Whatever?
Scott: next tiny news.
Scott: So command and conquer the original and red alert.
Scott: They made HD remasters And they're on Steam and they're only like 20 bucks.
Scott: and I thought about it, but I did it.
Rym: I. I also thought about it.
Rym: The problem is command and conquer.
Rym: one is not actually that good and well, I enjoyed it.
Rym: I never actually beat it because I am so bad at RTS.
Rym: is I did not.
Scott: I had command and conquer red alert I also.
Scott: I did not beat that or command and conquer.
Rym: I really only played command and conquer multiplayer.
Rym: I almost never played the single-player campaign at any point.
Scott: I tried I couldn't beat me multiplayer or single-player multiplayer.
Rym: I played with friends of mine who were just as bad.
Rym: either played with people who are Way better than we played literally with null modems or by calling each other like I play.
Scott: I played with the dial-up modem against some kids in high school and I was building my base right and defending me.
Scott: It's no rush and skit.
Scott: No, I was you know, I scouted out a bit, right?
Scott: I sent some infantries here and there right and eventually I got a recon plane and I finally found them and the recon plane Revealed a circle of in the fog and in that circle, I saw some factories and I saw medium tanks so densely packed In their base that there was nowhere for them to move.
Scott: Their base was just as it was buildings and a sheet of tanks just like bristling quivering With right and I was like how the fuck did they do that?
Scott: Clearly I saw get this game because I don't know what the hell they did.
Scott: I've got some tanks.
Rym: I feel like you to this day of that same problem in Civilization because you'll be like feeling pretty good got some science finally got some crossbowmen and then like the bombard rolls over the horizon Yeah, it's like.
Scott: what did you do to do that or not?
Rym: I don't understand how you did it faster than me, but this does remind me of a very brief anecdote from my high school life.
Rym: It was.
Rym: it was just a sublime moment of comedy.
Rym: I was playing command and conquer over with a null modem with a friend of mine in the den.
Rym: Like he was on one computer.
Rym: I was the other computer.
Rym: We had a null modem.
Rym: We were playing command and conquer kind of seriously.
Rym: the computer he was playing on was of course the worst computer like.
Rym: I'm gonna use Your house if I got a Pentium Pro, I'm fucking using it.
Rym: so I'm on that.
Rym: he's on like the 486 Which could play the game?
Rym: Okay, like it worked We're playing but there was a problem with that 486 where every now and then not often but like once a month or so The mouse driver would just go insane And if you move the mouse at all It would just go blew it all over and you were just screwed.
Rym: like there was no way to fix that without rebooting.
Scott: so happened.
Rym: while you're playing we're in the middle of the game and My Competitor suddenly says this is bullshit the mouse broke.
Rym: I can't do anything.
Rym: I can't command.
Rym: That's the whole point of the game.
Rym: And all I said was well, I guess your only choice is to conquer Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's the extent of my anecdote.
Rym: cool story, bro.
Scott: Alright, so next thing.
Scott: steam is having a summer Festival where there's like a zillion free game demos and like.
Scott: actually it's sort of like a little convention on the steam store Website like you'll see like it's like developer talks like on the front page of the steam store moderately excited about this.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So if you want to play demos of any of the the games on steam that are on there and there's a lot of games Like I've never seen before it's sort of like got an indie mega booth kind of feel going on.
Rym: Yeah, but unlike the indie mega booth as much as I love the indie game showcases at conventions, especially like Pax's.
Rym: they're usually so crowded and dense that I end up just Taking pictures of the games that look interesting and trying to play them later.
Scott: yep, Steve.
Rym: and then I forget and I end up never playing any of them.
Scott: and This just tons of tons of free game demos.
Scott: You can play it and see what's.
Scott: to see what's what out there?
Scott: Yeah, pretty good.
Scott: It's happening right now started today.
Rym: Yep, I'm looking at it right now and they're live broadcasting this game called the iron oath, which looks like a hex base turn-based Strategy multi.
Rym: there's something going on here.
Rym: It looks pretty Feeling it.
Scott: maybe maybe They announced the PlayStation 5 which I don't care about at all.
Rym: I care about it from an academic and industry perspective.
Rym: I also care about it because while you and I are the kinds of people who will drop several thousand dollars than a gaming PC and like That is in many cases the correct decision for a lot of reasons PS 5 is basically a gaming PC that a kid can buy for according to this price leak 500 euros.
Scott: It doesn't do.
Scott: I don't think it's really qualifies as gaming PC, right?
Rym: Well, it depends on what kind of games you want.
Scott: Oh, for example, it can't play 1700 1700 games that cost five dollars.
Rym: Oh, we'll get to that news.
Rym: But uh, but it does the thing about the PlayStation 5. the point I would see through all this is landing to the past randomize.
Rym: Since then like the Nintendo switch was one of the it was the only console they came out in recent memory.
Rym: Nintendo tends to do this that actually had something interesting going on with the hardware that made it like notable.
Scott: I mean like you mean like every Nintendo console.
Rym: Yeah, that made it notable beyond just the exclusive games that had.
Rym: but the PlayStation 5 while it is just a console It's basically the last generic big iron Console.
Rym: that isn't just like a gaming PC because I mean a very different direction.
Scott: Someone's buying the X bone and I don't know who it is.
Rym: The next one look like.
Scott: I don't know anyone who has one.
Scott: I just like know it exists But like I don't see like it's like.
Rym: it must be like in their own community somewhere like honestly everyone I know either has if they're a gamer at all like video games.
Scott: They either have a gaming PC and a switch or they have a PlayStation and a switch Yeah, I don't know anyone who has and the newer Xboxes and I think there's another one coming I don't know anything about.
Rym: I want to know who the person is who has an Xbox and a PlayStation.
Scott: I know more people who pay for the Xbox game pass on PC.
Scott: that gets you a whole bunch of Xbox games to play on your right.
Scott: I always like style subscription.
Scott: I always know people who have actual Xboxes the Xbox to eventually evolve.
Rym: I've you could listen to GeekNights from like the early days and I would say this the future of the Xbox was it's just Microsoft wanted to do.
Scott: is they wanted to be like, okay, we'll sell you a box in your house that can play the same PC Games, so if you're not a PC gamer, you can.
Scott: we can still sell our PC games.
Scott: Remember when you know.
Scott: remember in valve develop the game once for Windows and DirectX and we can sell it to people on console Or on a PC.
Scott: that's the original Xbox was about Originally and they just failed to deliver on that and they're getting closer to delivering on it as time goes on.
Rym: Partly blame a Failure of vision in that they did.
Rym: it's like a pendulette with the pigeon.
Rym: They didn't really want it enough.
Rym: They always made compromises.
Rym: They always backed off into.
Rym: well, really it is still just a console.
Rym: You can't just play all your games on your gaming PC.
Scott: I blame just the reality of hardware and that you know, the video game console works because you sell, you know Slower cheaper hardware that is customized and specific and doesn't have all this other PC stuff happening.
Scott: Right.
Scott: and thus you can and developers know that when they're writing the games that they're targeting this one specific hardware platform They know exactly what's on there, right?
Scott: So they can really heavily optimize the engines and things for that platform and thus you get higher.
Scott: You know graphics and performance for less money, right?
Scott: The thing only costs a few hundred dollars.
Scott: Yeah, the game ends up looking like you're playing at a thousand dollar computer.
Scott: Whereas and you're not a boy You're running Windows Right.
Scott: So you've and you got all this other shit on your computer and you got all this other stuff running.
Scott: and it's not You know at the people writing the game have to be prepared for that game to work on any computer anywhere.
Rym: All right, he's trying to play with a steam controller and an old Xbox controller.
Scott: He's got this guy.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: We got to have this game work whether they've got a GTX 770 or a GTX 10,000 Right.
Scott: This guy's monitor Hard or an Nvidia video?
Rym: this guy's this gamers aspect ratio is 15 to 1. what even is that?
Scott: right exactly so You know.
Scott: and so a PC ends up costing more.
Scott: So if you wanted to make a game that worked out a PC and a hypothetical Xbox The Xbox would need to be quite powerful like he's in point.
Rym: Look at the old days the NES.
Rym: a Lot of kids don't know what PC games looked like when the NES was out.
Rym: Go look at what our PC game looked like contemporary to like Super Mario Brothers.
Scott: Well, you can just look at like Commodore 64 games.
Scott: Yeah, right Commodore 64 versions of games are not as good as any as fresh.
Rym: That Megaman port is just amazing.
Scott: only the audio is good.
Rym: But I did find this one article that was sort of funny about the PlayStation 5.
Rym: We'll probably talk more about the PlayStation 5 like as internet news comes out about it.
Rym: I mean, it's notable.
Scott: It's important, but There's talk about the PlayStation 4 4 was less notable.
Rym: But there I saw this great headline when I was looking for the news that literally just says PlayStation 5 Exclusive games are quote more important than ever to.
Scott: Sony says yeah, because there's no other reason to buy it.
Scott: Yep, because I think that's really what it comes down to is that there are people out there I know who are huge fans of the Sony exclusive games like the spider-man game was an example.
Rym: and guess what?
Scott: Game I would like to play but I'm not gonna go out of my way to play.
Rym: but I hate exclusives that I accept the Nintendo exclusives because they're tied to Exclusive hardware.
Rym: that does something different.
Rym: I don't need exclusive generic code that could run on my gaming PC.
Scott: Well, that's the other thing.
Scott: Is that a lot of games, you know, the pattern I'm seeing now?
Scott: Is it a lot of games that were exclusive right in the in the some, you know past time, right?
Scott: No longer.
Scott: Yes exclusives right But you know even games like so for example, right?
Scott: I remember Journey was like a big exclusive when it came out.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: It's on Steam now, right?
Scott: I think it actually.
Scott: it came out on Steam five days ago, right?
Scott: So that game is pretty old several years old.
Scott: I think right, but I'm not in a rush.
Scott: What's my hurry?
Rym: Yeah, I have.
Rym: I own thanks to a news that's coming up in a minute.
Rym: I own more games than I'm ever going to play ever exactly so.
Scott: but yeah journey which was I believe I'm pretty sure it was a PlayStation exclusive game when it came out came out on Steam five days ago.
Scott: It's on sale right now for $11.25.
Scott: Maybe I'll play that now.
Scott: No, it's worth like.
Scott: I Thoroughly enjoyed it sure but like I didn't there was no harm done to me by waiting.
Scott: The game is not any worse now than it was then, you know, what's my rush right?
Scott: that spider-man game?
Scott: That's exclusive to PlayStation or whatever.
Scott: Well five years from five years from now six years from now Maybe I'll play it on PC.
Scott: and what's the difference?
Rym: So I got the stats.
Rym: of the 28 games that were shown as launch or near launch games for the Sony PlayStation 5 nine of them are from Sony Studios and are permanent exclusives.
Rym: 14 are timed exclusives that will at some point specifically be available on PC.
Scott: Yeah So 14, so what are any of those nine games games that I'm gonna like, oh my god, I need to play those.
Scott: I'll pay.
Rym: I assume the spider-man one is but I did not actually five hundred dollars.
Rym: I mean the thing is the Nintendo switch was not five hundred dollars.
Rym: and then it's also true What's worth the price of admission alone?
Scott: Just well, I'm not and this isn't saying it.
Scott: Yes what I'm saying This isn't saying something negative about the spider-man game.
Scott: Yeah, it's saying something about the breath of the wild is like Yeah spider-man game ain't as good as breath though you
Rym: got to divide the cost of a console by the total cost of all the exclusive game or the number of Exclusive games to that console to determine if that console is worth it.
Scott: and Mario maker and p cross and animal crossing and Pokemon Yeah, all the other Mario games and super the Super Mario Odyssey paper Mario this alright.
Scott: So yeah, let's move on to the next tiny news.
Scott: Okay, this is a big news.
Scott: There's a new.
Scott: there's a new paper Mario That's coming Real soon, I think like in a month from now July.
Rym: I did not see that Origami King.
Scott: Yeah, Origami King.
Scott: so this Yeah by all you know paper Mario as a whole taking every all you know is hit or miss, right?
Scott: But when you take all the Mario RPG ish games, right Mario RPG Mario and Luigi paper Mario Super Mario all these different things together for the most part.
Scott: Those are really good games I've enjoyed most of.
Scott: there have been a few stinkers in there.
Rym: I'd say they're like the whole cannon is above average, but that's because there's some really high highs Really low lows.
Scott: Yeah, but thousand-year door was.
Scott: That's the one right.
Scott: if you haven't played thousand-year door for GameCube do that now, there's probably a GeekNights episode about it.
Scott: It has to be.
Scott: but anyway this Origami King by all evidence we have appears to be on The thousand-year door level of paper Mario game.
Scott: that will be confirmed or denied.
Scott: what in a month from now?
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna wait for you to buy all appearances.
Rym: I get a confirmation from you.
Rym: I will buy it.
Scott: I'm pre-ordering that biz.
Scott: I'm all about it.
Scott: So we'll see what's going down.
Scott: All right.
Scott: next tiny news Magic the gathering Wizards of the coast.
Scott: They got a lot of problems going on at Wizards of the coast But they did one good thing, you know better late than never.
Scott: They went through all of the magic the gathering cards from all of history and they found some racist ones and I was like She's surprised by how many of the racist ones that I recognized and or owned.
Scott: Yep, yeah And that's actually somewhat of a credit to them in that if they did in fact find all the racist cards It's really hard to go through every magic card, right?
Scott: You know.
Scott: But if they found if those are truly all the racist ones that should be banned and they by the way They did bad them and remove their images and artwork from their website One of them was particularly egregious because its database ID was also racist.
Scott: Yes, which could horrible been a coincidence which which they did acknowledge the horrible.
Scott: Yeah Coincidence there is zero chance in my mind.
Scott: That was a coincidence But the fact that they acknowledge that means that they know it which is good.
Scott: Yep, right but anyway.
Scott: But yeah They they banned those cards as hard as any Card could be banned.
Scott: and if those indeed are all the ones that should be banned for this reason That I think is actually a credit to them and that it's seems to have been a very long time since they've made a racist Card so they've been doing somewhat of a good job.
Scott: It's not like there were any cards I believe like in the brand new sets that were yeah that needed to be banned.
Scott: Right.
Scott: These are old cards.
Rym: I mean granted my knowledge of the Magic Cannon Peters out around Alliance.
Scott: yes, I'm just saying I was very surprised by how many of those cards I recognized and or owned.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well part of that was cuz like.
Rym: most of my cards are from the oldest sets.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Scott: I mean my cards are from.
Scott: I actually looked up when they put out that magic anniversary timeline.
Scott: It's like wow, I played Magic the Gathering from like 1993 through 1990.
Scott: I played it for a very short time.
Scott: Yep, like two to three years like 1996 it was like a little after 96 But then it was like a two and a half year very brief period where I played Magic the Gathering and bought Magic cards.
Scott: And that was it.
Scott: Yeah, I thought it felt like much longer.
Scott: It felt like that was a major part of my childhood, but it wasn't.
Scott: it was just two and a half years.
Scott: Yeah, so like basically it was middle school.
Rym: So in a very positive news or up on the opposite side of that there was a bundle for racial justice and equality On itch IO if you're not aware everyone everyone knows about this by now.
Rym: gotta make sure everybody.
Rym: I got a. so It raised eight over eight million dollars Mm-hmm, and anyone who bought it got basically an infinite number of indie games, right?
Scott: So it started out with like, you know a smaller number of games But game developers just kept adding their games to it.
Scott: Like yeah put my stuff in the bundle and then itch IO would check out their stuff and say okay that can go in the Bundle.
Scott: in it goes and the bundle got bigger and the money got bigger and it's like you pay five bucks minimum.
Scott: I think it's over now.
Scott: I don't think you can buy it anymore.
Rym: It ended rod it ended today a few.
Scott: I had to like 3 a.m But like everyone bought it already right and anyone listening to this already bought this.
Rym: I hope you did.
Rym: if you didn't yeah Well, we're gonna be over time.
Rym: You're gonna see a lot of people reviewing a lot of really tiny.
Scott: in the ends A lot of the things in the bundle are not necessarily games.
Scott: For example, one thing I saw in there was just sort of a piece of software that let you procedurally build a tower of bricks in 3d and then Throw balls at it at.
Scott: you know, it's like a physics simulation engine and then watch watch the tower collapse.
Scott: It was fun.
Scott: It was fun for like 10 minutes.
Scott: Yeah, it was pretty great.
Scott: And you know, I was pretty happy with that, but it's not exactly necessarily, you know Like a game kind of right, you know, well, you know what it is.
Rym: We've talked about this quite a bit in our panels over the years.
Scott: It's like a software experience.
Rym: This is all entertainment software.
Rym: Yeah, exactly, well you enter there also.
Rym: was it software?
Scott: there's also quite a large number of the items in the bundle are Software to help you.
Scott: there was like I saw like a management like dragon.
Rym: pixel art tile set Here's just a really big are a lot.
Scott: There are a lot of pixel art tile sets.
Scott: So if you are looking to make a game and you don't want to make art You're just want to use like RPG maker and make a game.
Scott: This is like the mother lode because you have now a dragon.
Rym: I'm just scrolling through.
Rym: this is a full 2d game engine.
Rym: Yep Form tiny hot loaded.
Scott: Yeah, so there's all kinds of crazy stuff in there.
Scott: And yeah, if you buy it if you have this you probably don't need to buy any video games whatsoever for several years.
Rym: Yeah at this point.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: How many total games are it?
Rym: So there are 1391 things in this.
Rym: if I add that to my steam library, I own like 4,000 things.
Rym: Yep, you know my steam library is terrifying.
Rym: not I did not buy all those games.
Rym: It's terrifying for other reasons.
Rym: So, uh in some other big news.
Rym: as you suspected a lot of conventions are not happening and PAX has actually announced their plan.
Rym: they have Deferred pegs Australia to 2021 or to 2020.
Rym: Yeah 2021.
Scott: So it's hard to know when he packs us trip, so they're not gonna have two PAX Australia's in 2021.
Scott: They're just gonna cancel 2020 and have yeah 21.
Rym: obviously PAX West clearly is not gonna happen and instead there is going to be packs online.
Rym: Now the cool thing is they're doing it in an interesting way.
Rym: There's not a lot of details yet.
Rym: This is like breaking news.
Rym: now It's going to be 24/9 meaning.
Rym: It's going to be nine days 24/7.
Rym: well 24/9 from September 12th through September 20th And they have promised that there will be content rolling at all hours of the day during this experience.
Scott: Right, so they're gonna get you know.
Rym: There's gonna be live stream panels Pre-recorded panels eSports stuff.
Rym: They're trying to figure out what to do with an expo haul.
Rym: There's gonna be like panel submissions are open.
Rym: They're trying to set up a community thing tournament aggregation systems.
Rym: There's a lot of biz and we just have to wait for the details because we don't know any more than you do at this point.
Scott: Yeah, what I do know however is that If you are someone like me who buys packs t-shirts, right?
Scott: They obviously you know because the way the world works the they design all the packs merch each year and put in orders in advance.
Scott: So the PAX West and awesome merch was already ordered And probably in a warehouse somewhere and now they have to sell that off But they're not gonna have a packs to sell it at.
Scott: so they are in the penny arcade shop website.
Scott: They are selling all the PAX West exclusive merch.
Rym: They call it like the penny arcade garage sale.
Scott: Yeah, all that.
Scott: Well, no, that was it.
Scott: They were having a general sale on penny arcade Store in you know, just in general like like for the past week or so and it that now it seems suspicious.
Scott: Maybe they were trying to clear up warehouse space for the pack stuff.
Rym: No, that could make sense.
Scott: Maybe I'm just guessing but yet all PAX West stuff is pre.
Scott: all the pracs West Merch and packs Explorer merch that usually is packs exclusive is pre-order on the penny arcade shop and the packs oss merch is coming a week from now and Presumably there will be packs online merch that they're gonna make out of nothing.
Rym: I hope they do because packs online every packs has a color packs online has got the coveted green spot.
Scott: It's sort of.
Rym: it's too light.
Rym: It's too close to the PAX dev color to be honest.
Rym: and there will I expect like we'll see what happens.
Rym: They should have gone.
Scott: see I don't know why they don't go with green like freakin, you know, Koopa shell green That's the green.
Scott: I'm talking about.
Rym: I like a good 2380 23.
Rym: Yeah, anyway But we'll see.
Scott: you are someone who's never accept our panels.
Rym: We're gonna do stuff at this packs.
Rym: I'm breaking to take days off work and just like packs it up depending on exactly how this goes.
Scott: We'll see how it goes.
Rym: Where else am I gonna go?
Rym: Like I those vacation days are already earmarked for paxes.
Scott: I'm having real trouble finding ways to use the vacation days.
Scott: Let me tell you, you know staying home and doing a digital packs might be you might end up being the only way.
Rym: Yep, and You we can promise if our panels or our content is at this packs online.
Rym: We will have the highest quality and fidelity.
Scott: We'll probably go to Scott anyone out there and who actually listens to the show all three of you.
Scott: If You want to Do an online convention, right?
Scott: Because we could do that very easily.
Scott: Yeah, right we could stay home use dirt in vacation days.
Scott: all of us agree to do this during the online packs and basically create on our discord server like a Unofficial packs room.
Rym: It's like the GeekNights room during packs.
Rym: It's like it's like the place in tabletop.
Scott: We may or may not be officially associated with packs, but we can all agree that during the online packs we all take days off all go to the discord all day and Play.
Scott: we could play RPGs, right?
Scott: We got other kinds of games.
Scott: You just hang out.
Scott: we could.
Scott: we could do a panels, right?
Scott: We could do Q&A's with.
Rym: we could attend other panels and make fun of them.
Scott: Yeah You out there listening can submit panels to do on our discord for us and we'll watch your panel, right?
Rym: This reeks of an ancient past where we basically stole a panel room from ConnectiCon before we took over, right?
Scott: But this is just virtual.
Scott: we're basically.
Scott: we're basically Manufacturing up.
Scott: We're basically what we're doing is is a packs if this was a physical world, right?
Rym: We found a room impacts and we put a sign up outside of it.
Rym: No one stopped us.
Scott: No, no packs is going on in the convention center.
Scott: We're out in the parking lot with it with us with a shipping container and we paint GeekNights on the side.
Scott: We start doing stuff in the shipping.
Rym: we're like those billboard trucks just driving around Seattle all day.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: Yeah, so stay tuned on the details But we're definitely.
Rym: I got nothing else to spend my vacation days on.
Scott: if you're interested come to the disc the GeekNights discord now and You know make some stuff happen.
Rym: Yep, which I will post an invite link on this episode Once I post it just to get more people in there.
Scott: Yep All right, let's have any other.
Scott: gaming news is real quick.
Rym: last two news is dwarf fortress got graphics.
Rym: now It's on steam like it's.
Scott: yeah, you'll be able to get it on steam soon.
Scott: It's right now only like preview on but don't be sure steam page is up.
Scott: It's still dwarf fortress.
Scott: They got an official Graphical update to it.
Scott: So it should be much easier to play now, but and it's gonna be on steam.
Rym: But yeah for and last and least but also not least there is a fantastic Game that's been on steam for a while and then eventually made it to the switch Which I still think is the best form factor for it.
Rym: It is now on iOS.
Rym: You can play it on your tablets and your iPhone.
Scott: I've been wait been waiting so long.
Scott: Slay the slayer.
Scott: slay the spire.
Scott: iOS.
Scott: the iPad one is the best one.
Rym: This game is such a good fucking game.
Rym: I can I can now you enough.
Scott: I can play slay the spire on my iPhone or iPad.
Scott: That means when if I ever go back to work I can live the dream and play slay the spire on the toilet at work.
Rym: Yep I don't do that with your ascension while I'm pooping but I could beat one floor while I'm can't do that with your switch.
Rym: I mean I could.
Scott: and now I can play the slay the spire on the subway to work without having to bring a switch to Work.
Rym: slay the spire.
Rym: It's just we've.
Rym: I think we reviewed it at one point in the past.
Rym: this game So good single-player is the game generated deck builder slay the spire like.
Rym: that's the game.
Scott: It's me, you know, it's made by people from the netrunner community back in the day all you know five years ago.
Rym: Yeah, but if I had to sell you on it The one thing I would say is that you know how in a deck building game like Dominion Like a balance problem might ruin your game like you have to worry about that.
Rym: It doesn't matter in a single-player game.
Rym: So this is a game where you might just figure out an infinite combo.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: The game is totally single-player single-player.
Scott: Who cares?
Rym: Yeah, if you get over power, who are you cheating?
Scott: the spire?
Scott: Oh The spire has been cheated.
Rym: I should find that penny arcade and link to it.
Scott: I've I've I've found it many.
Scott: it was it was actually not the comic.
Scott: it was it was the text.
Rym: Yes It was the text.
Rym: I remember we figured that out.
Rym: He wanted to put it in a panel.
Scott: Yeah, Tycho was talking about Jerry.
Scott: Tycho was talking about people cheating at Diablo and he's like.
Rym: who's like cheated?
Scott: He's right.
Scott: who is right?
Scott: It's like who is the cheated party the devil?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: It's like you can't cheat a job.
Scott: Okay, it's not like you're cheating your friend Satan the devil Things of the day.
Rym: This is so weird that I had to link to it.
Rym: I did not know this was the thing.
Rym: I'd never encountered this in my life.
Rym: So the first thing I saw about this was a channel I follow.
Rym: Adam Neely like good music stuff but it talked about testing and potentially debunking the 432 Hertz frequencies and temperaments and all I could think was what what like what like that?
Rym: I know music I know audio.
Rym: that didn't make any sense to me and I don't know what you just said and this is a person Who knows about music.
Rym: so I was confused enough to where I watch this video.
Rym: Apparently, I don't know when this started there is some Ridiculous wackadoodle woo-woo out there of people who don't know anything about anything Believing that normal music is based on 440 Hertz which will damage your brain in some way.
Rym: but 432 Hertz that's the magic node.
Rym: That'll make you smarter and better and cure your cancer.
Rym: Okay, like.
Scott: it's not only that I could play those two notes Out of like a speaker, right?
Scott: I just make a wav file.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: No, this is so many for you.
Scott: It's only 8 Hertz apart, there was no way you could tell the difference in design.
Rym: so the argument is not that.
Rym: the argument is that we tune the key of a to 440 Hertz because that's the standard.
Rym: but if you tune a down to 432 and play your music there It'll harmonize with the universe and do all this magic nonsense.
Scott: You would never be able to tell.
Rym: so apparently There's all these scam apps that will just like detune MP3s.
Rym: You're playing on your phone.
Scott: Is the app?
Scott: you pay me money and I put an icon on your phone and it does nothing.
Rym: The icon actually just makes all your detunes your music.
Scott: It actually works.
Scott: Well, yeah It just doesn't just do nothing.
Rym: Some of them probably do nothing but some of them definitely bring.
Rym: they just detune they bring your music lower Which that's a trivial.
Scott: if I was if I was gonna scam Conspiracy nuts.
Scott: I would just make an app that does nothing.
Rym: Yep But this video is great because it it doesn't worry about the wackadoodle nonsense so much But it debunks how even if the wackadoodle nonsense were true It still doesn't actually work like the concept does not work.
Rym: Even if all the magic nonsense were somehow real Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's just a really good debunking that I enjoyed quite a bit.
Rym: I'd encourage you to not in any way try to look up the actual 432 Hertz stuff because it is so crazy.
Rym: I cannot stress how crazy it is.
Scott: So what are you guys honey?
Scott: Crazy?
Scott: It's not a crazier than flat earth It's more in-depth than flat earth anyway, so NARS go can bet.
Scott: there is a convention called narrow scope and Nara scope is a convention about narrative games, right?
Scott: You know everything from like a text adventure to a game with a bunch of cutscenes, you know story games But video story games primarily, right?
Scott: And that's pretty cool.
Scott: It's a cool convention.
Scott: It's been going on for quite a few years.
Scott: I approve of it Although I'm not deep enough into that scene to attend it or speak at it.
Scott: Definitely or I am not a Writer of any kind, right?
Scott: And obviously narrow scope like all conventions had to go online this year and that was between June.
Scott: It was like late May early June.
Scott: Yeah, they were doing all sorts of streams and they put all their stuff on YouTube and whatnot and the keynote speaker of narrow scope 2020 happened to be someone I'm a big fan of Zalavir Nelson who is doing the game.
Scott: I pretty sure I previously mentioned on GeekNights at least one or two times An airport for aliens currently run by dogs.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah As well as many other things He has worked on And his keynote.
Scott: I went and watched it, right?
Scott: It's like you look at the quality of this keynote, right?
Scott: and it's basically you're looking at 16 by 9 box and on the bottom of it is a narrow scope logo and Inside that is a 4 by 3 box or 6 maybe a 16. that's 16 by 10 It doesn't matter.
Scott: and in that box You're looking at a screen capture of what appears to be like a Google Hangout or a zoom or something Or a sky.
Scott: it might be a Skype actually, I can't tell.
Scott: it doesn't matter.
Scott: and on the left side is like the slide He's showing from his computer and on the right side is a tiny picture of him.
Scott: Some webcam pointed at his face, right and it's like this it looks like a ramshackle kind of keynote, right?
Scott: the keynote he gave for narrow scope 2020 is easily Five times as good as any packs keynote ever He's like does not even close, right?
Scott: so if you're someone who cares about narrative games, right video games with storytelling going on or or Tabletop RPGs also right with you know storytelling going out.
Scott: Yeah Or you just want to hear awesome game keynotes or you're interested in the work of the amazing Zalavir who is whose output is insane And pretty much gonna play everything he's ever made including all the ones I missed.
Scott: You need to watch this keynote, even though it's 90 minutes.
Scott: you could not Find a better way.
Scott: It would be hard to find a better way to spend 90 minutes easily.
Scott: I'm much better use of your time to listen to a GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah, right like why even listen to a GeekNights?
Scott: Just go watch this instead.
Scott: Alright, so met a moment.
Rym: We're not really reading right now.
Rym: We're not really doing a lot except like clearing our task lists and playing video games and trying to make that see book club.
Scott: book is still Theoretically the tale of Genji.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Not Hanzo.
Scott: Yeah, there was a Way way back when I decided to make this, you know the ill-fated time, but I decided to make this the book club selection Part of the influence, you know, I was already thinking about making it the book club selection.
Scott: I think I told the story before but I'll repeat it.
Scott: Anyway, I was thinking about making it the book club.
Scott: it was like on my mind and then I found out that the Met had a whole exhibit about it and on the final day I found out about the exhibit and I went over there on the final day of the exhibit to go see the exhibit.
Scott: And you know how museum exhibits always have like a book that they try to sell you.
Scott: That's like a big expensive coffee table book full of pictures and descriptions of everything in there.
Scott: right like really in-depth Sort of like letting you take the exhibit home with you in paper form as much as possible for a large amount of money To make profits for the museum.
Scott: and you know how museums right now are closed and no one's there.
Scott: So it just so happens that the Met is selling that book.
Scott: Normally you would have to like go to the Met gift shop to get.
Scott: you could just buy that book online from that exhibit Because that exhibit is long gone.
Scott: I went there on the final day.
Scott: But yeah, you can.
Scott: you can relive that exhibit in a book form coffee table book form Because they're selling the book now for probably I imagine a very large price at least 50 bucks, right?
Scott: But go to the Mets website.
Scott: I'm sure you'll find it there somewhere.
Scott: I don't have a link.
Scott: I just saw a tweet saying that they're selling the book.
Rym: But we will read this book once the world opens up again and we have opportunities to read.
Rym: but Honestly, both of us are busier now than we are like when the world is open.
Scott: So I've just I've just become unbusy.
Rym: No Unbusy enough to read.
Rym: or are you gonna get into the deeper hopper?
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: We got projects going we got things things.
Rym: We're not gonna talk about lest we shit-talk them.
Scott: That's right Yeah.
Rym: So all that stuff find us on the internet.
Rym: join our discord hang out with us.
Rym: check out the YouTube channel.
Rym: The last thing I'll say is that uh, you know, we have that GeekNights presents YouTube playlist.
Rym: That's basically all our board game reviews without the rest of the GeekNights episode.
Rym: So you can just hear like a review of a board game without having to listen to like.
Rym: I was talk about our bikes for 20 Minutes, so those have been moderately popular and I think it's a good way to like get the reviews out without the weird Context of what we're rimming Scott like on about in 2006.
Rym: I just want to find out what tigers new freddy's is a good game.
Rym: So I started doing the same thing for every anime review we've ever done.
Rym: I made a pipeline.
Rym: I Put together like 10 of these videos.
Rym: They're all uploaded.
Rym: They're gonna trickle out like every few days for the foreseeable future.
Rym: and all I want to say is that looking back at the archive we reviewed a lot of Anime.
Rym: good lord.
Rym: I think GeekNights Wednesdays by themselves are the longest-running anime podcast on earth.
Rym: terms of number of episodes good God No, maybe who knows.
Rym: so uh Well, I got to figure out a pipeline to deal with those old ones where the audio quality is not so great because they're good Reviews.
Rym: just we were young.
Rym: it was 2005.
Rym: So are you actually?
Scott: are you actually listening to those to make sure we don't say anything stupid before you upload them to YouTube?
Rym: I do because they're not that long and I also add I put images in them like from the shows.
Rym: If we say something stupid, it's buried somewhere in there.
Rym: Okay, most of the stupid things we would say are probably in the news or in the opening bits.
Scott: So I just want to do a say.
Scott: we're still in the meta moment here I had.
Scott: I was told I was listening to a sports podcast and they talked about another sports podcast And the fit and the other sports podcast they were talking about Was a long-running one and that long-running one They.
Scott: what they did on their anniversary is they played their very first episode.
Rym: Oh, we got a living at first and they talked and Commentaried.
Scott: it was like it was like a podcast on a podcast.
Scott: I don't know how we could do that because I thought I did that for all the beta episodes of GeekNights.
Scott: They're all talking on top of ourselves might be impossible to hear.
Rym: Uh, there's oh, I know how I would do it by Consider some auto ducking.
Rym: there's a way to make that work like it could have.
Scott: yeah I don't know if we actually want to do that.
Rym: I'm just saying someone else interested in doing it.
Rym: But we're not doing that with this live stream.
Rym: that has to be in person or I'm not even gonna try to make that work.
Scott: Yeah, I guess we could like pause ourselves and talk and then unpause.
Rym: I got I could.
Rym: I can envision a pipeline where that would work.
Rym: when I did that for all our beta episodes Which is all they're all free.
Rym: like you can listen to this crap on the patreon I'd recorded my own like half-hour commentary on each one of those episodes of like the fuck were we on about?
Scott: I think the other thing is, you know It's like we might want to do it where we only do commentary the first few minutes and not the whole right.
Scott: But I don't know Park style.
Scott: Yeah But we had to still understand the whole episode before we can once once we can get together in the studio again.
Rym: That's something I would like to try to do because I can make the pipeline work.
Rym: That is not hard to do.
Scott: It's so meta though, someone already has to care about getting nice to care about that.
Rym: There's people out there not not not a fan, but it could be.
Rym: we could do it for ourselves.
Rym: It could just be transformative and illustrative to us anyway.
Scott: So let's move to the main bit.
Rym: finally something that died Something that one of my favorite games ever in the history of gaming of all these games We talked about all these board games that we love all these video games.
Rym: breath of the wild.
Rym: Tie fighter on the PC from 1994 Remains one of my like top five video games I've ever played.
Scott: I do not play it as much but there is no.
Rym: I like perfect tie fighter.
Scott: Tie fighter is an amazing game and x-wing ain't bad and x-wing first.
Scott: tie fighter ain't bad.
Rym: X-wing tie fighter was bad.
Rym: x-wing Had all right everything that x-wing verse tie fighter had but it worked.
Rym: it didn't crash and the single-player was good like really good.
Rym: Yeah, just not as good as tie fighter.
Scott: the point is there was a series of Star Wars free space shooter games in the DOS Windows 95 era.
Scott: That were some of the best games because what nerd fantasy is greater than fly x-wing?
Scott: shoot yep But these games fly tie fighter.
Rym: the thing about these games the free space shooters in general like that genre of gaming.
Rym: There really were two kinds.
Rym: one kind was Really facile free space shooters that were kind of railroady or minimal or like they weren't that good.
Scott: and then game thing That's to say our rail shooter isn't really the same job true cuz they're near not in free space.
Rym: Even if you can look around in free space you can't move around.
Scott: You know control you have to be in the free space shooter genre.
Scott: it has to be right.
Scott: a first-person camera now Be you're in space right which means you know you're not.
Scott: you're not flying a plane in the air Right which always has to be going forward to maintain lift.
Scott: right you're in outer space.
Scott: So this there might be gravity pulling you somewhere, but you could nominally move in all directions.
Scott: Right you can sit still you could rotate in place.
Scott: You could do barrel roll in place.
Scott: You could you know Flip over backwards right you could do all sorts of ridiculous maneuvers.
Scott: and the final thing it needs is That the weaponry because you're shooting right is.
Scott: the weaponry in the game Cannot be like in counter-strike where you click on someone right.
Scott: it has to be like tribes where it's like a spin fuser that moves And you need to get your enemy to hit it right.
Scott: you need to lead them or right in some way.
Scott: You know the bullets aren't just like instant.
Scott: You know hit scan right.
Scott: did I click on them?
Scott: they get hit.
Rym: no That's not how it works Yeah, but has to almost simulate like dogfighting like planes, but without the constraints of gravity or the ground necessarily.
Rym: Mm-hmm though these are very similar to like plane simulators in a lot of ways like very similar mechanics very similar play style depending depending on the game.
Rym: because of course like if Descent counts descent is a very different experience from.
Rym: so the difference.
Scott: so the thing with descent.
Scott: right.
Scott: well There's descent and descent free space or so descent free space is clearly just free space shooter.
Scott: Yeah, right Descent one two and three are Different in that there's not a lot of gravity going on.
Rym: I mean they're free space.
Scott: FPS is almost right Is it?
Scott: is that you're?
Scott: you're also.
Scott: I actually played descent.
Scott: the most of any free space kind of game There's.
Scott: there's no gravity really to speak of.
Scott: the Weapons are still just like I said.
Scott: you know they you have to sort of you know make sure they hit the enemy.
Scott: They're not hit scan or anything.
Scott: you can move in all directions But there's not really a ton of like momentum in descent.
Scott: right?
Scott: you don't like.
Scott: you won't drift in space really right?
Scott: you like You'll stop.
Rym: well Tyler you didn't really drift either.
Rym: you had you.
Rym: if you turn the engines on you would move forward.
Rym: you turn them off.
Rym: you just Sat there.
Rym: there was no drifting.
Scott: Yeah, but the other thing in descent is that you were indoors most of the time.
Scott: Yeah, right There was some descent.
Scott: three had some outdoor action, but it was mostly indoors.
Scott: so you were navigating these mines.
Scott: Right so you're free.
Scott: You're like.
Scott: it's like it's a man.
Scott: It's sort of like in Star Wars when you know they you take your x-wing and you go into the Death Star.
Scott: All right, you're in it.
Scott: That's suddenly descent.
Scott: right you're no longer out in space.
Scott: You're confined by these walls.
Scott: You're trying to not hit and you would get damaged if sometimes if you smashed into the walls really hard, so But I guess descent is good stuff like.
Rym: I don't want to try to get into a deep analysis of the genre Right now partly because we went super long and everything else and we could talk about this for and I haven't played That much of the genre right.
Scott: I've played like you know the seminal games free space descent TIE fighter Wing commander.
Scott: I think counts.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it was good and count you know.
Rym: But I guess what I would want to focus on is what did we like about these games like?
Rym: what were the nuggets that these?
Scott: Games had that we're not really getting from current genre games or just gaming in general because I think Obviously the number one thing about these games is like compared to other Genres is that you really get that role-playing true simulation fantasy thing going on.
Rym: Yeah Like that feeling of I'm gonna get into a mech and hit a bunch of buttons and control everything.
Scott: Right when you play counter-strike you do not feel like you are a terrorists or a counter-terror.
Rym: Yep, I feel like I'm really good at that Mario fly swatting.
Scott: I'm just trying to win at counter-strike.
Scott: When I play tribes I don't even feel like I'm some tribe member whatever they are.
Scott: I'm a guy in my in my room trying to win it.
Rym: try these games Honestly like for me as much as I am all about competitive gaming and how I do really want competitive free-space shooters.
Rym: What I liked about these games was actually primarily the single-player experience.
Rym: It was your soldier in this tie fighter.
Rym: There's like intrigues.
Rym: you get.
Rym: mission briefings like.
Rym: that was what really sold it to me the fact that I'd have to sit through a mission Briefing where some dude is literally like on a screen.
Rym: like go to this waypoint here.
Rym: We suspect that there's enemies here.
Rym: There's a transport here.
Rym: You've got it like they give you this like human language Explanation of what the mission is.
Rym: but then you get into the mission, and you've got to just deal with it.
Rym: I hope you remembered what he said.
Rym: I hope you paid attention.
Rym: Yep Oh wait the rebels aren't where the guy said they were gonna be.
Rym: what the fuck do I do?
Rym: now?
Scott: the other genre that has That same sort of.
Scott: you know Immersion thing is like mech warrior time right, but the difference is that you know with something like mech warrior Right.
Scott: first of all the role-playing is lessened by the lack of Star Wars and the lack of characters Quite often because wing commander also had a very rich like story.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: But also you know when being in a battle mech right is is slow and pondering right.
Rym: you would spend a lot of time walking Right yeah, and you'd also spend a lot of time in the game like when you weren't fighting Customizing your mech and fucking around with your mech and like you're doing lots of lot.
Scott: There's lots of long-range weaponry.
Rym: Yeah, right, but you can level up in mech warrior in tie fighter.
Rym: You can't level up.
Scott: She's already good depends on which game.
Scott: It is no none of the time But the the dogfight the the of a mech is basically two mechs circles slowly circling around each other.
Scott: Maybe one jumps.
Scott: yeah right with free space shooters You the skill cap is insanely high.
Rym: like you know in Star Wars when someone is like Oh They're on my tail and like you've got to shake them you're living that Reality and only your personal skill with that joystick is gonna get you out right.
Scott: and it's like the speeds that you could reach.
Scott: They let you reach are like ridiculous.
Scott: right you can go really fast.
Rym: Oh, you know hard it was to like shoot down a transport if I was in like a Thai interceptor right?
Scott: But it's like can you can you go that fat if you step on the throttle of your type fighter?
Scott: Right and then try to fight while going at full speed.
Scott: It's like can you maintain aim on the enemy?
Scott: Can you not just crash into that space?
Scott: Can you not just you know fly out of control?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: can you keep your stuff together right?
Scott: it's like and and and not only that but also Manage all your stuff right it's like your they've.
Scott: you know it's almost.
Scott: It's not the level of like Microsoft flight simulator where you're simulating every aspect of reality But you're like the fun and interesting parts, right?
Scott: It's like you can manage your shields put energy to the rear shield to the front shield take away energy from the shields entirely And just go faster or start pumping shield energy like directly into your lasers that they charge up faster.
Scott: Right you know it's like you you can.
Scott: there's all these things you can manage in your ship And you know oh stuff on my ship got damaged, I guess I'm going slower now, right All kinds of stuff yeah
Rym: and I particularly appreciated how like in the fighting and the way like battles would break down in these kinds of games a Narrative could emerge from the mechanics of the game and from the world very directly very similarly to like very few games do that well But this
Scott: a lot like a dwarf fortress because this when you get your simulation level high enough And it's accounting for enough details.
Scott: There's an air is a natural narrative emergence that comes out, right?
Scott: So it's like you the more details you put in the more story gets told yep and the game will reach more rich it becomes how you achieve those goals.
Rym: like if I Solve the problem where like there's the traitor on the ship if I blow that ship up that works.
Rym: if I Get the Star Destroyer to come over and blow it up that also works.
Rym: if I disable it and then call the stormtroopers to Come and like board the ship well, maybe now a new plot gets unlocked because now we captured this dude alive yep.
Scott: So that's just high fighter, but yeah, that's just same right.
Scott: so the same things apply though to most free space shooters Right is the?
Scott: you know that you still have those right.
Scott: you have to control this ship right.
Scott: there's usually a mission-based game.
Scott: You know the narrative emergence is still there because crazy things happen on the mission no matter how good or bad the.
Scott: the game is Right and the genre as a whole seemed to have died out right.
Scott: and the reason it died out At least that I can say.
Rym: Factors.
Scott: there's a lot of factors but the games are hard to make expensive to make.
Scott: yeah right and as Games got more 3d right and technology advanced right?
Scott: It's like that increased the cost of making this particular type of game a lot.
Rym: But also these games require two things that are difficult for gamers.
Rym: one they require Physical peripherals that are not just commonly available.
Rym: like in the era when tie fighter came out Almost everyone even non gamers had a joystick connected to their PC.
Rym: like joysticks were kind of a semi standard Thing that people would just have and like every computer store just had a joystick section.
Scott: right joysticks are now Specialized equipment because I mean it's even even arcade.
Scott: joysticks are a specialized equipment for fighting game.
Scott: play out right.
Scott: It's like you know any kind of stick based control Which was like the default control on the Atari 2200 was just eliminated when the NES came out right from consoles.
Rym: I got my parents like we bought.
Rym: we spent $70 in like 1980s dollars on a flight stick pro just to play Microsoft flight simulator and tie fighter because the joystick wasn't cutting it.
Scott: yeah I feel like on PCs the joystick sort of died when like around the time USB came around.
Scott: Right because suddenly.
Scott: It's like you got a new computer.
Scott: It's like did.
Scott: there weren't new games to demand the joystick The old games I could like old joysticks.
Scott: We needed a game port.
Scott: new computers didn't have the game port.
Rym: Yeah, there weren't peripherals to make that work.
Rym: there weren't like adapters that work.
Rym: and even if there were USB joysticks I got a cheapo USB joystick.
Rym: I could not get it to work with my like bootleg emulated in a virtual machine tie fighter.
Scott: Yep You know there were also like you know specific things right in terms of like.
Scott: You know the it's like.
Scott: okay, we're even though someone might have wanted to continue the genre.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well Star Wars specifically wasn't in it right wing commander But like these John release the properties sort of individually fell out of game making.
Rym: yeah, but there's something else.
Rym: There's another factor.
Rym: even if the hardware were there I feel like there's a bigger problem that these games if the kinds of games the way we enjoyed them.
Rym: They require the player to learn skills to get better.
Rym: And there's almost nothing in these games to help you get to help you get better Except by getting better.
Rym: like.
Rym: there's no leveling up your biz.
Rym: you have to just Literally learn the skill of dogfight in this complex machine and learn the nuances of this machine, right?
Scott: To make the game more accessible to more people right or to make it playable with a gamepad or lesser controls Right in any sort of reasonable way.
Scott: you have to dumb the game down to the point at which it's no longer the same Genre right.
Scott: you look at like rogue squadron on like the n64.
Scott: I played those games.
Scott: They were okay, but like yeah It's like it's a good game, but it's not even this.
Scott: it's not even the same genre.
Scott: It's not as that itch.
Scott: There's an x-wing.
Scott: it's shooting things, but it's really just a rail shooter.
Scott: It's Star Fox right It's not a free space shooter, and it's like.
Scott: you know if you have an FPS You can get people.
Scott: FPS's aren't the easiest, but you can get people up into FPS.
Scott: You can play one with a gamepad with two sticks on it, right?
Scott: It's like you can get someone with a tutorial level to learn to control an FPS.
Scott: It's like not.
Scott: It's like it's not a mountain.
Scott: It's a hill.
Scott: right.
Scott: yeah, if you drop someone in tie fighter level one No enemies nothing to crash into right just like like fly from point a to point B. That's all you ask them to do.
Scott: It's like It's not easy like.
Rym: as a kid you know how I learned to play tie fighter.
Rym: it came with this long book and I read the book and then I had the Book open while I was futzing around in the game.
Rym: And now there have been games that have tried to do this over over time.
Rym: some of them succeeded a little bit But like the genre is still relatively morbid.
Scott: Yeah So that's how that is.
Scott: so now the big news is that EA is making what's the name of this game?
Rym: Oh, yeah, the a Star Wars something.
Rym: Yeah, find it again.
Scott: Supposedly we're gonna find out the truth the full truth in a few days.
Scott: But the current truth?
Rym: Star Wars squadrons.
Rym: Right so it less light art of Starfighter combat in immersive piloting experience with Star Wars squadrons and scrolling through this thing It looks like it might be exactly what I want.
Scott: right the information They have released so far is all there.
Rym: It's like they're saying all the right like.
Rym: look at this for the first screenshot.
Rym: playing your skirmish in the briefing room.
Scott: Right everything that they have revealed so far is like yes.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes, right first person Can modify your ship divert power between its systems, right?
Scott: There's supposedly multiplayer and single-player.
Rym: first five dogfights.
Scott: Yes, there's gonna be all kinds of story and a wings.
Scott: be wings x-wings y-wings Thai fighters.
Scott: I advance support bombers reality.
Rym: This is a killer app for virtual reality You know, they confirm that it supports VR and hotels.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta get that hot ass hot ass Right.
Scott: It's like everything they've said so far.
Scott: It's like EA is the worst, but it's like almost the worst.
Scott: But it's like everything they've said.
Rym: I trust everything about this website except the fact that it's EA.
Scott: yeah pretty much Seems like wow, they are really bringing it back aren't they?
Scott: it's gonna be.
Scott: this is gonna be it, right?
Scott: But this close what it might even be worth buying some VR.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Well, well,
Rym: you can try the VR in my place first because my dream has been to play a game like tie fighter with a VR helmet on But just like holding my joy like having a joystick Like a hot ass in front of me
Scott: I couldn't I couldn't get rimmed to play netrunner.
Scott: He couldn't get me to play overwatch, but maybe this will be our game We can play.
Scott: We'll make a little make eat.
Scott: We'll make eat night squadron.
Rym: So stay tuned Like we're gonna get it.
Rym: we're gonna get on this and see what the deal is.
Rym: uh If this game is good It actually closes one of the longest open chapters in GeekNights history because in ancient ancient times like so long ago We didn't even video this panel and we only ran it once at PAX West once It was called egregiously unrealized potential and we just listed all the Obvious genres and obvious games that should be remade.
Rym: there's.
Rym: no one was remaking and we couldn't understand why and how.
Rym: there's just a pile of money waiting for someone to pick up and Literally every game we talked about in that panel Except tie fighter s games had been remade basically exactly as we described.
Rym: This is the last one.
Scott: the one thing that we poke about Wasn't ever fully fulfilled.
Rym: drew Pokemon go Edged into that territory.
Scott: It's like there's a bunch of things combined that get really close.
Scott: There's like MMOs that are basically Pokemon clones.
Scott: Yeah, Pokemon itself got closer to em, but there is not Pokemon MMO.
Rym: Yeah, there is not the dream Pokemon MMO But otherwise if this game comes out and is good we've gotten pretty much everything we wanted out of that panel.
Scott: Yeah, so Yeah, free space shooters, you know, there's.
Scott: there are some newer ones out there.
Rym: I've tried a bunch of them.
Rym: They they don't like.
Rym: I don't want to get into like specifics of a bunch of the ones I played but they all failed me And like odd ways or they're not satisfying or some of them try to be too accurate with the physics Which takes away a lot of the fun.
Scott: It's like you need to leave some of the arcade gameplay in there, right?
Scott: Yeah, it can't just be like yeah true hard science real Have shit.
Rym: for momentum you could just stop on a dime, right?
Scott: It's too hard to do that It's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's already hard enough as it is.
Scott: It's like you don't wanna make it harder Yep, or something.
Rym: have the free space elements But they're mostly either fetch quest type games or like their narrative games.
Rym: But the narrative is not tied to what you're doing in the spaceship so much as like where you're going in the spaceship Right or simply a lot of the games.
Scott: It's just like they're not a lot of people playing them So you can't get your multiplayer action on right.
Scott: I've seen some of them that the mistake They make is like the the space that you're playing.
Scott: it is too big and kind of empty And there's a lot of like quiet flying around as opposed to you know even you watch a Star Wars movie And it's like yeah, they're out in space this infinite space that you could fly around in.
Scott: But really the battle is contained right in a tight spot with a lot of ships in a small space.
Scott: right That's what Star Wars is yeah.
Scott: And then the other good free space shooters were the same thing the wing commanders and the descent free space and descent descent and All the other good ones.
Scott: right they were all Small.
Scott: you know you're.
Scott: it's like even though you're fraud you're flying free But you're you're in a. you're like you're in a bottle right with a whole bunch of other people flying free And that's what makes it wild and crazy and fun.
Scott: if you're out in like space quiet It's like that's good for like 2001 Space Odyssey, but that doesn't scratch my tie fighter it just scratches a very different itch.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: So that's how that is.
Rym: so All I will say is that I am cautiously optimistic about this name, and I'm going to play it to see what the deal is.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are I gotta sort this Because the pledge manager is different Ellen Joyce hiding me nickel Marty green.
Rym: yet Just like a dude guy short option.
Rym: Graham Finch you hold the key to my heart But she packed my suitcase to set me on my way.
Rym: Clinton Walton J Bands written from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff sailor Vista the thirst for hydrated Ganon Through a dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Sherman von Harl and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their name, but now I leave you with Hello potion seller.
Rym: I Am going into battle, but I want your strongest potions.
Rym: My potions are too strong for you traveler potion seller.
Rym: I Tell you I'm going into battle and I want only your strongest potions.
Rym: You can't handle my potions.
Rym: They're too strong for you potion seller.
Rym: Listen to me.
Rym: I want only your strongest potions.
Rym: My potions would kill you traveler.
Rym: You cannot handle my potions potion seller enough of these games and going into battle and I need your strongest potions.
Rym: My strongest potions will kill you traveler.
Scott: You can't handle my strongest potions.
Rym: You better go to a seller that sells weaker potions Potion.
Rym: seller I'm telling you right now.
Rym: I'm going into battle and I need only your strongest potions.