Rym: It's Tuesday, February 25th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights Tonight Randomizers, like all of them.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: We are at the end of a surprisingly long Dense convention season for GeekNights, like way more than usual
Scott: Because some conventions, you know, start at PAX West in Seattle is normal on Labor Day
Rym: But then like all the other conventions just converge into like one a month for a very
Scott: Mostly because PAX East is early.
Scott: PAX East was early and then we have Unplugged like around like Because Unplugged and South are, you know, basically on top of each other.
Rym: Yeah, and also Magfest was early relative to when Magfest has been in the past.
Scott: South and Magfest are even more on top of each other.
Rym: Yeah, I worry next year South and Magfest might actually overlap.
Scott: No, because uh Magfest is later and it's not New Year's but it's also not MLK Day, which is when South pretty much always is.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta check.
Scott: South is MLK Day as often as West is Labor Day.
Scott: Yeah, not guaranteed No, but it's as long as, you know, Magfest is not MLK Day.
Rym: I'm pretty safe with South not overlapping it directly But what this means is what I haven't been playing all the kinds of games that I normally play because my like.
Rym: I've been really Busy.
Rym: just my life has been busy.
Rym: So I've been mostly playing like if I play Overwatch I play in the arcade like RNG mode.
Rym: I play like Slay the Spire on the Train or Genshin Clever or Dopple Clever.
Rym: I can't get above 200 in Genshin Clever 2.
Scott: Where did you even get Genshin Clever 2?
Rym: It's just on Android.
Rym: It's been on Android forever.
Scott: Oh has it?
Rym: Yeah, I have both of them.
Rym: Okay They were like a dollar fifty like they were.
Rym: I can get I can reliably like.
Rym: my average in Genshin Clever is like 270 280 like I can get that really reliable.
Rym: Oh, there it is.
Scott: Twice as clever.
Rym: Twice as clever.
Rym: 187 is the highest score I have ever been able to achieve so far.
Rym: That game is really hard.
Scott: Yeah Now someone posted a thing online that was like this is how to get the maximum score.
Scott: that the first one.
Scott: Here's a little.
Scott: here's a little graphic.
Rym: Oh, what did he say?
Scott: Luck is the rest.
Rym: But yeah luck is the rest because I did start penciling in.
Rym: what if I could choose my rolls?
Rym: Yeah, you can make a full web game Like if you just roll right you can have a ridiculously high score.
Rym: But I do have a very specific strategy that will reliably like 90% of the time get me well over 200 no matter what even with really bad rolls Mmm, so I basically only play that strategy.
Rym: I did try alternate strategies and I did some like math plotting like.
Rym: is there a way?
Rym: because the game comes down to both those games I realized come down to the economy of how many dice can you score?
Rym: Yeah, and anything you can do to score one more die somehow without like Sacrificing something fundamental is just how you get your score up.
Rym: Yeah, and It all other than that.
Rym: It's just luck mitigation like Yahtzee.
Rym: Yeah, I like these games a lot.
Rym: So, uh, there is actually a lot of big news.
Rym: as you know PAX East is this week Like we're not gonna do a show on Thursday because we will already have had most of our first day of packs By the time we normally record gig nights.
Scott: Yeah, but maybe you know, the Internet's good at PAX East.
Scott: I might experiment with some, you know posting some content from PAX East.
Scott: Yeah with their high quality Wi-Fi that is in the convention center.
Scott: But we're gonna do it lower and follow us at every single place that we exist to see if that happens.
Rym: Like I'm not bringing microphones or video equipment or like I'm not bringing the usual kit.
Rym: Yeah, my bag has mostly board games in it.
Rym: Yep, but the big news is pretty recently Sony just outright said they're pulling they're giving up on PAX East.
Rym: They're completely pulling out.
Rym: They will have zero present.
Scott: So if you looked at the play state the map of the expo hall previously There were these two three two giant blocks and one kind of normal block under the stairs because I had some big Announcements and they were really all said PlayStation on them.
Scott: and then it's like well We're pulling out.
Scott: and now the expo hall map has changed and none of those PlayStation things are there.
Scott: I know the aisles in the front of the expo hall where the mega booths are not the indie mega booth The actual industry mega booths, right?
Rym: Are much more widely Because there is no way to fill in a gap like that at a con like pack with a last minute with a week's notice.
Scott: Hey Anyone want to buy a giant expensive booth that I would like a week's notice and Be able to bring everything necessary to fill that space.
Rym: It's like no like it was a. and what's interesting is while there is the coronavirus global issue.
Rym: There was no Precipitating news in the US of any kind about this, right?
Scott: It's strange how if you look at coronavirus stuff just around the world in general, right?
Scott: What we see is pretty much very few places or at least very new.
Scott: I guess it's not.
Scott: it's not newsworthy when someone handles it correctly.
Scott: every single news story you see is either about someone not doing enough or Showing doing too much, right?
Rym: So there aren't really any places doing too much though?
Scott: No, so for example, right you have like Japan not checking the doctors who are on the boats taking care of people Even though the doctor in China, they're like, oh doctors know what to do.
Scott: They won't have it.
Scott: We don't need to test them except the doctor who discovered it died of it already.
Rym: Yeah, but what I can say?
Scott: and then you have people.
Scott: you have situations like this where PlayStation Sony is like pull it out.
Rym: It's like Boston is perfectly safe Because of travel to Boston.
Rym: that's it bought.
Rym: the fact that it's in Boston literally does not matter at all would not matter What city on earth the event is in?
Rym: Because I note Facebook has also pulled out of PAX East meaning oculus has pulled out of PAX East meaning another area They normally run is now empty and PAX is scrambling to fill it in the VR space.
Rym: Mm-hmm you know, I work in capital markets is my day job and Generally global companies around the entire world regardless of where they are have Drastically curtailed any official travel by employees to events of any kind.
Rym: No big gatherings of people anywhere.
Rym: because and the main reason is While the risk is relatively low because it's a global issue and because it's spread so easily The issue is every major convention or like industry event where a lot of people go Especially events that draw people from a broad area or an international place or that are just very dense are a Significant increased risk relative to normal times.
Scott: So it's still.
Scott: You know, it would make sense if the convention was you know somewhere.
Rym: no, like I just said it does there is It literally doesn't matter.
Rym: It's probably no more dangerous to have it in a city where there are more cases than in a city like Boston.
Scott: is a equation Moronic level of caution to the point where it's like one of those people who's like, you know Wearing gloves and walk around in a bubble.
Scott: It's like Idiots taking, you know taking too much.
Rym: think you know anything about this.
Scott: He's too much caution is just as stupid as being not enough cause.
Rym: this is really too much caution.
Rym: It does not cause Sony anything.
Rym: No, it doesn't cost them anything.
Scott: It's just still really stupidly too cautious for no reason.
Scott: It makes them look stupid.
Scott: No I don't think it actually the same way.
Scott: someone who's taking too much caution in any area of life looks stupid like someone wearing ten Helmets and like wrapping foam around their body.
Rym: the other reason why companies pull out of this stuff is that the people that they normally send to events something broadly like a Lot of events globally have been cancelled and a lot of companies have put the overabundance of caution.
Rym: No, I think it's an adequate like amount of caution.
Rym: It's overabundance of caution depending on the case by now because these are all also events where the people that companies send I'm not talking about you and me is like tax attendees But companies.
Rym: it tends to be a relatively small set of people who go to all the events and travel a lot.
Rym: The danger is that super spreader situation of people from a company go to one convention Then another one then another one then another one need.
Scott: they just don't travel to a place that there's a lot of virus.
Rym: I just said that's not part of the equation.
Rym: You don't know shit about this.
Rym: You're just you're just talking out of your ass.
Scott: Yeah No If it was a real danger then packs should just not happen.
Rym: if the packs if it's not dangerous Did I not just say there's no significant danger to the attendees the day.
Scott: There's no danger to the attendees.
Scott: then there's no danger to attendees who happen to work for a company.
Rym: Understand anything about like threat files or the stupidest thing.
Scott: if attendees are not threatened Then people who happen to work for Sony who are also attendees are also not threatened.
Scott: That is just not basic logic.
Rym: That's yeah, that's wrong And you don't know shit that's wrong.
Scott: impact should be canceled because it's not safe to be there.
Scott: It's either safe to be there or it isn't.
Rym: uh, that's like Really ridiculous reductive bullshit baby thinking.
Rym: Common sense like the.
Rym: no, it's not.
Scott: that says if it's safe to be.
Scott: if it's not safe to be there No, we shouldn't have the event.
Scott: if it is safe to be there then it's safe for any human being to be there.
Rym: That's all right.
Rym: I think you're stupid.
Rym: Okay, this like I think Sony is stupid.
Scott: They look like little babies who are like, oh, we're so afraid we're gonna hide from the world.
Rym: So you clearly didn't listen to any words.
Rym: I said about.
Scott: I'm saying the words you said were wrong and stupid.
Scott: Okay, if you're so afraid, why don't you why you go?
Scott: and maybe you shouldn't be going to pegs you work for a company.
Scott: Why isn't your company preventing you from going?
Rym: most of our business travel has been canceled.
Scott: Uh-huh Well, how come they're not preventing you?
Scott: if they should buy that logic.
Scott: They should prevent you from going east.
Rym: Uh, well because I am not part of a small team that travels to a lot of places on behalf of the company in a short Span of time.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Also I am banned from traveling to a bunch of specific places for the foreseeable.
Scott: Well, that is common sense.
Scott: I think Everyone should be banned from going.
Rym: I don't think you understand the like basic difference between a generalized threats profile versus like a more specific one.
Rym: Like you just don't know anything about this space and you're talking out of your ass.
Rym: You're like being the epitome of the white dude explaining something.
Rym: You don't know anything about.
Scott: I mean I don't even care if Sony goes or not.
Scott: The point is they just look really stupid.
Scott: And tendos not pulling out Nintendo's showing up just fine.
Scott: They don't seem to give a shit.
Scott: They're Japanese company.
Scott: How come Nintendo's not pulling out?
Scott: Are they stupid Nintendo?
Scott: You're saying Nintendo shouldn't go.
Scott: so because this Sony's all smart.
Scott: Is that what you're saying?
Rym: The difference is probably.
Rym: I mean, I don't know the details of the marketing teams in these different companies.
Scott: I guess I was going.
Rym: they're not pulling out.
Rym: Yeah, but again, like I said, I don't you know I don't know the differences between the marketing teams.
Rym: I don't work for any of these companies but some companies have a central team that goes all around the world to do this stuff and some companies have Regional specific teams.
Rym: and if you have purely like regional specific It's a lot safer to like, you know, I have to worry about this stuff nearly as much.
Rym: So if you have an entirely US staff that moves entirely to a US location That's much less of a threat vector.
Rym: Then a team that travels to the US to do the thing then travels to another like third country to do the thing.
Scott: As long as you don't travel to one of the countries of the diseases all over It's not as the US has like the third most cases and there are.
Rym: there were cases in Boston.
Scott: So if you want to do not think there were not see any.
Rym: yeah, there were two.
Rym: What do you read?
Rym: I have access to like real like live industry data about this.
Rym: I can pull it up right now if you want to see it.
Scott: Anyway, let us move on to the next news.
Rym: So what's interesting about this though?
Rym: Is that from the packs perspective?
Rym: It's a blow in the sense that a lot of the people who go to cons like packs They're really only there for the expo hall.
Rym: Like I think that's always.
Rym: that's something that I think is stupid like attendees.
Scott: well that we've always said that that stupid.
Rym: but The kinds of people who only go to an expo hall are the kinds of people who really want to play like the game that Sony's been hyping up for months saying we're gonna have it at PAX.
Rym: You can play it.
Rym: and They're the kinds of people who don't read websites and will not know that Sony is not there.
Rym: I really feel for the poor enforcers We're gonna be standing in the area where Sony was gonna be having to explain to a lot of really angry and dense nerds Why Sony isn't there?
Rym: Like that is gonna be an interesting thing to see play out.
Rym: I'm curious how many people will like just not know Sony pulled out and show up and be mad about it.
Rym: Mmm, the other interesting thing that happened.
Rym: Is that the mayor of Boston like Agrees with me.
Rym: Well, not really cuz one what he said.
Rym: like he's getting a lot of flack for the kind of bullshitty thing He said about this because he accused an Asian owned company.
Scott: Well, that's all that's true.
Rym: Like his whole letter is basically this plays into Asian stereotypes.
Rym: Yeah, and Like the response from Sony there is racism going.
Rym: What do you think owns us?
Rym: What?
Rym: what's your point?
Rym: Like so the mayor of Boston even sent a letter to the CEO of Sony Like mad at him for Pope for having the company pull out of the event.
Rym: I don't think the mayor of Boston understands that much about this.
Rym: The only interesting point about that is that The mayor of Boston cares that much about packs.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing.
Scott: I don't understand right is?
Scott: I think packs is a Does not lose right, you know?
Scott: forget about whether they should or they shouldn't Understand how convention centers were right?
Scott: But here's the thing is that pecs doesn't make or lose money whether Sony shows up or not.
Scott: There's tons of video giant.
Scott: video game companies aren't coming that used to come or right and it's like pecs sold out with or without Right packs used to sell it not selling less tickets because PlayStation pulls out.
Scott: They're not gonna sell less tickets next year because Boston makes the same money off packs Pretty much no matter who shows up and less like.
Rym: no No It's even worse.
Rym: it was like the whole industry pulls out and is basically like a barren expo hall Which could happen because a lot more companies are planning to pull out of GDC.
Rym: probably well GDC.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why they're either but you know
Rym: GDC actually has an even worse threat profile because GDC doesn't have like normal attendees as much as it has like Reps from the marketing teams of all these international companies all showing up and doing a bunch of meetings together.
Rym: Well, it has way less people though Yeah But I would consider GDC to probably be a worst threat vector for this particular kind of illness.
Scott: pandemic expert Rym.
Rym: over here I mean, I was the chief risk officer of a company for a while.
Rym: I am formally trained in risk assessment Like yes, that is true That literally is true.
Rym: That's part of my job.
Rym: But you don't believe me, you know, yes, the government is calling up Rym.
Scott: What should we do about the coronavirus?
Scott: It's such an expert.
Rym: Why would the government call me?
Rym: I'm not a government official.
Rym: I did that for a company.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Scott: No one's calling you for help.
Scott: You're not.
Rym: my company paid me to do this.
Scott: Uh-huh Oh someone paid you.
Scott: therefore you're an expert, you know.
Scott: Therefore you're right.
Scott: Someone pays you money.
Scott: Therefore.
Scott: You're right.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: No, all I'm saying is that I am a professional risk assessment.
Scott: All that means is someone paid you money.
Scott: That's all that's required to be a professional is to have someone pay you money.
Scott: that gives you no credentials whatsoever.
Scott: Someone can pay me to wash their car doesn't mean I'm a car washing expert.
Rym: So you don't Doctors are you don't trust?
Scott: because they're paid.
Rym: So what?
Scott: why do you trust a doctor that the doctor went to medical school for a zillion fucking years and work their ass off?
Scott: Did you go and study virus spreading or whatever, you know in school for six?
Scott: No to ten guys.
Rym: I learned generalized corporate risk assessment.
Rym: That's a very different.
Scott: You know, nothing about viruses.
Scott: No viruses are.
Rym: You don't need to know that there's.
Rym: you can just read data about this like there's data feed.
Scott: Oh, man If reading data just made me know everything and be an expert instead of studying something for a long time
Rym: You learn in risk assessment are like how to interpret data about risk to enable to figure out what the actual Real threat is to your particular domain or your particular company and then make decisions based on that.
Rym: Like that's what that is.
Rym: That's a job.
Scott: Yeah, it's a medical risk.
Scott: I'm gonna contact a medical person not just some Rym who read a data.
Rym: Don't think you know what risk officers do in companies or who they are?
Scott: Yeah, I know who they are people like Rym.
Scott: We think they know what they don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't know.
Rym: That's why I got trained in it.
Scott: Oh, so your training is equivalent to the training of an expert who went to school for a very long time There.
Rym: most people don't go to school for a very long time.
Scott: doctors do you said.
Scott: why do I trust doctors?
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot of shit.
Rym: Are you a doctor?
Rym: No, so if you sound the same over I mean if you want to be anti-intellectual and weird you can.
Scott: you're the one who's claiming to know something I guess I do know about like risk assessment.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: Okay, coronavirus Rym everybody.
Rym: I didn't say.
Rym: I didn't say I'm an expert in coronavirus.
Rym: I'm an expert in corporate risk assessment Specifically pandemics and epidemics.
Scott: Oh, you're an expert on pandemics, huh?
Rym: Now in the in the specific and narrow domain of corporate risk assessment Uh-huh.
Rym: Okay I had to draft a plan on what to do.
Rym: in fact right now because you know There's a global the entire finance industry everyone's pulled out their BCP plans for these kinds of epidemics and they're said like everything's set up in case where everyone has to Do the pandemic like procedure?
Rym: There's a pandemic procedure.
Rym: There's a button someone get hit and then me and everyone in the company that I work for now where I don't plan this But I trust the people who are paid to do it They will like they'll hit a button and then I have to follow a procedure where I'm not allowed to go to work And I have to work from home and there's all these things I have to do and everyone in the company has a different playbook.
Scott: There's a button.
Scott: you should find that button in the office.
Scott: I mean, it's you don't to go to work.
Rym: Yeah, it's up some keys on a keyboard.
Rym: I'd still have to work from home.
Rym: I don't get to just not work.
Rym: I don't actually need to go to the office to do a lot.
Scott: I don't push the button I'm telling you, but if it was such a button I'd be pushing.
Rym: the other thing the mayor might have been mad about is Reputational risk to Boston and the fact that the news said Oh big company won't travel to Boston.
Rym: But if that's actually what the mayor of Boston is mad about the mayor of Boston Doesn't seem to actually understand how companies work or how events work.
Scott: Well, I mean the thing is I don't think that hurts the reputation of Boston, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like people think there's a big they make up.
Scott: well So like there is a mind they think they've been sliding.
Scott: everyone's like what the fuck.
Rym: so Scott you realize though there has been like in the last month a drastic downturn in Tourism and visiting revenue in like every major city on earth basically entirely because of coronavirus.
Scott: Oh, yeah People aren't traveling because people are paranoid and traveling less sometimes with good reasons.
Scott: Sometimes not with good reason.
Rym: Yeah, people are traveling less.
Rym: They're spending less eating at restaurants and that's it.
Rym: But that of course but the real danger times the racist reasons?
Rym: Yeah pretty rarely it seems like it's mostly Just generalized caution coupled with the real economic damage is coming from supply chain misses.
Scott: That's also true.
Rym: so Pax East issued a statement about you know The safety of packs and everything and what it basically boils down to is what it boils down to at all conventions.
Rym: if you're going To Pax do the same thing you do at every gaming convention Don't touch other nerds and don't shake hands with people cars and wash your hands
Scott: Even if you're not gonna get the corona virus if you're gonna get
Rym: the flu
Scott: You could you could get anything.
Scott: if I write there was swine flu effects.
Rym: Yeah, but a bunch of our friends got it got diagnosed.
Rym: I remember I was on the phone with Robert Gu listing the flight numbers of our two friends that were on it, right?
Scott: It's like, you know that was but that was a time when swine flu was like in the area already.
Scott: It wasn't.
Scott: well, I wasn't like oh swine flu's in the other side of the world and we got it.
Scott: So so do you remember that actually?
Rym: One student I think it was from U of W who went to Pax Spread it at Pax and then Pax was actually a right.
Scott: but the point is it was already there to begin with.
Scott: Well, yeah, it wasn't like.
Rym: it was not widespread there.
Rym: It was not known to be there.
Scott: Well, I mean there was someone who had it there.
Rym: Yes, and they didn't know yet.
Rym: They went if they were sick.
Rym: They went to Pax.
Rym: they spread it to a few people and because it's Pax it spread to a lot of people at Pax and Then because it was a convention it spread to much of the coasts right like rapidly.
Rym: Pax was a big part of that spread.
Rym: So wash your hands don't cough in people's faces faces.
Rym: The really the thing people don't seem to realize You can put like those masks or more to protect other people from you.
Rym: But the real way you get things like this is not so much someone coughing on you It's don't touch your fucking face after you touch things.
Rym: Yeah, like if you can just train yourself and it's really hard.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I tell my face.
Scott: Look I just touch my face.
Rym: I touch my face all the time like Just think the whole time you're at Pax.
Rym: Don't touch my face.
Rym: Don't touch my face Don't because basically don't put salt.
Scott: my number one place The virus is gonna get is on your hands because your hands are always touching shit.
Scott: You're touching cards that you pass around the table.
Scott: You're touching arms on chairs.
Scott: You're touching tables.
Scott: It's touching all kinds of shit subway poles some railings on escalators.
Scott: Those are the worst right?
Scott: You're touching the flushers and the toilet.
Scott: you're touching all kinds of shit and your hands are disgusting Even if you just wash them, right?
Scott: It's all kinds of the hands.
Scott: have the most disgusting stuff on them Right?
Scott: the rest of your body's covered in clothes.
Rym: It's not you're not.
Scott: I'm often you touching something with your knee or your elbow Right, you're not doing not as much as with the hand But it's it's my hand.
Scott: nothing can get into your body if it's just on your hand.
Scott: Let's you got a big cut on your hand or something, but it's hand.
Rym: There's no hole.
Rym: It's specifically hand to mucus memory a hand to face.
Rym: That is how you most people get.
Scott: there's no way for the virus to get from the hand into the body easily.
Scott: But as soon as you put the hand on the face It's like let me bring the most disgusting stuff that I've collected and put it right here the entry hole into my body Right, and that's how you get in trouble.
Scott: So just don't touch your face So don't let other people touch your face.
Rym: wash your hands like often.
Rym: like however often you think you need to wash your hands.
Rym: Just wash it.
Rym: just do it more often.
Scott: I already wash my hands at packs like crazy.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much every time and however long you're a hand washer need to wash your hands Like how long they need to be underwater.
Scott: just double it.
Scott: learn to wash your hands properly.
Scott: Go to YouTube watch a video.
Scott: hand-washing Friction is the most important factor in hand-washing.
Rym: Yeah, I remember when I worked in the hospital I had to take classes on like how to wash my hands and you ever see a doctor wash their hands before surgery.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: They're mostly scrubbing.
Rym: Oh, and then when I worked in Scrubbing I worked in a NICU for a while like an infant like premature, baby Like and they make you wash your hands like crazy.
Scott: Oh you wear ten gloves.
Scott: The procedure don't touch the babies.
Rym: because I wasn't trained in how to like prepare to enter that area I had to have a nurse escort me and wash with me every time I went into that room.
Rym: Imagine like seven minutes of scrubbing on your hands and arms before we could even walk into a room.
Scott: Yep So it doesn't mean a baby gets sick they done.
Scott: Yeah so you it's like you get a cold.
Rym: it's like I you got a cold brand new baby and If someone tries to shake hands with you at a convention just don't like.
Rym: elbow bump is way better.
Rym: Like don't touch people's grubby hands for all the reasons we just described.
Rym: Yeah It's not news.
Rym: In fact official advice from penny arcade.
Rym: Do not let a stranger's weeping pustules drip into your urethra.
Scott: Yeah, so remember that really entering through the urethra would be pretty hard for a virus.
Scott: I feel like it's more likely to.
Rym: uh, All I'm gonna say is wash your hands before your jacket.
Rym: if you're a pax and you're the kind of person who jacks at a Pax, you know, you just jacket not in the front Yeah, but I feel like I mean the rosy palm is a very important technique.
Scott: It also a jacket in the shower where you're washing your hand and jacket.
Scott: It's simultaneous.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that could work.
Rym: I really know anywhere else that packs the jacket beside you not jacket in the shower If you are rooming with other people at packs.
Scott: Well, it depends.
Rym: Yeah, I have.
Rym: I Have not jacked it in a shower.
Rym: We're like we've been at a con together.
Scott: No, I haven't either.
Rym: Okay I was worried there was an implication what you just said.
Rym: No, I'm just saying it's not making sure.
Scott: I'm just saying like You know, all right, they're in the shower.
Scott: They're in there for a few extra minutes You don't?
Scott: they wash it away what's you know, I just if someone did I wouldn't be like upset unless they did it in a You know improper fashion.
Rym: They leave some issue the killer.
Scott: if there's any leftovers That's a problem, right if they take in the if they're in the shower too long That's a problem.
Rym: or if you hear it, right?
Scott: That would also be at least it would just be like come on, man.
Scott: I wouldn't like disturb me personally, but I would imagine it would be very Impolite to many other people.
Scott: I would just be like, come on.
Rym: someone in the chat just pointed out We have just done a sequel to the best episode of gig nights.
Rym: Okay, I'd leave it to the imagination.
Rym: You can search for that episode.
Rym: It's about.
Scott: I mean It's definitely more polite to be doing it in the shower when I'm saying in the expo hall or in your bed When the people are sleeping in the adjacent bed or same bed.
Rym: Someone also did point out.
Rym: I guess they have knowledge.
Rym: Nintendo does have regionally specific marketing teams.
Scott: Hey, that's true.
Rym: That's probably the main reason why Nintendo is not pulled out of anything yet.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So in some final news This is just the most wholesome thing and I love it.
Scott: if you're not aware and everyone everybody is aware.
Scott: Yeah, you'd be surprised You're not aware how you do.
Scott: We're nice.
Rym: He nice is super obscure just in case animal crossing and doom are gonna be released on The same day.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it's actually like a sequel to the new doom.
Rym: Yeah, which was a good game.
Rym: New doom was a great game.
Rym: We didn't review it.
Rym: I feel like we should.
Rym: I beat it.
Rym: Yeah, there's a VR version that I tried.
Rym: that's actually real good.
Scott: It's just the same game though with it's real.
Rym: It's real intense in VR like Almost too intense.
Rym: Okay Also really gross.
Scott: I mean it's gross my what?
Rym: Yeah, you see you think it's gross when you're doing it on a screen But when you're like in the viscera anyway, like even I was like, whoa okay, so The fandoms of these two games overlap more than you might expect Or not at all.
Rym: I think they do overlap.
Rym: I know some people who like both these games And there is a lot of fan art and discussion between these two communities.
Rym: that is just delightful.
Rym: Well, I
Scott: was like their games are releasing on the same day And I think somebody made I don't know which one was the first
Rym: the first one I saw the
Scott: person you saw wasn't the first one that was now but
Rym: the first one I saw was the one that was Isabel sitting on doom guy's shoulder and
Scott: also the first one I saw
Rym: yep And it was just like rip and tear until it's done,
Scott: right?
Scott: So someone made you know a meme crossing him over and I guess you know All the creative people in the universe on the internet were like, oh that's great.
Scott: and they started You know riffing on that theme and they just keep on riffing cuz it's a really great mix and it doesn't get old.
Scott: Do great taste it tastes great together.
Scott: I Stop now wait and you know and keep going till it's spent because you're not gonna be able to redo this one.
Scott: It's not like Animal Crossing for the next Nintendo console and the next doom are also gonna release on the same day Unless you know, they're so intelligent that they do that on purpose in like three or four years from now whenever.
Scott: But you know, it could be a much longer time than that.
Scott: because how long since the last Animal Crossing?
Rym: Yeah, because I like everything about Animal Crossing except I don't actually like playing the games like.
Rym: I like the aesthetic I like the music.
Rym: I like the fandom.
Rym: I just don't actually enjoy the game.
Scott: I've seen a lot of Animal Crossing and know a lot of Animal Crossing.
Rym: I've actually never actually played or bought and We could both play the new one and review it.
Scott: it's a lot of money though, I feel that's the main reason.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah anyway it's time for things of the day, so I Have to hate a man by the name of Alexander Ovechkin.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of reasons to hate that guy.
Scott: He is on the enemy team yeah, but I also have to deeply respect several enemy teams as Literally I can think of at least three teams.
Scott: He's on.
Rym: you'll see that my thing of the day will cover that.
Rym: he is also One of the best hockey players in history.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Like one man is the man is a legend.
Rym: He's not number one, but he is a legend.
Rym: He will go down in history and his career ain't even done yet.
Rym: No, like the man is just a hockey god.
Rym: So he recently set a record.
Rym: He has scored 700 goals in his career.
Scott: that's a lot of goals.
Scott: that is a lot memory.
Rym: It's hockey a sport where games will end like zero zero and go into overtime.
Scott: Lately scoring, you know scores being up and down over time.
Scott: But yes, you know You don't score a lot of goals in a game per team.
Scott: if you're an individual hockey player most games your score zero goals.
Scott: Yeah Maybe you get an assist if you score a point a game and a point is an assist or a goal.
Scott: If you score a point a game that's already amazing.
Scott: that is considered fantastic.
Scott: You're a star player.
Scott: Yep, right and that's not even a goal a game.
Scott: if you score a goal a game.
Scott: You're a legend.
Scott: Yeah, and even if you scored a goal a game you would get 80 something goals a year.
Scott: There's a reason to get to 700 goals.
Scott: There's a reason half a score a goal a game For like almost 10 years.
Rym: There's a reason.
Rym: the hat trick exists.
Rym: people will throw their $40 hat away If someone scores three goals in a single game because it's so crazy when it happens, yeah So this video is like two goals.
Scott: It's like whoa, that's crazy.
Rym: Yeah, but three in one game Was put out a couple days ago by the NHL's an official video and it is just a super cut of Every single Ovechkin goal like just the goal with like very little contacts and it is almost 13 minutes long.
Rym: Yep, it's Mesmerizing especially because 90% of them are him in the same spot.
Rym: Oh, I was about to say it's him in his office.
Rym: I want to make a super cut.
Rym: that just is him from the office.
Scott: You just want to remove all the non office goals?
Rym: Yeah, yeah, he.
Scott: basically it's like People don't know enough about hockey.
Scott: Basically.
Scott: This is one spot.
Scott: I'm like the circle where Ovechkin always stands and whenever I've seen him play live you see him.
Scott: He just sort of skates around there and sometimes your team is smart and has a defenseman just hanging near him.
Rym: Sometimes his sole job is to keep him from scoring a goal like just sometimes.
Scott: your team is stupid and he stands there all alone.
Scott: He just stands there waiting for his teammate to pass him the puck and assume when the pucks coming towards him He just takes a one-timer right at the goal and he's just practiced it so much.
Scott: I clicked on a raise in a lot of the time Even though the goalie knows it's coming from there the goal.
Scott: He's got to pay attention to where the puck is, you know, not to where Ovechkin is.
Rym: No, he's not.
Rym: I watched like a Rangers game.
Rym: Let's say and it's just like he's there.
Rym: He's there He's standing in the spot.
Scott: Don't let him.
Scott: don't let anyone pass the puck to him when he's standing in the spot.
Scott: Stand in between him and the goal when he's in the spot.
Scott: How hard is this?
Scott: I can see it from here and I'm not even professional.
Scott: you're paid millions of dollars a year to do this.
Rym: That's one guy you got to worry about.
Rym: What's wrong with you?
Rym: Ah, the latest comment on the video he scored on the Atlanta Thrashers.
Rym: so much.
Rym: They became extinct.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Yeah So what do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: So quite a long time ago many years ago we did When I was a kid, I had a toy called marble works Which is a bunch of plastic pieces you would put together.
Scott: and oh, yeah I had that.
Scott: you drop marbles on the top and they would run race to the bottom right through a series of things.
Scott: It's a very similar hobby that is related to like setting up dominoes and watching them fall.
Rym: Yep so here's also into dominoes weird.
Scott: and then we did a. We did a thing of the day quite a long time ago about this marble Olympics, which someone made these YouTube videos of marbles, you know Competing with each other as if the marbles were people, right?
Rym: What was fascinating about that video was that it was almost as exciting as real sports like on this particular wavelength, right?
Scott: So here is a video sponsored by a company that sells bulk dominoes.
Scott: Yeah, that is a marbula one.
Scott: It is brand new and they basically did extremely high production values of marbles racing around this Grand Prix track You know playing it totally straight as if it's a real race a real sport.
Scott: the marbles are on real teams.
Scott: they have real names.
Scott: They're actually competing, you know, it's somewhat thrilling like a real sport.
Scott: But really this is thing of the day because the production value Yeah, so insanely high if you're willing to put like just to play this straight.
Rym: That is amazing.
Scott: They even put like marbles in the grandstand And they called the whole thing as if it was real Competating.
Scott: and it's it's something to see props to whoever put this together.
Rym: I wonder how many All your camera flipped over.
Rym: I wonder how many takes it took for them to not crack up doing the commentary on these marbles.
Scott: It's just one person doing it.
Rym: Yeah So in that a moment, we're gonna be at PAX.
Rym: What's happening?
Scott: Today is what - we're recording this on Tuesday.
Rym: Most people probably listen on Wednesday by this time tomorrow In pre tabletop playing a board game.
Rym: February 27th PAX East 2020 is happening and there is official gaming in the hotel before packs.
Rym: tomorrow Wednesday night the 23rd the 26th Yeah, y'all eat packs hotel gaming official most basically almost our entire crew Will be enforcing in the evening shift.
Rym: So we'll be playing games all day and then around like six o'clock will disappear.
Scott: Are we getting a panel though, or we're just getting a free enforcing badge.
Rym: We are doing one panel.
Scott: So yet again for every single packs.
Scott: I've been to every single time.
Scott: I've been given a panel for some reason.
Rym: Yep, all right.
Rym: We are moderately popular at PAX.
Rym: So we're doing a reiteration with slight updates of take your fucking turn At PAX unplugged.
Scott: you can watch it on YouTube right the hell.
Scott: now You don't need to waste an hour of your precious paxi's time going to this panel or you can.
Scott: I don't know why you would But I guess I can't stop you just like I can't stop you from listening to this podcast in the first place But you can send your friend who takes too long on their turn to come to our panel.
Rym: I just send them to YouTube.
Rym: - no send them to our panel.
Rym: So you punish them and make them spend more time.
Scott: Why are you such a mean person?
Rym: They took more than 30 seconds to take their turn.
Rym: in a game like settlers They just make them watch a YouTube video.
Scott: They try to walk away from the YouTube video.
Rym: hit them.
Rym: There's more peer pressure.
Rym: people don't like to walk out of panels even bad ones at conventions hit them.
Rym: Yeah, I Love that slide.
Rym: I get the laugh every time of just the fist.
Rym: Yeah, I paid for that stock image.
Rym: Okay, there's a really good fist.
Scott: This is why I don't give him patreon money.
Scott: He'll use it on stock images of fists.
Rym: I have bought like four stock images of fists.
Rym: Oh, I should replace it with the statue of at Joe Louis arena.
Rym: That is literally in my top five favorite statues of all time, it's not bad It's just a giant statue of his fist.
Rym: Nothing else.
Rym: Also, you might have known, you know, we are review board games like Joe Louis punch you.
Rym: you would take your fucking turn If Joe Louis punched me, I wouldn't take my turn because I would be dead.
Scott: Yeah He's playing a lot of board games up in the good.
Scott: So we don't take their turn up there.
Rym: We have reviewed a lot of board games on GeekNights in the last 15 years.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and I have been taking and I've been doing this for a while.
Rym: So there's 65 of them on YouTube.
Rym: now I've been taking just the reviews without like the opening crap Yeah thing of the day.
Scott: that's the thing.
Scott: the format of GeekNights, which may change at any time but the format as it has been for a zillion years is do a bunch of bullshit first like the bullshit we're doing right now and Then actually talk about the fucking topic Just like when you watch a late show on TV and it's like yeah a bunch of bullshit at the start of the show and then They interview the celebrity at the end.
Rym: But if you're reading a recipe you don't want like my year in Sardinia before they tell you how to make some food.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: So if you want to hear just the main bit where we talk about the board game, they're on YouTube.
Rym: Yep 65 of them.
Rym: there's a playlist of all of them and I'm adding like regularly that I'm going through the back catalogue.
Rym: Eventually every board game we've ever reviewed will be here as a standalone review with like images and everything.
Rym: It's a whole thing.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah The book club book is book.
Rym: club book is tail of Genji.
Scott: Yeah, I'm still reading it on the subway slowly It's long.
Scott: Yeah, I'll read it.
Scott: I'm enjoying I'll read some on my way to Pax and I think I continue to be more interested in everyone.
Rym: but Genji.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's definitely a Genji muyo situation.
Scott: That's the first novel that has ever been written now not the first fiction for his now first novel Yep, so I figured that makes it important to read.
Scott: So we're reading it.
Rym: Yeah Before we get into the main bid because a friend of ours who was also very much into the randomizers pointed out something interesting And important send your friend to the panel so you can play a quick game without them at PAX.
Scott: Oh the slow person Okay.
Rym: Yeah, so Randomizers have been a thing and I feel like there are only two like People either like know the deal or have never heard of this or you know The other the people who like have heard of it, but like they didn't actually like for me.
Scott: I knew about it way long ago Right, but not until the past few months that I actually look closer and was like
Rym: Well, cuz I think I feel like the progression
Scott: is you know, you sort of understand it like, okay, I get what's going on there All right, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, I get the idea but
Rym: then eventually like someone says like something like a different format and they're like Oh wonder how they do those formats and then you kind of want to play one and then you're dragged in and you figure it Right,
Scott: so basically the deal is right.
Scott: There are a lot of video games out there Especially these days that are procedurally generated or randomized in some way even board games.
Scott: Yeah, right you start with a random map.
Scott: Why do we do this?
Scott: because we don't want to randomize the game, right?
Scott: So that one player has an advantage or disadvantage because of luck but we want to use luck and randomness in our games to get a different experience each time you play so we don't get bored and Play the exact same thing every time even if the spire
Rym: is great because I don't know what's coming.
Scott: Roguelikes are pretty much the first games to to capitalize on this idea, you know hardcore wise but you know Minecraft does it.
Scott: even Puerto Rico does it.
Scott: the plantations are different every time just a little bit, right?
Scott: So with the idea of a randomizer is like, okay We got all these new games we've made that are random and have tons of replay value.
Scott: But what if you know these games aren't the best games there ever were right?
Scott: the best games there ever were are games like Super Metroid or link to the fast or Mario's got about it.
Rym: I just say more that there's a lot of reasons why this particular era of games is most suited to this randomizer thing.
Scott: Oh, that's also true.
Scott: The best games that ever were also happen to be extremely suited to being randomized.
Rym: But it's partly that now.
Rym: recently we've seen something like there was the remake of link to the past not link to the past of links awakenings that people can play this game, but There aren't that many good Zelda games for example, like you can have played them all and memorize them all and then just fuck you.
Rym: There aren't more of these games to play and the indie ones tend to not be that good.
Rym: So now you're just sort of playing the same game over and over again slowly going crazy Especially the single-player games right where your inner you're exploring an environment, especially something like that.
Scott: It's like they become the first time you play the game, right?
Scott: You know, I always say how.
Scott: there's no spoilers or bullshit for movies, right?
Scott: But spoilers are not bullshit for a game like Zelda or Super Metroid or something, right?
Scott: Because the first time you play assuming you haven't like read a map or spoiled it, right?
Scott: You're exploring and learning and discovering and solving puzzles, right?
Scott: If you have a crossword puzzle, right the first time you do it You're looking at the clues and you're trying to figure out their meaning.
Scott: The second time you do it you just remember that word was in that spot.
Scott: It is now a completely fundamentally a different activity.
Scott: It becomes a knowledge based activity and not a you know, trivia based activity.
Scott: You're using a completely different part of your brain in a completely different part way.
Scott: The second or third time you do something it becomes all about knowledge and not about skills as much Or about anything else.
Rym: so but what you get out of it is different too.
Rym: Like you might be like you want to play a Final Fantasy 1 again But you don't want to just play Final Fantasy 1 again, but you want that feeling of playing Final Fantasy 1, right?
Scott: So if you play Final Fantasy 1 again, it's like well, it doesn't change on you.
Scott: But huh, let's randomize it.
Scott: different bad guys.
Scott: items are in different places.
Scott: People say different things different towns different.
Scott: right you can because these are such simple pieces of software.
Scott: We can emulate all of them.
Scott: It's really easy to take a piece right to go and look into that ROM and figure out which pieces Of memory represent what and shuffle them around.
Rym: Yep but I think there's a lot more going on here in terms of like.
Rym: why it became such a big thing?
Rym: because it's not just Play a randomized version of Zelda like most people are into this community.
Rym: It's overlapped with speedrunners and competitive gaming.
Rym: Oh, yeah people want it to be a competition.
Rym: I'll erase it.
Rym: I think it came out of a lot of this the like Link to the past and Final Fantasy like races that would happen like speedrunners racing.
Scott: speed running is definitely the added the Competitive element to the randomizers, right?
Scott: So the randomizers themselves are great for that.
Scott: replay value and eliminating knowledge games sort of thing.
Scott: Yeah, right, but competitive wise it's like, okay people were speed running.
Scott: We're already speed running a game like Zelda Super Metroid, right?
Scott: But it's the same damn game.
Scott: every time they find ways to make it faster But you're still.
Scott: it's all about improving your execution, right?
Scott: They're all working together to share the knowledge of how to do it the fastest.
Scott: It's all about who can actually push the buttons the most precisely right all in one go.
Rym: Yep, so these things end up being like serious players.
Rym: It's all about like can you do the frame perfect tricks you need to do and independently?
Rym: Do you know the game well enough to know all the locations and the kinds of things you might need?
Rym: and then you compete in?
Rym: This kind of random e world with all these other people.
Scott: by bringing the randomizer into the speedrun You're still testing the execution, right?
Scott: Because when like you have to fight a boss, well, you have to be good at fighting that boss.
Rym: But now there's a. there's a bigger risk.
Rym: Beat Ganon right and press your luck like in free enterprise the Final Fantasy 4 one.
Rym: It's like.
Rym: does someone go to the moon early and risk it?
Rym: like what if the enemy needs up there and strike to the room?
Scott: Isn't?
Scott: it's awesome?
Scott: because you don't know where anything is.
Scott: You actually have to think and make different decisions and now Decision making and not just execution come into play and you can test the broader set of skills.
Scott: Right, some of your knowledge is still tested right?
Scott: just it's just not purely knowledge.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you still need to know.
Scott: like aha with this item I can go to these places right versus.
Scott: this is the exact memorize the exact path.
Scott: Yeah Remember it's almost like there's a maze that's been shuffled and you just and it's not a straight maze of go from beginning to end.
Scott: You know, all right, you got you can enter the maze, but you can't get to the end.
Scott: It's locked, you know.
Scott: It's basically the equivalent game to Wolfenstein 3d.
Scott: We have to get keys to open doors to get keys to open doors to get to the exit.
Scott: It's the same exact game as that.
Rym: So imagine you're doing a Wolfenstein race, right?
Scott: It's a Wolfenstein race but it's a brand new map.
Scott: you've never seen before every single time and You know that like aha if I get a yellow key Then that means that I can open door I can go east right and if I get a blue key I can go west.
Scott: but it's still not a hundred percent the same every time.
Scott: so there's some knowledge plays into it.
Scott: Some of your execution skills still play into it.
Scott: It's all fighting the same bosses the same enemies, but the enemies might be different places.
Scott: They might you know different wet but some of your skills still matter But everything else is shuffled up.
Scott: so you're getting a brand new experience every time.
Scott: you still feel it feels way more fun to do and you test all those things as well as the additional test of Figuring out the optimal, you know figure out on the fly the optimal path instead of having a memorized optimal path.
Rym: And it is definitely like a little bit performative in the sense that like like Final Fantasy 4 like the the randomizer I like the most is the Final Fantasy 4 one Partly because Final Fantasy 4 is a game that I know inside and out.
Rym: So it's a it.
Rym: lets me apply this Completely useless knowledge from my childhood into a current hobby.
Rym: Yep but like what that does mean is that it's really hard to enjoy a Game like to an obsessive childhood degree.
Rym: I don't know about that.
Scott: It depends right on the the exact game.
Rym: and like I would not play the link to the past Randomizers of any kind until you had beaten.
Rym: link to the past at least twice like all the way through.
Scott: you should definitely beat it Not with the normal mode, but I'll play a randomizer.
Scott: But I think even if you've never played it you can still watch and enjoy the red.
Rym: Oh, you can definitely watch and enjoy but it's playing would be too too difficult.
Scott: You lose a few head.
Scott: They do have easy modes.
Scott: Like a lot of the randomizers when you randomize there's all sorts of choices of what exactly you're randomizing and how
Rym: much there's like website Generators you can use
Scott: and the links of the past was the one that gets mentioned the most because it's the one that's been developed The most thoroughly.
Scott: they're on version like 32 or something, right?
Scott: They've been out.
Scott: They've been honing that.
Scott: that's the sharpest knife of all the randomizer knives.
Scott: Final Fantasy 4 is pretty tight Yeah, and there are just so many options, but they do have like easy modes, right?
Scott: So for example the Super Metroid one, right?
Scott: There's a glitch in Super Metroid called the the mock ball.
Scott: that lets you get under these gates and go to I think into Brinstar without Like without having to fight the the plant boss out of the spore spawn whatever.
Rym: Oh, yeah, cuz you never see anyone fight that in a speed run.
Scott: You watch a speed run.
Scott: No one ever fights the spore spawn because they do the mock ball, right?
Scott: I've tried to do the mock ball.
Scott: I can't do it.
Scott: It's too hard because I'm not I'm an old man.
Scott: Right, but you can when you're making a metro a Super Metroid randomized ROM you can choose Say, okay put the items when you're randomizing them make sure that you don't put an item.
Scott: You know in such a way that means I can't complete the game without doing mock ball.
Scott: Yep, or you can say actually, you know what put the items, you know, I can do mock ball.
Scott: You put the items wherever you feel like I'm gonna get there.
Scott: And it's the same thing for all the other randomizers I've seen.
Scott: they let you customize how random it's gonna be and that actually plays into How you play the randomizer because you go.
Scott: All right, I just got you know, I haven't gotten a super missile yet.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: This these places are unreachable by super missile.
Scott: Therefore there must be a super missile in one of these five places because those are the only five places I haven't checked right that are Accessible right now with the items I have We're where is with what route do I take to check those places most efficiently?
Scott: Right, and that's where the skill of randomizer comes in.
Rym: Yep, and I think like my progression was I saw them like on speedrunners channels first.
Rym: Yeah, I saw speed run.
Scott: That's where I see them the most.
Rym: Yeah And I was like interested partly because like as much as I love RPG speedruns I've seen like the world record runs of all these games.
Rym: So there's not.
Rym: they're all the same now.
Rym: Yep unless it's like an AGT queue or like there's good commentary and a couch and all that but like I've seen these games to the Point that I don't need to watch them again.
Rym: so I started watching the free enterprise Final Fantasy 4 ones because it just gave me this like kind of Exciting speedrun or race that I can't get like watching a Final Fantasy 4 race straight is not that fun Cuz.
Rym: either they're neck-and-neck the whole time or one person falls behind and it's over right even formula one.
Scott: funny That my thing of the day was marbula one, right?
Scott: They have the same mostly the same tracks every year, right?
Scott: And even though they change tracks race to race which keeps it interesting and varied, right?
Scott: It's still year to year.
Scott: It's kind of all right.
Scott: Yeah, we're back at Monaco again, which is still a great track, but whatever right?
Scott: imagine if formula one literally they show up at the track in a car and An unknown track appears before them like they're driving there even know what the next turn is left or right or how close it Is or if it's a hairpin or anything, they're gonna drive around the track mad slow Right and learn
Rym: track
Scott: and then speed up and then you have like a real.
Scott: the competition is now not just who?
Scott: Fine-tuned their car for that track knowing everything going in and had the best practice and is the best of that track.
Scott: It's Fastest driver when it comes to tracks everyone already knows.
Scott: but if you had to learn a track straight up Maybe there's someone else who learns faster and they would be better or just has more raw racing skills, right?
Scott: Or there's also a luck factor though.
Scott: Maybe someone's really good at high speed tracks that right and they're good when they're like a long straightaway and it randomly happens to be a track that suits their style.
Rym: or maybe someone's falling behind because one thing that the all these randomizers have that makes the races so much fun and why I'm actually into them is You can press your luck in a way that you can't do in a normal speed run race.
Rym: if you're falling behind Take a risk.
Scott: Yep, take a big risk.
Scott: Well, it's like you watching.
Scott: it is sort of like gives the the spectator the feeling of scratching a bunch of lottery tickets.
Scott: Oh, right every time they open a chest.
Scott: It's like who is it gonna be?
Scott: It could just be some garbage or like be the best.
Rym: I get back to your race analogy.
Rym: I'm fine Sam way behind in the f1 like randomizer track.
Rym: Maybe I just accelerate hard into a corner and just hope that there isn't a chicane right on the other side.
Rym: Yep, like I'll go for it.
Rym: I'm behind.
Rym: Anyway, worst case I explode and die, but if it's a straightaway, I might catch up.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So some of these Randomizer things out there have really pushed the limits of what they're randomizing.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes to good extent but sometimes to questionable extent, right?
Scott: So for example, there's a lot of multi-world things going on, right?
Scott: So the there's two different kinds of multi-world cross games.
Scott: Yeah So one of them is is this thing?
Scott: it just so happens apparently by luck that the two biggest randomizer games Super Metroid and link to the past right.
Scott: for some reason one of them takes up one half of the super Nintendo cartridge and the other one take us the other half I. They're both the same chips in the cartridge Just memory wise.
Scott: one is on one half ones on the other so you could put both games in the same cartridge and they don't Really overlap each other.
Scott: so they made it.
Scott: they hacked it up.
Scott: It's super Metroid link to the past randomizer They.
Scott: this useless feels.
Rym: very chess boxing.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: It's very chess boxing.
Scott: Not only you're playing link to the past.
Scott: you walk into like a door.
Scott: You would never go in like the.
Scott: I think it's like the the fortune tellers, huh?
Scott: Useless place to go.
Scott: and you walk in and suddenly Samus walks out a door and you're in Super Metroid.
Scott: and Then Samus goes and fights a boss and grab, you know goes there's a chozo statue.
Scott: They shoot the ball in the chozo statue and it's like a hook shot.
Scott: Yeah They grab the hook shot and now Samus goes in a door.
Scott: that goes like a map room a place Samus a useless place for Samus to go right?
Scott: You don't need a map room.
Scott: Yeah, and suddenly link comes out in hyrule with a hook shot.
Scott: right, and then link goes and opens the treasure chest and It's a super missile.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: that's how that's crazy.
Scott: Right?
Scott: There's like actually very few.
Scott: It's amazing with to watch.
Scott: there are very few humans who can actually play it.
Scott: Right that's thing.
Scott: I'll have a problem in the competitive scene that there's like not enough people who can actually play this damn thing.
Scott: Yeah, right and then at least especially not to a competitive level.
Scott: and then the other kind is they've got these multi-world things where.
Scott: okay I'll play some link to the past and you play some link to the past.
Scott: right and we're gonna generate ROMs together and I'll give you ROM a and I'll take ROM B and We're gonna connect our emulators to the internet.
Scott: and When I pick up I see I see an arrow and I pick up the arrows lying on the ground and it's sometimes I might Just like oh that was your arrow.
Scott: Sometimes it was Rym's arrow.
Scott: Yeah, it's randomized it in such a way that the game is beatable, right?
Scott: It actually logically figures out.
Scott: Okay, we'll put all these items in a place such that all these people can beat the game.
Scott: There make someone was playing a hundred player randomizer.
Scott: Whoa And like if you forfeit and quit it just takes all the items that are in your game and gives them to the people they Belong to because you quit.
Scott: that way they can beat the games.
Rym: What if someone who has your item just sucks They'll hopefully quit.
Rym: So if I suck and I just keep on keeping on.
Rym: I'm just hoarding the item.
Scott: I might just be end up waiting for you for someone to find my stuff and I won't have any locations.
Rym: Check that's.
Scott: somebody finds my item.
Rym: we're in.
Rym: we're past like the early like bleeding edge of this and we're getting into like more amor of a plateau where the Randomizers that I think are the most popular and doing the best are the ones where?
Rym: Game design decisions are being made by the community and it's starting to coalesce into like the right number of people Who have the right sensibility to make these work?
Rym: Like.
Rym: I want to give you example of that because the link to the past randomizer and it like.
Rym: there's a little fact here that Explains what has changed from the original game?
Rym: I want to read some of these front for you.
Rym: Just give you a sense of like how the community has decided to alter the games just to make this work.
Rym: So it isn't just random bullshit.
Rym: That isn't fun.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You're guaranteed to get the digging game item by the 30th dig.
Rym: Yep, you're guaranteed to get the village of outcast chest item on the first attempt.
Rym: Mm-hmm The pyramid and waterfall wishing fairies no longer upgrade your items.
Rym: instead the caves contain two chests each of which account for the usual Upgrades like.
Rym: that's the kind of work people are doing to make this work.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, it's also way.
Scott: it's all once.
Scott: you've played the randomized versions of a lot of these games.
Scott: Also, they cut out because that's mostly speedrunning people who have speedrunning interests making these.
Scott: they cut out a lot of the time wasting Bullshit, so it's actually much more.
Scott: It's it's almost like a convenient version of the game like ah fast text a very minimal text.
Scott: I don't have to wait through cutscenes.
Scott: They've been removed.
Scott: This is great.
Scott: It's like it's like a you don't really if you go back and play the original game.
Scott: You're like Yeah, is this so inconvenient?
Rym: come on just give me the sword.
Rym: give me the sword.
Rym: just give me the fucking sword.
Rym: Let me go.
Rym: Let me go right pop up.
Scott: also, you know The thing is some of these randomized type things.
Scott: right.
Scott: sometimes, you know, cuz it's been randomized the game can end up way easy.
Scott: You get the dream, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, you start playing a game and it's like guess what?
Scott: You got the super powerful weapon right immediately.
Scott: The game is now gonna be way easy and fun and that's hella fun.
Scott: No denying that but sometimes you play this and it's like alright, it's been 50 minutes I've checked a million places and I don't even have a sword yet and I have to go and fight these bad guys with bombs And I have to beat.
Scott: there's nothing.
Scott: there's no item left for me to get except for this boss who has an item.
Scott: I have to fight them with my bow and arrow.
Scott: Yeah, right There's all kinds of crazy shit like that that goes on in randomizers.
Rym: It's got a little random feeling of like old Atari games that have a million modes.
Rym: like there's a million modes these randomizers, but honestly unless you get like Too deep like to where your predilections become increasingly esoteric I suggest you stick to the types of randomizations that the community tends to support.
Scott: Yeah, and you you know just for the super pro ones, right?
Scott: Either level your skills way up to play the or watch the pros or just watch pros and don't bother.
Rym: Yeah The Final Fantasy one.
Rym: what I love the most about it is like the game design changes.
Rym: You can go anywhere like imagine you start with the airship.
Rym: There's a bunch of changes, but you can fight Like when you go to where a boss would be Depending on how you randomize it.
Rym: either any bosses there But whatever boss is there has the level equivalent of the boss that should be there.
Scott: Yep, so you might go to the first boss in the game.
Scott: It might be the last boss in the game.
Scott: Yeah, they might Of the first boss.
Rym: Yeah, you might fight a rubicante But he sucks or you might fight the miss dragon in the giant robot and it's a dangerous fucking miss dragon.
Rym: Yep, you better actually know how to fight that miss dragon.
Scott: Yeah, it's like in the actual regular game.
Rym: You don't really have to know you don't have to worry about like how do I deal with?
Rym: Rubicante if like we're all level one and his spells suck But I also suck like you don't have to think about that kind of situation gives you all these new Challenges right and that's the thing is like I was saying before.
Scott: these are the greatest games there are.
Scott: it's like it would Be really hard to make a brand new game as good as any of these legendary games.
Scott: Right, it'd basically be like and some of that's not game design.
Rym: It's more like it's a genre that doesn't make sense anymore for like modern sensibilities There's.
Scott: I'm just saying it's like it's tough to beat the best of the best, right?
Rym: I mean, there's a reason there's only one chrono trigger game.
Rym: Like no one's made a game like that ever again.
Rym: That was popular.
Scott: No But somehow we can get more playability out of those old games.
Scott: That can.
Scott: that's really hard for any new game even a completely fresh one to compete with.
Rym: people are fucking talking about Like people younger than me are talking about Final Fantasy 4 because of this like.
Rym: That excites me as someone who is old and likes Final Fantasy 4.
Scott: Yeah So every day more and more games are getting randomized.
Scott: has been Crystalis randomizer?
Rym: crystalis won as much as I wanted to like it.
Rym: crystalis is not a good game for that.
Scott: I'm just saying this mario 64 randomizer.
Rym: is there different games?
Scott: Lend themselves to randomization.
Scott: It's sorry or worse than others.
Rym: Like I feel like more drastic changes need to be made to make some of these viable.
Rym: like crystalis I think they need to somehow like remove the grind to make it about map navigation Primarily map navigation and combat like stuff like that, right?
Scott: But you know also if the games aren't that great to begin with yeah, like a randomizing Pizanadu isn't really gonna make it any better.
Rym: Whoo.
Rym: What about uh, dr.
Rym: Chaos?
Scott: You could do a randomized dr.
Scott: Cas very easily.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Chaos basically is already a random.
Rym: I know dr Chaos actually is very like.
Scott: it's not random at all But it's just.
Scott: it feels like you're if you've never played it before.
Scott: it feels like playing a random.
Rym: I feel like I just take a speedrun of dr.
Rym: Chaos as is and just post it and pretend It's a random is like a randomizer and people wouldn't know it would be an easy game to randomize.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't think there's a demand for the head.
Rym: I don't think anyone why?
Rym: I don't think anyone remembers that game.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: so is the thing is like if you're someone who makes games right from that perspective if someone made a randomizer Of your game, right?
Scott: It's sort of like.
Scott: I don't know how to feel about that.
Scott: It's like you could have just done that yourself and then made your game more popular.
Rym: that way Yep, but also I think most randomizers will never become popular All right, and it's gonna come down to like.
Rym: the real takeaway I think is that randomizers are scratching an itch that the world and the entire game industry Just like did not even recognize was there in any meaningful way and it came into the scene completely sideways, right?
Scott: Well, I kept saying for how many years it's like how come you don't make more of the thing that everyone already loves?
Scott: You keep making new different things, you know, we need we want some not too much right but some more of the same.
Scott: Repeat yourself, maybe at least one time Nintendo is making another breath of the wild kind of deal.
Scott: Yeah, it seems like maybe they got the clue.
Scott: It's like yeah if you do if you get a hit Let us hit one or two more times and then it'll get stale.
Scott: then do something.
Scott: move on.
Rym: I need some more.
Rym: give me more - three right but shit like, you know shit.
Scott: That was so good.
Scott: That has never been repeated.
Rym: It's like well now we can do it but I think there's a broader takeaway that I don't know what's gonna happen, but I feel like Something from this randomizer community not now.
Rym: I think it's gonna be years.
Rym: I feel like the eSport that really takes off is gonna be.
Rym: it's gonna take some elements from what is popular about these randomizers coupled with things we haven't envisioned yet and I feel like the eSport is not here yet.
Rym: And this is what I mean.
Scott: I mean the most basic thing right is to take say a common eSport like FPS battle Yeah, and it's like.
Scott: how come?
Scott: I don't got you know It's like we have procedurally generated games and we use them for roguelikes.
Scott: We now you were now procedurally sort of manipulating older games Right to get these single-player experiences.
Scott: Where is the procedurally generated multiplayer experience?
Scott: Right.
Scott: How come there isn't like quake on a random map?
Scott: You've never seen before because it computer just made it.
Scott: Yep How come that doesn't exist?
Scott: I haven't seen it.
Scott: It might exist.
Rym: Well, like it edges the DDR competition where it's a song No one's ever heard before.
Scott: song no one's ever heard before.
Rym: arrows never seen before go up and then the game is just really different Skill than regular DDR.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I am way better at that than I am at like.
Rym: Better at that than I have a better in real D Way better, but the other takeaway might end up being the like The random part in the sense that people can come back from behind.
Rym: I know coming back isn't actually a thing but like you can press your luck and like That's something that doesn't really exist in a lot of the current eSports.
Rym: There's very little press your luck.
Rym: that is effective in eSports.
Scott: Well, you can't press your luck when there's no luck right.
Scott: a lot of these other games Like I said when their knowledge and skill based only.
Scott: it's not about luck It's about how well did you execute on that day?
Rym: Meanwhile, look over the randomizer, right?
Scott: The randomizer is still.
Scott: skill and knowledge still matter a lot.
Scott: If you don't have them, you're not going to win.
Rym: In fact, you need them to know when and how to press your luck, right?
Scott: But luck does suddenly come into it when it's a competition at least and not a. you know.
Scott: You just playing you know, Zelda again - yeah and making it more fun by you know Mixing it up and not just playing the same exact game again.
Rym: But that luck is what makes it a spectator sport and I think that is why Randomizers took off.
Rym: It's that they're fun for the people who play them and fun for the people who watch them.
Scott: Yep, but also you don't get old right?
Scott: And yeah, this is so this perfect.
Rym: There's no three true outcomes.
Rym: Baseball there are not but think of it.
Rym: like hockey Hockey has the.
Rym: you can pull your fucking goalie if you want.
Rym: Yeah, and that adds so much excitement.
Rym: Most of the good randomizers like people do the equivalent of pull their goalie.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I like it pretty much every time I watch a speed running competition of any game.
Rym: Yeah I see some sort of goalie pulling Because you know I saw someone get in that fucking whale and go to the moon and no one else was on the moon.
Scott: You're not?
Scott: you can't necessarily tell how the other players are doing.
Scott: You just had to.
Scott: it's like do I feel behind or do I feel ahead?
Scott: Yeah, am I doing well or doing worse?
Scott: Well, how much time is on the clock?
Scott: How many items do I have?
Scott: How much have I made progress right now?
Rym: Imagine playing this in like a stadium.
Rym: Yeah, and you can't see the other screens.
Rym: like you're just doing your randomizer and suddenly this the crowd starts going crazy And you didn't do anything.
Scott: Well, that's why you can't hear the crowd either.
Rym: Yeah, but that might actually make it even more exciting.
Rym: like suddenly you see the other players.
Scott: That is actually a negative of the competitive speedrunning scene.
Scott: Is that?
Scott: There's a big taboo about calling anyone out for cheating without evidence?
Scott: Usually all the ones I've seen stream have like 20-plus minute delays.
Scott: I'm James is because you know We're racing me and Rimmer racing in a randomizer and I go right and Rym goes left.
Scott: Right if I can see what Rym's up to.
Scott: I see he gets the hammer.
Scott: Well, I just stop what I'm doing.
Scott: I go left.
Scott: Yep, right It's.
Rym: or if he sees that I'm falling behind he knows that he doesn't have to be that risky.
Scott: Like you can play more conservatively Knowing, you know, you both have this because when you're competing you basically make the same exact random seed for both layers Not knowing what the other not having any information about the other player is Absolutely essential.
Scott: You must have that wall up like you're playing bridge.
Scott: No, that's otherwise the whole competitive aspect falls apart.
Rym: But that's where I wonder if in the further evolution like way beyond these randomizers now like eSports stuff Will know will revealing more information about your standing like your positional heuristic and your opponent Be a net positive or net negative for the game as a spectator sport in the long run.
Rym: right now It definitely is a net negative for the way randomizers work.
Rym: But I don't know what the future of game design looks like for that in the future.
Rym: I said in the future twice there because I'm really hungry.
Scott: I'm also really hungry.
Scott: But yeah, if you have never played a randomized game of any kind, right?
Scott: I would recommend looking up your favorite games.
Scott: that obviously not the newest newest games like Any SS NES era, right?
Rym: It's like the newest bar even in 64 games.
Scott: It's like the newer games are harder to randomize because the date you're basically manipulating.
Scott: you're looking at the ROM Technologically and shuffling the data in the ROM and a logical way to keep the game functioning.
Scott: But and consistent and beatable and there's a lot going on there.
Scott: It's not just like, you know, completely random bits, right and that is only you know.
Scott: So think of some of your old favorite games and go out and find a community of people Who are playing those games and have a randomizer?
Scott: obviously the more popular games are gonna have a bigger community of people.
Rym: but if you like like an obscure as any s game and Like say there's a pilot wings randomizer community.
Scott: I don't think there is no definitely not.
Rym: but say there was.
Rym: if You're the person who was so obsessed with pilot wings and you find the ten other people who together made a randomizer You're set.
Scott: it works best with games based on items Obviously right like link to the past.
Rym: There's a read.
Rym: There's a lot of reasons why the link to the past one is like the iconic one, right?
Scott: It's so strange that the link to the past one.
Scott: It's like they didn't make the game to be randomized But somehow it is.
Scott: it's as if it just by chance that the design of that game with the two worlds in the map Yep, it's just like it was as you couldn't make a better one if you try To predict the future of this space.
Scott: right now I'm like, why don't we just handcraft a brand new, you know Two maps cuz I don't in the past and try to make one that's like handcrafted and better?
Scott: It's like you couldn't.
Rym: it's so good cuz I don't think we still fully understand the extent of like what randomizers are Right.
Scott: It's like less than a roguelike where a roguelike randomizes everything like crazy.
Scott: It's like a net hack.
Scott: It's all new dungeon every time man, you know, it's like it's only randomizing certain parts.
Rym: There are games that do that.
Rym: Like.
Rym: there are other kinds of like randomizer procedurally generated games But none of them also have this competitive aspect and the spectator aspect all rolled into one.
Rym: and the overlap with the speedrunning community I think Randomized everything.
Rym: I'm sure there's a net hack speedrun But like the advent of randomizers is something that if you asked me or Scott like on game design stuff 15 years ago Or 10 years ago.
Rym: even not no one could have predicted.
Scott: this has already been going on for a few years Yeah, but no one.
Scott: I want to solve this.
Scott: who made like the first one?
Scott: Yeah, like who came up?
Scott: who decided to do that?
Scott: It was so clever.
Rym: Yeah I feel like what you would find is someone made a rom hack once and like played it with their friends and then later the Scene started independently right at best, but this was like.
Rym: this is not something that the game design world Expected right.
Scott: It's like there been rom hacks for a long time But like even the best most polished awesome rom hacks warrant, you know, like I guess like the Zelda was a call under whatever.
Scott: Oh, yeah Some of those really weren't but they weren't much until now.
Scott: the random the randomized rom hack is suddenly a huge huge deal.
Rym: I tried to play that like what bastard Zelda or whatever?
Rym: the really hard one.
Scott: Anyway, even I was like how hard could it be?
Scott: Fuck this?
Scott: Yeah, I recommend going to watch and/or try to play them.
Scott: Don't worry if you can't beat them.
Scott: Yeah, or beat them quickly Just you know.
Scott: pick one that you were familiar with or maybe you know.
Scott: Actually, if you haven't actually played any of these legendary games, maybe you should do that first regardless of what randomizers.
Rym: But the two will link to.
Rym: is like.
Rym: there's the link to the past ones The one Scott's into and like most people are into that's the big one.
Rym: I'll link to the Final Fantasy one because RPG speedruns and RPG randomizers are a very different ballgame.
Scott: You also write want to check Super Metroid and oh, yeah So it's called smz3 is like I said the combo one.
Scott: We're linked to the past and Metro is Super.
Scott: Metroid are joined at the hip Which is just watch that one.
Scott: You can't play that unless you're mad skilled because both of those games are very hard.
Scott: Yep, they are very hard games.
Scott: So You got to be mad skilled to be able to beat them both together.
Rym: I want to mash up bionic commando and anything.
Rym: What are you randomizing?
Scott: bionic commando?
Rym: Oh, there are items.
Scott: Okay, are they the same kind of items?
Scott: like they unlock areas.
Rym: they unlock areas but there's weapons that unlock areas.
Rym: There's also radio transceivers that unlock areas and the items.
Rym: there's a lot of doors and items can be different places and doors can go To different places.
Rym: you can make it work.
Scott: All right, go you do it.
Rym: I'm gonna look right now before we're in the show and see if anyone made a bionic commander randomizer.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: This Has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights will be read momentarily.
Rym: as you know We have a pretty new audio pipeline and new Equipment, so I'm just let me know.
Rym: Does the show sound better worse the same.
Rym: Is there any audio issue that might be bothering any of you with the current way the show sounds?
Rym: I'm Probably gonna finalize the new pipeline based on some feedback and leave it steady-state for a while But I'm pretty happy with this so far.
Rym: But anyway patreon patrons are Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol Marty Green.
Rym: Yeah, just like a dude guy chartavish and linky G you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: I got in one little fight and my mom got scared.
Rym: Clinton Walton my stady calm.
Rym: J Bants written from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open.
Rym: Lander Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff Mac the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread lily tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Thomas Hahn Shervin von Horl and a whole bunch of people who don't want me to say their name.
Rym: This is our last convention.
Rym: our lives are actually gonna get much less Busy after this meaning we can start making a lot more content doing a lot more stuff.
Rym: You're gonna see more page around things.
Rym: Rym's rants are coming back.
Rym: Remily reviews are coming back.
Rym: all this can be yours.
Rym: We are almost past the densest convention season we have had in the last eight years.
Rym: so now I leave you with Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba Haba.
Scott: But that apart that they're back on top of that ha ha Gonna burn down this hard Baba.