Rym: It's Tuesday January 28th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight time of crisis.
Rym: the Roman Empire in turmoil.
Rym: 235 to 284 ad the board game.
Scott: Let's do this So to be clear crisis.
Rym: this time of crisis game We're gonna talk about is the crisis that almost but didn't destroy the Roman Empire.
Scott: This is it was a crisis, but it was averted.
Rym: Yeah, this is the one that temporarily This is the one that ends when our boy Diocletian comes in and says oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, the guy who comes in is like yo guys listen But way before the aptly named Commodus.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Ah commodus, but after Caesar Nero Audius all those Roman emperors, you know, yeah after them I feel like you've heard of a few of the people here if you like started paid attention and AP Western Civ But otherwise, yeah Anthony and Cleopatra way in the back.
Rym: So, yeah as you notice we're back doing GeekNights pretty regularly Like I told you that hiatus would end and like once the convention season.
Scott: also It's Tuesday the easiest day to do an episode.
Scott: We have like please send ideas for Monday, Thursday, special Everything Wednesday, at least we have a little bit Monday and Thursday.
Scott: We really need stuff.
Rym: Well Wednesday I got a lot more cuz and ideas for Monday and Thursday.
Rym: idea I just I'm powering through the second half of Carolyn Tuesday after doing shows.
Scott: for How many years 15 year we run out of idea?
Rym: Yep, because we do not watch anime every single day like we used to yeah, but I play games Every single week.
Rym: Yeah Well, so, you know not done to get in a meta.
Rym: But we go to a lot of gaming cons and a lot of generic nerd cons.
Scott: Going to an anime con wouldn't give me.
Scott: I don't watch more anime at an enemy con.
Scott: Give me more Wednesday shows.
Rym: it used to talk about con.
Scott: right when I go to a gaming show I play games and then it gives me more Tuesday shows.
Scott: I could go to every I could go.
Rym: We got someone just gave us a really good suggestion.
Rym: Yeah tech news roundup.
Scott: No, I gotta wait two more months.
Rym: So in some games roundup is for March.
Rym: Yeah before we get it's coming up.
Rym: I'm ready You're ready.
Rym: that clock rings once a year.
Rym: I wake up and I'm like, what are we gonna do the Monday show?
Rym: Tech news roundup, is it true?
Rym: and I have to look and double-check the last time we did it and then I say Scott Let's do a tech news roundup and Scott will always say
Scott: so we
Rym: just did one There's no way and then we'll look cuz I deleted the one we just did from the CMS and then we do All right.
Rym: So in some news as you guys know, I still play overwatch.
Rym: like a lot Overwatch is my favorite like, you know You got your games that you play because they're knowing that it.
Scott: when did overwatch come out?
Rym: a few years ago?
Scott: How many years ago?
Scott: like three ish Alright, so I mean I played netrunner for X years.
Scott: You seem to just be playing overwatch for about the same number of years.
Rym: The thing is overwatch for me is like tribes 2 and weapons factory in that if they were still playable I would probably still be playing.
Scott: Well, I think the difference is is that You know netrunner requires significantly more effort to play.
Scott: Yeah Right Whereas overwatch you can just play whenever.
Scott: if I could if there was a way to just played netrunner legit digital not the bullshit Digital and all the fun like you go to a ready room.
Rym: You're like, I want to play.
Scott: There was the fans made one.
Scott: I just thought it was garbage.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and they had a good one and that was I mean Yeah, we play tribes - if we get those executable files on the internet and run a complicated and I probably still be playing it.
Rym: So, you know, yep But the holy grail for me, this is not the holy grail for the game industry.
Rym: This is old man Rym and the kind of game.
Rym: He wants that.
Rym: No one else gives a shit about the genre I miss.
Rym: the most of games that I've liked over my life is First-person shooter team-based capture the flag.
Rym: Oh, yeah like that that shit just gets me going in a way that is The flag IRL is great fun.
Scott: That's why that was what inspired.
Scott: capture the flag in quay Look even like which is just faster.
Scott: capture the flag with rules that are properly enforced on guns.
Rym: It's like even summer camp.
Rym: capture the flag with its vague ass rules Like you don't even have a paintball gun usually still is way fun.
Scott: I always do one thing, you know Is that real?
Scott: capture the flag in real life, but you know a million variants?
Scott: But we always played some sort of variant that involved taking prisoners Of course and the what.
Scott: the quake ones pretty much never have prisoners.
Scott: you kill someone and they respawn.
Scott: Yep Cool to have some sort of digital capture the flag FPS with the prisoner mechanic really Kill someone they're in a jail.
Scott: So now you're rushing the flag or do you rush the prison to bust everyone out?
Rym: so because overwatch is based pretty heavily on games like action quake 2 like it's from that era and In the arcade part of overwatch, they keep making like fun game modes and they try stuff out.
Rym: They keep tweaking and re-releasing different versions of capture the flag and when they first tried it didn't work that well.
Rym: for a lot of Reasons, I don't want to turn the whole show into this but they keep tweaking it.
Rym: They made a new tweak real recently and I think they're on to something.
Scott: What did they do?
Rym: They made it faster.
Scott: Okay, like why don't they just make all overwatch faster?
Rym: So all overwatch is already reasonably fast compared to most.
Rym: FPS is like today quake too fast.
Rym: Nothing's quite too fast it's not fast, but What they did with CTF blitz a new move that's in the arcade like right now.
Rym: They moved the flags closer together.
Rym: Whoa, you're like way closer together.
Rym: They put the flags now Where they own.
Rym: in the normal CTF they had previously.
Rym: the flags are kind of far apart in bases like tradition.
Scott: So is it like an icy world kind of feel.
Rym: it's more like an icy world kind of feels the.
Scott: really you're just like you just Throw it Bigger.
Rym: so the way it works is.
Rym: you know the old like to fort maps is like the base and the flag room.
Rym: They in regular CTF overwatch if the game is a tie the sudden death.
Rym: It's the same map.
Rym: but the flags are like on the bridge.
Rym: really Yeah, they're like on either side either side of the bridge fucking go.
Rym: They basically put the flags in a situation like that from the start.
Rym: They make you get more captures when you die.
Rym: in normal overwatch There's a long respawn timer before you go back in.
Scott: instant respawn instant respawn But you respawn way in the back.
Rym: you respawn way in the back But you also move faster for like 10 seconds after your spawn.
Rym: So it's like old quake to style CTF where if you kill someone they are instantly Running straight back into the action from spawn screaming.
Rym: Okay They made a bunch of other changes.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into the details of but the end result of these tweaks is it's not perfect yet It still has flaws but from my like fairly like deep it Intuitive and mechanical Understanding of CTF games throughout their history.
Rym: This feels the closest to the feelings of old CTF FPS's from the quake one quake two era of anything.
Rym: anyone's made up to this point?
Scott: still not tribes to know.
Rym: Of course, it's not tribes to try to choose the exact opposite flags as far apart.
Rym: Yeah possible.
Scott: All right, my where's the flag?
Scott: Let me use my binoculars.
Scott: Yeah, I seize it.
Rym: Oh you want to get over to the enemy base?
Rym: All right Get someone to spawn a truck.
Scott: you can everybody get into the truck and the game will be over by the time you get there.
Scott: You can use your jetpack.
Scott: That's pretty reasonable.
Scott: Or you can fly in this fighter jet or take a bike.
Rym: my goal in tribes too often was to be a medium guy and Fucking make my way all the way over to the other side and make a tiny base.
Scott: It's like oh the enemies didn't.
Scott: even the map is so big.
Scott: you didn't even see any enemy players.
Scott: But you approach the enemy base and died because it has automated defenses.
Scott: Yeah suck They just shoot at you and you die.
Rym: So in some other news Rocket League is doing the obvious thing that I was surprised they still support.
Scott: Oh, yeah I mean so Rocket League when it was new Did a great job of supporting all the platforms, right?
Scott: It was pretty much on.
Scott: everything is on, you know, PS whatever Xbox PC Even Linux Mac switch is just on everything that could run Rocket League.
Scott: They're like, yes, we will be on every platform and they had crossplay as much as as much as they could.
Scott: they had crossplay I would be on PC and I'd open up Rocket League during the time I played it and lo and behold.
Scott: Oh look this PlayStation people playing against me.
Scott: All right and it was.
Rym: it was like that from the start and I remember people even like making the point and I would kind of argue with Them that yeah, like there's a huge thriving community of Linux and Mac gamers.
Scott: I don't remember anyone saying that but I do.
Scott: but you know There are people those people who do right play on Linux and Mac.
Scott: They don't have a lot of games to choose from.
Scott: Yeah, so the games that they do play right?
Scott: They will be loud about right?
Scott: Yeah It's like oh my god a game is on my Linux I'm playing it like crazy and that's my game.
Scott: and so think I'm all up in.
Scott: so if you're a game developer You're the kind of guy who you play plays games on Linux or Mac.
Scott: You're the kind of person who's loud about it.
Rym: So if you are a game developer and it's a multiplayer game Theoretically by supporting Mac or Linux you'll capture like 90% of that audience, right?
Scott: But because rocket League does have so many players that audience of Mac and Linux Rocket League players is still 0.3% of all active rocket League players 0.3%.
Scott: so I didn't think it, you know is taking them a lot of effort to support those players.
Scott: I cuz it looked to me like they had some sort of really good, you know cross-platform build process.
Rym: You know, they were just you know, but they might have just papered over that with developer effort, right?
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: But apparently it's taking more than zero effort.
Rym: It's costing them more than zero money and it's worth a zero 0.3 right.
Scott: so?
Scott: and it's not a game where you pay for subscriptions game where you buy it and you're done.
Scott: So they're not making any more money from that.
Scott: It's like how many more people on Mac and Linux are buying rocket League.
Scott: They already have it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So it's like yeah, we're gonna stop supporting it.
Scott: So you can still play by yourself or locally with your existing rocket League patch Whatever patch that is or use like wine or boot camp or something.
Scott: Yeah, a new wine version came out recently.
Scott: It's like wine five.
Rym: Wow, and I have not.
Rym: I have not used.
Rym: wine is not an emulator since 1990.
Rym: I don't remember when I last used it.
Rym: No 2002 I I was the wine expert at IBM.
Rym: The point is I made old shit working wine that.
Scott: Yeah, you're not gonna be able to play online once the patch goes out or if it went out already Yeah, I'm gonna have to play on Windows or on a PlayStation.
Rym: The only viable gaming platforms are phones slash mobiles of phones and tablets.
Scott: Hey, can you play rocket League in your phone?
Rym: I don't think I'm just like.
Rym: if you want to play games, it's.
Rym: there's mobile which includes tablets.
Rym: There's the switch, you know consoles switch PlayStation, whatever easy.
Rym: and there's Windows PCs.
Rym: That is it.
Rym: So, uh some other news.
Rym: Pokemon home is not actually technically replacing Pokemon Bank or at least not yet.
Rym: but they announced it.
Rym: they announced all the deal with it and It's interesting because I see like the Twitter Discussion I see about this is like one-third people are like, yes I have a home for all my Pokemon one third of people who were like, but it cost so much money.
Rym: This is bullshit nonsense.
Scott: They charge money from Pokemon Bank.
Scott: Also how do I actually?
Scott: yeah I'd only paid for Pokemon Bank at the start.
Scott: It's I'm down and that was it.
Scott: So I guess I got the free like whatever the period was.
Scott: Yeah, and then I never paid for it again.
Scott: But I have a Pokemon Bank full of spirit tombs somewhere if I can possibly access it.
Rym: So Pokemon Bank was basically the old way to get Pokemon from various Pokemon games into a place that you could then get them Forward right.
Scott: So the original Pokemon the very first Pokemon Gameboy cartridge.
Scott: You could move your Pokemon from the original Pokemon red blue Right into Pokemon gold silver.
Scott: and then I don't there was a cut off at some point but for quite a while they had ways for you to use link cables or DS's with you know a GBA cartridge and a DS cartridge and there were ways to Bringing your Pokemon up and up and up, but there was a cutoff and then they started again.
Rym: And I don't think there was a second cut off until the newest switch game Which I believe you can transfer Pokemon from a third gen game to a fourth gen game provided you own an original Ds or DS light.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah, I there seems like there were.
Scott: there were a few.
Scott: I think there was a point where you couldn't transfer up anymore, but there was a surprising support for transferring your Pokemon.
Rym: You know, you're transferring Pokemon from Gameboy Advance to modern games.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like the goal was to get it to the minimum Pokemon game that could connect to Bank And then you were golden, right?
Scott: Yeah Bank was not Pokemon gold golden.
Scott: Just golden Bank was it until the switch came out and So now they're gonna have Pokemon home.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's just Pokemon Bank on the switch.
Rym: now It seems like people who play Pokemon on the switch to use all the online features Or you got to pay for the Pokemon stuff Nintendo online and on top of this they're actually 16 pay 16 bucks a year for Pokemon home.
Rym: So that comes out like 40 bucks a year and it still limits you to 6000 Pokemon which when I looked at this, that's all I need to you folks that is plenty.
Rym: But according to a third of the people I see on Twitter that is to paraphrase Bullshit, that is harmful to me as a person.
Scott: If you're a pokémaniac, you got more than 6,000 Pokemon.
Rym: if you're a pokémaniac I feel like I mean that's already the premium plan If you need more than 6,000 Pokemon, you need help or Nintendo could offer you a like Platinum plan.
Scott: Nintendo does have a history of increasing the numbers over time.
Scott: Yeah example in Mario maker They always have a limit on how many levels you can upload because at the start there's so many players Right and everyone's uploading levels like crazy, but then as players drop off the game They're like, okay anyone who's still playing Mario maker will increase your level.
Scott: upload limit.
Scott: Yeah, they've done it already like two or three times.
Scott: So I feel like for Pokemon home.
Scott: It's gonna be like, okay 6,000.
Scott: Yeah, all right, who's still playing Pokemon?
Scott: 10,000?
Scott: All right, who's still playing 20,000?
Rym: So it looks like if you don't pay you can't take Pokemon from Pokemon Bank and even put them in here.
Rym: Ah, and you can have up to 30 Pokemon in their total.
Rym: You can't use any.
Scott: but if you're not if you're not transferring Pokemon from old Pokemon to new What does Pokemon home even do?
Rym: trading with other people who play the switch Pokemon is basically you can just do that with the switch Pokemon.
Scott: why do you need Pokemon home?
Rym: You can't do like the wonder trade that's built into home.
Rym: Okay, they may have rooms or you can just like set up a little carpet and be like I got a Pikachu if anyone wants It okay.
Rym: And they got this judge function Which you won't get to use.
Rym: that will tell you how strong the Pokemon is.
Rym: They added a bunch of features that You need if you're Pokemon, yeah, you.
Rym: basically if you're serious about Pokemon I feel like what you need to do is pay for Pokemon premium.
Rym: paper Pokemon on premium.
Rym: Use the free month.
Rym: They're giving everyone in Pokemon Bank to use Bank.
Rym: If you haven't used it before they're gonna give everyone a month free on Pokemon Bank.
Rym: Get every Pokemon you got in the world into Bank.
Rym: get every Pokemon and Bank into home.
Rym: Cancel Bank home forever and then someday they'll be like, I don't know Pokemon But what about it Pokemon glue factor and you move them in?
Scott: So the new Pokemon Pokemon sword shield doesn't support every Pokemon ever.
Rym: so you can put them all.
Scott: Pokemon Bank supports as far as I'm aware every Pokemon every Pokemon except for the ones that are new in sword shield.
Rym: Yep, so, I don't know if you could.
Rym: can you transfer like a missing no or a broken boy?
Scott: There's a Pokemon say my guy Spiritomb who's not in Pokemon sword shield is right.
Scott: You can hang on to him until a future Pokemon supports it I can put him in Pokemon home, even though Pokemon sword shield does not support spirit.
Rym: Yep, it just means you can't put him into sword shield.
Scott: Aha, but I can.
Scott: I can save my spiritomb from from the the grave of Pokemon Bank after it gets robbed.
Rym: Yeah, basically if they're still in there Yeah transfers their own way true.
Rym: You can read all the details cuz we're not gonna.
Rym: I'm not gonna explain to you exactly how this works cuz it's not something I'll use.
Rym: I don't ever transfer Pokemon between games.
Scott: I've done it in my past.
Rym: I have done it.
Rym: I will never do it in the future.
Scott: I don't think it's gonna happen.
Rym: I'll just buy.
Rym: just play new Pokemon games.
Rym: Like what's that?
Rym: What's that Pokemon?
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: I might go and just look to see how it see how it does.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you can poke at it for free.
Scott: Yeah, I might just poke it when I get home like get my Brush the dust off my D.
Rym: Yeah, plus you'll get a moment there.
Rym: you get a month free of Bank.
Rym: What?
Rym: the one thing that I find interesting what I don't know what Nintendo will do Sam I do get a month free of Bank just no matter what.
Scott: or do you get a month free of Bank if you pay for?
Rym: Not sure, okay, but I wonder say I put 6,000 Pokemon in Pokemon home and I'm paying this money now, right?
Rym: If I stop paying to my Pokemon, I'll die.
Rym: just is gone.
Scott: I'm well gonna find out.
Scott: cuz I stopped paying for bang cuz Nintendo.
Rym: This is this is one of those ways like with certain unnamed MMORPGs you can basically extort someone into paying for this thing forever.
Rym: So their Pokemon don't disappear even if they don't actually play Pokemon anymore.
Rym: In some other news we haven't actually talked about this.
Rym: it's been the news for a while, but half-life Not three is coming out, right?
Rym: So they're making a game that is not half-life 3, but it's also half-life 3.
Rym: It's called half-life Alex.
Scott: I guess you play as Alex the other character from half-life 2.
Scott: Yeah, I decide the the sidekick girl and it's a VR only game and it looks great.
Rym: They're trying to push their VRs their steam valve VRs Yep, which not to the V the way the VR landscape right now is.
Rym: basically there's the normal VR Which is basically like the oculus stuff like that kind of thing.
Rym: Basically Valve is going with their index, which is like the high-end VR, but it's not really.
Rym: I don't think it's materially better.
Rym: I don't think there are significant experiences you can make with this upper-end VR that you can't make with like an oculus quest oculus Like rift oculus s type thing.
Scott: I guess it's gonna be like prequel to half-life 2 like what was she up to before?
Rym: Gordon Friedman was on yeah Which this is sort of a divide.
Rym: we even saw in the Ignites forum where it seems like there are some people who?
Rym: Primarily want a more half-life content because they care about like the lore and the proper right.
Scott: So we'll see.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: I don't care about the lore of half-life at all.
Scott: No, it's like but like.
Scott: what was the deal with the g-man?
Scott: I don't give a shit, right?
Scott: But the point is half-life 2 episode 2 whatever ended on a crazy cliffhanger.
Rym: But I already don't care like.
Rym: I just don't care about what happens.
Rym: I just want more games that do the mechanical type of cinematic gameplay Storytelling that half-life games do.
Rym: the proper nouns mean nothing to me at this point.
Scott: Yep but also It's interesting that valve is doing this right and not half-life 3 When valve has had like so many pretty much all their recent attempts since half-life 2 ended to make games besides dota 2 No, and besides counter-strike, but even sort of counter-strike and even worse.
Rym: based on my Like the people who have left valve over the years and talked about what it's like to work there I don't feel like valve is able to retain good game design.
Scott: No, so it's like their artifact thing.
Scott: Remember that fiasco?
Scott: So that game hasn't been updated in a year.
Scott: right?
Scott: counter-strike for all the fact that it's still alive has Tons of fiascoes going on with gambling like like even the worst possible game we talk about like.
Scott: Oh, yeah All these other loot box games is children gambling like counter-strike is even more literal gambling.
Rym: But also valve didn't make the original counter-strike.
Rym: They bought it, right?
Scott: You know, they got their dota.
Scott: they got their you know, their dota Underlords whatever.
Scott: I don't know if anyone's playing that still right there.
Scott: They're their auto chess version.
Scott: It seems like the League of Legends auto chess version has become the champion.
Scott: League of Legends also has a new card game That seems like is that gonna beat?
Scott: Hearthstone and you know, we obviously artifact isn't in the in the race anymore EBD, right.
Scott: It seems like the League of Legends or people are making all that riot.
Rym: Yeah, but there's some controversies about riot that have escalated recently, but I'm just talking about in terms of success.
Scott: They seem to be making these successful.
Scott: PC games.
Scott: Valve and Blizzard have fallen off and riot has taken their.
Scott: they used to have just one game League of Legends and now that they Made an auto chess and they made a card game Yeah, and it seems like they're branching out and being like, alright, we're the biggest game in town We can.
Scott: you know valve is weak, you know Blizzard is weak.
Scott: I guess attack while they're down.
Rym: what I trust about this game if nothing else is that Based it valve does not tend to release games like this.
Rym: Like they're not gonna risk fucking up their half-life franchise because half-life 3 They only risked it like several times.
Rym: Well, I mean they made it well, they made half-life 1. that was a risk And it paid out.
Rym: they made half-life 2. that was a risk.
Rym: that it paid out.
Rym: The portal is adjacent.
Rym: that paid out Half-life 3. if they fuck it up like that kind of ends the franchise.
Scott: the fortress 2 that you're left for deads.
Scott: Yeah That's well so but I did.
Rym: but I feel like the fact that they're making a half-life game means that They're.
Rym: I feel like they're gonna give it their all and I feel like this game is has the potential to be one of the few games that will take the fullest advantage of the current capabilities of Consumer accessible home VR and make one of the best possible games you can make.
Scott: I think it's gonna be a game that You don't know shit about VR.
Rym: So I'm really curious what you think.
Scott: I think it's obviously it's gonna be FPS, right?
Scott: They're gonna put lots of like the way that half-life 2 had all like those physics Puzzles gonna be a lot of like hand manipulation puzzles are gonna have Like, you know VR stuff.
Scott: that's you know, sort of scooby-dooed in to the to the half-life world.
Rym: Well, I think it'll be mostly that you'll be in a room figure deal with the room move on.
Scott: Yep It's good.
Rym: That's how the game probably also some rail shooter type elements.
Scott: It's basically that's what's gonna be like which I'm into.
Rym: I also don't.
Scott: I'm also guessing that this game will not be long.
Scott: Oh, no, that's that's like one and two were long.
Scott: I think it will be at most the length of one of those half-life episode have like two episodes.
Scott: Yeah, which will be the longest it could possibly be.
Rym: That's the right.
Rym: a lot of people in our game.
Scott: I think a lot of people get this play it be done with it and then put their VR back in the closet.
Rym: Yeah, well, it'll be like the Rick and Morty game, which is also one of these like surprisingly One of the best VR experiences anyone's ever made a lot of competition.
Rym: There's there's about 12 like great VR experiences Available for consumers that you can just buy.
Rym: it's still a hobbyist like so it's like an Atari Jaguar.
Rym: It's edging into the like I said the expanded market.
Rym: I think that's gonna grow rapidly.
Rym: still.
Rym: There's a lot of good stuff in pipelines of various company.
Scott: It's gonna be more like an Atari Jaguar.
Rym: see I disagree strongly But you've never even done modern VR's.
Rym: you have no idea what it's like.
Rym: You can take Scott's opinion with the Ignorant grain of salt that you need to but I'll play this game.
Rym: Scott could play this game.
Rym: I own two VR headsets.
Rym: Scott could just try this game, but I'll probably refuse to.
Rym: thus He won't even be able to talk about it, but I think I'll be fine without playing this game.
Scott: There's a lot of other games.
Scott: I also have not played.
Rym: I know I Shockingly like.
Rym: of all those games overwatch is the one you'd probably like the most.
Scott: yeah, no, I don't play that.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: why would I play that game?
Rym: So what?
Rym: what kind of game do you want?
Scott: what game do I want?
Rym: yeah like what game are you?
Rym: what game would make you?
Rym: Excited I don't feel like you get a game about games anymore.
Scott: I get excited about a game That is nothing like any previous game.
Scott: I don't want to see a game That's just more of a same old.
Rym: You know you just don't want more tribes to know there's what previous game.
Scott: There's no other game.
Scott: That's tribes to right now.
Rym: Okay, but you've played tribes - so why just play a better play tribe super.
Scott: such a brief moment in time You go look tribes - existed for mere months, and I've been alive for many years.
Rym: We played it for about a year and a half before it completely died barely.
Scott: it came out late freshman year and Died early sophomore year.
Rym: No died a late soft.
Rym: We played it a lot in the old apartment.
Rym: I did not go look at the timeline Yeah, but I know how much I played it tribes - did not live long, but it was still there.
Rym: We I also kept playing it long after you gave up.
Scott: It did not live long.
Scott: it was gone by the time in some So he couldn't play it anymore before we get on to reviewing some games.
Rym: so there's a lot going on in the eSports and straight eSports streaming and Like streamer streaming markets out there like the twitch youtube gaming all that stuff.
Rym: There's way too much to talk about but the one I think we need to talk about that's the biggest news.
Rym: All the Activision Blizzard things the Overwatch League Call of Duty League Hearthstone everything is Leaving twitch.
Scott: now that the contracts up YouTube exclusive, and if they had a contract with - it.
Rym: Yeah, there's that there was a exclusive okay?
Scott: But the point is right.
Rym: you get the impression that they were just waiting for this contract to expire.
Scott: well the point is You know the streaming world started out where it was all about the platform.
Rym: It's pretty much spent 90 million dollars for the exclusive rights to the first two seasons of overwatch.
Scott: Well, it was pretty much just twitch right in the in the early days.
Scott: everyone right.
Scott: there was no other competition and when competition appeared in the form of YouTube At YouTube it's pretty much YouTube Facebook, and then mixer came.
Scott: you know Microsoft right.
Scott: so all the big boys you got Amazon Google Microsoft and Facebook all four of those are in the streaming video game Competition realm and twitch was just the king because it was the oldest and everyone was there.
Scott: Yeah So it in the earliest days everyone who all the content makers the streamers whether you were pro or just some kid in your house Where you got to be on twitch because that's where the people were.
Scott: yep, right.
Scott: so everyone went to twitch.
Scott: But now ninja right for whatever you got to say about the dude ninja and whatever lot of fans.
Scott: He signed that deal with mixer right to leave twitch and all accounts are right.
Rym: that like Decimated the viewership on twitch across the board.
Scott: basically people who were on Twitch right.
Scott: some of them stayed watching twitch, but went to watch other people.
Scott: some of them followed.
Scott: They were just ninja fans.
Scott: They didn't care where ninja was.
Scott: they were such ninja fans.
Scott: They follow him wherever he goes.
Scott: So that's why mixer was.
Scott: Microsoft was willing to make an exclusive deal with Pam.
Scott: a lot of money.
Scott: Get those people to go to mixer.
Scott: so on mixer.
Scott: He has less eyeballs than he had on twitch, but he's got a bunch of you know luxury and his life is easier.
Scott: He doesn't have to stream like crazy and get subs because he's got the money from the exclusive deal.
Scott: Right and that seems to be why a lot of the individual streamers have you know sign these deals so easily because it's like ah I don't have to beg for subs.
Scott: You know I can live off this.
Scott: you know regular safe money.
Scott: I'm secure Right you know I don't have to have such a grueling streaming schedule and play games I don't want to play.
Scott: their life is more comfortable right It's a really good deal for them.
Scott: So you can't blame them.
Scott: But that when ninja did it and it worked out that opened the floodgates and made people realize aha This is the point at which it's no longer.
Scott: the platform owns the eyeballs and you the con talent.
Scott: Right and the talent was going to where the eyeballs were to try to.
Scott: you know fight over the eyeball pie.
Scott: that twitch was.
Scott: Now it's people are there to see.
Scott: you know the show right whoever it is whether it's overwatch league or ninja or someone else and They'll just watch whatever channel they happen to be on it.
Scott: Yeah, you saw the same thing with like Netflix like everyone has Netflix so everyone had to get the show on Netflix.
Scott: now There's other things to go to.
Scott: yeah, so everyone goes to where the show they want to watch is they don't know one.
Scott: There's no one who's like a Netflix fanboy who's like Netflix?
Scott: good You know the same way that like they're super Nintendo agenda seems like though.
Rym: There's two things going on here because overwatch league also It seems like one of the reasons they wanted to switch was that twitch only has about 15 million active users.
Rym: like that's the kind of the the Addressable audience of twitch today and YouTube has about 200 million.
Scott: Well, that's you're counting all of YouTube.
Scott: You know, if you count only people on YouTube who watch Streaming games on YouTube.
Scott: Yes much much much.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: That's why I said addressable market not active market or industry stuff.
Rym: so I Suspect that Blizzard Activision Blizzard because it's not just the Blizzard games.
Rym: It's like all that.
Rym: Call of Duty is part of this.
Rym: They want to have their eSports on a broader more mass-market platform.
Rym: That's more like Recommendations for it and the algorithms will hit like regular old sports fans, right?
Scott: But here's the thing is that you know, you would think it seems obvious right.
Scott: almost everyone on Twitch has a YouTube channel Yeah, and they post their clips to you.
Rym: Like I don't watch a DDQ anywhere but YouTube.
Scott: I just wait for the VODs on just about every twitch streamer, you know takes clips and puts them on YouTube and people who are some people only follow.
Scott: they'll follow a streamer like ninja on like.
Scott: I don't think ninja has stuff on YouTube anymore if Did.
Scott: but take for example, well Andy the the link to the past randomizer.
Scott: Oh, yeah, right He's got.
Scott: Andy has a YouTube.
Scott: All right, and they're.
Scott: they actually make jokes in like the twitch chat.
Scott: They'd be like, oh this twitch they'll go in the twitch chat and be like, is that YouTube Andy?
Scott: And they'll be like twitch Andy right and there's people though who like only watch him on YouTube.
Scott: Yeah, only watch him on Twitch care about him so much.
Scott: They follow him on both right and the thinking is there's so many people Watch cuz like you're a streamer You're making pretty much just as much money from people watching your clips on YouTube as you are from your twitch subs.
Scott: Right sort of an even deal maybe.
Rym: And I think it's a lot easier to make money on YouTube because of the ad stuff that I don't want to get into right now.
Scott: Could be who knows?
Scott: Well, there's Streamer as your as your profession.
Scott: you you want both of those income streams.
Scott: You want your twitch streamers and your subs and you want your YouTube clip, you know monies also, right?
Scott: And the thing is you think be obvious that you'd be able to translate that Audience of people who watch clips of streamers on YouTube to then click on like a related thing.
Scott: You know you pop up on the side.
Scott: You're watching a clip of someone who streamed yesterday and their YouTube streamer and there's like a thing like hey They're live now bro.
Scott: Click here.
Scott: Yeah, but you think that's so obvious.
Scott: it would work But it doesn't seem like it has worked.
Scott: not a lot of people watch live Streaming games on YouTube.
Scott: It's way smaller than it's.
Scott: feels like it's smaller than I don't have numbers.
Scott: Well, it feels way smaller than even like the Facebook gaming in the mixer.
Scott: It feels like YouTube's in last place.
Rym: So there's even more here.
Rym: There's an area where twitch just cannot compete.
Rym: part of the move.
Rym: Is that?
Rym: Activision Blizzard is also gonna host all the shit for the live streaming and the tournaments and the eSports in the Google Cloud and the Google Cloud will drive the streaming through YouTube.
Rym: Twitch does not have a cloud platform.
Rym: You can host your infrastructure.
Rym: They do.
Scott: It's Amazon Web Services.
Rym: Yeah It's not this.
Rym: it's not quite the same integration level.
Rym: Google appears to be providing services on top of that Like they're doing something here and they're integrating the ad network and AI in a way that might be ominous.
Rym: Now I'm reading the article.
Rym: in addition Blizzard plans to use Google AI for her ads.
Rym: quote.
Rym: players will have the optimal Personalized interactions as Activision Blizzard contacting can tap into Google cloud in AI tools to offer curated recommendations for in-game offers and Differentiated gaming.
Scott: I don't see it as I don't feel like any of the platforms except are Technologically better or worse than others.
Scott: I mean the Facebook obvious is the worst interface cuz.
Scott: yeah Facebook II.
Scott: but I mean Why did they go with Google?
Scott: I don't think it's because Google's better.
Scott: I think it's because there was probably a bidding war for this contract Google won.
Scott: It's hard to say because It's just how these things do.
Scott: yeah, it's which would have paid more money to keep them.
Scott: they would have stayed right?
Rym: Yeah, but I think I think Google offered in send you know, those incentives are part of the.
Scott: you know They're half of the deal.
Rym: But it looks.
Rym: it does look like Activision Blizzard awful also saw more value in being on YouTube Based on a bunch of the commentary.
Rym: I'm seeing here.
Scott: What are the point?
Rym: I mean, this is new enough news where I don't have any like insight.
Rym: I haven't talked to anyone.
Rym: I'm going off a Kotaku article.
Scott: I think that the main phone.
Rym: I mean this article was posted today at 4 30 p.m.
Scott: Yeah, the main point is not that one streaming platform is better than the other.
Scott: That's like saying one TV channel is bedding the other.
Scott: they're all just channels, right?
Scott: It's that the we have now reached this breaking point.
Rym: We are well, although you know, they are their ecosystems.
Scott: We are definitely past the point at which the platform is no longer the eyeball holder.
Scott: platforms now must fight over the content The contents.
Rym: the the streamer or the content makers are now the eyeball holders in this realm Which gives all the platforms even less reason to support non monetizable tiny streamers in any real capacity.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So it hasn't stopped, you know any social media site from letting Whoever the hell post tweets.
Rym: Yeah God total aside.
Rym: But you all you young kids need to remember that the only reason email works at all is that machines, you never see block 99.99% of all emails anyone ever sends you.
Rym: Mm-hmm Twitter and all social media needs to do the same thing and block 99.99% of all posted content for any from anyone ever seeing it but I digress cuz it's time for Things of the day.
Rym: I think I've linked a big Clive a couple of times in the past But he's the guy who will take apart like dodgy Chinese electronics He buys off eBay and talks about how dangerous they are.
Rym: He'll like look at circuit board like it's really fun channel.
Rym: He'll blow stuff up.
Rym: But he posted something that was so amazing and I watched this whole video and I'm still dumbfounded.
Rym: this fucking thing exists.
Rym: So now he's reviewing MREs from armies around Europe and the world.
Rym: Okay, like I got a Lithuanian MRE.
Scott: It's about a year expired But as well expired I wouldn't eat it, but well, it depends.
Scott: but the point is I mean It's probably gonna have like Lithuanian kind of food.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, these videos are great.
Rym: Like these army ration videos are already like you got like an Indian one.
Scott: It's like those aren't too different from like the bags of Indian food you get at the grocery.
Rym: I've gotten it eaten MREs before they're there.
Rym: Sometimes they're an experience.
Scott: I mean, they can't be that much different from like airplane food.
Scott: Uh, they're probably better than airplane.
Rym: Problem is they're richer.
Rym: Yeah and you need a lot of nutrition because you're military ing and MREs are the ones that you tend to eat like in Combat like that night while you're still like fighting like that kind of thing.
Rym: So but this video is a Scottish Army ration.
Rym: It's the winter calorie.
Scott: Is it full of haggis?
Rym: All right, Scott No, it definitely has had.
Rym: it's actually just ramen.
Rym: Oh But yeah, duh This is not.
Scott: I mean it can't be a good thing of the day of the Scottish Army ration doesn't have haggis.
Rym: So it's a winter ration meaning.
Rym: It's extremely high calorie haggis.
Rym: Uh What do you think it uses to heat up the food?
Scott: because it's MRE has to be completely self-contained, you know in In Japan, they have those things that are illegal.
Rym: in the US where you like pull the string And yeah, it's a lot of MREs use different kinds of things like that that kind of thing.
Rym: No, this one's fucking radioactive powered.
Scott: what?
Rym: yeah, what.
Rym: indeed watch this video.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: This is a radio a Radiation powered.
Scott: you can't hurry.
Rym: Yes, you can.
Rym: I kind of want one.
Rym: It's amazing.
Scott: What?
Scott: why don't you buy a whole bunch of them?
Rym: And then yeah, you get this radioactive thing.
Rym: you drop it in your ramen.
Rym: You can just cook ramen anywhere.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: Yeah, it's reusable.
Scott: Oh, it has some iron bruh.
Rym: It has oh my god Comes with like a bottle of whiskey some iron bruh.
Scott: There was something Scottish in there.
Rym: Yeah, I saw the iron.
Scott: Well, it's funny not Eminem the best Eminem.
Rym: Yeah Emily and I were watching this and we were like their Trident ingot radiator ration heater fucking radioactive shit What the fuck?
Rym: Yeah, it's amazing.
Scott: Wait, can we?
Scott: why don't we search on eBay for Trident ingot?
Rym: Yeah, I kind of want to get one like.
Scott: that would be quite a lot of them and then someone will pay as a visit.
Rym: Kind of want to get just one.
Rym: Cuz that would be a. that's a party.
Rym: You know the the party drink of Europe.
Scott: eat your own food with that.
Rym: like if you're at a cocktail party and you're like Oh, let me heat my tea and you pull up on a fucking radioactive heater.
Rym: I'm gonna heat my tea with this thing.
Rym: All you.
Rym: while we were watching this I joked with Emily like I wonder if it comes with whiskey.
Rym: And then of course it came with whiskey.
Rym: and then I was like, well, it didn't come with any iron brew.
Rym: And then sure enough he's like what do we have here?
Scott: So I mean I called the haggis.
Scott: I mean, I didn't think of iron brew until I saw it and I'm like, yeah, I was laughing so hard I had to rewind the video.
Rym: So what's your thing of the day?
Scott: So you may remember back in the day, right?
Scott: There was a. it was a series of animated shorts the Senpai Club.
Scott: Oh, yeah By animation pair of people named make babies make baby tightness, right?
Scott: So I was supporting.
Scott: make babies on patreon right like a dollar.
Rym: what I forgot all about him.
Rym: Their last video was 11 months ago.
Scott: Trion recently added this feature.
Scott: That is a very tight integration with discord.
Rym: Oh, yeah I've we.
Scott: I was thinking about using that and what it does is basically if you are Patreoning a patronus, right and they set up a discord and you link your.
Scott: I linked my discord to my patreon account.
Scott: Anytime anyone that I patronize makes a discord and links it to their patreon channel I'm automatically joined and inserted into their discord server.
Scott: Yeah without even asking for it.
Scott: and as a result once this feature was Established like I opened up discord and suddenly I was added to like a pile of server.
Scott: Oh, I was like, ah, well who had it?
Scott: Well, I'm I'm like.
Scott: am I logged into the wrong account?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: I realized patreon added me to all these discord servers.
Rym: So all these communities sort of formed and like some of them are rocking but it seems to have worked.
Scott: There was actually one discord I was in already that I was patronizing and before the feature was implemented And then when the feature came online suddenly a pile of users appeared.
Scott: Yeah, right but yeah, so Suddenly I was in the make babies discord just out of nowhere and I was like, oh, I guess it's got to be a good Community of people.
Scott: It's not that many people I guess but I was like, hey I guess this activity going on in that realm that you know, I thought was lost right.
Scott: and then suddenly Make babies posted this video on their YouTube channel uploaded two days ago about two days ago called menagerie.
Scott: Oh my god, this looks so cute, right and it's a short Hilarious animation that seems to have been done as seems like a student team animation kind of deal But it is very high quality.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait goblins.
Scott: All right, right and The make babies person worked on this.
Scott: Yeah made for another three-day animation Jam at goblins Alright, so I don't know if this so it's made for a jam.
Scott: okay, I don't know when it was made, but it is very well made very hilarious and Worth watching whether you like, you know Senpai Club or not because it's nothing to do with Senpai Club other than that one of the creators is involved.
Rym: I'm into this Scott.
Scott: how long is the video?
Scott: It's like two minutes.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the funniest two minutes You'll have today.
Rym: Scott links me to this and he's like, it's my thing today and I look at it like, okay This looks cute.
Rym: Then.
Rym: He's like look at look at it and I keep looking at it.
Rym: Then I see the YouTube channel like make make babies big baby.
Scott: Whoa How is bad before in the meta moment?
Rym: We are back from back south.
Rym: the video of our panel from back.
Rym: So the 41 table top games you must play is on YouTube.
Rym: The slides are linked.
Rym: The list is linked from the YouTube.
Rym: It's all there.
Scott: You can just watch it.
Rym: the schedule for PAX East is live at East dot pack site calm and we are doing a panel That will be new to a lot of people at PAX East.
Scott: Hey, we did it.
Scott: We did this panel once at.
Rym: this is one of my favorite panels we've done in recent memory.
Rym: Yeah, this panel unplug.
Scott: No, we don't plugged unplug.
Rym: We did it But it's a guy I like the content of this panel a lot.
Rym: like the moral is good The slides are good.
Rym: Like I love doing this.
Scott: It's not a clickbait panel.
Scott: It's a good panel.
Rym: It's all but it has a clickbait title that'll fill the room.
Scott: It's not that clickbait.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: take your fucking turn.
Rym: I feel like that'll that brought people in.
Rym: but more importantly It means that we already have a good YouTube video of this.
Rym: so we don't have to bring any of our cameras to PAX East.
Rym: Okay, so then yeah, so if you have not seen our panel take your fucking turn.
Rym: It's just on YouTube.
Rym: But for people have no idea who we are who just go to PAX East at 11 30 a.m.
Rym: On Saturday at PAX East we in the bumblebee theater.
Rym: We will be doing take your fucking turn.
Rym: It'll be a good time.
Rym: I Don't even want to have to think about that.
Scott: I have not seen too many people below the age of 13 at our panel
Rym: now of a plus
Scott: packs and I don't think anyone even notice
Rym: that that the the hosts of facts Mike and Jerry in the Opening address to the convention which is not flagged 13 plus they had a word fuck at least a thousand times.
Rym: So I feel like we're good there.
Rym: Otherwise PAX East will be lit.
Rym: Scott and I and most of our friends except a couple of them I see you will be enforcing in the evening So you will not see us between 6 and midnight unless you hang out in the respective areas that we enforce.
Scott: I see a lot of people what I'm.
Rym: I do see a lot of people what I'm.
Rym: it is a scary number of Geek guides.
Rym: fans like come up to the main theater entrance because usually all but one of the nights I basically run the entrance by myself for like hours and hours and hours at a time.
Scott: Lotta listeners come up and hang out which is I usually see people in line when they're checking in and checking out their board game.
Rym: Yeah, so, uh, yeah, we'll see you there.
Rym: And now let's talk about a board.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: And the GeekNights book a book is the tale of Genji.
Rym: Just read it.
Rym: It's about Genji.
Rym: It's kind of a while Not that smart Maybe is it?
Rym: you'll see it Genji.
Rym: I Feel like the whole Everything I've read so far is just kind of throwing shade at Genji by Showing Genji being Genji and everyone else.
Rym: everyone I've met who was not Genji seems like a better person than Genji.
Rym: All right Time of crisis the Roman Empire in turmoil, right?
Scott: So our friends bring this grog nard looking war game out.
Rym: Well, the box looks like your grog nard work.
Scott: It's a GMT game.
Scott: those that's the company that makes the grog nard war game.
Rym: Yep, right.
Scott: So you're looking at this thing and you're like, yeah, this is not you know, what's this gonna be like, right?
Rym: What if I told you it is a deck builder?
Rym: Yep, like Dominion But it's a deck builder where every turn at the end of your turn you take pick up your entire draw deck Choose the five cards you want to draw and put the rest of your draw deck back down, right?
Scott: So that's that's a real work of genius.
Scott: right thing about Dominion, right?
Scott: So Dominion is the like the first real deck builder, right?
Scott: And it's sort of set the stage for all other deck builders And all they all follow the basic template and nothing has been better than opinion.
Scott: You have a deck, right?
Scott: It starts out with just a few cards.
Scott: you draw some you play them all you put them on the discard Acquire more cards that also go in the discard and then you draw more.
Scott: but your draw you shuffle and draw randomly.
Scott: It's like well, what if you could just stack the deck and draw whatever five you wanted it, but everyone's stacking the deck?
Scott: Well, it's not that everyone's stacking the deck.
Scott: It's that okay, you're stacking the deck.
Scott: So for people out there who obviously are more likely to have played Dominion Imagine you're stacking the deck in Dominion.
Scott: turn one fucking five coppers.
Scott: Yeah, turn two.
Rym: what two coppers in three notes.
Rym: It's like if you blow your load on a big turn you're aft until that discard reshuffle.
Scott: What can you do?
Scott: It's like okay, and then you shuffle again.
Scott: See then you are.
Scott: you got mine.
Scott: now I do it again.
Scott: All right, I'm gonna do four coppers and the village that I bought or whatever, you know Whatever card it was that I bought right?
Scott: it's like.
Scott: but then you get to the end of your deck and your discard is full of all the good cars that you stacked to make beautiful hands.
Scott: and Dominion is a little different because you can do the infinite draws.
Scott: Yeah, so stacking your deck would be ultra powerful, but There's another thing.
Scott: you can't do that in this.
Rym: so there's nothing that lets you draw cards during your turn.
Scott: So stacking your deck in this game It removes randomness, which is actually good to make some more game of skill and you it doesn't really help you cheat.
Scott: It's not OP because if you give yourself a strong turn Then you you start to go through the whole deck before you can access the discard pile.
Scott: You're gonna have to have a weak turn and it's about choosing.
Scott: All right, maybe I'll take the weak turn on purpose.
Scott: Maybe I'll try to mix the turns together Right.
Scott: The other thing is that this text on some of the cards that does stuff, right?
Scott: But really what?
Rym: the cards are three currencies.
Scott: there are three different currencies influenced with the people influence with the Senate influence with the Military and those three currencies are used to buy actions.
Scott: Which are the real act?
Scott: you have like a menu of actions that all cost action points.
Scott: some of them cause yellow some cost red and some cause blue and Most of them cost at least two.
Scott: I don't think many of the actions cost one.
Scott: So it's like if you're you know, as you stack your deck, okay, I want to do this blue action.
Scott: So I'll take two blue cards in my hand.
Scott: I want to do that red action.
Scott: Oh, I bought a strong red card earlier in the game.
Scott: That is on its own worth to red.
Scott: I'll put that in my hand and I want to do this yellow action.
Scott: Well that cost three yellow.
Scott: Well, I can't put six cards.
Scott: So you sort of like plan your next turn, right?
Scott: You're picking the action points you need in currency from your deck of what's left of it.
Rym: Anyway, but and here's where the game gets fascinating Like this is what makes this game good.
Rym: and why like we played it multiple times that it packs When we could have played other new games.
Rym: like it's rare.
Rym: We want to play the same game.
Scott: We played it one and a half times.
Rym: We pretty much got to the end of that one game.
Rym: It was oh it was over the writing was on the wall And I would play it a third time like I would play this again.
Rym: I like this game a lot, but the deck building in this game is actually a Rondel builder that just happens to use cards.
Rym: You're basically just building a Rondel Yeah, and you're filling it in in front of you.
Rym: You're basically and the brilliance of this is that it basically makes the game have a very real-world Wargame like abstraction because the games at essence really kind of a war game.
Rym: Basically, I make my plan at the end of my turn.
Rym: so I look at the board.
Rym: I think about the things I want to do.
Rym: I could make a really complex plan where I have the exact number of points From my hand for the next turn to do something specific and powerful, but that might not work out.
Rym: If someone attacks me that I didn't expect barbarians invade the board state changes in a radical way And I have to react to this terrifying new world.
Rym: So I might choose instead a more safe or neutral hand to be able to be reactive.
Rym: So you sort of your plan and you invest in a path but then you have to react to the world when your turn comes about because if you've Invested in a military in the real world and then some shit goes down somewhere It's not like you can just teleport those soldiers somewhere different.
Scott: Yeah Also, you know Like we said the wait the cards are poor.
Scott: our currency points for different to buying different actions.
Scott: that are the actual doings.
Rym: Yep, right.
Scott: So you start the game with I think three three and three.
Scott: three blue three red three yellow.
Scott: Pretty much takes at least two to do a meaningful action, you know.
Scott: So you can't really do like all three different kinds of actions in one job.
Scott: You're gonna have like a red a military kind of turn or you know a people kind of turn.
Rym: So you got a debate like how are you gonna focus?
Rym: What kinds of things do you want to do?
Scott: Well, you can't balance it out.
Scott: You can't be like I'm gonna do a little bit of everything every turn because your hands not big enough and you also can't be Like I'm gonna go all military.
Scott: this game It's like okay you go all military in turn one and turn two.
Scott: You can put.
Scott: you have one red card left.
Scott: you can put in your hand which does nothing.
Scott: Right, you can't?
Scott: you have to do all three things and any given turn will almost definitely be not Hitting on all three notes.
Scott: it'll be your.
Scott: each turn will be focusing on one and a half of the areas of the game and Ignoring one area of the game pretty much completely like.
Scott: well, I did my military this turn.
Scott: I'm not doing any next turn.
Scott: I did a little bit of people this turn.
Scott: I can do a little bit of people next turn but not too much on either turn and only in the latest latest late Game when you have super strong cars that you've acquired from winning already.
Scott: Basically, you can do a whole bunch of things in one turn But then your next turn will still be crappy because you just spent all your huge cards in the first turn.
Rym: So kind of an aside, but I just saw this picture.
Rym: I want to lose this train of thought.
Rym: my main complaint with the game is that it has some like UX and mechanical problems Because it's made it looks like a grognard war game.
Scott: So all the UX and this graphic design of it is grog Nardi like to remember to know your purchasing power and everything.
Rym: They got to look at things.
Rym: They have to confirm numbers several times just to make sure you're doing things, right?
Rym: And the first thing I said after I played the game once was if you just made a simple player aid This game would actually go a lot faster Like I can envision a very.
Scott: I think I mean you can just take the same as that game and retheme it.
Rym: No, the theme is perfect.
Rym: I don't want a different thing.
Scott: But the point is if you just made it look like a euro right or like a you know Root style you could totally pass this off to just everyone and it would be like a super popular game.
Rym: But the board is fine.
Rym: The only there that the UX boards.
Rym: Okay, the board is fine.
Scott: It's okay.
Rym: I mean yours is you never actually looked at where barbarians could go with your problem?
Scott: No, I mean I looked at it.
Scott: But the point is it's just.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: you know, it's not like a beautiful board, right?
Scott: You could give this game just a graphical only makeover and it could be like one of the most popular.
Rym: But all you don't even need to change the board.
Rym: You just need to make a handful of player aids that sit next to the board.
Rym: I mean that would token sound that would help significantly.
Scott: But I'm saying if you just need this not look like a Roman thing.
Rym: But I don't that the problem is the UX not the UI.
Scott: I mean, I'm just saying that's to sell it.
Scott: Yeah, no one's gonna buy the Roman thing I'll buy the Roman thing.
Scott: mechanics of this game are a hundred percent.
Rym: but I'm looking at your aid your AI for because you can like have an AI in the game and it's pretty close to what I would have made as a player aid For the game itself, right?
Scott: But I think the game is you know, it's the Romani parts of it are parts that Rym likes But they're not parts that you know, the theme is not.
Rym: the theme is pretty.
Rym: even the core mechanics are pretty tied to the theme.
Rym: That's the other.
Rym: they are very tied to the theme Yes, but those that made that makes for a very natural Heuristics and that make the game objectively better.
Rym: For example, there's Italy in the middle and all the other provinces.
Rym: It's a Roman crisis game.
Rym: You're putting your governor's out in place.
Scott: Yeah, you can make it a fantasy theme and it would be fine.
Rym: But here's the deal one of the cool mechanics.
Rym: So one of the things you're tracking is you get points every round based on like how much control your dudes have in all the different regions and like how much you've invested into them like having buildings and things.
Rym: but You also track how many turns you had.
Rym: you were the Emperor.
Rym: Yep, meaning you control it.
Scott: That's really the number one way to get point.
Rym: That is super neat.
Rym: It's almost like a king of the hill game.
Rym: that's happening in the middle of the rest of this game, right?
Scott: But the thing is right unlike real king of the hill, right?
Scott: Which as you know the same sort of problems as last hitting and mobiles.
Rym: king of the hill in this game Just gets you points, but also makes you vulnerable.
Scott: is it's not about you know King of the hill type?
Scott: rules often get wrong?
Scott: Is that whoever's on the hill at the end wins and that can be good.
Rym: but usually it's man like try to do Really flag for the most number of second, right?
Scott: It's like you'll play really really really well and dominate the whole game and then at the very end you finally run out of steam.
Scott: Someone pushes you off and they win.
Scott: they are the winner and that feels like bullshit because you dominated all that time And that what seems like it was much more difficult and much more worthy of being called the winner, right?
Scott: So this game it's like yeah, you're getting points for the number of turns you were on top.
Scott: It doesn't matter if you're there at the end, right?
Scott: It just matters who is there.
Scott: the longest right the longer you're there the better.
Scott: if you got up fall down and get up Again, and you're up there twice.
Scott: That's great.
Scott: That's just as being good as being up there twice as long.
Scott: and even if you say You know dump on the last turn and have a sad ending.
Scott: Yeah, you know because Rome Yeah, Rome.
Scott: Yeah, you'll still be declared the victor I get I get.
Rym: I get into a really precarious situation But then like everyone else got into some bullshit and I ended up in Italy but really weak.
Rym: But everyone else was so stuck dealing with their own crap That I kind of just hung out as Emperor for a few turns Like I just held on because everyone really wanted to unseat me But no one was willing to spend their whole turn doing it because they had other like much more important things to deal with.
Scott: Well also mechanically speaking, you know There are many games out there that have a variety of victory conditions to choose from.
Scott: or if they don't have different victory conditions They have different ways to get victory points.
Scott: You could go say crown of Amara you could get red or you can go book right in this game.
Scott: You could go and as a way to get victory points try to be the Emperor the longest.
Scott: Yeah, that will totally help you get a lot of victory points.
Rym: You can also be popular in the districts that you control.
Rym: Yep, and or fight barbarians, right?
Scott: You could just be popular in a few places or somewhat popular in a lot of places like yeah, okay Rym You're the Emperor the whole damn game, but I'm super popular everywhere else.
Scott: Yeah, and you're just the pup, you know puppet Emperor.
Scott: All right Right.
Scott: Well, yeah, you guys are all popular and whatever I went around destroying all the barbarians and all of these different ways to get points are equally strong.
Scott: I can't say that like one of them is just better than the others.
Scott: Yep, right It's like.
Scott: yeah, you can win in any of those ways.
Rym: one You gotta gotta balance how you're approaching the game - you have to react to what the other players are doing Yep, and three the game is more like a war game and that there's a lot of random bullshit that happens.
Scott: Well, the barbarian fountains are random.
Rym: Well, yeah, the barbarian fountains are random.
Rym: The event cards are random Like shit just goes wrong all the time.
Rym: Yep, Zenobia came up like right away and it was like messing with Italy in both our games just randomly.
Rym: But that's fun because that uncertainty is what makes this more like a war game.
Rym: Well without the more naturalistic heuristic.
Scott: well because of this deck stacking, right?
Scott: There is no other source of randomness besides the barbarians and event deck.
Scott: Therefore without those you would just solve.
Scott: this game like this is the optimal play.
Scott: Start try to start in these places.
Rym: Stack your deck these this way buy these cards or at best it would end up turning into Honda's toy Tonica where the game is purely reacting to what other players are doing in a cycle, right?
Scott: Now the barbarian the randomness could affect one player more than others, but that's working.
Rym: sometimes It's like sometimes open like Africa just gets overrun early and that sucks.
Scott: But if you were there in aggregate it goes after everyone equally.
Scott: So even though the barbarians happen to overrun Rym this game, right?
Scott: It's like I still had to prepare just as much for barbarian invasion because it could happen in any moment.
Rym: yep, or I take a risk and I like don't put any armies in Africa because I got a plan and then Barbarians happen there.
Rym: It's like well, oops, but maybe they don't.
Rym: or maybe I got federati and I'm good to rock.
Scott: Yeah, but that's a gamble.
Scott: still it is a gamble and it's a gamble for everyone equally.
Scott: even though you know the tide might splash upon one player and not another everyone still had to pay the the price of Gambling, you know one way or the other or play out safe and I'm not gonna explain all the mechanic Like.
Rym: I'm not gonna teach you this game.
Rym: That would be.
Rym: we already taught you.
Scott: the core mechanic of the game is deck building game where you stack your deck But you still can't access the discard.
Scott: Yeah And you're buying power to buy more cards is based on your popularity and control of provinces And there's several ways to get points and control is only with Popular and killing barbarians and all three of them are equally viable ways to get points.
Rym: You're probably gonna have to mix it up to some extent and there's a bunch of fun little mechanics Like the only one I'll talk about like there's you know militias.
Rym: then you got like Roman legions and all this stuff.
Rym: But there's mobs.
Scott: Oh the angry mob.
Scott: The funniest thing about a mob is the fuck you stick.
Scott: It's like I just want I want and Rym's winning.
Scott: I put mobs on Rym, but mobs are real funny.
Rym: There's other things that can cause miles but basically if a mob it's usually putting them on other place.
Rym: if a mob is in your territory like you have a governor in A territory and there's a mob then if you don't deal with that shit before the end of your turn you get less popular And if you're too unpopular, you just get replaced.
Rym: Yeah, like you're out.
Rym: Yep, one way to deal with a mob is just if you have a legion there just go kill it But then people get pissed off.
Scott: Oh, yeah, this is.
Scott: there's two different ways to remove.
Rym: or you can build circuses You can run games.
Scott: Yeah, you can remove a mob with red military cards at but that costs you popularity.
Rym: You can play or you get yellow rifle card and placate the mob with yellow cards or you can build a build an amphitheater and then the mobs will stay and they'll still be a problem.
Rym: grow because Also at the end of your turn if any territory as a mob Daddy to mobs a bigger angrier mod the mob just keeps growing until you deal with it and the bigger if you have a Mob.
Scott: but I have a Colosseum so it's gonna be one last game we played.
Rym: I just kept a pet mob for a couple turns because I didn't want to deal with it.
Scott: There's also a building you can build that will deal with barbarians and convert them to your armies.
Scott: As long as your army is mostly Roman you could that's just no.
Rym: yeah the card Federati will do that.
Rym: the building just means when barbarians come into a territory where there's lemase or limes Yeah, they'll come in flipped over like inactive But then they're easy to bring in.
Scott: Yeah, you don't to fight them, right?
Scott: But him next turn if they're still sitting there, yeah, but you know, they'll just kill themselves effectively if you played the Federati's.
Rym: Yeah There's a lot going.
Rym: this game is meaty and fun.
Rym: There aren't really other don't be right.
Scott: Don't be fooled by its grog Nardi war game.
Scott: Look, it's basically an awesome Euro game just like all those other awesome euro games you're used to but with a lot of.
Rym: it's not any harder than a Dominion or a small world but with a lot of the war game type That make war games interesting there's a lot of little harder than this plan.
Rym: There's a lot of emergent behavior a lot of narrative will come about and the kind of planning you do in the game isn't the math of my next turn so much as the.
Rym: I need to focus on this area of the board or this type of thing next turn and I need to be mindful of the fact that based on that I will have fewer options until I reshuffle my deck.
Rym: So do I blow my wad now?
Rym: do I save my wad for a later turn?
Rym: What do I do?
Scott: not and also not enough can be said about again, you know There are lots of games that do this where they take a mechanic from another game and sort of let you cheat.
Scott: It's like well that would be cheating in Dominion.
Scott: So you get that extra fun of feeling like you're cheating and it's okay and it but then the game is actually good.
Scott: So it doesn't.
Scott: it's not that strong.
Scott: Yep I feel like I would have but it's fun to do a thing in a game that feels like cheating in the game The mechanic came from.
Scott: so I feel like that's actually for game designers out there.
Scott: find a game that has a mechanic and There's like an obvious rule for that mechanic that yeah, obviously you can't do that.
Scott: That would be crazy op and cheating.
Scott: but then make a game where everyone's allowed to do that and it's not op.
Rym: Yep, and if you keep doing that, you'll just make dune maybe.
Rym: But yeah, I feel like I want to own this game.
Rym: I think our New York set would like this and play it.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: And I was like, have we played any game?
Rym: Oh In New York, well, we haven't been in New York for a while.
Rym: is the problem?
Rym: like every weekend I'm an out of town or something.
Rym: Uh-huh last weekend I was skiing so the time you're ready to play a game in New York is gonna be warm Yeah, but then I can easily bike to your place where there's critical mass because there are four gamers and I'll be there.
Scott: I'll be biking.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, I'll also be biking but then that night we'll play a game.
Rym: obviously.
Rym: Yeah, don't go to bed early old man.
Scott: I'm gonna go there right now.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this observe GeekNights are Alan Joyce, I can pickle just like a dude guy.
Rym: He's our toppish and linky G the thirst for hydrated ganon.
Rym: Chris midkiff my state II.
Rym: calm J Band Shawn Yeager Nicholas brand out.
Rym: you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: 421 creations started making trouble in my neighborhood.
Rym: sure run harl Superboy Clinton Walton written from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and letter Finn dread lily tennebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas.
Media: on and now I Leave you Sir do you know anything about this?
Media: Last night man with him stick the bag.
Media: Big mistake y'all right there in that cooler.
Media: Oh wait, man Thanks boom here, let's go Man, I don't know what you're thinking man, but y'all got no man I ain't no damn Woody Allen with that soon leave - it's not gonna happen.
Rym: boom higher You're not gonna talk your way out of this one.
Media: Yeah, man That dang old Internet man just don't on there point-click.
Media: get in there talk about WWW.com.
Media: me you got in that naked chicks on there may just go click click click click click click.
Media: It's really nice.