Rym: It's Wednesday, January 8th, 2020!
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We're talking about some meta about GeekNights.
Scott: It's Meta Moment, the whole show.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So yeah, every year we have GeekNights hiatus around this time, usually because we have a bunch of conventions, we have to travel for the holidays, family stuff happens, it's a good time to reset, get some quiet work done, I fucks with the audio pipeline, all that kind of thing.
Rym: But this year, for a bunch of unrelated reasons, this was like the biggest hiatus we've ever had.
Scott: We did some episodes in there, but not many.
Rym: Not many, because one, there were some personal dramas among us and our friends, like some medical issues and things, like not me or Scott directly, but like our friends.
Scott: It all started after PAX West when I moved.
Rym: Yep, Scott moved.
Scott: A short distance.
Rym: I'm like tearing apart my bedroom.
Scott: It still took a lot of effort.
Scott: That bedroom's not keeping you from doing a podcast.
Rym: No, it kept me from doing a podcast like one day, because I had to do it some time.
Scott: Right, but then I was done moving, we did some shows a little bit, but then you went on a business travel.
Rym: Yep, the problem was, I used to do this Asia trip, like two or three weeks in Asia every year for work, but my new job, I didn't have to do that trip, so I planned my life and expected to take all this time off at different times, and then I also had to do this trip again, so I had double the time off from what I expected.
Scott: Anyway, and then we had a PAX Unplugged, and then a Thanksgiving PAX Unplugged, and then...
Rym: Like Christmasy time.
Scott: December, Christmasy time, and PAX South is next week.
Rym: Yeah, like this coming weekend is the only free weekend I'll have had in like more than a month.
Rym: I do not have free time.
Scott: No, but PAX South should only bump out maybe one more GeekNights episode.
Rym: Next week on Tuesday we're going to review Nokosu Dice, that's like the hottest new hotness.
Rym: We've been wanting to talk about this since PAX Unplugged.
Scott: Yeah, there was a pre-order for it and it sold out, so deal with it.
Rym: I mean, I made my own copy, that's how obsessed I am with this game.
Rym: It was sold out by the time I thought to go pre-order.
Scott: Oops, everyone else has one.
Rym: I got fucked.
Rym: But also, then we're going to have PAX East, actually not that long after PAX South.
Scott: PAX East is early this year, so we'll have somewhat consistent GeekNights in February.
Rym: March is going to get a little fucked.
Scott: Right, a little early March, May, who knows.
Scott: But then April through PAX West we're going to have consistent GeekNights again.
Rym: Yep, so don't worry.
Scott: As consistent as GeekNights is.
Rym: Because I know with webcomics in the early 2000s, whenever there was a news post that was like, "The state of the comic," that usually translated to, "We're
Rym: ending.".
Rym: And most podcasts, "The state of the podcast" literally is the show where people say, "Yeah, we can't do this
Rym: anymore.".
Rym: We're doubling down.
Scott: I always find it funniest in general when people feel the need to announce quitting, ending, leaving.
Scott: Just stop.
Scott: Yeah, just stop.
Scott: Someone who announces, "I'm leaving," that tells me, "Yeah, you might be
Scott: leaving.".
Scott: But you're looking for all kinds of attention and discussion.
Scott: You really just want to make a huff.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: Are you leaving in a huff or are you ending one project to do it?
Rym: What if we were like, "GeekNights is ending because we are now joining some company to make
Rym: gaming.".
Rym: We both work for a game company.
Scott: Yeah, if you're making just an announcement.
Scott: But I feel like most of the time when people announce--.
Rym: Here are my theses on why I'm leaving this community.
Scott: Right, when someone does that-- Things that are going to everybody's and everybody's wife, fucking everybody in everybody's room, fucking back door, fucking fish tank.
Rym: I'm just curious if anyone knows what I'm talking about.
Rym: That's an in-joke from the earliest GeekNights.
Scott: If someone does that, what they're actually saying is, "I don't want to leave.
Scott: I want to have a big discussion and I want you to acquiesce to some of my demands to change things to make me less upset so that I won't leave.
Scott: I want to see how upset people are that I'm leaving.
Scott: Show me how much you miss
Scott: me.".
Rym: Scott, here's the thing.
Rym: You're thinking about recent internet shouty men.
Rym: I know a lot of webcomics where that last thing was like, "Look, some shit went down in my life.
Rym: I can't do this anymore.
Rym: I hope you enjoyed it.
Rym: It's a real heartfelt
Rym: goodbye.".
Rym: I've also seen a lot of people like, "Look, I'm stopping this webcomic because I have been working for Marvel for five years and I can't keep doing this comic that you're all obsessed
Rym: with.".
Rym: It's not always your thing.
Rym: I think about most internet shouty men in the last decade.
Scott: The point is if you say it in more than a few words, you should be able to just be like, "Yo, I can't do this anymore.
Scott: Bye-bye.".
Rym: Yeah, but I would give a final farewell if GeekNights ever ended.
Rym: I suspect GeekNights will end when one or both of us die.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Let me get this poison over here.
Rym: Dude, I'm drinking some poison right now.
Rym: Uh-oh.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Let's do some news thing of the day.
Rym: First, the open event.
Rym: You know how we roll.
Rym: We've had a month of adventures, but we're going to talk about some things that happen in our lives that are probably pretty prosaic and literally all of those exciting things will be lost like tears in the rain.
Rym: For the last year, I've been getting bruises in the bottom third of my legs, above my knee, up there.
Rym: I'd have these bruises.
Rym: For a long time, they'd just appear every now and then.
Rym: I'd be like, "Oh, what did I
Rym: do?".
Rym: I was getting vaguely thought, "Oh, I must have just banged at rock
Rym: climbing.".
Rym: But I haven't been rock climbing much in the last month and a half.
Rym: I still got these bruises.
Rym: I was thinking, "Oh, no.
Rym: Do I have a disease?
Rym: Should I be a doctor about
Rym: this?".
Scott: Bruzitis.
Rym: So then, today, at work, I had a meeting that was a good heated conversation with one of my best engineers.
Rym: We're on a whiteboard, trying to figure out a big thing.
Rym: The tables at my office are at this height, and they have super sharp corners that come to this weird point.
Rym: I bumped into this table six times in the course of this discussion, getting up and down.
Rym: I realized that is literally exactly where the bruise appears.
Scott: You've been bumping into the table for a long time?
Rym: I've been bumping into these tables at work for the last two years, and I just assumed it was rock climbing injuries, and now I've realized the truth.
Rym: Fuck those tables.
Rym: God damn it.
Scott: Why don't you complain about the tables?
Scott: I will.
Rym: I'm going to open a ticket tomorrow and be like,
Rym: "Listen.".
Scott: Is anyone else bruising the cells in the table?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe I should ask the company.
Rym: I'll put out a blast and be like, "Hey, so, you all know me.
Rym: I'm the product manager of all these things.
Rym: The thing that's bothering me more about this community is these tables.
Scott: Get these tables out here.
Scott: I
Scott: quit.".
Rym: So, what happened to you in the last month?
Scott: Uh, whatever.
Scott: I went to some conventions.
Rym: Here's a question.
Scott: I stayed inside a lot to avoid the cold.
Rym: What was the best thing you did at MAGFest?
Rym: We were just there.
Rym: The most fun thing.
Scott: Top of your mind.
Rym: Because I got one.
Scott: I didn't tabletop a lot.
Scott: There was too much good shit.
Rym: Yeah, this was a good MAGFest.
Rym: I went to a lot of panels.
Scott: There was so much equally good shit.
Scott: There wasn't one thing that was like, "Oh, that was the best
Scott: thing.".
Rym: What's top of mind?
Rym: What's one of the great things?
Rym: Because mine is simple.
Rym: I went to more concerts than I normally go to.
Rym: But I caught the Anda Super Soul Brothers, who I love, but I've seen them a lot.
Rym: But then I caught this ska band.
Rym: Ska System.
Rym: Never is a band been on the fucking wavelength of Rym before.
Rym: Like this band.
Rym: They come out, they play some ska.
Rym: The second song they play is a ska cover of the Zelda II Temple music.
Rym: Then they did a ska cover of Sans Undertale's song.
Rym: It was good.
Rym: Also late 90s, early 2000s infotainment positivity songs.
Rym: It was a good ska band.
Rym: I'm feeling them.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It wasn't the best thing at MAGFest, but there was that.
Scott: for some reason I went to several computer programming related things.
Scott: I went to a panel of a guy talking about writing an emulator.
Rym: Oh, that was fun.
Rym: Because it wasn't like.
Rym: here's the science of it.
Rym: He was just like, I tried to write an emulator.
Rym: Here's the shit I had to deal with.
Scott: We went to the Tazbot panel.
Rym: That was actually pretty good.
Scott: They also talked about programming.
Scott: And then we went to the panel of a super late night panel, which shouldn't have been so late night.
Rym: I only came to the last third of it, and that last third was fascinating.
Rym: And apparently, according to Scott, the first two thirds were way more than that.
Scott: There was a guy who was an expert on Japanese PCs.
Scott: He was all into Japanese PCs and PC games.
Scott: Basically, Windows 95 is when Japan joined the Wintel, right?
Scott: Before then, they had all these other PC systems.
Scott: You may have heard of MSX, MSX2.
Scott: It was like FM Towns or something like that.
Scott: They were like, all these other PC systems, architectures that they had before Windows 95 when they joined the rest of the world.
Scott: And you don't have those computers in the West.
Rym: And people wrote games on them.
Scott: Japan didn't have Apple IIs and Commodores like we had, right?
Scott: And we didn't have ZX Spectrums like the UK had.
Scott: I watch a lot of games and other fascinating softwares for those systems and it was really cool to see.
Rym: Most of the people I watch on YouTube who talk about that kind of stuff are not in the US, so I literally think of it as the ZX Spectrum.
Scott: 8BitGuy does it yet.
Scott: 8BitGuy doesn't know nothing about MSX2, right?
Rym: No, I don't know nothing about MSX2.
Scott: There was MSX and MSX2.
Rym: I didn't even know there was an MSX2.
Rym: I knew about the MSX even when I was young because when I was a kid playing...
Scott: Well, it wasn't the MSX.
Scott: MSX was like a standard.
Rym: Yeah, but I knew it existed but didn't know anything about it because as a kid I knew Metal Gear and some nerd at my school was like, oh the real version is on the MSX but you can't play that.
Rym: And he didn't know anything more than that sentence.
Scott: That's also all I know.
Scott: But yeah, that was very fascinating.
Rym: So in some news, we're not going to talk about how the world's on fire and our president is literally.
Rym: The world is literally on fire right now.
Scott: The world is on fire in many places in many ways.
Rym: Both literally and metaphorically.
Scott: Yet somehow we can still sit here and make GeekNights and go to work and do everything normally.
Rym: But we are shielded by privilege and money.
Scott: We are shielded by many things but those shields are on fire.
Rym: I played some Artemis space bridge on Sunday at Magfest and I did engineering which I've never done before.
Rym: Repeatedly I had to remind the captain that we do not have any fucking forward shields because you will not go to a space station where shields are low but they're holding for now.
Rym: So in some other news College Humor and I'm not going to go too deep into the details but I'm going to link to a source of many GeekNights things of the day.
Scott: College Humor the first many years of GeekNights existence was a big deal.
Scott: I don't think you understand how important College Humor was to modern internet humor to internet video content creation around the time GeekNights was created up for several years thereafter College Humor was a big fucking deal.
Rym: And Adam Conover who I haven't talked to, I knew him.
Rym: I don't know him now.
Rym: he is more famous now.
Rym: he had a TV show but he was one of the people.
Rym: College Humor was a lot of very talented people doing a lot of really cool stuff.
Scott: a lot of those people went on to become like SNL writers and shit.
Scott: it was like an entry point into the world of big time comedy.
Scott: as you would go to College Humor you would get it's like SNL but good as an entry level comedian and then you would flex and then you'd bust out.
Scott: there was like a who was on College Humor who was like a cousin of the Perry Bowell Fellowship.
Scott: there was all kinds of people on there.
Rym: I knew a lot of people.
Scott: there was a guy named something Ruben who wasn't related to me but then my sister knew him.
Scott: but anyway
Rym: I'll link to this thread because basically College Humor was one of those things that existed back when there were more websites and if you're not aware we've talked about this a little bit before but basically Facebook and Google sort of conspired to destroy all other content creation on earth.
Rym: why have your own website say frontrowcrew.com with a bunch of videos on it or say ScrewAttack or College Humor or Dorkly or any of these sites that had independent content?
Scott: why make a website where you post videos and people come to your site to watch your videos?
Scott: when there's YouTube the place people go to watch videos you just have a YouTube channel.
Scott: you'll get more views that way.
Rym: but now YouTube owns you but also they made a lot of non-video content.
Rym: that was really good.
Rym: also cracked another one of these sites and basically Facebook lied so much about viewership numbers.
Scott: we've talked about this story before that it destroyed College Humor.
Rym: but College Humor limped on and only now is being completely decimated.
Rym: almost everyone was fired.
Rym: a lot of really talented people are out of work.
Scott: well they'll all get real comedian jobs being writers in SNL or whatever.
Scott: not that SNL is that great but it pays and it still exists.
Rym: but if you need comedy people or you need content creation people production line people anyone at Light Up College Humor come work for GeekNights temporarily.
Scott: we can't pay you enough to eat.
Rym: I can't pay you a salary but I can pay you contract gigs.
Rym: yes we can pay you contracting hours to make something if any of you want to come on GeekNights.
Rym: but anyway read this thread.
Rym: I tweeted about this but this is a real shame.
Rym: this is a sad day for humor and content on the internet and it's worth reading this thread to really internalize how fucked up a situation the internet is in right now.
Scott: it's similar to all the private equity destroying things.
Scott: by the way Bed Bath and Beyond next thing to be destroyed by private equity.
Scott: but I don't care because fuck Bed Bath and Beyond.
Scott: I don't like them.
Rym: I don't really have an opinion on the existence of Bed Bath and Beyond.
Scott: I just don't like that.
Scott: when I bought something there with my credit card they hassled me for info by email address and I didn't give it to them.
Scott: and somehow they still were able to spam me in my mail and email box incessantly and it was hard to unsubscribe but I did succeed at doing it.
Rym: I remember back in the day when Radio Shack would ask for your zip code and fucking wouldn't sell you things unless you gave it to them.
Rym: so yeah you got any news?
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: so in case you're living under a nerdy rock I don't know how any nerd doesn't know about this but AGDQ is happening right the hell.
Scott: now awesome games done quick and if you are sitting there and you're like I've heard of this GDQ thing it's not up my alley I don't really care.
Scott: yesterday yesterday they had a run.
Scott: was it yesterday or two days ago?
Rym: I don't watch them live that often.
Rym: it was yesterday.
Scott: they had a run of Mike Tyson's punch out.
Scott: now we've seen Mike Tyson's punch out at GDQ several times.
Scott: we saw people beat it really fast.
Scott: we saw people beat it blindfolded.
Scott: so this time they had people beat it 2P 1C.
Scott: that's two people.
Scott: one controller.
Scott: that is nuts.
Scott: one person's got the arrows one person's got the buttons.
Scott: I think the way you do this is you master it on your own.
Scott: the other person masters it on their own.
Scott: you master it with the same techniques.
Scott: then you just put one of your hands in your pocket and you imagine yourself pushing the buttons on both sides of the controller but only one of your hands is actually touching the controller and the other person's doing the same thing.
Scott: and much like Evangelion episode DDR whatever that is you beat punch out 9?
Rym: was it episode 9?
Scott: regardless what was fascinating was not that they managed to do this.
Rym: it was episode 9.
Scott: I'm a fucking nerd.
Scott: the point is they added a little twist.
Scott: they did a 2P 1C and blindfolded.
Scott: both.
Rym: people blindfolded 2P 1C.
Scott: they beat Mike Tyson's punch out something I cannot do 1P 1C eyes open.
Rym: I love Mike Tyson's punch out.
Scott: I've never actually beaten it.
Scott: I can sometimes beat Sandman and super macho man usually takes me down and if I use the password to go to Mike Tyson I basically can't beat him.
Rym: I can knock him down I can beat him but I only ever beat him by taking a password directly to him.
Rym: I've never beaten the entire game in one go ever.
Rym: I don't think I ever could.
Rym: I'm pretty good but not real good though I was getting so paranoid because as I'm older I play a lot of DDR but there's two songs that I have been able to pass that I cannot pass anymore.
Rym: but last night I actually almost passed max 300 again so I might be getting it back but I'm training real hard.
Rym: yeah GDQ is amazing and you should appreciate the craft even if you do not like video games or speed running.
Rym: so I guess it's time for Things of the Day.
Rym: I thought mine's pretty funny.
Rym: I like my Thing of the Day a lot but Scott's is way better.
Scott: I see Star Trek which I don't watch.
Rym: I like Star Trek but basically I recently rewatched all of Star Trek Voyager just like I watched it all.
Rym: so I've seen every episode of Voyager fairly recently and this is a video that is just Star Trek Voyager out of context and it is edited so well and it has good sets of recurring themes that it's actually really funny to watch whether or not you have seen Star Trek Voyager.
Rym: so I encourage you, particularly if you have never seen Star Trek Voyager to watch this video.
Rym: so what do you got?
Scott: so here's some people in an office somewhere, it's clearly not in the United States because they're not speaking the English but they have some issue with their computer monitors.
Scott: and this is not a faked thing, this isn't like some kind of setup or anything like that, right?
Scott: this is like a real deal.
Scott: whenever they sit in this chair and then stand up from the chair the monitors like go cancel out and then have to reboot all the monitors.
Rym: now at first I was like is it just some like power saving bullshit in this office, nothing like that like it's just a normal office chair.
Scott: so what's the deal going on here?
Scott: apparently they're using some sort of display link hardware, display link makes I guess video stuff.
Scott: I don't know, I've never used any of their hardware.
Scott: wireless VR technology yeah something like that, I don't know.
Scott: and this display link hardware is not shielded properly from interference.
Scott: so the electrical pulse of some kind, maybe static electricity related.
Rym: oh yeah, reading this bug thing when people stand or sit on gas lift chairs which is any modern chair?
Scott: you know the chairs that go up and down with the lever, that's a gas lift chair they can
Rym: generate an EMI spike
Scott: yes, that minor spike from going up or down in the gas lift chair of certain kinds too quickly causes some electricity in the air and that makes these monitors fuck up because the display link hardware sucks.
Scott: so don't buy display link crap, and also this is hilarious.
Scott: it's hilarious because it's not fake.
Scott: you'd expect someone to do this like a practical joke like they wire, put something in someone's chair.
Scott: but no, this is totally just a real bug, there's the bug report on the display link website, they admit it.
Rym: that's amazing I wouldn't admit it.
Scott: so in the meta moment it's the entire rest of the show right, so that's at least for the meta moment section, talk about the immediate meta.
Rym: so first, we were just at magfest, we did not video our panels.
Rym: we were lazy.
Rym: yep, mostly we were lazy, but also they were either repeats or they were like panel panels and they were all pretty good.
Rym: it was a great magfest, but I will be posting the slides for the real harm of games because the doctor who joined us added several citations that are fantastic and further solidify that we are right.
Rym: we also did a brand new panel that we're going to tweak based on feedback and based on how it went the first time.
Rym: I think it went pretty well.
Scott: we threw a panel together like slapdash that hopefully we'll do it again and then we'll record and put it online.
Rym: yep, but I'm going to change some points, tweak some slides, I realized some things about the panel, I think we can tighten it up pretty well.
Rym: but I might post for the patreon.
Rym: patreons, I did record.
Rym: I was doing it just on OBS.
Rym: so I think I'm going to post that to the patreon so you can see what an early gig night's panel.
Scott: so you can have audio and slides.
Rym: audio and slides, and also because I just did it for my own edification because the projector was actually a weird resolution and I didn't check that because I didn't care because we weren't making video.
Rym: the slides are cropped and zoomed in weird just because the projector was like a weird aspect ratio and resolution.
Scott: for some reason we're going to peck south, but we're just doing another one of those 40 whatever.
Rym: so the deal is we're doing the 41 tabletop games you must play.
Scott: but the deal is we never even finish all 40 when we do these things.
Rym: yeah we do, we only failed once.
Scott: you should change it to 30 something.
Rym: well the difference is, the panel we do the 40 X games you should play, the deal is always here is a wide variety of games that will like force you to touch every kind of gaming like chess nerd, play magic magic nerd, play any other game like that kind of thing, play these foundational games that teach you something.
Rym: but this is, we cannot talk about any game we've talked about in that panel.
Rym: it's just, there's too many games out.
Scott: now, here's a list of games that we think are worth playing for some reason since we're not doing one of the meaningful panels, I also don't know if we should record this one.
Rym: we definitely should because it's all new content.
Scott: it's not all new content, we've done this panel how many times already?
Rym: it's 100% different games from any version of this panel we've ever done ever?
Rym: also people really like these panels because you forget we see all the games and we like.
Rym: we know a lot about games.
Rym: most gamers don't know what games to play, they really need help.
Rym: go to BoardGameGeek and look at the top 20. that is not going to give you a good time not today, go find some YouTube.
Rym: shouty men, come to us.
Rym: we're just podcast.
Rym: shouty men.
Rym: YouTube is secondary.
Scott: so anyway, that's pretty much all the book club book.
Rym: Tale of Genji, yes I'm reading it again.
Scott: I reread chapter 1 on the train.
Scott: it's going to take a while but it's coming.
Rym: we're going to do some sub episodes of the Tale of Genji.
Rym: we're both going to read for a while and at some point in the next month or two we'll probably do an episode up to a certain point.
Rym: all I want to say is Genji's actually kind of a piece of shit at least in the beginning.
Scott: it's the first novel ever in the history of humanity is the oldest possible novel.
Scott: there are older writings clearly but those older writings were not novels like The Odyssey, not a novel nope, it's an oral story oral storytelling or an oral tradition, an epic poem.
Rym: every year around Christmas I usually read some non-fiction about World War I I'm weird, Christmas truths and all that and this year I picked a pretty thorough history of World War I instead of a shorter thing but I finished it a little while ago.
Rym: so now I'm diving back into the Tale of Genji.
Rym: all I really learned from this book other than a lot of details that will really help me in some of the games I might play with Chris at some point.
Rym: you might think the early learning of World War.
Rym: I you think, well yeah, Germany caused the war.
Rym: Germany was mostly a fault.
Rym: and then you think, well no the European power is a complicated thing.
Scott: everyone was at fault.
Rym: but galaxy brain, no, Germany was like 90% at fault fucking Germany.
Rym: it's like that Simpsons episode where Lisa causes the trouble and Marge is like, Bart, no and Bart's like, what'd I do?
Rym: and she's like, sorry, farce that happened.
Rym: when it comes to World War III it'll be like, Germany, no, oh, sorry I don't think it'll be Germany.
Rym: no, Germany's like if shit goes real bad, Germany's where people have to flee to to stage the resistance.
Rym: ironic yeah, quite I feel like Germany learned its lesson.
Rym: they got all the World Wars out of their system anyway.
Scott: GeekNights is a podcast.
Scott: GeekNights is 15. it depends how you measure, right?
Rym: because the first non-beta GeekNights was Halloween 2005 and funnily enough I found this on December 1st.
Rym: we recorded an episode that we called Meta.
Scott: I think that was about the concept of meta.
Scott: No!
Rym: Tonight on GeekNights we talk about GeekNights itself.
Scott: that was basically at the very start of GeekNights.
Scott: I wonder what the hell we said.
Rym: I'm gonna link to it, I don't know what we said.
Scott: I probably should have listened to that before we did this episode.
Rym: it's kind of better if we don't because I think what I want to do is do this show.
Rym: so this is 15 years.
Scott: it's hard to say if it's 14 or 15 or if 2020 is our 15th year.
Scott: I mean technically it's pointless.
Scott: it doesn't matter because it's the start of a new decade.
Scott: but no it's not until it's 20. whatever.
Rym: look, we started a podcast in the early days of podcasting back in 2005. somehow it's 2020 and almost no one who was podcasting when we started is still podcasting.
Scott: there are some, anyway not many.
Rym: also even the people who are still podcasting have not been podcasting that often.
Rym: we've done more like we're podcasting less often over time yeah, but we've consistently done two episodes a week except during the holidays for most of that time and we did do four episodes a week.
Rym: until what, like 2009?
Rym: yeah, anyway the point is we've been podcasting for a long goddamn time.
Scott: right now we're gonna make a turning point in the GeekNights way and so let us take this opportunity to discuss the ghosts of past, present, and future.
Rym: yup so we started this podcast because we had nothing else to do yeah, so we graduated college and that's a tough time for a lot of people especially in the US because you go from an environment surrounded by all your closest friends you have basically zero responsibilities.
Scott: well it depends what your college, I've come to realize not everyone was so privileged and lucky to have that kind of college experience.
Rym: I think it's partly because we went to a college.
Scott: even people who did go to people lucky enough to go to college right didn't necessarily have that experience where they went, and then a lot of people the high school was that experience for them, and they're still with their high school friends, even if they had a high school experience like that they were lucky enough to have that.
Rym: but yeah, we were lucky enough to have them and it was a combination of privilege of going to the school the fact that the school was actually pretty physically isolated and none of us had cars.
Rym: well I intentionally, that's what I sought out me too, I wanted to get the fuck away from my whole life and go somewhere new and be an adult.
Scott: I had already had the summer camp experience and I was like, going to college I was pretty much imagining going to summer camp but I'm like, man, I gotta go somewhere with nerds.
Scott: and that was my plan and my plan totally came through.
Scott: I was like, gonna go somewhere and make a bunch of nerdy friends and finally get to play a bunch of battle tech.
Scott: and it totally happened.
Rym: a bunch of other stuff, there was also a time a setting situation, exactly as I foreseen we entered college pre-cellphone and left college post-cellphone.
Rym: we went to college pre-bit torrent and left post-bit torrent pre-youtube post-youtube pre-facebook post-facebook.
Rym: yeah, like we, Orkut came out and we were like, whoa what is this thing?
Scott: what is a social network, hot shit like, we came in with Eamonn ICQ and he left with Eamonn ICQ.
Scott: yep, it was a little bit.
Scott: we'd know some Jabber kinda Google hangouts shortly thereafter.
Scott: yep, we didn't adopt Twitter right away which came way after Twitter came way after college Twitter, GeekNights is older than Twitter.
Rym: yeah, GeekNights is older than a lot of things.
Rym: that's right.
Rym: but that setting like, and the other crazy thing I saw recently, someone was talking about The Wonder Years that TV show, remember that show?
Rym: so, when that show was on yeah, so when that show was on TV the era it depicted was from the past like it depicted an era from the past.
Rym: and when you watch that show, like when I watched The Wonder Years, it felt like it was depicting an ancient time.
Rym: if The Wonder Years were produced today, it literally covers the five years we went to college, that's how long ago that was, by like cultural standards,
Scott: so
Rym: it was this right time and place to where, when I left college that left a deep hole in my day to day life.
Scott: well I mean, here, shout out to any writers out there, write a Wonder Years 2. just don't even it doesn't have to be based on the actual thing or you have the same name, just make it about people in the year 2000 to 2005.
Rym: yeah, like one of the episodes with the same format, just different names episode 43, Scott gets a cell phone because I remember when you got your cell phone, that was a big fucking deal like everyone was excited about it were they?
Scott: okay yeah, because no one else had one.
Rym: texting texting cost money.
Scott: back then it mattered the most at conventions, I was the point man.
Rym: we used to bring walkie talkies on road trips.
Rym: yeah, it's true anyway, so we left college like shit situated, we ended up in the mid Hudson Valley, we rented this house and we're living in this house, going to jobs and we'd like play five board games and watch a movie every night.
Scott: right, we had a long commute, but we still got home and had nothing to do.
Rym: well back then, I didn't have a long commute, I had a ten minute commute yeah, but we still had nothing to do.
Scott: when we got home we'd make some kind of dinner, maybe go to the grocery which is far, actually maybe go out to eat or order food.
Scott: but yeah, we needed something to do.
Rym: but we also missed the fact that we
Scott: ran the RIT Anime Club
Rym: and I was like on the executive board and while Scott never had an official role really, Scott was actually very important to running that club, you were like the shadow advisor, but we basically like, ran this club for a long time and it was actually a bigger part of our lives than we realized.
Rym: it was weird to be, more for me than you I think, to be used to having an audience to be used to having fans like, I was used to like, any time I went outside at RIT to class, people would just bother me and be like, oh hey, Ram, oh, Ram it.
Rym: and now I was living in the normal world where no one gave a shit about me.
Scott: well, I also, even less than that, having an audience, right I mean, audience is more my thing than your thing.
Scott: it was simply just having a social life immediately where you are at all times.
Scott: so it's like, you know, that's why I like summer camp so much, it's like you're just hanging out with your friends, like, you think about a sleepover, kids love a sleepover.
Scott: I love a sleepover now and I'm 37 you have a whole weekend with your friends, yeah summer camp is a fucking eight weeks sleepover, right, so you know, college is four years sleepover.
Rym: why do you think we're so obsessed with conventions, because conventions are that life for three to five days.
Scott: right, you get all your people together to have a good time for an extended time, which means you can do things that take longer, like play battle tech.
Rym: so we basically, sort of have an anime marathon, so for a lot of different reasons, we ended up basically trying to make our own community on the internet around ourselves just to get all these things.
Scott: we were missing, oh, we also, you know, we tried to get our friends also to come a lot.
Rym: yep, we actually used to try to get a lot of our friends to be on GeekNights, to do sideshows to make content, and basically no one we knew was able to do it consistently or reliably except us, for a lot of reasons.
Rym: so we gave up on that over time but we just kept doing it, and one thing, you know, I really I think it started out as we have nothing else to do.
Scott: yep, right, and we discovered, like the iPod Nano came out, we saw what a pod, we were like, oh, that's what a podcast is, we were in the perfect two white guys position to make one, yep,
Rym: we had money, free time no responsibilities,
Scott: we had time, technology, and knowledge.
Scott: yeah, because remember, we had the computer knowledge, the audio knowledge and we had big mouths.
Rym: I hope we talk about this in this meta episode from 2005 because the only reason GeekNights got as good as it did, because it got pretty good because you took some class at RIT.
Rym: well, not just that, I was in I was into audio engineering from like elementary school on, like I was making mix tapes I was fucking around with reel to reels, I had mixers, making
Scott: a mix tape on your Fisher Price recorder doesn't count,
Rym: no, I was like making mix tapes by, I had like dubbing equipment,
Scott: you made a stereo with two cassettes.
Rym: I had multiple stereos that I linked together and I would like crossfade songs and make mixes on cassettes, I started learning mastering, I learned a lot about audio and then in college, I like doubled down and learned audio engineering, I went to, I took several classes on that.
Rym: I mean, I did, two more than two, pretty sure it was like two.
Rym: I took three, it was three classes.
Rym: one of them was digital music, I remember only one, because music theory one and two also covered music production and media production, and also I did, you're counting the music theory class, cause they covered this stuff.
Rym: and also in high school I mastered like the audio and even recorded a lot of my friends shitty bands anyway, I played in some bands, they were shitty.
Rym: the
Scott: point is, we had enough knowledge
Rym: of
Scott: audio and plenty of knowledge of computer,
Rym: cause back then, I
Scott: had actually made a podcast earlier and didn't realize it was a podcast, I had like a blog
Rym: in college
Scott: and I was like, huh, what if I record like a WAV file of me talking and upload it to the blog?
Scott: there wasn't RSS, I think there was RSS but there wasn't like the embed tag that would make it automatically work, but I did do that, that might be.
Rym: I don't know if that was the oldest podcast on earth, but it was old yup, but that like, precursor knowledge we had was important, cause when we started, podcasting was pretty new.
Rym: there were a lot of people, mostly professionals who had audio skills, but they didn't have anything to say, and they didn't know how to make technology work, a lot of people had things to say.
Scott: we could do all the things on our own all three things we could do like, I already knew what a compressor was and we had nothing else to do, so we did them all.
Rym: yup, and that's partly why like, in those early days, like within a month, Geek Guides format is like, locked down and pretty tight and within two months, our audio sounds fucking great, compared to listen to any other podcast from 2007, even professional ones kinda sound like shit.
Scott: yeah, we also had money, cause we were living cheap,
Rym: yup, but not that much money, we, it was like we had all analog mixing equipment, like the mix, like the pipeline to make Geek Guides like, was literally an analog mixer, mixing down in all analog pipeline meaning if anything went wrong, the recording was fucked to a Linux box, running.
Rym: what was it, Audacity not Audition, not Audacity, it was Resound, I I defy you to make that software work in 2020.
Rym: I
Scott: don't think it exists, no, I mean you could probably get it cause it's open source, but I refuse
Rym: to use Audacity because it sucked
Scott: anyway, so that was what that was what GeekNights started, also the convention panel thing is actually older than GeekNights, yeah,
Rym: we were doing convention panels.
Scott: we did the panels before GeekNights, 2002 but it was me doing them by myself until 2004, right, and then as soon as we had the GeekNights, we were like, well, we're going to these conventions and we just submitted applications to do conventions.
Scott: we had a resume of ones we had done before, and we just tacked on.
Scott: oh, we're from this podcast, we want to do these panels, and we've done them before.
Scott: so people accepted us, which increased the resume, which allowed us to do more which allowed us to do more, and then it was 2008, when we were like, let's go to PAX.
Scott: we always wanted to go to it, since it existed, but we didn't have enough money for that.
Rym: we spent it all on microphones, one of my biggest regrets in life is not going to PAX.
Rym: a year or two earlier, I should have made it happen hitchhike, but basically, we back then, PAX did not have the concept of fan panels.
Scott: there weren't a lot of panels, period.
Rym: the way to submit a panel to PAX was like reach out to them, and I basically was like, hey we are these podcasters here's our resume, here are credentials, we want to talk about this topic at your convention let's talk, and they said okay.
Scott: and they said okay every single time since then, that we have asked.
Rym: we have presented at every single PAX in North America since 2008, and two of the PAX Australias and
Scott: if we had gone to the other Australias, because they don't pay for us to go there, or our hotel again,
Rym: the privilege of money, we can buy we can pay for all the things that for, if you're given access to take advantage of that access.
Scott: so yeah we did that, over time we added and removed various conventions.
Rym: we used to do a lot more cons, which was sadly one thing, that's actually, when we stopped doing a lot of smaller cons.
Scott: I think we did more cons in the earlier days because when we were in Beacon Upstate we had car, so we would drive to a Katsucon or we would drive to, right, we would drive to these other cons, but that was part of what was driving our growth.
Rym: we had more listeners then, like as a percentage of the podcast market.
Scott: then we do now by far who knows, but the point is we drove, so we'd go to other conventions even small ones, with our car.
Scott: now, that we're only in a city with no car, we go to the conventions that are in big cities and since we don't have a lot of time we go to the ones that we only go to the biggest conventions.
Scott: we only go to ones that we would go to if we were only attendees.
Scott: because we went to Anime Boston I think the longest of the non-gaming cons.
Rym: but it got to the point where going to Anime Boston was like going to a job.
Scott: it's like we went to it except for a few things that we did there like concerts, anime hell, the panels that we were on, walk around the dealer's room once we spent the rest of the time fiddling about, not doing much like basically
Rym: sit in the green room, wait for our next panel.
Rym: wish we'd submitted more panels.
Scott: we spent a lot of time there, not, you know the expense of going, even though they were very good and they would pay us to go, they were great and it was great as an anime con, I'm sure it still is the hassle of doing it, plus our friends stopped going.
Rym: well that's something that really happened.
Rym: our friends over time, even our close friends stopped going to almost all conventions like Magfest is the last one that a lot of our friends go to, and increasingly we have this like, two sets we have like the friends that go to Magfest and otherwise don't go to cons that we only see at like friend events, then we have this other set of friends that we see at those things, but we also see at all the PAXes.
Scott: our friend group started as the college friend group, but largely thanks to GeekNights it succeeded in creating another friend group that merged, and to the point at which it doesn't at least to us, since we're at the center of the social circle, it doesn't feel like two different groups, but when you look at the list of like, here's the list of all my friends and I look at it, and it's like
Rym: people who fly to every PAX and people who don't.
Scott: well it's like RIT, RIT.
Scott: I met them because of GeekNights, I met them at a convention, I met, right?
Scott: And it's like, these are all equally close friends that are basically family and some of them are from college and some of them are from GeekNights convention meeting, right?
Scott: Because we had all those things we were able to form this you know, this group Yeah, so we actually succeeded in a lot of our goals.
Rym: like GeekNights is not crazy popular partly because we've never really tried like, we don't do ads, we haven't tried to monetize.
Rym: we never went pro, like We bought ads crappy banner ads once but we didn't really push it.
Rym: but yet it's still like just word of mouth and content alone, like GeekNights is pretty popular.
Scott: More than zero people pay attention.
Rym: Yeah, like, I got almost 10,000 people just on the YouTube, though weirdly most of the people who watch the YouTube don't seem to know we do a podcast.
Scott: Anyway, so the point is, is that you know, for pretty much all the 2010s the whole past decade we pretty much like just carried on with habit, right?
Scott: We didn't really try hard or change much or right, like we just kept doing what we were doing.
Rym: We got better at doing what we were doing but we weren't doing new things like, we kept doing the convention
Scott: panels We didn't change the format, you know, we started uploading more things to YouTube
Rym: We started doing more video, and when we get to the future bit, we'll talk about that, because we're going to start doing
Scott: a lot more video.
Scott: We tried to do a few things, like the pony show and the antenna show Which were really popular, like really popular.
Rym: but at the same time those things take a lot of effort and normal people do one thing like that, and that's their whole hobby like, most people will do a pony YouTube channel and that's it.
Rym: We're still doing GeekNights and we tried to do a pony show at the same time with the same production value.
Scott: Well, the other problem is that we got GeekNights to this point where, you know, it doesn't take effort to make it.
Scott: We can just sit down and it is created without any work.
Rym: Ever wonder why we rarely have guests on the show?
Scott: Most people We want to have lots of guests on the show.
Rym: You know why we don't have guest hosts?
Rym: Because unless you are a professional at the three things that we're professionals at, it takes like four to twelve times more effort and time to make a show to what.
Rym: that includes you.
Scott: The amount of time to make a GeekNights is the amount of time it takes for us to sit down, talk push a few extra buttons.
Rym: Sometimes I should record the post production process, like what it looks like today and it's looked like that for more than a decade.
Rym: Like, even when we were living in Beacon, I had this crazy.
Rym: You didn't have Creative Cloud then No, but I had a crazy Python script that I would run.
Rym: We'd finish GeekNights, I'd run this script.
Rym: It would edit the show together like, do everything.
Rym: It was amazing.
Scott: But the point is, we can't do video that way.
Scott: Video actually takes a lot of labor which is why I've fallen behind on doing any anime judging.
Scott: I've managed to streamlight that quite a bit and I have ideas a way to streamline it more to make it less work, but it's still a lot of work.
Scott: It's time consuming.
Rym: The only reason GeekNights takes zero effort is that we actually spent months designing our pipeline and building it out.
Scott: It's not just the technological production.
Rym: We designed things like, once we figured out the format, we were like, how do we make the format work?
Rym: How do we transition?
Scott: It's also that we can just sit down with no preparation no writing, no anything and as long as we come up with an idea which is the hard part, we can just immediately start talking and just push record and talk.
Rym: and honestly, at conventions, we can do that too.
Scott: If we bring another person, they can't do that.
Rym: Nope, you should see when we interview people or even bring them on the show, I won't name any names just because I'm not going to be mean but we've had some great shows with guest hosts or people on the show that we've interviewed.
Scott: Not many, but good ones.
Rym: I remember an interview we did once, it took me four hours just to edit them so they didn't sound stupid.
Rym: They're very smart, but they're not good at this.
Scott: and also, it's like we can just sit down whenever I just show up and we do it.
Scott: if we bring in more people we have to schedule it.
Scott: schedule at a specific time which makes the whole thing more time consuming even if they can just talk.
Scott: it fits right into your day.
Scott: if you just
Rym: show
Scott: up and record when you happen to show up and then leave as soon as you're done that doesn't really you don't lose a lot of time if you have a time, like we have to record with this person at seven and they're here for an hour.
Scott: well now I need to make sure I show up before seven and spend time before waiting for them and setting up for them and then after we have to spend more time.
Scott: it's exponential how difficult it is to add another person or even short form content.
Rym: you remember a while ago I did that video "Why Five Nights at Freddy's is Scary".
Rym: that took ten times the effort of a GeekNights episode because one, I had to do research real research then, I didn't write a script I didn't use my teleprompter but I had to at least decide what I was going to say.
Rym: so it would be a coherent visual and audio essay, it couldn't just be me bullshitting for an hour.
Rym: then I had to go play Five Nights at Freddy's for a week to get all the footage and assets that I needed.
Rym: then I had to video it, and that was before.
Rym: I had bought nice cameras and lights and things so it doesn't even look that good.
Rym: and then I had to do the preprocess, postprocess and all the bullshit and then put it on YouTube.
Rym: that took a long, it took me like two weeks to make that fucking video and honestly I could make a video like that once a week if I had a production crew and that was my full time job.
Rym: I could make one like once a day but we both work full time.
Rym: that's not changing in fact, another thing that's happened.
Scott: someone wants to send me mad money or a winning lottery ticket or something.
Rym: one thing that happened, I haven't talked about this a lot on the show because I work for a company where you can figure out where I work but it's good to keep a certain amount of separation.
Scott: there's so many things going on in the present, right?
Rym: yeah, one, the world's on fire.
Scott: yes, the world's on fire.
Rym: we're in a fucked up time right now where literal Nazis are like a real threat to American democracy and like the world order we may have to turn GeekNights into like Nazi killing radio, if necessary like, not gonna lie.
Rym: I have contingency plans to leave the country if certain things happen over the next several years.
Scott: Jim's plan is to run, Scott's plan is to fight Nazis.
Scott: I will defend New York until probably I die.
Scott: I will die defending New York from Nazis.
Rym: but I feel like Radio Free America is a skill that I could bring to the forefront more than like actually killing people if it came to like World War 3 like Nazi resistance.
Scott: I don't mean, you know, even though my I can't do one push up, right, so how much of a I'm not exactly.
Scott: I'm not exactly ready for Wolfenstein 3D.
Scott: I'm just saying metaphorically, I will stay in New York and defend New York against whatever fire on Earth comes.
Rym: let's just say that we're in a very politically and socially fraught time and we're on the precipice of potentially very bad things.
Scott: right, whatever attacks New York be it flood, right or whatever I'm just thinking like, Seinfeld, neither rain nor sleet.
Scott: no, it's the first one right, that is Scott's plan.
Rym: yep, two of the worlds also literal fire but three, like I got a new job a few years ago and I'm very good at my work, like I've never had to work hard at any job I've ever had before.
Rym: the job I have now is not that hard but it requires honestly more like mental effort while I'm at work than any job I have ever had just simply due to the sheer scope of my responsibilities.
Rym: what that means is that for most of my life until a couple years ago I had a lot of like down time at work to think about GeekNights' production pipeline stuff so that I'd already done the thinking, so when I get home and I have to like make a video pipeline to do a video, I've already done the hard work but now, I do
Scott: not.
Scott: yeah, but just at work you've only got the bad screen.
Scott: you gotta go to home with the good screen.
Rym: I barely even chat with our friends at work because I'm literally at work thinking about how do I solve this very complex political problem across six engineering teams and I have to think a lot at work, when previously when I had to work hard it was doing, because the thinking I'd already done all the thinking, so I don't have time at work to think about GeekNights' which means when I'm home, I can either do something that I'm already good at and produce something that I can deliver to all of you, or I can think about something but then I deliver nothing to you.
Rym: I don't create anything I just build a precursor to create something different.
Rym: so we've both I think been defaulting to creating the things that we can create and getting stuff out as opposed to building the pipeline to do something new.
Scott: Anyway, so the present is pretty much that we've just maintained the status quo for a long time, but the world's on fire, and things in life are changing.
Scott: but that doesn't mean we're just going to give up and be like, well, right, no.
Rym: GeekNights' is way too big a part of our lives to stop any time in the next decade or two.
Scott: At least my plan for the future.
Rym: Let's get to the future because we've already gone on for almost an hour.
Scott: We've got to do some changing, so this means changing all the things.
Scott: but I don't think.
Scott: previously, someone point one of our friends pointed this out to me and they were exactly right, is that previously we've always had sort of a. this is like, you know, computer, software engineer talk, right?
Scott: We've had a waterfall development model for GeekNights which is, what that means is you do plan, plan, plan, plan, plan, plan, plan.
Scott: you do all your planning, then all your building, and you build the perfect thing and then you release it all.
Rym: Which I think is our flaw, like that Five Nights at Freddy's video, if I just sat down at the webcam and just fucking did it like unscripted in one go
Scott: right, now, if you look out in the world of people following that model even going to the moon doesn't follow that model, it was like they sort of did, right?
Scott: They built the whole rocket and then they launch it, but they took 11 rockets right?
Scott: They incrementally developed right?
Scott: And some of them didn't go very well, right?
Scott: And there were other rockets besides those 11 but you get the idea, right?
Scott: So I think what we had to do, and I've also, another thing I was discussing today, I forget where I read this so I can't link it, sadly, people were talking about, you know, shit talk which is something we've talked about in Ignite since the beginning.
Rym: I read that same article.
Scott: you were talking about Shit talk and crab people, which is basically you talk about that thing you're going to do, I've got a plan for this project, you need to tell everyone about it, right?
Rym: But we've always had a role, we very rarely talk about things until we've actually started on them.
Scott: Well, the thing is, I'm always in favor of being public, because I look at so many companies and things, keeping things unnecessarily private and secret, and I want to prove them wrong, that like, no, you don't have to keep things private and secret, you can be completely open about everything you're doing, and it won't somehow hurt you, your competitors won't steal your idea, like Apple could give us daily updates on like, you know, what the next iPhone's going to be, and it wouldn't hurt them at all, that's what I believe anyway Right?
Scott: So I want to be that way, that I believe, to demonstrate that I'm right, but the thing is I learned that psychologically speaking, if you say what you're going to do, right, just like on a personal level, psychologically it makes you feel like you've done it, and now you're less likely to do it, and it's more likely to become shit talk.
Scott: So I want to be open about plans and what we're thinking, but I also don't want to say, oh, we're going to like make a video show about this, and then end up not doing it or doing it less, because psychologically we now feel accomplished when we haven't accomplished anything.
Rym: Which I think the point there is that right now, we're going to talk about vision and strategy, but we're not going to talk about specifics.
Scott: Right, and that's because actually I don't want to do any specific thing.
Scott: I have so many ideas all the time for things, and I end up doing like none of them.
Scott: So my idea is, you know, starting now-ish, right, is why do we have to follow some format?
Scott: where there's like, we have a show with a name, and it has episodes, or we have a thing, like a project, and we keep doing it.
Rym: Look at the show, look at all those things.
Rym: They still were like Radio Free Equestria, Episode 1, Episode 2, Episode 3.
Scott: I'm just going to make whatever I feel like making whenever I feel like making it.
Scott: If I just feel like, you know, you're looking like Twitch streamers.
Scott: They always got to stream on a schedule, and they got to stream.
Scott: No, you know what?
Scott: If I feel like streaming right now, I'll just turn the stream randomly.
Scott: I don't got to announce it.
Scott: I'm just going to, whenever.
Scott: I feel like playing this game today.
Scott: You didn't get to see me finish streaming that game yet.
Scott: I didn't feel like finishing streaming the rest of it.
Scott: I'm playing a different game today.
Scott: I'm going to stream that.
Rym: Well, like that War Group thing.
Rym: I started streaming like every mission in War Group, and I was going to do a thing in episodes.
Rym: But I'm busy.
Rym: Fuck that.
Rym: If I play War Group, I'll stream it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I feel like making a video about this thing.
Scott: I make that video.
Scott: I never make another video like that ever again.
Rym: Whatev.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I'm going to post some photos.
Rym: I took some photos, I'm going to post them.
Rym: Not to say we're not going to plan, because one thing we are going to do is we're going to build, one thing we are going to build.
Rym: This is specific.
Scott: The point is I'm going for quantity.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Just make stuff and put out stuff.
Rym: But, think back to early GeekNights.
Rym: What we did spend a lot of time planning was the production pipeline to create a podcast like mechanically, regardless of what the content was.
Rym: Right.
Scott: I got to be, if I'm going to stream at random times or make videos at random times.
Rym: I need to be able to sit down here and go "boop" and everything is just working.
Scott: We have to set up stuff so that I can just do those things as soon as I think to do those things.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Before that momentum is gone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I can just set the thing up and do it right away with very little effort.
Scott: Load it up, upload it and be done.
Scott: One, two, three.
Scott: As easy as you know, like if I'm sitting at home with nothing to do and I say "You know what?
Scott: I got an
Scott: idea.".
Scott: Just do it as easily as I do this GeekNights.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So I'm not going to plan to do a particular video show, but what I am going to plan a lot is what is the hardware, software and setup to as quickly as possible, if Scott and I want to make a video together, how quickly can we just set up a standard kit that just works so we immediately start making the content.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Make all kinds of things in all sorts of mediums and all sorts of platforms, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I'm trying to use our social medias more, our Instagrams and Twitter or whatever.
Scott: We have Facebook, but I'm not going to put any work into the Facebook.
Scott: It's an automatic thing.
Rym: But to be clear, we are going to just keep doing GeekNights, like the show, because this costs us nothing.
Scott: But also, you know, GeekNights format, right?
Scott: It's like, we're not going to waterfall it and just be like "Okay, all new GeekNights format, but you know what?
Scott: We'll just change things over time.
Scott: If it works, we'll roll it back.
Scott: If it doesn't work, we'll roll it, you know,
Scott: whatever.".
Rym: One thing to our credit, I listened to those early episodes, once we locked the format down, I think our format, like the format of this for a podcast that is like buy Weet-Bolt twice a week, it's a really good format.
Scott: Right, but we don't have to feel like there's some law, like we must stay in this structure.
Scott: We can just do whatever we feel like doing.
Rym: Though, that's not to say that that is good advice for all of you, because the reason we are so good at this is because we set up this structure and we just fucking did it four nights a week for years and years and years.
Rym: Like, we forced ourselves.
Scott: Originally, we said at the very beginning of GeekNights, I was like "Look at those Penny Arcade
Scott: guys.".
Rym: Yep, they just made a comic.
Rym: and how shitty it was.
Scott: They make a three-panel comic and they make it three days a week no matter what.
Scott: We have to do the same thing.
Scott: And we didn't.
Scott: we're not as consistent as them.
Scott: But we're consistent enough that it works.
Rym: It really did work.
Rym: And we need to build the pipeline to easily make video, build the pipeline to easily start streams.
Rym: But what we do with that is you're just going to have to see.
Rym: We got ideas, we're not going to shit talk them until we just do them.
Scott: And also the things around GeekNights.
Scott: So I don't know, for anyone who's listening, right, so we got.
Scott: Rym has a YouTube channel.
Scott: I have a different YouTube channel.
Scott: There is actually a GeekNights YouTube channel.
Rym: We lost it.
Scott: I think I can access it maybe.
Scott: But I don't know if we need to.
Rym: The tricky part is most of our followers of video are following my channel because that's where I put all the panels.
Scott: Right, but yeah, I also have channel.
Scott: You know, and it's not like I can upload to Rym's channel.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: I have a Twitch channel.
Scott: I don't remember the last time I used it.
Rym: I'm not going to keep streaming on YouTube.
Scott: Usually when I stream, I use like this restream thing that streams to Twitch and YouTube.
Scott: There's also, who knows, maybe I'll try the mixer thing.
Scott: Maybe another site will appear.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: Yeah, you got to follow us on Twitter or Instagram, which I guess are the social Instagram, technically Facebook, but whatever.
Rym: Yup, just follow us everywhere.
Rym: And stay tuned for like basic stuff.
Rym: We are going to restructure.
Scott: Most of the time we tweet when a thing happens.
Scott: Right, so every GeekNights episode gets tweeted.
Scott: Every news post gets tweeted.
Scott: Every video we upload gets tweeted.
Scott: That's the number one way to see what's going.
Scott: I'm going to try to get GeekNights on Spotify.
Scott: It's on all the other podcasting places and the RSS feed.
Rym: But again, the only reason we are not, like we're on iTunes and everything else, but the reason we're not on a few platforms is because we're too old.
Scott: Our shit is so old school with RSS that new shit doesn't work.
Rym: And because we're busy, I'm trying to fix it.
Rym: We do need to make a lot of changes to the web pipeline.
Scott: We're going to, right, we're going to redo the website.
Scott: We have a new, we had a great graphic designer come and help us.
Rym: Many of you have seen, like, if you've seen us at a con, or like you've seen, like, bit by bit our logos are all updating in places.
Scott: Right, we're doing slow changes.
Scott: We're not just dumping this huge rebrand, right?
Scott: We redid all our business cards and our flyers.
Scott: We got a new logo.
Scott: We updated the avatars and the social media side.
Scott: We're still doing more of that.
Rym: But see this philosophy.
Rym: Old Rym and Skaad would have not updated anything until everything was ready.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But now, yep, our YouTube channel Whatever, we're not making money on this.
Scott: Let's just roll it out as we can.
Rym: We are making money, but not that much money.
Scott: Oh, you're taking all that money.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm also paying for the Libsyn.
Scott: I'm still not in favor of Patreon for GeekNights.
Rym: Well, I'm going to start putting.
Scott: Patreon is for people who, you know, need the money, like starving artist people.
Scott: Ah, but.
Scott: It's not for people who got the money.
Rym: I am putting, that money is going to be used to do, like, I paid for all the graphic design stuff with that.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: And.
Scott: But you could have afforded to pay for it yourself.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you didn't need that money.
Scott: But I do Stop giving him money.
Rym: I do have a goal in the end.
Rym: I would like to.
Scott: If you hadn't given it to him, he would have paid for the graphic design with his own money.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I would have made you pay for half of it.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I have money.
Rym: But the thing is, we're going to start paying for those kinds of things more often to accelerate ourselves.
Scott: Yeah, we paid the graphic designer a lot of money by the way.
Rym: Because another problem we have, like, this is getting back to past and present, is that because we literally made everything ourselves in the beginning, except like we paid some artists for a few things, but like, we made our whole website ourselves.
Rym: We made like everything.
Scott: I'm probably still going to end up making the website myself.
Rym: Yeah, but.
Scott: At least the backend.
Rym: When it makes sense, we're going to hire people to help us, because.
Scott: If you want to help us, let us know.
Rym: But we personally cannot be good at everything.
Rym: we need to be good at to make some of the content we want to make while still having full-time jobs.
Rym: Like, I'm a pretty good videographer.
Scott: I really want to pay someone to transcribe all our stuff and I've found people who will do it, but the problem is just the total amount of money, because we have so many episodes, they will never be able to do all of it.
Rym: Oh, here's a harder problem.
Rym: I would love to just pay camera people to video all our shit for us at conventions.
Rym: The problem is, most conventions, if anyone touches the camera that's recording us while we're on stage, the union's going to fuck us over and we, even with Patreon money, we can't afford to pay off the union.
Rym: We'd have to literally, like at PAX Unplugged, we'd literally have to pay, like, two people of wage to stand next to our camera.
Rym: So, some things we can't actually fix yet.
Rym: Right.
Scott: I brought back, recently, the GeekNights newsletter, which you may not know exists.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right, because someone reminded me the website Tiny Letter exists and I'm like, "Oh,
Scott: yeah!".
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That's what I use for the GeekNights newsletter.
Rym: I'm bringing back Rym's Rants for once a week.
Rym: I just, whatever's on my mind just goes to the Patreon, which is there.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I'm going to talk about this next to the following.
Scott: I don't know what Rym's is saying in Rym's Rants, because I don't pay him to see the Patreon.
Rym: People like him.
Scott: But, yeah, you should not listen to anything he says.
Scott: Whatever he says is wrong.
Scott: He's lying.
Scott: I don't know what it is.
Scott: It's wrong.
Rym: Watch, you like sneak in, like someone gives you a dollar and it's just like, "Man, Scott's so
Rym: good.".
Scott: Yeah, if people are listening to this as an MP3, I don't know if you know, but we just stream every, as we're recording every episode of GeekNights, we stream it on YouTube so you can watch it live whenever that happens to me.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: There's ten people watching this live right now and these things get a few hundred views.
Scott: I don't know why they're watching.
Scott: I gotta have something better to do, but okay, there they are.
Rym: One thing you get, the self-deprecating joke can only take you so far, because you just said, "We're going to try
Rym: hard.".
Scott: It's not a joke, though.
Rym: We're going to try hard, but don't ever look at anything we try hard on.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: It's about me enjoying making stuff.
Scott: It's not saying that you should be paying attention to it.
Rym: You're just being sad-piro.
Rym: No.
Rym: Just drawing sad girls in snow.
Rym: Telling people not to look at them.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: Come and see whatever we make, but actually don't.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I'll put it this way.
Rym: The show you're watching or listening to right now is going to keep going as it's going, but a lot of other stuff is just going to appear.
Rym: Some of them might succeed.
Rym: Some of them might fail.
Rym: I'm investing in the technology and hardware to ease the production pipeline on the kinds of new content we're going to do.
Rym: I think I'm finally going to give up on using a giant physical mixer board because we do not need that because the kinds of things I need that mixer board for are things we're not doing anymore.
Rym: That mixer is going to get busted out when we run a convention someday.
Rym: And I need that mixer board to be in the live room.
Rym: Part of that is because technology got better.
Rym: Cameras are cheaper.
Rym: Equipment's cheaper.
Rym: USB-C, like modern audio input devices, are good now.
Rym: They weren't that good a couple of years ago.
Scott: So the last thing is the gig nights community.
Scott: I don't know if people realize, so when we started gig nights, it's like, whoa, obviously we should have a community.
Scott: Every thing had a community.
Scott: It's usually its own web forum or news group or newsletter where people could reply or something like that.
Scott: In those days, that was the only way to have a community.
Scott: If you were listening to a thing and you wanted to get together with other people who were following that thing, you would go to a forum for the thing.
Scott: So we had this forum and the forum has.
Scott: it's been archived and it still exists and there's still people there and a community is formed.
Rym: There's a terrifying amount of content in this old forum.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But yeah, the forum's been going since 2005.
Scott: And people have come.
Scott: People have gone.
Scott: We've met people.
Scott: We've lost people, whatever things dramatically.
Scott: It's like a whole thing of its own.
Rym: We moved to new forum software.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like a whole separate thing from the show.
Scott: A lot of people in there don't even listen to the show.
Scott: There's a lot of people lurking in there.
Rym: Yeah, most people lurk.
Rym: Holy shit, a lot of people read the forum with accounts but never post.
Scott: Well, it's also completely public to the internet.
Scott: It's not something where only registered people get in.
Rym: But a lot of people have accounts but never post.
Rym: But I can see in the logs, they come every day and read it for credit.
Scott: If you want to register, make sure when you register for it, it's totally free.
Scott: You just have to type.
Scott: There's gonna be a box, like a reason for joining the forum.
Scott: You have to type something in there.
Scott: that makes me click the approve button because I think, ah yes, this is a real person who knows who we are and not some bot trying to make an account to spam.
Rym: Scott, are we saying that they can look forward to the listener more tech news roundup in 2020?
Scott: No, you can't.
Scott: Maybe less.
Scott: But anyway, that was the extent of our community.
Scott: And I think it's been 15 years.
Scott: I think now, if you are the person who makes content, your community exists not in a forum that you make.
Scott: It exists in social media.
Scott: People tweet at you.
Scott: People reply.
Scott: People comment on your Instagram posts.
Rym: I'm telling you something crazy.
Scott: People in your YouTube comments, that's where your community exists.
Rym: Our YouTube comments, like on my channel, that is an amazing fucking community.
Rym: Go look at the comments on our YouTube videos.
Scott: Those people aren't in the forum.
Rym: They don't even know the forum exists.
Rym: Half of them don't even know the podcast exists.
Scott: If you're a new content thing, you know, today, not from 2005, that's where you have your community.
Scott: So, the forum itself has sort of lagged because people don't need it, you know, various reasons.
Rym: Yeah, but here's a specific technical reason.
Rym: Over time, our website eventually broke in a way to where the episodes on the website don't actually link to their forum threads.
Scott: I don't think that's such a big deal.
Rym: It's one of the funnels.
Scott: It's a deal.
Rym: We lost a funnel.
Scott: The point is...
Rym: Also, most people don't even know we have a website.
Scott: Right, people don't use the website or forums or anything, right?
Scott: So, community-wise, I think we have to, you know, get with the times and update and now engage more with our community and YouTube comments, you know, social media posts, right?
Scott: The newsletter, if you reply to the newsletter via email, I see that.
Scott: That's how a tiny letter works.
Scott: And so, like, that's how you can give feedback on that and then I can address it in the next newsletter.
Scott: But yeah, reply.
Scott: Don't worry.
Scott: You can come to the forum if you want.
Scott: It's going to exist.
Scott: We're going to make changes to it.
Scott: We don't know what those changes will be.
Scott: Other than that, they will be slow and numerous.
Rym: Yeah, we got a good idea of the strategy, but execution is going to take us a while.
Scott: We're going to move the forum in different directions.
Scott: If you're in the forum and you don't like those directions, I'm sorry.
Rym: Not going to lie, tough shit, because a fundamental thing I see is that the GeekNights community, like the people who are just fans of this, are not like, the people in the forum generally don't listen to the show.
Rym: No.
Rym: But the people who listen to the show are not in the forum and the people in the forum are increasingly just using it as a place to hang out, which is not really what we wanted ever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We do have a subreddit that I'm the moderator of.
Scott: that is rarely posted in.
Rym: I think we're going to start using that more.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: But it's posted in more than zero, but it's extremely rare.
Rym: There's a GeekNights Discord.
Rym: that's like, people are in there hanging out.
Rym: I'm in there.
Rym: I mostly lurk, but I'm in there.
Scott: Yeah, there is an official GeekNights Discord.
Scott: It's actually adminned by a trusted listener because we didn't create it.
Scott: But, yeah.
Scott: It's there.
Scott: We have knighted it as the official, you know, public GeekNights Discord.
Scott: You can find it and get in there and see what's up.
Scott: We'll see what happens with that if more people go there or not.
Scott: It has not much activity.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: So.
Scott: But, yeah.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: GeekNights is gonna steamroll on, but everything around GeekNights, other than the show itself, is going to evolve.
Scott: The show will also evolve.
Rym: Yeah, but the show will evolve less, I think, because the format's so easy.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: It's so easy to make this.
Scott: We'll try a thing now and then.
Rym: Can we do the lounge?
Scott: No.
Scott: That's a thing.
Scott: we'll undo the lounge.
Scott: In fact, I hereby cancel the lounge.
Rym: I'm gonna call this episode the lounge.
Scott: The lounge is hereby cancelled.
Rym: No more lounge.
Rym: Hereby uncancelled.
Rym: No.
Scott: Here's the problem.
Scott: Lounge over.
Scott: Rip rip lounge.
Rym: The problem with GeekNights is that we have equal say and there's no way to break a tie.
Scott: Rip lounge.
Rym: Lounge forever.
Rym: Long live the lounge.
Scott: The triple L. Here's the lounge's grave.
Scott: Watch me rub my butt on it.
Rym: Yeah, so keep an eye on us.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: I know it's been a while.
Rym: This was one of the worst hiatus we've had in a long time, but we are back.
Rym: We are back.
Rym: As you saw, there's gonna be a lot of new content.
Rym: Stay tuned for all this fun stuff we're working on.
Rym: Maybe a zine.
Rym: I'll shit talk a little bit because Scott never listens to this part.
Rym: We're looking at doing a zine at cons.
Rym: We're looking at doing a lot of really focused board game videos, not just on how to learn games, but also live streams of us playing games, talks on how to be good at specific games, all that kind of nonsense.
Rym: But stay tuned.
Rym: The Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, JustLikeADude, Guy Kjortofsion, Link Kije, Hydrated Gannon, Supports Hong Kong, Chris Midkif, MyStacy.com, Jay Benz, Sean Yeager, Nicholas Brandau, YouHoldTheCrayToMyHeart, 421 Creations, Started Making Trouble In My Neighborhood, Shervin Von Harl, Superboy, Clinton Walton, Renn from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Droban Lander, Finn, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn, and now, I leave you with... What is this wonderful noise?
Rym: Those are the joyful screams of people on a roller coaster.
Rym: Human screams are my favorite of the Earth's delights.
Rym: I want to hear the human screams forever.
Rym: Okay, that's kind of troubling.
Rym: But your heart's in the right place.
Rym: One day, I'll make you scream, Steven.