Rym: It's Wednesday, February 5th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight Weathering With You, a film by Makoto Shinkai.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: I just want to point out that, uh, you know in GeekNights we always have this thing at the beginning of the show where we just talk about something like, "I was
Rym: bikin'!"
Rym: or "I ate a good
Rym: food!"
Rym: like whatever, like stuff, like the banter.
Scott: Usually, usually it's something that we sit down to do the show and someone just remembers.
Scott: We try to remember something recent or from the day.
Rym: Like, "Did anything happen to
Rym: me?".
Scott: But sometimes something happens and you're like, "That was a thing.
Scott: I can't forget.
Scott: the next GeekNights is far away.
Scott: I must tell the other person or perhaps digitally record to remember because remember the
Scott: thing.".
Rym: We are like fish.
Rym: No matter how, if something amazing happens to either of us and then something else happens before we do the next GeekNights, whatever that amazing thing was, it's just gone.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Gone forever, like tears in the rain.
Scott: All right, so I managed to remember a thing.
Scott: So I went to this, they're in Queens, right?
Scott: They're changing all the bus routes like from scratch.
Scott: So the MTA is like, "All right, erase the bus map.
Scott: Let's draw a new bus route map from nothing to be as good as possible and then let's go out and see what the people think and then let's do workshops and we'll work on it for like a year or
Scott: so.".
Rym: And then we're like, "This is real important 'cause Queens like buses are real important in New
Rym: York.".
Scott: If you aren't close enough to walk to the subway or the subway near you doesn't go where you want to go, right, the bus is real important.
Scott: As some neighborhoods, like there is just no subway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you don't have a car.
Rym: Part of why my rent is so high is while I have a- You don't want to take a cab everywhere.
Rym: My apartment costs more than Scotts and is not as nice as Scotts, but because it's next to a subway station, like that's the selling point.
Scott: Only by a few blocks.
Scott: Anyway, so I go to this local townie community government meeting, right?
Scott: You know, a state senator, not my state senator, but the adjacent state senator.
Scott: This badass lady, she's there.
Rym: But still, think about this.
Rym: This is like the local town discussion for a borough of a city that itself has 2.2 million people in it.
Scott: Well, no, one neighborhood of Queens.
Scott: It was just like Astoria, you know, only.
Rym: So, okay, so let's see.
Scott: So, it filled the meeting room of an old folks home full of folding chairs, right?
Scott: Alright.
Rym: So, a neighborhood that has 10,000 people in it.
Scott: Yeah, you know, like it would be like the equivalent- Wait, no, that's a different Astoria.
Rym: That's Astoria, Oregon.
Rym: I was about to say 10,000 seem low.
Scott: Yeah, it's way low.
Rym: A neighborhood of 120,000 people.
Scott: Right, yeah.
Scott: So, I go, you know, the local politicians are there, right?
Scott: My city councilman, who is trying to become borough president, shows up for five minutes and leaves, right?
Scott: You know, my Albany representative in the assembly, she's there.
Scott: She's got plenty of time.
Rym: I always see her- I like to go to things like this.
Rym: I always wanted to when we lived upstate, but they always scheduled them while I was at work.
Rym: That's how only old people could go.
Scott: Anyway, the point is I had to go because MTA representatives are there and I need to use this bus.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And, you know, I had to find out the info about this bus.
Scott: It was kind of important to my everyday life.
Scott: So, that'll get you out of the house to go to a townie thing.
Rym: Yup, and they're going to like every, like there's a million of these meetings.
Scott: Oh, yeah, there's tons of them, right?
Scott: And there have been a bunch before, right?
Scott: So, first of all, right, as you would expect what the composition of the room, whatever you're imagining the composition of the room to be, right?
Scott: Add some diversity because it's Queens.
Rym: Yup, I imagine a lot of angry old people yelling about nonsense.
Scott: Remember, it is in an old folks home and yeah, at least half old folks.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right, but yeah, you know, you have people who with reasonable complaint, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Almost, I thought I was going to be one of the only people there.
Scott: I was like, man, I have to go because it's the meetings like in sort of near where I used to live, closer to the subway.
Scott: I got to make sure there's some representation from Western Queens who are taking away this one bus.
Rym: Yeah, Western Queens is growing like in population.
Scott: From people near the water, right?
Scott: They're taking away this bus.
Scott: I got to go and be like, hey, don't take away this bus, right?
Rym: Even I care about this bus.
Scott: Me, the Rym who hates buses.
Scott: I don't think you've ever taken the 103 in your life.
Rym: I think I have.
Scott: You would need it if you wanted to go to the Astoria ferry, but you just go to the LIC ferry.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Oh, I'm thinking of the bus that took me to College Point.
Rym: It's not the 103.
Scott: I don't know what bus you're talking about.
Scott: Anyway, so I'm thinking I'm going to be the ones like represent that bus, right?
Scott: And, you know, be like, hey, we got to get to the water.
Scott: How can I get to the, you know, my city councilman.
Scott: The first thing he says is like, yeah, 103, what the hell?
Scott: And then the MTA guy, before he even starts, he's like, all right, who here is here to complain about the 103 and the 90% of the rumors.
Scott: He's like, he's like, the ridership has been real low.
Scott: And I'm like, yeah, it's because you only run that off.
Scott: You only run it that often.
Scott: So everyone doesn't bother to wait for it.
Scott: It's a, you know, it's a induced demand or, you know, the opposite of induced demand.
Scott: When you make something sucks and no one uses it.
Rym: Most mass transit in America has that problem.
Rym: They make it suck and then no one rides it.
Rym: But if they made it better, everyone would ride it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So anyway, so the funny comment number one that I heard at least two or three times was angry, really somewhat angry, really upset and frustrated person.
Scott: be like, you know, you guys, how can you put this on us?
Scott: You know, changing all the bus routes we depend on.
Scott: You don't come to the community.
Scott: It's like they're literally coming to the community.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This is them coming to the community.
Scott: They already said this is like a draft.
Scott: And this not what won't happen this year and might not even happen next year.
Scott: And they're still working on it.
Scott: And here they are to hear what you have to say of their just first draft.
Scott: And this they explained how they came up with it, trying to make buses straighter and have less traffic and all that, you know, right.
Scott: They explained to you the whole thing and they're here to hear from you.
Scott: And people like, how come you don't come in here from us?
Scott: It's like, OK, multiple people said that this is why I don't trust people.
Scott: And these are and those are people who go to a community meeting.
Scott: One hundred percent of that room was voted.
Scott: Yeah, for sure.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: Anyway, the one comment that was just I could not ignore that makes it open a bit worthy was some crazy dude.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's crazy.
Scott: He was recording the meeting on his iPad.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: OK.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It's an important meeting on his iPad.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He's recording everything.
Rym: Well, he's he's making his kill list, probably.
Scott: I don't know what this guy's doing.
Scott: So he's like, he's like, it tastes like I've been to all these meetings.
Scott: This guy's going around to MTA meetings, like all of them, apparently.
Rym: I mean, I could see myself doing that.
Scott: And he says, how come you don't answer the question right that we all want answered?
Scott: He's like, you never answer us.
Scott: And I'm like, us who?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Speak for yourself, bro.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The royal us.
Scott: And he starts talking about something that is a true, but I didn't know it until now.
Scott: And then be completely crazy after that.
Scott: He starts off completely true and I learned something.
Scott: So he's valuable education.
Scott: And then he goes off the deep end.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So he starts and he talks about, uh, when they, you know, when Bloomberg conglomerated the buses and I'm like, what?
Scott: Well, so we always talk about how the subway has like the IRT.
Scott: They used to be the IRT and the BMD independent line.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The buses used to be all private buses.
Scott: And they were not combined into the MTA until like, yes, Bloomberg, like 2005, six, seven.
Rym: Which is probably another reason why our buses kind of.
Scott: There were buses like queen surface and they'd said queen surface on them.
Scott: And that was a bus and it wasn't a public bus also.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I didn't know this.
Scott: Some of the buses that still run that look, they just look like a city bus.
Scott: You get on them.
Scott: It's a city bus.
Scott: You use your Metro card.
Scott: It looks perfect.
Scott: It looks like it's a public bus in all ways.
Scott: Is operated by a private bus company, right?
Rym: Like the early days of the IRT being run by the MTA.
Scott: It would be as if there was still an IRT company.
Scott: And there was people working there and they, and they operated trains.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That said on them, MTA, New York city transit subway, but there's a private company being paid to operate them.
Scott: So there's still buses like that somewhere.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So apparently what happened is they bought out all these private bus companies and incorporated them into this MTA bus company, but there's actually two bus companies and there was some shenanigans.
Scott: There's like M. they formed the MTA bus company.
Scott: And then this other one.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So I learned all that stuff from this dude.
Scott: But then this dude went off the rails with some, not, you know, not as crazy as a sovereign citizen saying the law doesn't matter, but possibly making up things out of whole cloth.
Rym: He said, might just be an R W N J.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But he said that when the buses were all combined, right, there was some agreement that they would not remove bus lines or merge them into New York city transit.
Scott: And therefore the MTA doesn't have the power to redo all the bus routes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It could be sued by the union if the union wanted to Sue or something.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: And I was like, uh, and then the MTA guy obviously doesn't answer the question.
Rym: Well, the MTA guy is probably just like waiting.
Scott: Like I recognize that the MTA guy obviously had heard the same guy several times before and is not as a bus route expert and not a lawyer for the MTA.
Rym: Pretty sure that guy is going to be in long Island city tonight.
Rym: Oh, they're doing ours tonight.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: At six, I could miss a missus happening right now.
Rym: That guy is probably right now at Jacob Reese.
Scott: Well, there's like a long presentation before question time.
Rym: He's sitting in the audience with his iPad right now waiting.
Scott: Anyway, the point is that, uh, the MTA guy was just like, yeah, I can't answer any questions about that.
Scott: We're here to talk about these bus routes and whether the new routes work for you or if you want, you know, how you think we should adjust them or change them or make new ones or what's missing, you know?
Scott: Uh, but it's like most of the people were just like, you know, they would, you know, regardless of how they would ask their question, like, you know, some exasperated person was like, uh, I have to go to mass, but then you took away the mass bus or you're not connecting the neighborhood.
Scott: These neighborhoods have a connection.
Scott: And the MTA guy is just like, all right, so we need, we still need a connection between Astoria and mass bath.
Scott: I gotcha.
Scott: He would just, he would just extract the actual route related suggestion from whatever crazy long rant he had to listen to.
Scott: And then you're like, okay, you want to route to mass bed?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: And he would just quietly listen while the person ran it, whoever long.
Scott: Uh, and that was that, but yeah, crazy dude is no matter what thing is being discussed at the townie meeting, there's always going to be some crazy person.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I, uh, my few experiences going to state good fight.
Rym: Same.
Scott: I did a cursory internet search and I could find nothing about an agreement not to move, emerge, or it is very sovereign.
Scott: It's always this idea, like who's someone who thinks they know some laws.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: This is a made up stuff.
Rym: Well, it's all.
Scott: therefore it's always, there is a do this and that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's always, there is a technicality that is too difficult to explain.
Rym: that therefore undermines the legitimacy of a very legitimate.
Scott: I'll say some magic words.
Scott: Now the government has to do a thing, right?
Rym: I did not make rejoinder with this bus.
Rym: I am a prime, a free man traveling on the land.
Scott: And obviously what he was saying was less crazy than what actual sovereign citizens say, but it was still, but it's the same sort of logic of magic words made up thing.
Rym: Therefore law, you can't do it when people like that, like, especially in this case, like what does he want?
Rym: Because you don't want independent bus lines.
Rym: That's garbage.
Rym: Like you want one cop thing to run all the mass transit.
Rym: Right.
Rym: But here's the thing, right?
Scott: So if they had a subway, like kind of like has problems because of this, well, it's like, you know, okay, we have, but we, they're trying to improve the bus line, whether they're doing a good job or not is debatable.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's.
Scott: obviously it's not perfect.
Scott: It's also a first draft.
Scott: If they just had a meeting to come and say, suggest changes to the current bus line, there would be a packed meeting of the same crazy ranting people.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So why, if they have a meeting, we're going to change it.
Scott: People come crazy and rant, put it back the way it was.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So if you say, put it back the way it was and make no changes and leave everything as is, then I expect if we have a meeting on how to change the current bus line, we're going to, or otherwise you're leaving it the way it is.
Scott: I expect you to stay home because you think the current bus line is perfect.
Scott: Great.
Rym: They want everything to be different and they want nothing to change.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: The same person would complain at both meetings.
Scott: In my experience, these people, how come the bus doesn't come enough, right?
Scott: We're going to change the routes and hopefully try to fix some of these problems and work with DOT maybe.
Scott: No change.
Scott: How come you're changing the bus line?
Scott: What am I life undoing my life?
Rym: No take, only throw.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: One, the one thing that I did here at the, the meeting that, you know, cause a lot of the things they complained about were things I also complained about, but the MTA at least, you know, appeared to have actually known these things, right?
Scott: Like I was going to be like, ah, 21st street.
Scott: They're like, yeah, we're working with the MTA on 21st street.
Scott: They had already preemptively thought they were like, you know, accessibility.
Scott: Everyone was like, eh, you know, I can't get around.
Scott: I'm an old person.
Scott: There's no elevators at the subway.
Scott: Even if I can get on the subway at Astoria Boulevard, let me finish the elevator.
Scott: Where the hell can I get off?
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's no elevator where I'm going.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right.
Rym: The terrifying and sad thing about the New York city subway is a disability activist a while ago made this great map that showed the map of the New York city subway.
Rym: If you're in a wheelchair.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And on one hand, it's way sparser than the full subway, but on the other hand, that map by itself is a better mass transit system than any other city in America.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's still garbage though.
Scott: Uh, but the point is some billions from upstate.
Scott: One thing, a lot of people complained about that the MTA did not take into consideration and didn't have like a, they didn't have like a response to that.
Scott: Like all the people like accessibility, they were like, yeah, we knew you were going to say that 21st street.
Scott: We knew you were going to say that, right?
Scott: When people, the thing that they messed up was that New York city buses, a lot of kids use that to go to school and there's a lot of bus stops around schools and there's a lot of, you know, and kids will often get on a bus, right?
Scott: Take the bus and get off at school.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that's how they do.
Scott: And by changing the buses to be less and more straight kids are going to have to make transfers.
Scott: They don't know how to make or the bus stop won't be right next to the school.
Scott: And a kid might have to walk like two blocks to get to the school.
Scott: And that might not be a problem for like high school or middle school even, but elementary school, but it's a problem for, you know, it's definitely a problem.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I think a lot of the bus routes originally, or a lot of the school placements originally, that is why we're done, you know, in concert.
Rym: And now they, you know, well, this gets back to a broader point where a lot of people who don't know anything about mass transit try to argue that buses are more flexible than trains.
Rym: And that's bullshit because the real argument would be trains by the nature of their inflexibility guarantee access to a route.
Rym: It's hard to move a train line.
Rym: So you naturally build infrastructure around the paths of rail.
Rym: Whereas a bus route, if you build infrastructure on a bus route, if it changes, all your infrastructure is now fucked.
Scott: But yeah, they didn't seem to realize that on Vernon Boulevard, there's all these buildings under construction.
Scott: They're like, "No one uses the Vernon Boulevard bus.
Scott: It's gone
Scott: bye-bye.".
Scott: And everyone's like, "No.
Scott: How are we going to get to the ferry?
Scott: How are we going to get to the park?
Scott: How are we going to get to any of the water
Scott: stuff?".
Rym: Also, there's going to be an infinite number of apartments there before too long.
Scott: It's like three giant apartment buildings.
Scott: One's done, but no one lives in it yet.
Scott: And two are under construction.
Scott: You're going to need something over there because those people, right?
Rym: Well, you know, we need over there.
Rym: We need a new subway line that goes through all of Australia and Queens and down into Brooklyn.
Scott: Well, instead they're building, they're trying to build a somewhat corrupt light rail.
Scott: that's not the subway.
Rym: I would be okay with a bunch of trams and light rails in the city if they were also building a bunch more full subways.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: Anyway, this isn't the New York City Transit Show.
Scott: So, the news.
Rym: So, "Ride Your Waves" is in theaters in the US.
Scott: Well, it's going to be in theaters on one day.
Scott: So, it's a new movie directed by Masaaki Yuasa, new anime.
Scott: I guess it's not new.
Scott: It's been out for a while.
Rym: We mentioned it on the last GeekNights.
Scott: It came out in Japan.
Scott: when?
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: Maybe sometime.
Scott: 2019.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: June.
Rym: June 2019.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, now it's going to be in English in the US in the theaters with subtitles on February 19th and only February 19th.
Scott: Now, Masaaki Yuasa has never steered me wrong.
Rym: Nope.
Scott: Everything Masaaki Yuasa has touched with their directorial hand has been gold or gold adjacent.
Rym: But "Walk on Girl" I think is my favorite?
Scott: Yep, maybe.
Scott: But I haven't finished watching "Tatami
Scott: Galaxy."
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Which is "Walk on Girl" adjacent.
Rym: "Walk on Girl" long form.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or "Walk on Girl the
Rym: Wanderers."
Rym: Right.
Rym: There's an anime reference.
Rym: None of you are old enough to remember.
Scott: "Ride Your Wave," based on what I can tell about it.
Scott: I didn't actually watch the trailer.
Scott: Perhaps I should.
Scott: Appears to be the most boring Masaaki Yuasa.
Scott: It's just like a romantic comedy about a girl and a guy.
Scott: It's very hetero.
Scott: And the dude dies and he's a ghost.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And it reminds me a lot of-.
Rym: Well, like I said, it's transformation, water as metaphor for transformation and/or death.
Scott: It reminds me of, you know, the famous ghost movie with Whoopi Goldberg and what's-his-face with the pottery.
Rym: Also the other recent Yuasa movie with the mermaid.
Scott: Right, but less silly.
Rym: But that one also was water as metaphor for transformation and death.
Rym: When she turns, all the animals in the kill shelter into mermaids, like, pretty on the bottlenose there.
Scott: But anyway, you know, Japan's an island, right?
Scott: They like water.
Rym: But also, you live, like, if you live in America, just watch every anime movie that comes out in a theater.
Rym: that is not a sequel to another anime series.
Scott: So I mean, you know, I have less expectations for this than I do for other things with Yuasa's name on it, but I can go see it anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: He hasn't steered me wrong.
Scott: And also, damn, that dude is prolific, right?
Scott: You look at, like, say Hosoda, right?
Scott: Hosoda has been coming out with a new anime pretty much every three years.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Like, Summer Wars, one, two, three, Wolf and Boy, whatever that was called.
Scott: What was the one with the wolf and the kid?
Rym: Oh, God, I forgot the title.
Rym: We reviewed it.
Rym: I saw it.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: And then one, two, three, and then the one with the architect house that we just saw.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Rym: I like that one.
Scott: I do like that one a lot.
Scott: I forget the name.
Scott: I knew it.
Scott: I saw it the other day, the name of it, and I forgot.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Mirai.
Rym: Yes, Mirai.
Rym: Mirai.
Scott: And then I'm sure three years after Mirai was, what, last year?
Scott: It's already one.
Rym: Was it two years ago?
Rym: I lose track.
Scott: I feel like next year or the year after is going to be another Hosoda movie.
Scott: The point is, that's every three years.
Scott: Hosoda is putting out a movie, like, several per year, like two per year.
Scott: He's just cranking him out, like, damn, are you sure you're not?
Scott: I'm worried about overworked animators going on over there.
Rym: I haven't heard any bad stuff about those two years.
Scott: No, they're putting out good work.
Scott: But yeah, that's a lot of quantity over there to be having the quality.
Rym: So some other news.
Rym: This is like weirdly big news in the anime world.
Scott: It's big news in the US anime fan.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Scott: In the scene of people who go to anime cons in the US and the scene of people who tweet about anime in the US or make YouTube videos about anime in the US.
Rym: Yeah, there you go.
Rym: This is big news among the subset of mostly white dudes who review anime on YouTube and like titty anime.
Rym: That demographic is really butter about this and no one else cares.
Rym: But good lord, if they saturated Anna Twitter and like every forum talking about this fucking show.
Rym: So basically what happened, I'm going to super summarize.
Rym: There is this garbage porn manga called Interspecies Reviewers.
Scott: Now, I'm not saying that you can guess from the title exactly what the fuck it's about and you would be exactly right.
Rym: Well, yeah.
Rym: So there's been a lot of Monster Girl type anime content lately.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Of varying levels of quality.
Scott: But this is literally like they go around fucking different species and they review how good each species is at fucking.
Rym: You go around and fuck like the cat girl.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: Lamia is great.
Rym: You know, here's the thing.
Rym: So this show, like all those other Monster Girl shows, like the one you're all thinking of monster.
Rym: God, I don't know the names, any of these shows.
Rym: The one with the Lamia, like the red Lamia girl.
Rym: That's like the one everyone knows.
Rym: That's the first one that kind of made it big.
Rym: They're at least like like a centaur.
Rym: Like they're actually like monster girls and there's something going on.
Rym: It's more like a edgy comedy type show.
Rym: This is just porn.
Rym: OK.
Scott: And it's not hentai.
Rym: It's not kind of is just hentai.
Scott: I heard that it was basically like on the border line where it's not actually like it's on the border.
Rym: It is.
Rym: It is the border, right?
Scott: It is a razor's edge, but it's not just like completely explicit.
Scott: We're showing everything right.
Rym: This is way past Elvin Bride, like that level of like hentai comedy into.
Rym: But here's the other thing.
Rym: I read a bunch of reviews about it to see what the deal was, because apparently it's not even good.
Rym: Like no one who knows anything thinks this show is good.
Rym: All the reviews say it's kind of a garbage, low effort show with ridiculous, like big titty to anime girl nonsense.
Rym: Like there is no reason to consume this.
Rym: There is no value to the show, even if you're an anime titty type of person.
Scott: But like, I'm sure like, you know, it's on the one hand, right?
Rym: It's like, imagine anime titties the side, like double the size of basketball.
Rym: Like it's that level of absurd crap.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's a. it's not a good show.
Scott: So if you if someone comes and says this is a good show that I cannot respect.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if someone is just like, yeah, it's bad, but that's my fetish.
Scott: I'm like, all right, you do you, bro.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But at the same time, if that is your fetish, wouldn't there be better things that are the same like, look, they're way better hentai.
Scott: Like if you're in there a way better monster girl show, you're into monster girls.
Scott: Aren't there hotter, better monster girl things to fat to than this one, right?
Scott: This can't be the best monster girl thing.
Rym: There is a lot of monster girl counts, right?
Rym: There has to be a Sumi.
Rym: That's the one that everyone knows, right?
Scott: There has to be a better one to fat to than this one.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That one.
Rym: That's the one everyone knows.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So what happened with this perverted show?
Scott: So funimation pick this show up and not know what it was.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: They picked it up and they started dubbing it.
Scott: I heard.
Scott: I heard that they were going to dub it.
Scott: And I'm like, man, you got to know what the show is.
Scott: If you're going to invest in dubbing and not just oven.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, they got a couple episodes in and then they immediately announced that they were going to cease dubbing it and it's not coming out anymore.
Rym: And they issued a very simple statement quote after careful consideration.
Rym: We determined that this series falls outside of our standards.
Rym: We have the utmost respect for our creators.
Rym: So rather than substantially altering the content, we felt it, we felt taking it down was the more respectful choice.
Scott: Maybe that they, maybe what happened is they knew, okay, this is going to be one of those kinds of shows.
Scott: And they had done shows like that before, but then when they were actually started working on it, you know, it's like episode one, episode two, and then like they watch, they were doing it as it came out.
Scott: And then once they actually saw episode three, they were like, Oh, this goes over the line for us.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Or maybe we thought it was just the regular old normal, you know, edgy kind of stuff.
Scott: This is going to this go too far.
Scott: We're going to stop doing this now.
Scott: So
Rym: I see a lot of angry weebs who are all in the demographic we described before, which is an almost perfect overlap with the demographic of people at anime cons who wear that stupid Ahego shirt, uh, which is a giant sign that says, uh, please avoid me under all circumstances.
Rym: But what they're mad about is that this is funimation, like trying to police sexuality and police started doing the show in the first place.
Scott: Would you be saying that?
Rym: And then they're like, but what about Penny and stocking?
Rym: Was that over the line?
Scott: Like they don't any inside needs even close to this show.
Rym: Like they don't like the people who are mad about this have no sense of context or nuance or the idea or something can be close to the line and not over it.
Scott: Something can be close to the line and over it.
Rym: This is a trend I see generally in.
Rym: like anime fandom in particular, but it is in other areas as a company, freedom of speech, whatever.
Scott: Like if someone who was, if the government was saying this show is banned from the U S then I'd be like, yeah, fuck your censorship.
Scott: But no, it's like, we're funimation.
Scott: We're a private company.
Scott: We can do whatever we want and we don't want to do this.
Scott: So, but they don't want to do it.
Rym: They don't have to do it.
Rym: It's like that wint tweet.
Rym: Like there's no difference between good things and bad things.
Rym: Like these are people who like cannot understand that two different situations are in different.
Rym: So somehow this is like the biggest news in the anime community and TLDR.
Rym: it's a crappy show that was way more pointy than the funimation expected.
Rym: So they dropped it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, if you want to fat to it though, go ahead.
Scott: It's not, it's not my bag, but I'm sure you could find a better bag.
Scott: That's the same colored bag.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like good Lord.
Scott: But the, the, the, also videos about it, if you want to fat to it, do you really need a dub or sub?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like, well, yes.
Rym: I feel like you just need an animated gif.
Scott: I feel like you can just watch it raw, baby.
Scott: I like it wrong.
Rym: But anyway, it's time for things of the day.
Rym: So, uh, many of you, if you don't know, uh, Sarah Anderson, you've probably seen Sarah Anderson comics.
Scott: You see a Sarah Anderson comic and then some, and you'd be like, oh, I've seen those.
Scott: And then, well, now, you know, that's a comic by Sarah Anderson and you can search for Sarah Anderson and find Sarah Anderson things that are adjacent to that.
Rym: So Sarah Anderson's got a new ish comic.
Rym: Like it's pretty new and it's drawn in a very different style and it's utterly adorable.
Rym: And weirdly enough, it is actually kind of adjacent to my news.
Scott: Today's GeekNights brought to you by the word monster girl orthogonal.
Rym: It's called fangs and it's a serial and the comic is like a four comedy kind of thing, but it's about this vampire girl who starts dating a werewolf dude.
Scott: That's pretty normal.
Rym: And like, she's just like, she's a vampire.
Rym: Like she just kills people and he's a werewolf.
Scott: Vampires do bro.
Rym: And this comic is adorable and delightful.
Rym: And I recommend you all read it.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So it's little comics like she's asleep because they were on a date and he wakes up and he's like, good morning.
Rym: And he opens the blinds and then she catches on fire and he closes the blinds like, oh no, I'm so sorry.
Rym: Or she starts telling the story like, yeah.
Rym: So I was like eating this dude once and I bit him through the artery and the blood whenever it was like dragged him into the tub and there's blood everywhere.
Rym: And as he was like the tub and as he was bleeding out, I laughed.
Rym: And I just told, I told him before he faded out, like, Hey, this sure turned into a blood bath.
Rym: And he's just like fist bump.
Rym: It's just really cute.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: So, uh, there was a movie that came out live action movie called parasite.
Scott: You may have heard of it.
Scott: Uh, it's a pretty big deal.
Rym: I haven't seen it yet.
Rym: I plan to it's Korean movie.
Scott: It is a great movie.
Scott: I pointedly avoided.
Rym: Like I literally don't know what it's about and I'm avoiding it's about capitalism.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I've heard that and that's all I need to say.
Scott: I spoiled the whole movie.
Rym: I don't want to know anything else about it until I see it.
Scott: There's nothing else to know.
Rym: I mean, I went into walk on girl.
Rym: the night is long, not even knowing like what it was about, whatever.
Scott: Uh, I don't think spoilers can ruin parasites.
Scott: Greatness.
Scott: The point is, uh, if you haven't seen it, go see it.
Scott: Unlike Rym who hasn't, I plan to, but the director, uh, and also the, uh, actor of the main ish character, right.
Scott: Uh, are here in this YouTube video on what vanity fairs, YouTube channel.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And what they're doing is they're breaking down in great detail.
Scott: Uh, the first scene of the movie.
Rym: Ooh, I love this like that.
Scott: And they really break it down.
Scott: It is quite fascinating, you know, on many levels, right?
Scott: They're talking about the metaphor of the things that are happening.
Scott: They talk about the actual like making of like, Oh yeah.
Scott: And this scene, this was all real.
Scott: And the stuff back there was made by graphic like VFX, right?
Scott: You know, the soundstage ends about here and this is where the CG starts, right?
Rym: I love videos like that.
Scott: You're getting all these different details from all these different angles, right?
Scott: The stories of the experience of, you know, how it was filming the scene or talking about the other actors and all this kind of, so, uh, if you've seen the movie, you can come and watch this and also go around YouTube and other places looking for other, you know, because this isn't the, you know, usually a lot of times the commentary on DVDs or extras or whatever it is these days, wherever you get extras these days and the days of digital
Rym: always think back to eco horror is commentary on the your tenant movie.
Scott: They vary wildly in quality and content, right?
Scott: But here, this is my favorite kind because I don't like the commentary.
Scott: We have to watch the whole thing again.
Scott: And they're talking the whole time.
Scott: This is like, you know, brief.
Scott: It's like, how long is this video?
Scott: Five minutes, 10 minutes, 13 minutes, 13 minutes.
Rym: Remember way back where you're watching all the commentaries for like old South parks.
Rym: And they only go for like five minutes in the beginning.
Rym: And then they just, there's no more commentary, right?
Scott: It's like, that's what I like is, you know, I don't want to have to rewatch the whole thing with the running commentary the whole time.
Rym: The commentary is dense and good the entire time.
Scott: It's really hard to do, right?
Scott: But by, you know, just a short commentary, that's really fascinating.
Scott: It can satisfy my need for meta about the thing, uh, without having, you know, if I want to watch the movie again, I'll just watch it again and learn on my own.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So in the meta moment, the book club book is still the tale of Genji.
Rym: I am reading through it.
Rym: I am learning about Genji.
Rym: Everyone is cooler than Genji, even though it's Genji's tail.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's sort of like, it's just sort of like what happens about Frodo or Bilbo.
Scott: I mean, it's increasingly cooler.
Rym: It's more like what happens or like due to the circumstances of Genji's birth and life, what happens around Genji?
Rym: Like Genji's Genji's.
Rym: It's almost like 10 G Muyo.
Rym: Like no one gives a about 10 G that care about everything, but 10 G I'm getting that same vibe from the tail of Genji that I'm supposed to care about.
Rym: Literally everyone else.
Scott: Genji Muyo, Genji Muyo.
Rym: No need for Genji.
Scott: Genji in Tokyo.
Rym: Has anyone made that joke?
Rym: I got to, we'll see.
Rym: Well, we'll talk about this at some point.
Rym: We'll, we'll pick a stopping point and talk about how, what we've read up to that point and do like, this'll take probably four or five GeekNights book club shows.
Rym: Who knows?
Rym: Uh, I'm enjoying it.
Scott: It's just, yeah, it's a thing.
Scott: It's the first novel ever in the history of humanity.
Scott: The first novel.
Scott: It's not the first fiction, obviously, is the first fiction in the form of a book that could be called a novel and not say an epic poem or something like that.
Rym: Our brand new panel from PAX South 2020, the 41 tabletop games you should play is just on YouTube and we will be live at PAX East, which is coming up with Take Your Fucking Turn, which we did at PAX Unplugged.
Scott: So if you are going to PAX East, you don't have to waste your time coming to see us at PAX East.
Scott: You can just watch this video on PAX Unplugged.
Scott: and at PAX East you can, instead of going to our panel, go to a different panel, play some games.
Rym: The differences between the YouTube video and we did this at PAX Unplugged and when we do it at PAX East, we'll be like, two slides will be tweaked.
Rym: We'll tell a couple different jokes.
Scott: We'll say the word Boston instead of Philly.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: We won't be as, we won't talk about how much we hate Boston as much as we talked about how much we hate Philly.
Scott: I don't hate Boston.
Scott: Get a different New Yorker if you want to hate Boston.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's plenty to choose from.
Rym: What did I, someone, I saw a Philly.
Rym: I don't hate Boston.
Rym: Boston is beneath my contempt, but I hate Philly.
Scott: Like I'm not like a Boston fan, but I don't hate them like other New Yorkers do.
Rym: I mean, Boston is one of the few cities in America.
Scott: They hate me.
Scott: They hate us.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But there's jealous, but they got some mass transit.
Rym: Like they actually have a semi-functional like subway train system.
Rym: Kind of more so than most places.
Rym: Way better than DC.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: Good Lord.
Scott: Kinda.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: First, Philly's is actually not that bad.
Rym: Anyway, so anime movie weathering with you.
Rym: We saw it, we got, I saw it a while ago in the theater.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So to review, Makoto Shinkai, this dude we found out about when we were in college, when we saw Hoshino Koi, the story that we learned was that this was some dude who made an anime, a very short anime in like his basement with his wife.
Rym: Voices of a distant star Hoshino Koi.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And it was this, you know, very moving, very short tiered jerky and short animation about young lovers separated by space and time.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: To 2002, this came out.
Rym: We watched it like right after it came out and Makoto Shinkai 20 ish minutes long.
Scott: Makoto Shinkai went on to make a whole bunch of other things.
Scott: Uh, like five centimeters per second.
Scott: That was Shinkai, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Uh, well, he's promised in our early days, children who chase lost voices, which is terrible, which we saw at the New York Comic Con.
Rym: words.
Rym: I saw the garden of words.
Scott: I'd haven't seen a garden of words.
Scott: I don't think either.
Rym: anime drama film.
Rym: What?
Rym: He has a movie he made in 2013.
Rym: I didn't fucking know about me either.
Scott: Uh, the point is Makoto Shinkai, while there's a lot of great things about Makoto Shinkai is not on the level of like, you know, the Satoshi Kans, the Miyazaki's where there's batting out hits.
Scott: Well, right.
Rym: Uh, well, so I would say voices of a distant star because it was his first one.
Scott: That's still a hit.
Scott: It was a hit because I bet the CG's really dated, but I don't care.
Rym: I've cried a lot at anime before.
Rym: Like that one works every time, but voices of a distant star.
Rym: That's a cult 45 anime.
Rym: Like I edged into ugly crying and I get a little choked up if I think about that movie too much.
Scott: And it's only like five minutes long.
Rym: 25 minutes long.
Scott: Oh, it's longer than I thought.
Rym: But it was also like it perfectly distilled the genre that I would describe as lovers separated by space and time with clouds in the background.
Scott: Well, they didn't have clouds.
Rym: Yeah, they did.
Scott: You don't remember when he was on earth, there were clouds.
Rym: No, also her, the background when she's in the ship is cloud coming down.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, the point is we should watch it again and cry.
Scott: Shinkai specialty, right?
Rym: It's over separated the space and time and is the lover separate space and time storyline and the cloud.
Scott: environmental, you know, not necessarily the animation.
Scott: It's not about the movement.
Scott: It's just about how it looks like even still, right?
Scott: They're like, you can see like TV commercials animated by Shinkai and it's just like the unbelievable sky that he draws or gets his team to draw.
Rym: You see two seconds of and you're like, that's Makoto Shinkai.
Scott: It's like you can see a single cloud and be like, that's a Makoto Shinkai cloud.
Scott: The same way that it would be like, you know, uh, you know, that's a Itano circus.
Scott: Look at the way those missiles move.
Scott: I can just tell, I can tell right away that that mech was made by Itano.
Scott: I feel like someday we're going to talk about the Shinkai cloud or like the way that like Shinkai sky, the way to Miyazaki movie, the monster will be kind of like, we'll kind of move in that sort of blobby way.
Rym: Like the, you know, the board at the start of, but also in Miyazaki, the way when there's a machine, like a car or a plane, like that way, it sort of vibrates and throws the way like it's about to fall apart.
Rym: or the way a building collapses in a, in a, you know, or the way an hour will come up over a hill and come down while there's someone walking on the road next to anyway.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But those are all things that happen animatedly, right?
Scott: Shinkai is just about, it captures the cloud in the sky, mostly the environment, the weather, and is still image.
Scott: So here in a lot of his previous movies, he went hard on the weather, right?
Scott: Your name was, and you know, eventually, right.
Scott: He got to your name, which is the biggest fucking deal in like anime history.
Rym: I also think it is his greatest work.
Rym: Probably your name is a phenomenal movie, right?
Scott: Uh, it's not perfect, but it's, it's not perfect, but it is phenomenal.
Scott: His greatest work.
Rym: Yeah, but I would call it a phenomenal movie.
Rym: I would put it up there.
Rym: It's good.
Scott: Uh, so then it's like, follow up to your name.
Scott: Here I go.
Scott: Weathering with you.
Rym: Literally about skies and weather.
Scott: I got to give you credit.
Scott: You know what your thing is.
Scott: It's lover, server, space and time and weather.
Scott: You're just going all in and weathering with you.
Scott: W E A T H. I'm not backing.
Rym: I know who I am.
Scott: I'm a koto Shinkai.
Scott: This is what I do.
Scott: Watch me do it more.
Scott: I'm not going to, I'm not going to try to do something different or try to show people that I'm, that I have skills that I can vary my game.
Scott: I'm just going to master my one thing.
Scott: The way it's a very Joe, a guy, Richie mastered a certain kind of movie.
Scott: I think it's a very Japanese thing.
Scott: Also, like I'm the sushi chef.
Scott: I master the sushi, right?
Scott: It's like a thing where the, you know, they hone, they're all.
Scott: of course, there is a long history of honing craft.
Rym: There is one deviation because children who chase lost voices felt like an air Satsumi, a sake movie.
Rym: Yes, but it didn't feel like the rest of them.
Rym: It just felt empty and broken.
Scott: I hardly remember anything.
Scott: I just remember that it was really boring.
Scott: And I understand what's going on.
Rym: I'm pretty sure we reviewed, I'm pretty sure we reviewed almost the U S premiere at the New York comic con.
Scott: And then we saw an interview and he was there in person, but yeah, I don't remember the movie was no good.
Rym: Air Satsumi, a sake.
Scott: I'm telling you the point is, uh, weathering with you came to the U S and not only is it think still in theaters and places it's popular.
Scott: It's doing really well mostly because of the success of your name.
Scott: weathering with you got, you know, got to have a bigger run.
Scott: They're also showing it in four DX, right?
Scott: So I don't know if people know.
Scott: this four DX is basically amusement park theater.
Scott: You sit in like a seat that moves and like they spray water on you.
Scott: It's like fucking honey.
Scott: I shrunk the kids or, you know, Terminator with the 3d glasses where, you know, seats are moving and they're, they're blowing air on you.
Scott: So it's a movie about weather.
Scott: So I presume that if you go see this in 40 X, which I did not, that they would like spray you during, you know, water scenes or shoot you with that gun, shake you during chase scenes or jolt you during, you know, gunfire firing scenes, fucking gun.
Scott: So if you want to go see it that way, be my guest.
Scott: I've heard mixed opinions on how that is, but I just saw it in the normal theater, the normal way.
Rym: Now it's also like it won four Annie awards.
Rym: Uh, it is the, it's not like.
Scott: there's a lot of competition this year, including best independent animated feature.
Rym: It's the third anime film tying spirited away and millennium actress to have four nominations, highest anime film in the antes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Bunch of stuff here.
Rym: You can read the Wikipedia and like news articles about all those details.
Scott: So I think, you know, he followed up your name.
Scott: I don't think it's as good as your name, but let's talk about what it is.
Rym: So we won't spoil anything yet.
Rym: Cause just what we will talk, we will shift into spoilers so we can talk about, I don't think you need to spoil that much.
Rym: Yeah, but I want to, I don't like some of the readings of like how you can interpret this movie.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: I feel like it's, I don't know if it was, if some of the readings are intentional, I'm worried about his opinions on things and if they're unintentional, then they were poorly, uh, not proper care was not taken, but I would not send an incorrect message.
Rym: But the things I will say are one, it is utterly beautiful.
Rym: Like the animation is superb.
Rym: It looks great.
Scott: It looks like, you know, as, as good as end or better than your name, you know, and he brings up the hallmark cloud.
Scott: It's like, you still got it.
Rym: It is, it is very funny at many moments.
Rym: Like it is a funny movie, but also serious.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There was definitely, I think more comedy than your name because there were the side characters had more screen time.
Scott: And this, I do like the fact that, you know, a lot of times there'll be animes where you have a side character, right?
Scott: And the side character is way cool, but you hardly see them at all.
Scott: They don't get a lot of time, right?
Scott: So for example, Promare had lots of cool side characters, like a whole bunch of them, but individually, any one of them barely got enough play.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So even though that Robo has that problem, they had their cool scene, right?
Scott: And then that was sort of it.
Scott: Like, think about say a Promare, uh, adjacent, uh, story tank police, right?
Scott: There's the chief who's bad-ass and awesome and hilarious.
Scott: And the chief has like a couple of scenes, right?
Rym: And I would watch that.
Rym: You can tell it's a show like that or a movie like that.
Rym: If you would legitimately be excited, if someone named any character from that show and said, they're getting a spinoff movie just about them, right?
Scott: So here it's more of a cowboy bebop situation where the side characters, you know, Ed Ein, whatever, there's not too many of them, right?
Scott: And they get plenty of screen time each.
Scott: And therefore the more humorous side characters continually bring their humor more throughout the movie and they're present throughout the movie.
Scott: They're not like, you know, your name.
Scott: I felt like they were more present.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: I only saw it once.
Scott: I don't remember a hundred percent of it, but I felt like those side characters were present earlier in the movie.
Scott: And then towards the end and climax were left in the town.
Scott: Well, yeah, because the main characters left the scene.
Rym: Well, cause they sort of bookended the, cause the main journey of the movie was just the two main characters.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Whereas here in weathering with you, those side characters are there throughout, like they don't disappear even like up to the last second.
Scott: You're not like escaping the funny part and going just with the main characters who aren't humorous.
Scott: And also the main characters had some humor in themselves.
Scott: They weren't purely just, you know, the romance, even though they were.
Rym: So the vague plot is this young boy runs away from home for reasons that are not explained and tries to make it in the city.
Scott: He lives on an island.
Scott: So he had to take a boat to go to Tokyo right?
Scott: So I guess he lived on, what's the Southern island in Japan?
Scott: The big one.
Rym: Well, you're talking about the main Japanese islands.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: What does the main one?
Scott: And then the big fat one that's underneath.
Scott: I'm pretty sure he came from the big, what?
Scott: Chikoku.
Scott: Oh, the one that's like, sounds like hell.
Rym: Chikoku.
Rym: Right there.
Rym: That one.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: He's from not the same island that Tokyo is on.
Scott: And so we had to take a boat to go to Tokyo.
Scott: and that's sort of how the movie opens.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And he's like clearly like running away from home.
Rym: Like it's not clear if he's abused, like what's going on, but he's no real explanation for why.
Scott: If kid is running away from home to make a life in Tokyo and is not a legal adult in any way, definitely a high school student who is not going to high school.
Rym: And this is a movie that is set in modern times with cell phones and cameras and things.
Rym: So like he can't just get a job.
Rym: Like he ends up having to work illegally for someone and like kind of just live in his office.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And it seems like the dude is shady.
Scott: Like you think it's going to be a Yakuza situation, but no, the dude is actually okay.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Even though the business they're in is not like, it's not an illegitimate business.
Scott: It's just not like a great business.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's basically a tabloid.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like a, but it seems to actually world news level tabloid.
Scott: It seems to actually make some money.
Scott: It actually doesn't seem like they make their own tabloid.
Scott: It seems more like they're contracted to make content for other tabloids.
Scott: Anyway, it doesn't matter.
Rym: And you know, things happen.
Rym: It's just moderately long.
Rym: It was 112 minutes.
Rym: And he ends up meeting this girl who is kind of like a weather witch, right?
Scott: So the thing is, as you're watching the movie, it's basically always raining.
Scott: It's set always, it is heavily implied.
Rym: It's set during an era of extreme climate change that is slowly flooding Japan, right?
Scott: In the same way that when you watch Evangelion, it's eternal summer and you sorta like it, you know, it's not pointed out to you so strongly here.
Scott: It's pointed out more strongly than an Evangelion, but it's like, yeah, it's always raining.
Scott: It's almost never not raining.
Rym: Sunshine is rare to the point that if the sun comes out, like people freak out.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, Oh, the sun is out.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Finally.
Scott: There's a brief moment of sun.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not like unusual that people haven't forgotten the sun.
Scott: It's just sort of like, yeah, it started raining a while ago and it really hasn't stopped in a long time.
Scott: And if it's not raining, it's still gray and drizzly and meh.
Rym: This is so pervasive and such an integral part of like the theme and everything about the movie.
Scott: But also it gives them a chance to flex his cloud because the strong visual contrast between the constant gloominess and all right, I'm going to put a meaningful scene.
Scott: I can just open up the clouds and get boom, instant contrast, visually instant meaning.
Scott: And it's so easy.
Scott: And to do and he's making like that plot and that visual motif.
Scott: Also, the thing that he is the best at.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All in one go.
Scott: It's like, aha, I have craft.
Scott: It's like, I'm really good at this thing.
Scott: Let me write a plot that makes being good at that thing really use.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So this girl is like making a sheath to fit your sword.
Rym: So basically this girl he meets, who's a little, it seems to be a little bit older than him and kind of has her like her act together.
Scott: She can summon sunlight, right?
Scott: It seems at first, it seems like some sort of, you know, like, can.
Scott: she really is a coincidence, but it's like gradually.
Scott: it's like, no, it seems like the rain is actually some sort of angry rain God.
Scott: And she has some sort of spiritual meaning, power, some kind of connection to the, whatever the God based on some ancient thing, like ancient writings and like knowledge that is kind of lost.
Rym: Like there's one old priest who kind of knows the deal, right?
Scott: She can make it, you know, by, by praying and concentrating or whatever.
Scott: She can make it be sunny around her in an area for a period of time.
Rym: And the movie is about all these things and we're going to, we're going to, I'm not going to like explain the plot, but from this point on, I'm going to react to the conclusion to this movie.
Rym: So if you haven't seen it and you don't want anything to be spoiled, you should probably stop listening now and come back.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the conclusion you should draw, uh, is that you go see it.
Rym: It's okay.
Scott: Don't expect it to be like the best thing you've ever seen, but it ain't bad.
Rym: And it's worth going to the theater, but I am bothered by some of the apparent morals and themes of this movie.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what are the morals and themes of this movie that bother us?
Rym: So on one hand, I mean the plot and again, spoilers once you find out that that girl who seems so together is actually like really young and like kind of in the same boat as the kid.
Scott: And well, she didn't run away.
Scott: Her parents died.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But then she tried to make it on her own without the authorities.
Rym: Cause they, they would separate her from her brother, but he like doesn't have his act together and has all this baggage that's out in front.
Rym: And he sees her as very competent and stable relative to him.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, cause she's taken care of a brother, like sort of does have some shit together, but it did.
Rym: The big reveal is that she has her own like equivalent level of baggage and the two of them together, you know, the, the title weathering with you or weathering you want to get argue.
Rym: There is a reading that this is about the way relationships form and how people bring baggage together.
Rym: And you almost have to weather each other and then together weather the world.
Rym: And like that feels like a very Magoto Shinkai kind of reading.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And I feel like that is one of the primary readings of this, but it's set in an era of climate change.
Scott: And if this came out, even 10 years ago, you would never do the climate change reading of this right ever.
Rym: But, but because it comes out in 2020, you have to, and it seems to make this point that young people like her who have this power can work hard and sort of sacrifice themselves to make the rain go away.
Rym: But the moral of the movie almost seems to be children should not try to do that.
Rym: Don't throw your life away trying to save the world.
Rym: Just whether the world that will come.
Rym: your children, it's not your fault, right?
Scott: So basically give up, right?
Scott: So what they're trying to do is they make this illusion that, yeah, way back in the ancient times, they would like sacrifice the local witch, you know, to the gods to appease them.
Scott: And that would make the rain go away, right?
Scott: But they haven't done that in a long time because, uh, we don't do that shit anymore.
Scott: And she just happens to be the weather witch.
Rym: So they could sacrifice her to the god and make it the sun come back in the same way that the youth of the world could sacrifice their childhood to like actively fight for climate reform.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Uh, and then in the end, the dude, the main character dude chooses to not have his love separated by space and time and bring her back and make it rain forever.
Scott: And then what they illustrate is a world where the rain continues nonstop pretty much and Japan like starts getting destroyed.
Scott: Like Tokyo is like sinking, like a lot of it, like, you know, Akira situation.
Rym: fast forward time skips to the future.
Rym: He, they come back together a few years later, like the world is approaching ruin, right?
Scott: The world is approaching.
Scott: Like you look and they show you a picture of like most of Tokyo underwater.
Scott: And then they show you people like adapting to it and just getting along just fine.
Scott: The dude who was in a tabloid office underneath the building is now in a much better office because he also grew up.
Rym: I'll get to that third reading about like growing up, which is also there.
Scott: He got his family back together.
Scott: It's like, okay.
Scott: He finished high school, he got it done.
Scott: And then he went back to Tokyo and met the girl again.
Scott: And now they're happy that they're together.
Rym: It's more of like, you can weather the storm, the world will change.
Rym: Just try to adapt to it.
Rym: Fuck that noise.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like, uh, are you trying to say that the climate check?
Scott: if New York flooded the way Tokyo flooded in that image that you could, we would be able to just deal with it.
Scott: And there wouldn't be a global catastrophe that results in like, you know, riots, global emergency, disease, war, famine, et cetera.
Scott: It definitely portrays the world where people at this, not something you can, like he shows modern Western society continuing and thriving and adapting to a great catastrophe.
Scott: It's like, bro, that's not how it's going to go.
Rym: Nope.
Scott: That's not how it's going to be.
Scott: And if Tokyo sinks that much, Japan is boned.
Scott: And my real word is like, no food.
Rym: Like, if you watch this movie, this is not a, like a stretch as a real economic disaster and center.
Scott: Like you could make a video essay about how that is the moral of the Japanese people would like you to, I can, you know, continue even having, you know, anything.
Rym: And they even like the movie gets like, makes this point over and over again that if it's not your fault, it's not your responsibility.
Rym: And the reality is for young people in the world today, yes, it's not your fault, but it kind of is going to be your responsibility because old people failed.
Scott: Well, it also portrays the right by using, you know, the, uh, the story of, you know, the ancient story of like, oh, God's making the weather sacrifice to the, you know, your, your weather, which to them to appease them, portrays the climate change as not your fault.
Scott: And as a natural thing, as a God thing, as opposed to a thing that was caused by the people, right?
Scott: They caused the bad weather.
Scott: It's not the people aren't sacrificing to get rid of the bad weather.
Scott: They made the bad weather in a nice place.
Scott: And the sacrifice is not a natural thing.
Rym: The sacrifice as portrayed is not really like sacrifice people to our God.
Rym: It's a third reading that is probably good.
Rym: before I get into the last thing that annoys me about the movie, which is the gun, the gun bothers, the gun would have been fine if they didn't use it multiple times and it didn't drive the plot forward twice by being fired.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It seems like the lower level, the lower level things in the movie, like the character lines and those stories, like about the, the, the niece of the, the business guy, right.
Scott: And like the business guy himself getting his, you know, his divorce and his child custody situation, all those things, those things I think are all good story.
Rym: Cause they get back to that first thing about weathering with you or weathering you like weather the world together.
Rym: together, you can weather catastrophe better than separated.
Rym: Although there's a lot going on there, but it also has this reading of like, the kid doesn't want to give up on whatever his dreams were and why he ran away.
Rym: The moral was sort of suck it up, go back and live the life you hate to become an adult and be responsible.
Rym: And it lays that template out for literally every character we're introduced to of suck it up, be an adult and join normal society.
Scott: And this coming from someone who made, who is, I guess doing, who knows, I forget what his job was at the time, but he made an anime in his basement and got lucky.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also made a good anime.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: But it like, we don't know what he was running from, like why he was running away from home.
Rym: It's easy to see that he might've been abused.
Scott: Like there's something up with, they never say why he ran away from home, but there was no indication of abuse.
Scott: They never show you his parents.
Scott: You don't know if he has siblings or anything.
Rym: But they definitely imply when he goes back home, like, and then there's the time skip at the end of the movie, that he was miserable there and counted the seconds until he could leave and he just sucked it up.
Rym: And then you get the cool guy who ran the tabloid.
Rym: And now he's like a normal stuffy businessman because that was the right thing to do.
Rym: And everyone like became a normal adult.
Scott: It helped him get his, you know, time with his kid again.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Because, you know, if you're a dude who lives in a basement, it's harder to convince the, you know, them to let you see your child than if you are a successful business person.
Rym: But at the same time, that could almost be more an indictment of society's expectations, but the movie portrays it more as suck it up and join society as it is, which leads back into another bad interpretation that it almost has this undercurrent of.
Rym: you've got to not like stand out or buck the system so that you can have harmony together to weather the world around you.
Scott: And I don't, I think is, you know, it's, and that's the thing is that lesson is fine in some contexts, but not in the context of a global catastrophe.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the, the show, the, the putting them both together like that is the real problem.
Scott: If it was something else besides climate change that you showed, right.
Scott: It could have worked, right.
Scott: But not climate change.
Rym: And they almost could have gotten away with this.
Rym: Like the movie could have gotten away with it, except that it portrays a sunken and ruined Tokyo.
Rym: And yet everyone's just totally fine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like people have adapted.
Scott: They're using boats and they're wearing long boots.
Scott: They got their umbrellas out all the time.
Scott: They're just, they're dealing with it.
Scott: Life is going on.
Scott: The economy's not ruined.
Scott: Somehow everyone still has food.
Scott: Somehow the electricity still works.
Scott: All these giant buildings and entire neighborhoods of downtown are completely underwater.
Rym: If the ocean like rises too much, New York, isn't just going to be a bunch of canals among skyscrapers.
Rym: It's going to be on fire and abandoned.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's going to be fucking like escape from New York, but no, for real.
Scott: So not a joke.
Rym: The gun on one hand.
Scott: So a gun is a big deal in any Japanese movie, except maybe a Yakuza movie.
Rym: But even then, like even in Yakuza, because like that old, that old movie, which we love, like nobody has guns.
Scott: And at one point, the cops have to go get their guns from the special place.
Rym: Like there's a big plot point where a crazy dude has a gun and no cops have a gun and they got to go get permission to get their guns out, but they don't.
Rym: They just talk the guy down and take his gun away.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And like knives are a big deal, right?
Scott: Like in Japan, any Japanese thing, guns are a big deal.
Scott: Uh, and this movie early on, the kid finds a gun in a trash can outside of a strip club or a whorehouse.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And it's basically what some Yakuza guy dumped it there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the kid by random chance finds it and has it.
Rym: But right then he basically gets attacked by a pimp.
Rym: And because he has this gun, he pulls it out and shoots at the pimp at the end of the air, which scares the pimp away.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And that's, and then he, you know, fine.
Rym: That drives some of the plot.
Rym: Now there's a reason for the police to be looking for him, which escalates the attention.
Scott: Like he abandons the gun in this building.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Like he leaves it somewhere.
Scott: And the building is sort of like the central building in the movie.
Scott: It reminds me of the building in the matrix that they go back.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I got that same impression.
Scott: Uh, the, what are the heart of the city hotel in the matrix?
Scott: Like he going back to that same place, right?
Scott: This is that same thing.
Scott: There's a building with a little shrine to the weather God on the roof, but also it's an abandoned building.
Rym: It looks like it was ruined by the flooding, right?
Scott: It's the plot place and they keep going back to it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the gun is at the, you know, an early scene, he abandons the gun there.
Scott: And then very late in the movie, he's being chased after by the cops who think he has the gun when he doesn't.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then they chase him to the place cause that's where he's going.
Scott: And he picks up the gun while he's there.
Rym: And he is able to save his lover separated by space and time, avoid the police and like solve everything by firing the gun in the air again.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So the gun was a positive plot moving device that was required by this child's twice to assert authority on the world, which is a weird message to we, like, I don't know what message that gun was intended to portray.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Like the kid gets to wield the authority of an adult twice and it saves them both times.
Scott: I mean, you can positive both times.
Scott: You can see this connection, right?
Scott: You can see the impact of a gun in a, in a Japanese setting and a Japanese movie to a Japanese audience.
Rym: And it's awesome.
Rym: It saves his life.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can see that the impact of the scene, you can, you can line both scenes up together and see how they're similar, but I can't understand like what the meaning is.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Because if the meaning is, you could have done something else in a chase scene.
Scott: or if the meaning gauges back into like, you can't have something with that big an impact that has no meaning.
Rym: Like shoujo kakame Utena kind of gets into that with the idea of like adults have a power to wield over the world that children don't, but children can sometimes acquire the tools of adults and wield that power in a local context.
Rym: Like there's a, there's a way to look into this.
Rym: And this movie could have been saying that that child needed that power of like being an adult or being in society.
Rym: And the gun was a vehicle to wield that before he was ready or before society would give it to him.
Rym: But at the same time, wielding a gun in Japanese society is extremely transgressive and thus ruins that entire reading of it kind of.
Scott: also, uh, you know, most of the things that happen in the movie besides the supernatural weather control are completely realistic and modern, right?
Scott: The way they use the internet to get jobs, right?
Rym: The way the hotels won't rent a room to them because exactly.
Scott: And everything is super believable for a modern time, which is great to see.
Scott: Uh, except for the fact that like, bro, if you had that gun and shoot it in the air, when there's cops right in front of you, they're not like sending you back home so you can finish high school.
Rym: They kind of do.
Scott: So right.
Scott: You would be, I'm pretty sure you would be in jail, uh, for a long ass time because the Japanese justice system is, uh, not just right.
Rym: Not, not saying the U S one is no, but in Japan, it's even worse.
Scott: You're just guilty until proven innocent over there.
Rym: The prosecutor better be right.
Scott: You know, they make you confess and then they sentence you.
Scott: Uh, right.
Scott: So yeah, but even slightly unbelievable.
Rym: So there's this other undercurrent that there's this unexplored world of the sky that could solve climate change.
Rym: And they prove it's real because the girl disappears up there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: They should study that.
Scott: They should send drones up into the clouds and try to figure out like they clearly show like the turtle rain God a couple of times.
Rym: The movie almost makes this point.
Rym: Only this don't try to solve the problem, right?
Scott: This priest guy clearly knows everything that's up because he's a. this is absolutely a real thing and we could solve it by sacrificing our friend.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: We've decided not to do that.
Rym: or let's fly up there and like investigate these sky fish that are slowly.
Scott: And it's like, all right, well, you're not going to try anything to make it not rain and say, well, I guess if society is not ruined, you wouldn't care about trying.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that's it is unrealistic that the society would not be ruined.
Rym: And I guess like in conclusion, just cause I'm hungry and I'm, I think I've done with the show here, all this combined left me very like unsatisfied and unsettled.
Rym: after this movie, like after it ended, I just felt conflicted.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, there were definitely like, you know, great moments, like the little cards and who's dating every girl in his school and then the girl, like the girls help him escape from the college.
Scott: That was awesome.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's, there's parts and this characters that are totally awesome.
Scott: There's a lot of stuff that's in here.
Scott: That's like really great.
Scott: And like it feel like parts of a great anime, but then that overall picture, right.
Scott: And, and message.
Scott: When you look, when you zoom out is like, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like it edges into problematic to a point that I'm kind of mad about.
Scott: It's like you edited, you edited parts of a great anime movie, you know, to make, uh, an overall picture.
Scott: that doesn't work.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, uh, that's what that is.
Scott: Like you get to plenty of Shinkai clouds though.
Scott: Expect more Shinkai soon, I guess.
Rym: Like if I had a lot of money, he's going to keep making more in terms of the list of movies here that he's known for.
Rym: Like if I had to rank them, I think, I mean, your name is the best one from every angle I could look at.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I actually think the place promise in our early days is the second best work.
Scott: I agree with that.
Rym: Uh, and then voices of a distant star and then children.
Rym: I mean, we reviewed it.
Rym: You can listen to our old review of children who chase lost voices.
Rym: It's got, it's deeply because I don't remember anything.
Scott: So you have to go, you have to go ask Scott who saw the movie recently to get information.
Scott: Weathering with you reminds me of children who chase lost voices in one very specific way, but that made the thing is whether I disagree or don't or find some parts of weathering with you like distasteful, I can't say it's a bad, boring, no, no, no good movie.
Scott: Like it's voices.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But children chase lost voices left me feeling very empty afterward.
Rym: Like I didn't feel anything about the movie, but I didn't feel anything during the movie.
Scott: I couldn't tell you the name of it.
Rym: I couldn't even tell you a character, but during the movie, it was almost like an, an inverted, uh, castle in the sky and that it almost portrayed like a broken down Lopita type world.
Rym: Everything's just broken down.
Scott: I was, I was bored and uninterested right here.
Scott: I was.
Rym: well, that could be form as function like sky crawlers, which you loved, which is boring on purpose to make you start.
Scott: That's a different, that's a different kind of boring.
Scott: That is boring because the tone of sky crawlers or night in the galactic railroad.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I knew you were going to bring up that on the tone of those is quiet and slow paced consistently.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that's could be boring because you could fall asleep just because it's sort of like a lullaby, right?
Scott: But you, there's a difference between a good lullaby and a song that is not a lullaby.
Scott: That's just, you fall asleep, but you're not supposed to.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So, but they both left me feeling kind of empty.
Rym: Like I didn't come out with a strong feeling about any like message or moral.
Rym: And it also what didn't have that, like the emotional climax was not that strong compared to almost any other movie he's made.
Scott: Well, if you want to come out feeling right and have a strong climax, I got the movie for you.
Scott: It's called parasite.
Scott: You should be able to see it somewhere, hopefully digitally soon.
Scott: And I'm going to go eat dinner.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the GeekNights, Patrion, Patrion's for this episode of GeekNights.
Rym: Uh, the order might be a little bit different than you're used to because they, they made a new patron manager and the internal UI change.
Rym: So, uh, it looks like it's sorting slightly differently, but it's still roughly in the, it should be in the order of how much you're pledging, but some other stuff changed.
Rym: Uh, Oh, it doesn't even show me the whole name.
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: I got to hover a little bit.
Rym: Anyway, I will figure out how to make this work better in the future.
Rym: But for the time being, the Patrion Patrion's are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Greenia.
Rym: Just like a dude, Guy, Shartavishan, Link Ichi.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart.
Rym: I got in one little fight and my mom got scared.
Rym: Clinton Walton, MyStating.com, Jay Bantz, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Nicholas Brandau, Chris Midkiff, Mac, The Thirst for Hydrated Ganon, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Finn, Sean Klein, Thomas Hahn, Shervin Von Horl, and a bunch of other people who chose not to be named or are given like a dollar, which is totally fine.
Rym: You give a dollar, you get pretty much the same as everyone else.
Rym: You might've noticed I uploaded something brand new, uh, for the patrons only.
Rym: The slides slightly zoomed in and weird, but basically it was a YouTube video of us doing an early version of a panel as we're workshopping it well ahead of anything we would ever put on YouTube for regular consumption.
Rym: There's going to be a lot more content like that, a lot more like behind the scenes, like variant runs.
Rym: like the other times.
Rym: we did a panel before.
Rym: we did the one that we thought was good enough to put on YouTube.
Rym: All that kind of stuff will all be all over the Patreon.
Rym: But now I leave you with some good life advice.