Rym: It's Tuesday March 10th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We review first contact.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So in the United States where we stupidly move our clocks around we have smartly moved them back.
Scott: Yep, do the correct position.
Rym: There is the incorrect time, which is what people use for most of American history.
Rym: There is the superior time that we move to only in the summer.
Scott: Anyway, we are back in the correct time.
Scott: The Sun is out.
Scott: It is not warm, but warmer.
Scott: It's free gives almost 70 today.
Scott: That's not that warm.
Rym: That's for March.
Scott: That's a little chilly.
Rym: This is normally when I would be like skiing in Vermont.
Scott: It's a little chilly.
Scott: So and I was able to brought both bikes out I was gonna go time again.
Rym: I want I wanted to go was out.
Rym: Yeah I wanted to go bike but I didn't like.
Rym: I gotta go like Put air back in my tires and like lube everything and fuck to my bike a little bit.
Scott: I did that.
Rym: Yep, I'm gonna do that this weekend.
Rym: Probably.
Rym: I think it is gonna get cold again, but it is Freakishly warm for this time of year.
Scott: It is nice and warm, but even worse We're not warming up.
Rym: Emily and I were planning on doing a few week vacation in Japan, but due to the coronavirus thing I'm basically forbidden by my job from traveling overseas for the foreseeable future.
Scott: Good thing I didn't buy tickets cuz we almost also went.
Rym: Yep I got free refunds from every airline like everything was a free refund.
Rym: No, that was fine.
Rym: I'm out nothing though this is definitely a like rich man problem.
Rym: but I bought plane tickets on Air China and Then I had to cancel them for obvious reasons because I was gonna fly through Beijing and like poke around in Beijing and then go on to Tokyo.
Rym: so I Wanted to cancel those but they were non-refundable tickets and with their China.
Rym: non-refundable doesn't mean like oh pay a thousand bucks and you Can like get the rest of your money back.
Rym: it is fuck you Zero dollars back.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: So Thankfully, the Chinese government was like yeah free refunds because there's a problem.
Rym: Mmm, but I don't get that refund for six to eight weeks.
Rym: I am.
Rym: I have to wait it up to seven almost almost seven more weeks to get Several thousand dollars back that are just sitting on my credit card.
Rym: So I booked flights on jail instead Not having gotten the refund back and then because the work stuff bad to cancel jail.
Rym: They also gave me a full refund, but we'll also not refund my money for several weeks.
Scott: You know if you had done the bought the cheap ticket that I saw.
Scott: the cheapest ticket I saw was fly to Montreal then take Air Canada.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think I could have gotten that one canceled for free.
Scott: I think you could have gotten the leg from Montreal to Japan canceled which would have then caused everything else to cancel.
Scott: Yeah, but you could have had a vacation in Montreal.
Rym: Ah, yeah, but not too bad I only want to go to Montreal if I'm gonna ski, I'm gonna go to Treblanc.
Scott: I only want to go Montreal if I'm gonna eat poutine.
Scott: second best bagels.
Rym: You want to go to Montreal?
Rym: Just take the sleeper car on.
Rym: Amtrak took to over like all the way up there.
Scott: Oh, no, there are buzzes that go there too.
Rym: Yeah, there are or There is an airline that flies out of.
Rym: it only flies out of Newark here But it goes straight to the mountain up there for skiing.
Scott: Yeah, I don't need to go to skiing.
Scott: I want to go to Hockey and the second best bagel after the New York bagel and other food.
Rym: But because I wanted to I had to cancel this thing.
Rym: So I have a lot of vacation days like extra this year now that I hadn't planned on having.
Rym: So I thought oh, I'll do like some other thing.
Rym: Maybe I'll do a bunch of skiing Maybe I'll go out to like Colorado and ski for a long weekend or something.
Rym: Like I got all this for vacation time.
Rym: No, skiing is basically fucked everywhere right now except of all places.
Rym: Japan which is having like one of the best March ski seasons in Japanese history right now.
Scott: Sure, this skiing somewhere like some some alp or some Andes.
Rym: Yeah, but like in a I can't travel overseas right now Not even to South America.
Rym: No, I can't.
Rym: I cannot leave the country without repercussions.
Rym: for the time being.
Scott: I'm sure there's like probably, you know, it's really great.
Rym: So I look Colorado, Utah crazy warm like not good skiing.
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: I don't know what the weather situation is right now on New Hampshire.
Scott: No good See degrees at Hunter Mountain, I think we've talked about in GeekNights before about how Iran has amazing skiing.
Scott: Yeah, I would love to go skiing in Iran, but I don't know if you can I could go.
Scott: No, I'm saying I don't know if The weather is good right now.
Rym: Well also coronavirus right now.
Scott: So is the coronavirus in Iran?
Rym: Yeah, it's actually a huge problem in Iran.
Rym: a bunch of government officials got it.
Rym: It's a. it's a crisis?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It was there.
Scott: Okay, I thought I didn't.
Scott: that's not a place that I'd heard of it being.
Rym: uh That was all over the news Like be all over the news.
Scott: Anyway, it wasn't like examining the list of countries that are most troubled very closely up.
Rym: So now I'm relegated to.
Rym: I think I'm gonna use some of those vacation days to go to Cedar Point this summer.
Scott: That's a big downgrade.
Rym: Well, I haven't been to Cedar Point at this point in 19 years and I miss it.
Rym: cuz I you know, I've talked about the GeekNights.
Rym: I'm like a weirdly obsessive rollercoaster nerd, but I haven't really ridden rollercoasters much in a long time.
Rym: Mm-hmm So and you actually have to book like for this summer Around.
Rym: now is when you have to book if you want to get like the skip the line passes or stay in the fancy ancient Hotel from the 1800s like all the good stuff.
Rym: So I think I'm just gonna plan that trip instead.
Rym: You wanna go to Cedar Point?
Rym: No, no best rollercoaster park in the world.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: No, I'm good.
Rym: All right, you'll miss out on good rollercoasters.
Rym: Oh, no, I think it'll be me Emily and chase.
Scott: Okay, have fun.
Scott: Well, I'll do something much more interesting.
Rym: I will ride the Millennium Force which is to this day Barely disputed.
Rym: like very few people dispute this the best rollercoaster ever crafted Newer than that.
Rym: Yeah, and to this day It still tends to rank one or two by the roller coaster Association And I forget the name of that other group that fights with them all the time.
Rym: Okay, it is a triumph for roller coaster design.
Scott: So let's talk about other stuff.
Rym: This news is not actually that big a deal, but we got to talk about it because it's Reggie, right?
Scott: So people I think don't understand how not big a deal this is.
Scott: So if you don't know a GameStop for a few years now has been going down.
Rym: It stops that store that kids sell the games They stole from their friends to get cash to buy loot boxes on.
Scott: the GameStop has been going down the Turlet for quite a few Years, it's every a con shop as every console adds an online e-shop of some kind.
Scott: Right GameStop isn't going down the toilet.
Scott: Everyone knows it.
Scott: It's just taking a really long time to die swirling.
Rym: It's been swirling for a long time.
Scott: So a latest development in GameStops, you know.
Scott: They've had some big layoffs recently.
Scott: that you know, they've been.
Scott: it's been a more rapid increase in the swirl speed.
Scott: So the news is they appointed Reggie Fils-Aime to you know, formerly Nintendo of America, you know bought president Yeah to be on the board not the CEO of GameStop.
Scott: to be on the board of GameStop.
Scott: 10 members.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So first of all a company dying like that.
Scott: Why does it need 10 people on the board?
Scott: There must be some regulation that says it has to be 10 or something.
Rym: No, it will it.
Rym: I mean board structures can vary widely and I have never been on a board.
Rym: That was big.
Scott: Yeah, no 10 is weird.
Scott: Anyway Regardless people have to understand that when you're on a board of directors for company You are simply a representative of shareholder interest.
Scott: right and you really you know You vote on some things and like dividends what they're gonna be and who's the CEO gonna be?
Scott: But you don't really run the company.
Scott: You're not an employee.
Scott: Yeah, right You're not like, you know, you're not calling any shots, you know directly.
Rym: so the really good example and when I worked at my like a company previously the The CEO was also on the board.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: That's possible.
Rym: the CTO happened to also be on the board.
Rym: There are some other people on the board But the board.
Rym: if the board officially got involved in my biz then shit was going down Normally just like the CEO would get involved in my biz, right?
Scott: Yeah, the day-to-day operations you basically ignore.
Scott: do not care.
Scott: Do not say do not look.
Scott: Yeah, right you're on the board.
Scott: So why is?
Scott: why would the investors in GameStop right?
Scott: So first of all, if you're an investor in GameStop What is wrong with you?
Scott: Well, it's clearly.
Scott: if everyone has seen this toilet swirling going on, right?
Scott: So you're either a a really dumbass investor.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, you believe in the future of GameStop.
Scott: We're not giving investment advice saying Yeah, sure or be.
Scott: obviously if you're in if you own enough shares of GameStop now you bought them low Right you bottom low.
Scott: you were like, well, look at that swirl swirl swirl swirls going down.
Scott: It's going down.
Scott: Let me buy it.
Scott: Hope it goes up a little bit and then sell it, right?
Scott: You're not hoping to.
Scott: actually you're not.
Scott: you're thinking GameStop will actually revive fully.
Scott: That's a big gamble.
Scott: You got money to buy some 14%.
Scott: Sure, that's exactly why I'm mentioning.
Rym: Yeah, why did you're like one day five day?
Scott: Oh, yeah Yeah Exactly the point is why would the people who are still holding shares of GameStop?
Scott: Why would they vote to put Reggie on the board?
Rym: Well, they might be doing some sort of consolidation liquidation plan They might be doing some sort of bankruptcy plan like we don't know but that that is somebody who can inspire confidence.
Scott: No So when other people are reading the finance news and they see in the news Reggie and it's like oh, that's a name I know that's a person who is very good at what they did.
Scott: positive Social media sentiment will short a bunch of bots for Nintendo, right and people will say oh Maybe Reggie is gonna have some positive influence.
Scott: and maybe not, you know bring GameStop back to life.
Scott: But at least slow that slow that tumble maybe and that might inspire some people to buy some share.
Scott: Not that you know other things influenced it got away.
Scott: But like the whole market crashing like I just got a big don't weren't for that?
Scott: Right, you know that might have boosted the shares a little bit giving those investors who just voted for Reggie a chance to sell Those people who are now buying because of Reggie.
Rym: now, he might have some good ideas as a good plans.
Rym: But remember he is one member of a large board and the two other feet like two other people that are joining at the same time as him are some like Walmart Cadbury Pepsi Nabisco
Scott: guy retail people for a retail business and you make sense PetSmart
Rym: Sam's Club Another resource
Scott: retail people for a retail business.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So people who have knowledge relevant to what GameStop does retail people video games people Appointed to the board to inspire confidence.
Scott: They don't actually do much work or have that much influence over what's going on but just hopefully to get the shares a little boost so that the shareholders can sell to someone else and get the hell out because That ship going down under
Rym: I mean that ship was swirling and I feel like Coronavirus like retail slowdown is gonna be the poop knife in the gut.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean if anyone you know It's you know, do you know about the poop knife?
Rym: Is that a reference?
Rym: That is just too old.
Rym: You don't know about the poop not know about knife to the gut.
Rym: There it's an old.
Scott: you poop on a knife and then staff.
Rym: so it's not quite a meme But it's really all I'm gonna say about the poop knife.
Rym: is there was an individual who asked the internet a question about a poop Knife and most of the people who responded said the fuck is a poop knife which turned into a. what do you mean?
Rym: I thought every family had a poop knife.
Rym: There are poop knife families and non poop knife families.
Scott: Their poop Kinda so that it flushes more easily.
Rym: Some people keep a ruler in the toilet.
Scott: I've seen yeah.
Scott: Yeah I thought this.
Scott: I thought this was cover a knife in poop and then stab someone with it.
Scott: that way They'll be really fucked up.
Rym: That is big Bart with the shrimp on the end of the peanut.
Rym: was the shrimp or the peanut.
Rym: I think he's allergic to it.
Scott: I'm just.
Scott: I'm just saying like, you know If the stab doesn't get him poop will.
Scott: yeah If you get poop like a pussy stick if you get poop into someone's guts, they're in deep shit deep.
Scott: Yo, they're gonna be very ill.
Rym: They're in perhaps shit, right?
Scott: It's like haha.
Scott: Not only will I stab you and you'll have blood coming out, but you will also be infected By all kinds of things.
Scott: Good luck with that.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: Have fun.
Rym: So yeah, don't like GameStop is just done.
Scott: Yeah, and if you still shop at GameStop ever for any reason why stop?
Rym: I still know why the people who shop at GameStop are one.
Scott: You're better off going to just like Target.
Rym: Target, well people don't know shopping GameStop.
Rym: They go to GameStop to pawn and sell old games.
Scott: sell on Amazon or eBay.
Rym: These are people are too young to do that legally.
Scott: See your school kids.
Scott: see your friend trade a game with your friend like I don't know.
Scott: I have a physical game in the first place.
Rym: I almost want to go into a GameStop with with like just like interview people.
Rym: They're like, what do you care for?
Rym: Why did you come into this store?
Rym: I Feel like that'll end with me being kicked out of a GameStop.
Scott: You could buy the GameStop really cheap and then do that.
Scott: No I'm sure I could do.
Rym: I could stand outside the game.
Scott: They would love to sell you their franchise license.
Rym: I'll just stand outside a GameStop in Manhattan and just be like, why are you going in those doors?
Rym: Just curious.
Rym: or when people come out be like, what did you do in there?
Rym: It's not like a funko land where it's just free babysitting.
Rym: Anyway, so some other news there are.
Rym: there's some good kickstarters going on But the one I want to talk about first Pax Pamir got a second edition.
Rym: Pax Pamir.
Rym: I have not actually played it, but I have read the rules as Scott has played it.
Scott: So there's a bunch of games called Pax games.
Scott: They're all Pax something.
Rym: They're cold where the games some of them are not all of them.
Scott: But yeah, this Pax Porphyriana, which I played one My favorite one is actually Pax Renaissance But I have not actually played that.
Rym: like three or four time X Renaissance is the most approachable Pax game But Pax Pamir might be the best one, but I haven't played it.
Rym: But I've read the rules and I've listened to you and Chris talk about it.
Scott: Yeah, but basically these are like, you know Historical simulated kind of ish games but not in the way of a grognard war game in a different way.
Scott: It's kind of hard to explain how they work.
Scott: Well, yeah In talking wise but regardless they made Pax Pamir 2.0 Which it also.
Scott: they have nothing to do with the past invention whatsoever.
Scott: Yeah And Pax Pamir 1 had some issues.
Scott: Pax Pamir 2.0 really streamlined it and made it really sexy.
Scott: this is a reprint of Pax Pamir 2.0 because it sold out.
Scott: and So I played Pax Pamir 2.0 First edition first printing.
Scott: I liked it and I'm like, well, you know, I'll own one Pax game.
Scott: I'll let this be the one.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So I pre-ordered it.
Scott: I mean I kick-started it.
Rym: I am waiting to see if there is a Pax Renaissance 2 in which case that'll be the one I get.
Scott: Yeah I like.
Scott: that's the one I like.
Rym: Yeah, I want you could use some streamlining.
Rym: It's only the most accessible because I feel like the average nerd knows a little more about the Renaissance than they do about Afghanistan.
Rym: Yeah, which says a lot about our culture, but that is mechanically.
Scott: Pax Pamir 2 and Pax Pamir and Renaissance are pretty similar.
Scott: Mechanical complexity.
Scott: Those are the two that I can actually grok the mechanics of the game.
Scott: Yep For And the other I didn't play trans humanity I've now played.
Scott: I did play trans humanity.
Scott: I couldn't understand what the fuck was going on.
Rym: I sat down next to a game of trans humanity and Actions were being explained.
Scott: trans humanity has the theme.
Scott: I like the most.
Scott: I couldn't understand what the fuck was going on.
Scott: Yeah, and for furiana the theme I like the least.
Scott: the graphic designer like the least.
Scott: I only half understood It was going on but Renaissance and Pamir I 90% understood what was going on.
Rym: Yep So Pax Pamir.
Rym: the second edition is getting a Kickstarter for a reprints.
Scott: Yes This is your chance and if you have the first printing of the second edition you can order modified chippies for one component of the game or something.
Rym: one thing I do if This sounds at all intriguing I suggest you just back this Kickstarter because these are the kinds of games that get Semi out of print and hard to get pretty quick.
Scott: Yep I mean, there's a reason they haven't a kickstart a second printing because the first one was gone and that was it.
Rym: I also want to note this game takes between one and five players and Games that have a one as an option.
Rym: that is an official option Even though I tend not to like those ones.
Rym: Often they tend to be really good in engaging games.
Scott: Yeah but I mean just to just to sum it up thematically what the game is about is this Afghan warlords fighting and You want to have like, you know control or like influence with the warlords that are dominant at certain times Points and I mean like pecs.
Rym: Renaissance is you're just bankers during the Renaissance and you just want to be positioned Right to be able to take advantage of the full-on Renaissance.
Scott: So it's like I played one game and I basically won.
Scott: but it's like, you know It's like they'll be different colors competing for your dominance and it's like you want to be.
Scott: you can.
Scott: your alignments might change.
Scott: You just want to be Allah.
Scott: if blue is strong you want to be allied with blue at the scoring time?
Scott: And that's how that game works.
Scott: anyway Another Kickstarter for some board games going on right now is a company called big cat games if you haven't heard of it.
Scott: It is a small video board game publisher and they do a good work so far.
Scott: They publish very tiny Mostly Japanese board games in the United States or in English, maybe in other places besides the United States.
Scott: They're the ones who publish Nikosu dice in English the hottest game from PAX unplugged 2019 still the hottest game of the year for us, uh, maybe I don't know.
Rym: last year's the hottest game of 2019 for me for sure.
Scott: Yeah, anyway So they've got you know, go to their website.
Scott: They're publishing a lot of other cool games.
Scott: There's one that's like Pacific go which is I'm pretty into that.
Rym: Oh, it's almost sold out.
Rym: I think I should buy.
Scott: it's like an abstraction of you know, Pacific front World War two with naval battles and There's only three left about it right now.
Scott: Okay I don't know if that's any good.
Rym: Let me move my credit card information off of the stream.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if that game is any good or not, but they have a key only three left.
Scott: I'm getting it.
Scott: They have a Kickstarter right now for a for an abstract trio.
Scott: So three abstract Japanese board games.
Scott: one of them is called quiek, which I guess is the onomatopoeia of the mouse squeaking noise.
Scott: yeah, right and It's.
Rym: it's the move the thing to the end as far as the kids the video game ice puzzle.
Scott: where you're on ice you move In a direction you move that as far as you can until you hit a wall and so you hit the cheese.
Scott: Right kind of thing.
Scott: There's another one which is basically put 3d blocks onto the grid And when you look down on top of the game board from you know vertically straight down Which of the two colors is covering the most spaces and then yours.
Scott: you want yours to cover the most you win.
Scott: and the third One is the one act you can actually pick.
Scott: you don't have to buy all three.
Scott: You can kick start one of the three or two or three or all three.
Scott: The only one I kick-started was fillet which is basically sort of like a versus Splatoon board game where you take turns moving your pawn
Rym: with some wits Marrakesh adjacent Yeah,
Scott: and your pawn shits out chips and you want to cover the whole board in your chips and cover your opponent's chips and sort Of, you know conquering the board kind of situation.
Scott: So that one, you know for big.
Scott: the rules for all three games are already up there.
Scott: You can just read them in English completely.
Scott: You're basically just deciding if you like those rules enough that you want to own that game and play it frequently.
Scott: And I think that fillet game would be played frequently enough to be worth the cost of buying it Just revving setting the rule and it's tiny.
Rym: It feels like it'll be hive adjacent for us in terms of like exactly when I would play it.
Rym: why I would play it Exactly.
Rym: I wish play hives been a while.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Do you remember the the beetle opening?
Scott: I mean, yes, of course, I remember the below but that was your go-to move.
Scott: Well, what I would do when I played hive is I would do the beetle opening until the opponent figured out how to not lose To the beetle opening.
Scott: Yeah, and then we would play real.
Rym: That's that's a lot how my progression when I was in a.
Scott: I'd be like if I play hive with a brand new person.
Scott: I teach them hive with no expansion bugs.
Scott: Yep, right then I just like I tell them I'm gonna listen.
Scott: We're gonna play a bunch of practice games in every single game.
Scott: I'm gonna do the beetle strategy as soon as you don't lose to the beetle strategy.
Scott: We're gonna play pride for real.
Rym: now You are ready.
Scott: now Challenge the master and then you teach him how to use the mosquito and then whatever.
Scott: Yeah ladybug.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so, uh.
Rym: and last as you know I play a lot of overwatch and I did a live stream.
Rym: all I did.
Rym: I I like to do all my ranking matches solo.
Rym: just rando Q solo like fuck it.
Rym: See what happens.
Scott: I guess it's maybe more accurate on average if there's enough Matches.
Scott: because I guess if I played if you play with the team and you try to get your ranking matches the coordination Artificially inflate your rank.
Rym: but thank you.
Rym: So you realize that what the game does is tough call.
Rym: No, so the way the game doesn't know if you're doing it.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So here's just so.
Rym: here's the way the game.
Rym: Here's the way overwatch works.
Rym: This is actually really fascinating.
Rym: We haven't talked about in the show You don't play so you wouldn't know this.
Rym: if I join a game rando It'll it'll put it'll make a team of six with me in it I'll make another team of six and we'll fight six on six.
Scott: right if Two?
Rym: if there's two groups of five out there It'll pull them in to face each other and fill in the ones with two randos No.
Rym: or it'll make the teams of like two groups three groups of two.
Rym: It'll try to make sure that if one team has a big group the other team also has a big group.
Scott: if one team's a Bunch of randos would never put a six against like two threes.
Rym: only if it has to try to avoid There's enough players you would never have to.
Rym: uh, well because it all it does this within the ranking bands and the elo adjacent stuff And also I assume there's also a time constraint.
Scott: You don't want to leave someone waiting for a game for five minutes.
Rym: yep, but if you're skilled enough like depending on where you are in the ranking like Sometimes it'll take a while to find a match because it's not gonna ruin a match or ruin things.
Rym: It also does the elo type thing where if you if your team is rated lower than the team you're up against and you beat Them they're fucked and you rank up a lot.
Rym: Yeah, like it does everything, right?
Rym: yeah, so one of the problems with a game like this or one of the but also one of the Benefits of it is that unlike say League of Legends with what?
Rym: 4,000 heroes or whatever and all that nonsense Overwatch has got like 31 heroes.
Rym: They're all radically different.
Scott: It's about as many as like super Street Fighter something like that.
Rym: It's something it's like a good number and I like that.
Rym: They're not just like adding a ton more.
Rym: they're keep like every time they add one.
Rym: It fills a very specific unique part of the game.
Rym: Like there's no heroes are similar to each other in any meaningful way.
Rym: so The problem is because it's a competitive game.
Rym: there's gonna always be a meta.
Rym: you make torb a little bit stronger.
Rym: Everyone uses torb in every competitive game.
Rym: You make torb a little weaker.
Rym: torb gets used 0% of the time.
Rym: There's a character who's good on one map.
Rym: They're always used in that map.
Rym: So over the people who design overwatch one thing they've been very good about is being willing to change the game to continue to make it interesting and to make sure like if there's a problem whatever.
Rym: the most common problem with The game is they try to fix it and they just always move on to the next most common.
Scott: They weren't willing to do that.
Scott: the game be dead already.
Rym: Yeah, and there's a reason why overwatch is actually it's been pretty it's been hanging on pretty well And the league's doing well and everything's going well there.
Rym: So what they've added now is the idea of hero pools and it's really simple.
Rym: They will take like four heroes every week.
Rym: So four out of thirty one thirty one so that leaves twenty seven twenty eight Yep, and they'll just remove that.
Rym: like.
Rym: you can't use them that week in competitive play just fuck you Oh, but you could in non-competitive.
Rym: Yeah, yeah non-competitive, you know, whatever you want.
Rym: They don't care.
Rym: Okay, like whatever There's some non-competitive modes.
Scott: They're like basically any of the competitive modes regardless of which competitive mode it is.
Scott: just randomly each week four heroes are not allowed Yep, like right now Orisa.
Scott: Those are low tier heroes that no one uses doesn't matter.
Scott: I think so can't be random It has to be manually.
Scott: Oh, yeah They'd have to choose.
Rym: they seem to pick because they picked Orisa and may along with two other people in the current lockout and so they picking them better Removing the meta choices.
Rym: Yep, they're missing.
Rym: or they're or they're fucking with the meta.
Rym: like some there are some characters that like Snipers aren't always that viable especially in like silver gold because like people just aren't that good at clicking on heads.
Scott: Yeah, okay, but.
Rym: or.
Rym: and also they're vulnerable to flankers if you take the monkey out Suddenly in that air tier like it's a lot easier to be a sniper.
Scott: Okay, so they make others stronger that are still in by removing their counter play.
Rym: Okay, but the cool part is because they're gonna.
Scott: nobody's picking this hero ever.
Scott: it's tier one because this other hero exists.
Scott: Oh, we'll take that one out this week.
Scott: Oh shit this bottom to your hero.
Rym: So top tier and holy shit with Orisa not in the game.
Rym: There's one map.
Scott: Oh my god They banned scissors this week.
Scott: Everybody rock.
Rym: Yeah rock rock rock rock rock.
Rym: Orisa is real good at sucking.
Rym: I mean paper, but also the map.
Scott: Oh, no, there's got it wrong.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: They're only three choices and I got it wrong.
Rym: There's a lot of maps and the maps are all radically different but different maps have different metas, too.
Rym: All right, so the combination of the map meta and the player meta and the hero pools.
Rym: I've seen some really interesting games and the seasons only been going for two weeks.
Scott: point Is that they remove.
Scott: if they remove scissor do paper don't do rock.
Rym: Yeah, but what if you're on the map where there's a bunch of water and paper gets weaker now.
Rym: Oh, I Played diva competitively and everyone was like yeah divas real good on that map.
Rym: and that does not happen normally on that map because Orisa is so good.
Rym: So I urge all of you to play overwatch with me because I need to reform a team that is primarily US timezone because as much as I enjoy playing complete rando queue I want to go back to having a team and actually practicing with like a team.
Scott: join the New York Excelsior.
Rym: Yeah, I'm I am right now like upper silver low gold like I am NOT a platinum tier anymore.
Scott: axis.
Scott: You love this game so much just get better.
Rym: Yeah, but you gotta get good at the team to get that good.
Scott: Yeah Good.
Rym: Yeah, so I gotta find a team.
Rym: I'm looking for a team of like three at least that regularly instead of looking for a team.
Scott: Why don't you?
Scott: Join a team that is looking for people.
Rym: Yeah, I've poked around.
Rym: I'm thinking about that.
Rym: I'm making more.
Rym: I'm talking to a lot of people while I play games.
Rym: I've got some shortlist actually found some groups the scrim that I'm gonna start playing with.
Scott: Maybe you could find some like Enforcers, but overwatch is great.
Rym: I still don't know why Scott plays it.
Rym: It's basically action quake X weapons factory 2 with modern sensibilities.
Scott: I got another shit going like why?
Scott: Lot of shit.
Rym: I like Luigi's Mansion.
Scott: Yeah, I haven't played that in months.
Rym: Yeah, I got I got a beat it So we can review it.
Rym: But anyway.
Scott: so Things of the day.
Scott: I have a thing of the day So strong that Rym cannot possibly compete with this amazing thing of.
Rym: you have brought a terrible power to this podcast.
Scott: Yes, so there is a person I'm trying to find their name right now.
Scott: What is their name?
Rym: Ah art of envy?
Scott: Somewhere in their Twitter account.
Scott: regardless.
Scott: This person is a collector and usually I'm like meh Collectors.
Scott: right all these people collecting comic books or action figures or it's like, you know I understood the collecting mentality when I was a kid and then I realized wait a minute There's no point in wasting a bunch of money just to collect stuff.
Scott: You're just having stuff It's.
Scott: if it's not stuff that does anything it just wasting money in space.
Scott: It's not like, you know, if you're a museum that's a collection Yeah, but if you're just like a person collecting things you could buy at the store Yeah, it's kind of lame.
Rym: I mean I'm not gonna lie.
Rym: but uh, oh In 40 years give or take there are gonna be a lot of kids Trying to figure out what to do with grandma's Funko Pops the same way that Kids are trying to figure out what to do with grandma's precious moments pins.
Rym: people buying I'll go pops are just nerdy precious moments guys.
Scott: Yeah anyway so.
Scott: but here is a person who recently came on to the Twitter scene with a Incredible and amazing collection the likes of which I have never seen.
Scott: this person collects original Nintendo power Magazine artwork.
Rym: now you said original and it took my brain a minute to me realize that that means original original.
Scott: Yes, like this person doesn't I mean, I'm sure they do have a copy every copy of.
Rym: I mean I have a copy of every Nintendo power up through like issue hundred.
Scott: The only Nintendo power issue I have is the final.
Rym: in fact I bought the first issue of Nintendo power in stores the day it debuted and I subscribed from the card in that first issue.
Scott: Anyway, no, but this person has the original artwork.
Scott: So like there was that cover of the early Nintendo power that like the clay Megaman.
Scott: Yeah, dr Wiley model for Megaman - yeah, which was in fact a photograph.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: This person has the models.
Rym: Oh shit the original jackets.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: This person has The just.
Scott: that's why I'm linking to the whole yeah Twitter account not just to a single tweet.
Scott: scroll through It's like illustrations that appeared in the magazine.
Scott: They have the original illustrations that an illustrator made with ink and pencil and paper that were then Scanned or photographed into the magazine.
Rym: whatever it takes.
Rym: I wanted if mag fest of all places Should pay this guy.
Scott: put this stuff specifically this person has in their profile.
Scott: if you want me to Fact exhibit my stuff call me bro.
Scott: I want to exhibit my stuff at your place.
Scott: Let me know Oh my god that in tag fest is definitely the place for this person to be.
Scott: call this person up and also look at every single tweet in this Twitter account.
Scott: the artifacts of video game history that this person possesses are Truly incredible.
Scott: This is like, you know hard again.
Scott: It's gonna be hard to beat this thing of the day.
Scott: I can't rest of 2020 ahead of us.
Rym: So I had some good things of the day, but I had to respond to Scott's powers.
Rym: I could not respond.
Scott: I'm playing with power.
Scott: You can't know.
Scott: there's no company competing with this thing of the day.
Scott: It's so bad.
Rym: I feel like instead of linking to an individual thing of the day I also have to link to someone's entire profile to even have a chance.
Scott: You got no chance.
Rym: So I've been following this channel for a while, but in the last like three weeks, I've been watching the shit out of it.
Rym: It's called to set violin.
Rym: Okay, it's these two dudes who play violin professionally.
Rym: No good at it.
Scott: Like are they in?
Scott: like a symphony or something?
Rym: Yeah, like they're professional violinists.
Rym: All right, they Do this amazing YouTube channel that feels a lot like Asian television like the way it's structured Mm-hmm, and it's just them knowing like a lot about violins being awesome and doing stuff and it's so wholesome and So fun and so good and the content is so varied.
Rym: I cannot recommend this channel enough.
Rym: like some of the things they do instead of linking to one individual video is they pick a bunch Of new violin pieces.
Rym: They've never played before and just try to sight-read them all on a live stream.
Rym: Okay, they will watch a Popular and I'm making finger quotes right now videos of famous Violinists who actually kind of suck and people just don't know better like a famous violinist who performs on Jenny Fallon But isn't actually that good.
Rym: but people don't know better and they talk about that in detail.
Rym: They're just wholesome and funny and You I cannot recommend this channel enough.
Rym: Okay In the moment the GeekNights book club book.
Rym: Tale of Genji still reading it.
Rym: Not the Genji from Overwatch The actual original Hanjo to show up at some point.
Scott: first Novel ever created by human beings is the tale of Genji and we are reading it.
Scott: I read a chapter on the bus this morning train this morning.
Rym: I'm moving a lot faster reading it now that I gave up trying to catch every nuance.
Rym: cuz good fucking God.
Rym: Yeah, it's actually I gave up on romantic.
Rym: if a character eat like interacts in a scene I don't even try to figure out who they are anymore unless They keep reappearing or I see them again in another chapter.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I know we're slow to read this one.
Scott: It's not because it's ultra long.
Scott: It's only regular long.
Scott: It's because it's Translated from ancient jet not me not ancient.
Scott: Yeah, you know old style Japanese.
Scott: I imagine that even a modern Japanese speaker would have some trouble with it.
Scott: You're reading it in the old Japanese the same way.
Scott: I guess not as bad as us trying to read old English But you know less bad than that but not as easy as reading regular English sort of like reading Shakespeare.
Rym: well, the problem the problem I have is that and it's partly just due to the culture of the era it depicts that Oh Characters are very rarely referred to by a consistent name.
Rym: It explains that in the beginning characters are often even just referenced obliquely to the point to where.
Rym: unless you're really reading carefully You won't be aware that another person is now in the room.
Scott: Like that is the level of and once I just saw that one they're referring to a person not by name But by like their job.
Scott: Yeah, and then later they're referring to a person.
Scott: It was the same person.
Rym: They're referring to them differently now or they refer to someone as being like the leaf of a something Because they had called someone else as something earlier and that is actually that person's son, but fuck if I'm gonna catch that.
Scott: Anyway, that's the book club book.
Scott: Yeah in metamoment PAX East is over.
Scott: We did it.
Scott: We didn't do any panel at it.
Scott: That was new.
Scott: So there's no video to show you from it.
Scott: But if you saw us again at PAX West in Labor Day probably up if it happens.
Rym: Well, hopefully it will happen.
Rym: Yep, but Yep, we did.
Rym: you might notice usually around this time I'm talking about how I'll be doing like four or five panels of zinc icon, but actually not going to zinc icon this year.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I'm actually forbidden from work for good from going to any conferences for the foreseeable future.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So also in the meta moment, I want to point out that You know streaming wise right?
Scott: We got a twitch that we use Rarely, yeah, we got YouTube that we use for streaming this right now.
Rym: Yep, which happens to also be my personal YouTube.
Rym: So sometimes this channel will just have me like playing overwatch.
Scott: I got my personal YouTube.
Scott: I stream sometimes Rarely, right, but I found out that discord has a feature Right where you can stream in Discord right?
Scott: So like you're in discord, you know twitch no OBS.
Scott: No YouTube.
Scott: No nothing Right.
Scott: you open up a video game and you literally push one button in discord And now that video game is being streamed to people who are on that discord server in that room can now voice chat and Watch you play the game at the same time.
Scott: I'm planning to do something with that and you know Not too many people are watching when I do that because the half semi official GeekNights discord server is Not that crowded but maybe one or two people watch when I do that.
Rym: But a high engagement low audience stream right pretty fun compared to a low engagement high audience That's true.
Scott: But really what it comes down to is that the effort to turn on that stream is so low.
Scott: if I do a stream on Twitch YouTube mixer, I got to set up OBS.
Scott: I got to do lights I got to do all kinds of stuff microphones checks and all its effort to set those up to stream.
Scott: on discord I literally I'm playing a game on my computer and discords like hey literally push one button just one fucking button.
Scott: you push it Boom, you'll be streaming and it's like might as well push that one button.
Scott: if I don't mind right right now I'll push the one button.
Rym: Yeah, so and then you're not doing a show like.
Scott: I'm gonna talk about advance for I don't have to worry about like, you know People randos coming in the chat.
Scott: I don't got to worry about trying to engage the audience.
Scott: I don't got to worry about and not that anyone not that I have enough viewers on Twitch to have subscribers But I don't have to do any of that.
Scott: It just I'm playing the video game.
Scott: So You should join the unofficial GeekNights discord.
Scott: There are links on our.
Scott: very come and find us on the internet and you'll be able to find links to it.
Rym: So I'll post a link because I'm trying to hang out in that discord.
Rym: more and more discord seems to.
Rym: Sadly it's the only thing we got for this level of like IRC style community in the modern era.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So maybe if you get in that server You'll see a little notification that I've gone or other.
Scott: I saw a listener doing it too.
Scott: Yeah listener was playing DDR but only with their fingers.
Scott: I So when I that was kind of sad.
Scott: so I didn't watch that.
Rym: so I'm curious Would any of you be interested in watching me just like say something in the comments of the forum?
Rym: I might just live stream myself playing DDR.
Rym: Yeah, like I might just start doing DDR live streams for the fuck of it.
Scott: I mean that you can't do that discord though easily.
Rym: No.
Scott: Well, that's an OBS it.
Rym: Yeah, that's that's gonna be a full-on OBS situation because my PC is starting to get near its last legs So I got to build a new one.
Scott: Anyway, I just want to say come to the discord and you might get a notification and you might see me play some video games.
Scott: Yeah, because it's so low effort.
Scott: I'll just do it.
Rym: All right, so we played this game.
Rym: It's not that new.
Rym: It's relatively news from 2018.
Rym: It's new to us.
Rym: Our friends Chris and Anthony busted out and we played it two times at PAX East.
Rym: now For those of you who might not be super familiar with us if we play a game at PAX more than once that is already A huge glowing endorsement.
Scott: Yeah, that means there was something in that first play that made us want to take a second Look, yeah, it's just spend precious packs minutes playing a game.
Rym: We've already played is a big deal.
Rym: Mm-hmm first contact is real fun And basically it is.
Rym: it's a Russian board game designers a dumber.
Rym: Cuz not enough or coups not enough side.
Rym: I'm not great with Russian pronunciations not Dean of cuz nothing off I'm sure who knows.
Rym: cuz not enough.
Scott: Anyway, Russian game designer It's very code names adjacent, but it's not a very very code names adjacent.
Scott: I like code names.
Scott: first contact is a very.
Scott: it even has a grid of cards that you randomly lay out And communicate through.
Rym: if you like code names by this if you like this by code names.
Rym: But I've never played a game like this.
Rym: That was good before right?
Scott: so what first contact is about?
Scott: that makes it so.
Scott: code names is a game where there's teams and you're trying to Sort of in use inferences to get your teammates to pick the correct cards from the grid Yeah, right and not pick the wrong ones and you're up against a team.
Scott: That's also trying to do the same thing right in first contact.
Scott: what's happening is this is a team of aliens and a team of humans and the Aliens have a language a written language that looks somewhat adjacent to Egyptian hieroglyphs.
Rym: Right bunch of rune looking thing.
Scott: a bunch of rune looking things.
Scott: It has an Egyptian theme sort of like a Stargate alien kind of.
Scott: you know idea, right?
Scott: and the humans Are looking at this grid of 25 cards and those 25 cards are items and you know
Rym: and it's like papyrus cow a whip
Scott: Pharaoh Right stuff that would be in an ancient Egyptian bird
Rym: a fly like
Scott: whatever and you know Since they can't talk to the aliens with English All they can sort of do is point and gesture at objects and the aliens have a written language that they can show To the humans.
Scott: so what the humans are trying to do is to give the aliens the Objects that they desire.
Scott: Let me give you you're right.
Scott: They're offering gifts to the aliens.
Rym: They're trying to give the aliens what the aliens want and they're trying to learn the alien language to better Figure out what to give.
Scott: and the aliens are trying to get the humans to learn the alien language Because that way the alien can get the gifts that they want if the humans understand them And the aliens will be able to ask for what they want and get what they want and not ask for like an unk and Get a cow.
Rym: now the brilliant part of this game Like I think what makes it like magic is that the alien team and the human team are not competing against each other.
Scott: Oh, no, no, no, no, no among the aliens.
Rym: There is a winner among the humans.
Scott: There is a winner Yes, the alien who receives all the things that they want because all the different alien players want something different, right?
Scott: Different set of things.
Scott: Yep, the alien who gets all the things they want is the winner.
Scott: the on the alien team the human winner.
Scott: So they'll always be two winners.
Scott: The human winner is the human who gives the most correct things to aliens.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: So let's say it's three on three, which is how we played it most of the time, right?
Scott: One of the aliens gets all five things they wanted.
Scott: they win game over Another.
Scott: one of the humans gave three correct things to each of the three aliens the two losing ones and the winning ones.
Scott: That's nine correct gifts and no other human had nine correct gifts.
Scott: They win amongst the humans.
Rym: Yep, so every player on the human side behind their little shield They have a big grid of the words.
Rym: It's always the same 25 words like weapon English Beautiful fly valuable power.
Scott: They're trying to figure out which of those 25 words corresponds to each of the Egyptian runes.
Scott: Yeah, this is not a glyphs.
Scott: glyphs is.
Rym: this is not one glyph per object like this is literally.
Rym: uh, Well, I'll explain the human turn first and this will make sense.
Rym: So on the human turn all these human does one by one.
Rym: is you touch or tap or flip or point at?
Rym: Between one and five objects and the aliens have to tell you the symbol the glyph.
Rym: Yeah, the glyph that represents whatever you selected, right?
Scott: So maybe I'll tap, you know all of the animals.
Scott: and then right the the aliens will all talk to each other and hold up a glyph in the air.
Scott: Like I look at that glyph and I'll say to myself Well that glyph must mean animal.
Scott: Yeah, cuz we communicated by pointing at things.
Scott: I pointed at a bunch of animals and the aliens go Mmm, and they hold up the symbol for what?
Rym: Yep, but they could want a symbol.
Rym: You can't write a sentence in this case, right?
Scott: But it might be that might be the symbol for alive or Pointy.
Scott: it may be there's only a bull and a ram where the only animals and they consider that to be pointy even better.
Rym: The aliens might disagree Yeah on what the answer is.
Rym: and if that happens the majority aliens first are like here's the glyph for that and then the idiot Aliens like no, no, no, it's this glyph Right.
Scott: So then on the aliens turn.
Scott: the aliens don't write will write.
Scott: each will each in turn one at a time Will hold up a full sentence or you know one or more glyphs Right or phrase written in alien language and the pro move is saw a lot of times.
Rym: the aliens will write a sentence that uses Some glyphs that they're pretty sure the humans understand.
Rym: I won that way and some glyphs the humans don't understand.
Scott: That's how I won.
Scott: I taught the the humans a glyph that they did not learn on their turn Yeah, and was able to use it to then win.
Scott: But anyway, the yeah the H alien in turn will write in multiple one or more glyphs the name of the you know Objects that they want as gifts and then each human will give one gift To that alien.
Scott: and if they give the right gift they get a point.
Scott: Yeah, and if the alien gets the gifts they want they get points.
Scott: If you give the say, you know, say read me and Rimmer both aliens Rym once I'll keep using cow and I want a whip and you give me a cow that doesn't do anything for him.
Scott: Yep, we're using code names.
Scott: That would be great for it.
Rym: Yeah Uh, the other interesting thing that makes this really fun and like really makes an interesting game Is that you can negate any glyph by drawing a line over the top of it?
Rym: so I could say that the like this glyph means alive or I could say like I could ask for something that is Not alive and powerful.
Rym: Yep But like the moment where the aliens disagree that was funny.
Rym: That made this game fun was I think it was a Pharaoh and a whip and a rod Like.
Rym: those are the three things the humans asked for.
Rym: so two of the aliens were like.
Rym: that represents power And the other alien was like.
Rym: that represents danger.
Rym: And that interaction and that give-and-take just makes this game really fun and engaging.
Scott: Yeah So the thing about this game is that I think it's it's very codenames adjacent.
Scott: I think you want to play it with the same crowd the same niches codenames Right the same same social scenario.
Scott: You're gonna whip out first contact as you would codenames, right?
Scott: So having both is somewhat redundant, but I think that I like first contact more.
Scott: I think it's a more fun game than code names at least for me because the deciphering of glyphs and communicating in the alien language is more fun than simply Choosing the right cards from a from a board.
Scott: But I think that first contact has less replay value than codenames as Designed and presented in this box though.
Rym: Well partly because there's the same number of words every time that's exactly it.
Scott: There's the.
Rym: the number of cards doesn't matter too much right because there are a lot of cards Which I think does give this a lot more replay value does otherwise.
Scott: But you're always playing first contact with the same 25 words warm defense knowledge fast power valuable fly.
Rym: I was saying a bunch of them to give you a sense of scale.
Scott: It's always the same 25 words.
Scott: We're using code names.
Scott: It's just the cards are it?
Scott: so it's completely different every time.
Scott: so code names I think is less fun.
Scott: You get more plays first contact.
Scott: I think more fun.
Scott: You're gonna get less plays before you're like.
Rym: I don't need to play first contact ever again unless you just make a custom board That's like one row bigger and has more clip more words.
Scott: I think another problem with first contact that we did not play anywhere near enough time.
Scott: Yeah a problem, but let's say you do keep playing it and keep playing it and keep playing it a whole bunch, right?
Scott: There were only so many answer keys in that box.
Scott: Yeah You could reach the point where you've memorized.
Scott: Aha If that Glyph is that word then I've memorized the rest of the key and I because I've played this so many times Yeah, there's only one answer key where that glyph is that word.
Scott: I know the whole language now.
Scott: I can just win if I'm the alien.
Scott: I guess if you're the person it wouldn't help you if you were the alien.
Scott: But I think the idea is that there's a limited stuff in there and it can run out and it needs.
Rym: I think it could only run out though.
Rym: If you play this the way we play like heavy cardboard Yes, I'm doing a lot with the same group of people.
Scott: The point is it could and will run out with enough plays unless it gets expansion.
Scott: If you got some expansion or some modification you can stretch this out in which case I would never want to play codename.
Scott: But I think once this runs out then it's like.
Scott: well codename is still fun not as fun but still fun.
Rym: But I feel like where I play like the value.
Rym: one thing I liked about this was that we played it Late at night on Sunday after PAX and even though everyone was tired.
Rym: It still totally worked.
Rym: This is a great like.
Scott: we played it late at night.
Scott: both times We played when we arrived at PAX late and we played it right before we left PAX late.
Rym: It's a good wind down game that has just like.
Rym: it'll keep people awake and keep people engaged But doesn't require you to be like a hundred percent on point to play.
Scott: effective, right?
Scott: And it doesn't feel as sort of shallow and you know thin as Codenames.
Scott: it has a little bit more brain noodling deciphering the language going on.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I like this game a lot.
Rym: I actually bought a copy of it and also the theme is ancient Egyptians like specifically aliens.
Rym: yeah, the aliens are the Egyptian gods yes, and The art is really funny.
Rym: like it one of them is just like an Egyptian God Just like looking at an onc like lay in there like it's a cell phone.
Rym: Yep But yeah, if If you need like party games that aren't just like crap.
Rym: This is like a must-buy.
Scott: Yeah, if you're playing codenames and you want something that's a little bit meatier a little bit You know something to wrap your brain around a little bit more than codenames is but still fills that same niche of Low effort kind of game.
Scott: You can just bust it out.
Scott: Yep then this is the way to go and the pro the most fun is you.
Rym: you can get a like if you get Esoteric about it.
Rym: like it.
Rym: like sometimes players they'll pick a combination of objects where there is no fucking answer to that.
Rym: just to see what the aliens do mm-hmm.
Rym: and Also, you could mod this game pretty heavily if you got bored with it like really easily.
Rym: just make new answer keys make new anything.
Rym: This game has got a lot of potential.
Scott: Yep The only thing is like.
Scott: I said you you wrap your noodle around it a little more.
Scott: Yeah, but I think it might be a little less accessible.
Scott: Do you say children's?
Scott: I feel like kids.
Rym: I don't.
Scott: I feel like almost anyone.
Rym: I feel like you've got to be at least 14 or smart like really like.
Scott: I don't know 14.
Scott: But the point is I feel like I can't imagine like a ten-year-old playing.
Scott: Minimally.
Scott: minimum age for first contact is a little bit higher than codenames because codenames is super accessible to just about anyone.
Scott: You even have Disney codenames like.
Scott: yeah, one can play it.
Scott: you have to you know Understand the concept of matching glyphs to words and deciphering language.
Scott: Yeah to be able to play first contact.
Scott: so the barrier to entry is higher.
Scott: But we're a code.
Scott: names especially codenames pictures is super accessible to anyone.
Rym: First contact is but this game will work very well with mixed company like if you have a few it a few like capable players and a few kids.
Rym: It'll be fine because a poor player will not significantly disrupt the game.
Scott: and also It's so even if you it's super not really competitive.
Scott: that much Right because you're only the other aliens.
Scott: the aliens are competing with each other But not directly and most of the time they're cooperating to choose a glyph.
Rym: And it's just.
Rym: it's more it's fun like Chris at one point asked for like this giant fucking sentence for the humans just to see What happens.
Rym: yeah, and someone got it like it works.
Scott: Yeah, I intentionally taught the humans a word.
Scott: I needed them to know that they didn't ask for and then I used that word To get the things I wanted and the humans understood what I was saying and gave me the thing I wanted and I won.
Scott: So that was fun.
Rym: Yep So this game is pretty good.
Rym: add to your collection all things considered.
Rym: It also does not take long Not very short half hour.
Rym: You can knock this game out.
Rym: Yep, maybe 45 minutes.
Rym: if people are really slow and you're teaching and some people have problems like it's it's pretty good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Grenier, just like a dude guy, Shartavish, and Link Egee.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart.
Rym: I got in one little fight and my mom got scared.
Rym: Clinton Walton, Jay Bantz, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Dropen Lander, Nicholas Brandow, Chris Midkiff, Mack, the thirst for hydrated Gannon, Dread Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Finn, Sean Klein, Thomas Hine, Shervin Von Harl, and a whole bunch of other people who don't want me to say their name.
Rym: I had to pause there because the patron manager right now will not actually show the entire names unless I hover and see a tool Tip, which is annoying, but I guess I gotta live with that.
Rym: GeekNights has resumed with its regular schedule and we will see you in all our streams.
Rym: And now I leave you with Bart, your word is imply.
Rym: Imply.
Rym: I-M-P.
Rym: Bart said I-M-P.
Rym: He's made it B!
Rym: I got my laugh.
Rym: I'm out of here.
Scott: Well, we're down to our last two students.
Scott: Milhouse, your word is choke.
Rym: Oh, I know this one.
Rym: It's so easy Stop laughing.
Rym: It will scar him for life.