Rym: It's Monday, May 11th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are in fact in our late 30s, and you can tell because we are talking about kitchen appliances.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know when I was a kid like I just didn't like.
Rym: Appliances were just in the house Like they were just there like the fridge just existed by the will of the gods And I never thought about it.
Rym: And I remember always wondering why all the adults around me always had all these opinions about the fridge.
Rym: whenever we visited like some other kids family's house all the adults would be standing in the kitchen and they'd have the same conversation like Oh kind of fridge that oh, it's a fridge dare extra Express with an ice maker.
Rym: Oh, I wish I had nice maker.
Rym: I just remember thinking that was the stupidest thing ever here.
Scott: I am Okay, sure.
Rym: So Has anything happened to you?
Scott: we do anything Inside not going anywhere.
Rym: I did go outside.
Rym: Sunday was warm.
Rym: I actually went out for a long run.
Scott: So I've been having You know for many months now, right?
Scott: It's like I've been having like, you know Not obviously not symptoms of.
Scott: you know the virus like phlegm in the morning and you know some Like I'll sneeze a bunch when I'm cleaning a dusty area under the bed.
Rym: that just sounds like allergies, right exactly.
Scott: But I've never had allergies my whole life except develop them at any time.
Scott: I know that's what they said.
Scott: so I still don't know if I have allergies or not.
Scott: it is right and I clearly don't have like Like this, you know because I don't have any frame of reference other than like the stereotypical allergy Symptom that you see.
Rym: we're like people read eyes like watery eyes runny nose sneezing You right people only get that with like seasonal pollen type allergies, right?
Scott: So I don't have that animal allergies because I'm not suffering extensively.
Scott: You sound like allergies.
Rym: This sounds like dust mites or mold or something like that.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: but like, you know, I was thinking huh?
Scott: Maybe I have allergy.
Scott: and the last time I was at the doctor some months ago I was like, hey Is it safe to take allergy medicine if I don't have allergy?
Scott: because I'm not gonna waste my time going to an allergy doctor Right now?
Rym: my answer to that is definitely yes antihistamines.
Rym: Don't do much else to your body.
Scott: Yeah, so I took What is it?
Scott: I basically went to the drugstore and I bought ten pills of the store brand of Loratadine, Claritin, Zyrtec.
Rym: Oh Zyrtec.
Scott: I don't like Zyrtec Cetirizine, yeah, I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, it totally and actually I can't prove that it did something right.
Scott: I need to more data But I think it did something.
Rym: Probably just have allergies.
Scott: Maybe I have some kind of allergy to something.
Rym: I'm just trying to figure out what Zyrtec is because I don't think it's Loratadine But I forget.
Scott: if it's no it's it's Cetirizine or something.
Rym: But I don't remember if that is just a metabolite in the same like pathway as Loratadine or not.
Scott: It seemed like the Loratadine Was had more.
Scott: it was more side effect II especially like with more drowsiness and more liver Pretty sure.
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty sure Zyrtec is newer and the Cetirizine Seemed less side effect II, you know.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you're come a long way.
Scott: if you got allergy you shouldn't drink alcohol, but I don't do that.
Rym: I mean if you got allergies like that when I was a kid You'd have to take like a Rhinocin or something.
Rym: that shit had way more.
Scott: what happened to your nose thingy?
Rym: That is not.
Scott: that is a diesel crumb.
Rym: Nasal crumb is a chromelain sodium that is a different Non-systemic kind of any histamine in quotes.
Rym: It does not have any body effects.
Rym: All it does is Actually prevent the cells in your nose that would react from reacting like it off at the source because it's a pain in the ass.
Rym: you I still use it only in the spring because To make for it to be effective You have to put it up your nose like three or four times a day every day and not stop and it smells and tastes like shit.
Scott: I've heard that.
Rym: But it's super effective and it has zero side effects because it doesn't do anything in your body.
Rym: It's not systemic like.
Rym: it only stabilizes those mast cells up in your nose.
Scott: Once long ago, I had a the doctor prescribed What's it called flonase or whatever?
Rym: Oh, no, you don't want it.
Rym: That's like Afrin, right?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: It's like the Yeah flonase.
Scott: it's like You know you spray it up the nose, yeah, I don't know what's in flonase Anyway, so I had to add when it was.
Scott: but now it's like not prescription anymore.
Scott: I don't know if the not prescription one that they sell is.
Scott: I'm sure it comes in since they're all different varieties.
Scott: now that it's over-the-counter.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you don't want it.
Rym: That's a steroid one.
Rym: You don't want to fuck with flonase.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't know if the If the over-the-counter one is as strong as the Prescription one was or if they just said okay everyone can have this now, whatever or so jet the general rule.
Rym: I'm not gonna name specific drugs, but there are no sprays that will basically stop congestion.
Rym: But those have this rebound thing where if you use them You'll have to use more and more of them and get dependent on them to prevent like stuff from coming out of your nose.
Rym: And if you stop using them, you'll have a rebound and your nose will run like crazy for weeks.
Rym: Maybe longer.
Scott: So it's sort of like using.
Rym: but that's like after an
Scott: aluminum deodorant, yeah
Rym: Presprint
Scott: where it's like yeah clog up your your armpits with a bunch of aluminum shards and then you know If you it'll prevent you from sweating in the armpit, but if you ever stop using it Well, now your pores are all opened up because they've been cut with aluminum shards.
Rym: It's not quite that it's.
Rym: it Doesn't cut them.
Rym: It's not aluminum shards like you're thinking of.
Rym: There's actually evidence of rebound perspiration, that's just anecdotal.
Rym: granted I experienced that when I stopped using antiperspirant, but I don't think there's.
Scott: I have not experienced it because I didn't use any first print but I see that in a lot of people where it's like, you know, it's sort of like you can't tell because the people who you It's like oh those people who sweat a whole bunch.
Scott: They're the ones who use antiperspirant.
Scott: these people who don't sweat a whole bunch.
Scott: They're not using it, but it's like.
Scott: And then you tell someone stop using it.
Scott: It's no good and they sweat all over the place.
Scott: It's like.
Rym: but do they ever stop sweating all over the place?
Rym: Maybe they just sweat a lot.
Rym: That's what I don't know because I don't think I've ever seen this study that actually definitively said that ceasing any perspirant use will cause rebound perspiration.
Scott: I Guess not but the point is you should avoid the antiperspirant if you can.
Scott: Yeah, but only deodorant only is the way to go.
Rym: I would just say my question to you is why if there's no evidence of any particular harms Mmm You're going on a gut feeling about a chemical that you seem to think is a shard of metal?
Scott: no because It's actually aluminum combined.
Scott: it's like aluminum something I hate or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, but the point is it does work by physically clogging your pores.
Scott: It's not like.
Rym: it's a kind of put it this way be like the zirtex and the radidines.
Rym: Those are later generation antihistamines.
Scott: They don't really have a lot of side effects compared to like Benadryl Benadryl I just oh yeah Benadryl is for like if you're having a severe thing right now like you're breaking out in hives or some shit.
Rym: Yep, Benadryl also has a lot of random side effects.
Scott: Yeah, what do you use?
Scott: Benadryl every day?
Scott: That's crazy.
Rym: I mean there used to not be a lot of options for allergies.
Rym: There used to not be a lot of allergy drugs.
Rym: antihistamines were invented.
Scott: I'm sure whoever invented the zyrtec is making mad money, but you know It's like.
Scott: I bought ten of them, and I've already used two right.
Scott: so
Rym: yeah I don't know about that one because with most like one pill a day ones you got to take them for a while to kind of Build up the effect, and then you got to just know
Scott: this you this and if this is truly working It works almost immediately in the last 24 hours, and it's tiny
Rym: not bad.
Scott: But the thing is it's like okay.
Scott: How often am I gonna use this?
Scott: once every few days once right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: so go online to buy some.
Scott: I don't want to buy the name-brand one because it costs a fortune.
Rym: Yeah, but online you might get some dodgy like doctor.
Scott: exactly Exactly right.
Scott: so even the store brand one was overpriced compared to some of the online ones.
Scott: But the online ones I couldn't get.
Scott: a nice quantity like a nice quantity would be like fitty right.
Scott: That's a good number.
Rym: That's not even a month because you take it every day.
Scott: I wouldn't take it every day, but you're supposed to or like a hundred.
Scott: You know, but like they're selling like 500 I'm like no that's what I buy.
Rym: cuz just take one every day just 500.
Scott: I also don't think I'm gonna take it every day I'll just take it.
Scott: if I haven't taken it in 24 hours, and it's really bothering me I will say how that goes.
Rym: welcome to the wide world of it.
Rym: You can always get yourself tested.
Rym: all it requires is 60.
Scott: now is not the time.
Rym: 60 to 80 jabs in your back with a needle and then based on the results of that 12 to 24 Bigger jabs on both of your forearms with bigger needles.
Scott: Do they still do it that way?
Scott: Oh?
Rym: At last I saw.
Scott: yes, they haven't invented a new better way of doing.
Rym: I don't think there's a better way to do allergy testing.
Scott: That's not good.
Rym: Maybe I'll try to look it up while we do a news.
Rym: so it is Monday.
Rym: talking about tech.
Rym: got some news.
Scott: I do have some news.
Scott: I got a couple newses right.
Scott: so the first news is that Tomorrow is Windows Tuesday right the second Tuesday of the month of May.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and the the windows update that comes out on the second Tuesday of every month Is actually a surprisingly big windows update?
Scott: It's gonna do all sorts of stuff right.
Scott: there's gonna be some Cortana bullshit for you to turn off.
Scott: yeah They have a new cloud download option.
Scott: so this is important for anyone who might need to Reinstall windows right rather than having rather than having to like download windows make a USB stick Right and all that bullshit.
Scott: You're gonna be able to do this cloud download reinstall where it will download Windows and then reinstall it with one Breton press.
Scott: so you're in a windows.
Scott: It's already set up But you want to reset.
Scott: you want to reset it back to nothing and I do.
Rym: maybe I don't have that USB stick that I got From Microsoft a long time ago.
Scott: right exactly you push one button.
Scott: It'll download windows and then reset the whole thing.
Scott: You know to nut to original, but it'll have all the updates because it's downloading a brand new windows So you won't have to go through like Windows update bullshit when it's done.
Rym: or as much Because when I fix my old laptop I just did a clean windows install using that USB stick and the USB stick was mighty old and it had a lot of Windows updates to get.
Scott: yep, they're also They're fixing Some bullshit regarding the search.
Scott: you know the search in windows basically never works.
Rym: It works 90% of the time for me.
Scott: It's kind of mad.
Rym: It's only had issues, but well Not not the taskbar like type an application if you're talking like search in a folder the index sir.
Rym: Oh, yeah, the index search has been garbage for as long as we have this exist exactly hopefully making it Know what.
Rym: to imply that I endorse the way that fucking search works?
Scott: No, no, no, but you can read all about the other changes, but the big change for Scott is WSL 2 is now in a stable Released version of Windows and not in it because you know you don't know this.
Scott: If you really want to get like a newer ahead of the curve windows you can join like their beta program and get like You know newer windows versions.
Rym: Yeah, that is that kind of thing is generally not useful to most people.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, you don't have to use the.
Scott: you know the old ass.
Scott: You know windows whatever that everyone else is using.
Scott: What happened?
Rym: you have in trouble.
Rym: I know I still hear you.
Rym: I don't know what you what problem you think you're having.
Scott: you still hear me.
Scott: Am I the same loudness?
Rym: Yeah, you're the same loudness.
Scott: Okay, the wave on the thing got way smaller All right.
Scott: Well, yeah Something's up with the thing.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: All right, I figure that out.
Rym: Okay, why do you keep your knob?
Scott: I'm not messing with the knob.
Rym: you don't have windows like auto ducking set up or any stupid crap.
Rym: That's in your audio.
Scott: Windows even have that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, you're using like an ASIO driver, right?
Rym: Let me check what drive what device driver.
Rym: you're not using MME to take this audio input into audition.
Scott: Are you know we said it when we started right?
Rym: Yeah, you didn't change it.
Rym: Did you know?
Rym: I haven't changed anything You sure because you keep changing your knobbly for some reason.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: something's bumping it.
Rym: Don't bump it.
Scott: Anyway What is it saying?
Rym: All right, I see this update about making your device passwordless because Windows has supported that for a long time.
Rym: It looks like the difference here.
Rym: They added some options around it.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Yeah to make people sign in with a pin instead of a pet.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: All right, you can already sign in with a pin.
Scott: That's not new.
Rym: I'm trying to figure out what's actually new here.
Scott: Hmm, whatever WSL 2 is the big change.
Scott: Basically, it's way way way better than WSL 1 and the only part of it That's meh.
Scott: is that because it's actually a virtual machine now and not like a fake kind of deal?
Scott: you You have to like set up the networking for it doesn't just share the windows network.
Scott: So you can't just like run a service and then like go to localhost Because it won't be there.
Rym: Huh?
Rym: One of the updates.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I'm looking at they're adding built-in support for network cameras Mmm, IP cameras though.
Rym: They are good.
Rym: That's not actually telling me if it'll support like RTMP here like exactly what they're gonna use.
Scott: Lava, you know, it's a big big Windows update for everybody.
Scott: you should definitely get on top of it.
Rym: for now Windows 10 only sports network cameras that are compliant with the ONVIF profile s. I don't even know what that is.
Rym: I suspect I can't just point RTMP at Windows and then watch it.
Rym: I suspect this is going to be utterly useless to the vast majority of people.
Scott: I Mean, it's useful to someone.
Scott: I just don't think it'll be useful to You.
Scott: know you for the purposes you have.
Rym: yeah, I'm just curious what the use is Generally for that kind of thing.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: Yeah, I'll have to read through that having to install shady ass software If you want to see what your IP camera is looking at right now.
Rym: Yep, if your IP camera doesn't just speak a normal protocol like RTMP.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: All right interesting.
Rym: so in some other news There is a general problem right now.
Rym: Obviously with a pandemic like this is not news that there is just fake Nonsense and like fake bullshit and ever all over the place on the internet.
Rym: so Twitter is Saying they're going to at least try to detect and flag any tweets that have Disputed or misleading information about the pandemic.
Scott: Why not just immediately ban any account that makes such a tweet?
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: What I don't understand about all these technological solutions to this is that I mean I want.
Rym: the one part I understand is that these tech companies are stupidly trying to avoid being editorial.
Rym: So they seem to be extremely hesitant to ever just say This kind of content is bad.
Rym: No Nazis like they really want to keep the Nazis on their platform and just minimize the most abhorrent behavior of the Nazis.
Rym: Same thing with bots and stuff like this.
Rym: They don't actually want all these accounts to go away.
Rym: They don't want all that traffic to go away.
Rym: They just want to put a veneer over it to be able to say they did something and they always take these ridiculous half measures.
Rym: So supposedly what they're gonna do is detect a tweet that has disputed or misleading information about it and flag it in some way.
Rym: I Don't know how we can do better until we take over the government make it reasonable and then just start breaking up these tech companies like nationalized Twitter.
Rym: The tricky part is I'm also curious how they actually expect to detect this stuff because as far as I can tell like they look At Twitter in Germany Nazi shit just never shows up like ever.
Rym: why can't they just use the Nazi filter on the coronavirus stuff and just apply that globally?
Rym: because every other realm of technology Especially email but also other things we have this idea that if there's a lot of bad content out there We're willing to accept collateral damage.
Rym: We're willing for real emails to get lost as long as we never see spam.
Rym: Why can't every platform just be like that?
Rym: I feel like it won't happen.
Scott: I'm willing to have good tweets get lost and as long, you know, I'm willing to let good accounts just get banned.
Rym: like that sucks.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: I mean a lot of people today didn't grow up in the era where like you might just lose your email address because it happened To be routed through the wrong IP address one day.
Rym: that just sucks.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: That's a small price to pay to never say it's a lot.
Scott: Also.
Scott: It's a lot easier to Have someone go around looking at accounts that were falsely banned to reinstate them.
Rym: Yep To very trivially identify these bad accounts like The.
Rym: the problem is clearly not that they can't detect them and don't know how if the problem is that they don't want to deal With it.
Rym: case in point.
Rym: There's that plug-in blah blah not blocked together.
Rym: the other one the blockchain one where you can basically look at an account and Tell Twitter to auto block every single person who follows that account.
Rym: so all you have to do if you see one shitty bot is click on that bot and tell Twitter to block every account that Follows that bot because anyone that follows that bot is either an idiot in which case you shouldn't be following them Anyway, or is also a bot or possibly a person who believes the bot?
Scott: Yeah, there are a handful Follow back like any account.
Rym: that does the thing where if you follow me, I'll follow you.
Rym: those accounts should all be banned, too.
Rym: So screw them.
Scott: There are a handful of people who?
Scott: You know are like good people But they have this belief that like yeah, I should follow some disgusting people just to see what the other Argument and my mind is.
Scott: they want to keep themselves out of the bubble right.
Scott: so the problem is you would end up blocking those People.
Rym: I already blocked those people, and I don't even know.
Scott: those people can often be quite good right yeah.
Rym: But I feel like if someone's
Scott: be wrong in that belief if someone's
Rym: truly a researcher or something like have an account that you use To follow the bots just like you have the throwaway email you use to sign up for dodgy websites like
Scott: Like for example, I know a lot of like high-quality Journalists who will follow.
Scott: you know Fox News type journalists or quote journalists, right?
Scott: Yeah, they have to see what those people are saying to comment on it and whatnot.
Rym: yeah But I'm saying like the level the threshold you apply this to like as much as I would want to.
Rym: I don't add to that My massive block list like everyone following some random Fox News piece of shit, but if it's like an obvious troll bot No following it and there are so many obvious troll bots like right We're talking about.
Scott: but the thing is is like I'm saying is like you know someone might be following a you know Someone who's a disgusting right-wing person.
Scott: collateral damage right, but it's like now you're.
Scott: But you're blocking someone who's like you know and it's not like.
Scott: if we had what we were talking about before where Twitter would unban Right the legit person right yeah, this wouldn't be a problem.
Scott: But if you're just blocking all followers then yeah, you're.
Scott: you are gonna block that.
Scott: you know super awesome journalist who is You know constantly retorting right-wing people.
Rym: ah but that retorting probably doesn't actually do anything.
Scott: And I'm just saying is that you know that person is gonna also say other awesome things.
Rym: They're a good person right yeah But then they should be smart enough to have a separate Twitter.
Scott: Maybe your friend will retweet an awesome tweet that they make and you won't see it.
Rym: Yeah, I'm willing to.
Rym: I mean I just looked a minute ago in the spam filter at my gmail.
Rym: We've.
Rym: collateral damage is acceptable in this case good.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But I guess what bothers me is that I could right now with that plug-in And I don't know 20 minutes of poking around I could probably identify with a high degree of accuracy the majority of English speaking Twitter accounts that are posting misinformation about the pandemic.
Scott: That's just too many.
Scott: you'd be sitting there all day I don't know because you click on one.
Rym: you do you these net.
Rym: these shitty bot accounts almost always have a nexus And there's always like one account that follows all of them And that's usually how they do their tracking and everything.
Rym: once you find one of those mega accounts That's the ticket.
Rym: those accounts don't actually tweet anything.
Rym: usually they just follow and are followed by all the different bots in their little shitty network.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Rym: So we'll see what comes of this.
Rym: I suspect Twitter's policy will have zero in fact too little too late And we need laws around this any other anyway.
Scott: Yeah way back in the day of GeekNights We talked about how Apple was changing OS X So that if you installed an app that wasn't from the OS X app store that wasn't signed and approved by Apple That it would warn you and say hey Are you sure you want to install this app that Apple hasn't reviewed to go into the App Store and such right?
Rym: Oh, yeah Right.
Scott: and we thought that they would make OS X a closed platform like iOS where every app on OS X had to be signed By Apple and you couldn't run open source software, and you couldn't.
Scott: you know that'll be it.
Scott: They didn't do that.
Scott: they stuck so far for all these years with the.
Scott: you know only the warning message.
Scott: Windows actually sort of has the warning message sometimes when you install stuff Stuff, but there's other handful of just exes that I install still.
Scott: yeah, sometimes it warns you and sometimes it doesn't.
Scott: it's interesting It's not OS X.
Rym: I think always I mean I did when I installed Windows disable all that stuff anyway.
Scott: Yeah but anyway Another thing that happened in OS X way back in the day Apple is they switched from power PC To Intel as their CPU and there was this whole time period where they were like you know power PC binaries Didn't work if you bought a new Mac with the new with an Intel CPU And they had some a little bit of crossover capability and they had universal Packages that would work on both that you had to produce right, but those days are so far behind us.
Scott: now every OS X Machine is just running Intel.
Rym: yeah like that the writing was on the wall as soon as they started that migration.
Rym: While a lot of people seem to weirdly like and erroneously believe that power PC would be supported indefinitely like Definitely the writing on the wall was that they will be fully x86 by some dates And it.
Scott: they managed to get through that transition without a problem And it seems to only have benefited them.
Scott: and no one is saying go back to power PC.
Scott: No one's complaining about it anymore.
Rym: There was a brief time when there were a couple of games that ran on max.
Scott: Yeah, they said they would get rid of flash.
Scott: You know they did and it worked and flash that killed flash Everywhere as a consequence of not including an iOS.
Scott: But yeah, so the report is that next year Apple is gonna ship not just their iPads and iPhones with their their own Processors that they make the a. you know the Apple CPUs there which are ARM architecture and not x86.
Scott: but they're gonna ship MacBooks with ARM CPUs and We're gonna see what the straight You know.
Scott: who knows if this is true or what this the strategy will be the same as the strategy last time.
Scott: Yeah, all I can tell you is that a if they do this right if this happens people are gonna complain Just like they did when they switch to x86.
Scott: yup.
Rym: There'll be a few.
Rym: I think there'll be more Creative applications that are used by professionals that will never support ARM or at least not I don't know.
Scott: I think it's gonna be whatever happened last time.
Scott: I think it's just gonna happen again.
Scott: It's just gonna be a rerun of the exact same thing that happened before.
Rym: It's just interesting that they went from being the non-standard option to standard with everyone else to the non-standard option again.
Scott: Yep, also, I think because processors are a lot faster now than they were especially the.
Scott: if Apple's putting one in a MacBook That's probably considering how much better the iPhone iPad chips are compared to the competition, right?
Scott: It's interesting to see.
Scott: if it says they make a 12 core 5 nanometer ARM processor To go into a MacBook like pro How powerful is that thing gonna be?
Scott: and do they start?
Scott: maybe that maybe they get around this right by not starting With like the pro right?
Scott: what if like the pro line still has x86?
Scott: because those are the complaining people.
Rym: So they say put out our Mac will continue to run Mac OS rather than switching to iOS.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Yeah, of course, but I've got a run.
Scott: It's needs.
Scott: all you know.
Scott: Software has to be compiled.
Rym: this article specifically points out that Bloomberg Speculates that Apple's first ARM based machines will be significantly lower powered MacBooks because its own chips won't be able to match Intel's performance In the higher end MacBook pros.
Scott: I max and I don't know about that.
Scott: But I do think I was just saying going for the lower end MacBooks to start is a good idea.
Scott: Yeah Because someone using a lower end MacBook is not someone who's running like their own is not someone who ever gets that dialog box.
Scott: Exactly, right, so they're just gonna be installing from the app the Mac App Store everything.
Rym: Yeah The kind of person using a lower end MacBook is probably the same kind of person on the Windows side.
Rym: I just like a lower end Windows PC.
Rym: They're not bad in.
Scott: Apple will have some way where they could go into the App Store Right and like recompile every single or cross compile every almost every application in there.
Scott: Right to get them to run on, you know arm instead of x86.
Rym: It'll be really interesting.
Rym: What happens with the third-party software that's relying on heavily like the Adobe type stuff like the 3d rendering software all the things that are third-party and performance intensive and big that don't really care that much about Apple because There are.
Rym: there were like ARM Windows PCs and most software does not work on them.
Rym: Like.
Rym: I don't even know if Adobe stuff would work on that.
Rym: I don't think there was ever ARM Adobe.
Scott: You know Adobe would have to read it to recompile everything for ARM, yeah, and I don't know if they would Why wouldn't they?
Rym: I don't know?
Rym: No one's done it for those Windows ARM PCs.
Scott: Yeah, I think you know, this would be like a transition period right?
Scott: It's like put it out on non Pro.
Scott: So it's like okay who's running Photoshop on a non Pro MacBook, right?
Scott: But it's sort of like alright now Adobe It's like you guess what you better Right get ready to release photo if you want to get these custom, you know,
Rym: yeah Yeah, I found an article talking about the the Surface Pro X because that's Microsoft's new newish ARM based Laptop like it's a tablet laptop very similar Goals and the reviews are not glowing about its performance and compatibility,
Scott: right?
Scott: But that has an off-the-shelf ARM processor.
Rym: Yeah, they won't do the like integrated design that Apple likes to do.
Scott: It doesn't have the best ARM processor.
Scott: Probably the best consumer ARM processor that you could get which is when Apple made.
Rym: Yeah, that'll be the line.
Rym: because the line from this like to see where this is going.
Rym: because the line from this article other article Which isn't that old quote more intense tense apps like Photoshop do technically run on this computer But they're so slow.
Rym: They'd might as well.
Rym: not Microsoft says anyone.
Scott: anyone who come yeah, but anyone who complains about this transition if and when it happens I'm just gonna say you went through this before and it wasn't a really big deal.
Scott: at the end.
Scott: Did you complain then?
Scott: but it ended up just fine.
Scott: You're not complaining now Are you still?
Scott: are you?
Scott: listen?
Scott: if someone has been complaining for that many years to go back to power PC?
Scott: That person is allowed to complain about arm.
Rym: I feel like a lot of the thing.
Rym: no one else is that we're supported on powers of power PC and we're not Supported.
Rym: when they went to Intel were things that were old and dying anyway.
Scott: Yeah, they were.
Scott: you know, they were.
Scott: a thing is if an app is maintained, you know Actively maintained app that means that there's a developer with the source code to recompile it and cross compile.
Scott: Other article which is from like November like a software that's lost is the old software that yeah I only have a binary of.
Rym: but the article does not say that Adobe has committed to supporting arm.
Rym: The article says that Microsoft says that Adobe is committed to creating 64-bit arm versions of Creative Cloud apps But there is no timeline.
Rym: And it also says gaming is quite literally a non-starter.
Scott: Oh, yeah Mings a non-starter on a Mac book.
Rym: So I'd say this is a nail in the coffin, but the sarcophagus is already in the pyramid.
Rym: like there's.
Rym: no more nails are necessary.
Scott: Yeah, GG.
Rym: So one last little bit of news that uh, I guess is another writing on the wall article.
Rym: People are of course cutting their cords.
Rym: They're killing their cable television faster than cool.
Scott: Thank you that you think that would have slowed down a little bit because people are stuck at home.
Rym: You know why it's probably have more time to get it done.
Scott: they got.
Rym: no no, no, it's real simple ain't?
Rym: no sports?
Scott: Oh, that's true.
Rym: And that's all anyone actually cares about anymore.
Rym: The only thing is actually People are sports and Fox News.
Scott: Where was the lawsuit?
Scott: Sports TV like no live sports lawsuit.
Scott: I think there was a lawsuit was it?
Scott: in New York?
Rym: the last quarter There were 1.7 million lost subscribers the largest decline in a first quarter ever.
Rym: They're projecting a total to 2020 decline of 8 million.
Rym: and what's crazy is these big numbers have been happening for a long time.
Rym: I think people just like forget how many people have cable and just haven't stopped paying for it yet.
Scott: yeah, I forget if there's a Lawsuit in this or not, but I read a lot of articles recently talking about how people are paying cable for live sports.
Scott: Yep, right and there's like extra.
Scott: it's not just like you're.
Scott: it's not like I'm buying cable because I want live sports.
Scott: It's like there's specific line items on your cable bill because you're buying like, you know, a Major League Baseball package.
Rym: Yeah, you get the package without ESPN and without like MSG or whatever.
Rym: It's just way cheaper, right?
Scott: You can't?
Scott: I don't think you can get without ESPN, but you're not paying for specifically extra sports.
Scott: shit, right?
Rym: Yep But if you if you're one extra then shouldn't they have to pay you back if there's no sports, right?
Scott: So it's like you're paying extra Specifically for live sports like it's an add-on feature Like if you got a car and it said, okay We're gonna add $100 to your car for special paint and the car didn't have the special paint because they ran out.
Scott: Yep, we ran out of sports, right?
Scott: You're paying $100 extra on your cable bill, but we ran out of sports.
Scott: But we ran out of sports.
Scott: There ain't no sports to watch.
Scott: So they're still charging people for it because it's like well you still have the channel, right?
Rym: Yeah, what's on?
Rym: What's on ESPN?
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's not that it's not ESPN though.
Scott: Everyone has ESPN even with the most basic of cable, but like any What's actually on a sports network right now?
Scott: all kinds of crazy stuff.
Scott: But anyway, the point is that I don't.
Scott: I think there might have been lawsuits or at least lots of complaining.
Scott: people want their fucking Money back, right?
Scott: Canceling cable.
Scott: They want their fucking money.
Scott: They're like, hey, you can't be charging me for that.
Scott: You didn't give it to me There isn't any.
Rym: yeah, you didn't bundle it.
Rym: I paid for that.
Rym: There's a line item for it.
Scott: Yeah So I think there might have.
Scott: there was.
Scott: I can't find a story about it right now while I'm doing the show.
Rym: Yeah the sport the tea the court-cutting thing is interesting though because it seems like the trend was Accelerating coming into 2020 already for a lot of reasons mostly because the streaming services are all pretty good.
Rym: The ecosystem has gotten to the point to where everyone's willing to pay for like between two and four different streaming services.
Scott: Well, and it is less cheaper than cable.
Scott: Yeah, and it's just less and less things That you would be like, ah, you know, if I don't have cable, I can't watch this.
Scott: It's like what it's almost no this is left except for the sports.
Rym: yeah, even if you're not pirating like it's pretty easy to have access to most media.
Rym: and but it seems like the kovat 19 pandemic is actually Accelerating this.
Rym: because on one hand there's no sports.
Rym: So One of the main reasons people even turn on a TV is not there.
Rym: so they might question.
Rym: Why am I paying for cable?
Rym: I don't even turn on my TV anymore.
Rym: And the other half of it is with massive unemployment.
Rym: Cable is one of the things people can just cut if they have to.
Rym: It's true if you have no money And if you have no money And there's nothing to watch because there's no new content because there's no sports like killing cable is the obvious choice.
Scott: That'll save you also, I think you know, you have time at home, right?
Scott: You think y'all got all this time.
Scott: I need to spend it watching TV.
Scott: But also I got all this time.
Scott: I got time to Spend, you know as I spend money to get content without effort.
Scott: Well now I got time.
Scott: I can put effort into plugging shit into my TV and figuring out how to get content You know without having to pay for cable.
Rym: Yeah, how many desperate families are turning to their 12 year old kid who's teaching them how to pirate bay on the HDPC?
Scott: All right, just getting an Apple TV and plugging a network cable into it.
Rym: Yeah Either way, you even just plug in the network cable into whatever like stupid smart TV They got and making that menu that they've never clicked into work.
Scott: Yeah Wi-Fi with the smart TV.
Scott: Yeah, you know, whatever.
Rym: alright, I think we can just jump right into things of the day.
Rym: so as you know me and Emily are continuing our Review and discussion of every Disney theatrical animation and one of the things we I learned When we watched Dumbo was that Dumbo was one of the first films ever to use in early voice synthesizer vocoder type thing Like a like a like an early version of a talk box.
Rym: So okay that technology son of ox was pioneered the year earlier and what I have here is a YouTube video.
Rym: That is a film a 1940 film.
Rym: It's short It's like three minutes long and it's basically a tech demo of the son of ox voice synthesizer talk box program Mm-hmm.
Scott: It's crazy.
Scott: So it's a. so it's a machine that synthesizes human speech.
Scott: So it's more like it's not a digital computer because it's 1940.
Rym: It's more like a talk about.
Rym: it's like the thing that Peter Frampton Used to make his guitar talk.
Rym: It's the first iteration of that.
Rym: Do you know how that actually worked?
Rym: That's all analog.
Rym: there's no digital technology required for that at all.
Scott: I thought it was just like, you know, like just a guitar pedal that just like bends.
Rym: the How talk boxes work is Basically, they will pipe the sound like your guitar or whatever it is.
Rym: You can put any audio into them into your mouth.
Rym: It's audio vibrating in that tube that you see him sucking on when he's doing it into his mouth and Then he just moves his mouth like he's talking and The sound will come out of his mouth modulated by his own mouth.
Rym: But instead of his vocal cords making the sound it's the instrument making the sound.
Scott: So but you still have to have a person involved here.
Scott: Yes, you use the person's physical To be not really synthesizing speech if a human mouth is doing it.
Rym: This is a different kind of audio stuff.
Rym: this is more like Though like the way they used to do reverb, you know reverb worked in the old days.
Rym: You'd have a big box and you plug a microphone into one end and a speaker into the other end.
Rym: So this is basically a synthesizer where you plug and a pure signal in one end.
Rym: You plug it into someone's throat and then you use the shape of their mouth to shape and modulate that noise.
Rym: So they don't actually say anything and the instrument comes out.
Scott: Why not just fucking talk then?
Rym: because they want it to not be a human voice.
Rym: they want it to sound like something else.
Rym: You've seen Peter Frampton perform right?
Rym: Yeah his guitar talks.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: that's the technology and this video is the precursor to that technology being debuted to the world and The wall.
Rym: this seems kind of shit like it sounds pretty shitty by any modern standard.
Rym: like you can't imagine why someone would use this technology, but Nothing like that existed before.
Rym: Sure, like this is actually groundbreaking kind of amazing technology and it actually works pretty seamlessly.
Rym: all things considered Okay, all right, what do you got?
Scott: All right, so since there's no sports, let's go back in time to the year I was born 1982. but right it's like if we go back far enough, it's like well, you know, I've all the sports since 1980 something I've seen Not all of them, but enough of them.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like I want to see some new sports.
Scott: Let's go back to what I can't remember so that the year I was born I definitely don't remember this because it wasn't even on American TV as far as I can tell you Wasn't until like 1988 that I even recognized sports exist and paid attention to them.
Scott: I Recognized sports exist earlier than that.
Rym: Yeah the problem was I was watching the Simpsons and Occasionally a Simpsons premiere would be delayed a little bit and you'd miss the beginning of the episode because football took too long.
Rym: So I actually hated.
Scott: tell it watch football and then during the football they'd be like yo.
Rym: as soon as football's over Simpsons you'd be like, oh, yeah If the football went into OT you'd miss the first five minutes of Simpsons anyway Until I watch TV sports.
Scott: I don't know which country this is.
Scott: Sorry to the country that it is from I can't.
Scott: it seems like based on the language.
Scott: It's a Dutch country.
Scott: could be You know, well, that's good.
Scott: It could be the Netherlands.
Scott: It could be Sweden.
Scott: I'm not sure exactly.
Scott: it could be Denmark.
Scott: I don't know which country this is from.
Scott: I'm sorry It's one of those countries.
Scott: they had a televised event that was a big deal called World Sports Masters and this tweet is actually from 2015 But the entirety of the program in five parts is on YouTube as long as no one takes it down.
Scott: And what this was is something that needs to be replicated.
Scott: ASAP.
Rym: looks like it kept going.
Scott: Yeah, no, but it should exist today right in 2020.
Scott: But what they did is they took many many legendary athletes of the day right Wayne Gretzky sugar Ray Leonard Palay Bjorn Borg Michael Keegan all these, you know, like so the most famous soccer tennis Skiing guy.
Scott: I forget his name, right?
Scott: You know athletes of the day and they had them compete against each other directly in other sports.
Rym: Just the omega-thon for sports professionals Exactly.
Rym: So here you have in this short in this tweet if you are LeBron Let's see you catch a touchdown pass and we're gonna do a thing and then run a 5k then we're gonna do some biathlon Right.
Scott: So here the tweet just has a short clip.
Scott: That's the most exciting part, which is a very short sprint race between Bjorn Borg sugar Ray Leonard Palay and Wayne Gretzky.
Scott: It's a little unfair Because Palay at this time is at least like 20 years older than the other people involved.
Scott: So just keep that in mind when looking at the results here, but if you want to watch the whole thing It's in five parts on YouTube.
Scott: I didn't watch the whole thing because that's long.
Scott: This is pretty good, but maybe I will if I get bored, but it's still Fascinating and amazing and they should do this again, right?
Scott: Let's see, you know The current world's best athletes up against each other, right?
Scott: Why shouldn't we?
Rym: Oh Apparently Peter Frampton is was about to go on tour and then the pandemic stopped him.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I didn't know he was gonna go see him.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: maybe I've never seen Peter Frampton in person.
Scott: All right good reason for that met a moment.
Rym: Uh Guess well at some point we'll read again.
Rym: I don't actually have any free time So I actually haven't been reading like life's been forgot how to read.
Rym: life's been weirdly busy.
Rym: still like every night I don't finish all the things I need to do in the day and then it's like midnight and I go to bed.
Rym: I Still need my weekends.
Rym: So we haven't read much.
Rym: hopefully when it gets a little warmer I'll go out to the park and hide and just read and then we'll catch up on the tale of Genji and then perhaps that Nine-fox gambit will be the next book because multiple people keep bothering us to do it and I suspect we'll like it.
Rym: So we'll see Mm-hmm.
Rym: Otherwise, I'd say look for us at your next convention.
Rym: but well so if there are any online conventions that you think we should be a part of you want to see us there or you want us to go to one of These online conventions and present on a topic that for one some reason we've never presented on that Maybe you think we should.
Rym: you want to see our weird stuff?
Rym: You want to see the panels that no one's ever?
Rym: Accepted like now's the time.
Rym: if you convince some events to invite us to perform We will bring something to perform even if it's something that say even packs and MAGFest.
Rym: We're like, yeah, we'll pass on that.
Scott: Also, uh, I updated you might.
Scott: you won't notice.
Scott: you shouldn't notice any difference.
Rym: if you notice the difference there's a problem.
Scott: Yeah, but the the server that the forum is hosted on I updated.
Scott: it's the parts that you can't see.
Scott: so There was a small amount of downtime and also That's it.
Scott: So it should be working perfectly now.
Scott: And so let me know if you see any problems with it.
Scott: But otherwise, yeah, it should be a really solid and good to go for five years or so.
Rym: All right kitchen appliances great We're.
Rym: uh, Mondays are tough because like not gonna talk about work stuff really like if you have Monday show.
Scott: I didn't realize he Rym told me the show idea and I was like I didn't protest.
Scott: I was like, oh good idea, but my brain for some reason like put it in as a Thursday Even though I know it's Monday.
Scott: So as soon as I put it two and two together, I was like, wait a minute That's not a Monday idea.
Rym: Here's my stretch number one What's the main purpose of GeekNights?
Rym: to get the person who's only into silver age silver surfer comics to at least take a look?
Rym: At a comp.
Scott: I don't think someone who cares about computers needs to know about kitchen appliances.
Rym: I think they do though because the Minor point I would make but again, this is a stretch Is that a lot of you listen to our Monday episodes your nerds.
Rym: a lot of you work in IT or your code?
Rym: How do you know how you feel when someone asks you for help with their computer or is even paying you to help them with?
Rym: Their computer and the problem is obvious and you feel like they're stupid like just plug your mouse in dude.
Rym: Like that feeling.
Rym: that is exactly how the dishwasher repair person feels when they come in and they look at your dishwasher And you're like, please help me.
Rym: I flooded my house.
Scott: Yep, I'm sure that I imagine that most people out there who can build a computer from parts and fix their computer And do every computer thing Wouldn't know the first fucking thing to do with their dishwasher.
Rym: Yep Same thing with cars and I guess the the my the meta point.
Rym: the stretch to make this fit into a Monday night episode of GeekNights is that if you truly are a geek if you want to know things about things You should understand at least the basics of the technology that you use on a regular basis.
Rym: Make it one step less wizard-like.
Rym: you might not be able to fix it Like.
Rym: I might be able to identify the problem with a car, but I might not be able to fix that problem But you should at least have some idea of like.
Rym: why is that refrigerator better than that refrigerator?
Rym: Why do some people have a second refrigerator in their garage with a door on the top?
Rym: Like why do people like Rym and Scott get so weird about gas stoves versus electric stoves?
Rym: You should at least know enough to understand the context of those questions.
Rym: Also someday you too will be in your late 30s and you will actually care about which refrigerator you own.
Rym: You'll care a lot more than you think you will.
Scott: Well, that's all true.
Scott: It's still not a Monday episode, but I guess we have no choice because we have no other idea.
Scott: So send your Monday show ideas At frontrowcrew.com or via any other internet communication mechanism.
Scott: Hopefully, you know how to use some means of contacting us and know how to use Google to find a way to contact us.
Scott: so
Rym: fridges the cool thing about fridges is that with the exception of a few weird ones like a propane fridge or a Peltier which are not like they're not really normal or a
Scott: super old-fashioned icebox
Rym: True one that takes like literal blocks of ice
Scott: But yes that kind of like
Rym: since the what 50s fridges have pretty much just worked Mostly the same like.
Rym: not much has changed in that technology.
Scott: well, I think that's something that I think is universal.
Scott: amongst the major kitchen appliances is that Generally speaking compared to a lot of other Expensive large items you might buy they are extremely reliable.
Rym: Yep, right I mean my grandparents.
Rym: so they had a this old GE fridge from like 1951 and Until they sold their house when I was an adult That fridge was still working had not only been unplugged like three times in its life was totally fine.
Rym: Literally nothing wrong with it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know.
Scott: cars like, you know, they wear down a lot.
Scott: But I guess that's because they have more moving parts and they interact with like road bumping them and stuff like that.
Scott: And out they got in the elements that deal with hot and cold temperature changes.
Scott: Yeah, that can affect them in many ways.
Rym: very rarely do two fridges collide with each other at 45 miles an hour.
Scott: Right, exactly, right.
Scott: So the Appliances in your house.
Scott: Not only are they not Facing such conditions that cause them to wear down as quickly But I think the people making them right are not trying to make ones that are like intentionally shitty that break Right, but also you
Rym: don't want
Scott: to deal
Rym: they have to kind of just work because the user experience design You know Like if you're designing a interface or a computer or something The user experience design has to sort of assume that the people using them understand nothing like nothing at all.
Rym: little kid I'll just start using it.
Scott: It's like with a car.
Scott: you at least have to learn something.
Scott: You'd learn how to drive how to use all these buttons and things.
Scott: right, you know.
Scott: with a refrigerator You don't you don't know anything.
Scott: It's just a door.
Rym: It's just magic.
Rym: No, you there's a In there.
Scott: Right, even a dishwasher these days is like you push.
Scott: basically they have a bunch of buttons on them But you basically push clean my fucking dishes start, right?
Scott: And that's it.
Rym: I do use different cycles on the dishwasher, but I have realized we did a show on laundry a long time ago.
Rym: So I'm probably iterating and I'll link to that one.
Rym: but I find that a lot of people who even if they've had a dishwasher or a washer or a dryer or a Stove for their entire lives like decade-plus there will be buttons and options on those things that they have never pressed Do not know what they do and are in curious.
Scott: I know what all the ones on my dishwasher do because I read the manual I also did.
Rym: I don't have use them all But I know what they all I use, you know what you want.
Scott: I use auto.
Scott: That's the one I use.
Rym: Oh, I use a normal load, but sometimes I use heavy load.
Scott: Yeah, the only thing I don't use is the one that's like the heat drive.
Rym: I do use that in one specific rare use case.
Rym: Okay, that use case is if we're having a party at our apartment with a lot of people and a lot of food and but Then I make sure there's no plastic.
Rym: Oh, yeah, because the thing is in a party like that 99% of the dishes are glasses and plates and I want them to be dry Quickly so they can be used again or so I can refill the dishwasher.
Rym: But that's like an edge case.
Rym: but my point is if you own something and you're gonna own it for a long time and You are a geek or a technologist or a person at least know what every button on that thing does I'm not saying push all those buttons.
Rym: There are bad buttons on things that you should never push but you should at least know what that bad button will do like if?
Rym: Imagine if someone just turns on the clean function on an oven but doesn't quite know what that actually does.
Scott: They might.
Scott: I saw a video just the other day.
Scott: somebody Wanted to make pizza in at home All right, and they're their oven would not get hot enough because most home ovens go to up 400 maybe 500 go to 550.
Scott: I think that's still not hot enough for pizza.
Rym: Not another for that kind of piece.
Rym: You're not making a pizza oven like 650.
Scott: whatever pizza ovens are way are like try like 700 C. Yep, right pizza ovens are crazy hot.
Scott: So you could buy like they do.
Scott: make some home pizza ovens that get crazy hot that you can buy.
Scott: Or you can set up a brick oven with a fire situation.
Rym: internet says pizza recipes.
Rym: Generally 450 is the most anyone needs.
Scott: Yeah, the point is is that this dude?
Scott: What he did is he said hey, I know how my oven works.
Scott: There's a clean setting and the auto clean setting will make my oven hot enough.
Scott: So the oven can get that hot.
Scott: but if you activate that setting the oven will lock itself shut.
Rym: Yep I was waiting for that.
Scott: He sawed off a little bit the safety mechanism.
Scott: Oh the oven.
Scott: the oven believed that it was sealed shut and locked But yet he could open it.
Scott: It was very dangerous to do this But he made amazing pizza in his oven with this way.
Rym: now on one hand This this is illustrative of this point.
Rym: on one hand if you understand what the bad button does Fully understand it.
Rym: if you grok it then you can do things that you didn't think you'd be able to do.
Rym: But at the same time if you kind of understand how that button works, but do not grok it You're about to be in a lot of trouble.
Scott: Yeah Also, like for example, I read the manual to the oven when we moved into the apartment.
Rym: That's just what I found out.
Rym: I read the manual to every appliance I ever encounter in my life.
Rym: Basically, it's just a thing I did.
Scott: I found out it has a feature where I can tell it.
Scott: Hey, by the way oven like tomorrow morning at 7 a.m Turn on the oven and heat up to this temperature.
Rym: Oh I don't think I could wake up.
Scott: I Can wake up and the oven will be preheated already and I can just put a bread in immediately.
Scott: I don't have to like wake up to turn the oven on him to have it preheat.
Scott: So I get 45 extra minutes of sleep because I learned about a feature on my oven.
Rym: Yep I learned the only thing I learned about on my oven that I didn't know because it wasn't in the user guide It was only in the service manual.
Rym: Maybe I'm a nerd but I actually do find and read the service manuals to every appliance I have if I can Because they tell you a lot more info and it explained some features I didn't know.
Rym: there's a. there's multiple ways to regulate the air intake for the four different burners and for the oven in the broiler So that depending on the quality of the flame you can increase or decrease the air Depending on the quality of the fuel that's coming in.
Rym: Oh, so like if it burns a little yellow like you could fix that by changing the air intake slightly.
Scott: One thing I did do is I have a. you know Cuz ovens have their own thermometer that they use for preheating so they know when they've preheated it up.
Scott: But you can't ever really trust those.
Scott: right, you know a lot of times like, you know people they preheat the oven.
Scott: The oven says I'm ready and each and it's not actually as hot as it says it is.
Scott: So I have a separate oven thermometer, which everyone should have.
Scott: they're so cheap.
Scott: You put it in the oven and then you can look through the window and see what the actual Temperature is in the oven.
Scott: right for real.
Scott: Not the one it's lying to you about.
Scott: And I noticed that like hey every time it says it's preheated It's actually like 15 degrees short of you know, where it's supposed where I want it to be.
Scott: so I've checked the manual for the oven and I was able to Calibrate the thermometer on the oven and tell it hey heat up 15 degrees hotter than you normally do and now The thermometer in the oven matches the thermometer on them.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: so in terms of ovens like we know I mean we've already gone on for a while on the show, but Know how your oven works I guess they're usually pretty simple like the user manuals are only like six or seven pages tops usually with a bunch of diagrams.
Rym: Yeah, and don't fuck with your oven if it's a gas oven.
Scott: Yeah Don't fuck with gas.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I don't really.
Scott: I mean Don't fuck with electric oven either.
Scott: you could hurt yourself there too.
Rym: Yep, but uh at least electric ovens Or at least for me like not everybody the same.
Rym: I do know a lot about household electronics Like I could deal with ovened installation.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah, you might electrocute yourself or burn yourself But with a gas oven you could blow up your whole place.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Rym: Also, I am very confident that I can stop all the electricity coming into my apartment very easily.
Rym: I'm not actually clear on where or how I could stop the gas coming in.
Rym: None of that is accessible to me.
Scott: Yeah, if the if the oven is leaking gas and I've turned the oven off completely then I'm at a loss and after run Yep, pretty much you open all the windows get the fuck out.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah, somehow I'm actually surprised.
Rym: It's just kind of an aside.
Rym: I'm really surprised how relatively rare It is that people blow themselves up with gas ovens because I've seen the way people think a lot of people just don't have gas.
Scott: Oh, yeah, they're pretty they're.
Scott: they're more rare each day.
Rym: Like I've seen the way people live their lives I'm shocked.
Rym: They don't blow up more often.
Rym: Like.
Rym: I want to see the stats like how many are out there versus how many blow up at any given day.
Scott: It's surprisingly difficult to actually like blow up right?
Scott: It's easy to start a fire.
Scott: Yeah, it's hard to explode.
Scott: You have to really leak that gas and the gas smell is A very good thing.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure before the gas smell there were a lot of blow-ups.
Rym: Yeah, but imagine in a big house like you Uh, I don't know you just leave one of the burners on like you just gas is slowly coming out.
Scott: Whoever had the idea to put a include a bad smell in gas that was sent to houses Saved some large number of lives.
Rym: I can give you a guy got a good thing of the day for next time that talks about the Edwardian era and the old Gas lamps and like how safety had to be added to gas because of all the problems that happen with gas.
Rym: Yep, little subtle things like at night the gas pressure would lower.
Rym: So what would happen is if someone had their gas light set too low It would go out and then gas would just start coming out not burning and that would kill everybody.
Rym: Yeah, also people tended to gas themselves in their bathrooms because of heated baths.
Rym: Oh That was like I shouldn't exist.
Scott: Yeah, that was shouldn't exist Shouldn't be?
Rym: I mean we still have heated baths.
Rym: We just put the dangerous part far away from us.
Rym: But it's still like if you have a house it's still in your basement or maybe your garage and it's still moderately dangerous.
Rym: But that's not.
Rym: we're talking about kitchen appliances.
Rym: I don't want to talk about how.
Scott: water heaters Yeah, so I mean if you couldn't tell we don't know that much about how appliances work because we haven't talked that much about it You know because it's not like we.
Scott: you know Like we said.
Scott: people who know how to fix a computer probably don't know how to fix a dishwasher, which is true.
Scott: I could not fix most things wrong with a dish.
Rym: Yeah, but I have a good anecdote.
Rym: The reason I thought of doing this show was our dishwasher actually broke yesterday.
Rym: It just stopped working.
Scott: So for real broke real broke.
Scott: now, how did it?
Scott: how did it break?
Scott: so
Rym: one day I did my wash stuff like a few days ago And I was taking the dry the dry stuff out to put it away and I noticed there was like a centimeter of water Just hanging out at the bottom of the dishwasher And I was like, hmm
Scott: that aren't you?
Scott: did you clean out the little little?
Rym: I looked at it completely clean Like there's no debris down there at all.
Rym: There's a big cage, but it wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't draining.
Rym: It mostly drained because there was.
Rym: there was only like a centimeter of water on the bottom.
Rym: Okay, so there's a lot more than a centimeter of water in it when it's actually running.
Rym: so it clearly had really to some Amount and it washed the stuff fine.
Rym: So I was like, huh and I know based on just knowledge how the out like how the draining in a dishwasher works.
Rym: It's actually not just a drain like gravity drain.
Rym: It's a more complicated mechanism for reasons.
Rym: so I started a new cycle with a dishwasher empty and I immediately interrupted the cycle because I knew from the user manual and from Experience that if you interrupt a draw of dishwasher, it will immediately enter a purge cycle.
Rym: That's the kind of stuff like as a nerd you should know.
Rym: so I did that and it does its thing.
Rym: it goes Oh shit purging time and then I hear it and it starts pumping the water out.
Rym: I can hear the water going down my sink.
Rym: So then I it finishes the purge.
Rym: I open it waters gone Problem solved.
Rym: this will clearly never happen again.
Rym: So then we do dishes again and now there's like two inches of water down there.
Rym: Yep, so now I got to learn things.
Rym: I didn't know about dishwashers So I start taking it apart to look if there's like a deeper clog no clogs of any kind.
Rym: pretty sure the impeller that actually pumps the water out is dead or that the valves that Control the backflow have rotted and are preventing the impeller from pushing water out.
Rym: because that's to push the water out Up over a u-bend and then into the drain for reasons.
Rym: I don't want to get into read your manual if you care about why.
Rym: Okay, so I'm pretty sure what happened because based on my Investigation.
Rym: I also went found a million videos of like how to fix dishwashers.
Rym: I learned a lot more about dishwashers.
Rym: But the problem is deep enough to where I would have to take this thing apart to a degree that I am NOT comfortable taking apart.
Rym: So now I gotta wait for the building to Decide they get it safe enough to just replace our dishwasher probably because it's probably cheaper to just replace it than to try to Replace the impeller that's buried in there somewhere.
Scott: Yeah, usually that's what happens a lot especially in a big building Like if I go down in the basement of my like ten more dishwashers down there.
Scott: Yeah, they've got dishwashers.
Scott: They got fridges.
Scott: They got each, you know P-tach units.
Scott: they get all every unit every appliance in an apartment.
Scott: They have several extras.
Scott: So if one breaks, they're just gonna do a swap and then fix them elsewhere.
Scott: Yeah, if they're gonna fix them at all as opposed to just buy more one, you know.
Rym: but the cool thing about dishwashers at least like as a kitchen appliance is I Think like I think the fridge is the most important one because the idea of storing food for long periods of time is made Civilization happen to it.
Scott: You can go without the stove right.
Scott: you can go without the dishwasher Right.
Scott: you go and get out.
Scott: the fridge is hard.
Rym: Yep, like that's a different life.
Scott: It's like, okay I don't have a stove.
Scott: I could buy a hot plate.
Scott: I could not cook food.
Scott: I could just eat not cooked food.
Scott: I could make salads.
Scott: You can still have food without fire.
Rym: Also, I have a toaster and all these other things like a microwave.
Rym: There's a lot of ways around that problem Right.
Scott: There is dishwasher.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I'll wash all my dishes by hand.
Scott: people do it.
Scott: I did it.
Rym: I never want to do it again.
Scott: This is severely disruptive to my life right now.
Scott: No fridge means you could only eat food that doesn't need to be chilled or frozen.
Scott: Yep, and that's not a lot of food eating cereal.
Scott: Yeah Fresh fruit bread.
Scott: you can't bake a bread, but you can buy a root vegetables It doesn't need.
Scott: giving a lot of like potatoes needs to go in the fridge.
Scott: Yeah, you can buy a carrot and eat it immediately keep it for a while.
Rym: Actually, I learned recently that you're better.
Rym: There's a lot of those vegetables unless you're gonna store them for a long time.
Rym: If you're starting for a moderate amount of time refrigerating them is just going to make them worse and may even decrease their longevity.
Scott: Yeah, no I mean my rule is basically if they keep it in the fridge at the grocery goes in the fridge.
Scott: if they it's like a Tomato right a tomato in the groceries.
Scott: It's in a pile.
Rym: You don't put tomatoes in the fridge unless you're gonna turn like you or something.
Scott: I do after I cut into.
Rym: Oh, yeah Yeah, but that is not.
Rym: I'll say maybe it is just tomato.
Rym: It's not a.
Scott: if I got half a tomato half a tomato goes in the fridge But a whole tomato that just sits out just like it does put in the fridge It'll taste worse for reasons.
Rym: I don't want to get into Right, but The dishwasher because fridges I just assume work like if I have no fridge, I have no civilization like radical response to not having a fridge but Dishwasher, you know, we talked about this when we first moved to the city.
Rym: So back in 2009, we both assumed that having a dishwasher would make our lives better But we didn't quite grok how much of a difference having a dishwasher makes it.
Rym: I did once I started doing dishes in the dishwasher when we moved here because it'd been a long time since I had had a dishwasher.
Rym: We didn't have one in colony.
Rym: no, those are dark days.
Scott: Yeah, I think one thing about dishwashers in particular Is that a lot of people like to rinse their dishes before they go.
Rym: my manual specifically says don't rinse your dishes Like it has a line.
Scott: It's not rinse them Obviously if you've got like some fucking bones on there, right?
Scott: It's a big big stuff like an entire chicken wing.
Rym: Like yeah rinse that off, right?
Scott: You got to put that in the trash, right?
Scott: So you can scrape the plate right to get the big stuff.
Scott: Don't put a napkin in the dish, right?
Scott: Stuff that's big enough to go in the trash should go in the trash But then you don't need to rinse the dish before it goes in the dishwasher.
Scott: What do you think a dishwasher does?
Scott: Yeah, it's washing.
Rym: the crazy thing is kept telling me.
Rym: Old dishwashers would handle that stuff but newer dishwashers like are there for reasons artists like they're not as capable That?
Rym: I've heard the opposite story.
Scott: The opposite story is what I heard which I still don't know.
Scott: if this is true.
Scott: the story I heard is that dishwashers used to suck and you used to have to rinse things off a little bit because Otherwise the dishwasher wouldn't clean it all the way.
Scott: and modern dishwashers don't suck and can clean.
Rym: a very dirty Grandma dishwasher held a ton of dishes was oldest crap.
Scott: people are used to Right having to rinse therefore.
Scott: They still do it even though you don't have an alternative hypothesis.
Rym: I think I have an explanation for all this annotated not matching up.
Rym: I think the problem is most people load their dishwashers incorrectly and then wonder why the two bowls that are stuck together The inside of the bowl that was stuck didn't get washed.
Rym: I think that's what happens.
Scott: I Correct That's also true.
Scott: I'm aware that there is a correct and incorrect way to load the dishwasher.
Scott: However, I will often Lazily load it look at it and say yeah, that's overloaded or loaded incorrectly.
Scott: not care Yeah, I mean run it anyway, and then when the bowl comes out and it's still half dirty I'm like, yep, that's what I expected.
Scott: and then I and then and then I wash the other half of the least.
Rym: you weren't surprised?
Scott: Yeah, no, I'm never surprised.
Scott: when something comes out It's like put too much.
Rym: It's like if my computer like crashes and I'm like, huh?
Rym: Well, I'll just power it back on first like I don't investigate further and then if it doesn't post I'll just look at it for a minute and I'll usually just power it off and power back on at least one more time to see if anything is more like.
Scott: It's more like there was that time where I tried to downgrade the BIOS And it's like if it didn't reboot I'd be like, all right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah been there All right a dodgy hard drive for my old computer and I was like What if it'll work in the new computer it turn the computer on didn't post like that.
Rym: if I just unplug that one drive It'll boot again.
Rym: plug the unplug that drive.
Rym: it posted and I just I just I kind of expected that and I went with it.
Rym: Yep But I've seen people people we know like visiting people's houses.
Rym: I've seen them do things like put a plate or a bowl Over that part of the middle where the arms gonna come up to wash and not understand the number one thing I never do no matter how poorly Intentionally poorly I overload the dishwasher with too many dishes.
Scott: I make sure that both spin ease are free to spin without.
Rym: I spin every time before I run it.
Rym: I spin the top one to make sure it's not gonna bump anything and then the bottom I just make sure there's that column of free space.
Rym: Yep, so the arm can get off.
Scott: that arm is the two spin ease can't spin then you're nothing's getting.
Rym: I think the other thing I can say why did you even write looked up some pictures of old dishwashers versus new dishwashers?
Rym: and one thing I noticed Older dishwashers have a lot more density of how many plates and things you can put in them for a same amount of space.
Scott: The density is is not really a problem as long as there's enough space around each dish so that its surfaces are open to come.
Rym: But I think that density means that you have to load it a particular way or you'll cause problems.
Rym: But with modern dishwashers, there's a lot more space between things.
Rym: So even if you kind of just throw stuff in it'll probably just work fine.
Rym: I feel like that's also a factor.
Rym: another user experience problem.
Rym: Shall we say?
Scott: Yeah Much longer do.
Rym: we have talked for over an hour that is we made a show.
Rym: Remember if you would like us to talk about a technology topic send your suggestion to GeekNights at front row crew calm or tweet it.
Scott: ed like me are still listening to podcasts at all for some reason.
Scott: Contact us and let us know.
Scott: come to one of our communication places Twitter Even fucking Facebook where we still have a page for some guy won't see it, but Scott well Yeah, our forum obviously that I just upgraded the hardware for you know Literally any place on the internet that you can contact us.
Scott: do so to let us know That someone's still listening to this show for some reason.
Rym: yep And the stream?
Rym: someone pointed out.
Rym: premium UK sports networks are letting their subscribers suspend their subscriptions But continue in the UK where things are slightly better in some way and showing archival footage and getting sports stars to do cut.
Rym: They're basically getting sports stars to do twitch reacts to old sports games.
Scott: I Could be okay one I would.
Rym: I would like to see like a bunch of hockey.
Rym: men like get like.
Rym: Get the goalies from like four different NHL teams to watch a game Or neither one of them played and just listen to them shit-talk the goalies on those teams like I would buy would pay money to watch that Mm-hmm.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Oh someone will sell you.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights, ah Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol Marty Gringotts like a dude guy.
Rym: church option linky G you hold the key to my heart But she packed my suitcase and sent me on my way.
Rym: Clinton Walton J Bants ran from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and Lander Nicholas Brandau sailor Vista the thirst for hydrated ganon dread lily tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Sherman von Harl and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Check out the feed.
Rym: you might have seen our Emily Rym and Emily review of Dumbo.
Rym: that's only out for the patrons right now until we Go back and actually record the one that is next in that series.
Rym: We got to watch the reluctant dragon and do a show on that.
Rym: Until that one's up.
Rym: The Dumbo one will only be for you patrons.
Rym: Uh, so yeah, stay tuned.
Rym: We're working on stuff as I keep saying but for now I leave you with.
Scott: tonight We present a new miracle of electricity the sauna box.
Scott: Harry Babbitt using special sauna box units gives diction to the tones of the instruments as they play.
Scott: Harry forms the words, but the instruments sing them say it's axis No you Your eyes Something.
Rym: I'd like to sing one track mine.