Rym: It's Monday, June 8th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about computer maintenance.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Cuz I got an opening bit.
Scott: Is there another opening bit somewhere?
Rym: So on a normal episode of GeekNights right now is where I talk about like my Quarantine beard and how it's getting kind of thick, you know, something like that.
Scott: Oh, and that's a normal episode a quarantine.
Rym: Yeah Well, I mean we're against the global pandemic.
Rym: We're all like misspeak and say oh the quarantine what I mean?
Rym: their curfew the reason we hate that.
Rym: you all know Why we didn't do shows last week.
Scott: shit is on fire Multiple things as if shit wasn't already on fire, right?
Scott: It's like I did a GeekNights episode.
Scott: What was it like the opening bit?
Scott: Few months ago already Right where I was like listing all of the things that were on fire at once and now it's more on fire than it was Then.
Rym: yep, so I'm not gonna talk about the trivialities of my quarantine beard because uh There's some important stuff going on.
Rym: as you might have noticed We didn't do shows last week mostly because the movement was really picking up momentum.
Rym: We didn't want to distract like if I look at my social media feed.
Rym: even now, it's 99% people fighting.
Rym: So yeah, we're getting worried.
Rym: We're doing the show again.
Rym: We're not gonna live stream the show for the foreseeable future because I don't want to take people's attention away.
Rym: Listening to some podcast like when you have free time is different from like social media like hey check out our thing.
Rym: We're not gonna be talking about our games or anything that much on social media.
Rym: We'll keep doing the show.
Rym: but follow my Twitter for the foreseeable future It's pretty much gonna be videos of police attacking people.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: but at the same time, you know people out there Still need you know to be able to escape to something else right to a degree.
Rym: on one hand I believe that people should be able like there's entertainment like you can but also you shouldn't let people completely escape, right?
Rym: Yes, that's something I want to get because I posted, you know, we posted our statement basically saying we're not gonna like last week No shows because we just did not want to distract at all from what was going on or trivialize it or anything.
Rym: But when I posted that announcement on YouTube one Individual responded pretty much right away saying yeah you guys talk about games and those are the kinds of things I want to hear.
Rym: But now that you're getting political I'm unsubscribing and I just have to make this very clear.
Scott: See ya.
Scott: Fuck you, dude We don't watch you.
Rym: Yeah racism is not a political opinion.
Rym: So the news like the big news just to get it out like full disclose like that Just getting it everything out there.
Rym: The most important news right now is the fact that we have this sort of literal Uprising against the police as they exist in America today in the middle of a global pandemic.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: It's justified.
Rym: I'm on the side of these protesters and If nothing else I would suggest if you are a patreon patron of GeekNights If you turned off our patreon and pointed that money at one of these black lives matter causes for the foreseeable future I'm not gonna much.
Scott: Why did why did you ever give us money?
Rym: Yeah, we got fans people like us.
Rym: But I'm not gonna be posting much exclusive content in there for a while because the money money needs to be going to these other Causes right now.
Scott: So why don't you just route all incoming monies?
Rym: I am actually doing any substantial amounts of money to these things.
Scott: I'm saying specifically all patreon money is 100% will just forward because you show, you know Being like.
Scott: if we forward our patreon to someone else's patreon patreon itself gets the fee twice.
Rym: also I will still be paying income taxes on that reducing the effectiveness of those donations.
Rym: and you cannot say yeah, that's how it goes because I can't itemize my deductions because Donald Trump and the Republicans got rid of the ability for most people Living in places like New York.
Scott: the itemized deductions What that's not true at all.
Rym: The standard deduction is greater than itemized deductions for a lot of people now Especially if you it's because the only thing that changed that was significant is now your state tax is not Deductible.
Rym: state tax is being deductible was the only reason I could itemize my deductions previously.
Scott: Well, you can just donate so much that you clear the throw the.
Rym: you know the fence Yep, but you also can't like I can't say that I'm going to take money from the patreon and donate it.
Rym: That's against the terms of service.
Rym: You can't make promises like that.
Scott: Oh Fascinating a lot.
Rym: a lot of places like patreon and kickstarter have rules about that.
Scott: because okay in that case We don't promise we'll do that.
Rym: Yeah, all I'm saying is if we lose a bunch of patreon patrons for the neck for like that during all this.
Rym: I'm not gonna complain at all.
Scott: And if you're on the side of the if you're on the side of the the current government or police Why are you listening to the show?
Rym: go away so I'll link to you.
Rym: don't like you?
Scott: We don't want to hear that.
Scott: I could thank you from listening.
Rym: I would because this donation page will basically split your monthly donations across a Good variety of really good vetted organizations that are fighting for these causes.
Scott: And if you said it, you know, you want to set it to be monthly, right?
Scott: Because basically some of these groups have gotten so much money.
Scott: They don't even know what to do with it all right now.
Scott: So you got to go to the ones lower down the list but still the legit ones.
Rym: but a small monthly contribution matters a lot more than one big country.
Scott: monthly is where it's at.
Scott: because You know, we don't want to let anything Peter out right, but you know, it's gonna happen eventually.
Scott: Hopefully we can you know, hold on long enough to make some significant wins right.
Scott: right now I'm only seeing kind of mayor wins.
Scott: I want to see big wins, right?
Scott: But if you just don't turn off that monthly thing right cancel all your other shit first cancel your Netflix first to your crunchyroll first.
Scott: Right, keep that monthly biz on and never turn it off until it's like, you know I guess you would turn it off before you turn off the electricity, right?
Rym: Yeah But because remember these organizations will just do good and make the world better.
Scott: They and these kinds like a year from now, right when you know, it's like shit.
Scott: Even if we get big wins shit ain't gonna be perfect.
Scott: There's still a ton of racists out there, right?
Scott: There's still a bunch of you know bad cops out there.
Scott: I mean even now.
Rym: today 38% of Americans are literally on the side of the fascists like they want it.
Scott: And it's not just in America, right?
Scott: You know, we got the protests are going on all over the world, right.
Scott: and you know, for example in England They threw the slave trading statue into the into the the drink, right?
Scott: I just saw today, you know some three I assume racist white dudes pulling out.
Scott: They were trying to pull it out.
Scott: Anyway, it was pretty funny-looking picture.
Scott: So those dudes will probably be alive I assume next year.
Scott: So we're still gonna be need to fight in them next year even if we defund police and such and such.
Scott: yep,
Rym: but the Biggest thing I want to say before we move on to other news is because we're basically gonna talk about this Every episode for the foreseeable future because we're at this crisis point right now, but I cannot stress enough These protests in particular because of their momentum and because of their staying power.
Rym: It's working.
Rym: Changes are happening.
Rym: They're not the big changes They're not the ones we want.
Rym: but like the Minneapolis City Council said yes We want to disband our own police department and we're going to do it.
Rym: We have a veto.
Rym: mayor didn't join.
Rym: Yeah, they can override the mayor.
Scott: Yeah, you know the New York City mayor.
Scott: He's like, yeah, I'll do a little bit and we're like no no, no You should do a lot more than that right.
Scott: but you know politicians who were you know Progressive right?
Scott: They were standing for things like, you know bail reform and whatnot, right?
Scott: You know, it's like but they weren't pushing for the kinds of you know, even these sort of Compromised things that they're a lot, you know sort of supporting right now, right the sort of halfway measures No, that wasn't even on their agenda previously, right?
Scott: And that's the thing, you know These and these are progressive representatives like, you know, the ones that I vote for.
Rym: Yeah It wasn't that long ago the mayor of New York de Blasio.
Rym: the scandal around him Was that because he even vaguely hinted that the police needed to be more accountable?
Rym: The police union like rose up against him and like all turned their backs on him and threatened to primary him and all.
Scott: I think he's still.
Scott: he's still scared of that.
Rym: Oh, yeah, he's a hundred percent scared of that.
Rym: and But the point is these little changes like yes the bill the Democrats just announced in Congress doesn't go far Enough, but you know what?
Rym: When was the last time we had a conversation about a bill like this?
Rym: These little changes matter, but even if we get rid of Trump, we got a Democratic president Democratic House Democrat Senate.
Rym: We still have to keep pulling that window more and more left whatever they agree to.
Rym: We just got to say something even further out.
Scott: No, it's working.
Rym: So Yeah, you heard it here first Scott Scott Rubin on GeekNights.
Rym: Just admitted that the protests are having an effect.
Scott: No, I mean, you know, it's doing something.
Scott: Yeah The thing is it only works.
Scott: right, you know, this is something I've believed for a long time, right?
Scott: Is you know, you look at the history of you know, non-violent or mostly nonviolent protests like Gandhi and such, right?
Scott: You know, it's like what a Gandhi right?
Scott: For example, right?
Scott: He did a lot of hunger strike action, right and The point is is like Gandhi won a hunger strike and people were like, no, they didn't want Gandhi to die.
Scott: It's like they sort of felt bad.
Rym: the British people even if it was pure self-interest of the optics are bad for us right there.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: Some people will do the right thing for you reasons as as evil and imperialist and awful as they were.
Scott: Right, they were, you know, extremely awful.
Scott: I don't want to let that go right.
Scott: there was some amount of heart involved in which Enlightened and selfish self-interests Yes something that there would.
Scott: you know that the like an action such as Gandhi's hunger strike would work on them and influence them and change their actions, right?
Scott: But you look say at the US right today.
Scott: It's like okay these large protests They're moving, you know, who are they moving?
Scott: mayors governors and largely Democratic places?
Scott: You know are being moved by.
Scott: you know These largely nonviolent protests, right?
Scott: It's like that.
Scott: it affects them.
Scott: but people who are just you know Cruel and evil right who don't give a shit like the president they are unmoved, right?
Scott: It doesn't work on them.
Rym: Nothing will move them, right?
Scott: It's they're unmovable, right?
Scott: So it's like if I you know, it's like When you talk about nonviolent protests working, right?
Scott: It works on people who you know, at least to some even a small extent listen, right?
Scott: Someone who is beyond that point to where they don't care anymore, right that no longer work.
Rym: But then that's when you can protest can make them care either by causing economic disruption or social disruption.
Scott: Yes that you need to.
Scott: you need something like that.
Scott: But anyway, yep, so Just direct action gets the goods and it's working.
Rym: Yep, so just in case it wasn't clear to the why especially to that one fucko who I banned from our YouTube channel Black lives matter and we support this movement 100% Mm-hmm, and if you're bothered by that how the fuck did you listen to us for 15 years?
Rym: Like what the fuck?
Rym: All right, is there any other news?
Rym: now that we've gotten past the most important news?
Rym: You sent me something about a really funny Google story Did I?
Scott: oh, yes So Google+ died a long time ago.
Scott: I don't even remember right?
Scott: Yeah, it died.
Rym: rest in peace.
Rym: It was used by the indie RPG community.
Rym: And as far as I can tell literally no one else.
Scott: It was the only good use of it was the indie RPG community regardless For people who are using G suite, right?
Scott: Which are basically?
Scott: companies are paying to use Google to manage, you know to use Gmail instead of Outlook for their company.
Scott: And have you know, Google Drive for the company?
Scott: my company uses it, right?
Scott: They are rolling out what used to be Google+.
Scott: they've rejiggered it.
Scott: It's the same software with a whole bunch of stuff done to what I presume It is now called Google currents not to be confused with a previous product.
Rym: God damn it.
Scott: Google used to make something called Google currents.
Scott: That was like a magazine app that eventually became Google news.
Rym: What about Google wave which would be currents of water?
Scott: no Google wave is just dead day I know.
Scott: so this Google currents is simply Google+ Rejiggered.
Scott: it's only for people who are using G suite So companies not individual people.
Scott: you won't see it if you just have a regular old Gmail account And they're rolling it out as sort of like a Google+ for your company, right?
Scott: internally you have a little Google+ that all your employees can use together, but no one else and It's sort of kind of like a slack Microsoft Teams SharePoint competitor, maybe I don't even know SharePoint.
Scott: still a thing.
Scott: I don't know I never even I've heard of it, but I never actually used it.
Scott: But yeah, we'll see if anyone uses this or cares.
Scott: But yeah It's something to keep an eye on.
Scott: I guess I Would be very shocked if I want to hear if anyone's company Adopts Google currents and uses it a lot.
Rym: Yeah, I would like very interest.
Scott: I want to know about that company and the people who work.
Rym: the problem is even if it solves all these problems I don't even think Google employees will do it.
Rym: No, but even if it's great like even if it's like the best user experience anyone's ever come up with for this kind of thing No one could trust Google to not shut it down right after you start to adopt it.
Rym: because Google is shut down Effectively this thing so many times like if I get bit by the same dog five times in a row I'm gonna stop trying to pet that dog on the one hand.
Scott: Yes, that is correct.
Scott: However, as Google's graveyard is vast of the products that they have shut down.
Scott: They have shut down very very few G-suite products, right?
Rym: Well because that is the difference between the products They give to people because the people are the products and the products they sell for money, right?
Scott: So if you have a g-suite account with your company Right your company can choose How many Google products to give you access to and they can even buy more third-party products and like add them in and stuff.
Scott: But we're don't worry about that.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So for example, I could use my company's Login to log into YouTube if I wanted to and start uploading videos, right?
Scott: They didn't put.
Scott: my company chose not to put a restriction on that as far as I'm aware.
Scott: I haven't tried it, but I just assume it will work.
Scott: but they could.
Scott: they could say no YouTube right and therefore everyone at the company who wants to log into YouTube would have to use their personal Gmail account and not the company one.
Scott: Yeah So they could also as if your company and you had.
Scott: you're paying for g-suite.
Scott: You could be like no Google Docs And no one can use Google Docs with those accounts because you just turned it off.
Scott: so your company could turn on or off Google Currents for your company.
Scott: Yeah And they could also turn on and off other Google products.
Scott: So those other Google products right could be shut down But the what some Google products like Google Docs have special functionality for companies Gmail Google Docs Google Calendar Google Google Meet Google Hangout.
Scott: well, which is now Google chat or whatever the hell they're calling single sign-on integration Google Voice Google Currents.
Scott: these Google products have special company integration for g-suite Specifically and as far as I'm aware I could be wrong probably None of those have been shut down.
Scott: Some of them have morphed but none of them have been shut down because there are companies using them and paying for them.
Scott: Yep, and while I see that it's only those other products that even though you're using on a company account You might log into it those, you know, whatever.
Scott: but the company specific products the g-suite specific ones as far as I'm aware Have not hit the graveyard.
Rym: But while I see that and I see what you said I would not be an early adopter of this if I had a small company where I was in charge of those decisions.
Scott: No, why the hell would you?
Scott: not even sorry not even useful.
Scott: it's like even if you adopted it and stayed alive what good.
Rym: So in some other news, uh, this is gaming adjacent, but it's an art.
Rym: It's something I want to talk about in the light of technology.
Rym: Smites Reviewed chat logs like they have archives like if I write a video game company and there was chat in the game.
Rym: They're probably be some like terrifying archive of anything anyone ever said in the game.
Rym: So Basically as best I can tell what they did is they went through a whole bunch of their chat logs looking for like Obviously racist things and just started retroactively banning anyone who was racist.
Scott: Like don't wait some people don't know smite is I believe it's a paid-of-winnish kind of game.
Scott: I don't know about that, but it's basically.
Scott: it's a MOBA with a third-person view.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like.
Scott: it's sort of like playing a third-person shooter, but you're it's a MOBA like like dota, right?
Scott: And yeah, this games on a lot of platforms.
Scott: I've seen the game around.
Scott: I've never played it You know, it's not really my kind of game.
Scott: But yeah, the thing is why did it take this long and how could no one else?
Rym: Yeah, why is anyone else doing it?
Rym: Why do I have to report every time someone says the n-word like in a random overwatch game like hey this person.
Rym: and then later They tell me that oh this person got in trouble because of you just go through the rocks.
Scott: The reporting should be for this, you know, those things that fall through the cracks because automated systems can't catch everything.
Scott: Yeah, the reporting helps tune and reporting should not be the first system and this just applies to I think everything.
Scott: Also in a somewhat related news, right?
Scott: I believe there was like some sort of Pathfinder online Platform.
Scott: Oh the Pathfinder.
Scott: Oh, no the Pathfinder Facebook group.
Rym: Oh, wow, man, you just said two things.
Rym: I would never interact with.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the Pathfinder Facebook group banned all their racist members.
Scott: I don't know why they took them this long to do that, but they they just did it.
Scott: the next week Basically, they saw a drop in harassing and threatening posts of all kinds, huh?
Rym: It's almost like there's a correlation there.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Scott: but
Rym: any technology company Especially companies that are small enough to not be like an ISP or run into like word common carrier stuff Like if you're just a video game
Scott: It
Rym: would be pretty trivial to do some control F's like full-text searches through your database or your logs of chads.
Rym: you could probably find a lot of really low hanging fruit to ban.
Rym: and if your first instinct is but what if I Ban too many people in my game fails.
Rym: That just means your game was only popular with racists.
Scott: Yeah, I mean.
Scott: basically it's like, you know, we talk a lot about you know, like codes of conduct Which we're still working on.
Scott: please come discuss it with us.
Scott: right and various, you know All these, you know semantic arguments and how to write rules for how to behave in the community, right?
Scott: But those rules are really for you know, people who are generally good right and it's just to sort of keep them off the ledge.
Rym: Yep, they're also for the edge cases.
Rym: Like how do we handle this complicated question of like historical violence, right?
Scott: It's like there are so many easy bans that you know We just haven't had to deal with those because they don't even make it into the our community in the first place.
Scott: Yeah, but like if you if you have if you have a large community like this game smite There's a lot of people who are just easy bands.
Scott: You don't need any adjudication.
Scott: You don't need any discussion You don't need any complicated rules.
Scott: It's like you said the n-word permanent bad done the exit.
Rym: We don't need nothing else Right and the story so much low-hanging fruit and they just like no one's willing to do it and props to smite for doing The retroactive bands.
Rym: I want to see a lot more of this.
Scott: Yeah, it's like just friggin I would love to see.
Scott: I really wish Like.
Scott: if I were I I don't know how possible it'd be because people could always stop payment.
Scott: But if I mean I would want to make a video game with like a monthly payment You bring this idea up a lot or like a deposit.
Scott: and if you're if we if we find a reason to ban you Not only do we ban you but we like fine you right?
Scott: Just like you get fined in sports It's like oh you're playing a counter-strike 50 cents a month, you know We?
Scott: just so that we have here a reet we can know that we have a real credit card on a file.
Scott: Oh, you said a bad word.
Scott: Boom thousand dollars Deal with it way back.
Rym: This was like Seven ish years ago.
Rym: whenever I was I was enforcing in the live streaming team but I remember trying to moderate like a fast-moving twitch chat live and The racism came by faster than like any team could deal with and the tools didn't exist to deal with it effectively.
Rym: The the technology exists is do something like this where AI is not used to try to do auto bands or anything because that Tends to have its own problems when people seed the system with fake data to try to trip it out.
Rym: but instead you need a system to like flag the things that are most likely to have been problematic from a Previous event so that you could have a moderation team that then does the slow work of Looking through and saying yes.
Rym: No to tune the algorithm instead of relying on your community to do it.
Scott: Yeah, especially when it's just text, right?
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's like voice chats hard right videos hard But if it's just text you're dealing with there's no excuse.
Rym: Yep, but anyway things Of the day what he got?
Scott: So I think we might have talked about this on GeekNights before Possibly But there was a woman named Marion Stokes and from the year 1975 ish up to like 2012 She recorded television 24 hours a day seven days a week on VHS tapes.
Scott: each VHS tapes about four hours long Right times about 70 over 70,000 tapes.
Scott: That's 30 years of video just straight, right?
Scott: Thanks to this one person right this miraculous heroic effort, right?
Scott: That no one knew about.
Scott: but now the Internet Archive has the tapes and is digitizing them.
Scott: Right, so, you know, I'm sure like TV stations Keep video of everything but they keep it and you know If they did they probably don't have it going back to 75 and
Rym: often they won't have like what was Broadcast on this date so much as they'll have the live stuff.
Rym: They recorded they'll have like the show But the commercials were stuck in like at the time.
Rym: Commercials aren't necessarily part of whatever tape they archived right?
Scott: They would have you know, they would have like the programs, right?
Scott: They'd be like, okay.
Scott: This program is broadcast.
Scott: Here's the footage of that program, right?
Scott: But they wouldn't have like, you know the TV as it was shown on TV, right?
Scott: I've been shown different things in different places on different channels at different times.
Rym: It might have been a breaking news that co-opted some programming or preempted it and you wouldn't have that context of What did people actually see in the real world when this news broadcast?
Scott: and also people who have archives like this.
Scott: for some reason They don't open them right.
Scott: libraries have archives but companies that keep archives keep them for themselves.
Scott: They don't share them.
Rym: I don't know why a lot of times they don't have the right to redistribute the content because so many people are involved.
Scott: There's a lot of.
Scott: there's a lot of reasons.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot but you know Regardless of the fact that there are reasons.
Scott: the fact is they don't do it.
Scott: So this is an amazing Archive to have and there was a documentary made called recorder the Marion Stokes project.
Scott: It's like a two-hour long documentary.
Scott: I think it was shown at a film festival recently.
Scott: Regardless it's about.
Scott: it contains obviously a lot of footage from the tapes, but it's also about right this woman And they're showing it on PBS soon.
Scott: So you can watch it on PBS the documentary.
Scott: But also here is an event bright link for a special online event, which is going to be on June 16th June 16th at 7 30 p.m.
Scott: Eastern which will include Online showing of the documentary right and then some Q&A like you would get at.
Scott: you know A special a special showing.
Scott: only it's online.
Scott: So you register here for free this little event bright link, right?
Scott: And Yeah, this is some pretty amazing stuff.
Scott: And if you want to you know, make sure that things like this, you know are preserved for all humanity and the best way We know how.
Scott: Internet archive pretty good.
Rym: So my thing of the day apropos of nothing is just a very simple interesting video.
Rym: as you know, I follow and often talk about the lectures of DV and Olam who talks a lot about operational security and Lockpicking and elevators and fun stuff like that.
Rym: but this is just a video from his YouTube channel of him demonstrating the 1284 X fleet key, which Basically is the key that almost every police car in America uses and it's a really short video.
Rym: He uploaded it himself and he just takes this key that you can buy on eBay for like four or five Dollars or just make yourself.
Rym: and he goes over to some random police car Opens it sits down and starts the engine.
Rym: This is the same guy who did that talk.
Rym: I'd I used as a thing today a long time ago about elevator hacking but this is pretty interesting and So I guess I should slip into one more news then because the Internet Archive might go bankrupt.
Rym: Maybe we'll see Internet Archive is currently being sued by basically all these book publishers.
Rym: It looks like for Infinite money saying that it's just a quote willful digital piracy on an industrial scale and It's not clear if the Internet Archive even has the money and the legal resources to fight back effectively.
Scott: Well, there's a lot the many many people who come to the defense of the Internet Archive.
Scott: I sure hope so many that many many people should include you.
Scott: Yeah listening in the meta moment.
Rym: I've not read much more of the tale of Hanzo just yet.
Scott: No, I haven't read any.
Rym: I've been reading other stuff Yep, but I can go outside again, and I'm doing long runs and bikes again meaning at some I will Occasionally just stop out at a park and read.
Rym: so I think I'm gonna start reading this book again imminently Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean my main problem is I was reading it with my phone reading strategy which involved the subway.
Rym: So, oh, yeah, even if we start going back to work at some point, which I doubt I'm not gonna be on a subway anytime soon.
Scott: Yeah, no.
Rym: Otherwise, I mean obviously we have no conventions planned.
Rym: Pax the next possible convention has not made any announcements and honestly, it's not looking so good.
Scott: Yeah, if tickets for PAX West 2020 were to go on sale, they would be going on sale quite soon.
Rym: Also, we would have already submitted our panels and like already be talking about like the final schedule and like there's a lot of stuff That would already have happened.
Scott: that seems unlikely even though they have not officially canceled it.
Scott: However Uh Yeah, we'll see what happens.
Scott: if there's no what?
Scott: the last time I was April 20 I would not worry about camping for those badges.
Scott: nor would I if they do go on sale.
Scott: You should be able to buy one easily because most people will not be buying.
Rym: Yep, and even if you buy one, I would suggest not booking your flights right away necessarily Because unless they only but only pay for things you can cancel or return.
Scott: Yep, and we'll see what happens Otherwise gonna Ford don't have that money being held up somewhere.
Rym: Otherwise, we're keeping an eye out for good online conventions to do panel content at because we should be able to get together to do Some live panels.
Rym: stay tuned on that.
Rym: if there is an online convention you would like us to perform at Point their laser at us and we will see what we can do.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna be double-checking though to make sure that it's a quality convention.
Scott: You know, oh, yeah, I'm not helping them at all.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I do see that Kinetic ons talking about doing something.
Rym: they'd be pretty easy to work with packs.
Rym: if they do something We'll definitely be willing to work with Kinetic ons canceled by the way.
Rym: Yeah, ConnectiCon is canceled.
Rym: So there if anything there'll be an online ConnectiCon.
Rym: so I guess we get right into the main bit.
Rym: then Don't think we have any other meta.
Rym: It's not like we're going anywhere.
Rym: So computer maintenance I don't think we've ever actually talked about like the maintenance that is done on like our computers Nevermind like other electronics that we have.
Scott: maybe we have and I forget.
Rym: but the other thing I'm think I made me think about this when we were talking about what did the show on is that I Definitely have gotten the impression over much of my life that most people around me when they have computers Don't perform any maintenance on their computers at all.
Rym: and the kinds of failures they have tend to be caused by that lack of maintenance.
Scott: Primarily, right?
Scott: It's like, you know people have cars even people who are clueless and have cars.
Scott: They do some amount of maintenance.
Scott: they change the oil, right?
Rym: Yeah Granted they change the mile, you know, the oil says do it every 3,000 miles.
Rym: A lot of people think it's a scam and they do it every 6,000 miles or something.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Scott: the point is they do it right, but they don't do all of it.
Rym: They don't like get their transmission flushed when it's an old shitty car that probably needs that like.
Rym: there's a lot of it.
Rym: But the point is to check.
Scott: engine light turns on the you know, the tire pressure warning goes on People do something about it.
Scott: They fuel the car, right?
Scott: They clean the windows They do some small amount of unavoidable maintenance, right?
Scott: If you have people who have computers It seems like a lot of people even smart people who are tech savvy ish Their equivalent of the check engine light on the computer will turn on.
Scott: Yeah But as long as the computer is working people will not do anything other than continue to use the computer in the way they want.
Scott: Right, they will not like go about and do Maintenance tasks on the computer itself until the computer actually stops working.
Scott: That would be like if you didn't change your oil until the engine seized.
Rym: Yep like these two late were like in your taskbar on a Windows PC like there's a warning because something isn't fully set up or you go Into device manager and like there's a USB device that's unrecognized but yet somehow you've been using for the last four years.
Scott: Yep, so they just don't do anything about now back in the olden days.
Scott: You had to do more maintenance on Computers than you do nowadays.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean I had to take my mouse apart like once every other week and clean You know your mouse ball.
Scott: You had to defrag your hard drive All kinds of stuff you had to do back in the day.
Rym: I do my rotation of.
Rym: what games do I uninstall and what games do I reinstall?
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of stuff you had to do.
Scott: You don't have to do anymore But you still have to do a lot of stuff.
Scott: Right your computer.
Scott: no matter how well your case is designed and how good you've managed your pressure and your airflow.
Scott: You got filters at least that are getting dusty and even if the cleanest house in the universe, it's getting dusty You have to clean out that dust right or your computer will overheat.
Rym: So what I do is my case is positive pressure.
Rym: I got two Crazy powerful intake fans in the front and I got an intake fan in the bottom and both of them pull through a filter Like each one just just a filter with magnets.
Scott: I have the exact same thing.
Rym: once a month I turn my computer off so the fans won't pull dust in.
Rym: I pull those filters out and I wash them and then I put Back in my computer.
Scott: I don't do it once a month.
Scott: I do it like once every few months, but I have a reminder to do it.
Rym: Well once a month I pull them out because they're not.
Scott: dust is out of sight, right?
Scott: It's behind a plastic, you know lid right?
Scott: So I would never know.
Scott: I need that reminder.
Scott: I'm like, you know my Google tasks.
Rym: I check it once a month to see something.
Rym: I don't reply.
Rym: don't clean them every month because sometimes I pull it out.
Rym: There's barely any dust.
Rym: I just put it back in and wait another month.
Rym: But I will not name any names.
Rym: but I know multiple people who Basically said something to the effect of why would you put filters on your computer?
Rym: Won't they just get clogged and make your computer overheat?
Scott: Okay, so that if you don't put the filter is the dust will come into the computer case and then you have to find old-style Maintenance that I used to do a clock.
Scott: Yeah Inside the computer
Rym: every couple months me and Scott we take those expensive Air-dusters and we'd sit there and take our computers apart outside and blow a Terrifying amount of dust out of all the little cracks and all the little crannies and it was messy and disgusting and horrible.
Scott: Yeah, it's no good.
Scott: Yeah, so another thing you got to do with your computer maintenance wise is update stuff right up and honestly modern era.
Scott: You've got to let all your software update all the time Right, so some people I think you know have stuff that auto updates right.
Scott: Chrome is auto updating you can't.
Scott: it's hard to stop it.
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: But some people try to avoid updates right and sometimes there's a good reason to avoid an update Right because you know about a specific thing that will break with your specific thing and you were paying attention So closely to the update news that you know that this updates gonna hurt your computer specifically
Rym: Yep, like.
Rym: I have an example of this.
Rym: for a few years ago There was one like Nvidia driver update that broke civilization 5 for a brief time.
Rym: Like if you've got this updates that 5 wouldn't work.
Rym: I knew about it and I paused those updates and waited for a later update to come out.
Rym: that fixed it.
Rym: but 90% of the time anyone who pauses or avoids updates is doing it for a bad reason.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Those updates are Universe almost universally good right updates that will mess you up off it.
Scott: Right now I've got the windows update the new one, you know the 2004 with you know, WSL 2 and everything.
Scott: I've got it updated on my work laptop.
Scott: No problem on my PC.
Scott: It says actually your PC's not ready.
Scott: We we've discovered, you know some incompatibilities.
Scott: We're not gonna let you update.
Scott: Yep, right?
Scott: They've taken care of that for me.
Scott: So I'm good, right?
Scott: It's like just push the update button on everything.
Scott: right to make update your Nvidia driver update your computer Streamer like OBS has updates all the time.
Rym: VLC has updates all the time.
Rym: How many of you I've seen people at fucking anime cons start VLC and it pops up and says hey You're using a version from 1970.
Rym: I think you want to upgrade and I watch them.
Rym: Just click.
Rym: Nope every time like what?
Scott: Not only does clicking.
Scott: Yes, right give you updated superior better software with new features.
Scott: That's just better in every way.
Scott: It also stops that thing from popping up again for a while.
Rym: Yep, right now the minor exception you might defer it update a little bit like if we're about to do GeekNights like a live stream and OBS has a brand new update.
Rym: let them pops up right then right before we're about to do the show.
Rym: I will say Remind me later.
Rym: I'm not gonna run the update right before I do something critical.
Rym: I'll install the update when I have some time to you know, test whatever it is that might break.
Scott: So after the GeekNights is uploaded.
Rym: exactly but I do it like that night after the GeekNights is uploaded right update all software.
Scott: Another thing you got to do is you got to keep looking around your computer every once in a while because like, you know Over time you just accumulate stuff.
Rym: Yeah your computer like your desktop We'll probably have a folder that bit by bit a bunch of gifts you downloaded Right.
Scott: You've got your downloads folder where it's just like filling up with all sorts of things you downloaded and it's like What is going on in there?
Scott: It's like go in look around delete stuff.
Scott: You don't need uninstall steam games You're not playing.
Rym: I do this about every couple months like every two ish months.
Rym: What I'll do is I'll just basically I don't schedule it.
Rym: I just sort of know it's time to do it But about every two months and I'll basically go into each one of my main volumes and I'll just look at the directory like alright What do I got set up in here?
Rym: like what's this drive for again?
Rym: and Then I'll just poke around and make sure that everything seems like it's where it needs to be.
Rym: Is there like a directory that seems really big?
Rym: that probably shouldn't be.
Rym: If this was a server, I would automate a lot of that, but it's a desktop.
Rym: It does not take me that long to do this automating.
Rym: It would be harder than just looking at it every few months.
Rym: But like when I ran servers I had scripts that would be like warned me if any directory Got more above like 10 gigabytes no matter where it was and then I would flat white list directories where I agree They should always be really big.
Rym: so you know as soon as any random place in my computer gets too much stuff the server would Send me a notification saying yo you sure there should be 10 gigabytes of crap in like slash temp slash foo.
Rym: Maybe you left some files there.
Scott: Now you might say I got so much storage.
Scott: right I'm loaded on storage.
Scott: It's so cheap these days.
Scott: I got money.
Scott: I got a lot of hard drives.
Scott: Why do I?
Scott: why should I be go around deleting files, right?
Scott: Well the number one reason is because you're part of your maintenance should be.
Scott: obviously we've talked about this.
Scott: Backing up.
Scott: yep, right.
Scott: so the more crappy files you got lying around the more crappy files you back it up.
Rym: Yeah, and if you're backing up like a gigantic temp directory That's just a waste of everyone's time and energy.
Scott: Right so and part of your maintenance is gonna be testing that backup and restore system a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, right make sure your backup actually works.
Rym: Maybe once every I don't I don't do this as often as I should.
Rym: every six months I pull down a Subset of my glacier backup of my NAS and make sure that the recovery process works.
Rym: mm-hmm Actually, that's coming up in Next month.
Rym: I got to do it again.
Scott: Fine is if you're back.
Scott: if you can't if you haven't tested to make sure your back your restore process works And your backups aren't backups.
Scott: They're just bullshit.
Scott: Yep now I'm not talking to know.
Scott: if you if you don't know for a fact that you can actually take those backups and restore them then How do you know you're backed up?
Scott: Yep?
Rym: You might just be routing it all to dev null as far as you know.
Scott: Yeah, it could be useless but part
Rym: of that too is Reorganizing all my stuff because when you're using a computer especially in your anger in a hurry Oh, you're doing stuff I'll just kind of get around like you might be really quickly throwing together YouTube video for some reason and You download some images for it, and you just leave them in your downloads folder But then later you want to move them to the place with all the other assets for that video before you archive it.
Rym: So that's not the maintenance of testing backups or deleting unused files But that's the maintenance of all the places files will accumulate through normal use should either be purged or the things in those places should be moved to their real home so that you can maintain an Actual file and directory structure.
Rym: that is sensical.
Rym: do not trust that you will remember Why you put something somewhere in the future.
Rym: you will not Mm-hmm.
Scott: so to go along with that right.
Scott: not only your update in software right and you're organizing your data keeping it You know nice and clean right.
Scott: you also got to keep your Configurations clean.
Scott: a lot of people.
Scott: you install some software you configure it right.
Scott: you set all the settings Which you should be doing anytime.
Scott: you install a piece of software Set go through the settings and check all of them and make sure they're set the way you want.
Scott: But when software gets updates settings change this.
Scott: new settings old settings go away.
Scott: Yeah, right and You know software.
Scott: most software does it.
Scott: it's best to you know translate your old settings into new settings that are comparable.
Rym: Good at that compared to a lot of other things.
Scott: all right, so you won't really notice.
Scott: But you know you'd be surprised if you installed say Chrome like a year ago two years ago And you've been updating it and you hadn't checked the chrome settings.
Scott: You should go in there, and you'll see like stuff You've never seen before.
Scott: and all kinds of new biz right and it's like whoa you know.
Scott: so you should be checking once in a while.
Scott: You know you open an application you haven't used in a while right go check the settings on it See if there's anything new different updated right new features, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, right especially if it's software that you rely on.
Rym: or is it particularly important to whatever it is that you do?
Scott: Mm-hmm you know you might find like some feature.
Scott: It's like whoa I could have been having like increased performance because they add a GPU acceleration to this.
Scott: three versions ago I just never update.
Scott: I clicked on that option.
Scott: it wasn't enabled.
Rym: yep You know or I've seen a lot of podcasters in particular one.
Rym: They won't really understand how Adobe creative thought updates work.
Rym: So they'll have like three versions of audition installed because every like yearly update just gets installed.
Rym: But it leaves the old one there for pipeline testing.
Rym: But people just leave the old ones installed or sometimes get the new version But keep running the old version and then they don't know that the new features exist.
Rym: And I see a lot of people especially in the podcasting space Asking questions like how do I remove reverb?
Rym: and there's all these videos explaining how to remove reverb with these complicated filters.
Rym: They don't seem to know that.
Rym: audition added a feature called deep reverb that just works and is 99. it's better than what 99% of you would ever do on your own mm-hmm.
Scott: something else right is That you know your computer over time right.
Scott: you know it doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't have a lot of moving parts Especially today with a lot of SSDs.
Scott: you might know moving parts at all other than fans.
Scott: Maybe not even fans But You know there is still no matter What is the law of entropy right things over time sort of are gonna fall apart slowly in some way right?
Scott: So you just gotta you know check on things.
Scott: go look at your CPU temperature once in a blue moon.
Scott: You don't need a thing on your desktop like some overclocker.
Scott: That's telling you the temperature all the time.
Scott: Yeah, right, but just take a look at it, and you know what if like over time.
Scott: It's like oh It's a. it's a bit warmer than it used to be.
Scott: go take a look at your fans.
Scott: See if they're spinning as well as they used.
Scott: to make sure you know you're cooling.
Scott: if you have a liquid cooling system that It's working as well as it used to it might need You know some attention.
Scott: if it's super old and you've never done anything to it right.
Scott: it might be a crummy one that you know.
Scott: It doesn't last that long right?
Scott: it needs You know to be pressurized or I don't even know I've never had to do it because mine is a good one.
Scott: Yeah, but
Rym: even though I have checked on it Fans will just die sometimes and The you don't want to be the person who just like the person being me in the past Shoves a nail into the side of their case to prevent the loud fan from spinning to deal with later because I left that nail I air for two years.
Scott: It's like I haven't done any maintenance because I know I haven't had to do any.
Scott: cuz I'm checking on it.
Scott: Yeah, right just once in a. you know it's like when you remember to write.
Scott: It's sort of like you know I have.
Scott: this is unreal.
Scott: is maintenance of a non computer right, but I have.
Scott: you know the Things I shaved my head with right.
Scott: the clipper is the same one.
Scott: the barber has you know the big red one right?
Scott: And you have to lubricate it.
Scott: It's basically a little motor that just goes back and forth right.
Scott: So it needs lubrication.
Scott: and when should you lubricate it?
Scott: whenever you remember to right because it's not something you remember to do Automatically.
Scott: that often right.
Scott: it's something you know.
Scott: you remember once in a blue moon and once in a blue moon.
Scott: That's how often it needs to be lubricated.
Rym: yeah, and for PCs There's a lot of maintenance like that as well like every now And then maybe even like only once a year.
Rym: just even if you're like have filters and somehow your PC like it never gets dust into It.
Rym: just open it up and just like look around in there and make sure nothing seems hinky Like or in particular with peripherals to like.
Rym: everything's USB.
Rym: now, and there's a lot of USB ports.
Rym: Take a moment every few months just to make sure you know what all the things plugged into your computer are.
Rym: You might have a bunch of USB cables go into nowhere Mm-hmm.
Rym: I see that I see that kind of often especially people who do VR or who do a lot of live streaming or Who charge peripherals off of their computer for some reason?
Scott: Hmm I don't know about you, but my computer has UPS attached to it.
Scott: right the UPS battery is definitely something.
Scott: Then any basically any battery at anything needs you know some sort of maintenance attention.
Scott: Yeah, right, but the UPS battery specifically.
Scott: you got to keep an eye on that because you know I've had to replace the UPS battery once in my life right it?
Scott: It was like well.
Scott: I can't I don't have I'm not a good battery anymore.
Scott: I won't keep your computer like well I guess I need a new battery then.
Scott: so I got one and I swapped it in.
Scott: it was good to go.
Rym: Yep, I do not use the UPS stuff, but I've also never had a power outage in the entire time I've lived in New York.
Scott: I also have it, but that's why I have a UPS.
Scott: I'll be totally safe.
Scott: what if it goes out right now?
Scott: I can I can press save and audition and exit and then turn the computer off.
Rym: Yeah, but in terms of battery instead of losing a whole podcast and we're not talking about all technology But with computer peripherals if you have like a wireless mouse or something that doesn't charge like with its own intrinsic battery Even if like at least once a year.
Rym: just like open it and just look inside and make sure nothing looks weird about those batteries.
Rym: Batteries can keep working while leaking and you would not notice until it was way too late.
Scott: So double-a triple-a rechargeable style or non rechargeable alkaline You know nickel cadmium whatever kind of battery you got right.
Scott: if it's that kind You know you don't want to leave those in us in the same device for a super long time and some devices won't wear out.
Rym: So you won't think to look like a wireless keyboard or especially like a computer television remote control.
Rym: That battery might last five years with because it uses so little power.
Scott: Right, but meanwhile, it's it's lasting five years, but if you open it and looked in there.
Scott: Oh, no It's all corroded and some acid got out, but it was working right.
Scott: It's like yeah, you shouldn't leave the same batteries in the same thing or at least take them out.
Scott: You know rub them a little bit make sure it's not crusty in there and put it back in right You know let it let it air out a little bit.
Rym: Yep Now I did.
Scott: I don't use other than for like you have a device you don't use like in forever.
Scott: for example I like cameras on the show.
Scott: take the batteries out.
Scott: Don't leave batteries in something You're not using.
Rym: I have a shelf or I put all my batteries both the special batteries that go in like my cameras and things and all the Anna loops and rechargeables and All the chemical cells.
Rym: like I have a bunch of 9-volt batteries just for basically one purpose all the things I don't use.
Scott: often the batteries are not in them.
Rym: They're in a separate place yep, but also if you have if you use rechargeable batteries like Anna loops in the equivalent Not so it because with the lithium-ion cell like you charge it right before you're gonna use it like if you know you're gonna use Your cameras.
Rym: charge up all your batteries the day before.
Rym: that can take a while but with the more like double-a triple-a cells the system I use I have one bin that holds them all and If they're faith the head if the plus is facing up it means that last I touched this box it was charged and any battery that goes back in there to be recharged later.
Rym: if Positive is facing down It means this battery is either not charged or I do not know if it is charged.
Rym: I assume I would have to charge it before I put it in something Like a really really simple system.
Rym: Just like a lot of people do the thing with SD cards put it in facing out if there if it's free to use Put it in your little carrier facing in if there's even one file on it.
Scott: Yeah, and you can also.
Scott: SD cards also have these little lock unlock tabs on them that you can use to prevent writing.
Scott: Yep, pretty useful.
Rym: so keyboard mouse Mice don't really need maintenance anymore.
Rym: I found that mice tend to just break Long before there's anything you could clean or fix in them.
Scott: however Much like game can game pads mice.
Scott: often depending on the design of your mouse There will be sort of like seams in between the pieces of plastic and in those seams like, you know Oils and other gunk from your hands can sort of build up and create this.
Scott: I don't know what you even call it like debris.
Rym: So you want to brush that shit out of there before it gets like get a toothpick and or like some sort like some Sort of implement to pick that stuff out.
Scott: I'll use what I'll use a lot of times is I'll just take a piece of paper And fold it in half and sort of slide it along just like a second to use like a scraper.
Scott: Yep, right just scrape out all the stuff in the grooves on game pads and mice.
Rym: but but keyboards good lord I'm sorry boards guys.
Rym: Good lord keyboards.
Scott: It's like people like get germophobia in the bathroom But it's like a keyboard is the dirtiest thing in the universe, right?
Scott: It's like your hands are on it all the time.
Scott: How often do you clean it?
Scott: basically never right?
Scott: You're just rubbing your dirty hands on it constantly, right?
Scott: It's like oh you get it from your computer wash your hands you sit down you touch the keyboard again.
Scott: Yeah, what the hell did?
Scott: what did you do?
Scott: Why'd you even wash your hands, right?
Scott: So the thing with keyboards is that you know, there's this heat caps necessarily Have to have travel right?
Scott: That's how they work their buttons that go up and down, right?
Scott: And there has to be space between the keys.
Scott: and even if you have some sort of chicklet keyboard, right?
Scott: It's moving up and down and there's a space around it.
Scott: stuff can get in those spaces Right.
Scott: most keyboards which I imagine using with likes normal mechanical keys You know a typical desktop keyboard It's like there's a huge cavern underneath.
Scott: all the keys or all sorts of filth can build up and that's in addition to all the grime On the key.
Rym: Yep, but it's bad because a lot of cheap keyboards You can't remove the keys easily like you can easily break it or like they don't even come out on some crappy keyboards.
Rym: but the keys No amount of shaking will get all the grime out because the grime will just fall into the top of the keys like little dirt Cups and then when you turn the keyboard back over, it'll fall right back down into the keyboard Right.
Scott: So what you want to do is you want to once in a whenever right take all the keys off the keyboard.
Scott: They can be put back on.
Scott: it's not a big deal Right, then you can use like an air blaster or something to you know Clean out the underneath the key area and then for the keys themselves You can clean them individually with like some soap and water I guess, you know, or you or you can even put them in the dishwasher Depending on the design of your keyboard.
Scott: You may be able to put the whole fucking thing in the dishwasher.
Scott: I've done that.
Rym: Be with Larry Expensive.
Rym: nice keyboards tend to have a lot more options here, but cheaper keyboards.
Rym: You might not have any options when in doubt.
Rym: just shove that little red stick into the end of your air duster and just shove it under the keys and blow As much crap out as you can.
Rym: you're not gonna get it all.
Rym: don't pretend you're gonna get it all but do something Now.
Scott: another thing clean right is your monitors, right?
Scott: So monitors get dusty.
Scott: I don't care where you live.
Scott: They're getting done.
Rym: Yep, right Unless you have a monitor in like a clean room or something The clean rooms would actually like back when I work in clean rooms They would attract the tiny dust like the the bare minimal amount of dust that exists.
Scott: The one dust that was in the room would be attracted to the monitor.
Rym: Yep, because monitors will attract us for reasons.
Rym: We don't want to get into but the magnetic fields will attract dust effectively.
Scott: yeah, anyway, so What you got to do to clean your monitor right is you want to a obviously use some sort of non Abrasive cloth like a microfiber cloth, right so that you're not scratching your screen up, right?
Scott: And even though your screen might not have any large scratches on it.
Scott: You're like, oh use paper towel.
Scott: No big deal.
Scott: that paper towel might be making micro abrasions on the screen that you can't.
Rym: Whenever I see someone use a paper towel on a screen unless it's a shitty old like screen that's on his last legs And you might not notice because it's just.
Scott: they're so small like these tiny scratches that are smaller than like a human hair.
Scott: Right, but those scratches over time build up and build up and build up.
Scott: and then if you keep cleaning the screen with paper Towel or something frequently the screen is now blurry and you wouldn't notice if you look at the screen.
Scott: But if I put it next to a brand new screen of the same model, you'd be like, holy shit.
Scott: Why is that my screen all blurry and messed up?
Scott: It's like as you've been taught you've been micro Scratching it right all for years with your paper towel.
Scott: So make sure you use a microfiber non abrasive cloth and you can just wipe to get dust off, right?
Scott: But what you would you can do If you want to do even better is you can either take some like rubbing alcohol and dilute it in a spray bottle of your own.
Scott: Right, don't leave it at the whatever even though it's already pre diluted.
Scott: No one sells 100% isopropyl alcohol.
Scott: Yeah Well, you got to dilute it more right than what it is Yeah, and obviously your mileage may vary depending on the manufacturer.
Rym: But the the real story is some cleaning chemicals in certain concentrations Depending on what the surface of your monitor is actually made of could destroy it or destroy components of it, right?
Scott: So you ought to make sure you're using the right stuff at the right dilution.
Scott: One thing I've found, you know If you want to be extra safe, you can buy like glasses cleaning solution or camera lens cleaning solution Which is basically just pre diluted stuff, you know, but it's sort of like someone else did it for you.
Scott: They put it in a spray bottle for you, right?
Scott: It's guaranteed to be good and safe and what you want to do with that stuff is spray it not on the screen.
Scott: You spray it on the cloth.
Scott: Yeah, and then you'll wipe the screen, right?
Rym: Now here's an important point though.
Scott: You can get it really nice and clean.
Rym: You shouldn't need to use any cleaner on your screen.
Rym: If you just wipe it down with a microfiber semi like pretty regularly Then the dust won't cake in.
Rym: usually people spray it on the screen because there's that caked in dust that has settled.
Scott: I won't solidify That is true, but I will often have to get out the spray if for example someone sneezes on the screen.
Scott: Oh, yeah That's that.
Scott: that's when the spray has to come out right?
Scott: It's for the dust.
Scott: you just the cloth is gonna get you there.
Scott: It's for when something else accidentally gets on the screen.
Rym: true That's when you need some help, but and I shouldn't need to say this don't touch your monitor if it's not a touch screen.
Scott: Yeah, do not.
Scott: Yeah, if it's not a touch screen do not touch the monitor if it is a touch screen.
Scott: For example, my iPhone or my iPad right?
Scott: Those are made with like special glass, right?
Scott: Like my LCD monitors here are not made of glass.
Scott: They're like the screen is plastic, right?
Scott: So I really don't want to scratch it.
Scott: the iPhone iPad.
Scott: It's a glass screen.
Scott: It's special glass.
Scott: So even though you know, I've got hand oils all over it The way it's designed is like the microfiber alone.
Scott: with no spray the oil will come off.
Scott: Yep, right and it will be perfectly clean.
Scott: with microfiber only the oils get absorbed into the cloth.
Scott: Also, you know replace your microfiber cloths once in a while.
Scott: don't keep using the same one for a hundred years.
Rym: Yep They cost like they're.
Scott: they're.
Scott: they're absorbing nasty shit right from.
Scott: you're cleaning all this other stuff.
Scott: So, you know get new ones once in a while Yep.
Rym: But seriously if short of like sneezing on it or spilling something if you just wipe the monitor down like once a week You probably won't ever have to spray anything on it short of an accident.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: Oh What else we got?
Rym: because luckily a lot of the things I would talk about do not need to be done anymore.
Scott: Yeah, D fragmenting doesn't need to be done anymore.
Scott: You know that's been solved by file systems and such.
Scott: Yeah and hard drives that are so large And you know firmwares and things so it doesn't really matter.
Rym: But it was a big thing back in the day Yep, and the other maintenance we could talk about are not computer specific and really out of bounds for a Monday cuz you know We're gonna need a Thursday show at some point.
Scott: Yeah, probably Anyway, but yeah, that's the only idea we could come up with for our Monday show.
Scott: I don't know how helpful that was because it was a lot of common sense To a lot of people.
Rym: Yeah There's the last bit we can talk about what are.
Rym: some day There's some things that I see certain people do and that I might have been guilty of doing when I was younger and fiddled a Lot more with my computer.
Rym: but are there some maintenance things people are doing now that they shouldn't do?
Rym: like?
Rym: one example I have is the one thing that I Don't just automatically go update without doing any research is certain firmware Mmm, like I won't just update my camera to the newest firmware.
Rym: every time firmware comes out I do check to see if there's a reason but that's because Updating firmware on a lot of devices is a moderately dangerous process where if it fails you can be in trouble.
Scott: Yeah, so like your BIOS update if you went.
Scott: if you if you want to install a BIOS update Right figure out what version you have.
Scott: Yeah Figure out what version you're updating to and look at the change log and see.
Scott: Do those any of those changes actually affect you?
Scott: right?
Scott: and then do the update?
Scott: It's not gonna.
Scott: you know, if it's a software update like Photoshop is updating a video game is updating, right?
Scott: Yeah, checking is good, but you're just.
Scott: you can just update.
Scott: you can just update Firefox.
Scott: you're pretty good right?
Scott: Yeah a firmware update your BIOS EFI is updating.
Scott: check on that if you don't need any of the things listed in the change log update if they don't affect you In any way, why are you updating?
Rym: Yep What I do is when I build a new computer or like if I'm doing a free install for whatever reason like just starting from scratch I'll get myself to the latest BIOS or you know, whatever firmware for all the different devices.
Scott: But I won't really update it beyond that unless there's a specific reason to Because it might see it might seem sort of like hypocritical to be like update everything immediately.
Scott: No, don't update be careful.
Scott: It's like if it's a firmware, right something like that that could risk bricking your device simply because of the firmware update process Which is still exceedingly rare.
Scott: Don't be afraid to update a firmware.
Rym: if there is an update that in the old days It used to be a lot dicier Like.
Rym: I remember trying to operate the upgrade the firmware on individual hard drives to solve a problem.
Rym: That was not a fun day.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you look there probably are like firmware updates for like your SSDs or something.
Scott: But you don't odds are?
Scott: you don't need them?
Scott: Don't don't mess around unless you've already know you have a reason to auto up Right, and usually those sorts of things right won't be auto updated.
Scott: There'll be manual updates because they're only for people who need them who are seeking them out.
Scott: The auto updates if it's an auto update it's like yeah, that's because everyone.
Scott: it's appropriate for everybody.
Rym: yeah, the other thing I used to do is Butts with my BIOS and try to tweak the performance of my PC based on benchmarks.
Rym: I used to do that semi-regularly and I Think the error where that matters is long Past.
Rym: it's not like the old days.
Rym: We've talked about this gig guys before where you can buy an 800 megahertz CPU and by futzing with it You can over time tune it and get it to like 1.1 gigahertz.
Rym: That's a huge.
Scott: Overclocking is a hobby.
Scott: It is not maintenance.
Scott: Yeah It's expensive hobby too.
Scott: However, one thing I do see other people doing that they shouldn't do is Like maintenance.
Scott: that they're doing that they don't need to do is on their phones on their iPads on their even on their computers is Closing applications Unnecessarily.
Rym: Oh my god, like oh chrome is using so much RAM.
Rym: I gotta like close everything and reboot like no, it's just cached like the whole point of RAM.
Rym: Is it's just caching stuff that you might need?
Scott: Yeah, it's like you're good.
Scott: Don't close things to you know for the sake of closing them, right?
Scott: It's like it's okay to leave things open if your computer hasn't people like oh, it's using a hundred.
Scott: You know, it's using a gig 10 gigabytes of RAM.
Scott: How much RAM do you have?
Scott: 32?
Scott: So that means you've got 12 free.
Scott: It's like our 22 free.
Scott: It's like well, yeah.
Scott: Well, then what's the problem?
Scott: Right if your RAM is not full It's not a problem and the way phones work is all those applications that like you're swiping away to make completely closed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: and you know, it's like those are hibernating.
Scott: They were like on your right.
Scott: those weren't in your RAM on your phone.
Rym: Yeah, right like at a Windows PC.
Rym: You got a swap file and like stuff.
Rym: You're not even looking at.
Scott: Just get moved over there hanging out And if your swap file gets hit your computer needs more RAM.
Scott: Yeah, you don't need to close applications.
Scott: You need more RAM.
Scott: Like for example on an iPhone if I open one app a game and then I switch to another app what the iPhone does is It takes a screenshot of what that game looked like when I when I put it in the background and then it takes the RAM From that game and it's gonna put it like not in the RAM But like and you know some solid-state storage or somewhere else.
Scott: Right.
Scott: and then if I switch back to that game what the iOS does is it shows me the Screenshot of the game as it was when I closed it.
Scott: and while I'm looking at that screenshot It's moving the that game back into RAM and then it starts again exactly as it was when I left it Right, so there's no if you swipe it away.
Scott: What you're doing is you're basically Removing that saved state of the software you were using and that's a good thing to do.
Scott: If the app is messed up and you need to like get it to relaunch from nothing again Yeah, right because there's a problem, but there's no reason to just go doing it to apps that are working perfectly fine.
Scott: It's not gonna help your phone or change it in any way It's not.
Scott: it's just gonna make your experience actually worse because now every time you open apps They're gonna start from nothing instead of starting from where they left off and being more convenient.
Rym: Yep, well, I gave it.
Rym: now I got Chrome open.
Rym: Chrome's using about two gigabytes of RAM.
Rym: who cares?
Rym: Yep, I've got twelve point eight gigabytes in use and I've the rest is available.
Scott: My Firefox is using one and a half gigs.
Scott: Oh, no, maybe like three.
Scott: Oh, it's using a lot.
Scott: It's got several processes Discords using seven to eight hundred megs.
Scott: Who cares?
Scott: Yep, right Not a big deal.
Rym: Yeah, I've seen people to sit there in task manager like killing stuff.
Rym: We're past the days of hold f5 to boot raw and that or like use a boot disk to make a game work.
Scott: What you should do However is if you notice your computer being slow and you look in task manager and you see some processes that you don't recognize You should google them.
Scott: You'll see what they are.
Scott: if they're normal windows II kind of things don't mess with them, right?
Scott: It's like even if it sounds oh, it's like.
Scott: only mess with it.
Scott: if it's like.
Scott: yeah This is suspicious.
Scott: in which case if it's suspicious you should erase your whole computer.
Rym: Yep, that's that's a point like that.
Rym: There's no maintenance you can do.
Rym: I'm not exaggerating around Malware other than like if it's a Windows PC keep Windows Defender up to date But don't install like McAfee or like anything else unless you are an IT professional managing an environment where you need specific protections.
Rym: But if you're a compromised at all, if any malware gets on your PC, it's just F. There's no way to save that OS Mm-hmm the end.
Rym: Yeah, don't.
Rym: and uh do not run like the last thing.
Rym: I want to say anything that claims It's gonna clean up your win micro your Windows registry.
Rym: That is just a scam.
Rym: Like do not install stuff like that.
Rym: You're the Windows registry does not need maintenance.
Rym: There's an asterisk next to what I just said.
Rym: that asterisk does not apply to any of you.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Rym: That asterisk applies to like someone who is managing the Active Directory policies for an entire company.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Scott: I Need food.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So yeah Stay safe out there.
Rym: if you're gonna join the protests like remember that kovat also exists and take the appropriate precautions necessary.
Scott: And as you know, you are no good to the movement if you are ill or deceased, right?
Scott: Yeah, there that is, you know by You know being killed by a virus or killed by a police person.
Rym: Yeah, and if you if it's not safe for you to go to protest There's lots of other things you can do.
Rym: call your senators calling her.
Rym: mayor All of New York is gonna get the opportunity in July to yell at the mayor for like two minutes at a time And that's gonna be a fun time.
Rym: I signed up.
Scott: how long is that gonna be for like Weeks on end.
Rym: Well, I mean the LA one went what like all day and it was nothing but people just chewing them out.
Scott: It was so many New Yorkers.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, hey McNichol Marty green yet.
Rym: Just like a dude guy chart option dread Lily Tenebrae But she packed my suitcase and sent me on my way.
Rym: Cassandra Valenzuela Chris midkiff Chris Reimer Clinton Walton drew open.
Rym: Lander Finn Graham Finch J Bants Nicholas Brandau ran from New Zealand Ryan Perrin sailor Vista Shawn Klein Shervin von Hurl the thirst for hydrated Gannon.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Like I said, it's tough times.
Rym: if you want to redirect your patreon patronage to another worthy cause like say I'll post some links to some other patreons will not fault you.
Rym: I'm gonna be posting almost all of our patreon specific content Publicly for the foreseeable future because black lives matter.
Rym: that money needs to be put to good uses.
Rym: but for right now leave you with.