Rym: It's Wednesday July 22nd 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are talking about the post adventure time continuing adventure time adventure time distant lands episode 1 BMO.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: All right, so you know it's it's that time of the year when certain fruits are are in season The stone fruits the melons, that's right.
Scott: So we've been getting stuff.
Rym: so
Scott: the last time we ordered some fruit to be delivered right because first of all in New York City You know you can get any kind of fruit, but most of the if you go to the grocery to buy fruit Usually it's not the highest quality perfect timed fruit.
Scott: It's usually like unripe too, right Yeah, not local right you can get some good stuff at the farmers market.
Scott: You can get some good stuff actually in Chinatown or really not.
Rym: fresh direct is usually really good about that because they actually tell You how good the fruit is and sometimes they're crazy stingy with that five-star Kinda, but you know.
Scott: so we got some.
Scott: we got some fresh direct fruits right.
Scott: so last time our fresh direct fruits We got we were like we don't know which fruits gonna be good.
Scott: Let's get a couple yellow peach and also some doughnut.
Rym: Well how many stars were on that website?
Rym: That's the key.
Scott: whatever We got.
Scott: so we got two regular peach and four doughnut peach, and they all showed up, and they were all Kind of hard yeah, and so we waited a little bit till they were perfect and we ate him right away.
Rym: Oh, they became perfect.
Rym: This was not the story.
Rym: if they went from hard to blackened no.
Scott: And then the doughnut ones.
Scott: what got perfect if we ate those right away?
Scott: Yeah, we decided the yellow ones were a little bit better than the doughnut ones.
Rym: Yeah, we also got a tiny watermelon, and we got a really good tiny watermelon the other day.
Scott: So the tiny watermelon was okay.
Scott: But then after it was is better like on.
Rym: after cutting it open and letting it be in the fridge for a day or two We left ours in the fridge for a couple weeks and when we finally cracked it open It was just.
Rym: it was one of the better watermelons.
Scott: I've had like not top ten, okay We only had our sit around for maybe less than one week before we opened it anyway, so so we order some more.
Scott: We're like okay.
Scott: We like the yellow peach better.
Scott: Let's order for yellow peach instead of two and no doughnut peach and let's order some.
Scott: You know cut up watermelon cuz we're lazy.
Rym: That's fair.
Scott: so the Cut up watermelon comes in four separate plastic containers.
Scott: Is it just water?
Rym: Ordered.
Scott: we ordered the minimum amount.
Scott: so it's like you.
Scott: what should the minimum amount be?
Scott: one of these containers?
Rym: Because I can order like a quarter pound of deli meat from them And they will send me this tiny package with like two slices of meat right exactly.
Scott: And then so the peaches right.
Scott: so we had ordered yellow peaches, and we got two normal-sized ones right and that was the right.
Scott: So we ordered four and we ordered the exact same thing on the website.
Scott: We checked.
Scott: It was like a reorder.
Scott: It was the exact same item right yellow peach or whatever.
Scott: no they sent us four enormous ones like Bigger than an orange like huge peaches so big I couldn't even eat a whole one I had to like.
Scott: it's like cut it in half and like split it up when it finally got soft, right.
Scott: So we've eaten three of the four But it's like if I knew that they were gonna be this big I would only gotten two.
Scott: you should have cobbled made some cobbler But yeah, we had to basically you know.
Scott: again though They sent him to us hard, and we I basically every day I would wake up and poke them.
Scott: no and then it's it.
Scott: I think it was two days ago.
Scott: It was like oh eat him now eat him now.
Rym: We did that.
Rym: we got a bunch of black plums in a Like.
Rym: eat these today and every day I'd in the morning I'd open the fridge I'd poke every black plum and as soon as one of them was squishy.
Rym: I ate it instantly.
Rym: Okay, the weird thing is they came in a group before and they like ripened on like four different non consecutive days Mmm.
Scott: Oh wow it's raining a whole bunch of suddenly.
Rym: Oh, yeah, there's a big storm coming.
Rym: It's gonna be storms and crap all weekend looks like okay.
Scott: Oh, I wanted to bike this week.
Rym: I might just bike anyway.
Rym: It's scattered storms.
Rym: You can get away with it.
Rym: The thing is the heat waves still going.
Rym: it's not gonna cool off at night.
Rym: It's it's like 95 during the day and like It says here Saturday 75 to 89 clear and Sunday 79 to 94. that is a radical change from what I was looking at Literally a little while ago trying to plan a bike ride.
Scott: it also says rain through Friday though It's a Friday or super early on Friday like 2 a.m..
Rym: This the rain will I see Friday scattered thunderstorms in the morning Oh, yeah, and then Friday evening Saturday Sunday looks good, so I'm gonna buy and do some biking for anyway.
Rym: Yeah But Sunday is gonna be 95 degrees heated at the index of a hundred and four.
Scott: so the point is Right as shitty as Florida is for just about everything.
Scott: I still remember when I went to Florida and we went to this place near my grandma's house called the boys Market.
Rym: you told me this story like ten times, but it's like all the fruits like the mango stories.
Scott: Every fruit there was so cheap and and always just like perfect and incredibly delicious.
Rym: It's like well like when I was in Thailand, and I grabbed a banana.
Rym: I've been into it and my mouth just said whatever this is you've never had a banana like this.
Rym: This is the god banana.
Scott: It's like every but like they didn't have.
Scott: yeah, I guess they did have weird fruits Yeah, but I what we were just buying normal fruits cantaloupe Costa Rica like I remember like I always kind of like mangoes.
Rym: But the first time I was in Costa Rica And I ate a mango that had been like recently just picked.
Rym: that was a transcendent experience.
Rym: I think back to that mango.
Scott: Right why can't we just fucking ship it faster?
Rym: Well if climate change gets bad novel just grow them here.
Scott: Well, but sure that'd be good, but good in some way good.
Rym: It's definitely a silver lining on a on a fire.
Scott: The thing is we have Apple here apples our thing and we go and a lot of times you go eat an apple right off A tree and it's sometimes.
Scott: It's not that good.
Rym: Yeah apples are pretty variable unless you get like particularly good apples.
Rym: But the particularly good apples that the truth of the universe that I've learned as I became older Is that the better the product of a plant tastes the more?
Rym: Fiddly that plant is and the more care and effort and nonsense you have to do to make it not die and to make it Produce the thing you want.
Scott: yeah, I just want to remind everybody though that also in addition to fruit right now is the time of corn.
Scott: So the thing about corn is like you can make Incredibly delicious meal.
Scott: that is like easier than like some crappy microwave food.
Scott: Just get yourself a fucking ear of corn right.
Scott: take the ear of corn remove the husk husk that shit.
Scott: Yeah, right cut that shit in half if you need to because in case it's too long it don't fit in your pot Right.
Rym: boil it a little bit.
Rym: put some salty ass water in the pot not salt potato level But like put a bunch of salt in there.
Scott: put a bunch of salt in that water boil that shit.
Scott: Put the corn in that boiling water for literally five minute like exactly five minute.
Scott: Then just take the corn out put butter on and eat it.
Scott: That's all you gotta do and it's fucking delicious corn.
Scott: and you feel like you cook.
Scott: Yeah, and now is the only time you can do that because if you wait too long Won't be good corn.
Scott: It'll be shitty corn.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you can even eat that corner raw and it's pretty good.
Rym: I've eaten raw corn off the cob, but the tea like it raw corn.
Rym: I do like it raw with the corn.
Rym: raw corn cup.
Scott: Old old dirty Rym likes the corn raw.
Rym: Wow that just evoked Adam Sandler.
Rym: ask high school memories.
Rym: That was a very at it.
Rym: We that was a very Listening to Adam Sandler when you're like 14 and a freshman in high school.
Rym: So there is a bunch of anime news actually but the one you're probably all gonna be interested in is a Gretzky Co.
Scott: yeah, so Gretzky Co.
Scott: for some reason Netflix had a season one and then they had a season two and it's like oh look at that one Season two was just like better done.
Rym: Like they.
Scott: just I didn't watch it, but I was planning to watch it.
Rym: It's uh, so it's got an Elon Musk character in it.
Scott: Oh, are they the bad guy?
Rym: Uh, it's complicated.
Rym: watch your show great.
Scott: The point is Surprise, this actually was a surprise.
Scott: I thought a Gretzky Co was done for nope season three.
Scott: It's coming.
Rym: Well, I think all right, it's gotten a lot of lanes like.
Rym: it's a pretty good show like it's not great But I like it.
Rym: I watched all of it.
Rym: I'll keep watching it.
Rym: but and and generally like anime fans like like it to a degree but they're not like going crazy over it.
Rym: They're not like getting tattoos of it like they do Attack on Titan or someone has a tattoo somewhere I'm sure but not not the weeb level.
Rym: more like.
Rym: I see a lot of people who don't watch a lot of anime But just watch Netflix Like people who don't even really think about anime getting really into this show because it's got a perfectly good dub.
Rym: It's just on Netflix and a lot of what goes on in the show really speaks to The kinds of problems that a lot of people run into in their actual offices.
Scott: Mmm, it is a combo there, right?
Scott: So no, you know, it's not like Detroit Metal City, which is you know, the the The Unexpected character is into is a death metal person, right but it's you know, it's office humor plus, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's all the layers in a grits ago.
Scott: We did a show in a grits ago.
Scott: You can go listen to it.
Rym: Yeah, we did it.
Scott: The thing is I don't know if anything in that show and if anything in that episode I said It was any.
Rym: you are not into that show and that review like you were really down on a grits ago I don't remember at all Because I may.
Rym: I took the review itself out of the whole GeekNights episode and made a YouTube video that I haven't published yet as part of that pipeline with the standalone reviews and I noticed the review was only like Nine and a half minutes long.
Rym: So I went to listen and it's basically you being like yeah, Gretzky go ain't that good?
Rym: I don't know if I'll even watch the rest of it.
Rym: Why at the end I can review it from one episode.
Scott: Okay, if you're really that's also true is that?
Scott: Anyway, I There is something else that I want to say about some Netflix anime, right?
Scott: So we did an episode on the not-so-great ghost in the shell 2045 Yep.
Rym: So one person tried to come at me and say that the writing is just as good as standalone complex and we're just hitting on It because of the animation.
Scott: Whatever that person said is right.
Rym: Yeah, I disagree with that that right.
Rym: So I watch Huh?
Scott: I did watch All of the show.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: Whoa, wait, wait, why?
Scott: Cuz I had I was like I was.
Scott: I was thinking there and I was like, you know what this thing really isn't that long All right, it's only 12 true.
Rym: Maybe you can.
Rym: I've already watched it like.
Scott: I've already watched a third of it.
Scott: I bet no one else has watched a third of it as it has watched all of it.
Rym: I guess there's a point you make there to The show even if it's bad if it has even like the bear is glimmer of some of the parts I like from standalone complex.
Rym: the juice might be worth the squeeze.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: no.
Scott: So, you know, I was like, hey, maybe if I watch to the later episodes, right?
Scott: I was thinking maybe there'll be something so ridiculous there that I could post it on the internet.
Scott: and because no one else has seen It because no one posted anything.
Rym: I can find a guy back flipping backwards up the stairs.
Scott: So yeah, that's in an early episode has to be crazy on that.
Scott: so here's so I can tell you that basically the rest of the show is, you know, basically once they get back to You know Japan they make section 9 and it becomes much more episodic, you know trying to find the whatever They are called.
Scott: I don't even remember, you know, the fortnight players and whatever that shows.
Scott: Yeah, the people with the super the super strong, you know transhuman people, right?
Scott: Oh, yeah The ones they find like aren't nearly as strong as that first one.
Scott: that like that first one They found the naked guy was like super dangerous.
Scott: Right the ones they go after after they get back to Japan are like not even remotely Doesn't work stand-alone complex.
Rym: part of why it was good was that the threat they were facing was like an entire government and military.
Scott: They introduce a character who is basically like a very Anime, like yay Character who like stays in the in the office and like works the touch of comas and does computer stuff and makes mischief and whatever.
Scott: It's an annoying character.
Scott: Yeah But what I do want to tell you is that the episode Someone told me.
Scott: Oh, you got a episode 7.
Scott: I have something about episode 7. so episode 7 is basically the only episode with any glimmer of Ghost in the shell.
Scott: standalone complex quality, right?
Scott: So here's what happens in episode 7 is that it's basically Bato is going back to Japan on a plane alone ahead of everyone else.
Scott: He's going back first, right?
Scott: All right, and he gets a little helicopter ride and in the helicopter ride is the introduction of that annoying characters But it's brief.
Scott: so you can see what that annoying character is, right?
Rym: Get a little taste.
Scott: inoculate yourself, right get a little taste.
Scott: So, you know what they're that that character is gonna be a prominent character in the show going forward and then they leave and they're Not in the rest of the episode.
Scott: So you you can just get that information.
Scott: and the rest of the episode is Bato goes to the bank to deposit Launder his illicit.
Scott: other people have told me about this episode from mercenary work, right and someone else Tries to rob the bank.
Scott: and the whole episode is Bato trapped in the bank with The old people who are the only ones who go to the bank anymore And the bank robbers.
Rym: that feels a lot like Aramaki seller kind of episode.
Scott: or is a very or the pachinko parlor episodes?
Scott: It is exactly like that kind of episode but only Bato's in it.
Rym: So I'll watch that episode.
Scott: Right, if you have not watched Ghost in the Shell 2045, all you need to know is that all the characters?
Scott: Were in the u.s.
Scott: Doing mercenary work and they're now on their way back to make section 9 again and Bato is going to the bank with his money that he made being a mercenary.
Scott: and you don't need any other information to understand this episode And you don't need in this episode will also not make you curious about any of the overall plot of this whole 12 episode thing because it's a standalone Episode.
Rym: Oh standalone you say so.
Rym: indeed is the Intended wording that pink haired purin is a key?
Rym: Yes, okay Because when I googled for sack 2045 episode 7 just to see some screenshots while we're having this conversation What immediately comes up is this meme that shows that character with an X through their face and it just says no more purin is Aki.
Rym: society has progressed past.
Rym: the need for purin is Aki.
Rym: I Need for this kind of character in a show.
Scott: it is a very.
Rym: it feels like a very 90s anime annoying cute Sidekick that gets a bunch of over sexualized merch character.
Scott: Uh She's not sexualized in the show.
Rym: She'll be sexualized in the merch.
Rym: I guarantee it.
Scott: I'm sure she will be but it's basically like yeah, she's this super smart girl, but she has a very, you know, anime personality Stereotypical anime.
Scott: Yay Personality, right?
Rym: Yeah, I think anime has progressed past the need for that.
Scott: Yes So, there you go.
Rym: So speaking of a show that I watched I mentioned this a couple times.
Rym: I was watching it with Emily but keep oh and the age Of Wonder Beasts the.
Rym: it's all just on Netflix.
Rym: Like we're just kind of watching it between all the other shows we're watching But we finished it.
Rym: There's two seasons out.
Rym: We watched them both all the way to the end and the show is Definitely worth watching.
Rym: It's a DreamWorks television animation.
Rym: It's aimed at kids.
Rym: It starts out kind of like She-Ra is a like super kids show but it actually does a much more complex plot than I expected.
Rym: like What's the deal with the Burroughs and the humans underground?
Rym: and like.
Rym: but all.
Rym: I'm not gonna spoil anything But for a kids show.
Rym: this went way further and way Darker than I would have ever expected and also the vast majority of the human characters that get any screen time are not white.
Rym: There's like no white people in this show.
Scott: that's nice.
Rym: and Otherwise, like if you haven't checked this show out This is the last I'm gonna speak about it because I've mentioned it several times along the way.
Rym: Having seen the end of season two They have definitely set up a season three But they have also answered all the questions you had from season one and two.
Rym: So if there never was a season three You're not gonna be tearing your hair out trying to figure out what the deal was with anything Like.
Scott: I noticed a lot of Netflix shows are following that pattern of Wrap up your plot and leave room for another season, but don't guarantee another season.
Scott: most recently BNA Did the up.
Rym: Dragon Prince did that?
Scott: The Dragon Prince seems to always do that.
Rym: Yeah With one exception.
Rym: Dragon Prince did not answer shit about what's the deal with their dad in that bird that escaped.
Rym: They just like drop that thread Really?
Scott: I mean it was so obvious that the dad is in the bird And they just added it so heavily.
Rym: it's like Chekhov's gun and then like Someone sneaks on stage and steals the gun and then the play ends.
Scott: I'm mad.
Scott: I just want all I want.
Scott: It was dad bird.
Rym: Yeah, cuz also that dad is pretty hot and probably like you foreshadowed it.
Scott: Just let it let it go.
Scott: Let them learn magic and take the dad out of the bird and put him in a new body.
Rym: Yeah, or just haven't come back and like go to the show, right?
Scott: They go to the Dragons.
Scott: the Dragons, you know They make friends with them.
Scott: Then the Dragons help them get dad out of the bird.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right, come on.
Scott: That's what I want.
Rym: Yeah keep us worth watching.
Rym: and all I gotta say is you think you know what the deal is with these humans and it is Not what you think and it's pretty good what the actual story is.
Scott: All right, that's nice.
Rym: some other news.
Rym: I think we mentioned this before too, but the virtual crunchyroll Expo is coming up September 4th through 6th We will be doing a panel edit Probably a like Highly evolved new form of our judge anime panel not aimed at like you the listener who know the deal with us but at people who don't necessarily know about us because we haven't really been going to anime cons for Some many years now for a lot of reasons.
Rym: This will actually be our first anime con since I think 2014 Maybe 2015 at the latest Maybe yeah, I had to go like dust off anime.
Scott: Actually, I find that I just the thing of the day I sent you will be used as a thing of the day, but I just remembered a better thing of the day.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Oh That's got a better thing of the day sneaking it in right before it's time for things Of the day.
Rym: All right, Scott.
Rym: I'm not even gonna look at the link until after we record the show.
Scott: All right, so, you know you go to anime con when we did that.
Scott: Yeah back in the day and you go to everyone's favorite place the dealers room.
Scott: Yep, and there's certain kinds of dealers in the dealers.
Rym: There's the one booth selling just a pile of cells and there's a bunch of old people looking at those cells that are all like $500 each.
Scott: right there's the booth.
Scott: It's just selling manga walls of manga.
Rym: Yeah, right There's the booth that has like old broken crap and then discount bins full of VHS tapes under it.
Scott: Yep, DVD guy, right?
Scott: Nothing, you know, there's the sword.
Rym: you the sword booth just or guys sword booth, right?
Scott: And you know, there's a certain kind of booth right that sometimes is not even a booth.
Scott: Usually it's more often it go to a standalone anime store that's been around a long time Right where they've got the old stuff, right?
Scott: We're talking like, you know old dusty Godzilla figurines.
Scott: You know that kind of booth the kind.
Scott: that's the kind of booth where you won't buy anything but you'll spend a lot of time looking at that booth and they'll have like an Actual Akira t-shirt from the 80s for a hundred bucks.
Scott: Yeah and shit like that right that kind of booth.
Scott: Well, it's more like a museum Exactly, but I found I'm sure this has been around for a long time and I just didn't know about it There is a store called Kimono my house toys And I guess their Instagram and their eBay site are basically their website.
Scott: and basically, that's what they are is they are the super old dusty anime merch.
Scott: lots of Gundam lots of Ultraman lots of Godzilla lots of You know lots of Galaxy Express Yamato captain Harlock's Astro boy.
Scott: all you know the old stuff, right?
Scott: That's the kind of stuff that they got at that store.
Rym: That's my kind of stuff right, you know?
Rym: Don't buy any of that stuff?
Scott: No, no No.
Scott: Well, you can go to their eBay and buy it because I presume their store is not open to that many customers these days.
Scott: But just follow them, you know peruse their Instagram account to get that experience of Going to one of those booths at an anime con since you can't go to anime con right now, right?
Scott: You can get that experience of the old dusty booth, and you can maybe even buy stuff if you really want to.
Scott: But you can also just follow them on Instagram And you'll constantly get posts from them as they post photos of their stuff.
Scott: for example mr.. T wearing an Akira t-shirt Or a whole bunch of pit Akira pins and lensman pins on a board You know.
Scott: or the San Diego comic-con 1992 you know t-shirt.
Scott: or this giant pile of old Disney stickers who knows if they're still sticky.
Scott: But I kind of want one.
Scott: All kinds of great stuff on this Instagram from this store, so there you go.
Rym: So this is a Twitter thread But it's a pretty dense Twitter thread of exactly what you want to see without any text or anything in the way.
Rym: It's just a long thread.
Rym: You can just scroll down and enjoy.
Rym: it is just a whole bunch of photos of Soviet bus stops from all over the Soviet Union and The reason why these are so cool is something.
Rym: I only learned about recently.
Scott: I feel like I've seen these before.
Scott: talked about them on the show before.
Scott: I think we've seen a few nice Because they see they.
Scott: I've definitely seen some of these before in my life.
Scott: They're familiar to my eyeball.
Rym: Yeah, I hope I didn't reuse that.
Rym: I did a search and didn't find a thing of the day.
Scott: There was I think there was a Kickstarter for a Soviet bus stop book.
Rym: If I talk about we might have talked about talked about that book, but basically this is just an archive of all these photos.
Rym: but what I learned from this thread is Why?
Rym: Specifically Soviet bus stops are so crazy compared to a lot of other Soviet architecture.
Rym: That's so utilitarian and samey.
Rym: What it came down to is the central government Didn't give a shit what bus stops looked like like they didn't care at all.
Rym: So when they told a local area to make bus stops The local area had complete discretion to do whatever they wanted and they tended to Get architects who wanted to just go crazy and do something cool And as a result They are so radically different like every area of the Soviet Union has Radically different styles of the things that the central government didn't care about.
Rym: So if you want to find cool stuff on the internet try to find more examples of things that were very important to the Soviet Union But where the government of the Soviet Union did not have any particular ideological concerns about the nature of said thing.
Scott: what I find really interesting is that You know you look Historically right and that you know, the very Milton Friedman capitalism is freedom.
Scott: people right are always like, ah, you know if the government is is Paying for the art and control in the art It's like, you know, it's like you won't be able to print any sign you want if the government owns the printing press Right to get the government's paying for the art.
Scott: You're gonna get meanwhile Cool bus stop in America like anyway, what I'm saying though is if you look at you know The art that is produced by you know government's paying for it Even if that art is propaganda like Soviet stuff often was.
Scott: yeah, it's often fucking cool No matter what country it's in evil country or a good country or anywhere in between.
Rym: right if an artist paid a living Way to make something they'll try to do a good job.
Scott: Look at the mosaics you get in like New York City subway stations, right, you know, even North Korean shit, which is At least, you know.
Scott: all those propaganda posters look cool Even though they're all.
Scott: you know, it's awful, but it's right.
Scott: It's like when government pays money, you know.
Scott: Look at all the Canadian animation.
Scott: the government pays people to make art kpop.
Scott: is the government paying people to make art, right?
Scott: They get all kpop.
Scott: people are getting government money.
Rym: Do you understand how good GeekNights would be if the government just paid us to make it right?
Scott: And that's the government was paying podcasters because they felt that Podcasts were an important thing to have and we were getting.
Scott: we like applied for a government thing and they were sending us cash.
Scott: It's like oh man, he would be killing it.
Rym: Yeah, we were.
Scott: I would I would start doing a lot of things that I do Not do today Right, so it's you know, any kind of government funded art is like, you know government funding for the arts PBS All right.
Scott: Come on.
Scott: It's all good shit.
Rym: Sorry for a little distracted.
Rym: The Thunder outside is actually getting pretty intense.
Scott: I'm watching lightning like hit the buildings in Manhattan.
Rym: Yeah, so it's a good time Good time for a storm.
Rym: Hopefully doesn't interrupt the stream suddenly.
Rym: All right, met a moment.
Rym: We're stuck at home Can't go anywhere.
Rym: Like I said, so stay tuned.
Rym: You'll see us at PAX online the magfest online stuff.
Rym: You're gonna see us at the crunchyroll online Expo and see our stuff on the internet.
Rym: We're working on Pipelines to make the kind of stuff that's hard to make when we can't get together in person.
Rym: so stay tuned for all that.
Rym: we are currently not reading the tale of Genji because Don't have a lot of free time don't have a lot of travel time.
Rym: Like normally.
Rym: I'd read that book on the bus or the train or the subway, but not going anywhere.
Rym: I'm not gonna read it while I'm biking, you know, the excuse is stronger.
Scott: Would you say the same excuse every episode every time.
Scott: it's just like it were it works better?
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: It's like if you keep making a different excuse.
Scott: It's like ah, these are excuses.
Rym: Well, then you're just Jake.
Scott: There was an earthquake.
Scott: same excuse every episode of GeekNights for a year.
Scott: You just keep saying the same reason we haven't read the book club book And while we're encouraging other people to read the book club book.
Rym: That was a big that's a Thunder.
Scott: I saw the big lightning hit building in LAC.
Rym: Yeah, I shook our windows a little bit.
Scott: It was a big boy.
Rym: Yeah, I could feel it All right.
Rym: So yeah all that aside met a moment.
Rym: But one thing I want to bring up because the news I just caught this while I was looking at my thing of the day The federal government in the United States is sending more of those Gestapo stormtrooper things to Chicago like right now.
Rym: So go like.
Scott: good luck Chicago.
Rym: Yep, Chicago.
Rym: Good luck when they come here.
Rym: We'll be ready for them.
Rym: so I hope you guys are ready.
Rym: stay safe out there, but I'm gonna link to this news in the episode too because this is Escalating rapidly and this is way more important than the nerdy stuff.
Rym: We're about to talk about Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the nerdy stuff we're about to talk about Adventure time ended.
Rym: it ended a while ago and ended perfectly like.
Rym: adventure time was a fantastic Transformative show that probably will be a cornerstone of like the history of animation in America.
Rym: There's a lot we've said a lot about adventure time over the years, but it ended.
Rym: it was done.
Scott: Oh, you know, there's still other adventure time stuff.
Scott: There is technically and yeah The comics are actually doing that shtick where they're like adventure time season, whatever, right?
Scott: But I do enjoy that shake a little bit even though it's a bit corny, but I think they basically gave up on that Right.
Scott: It's like I think that was a news if I remember like they started it and they're just like yeah No, yeah, no one bought no one bought it.
Rym: All right but Adventure time continued with.
Rym: there are four episodes hvomax.
Rym: We talked about this being announced a while ago.
Rym: They're for like our ish long brand new episodes.
Scott: Yeah, they're longer than a regular episode, but they're not that long They're not even 90 minutes.
Rym: Yeah They're like.
Rym: they're like take three or four adventure time episodes that have a contiguous plot and just ram them all together.
Rym: They're almost the equivalent of like the island episodes or like all the elemental episodes like those Miniseries that they did along the way just condensed into one long episode.
Scott: So it has been revealed that episode one which we buy is out.
Scott: You can watch it.
Scott: So we're gonna talk about it.
Rym: We just love it.
Scott: It's about BMO.
Scott: the next episode who knows when it's gonna come out?
Scott: It's on it's unannounced is gonna be about Princess Bubblegum and Marceline.
Rym: Yeah, it's called obsidian.
Scott: They go to The glass kingdom or something.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, they third one on their relationship while on a mission to the glass kingdom.
Rym: It's basically what you all want what the show didn't get to get to until the very end.
Scott: The third one will.
Scott: what I want the most is peppermint, but oh, yeah school to learn to relearn evil magic In wizard city.
Rym: wizard city is my favorite part of adventure time.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and then the last one is Finn and Jake doing something again right up together again as they know.
Rym: what's interesting is it says rediscover their brotherly blah bond Implying that something might have broken that bond at some who knows who knows when in the adventure time time timeline The episode takes place.
Rym: Yes, because not to spoil anything but BMO does not take place.
Rym: when I assumed it took place, right?
Scott: We assumed oh, okay These episodes are going to take place after the end of the TV show But before the end end of the TV show, right?
Scott: Cuz the.
Scott: basically the TV show has epilogue at the end that take place far in the future from The actual like end of the plot of the main characters and you would assume like all four of these episodes are gonna take place after the end of the TV show, but before the epilogue end of the TV show
Rym: Because we know for a fact obsidian takes pleasure not obsidian wizard city takes place after Because it is reacting to events from the show.
Scott: sure but anyway That is not necessarily the case as we learned watching this it could take place anytime in the adventure time timeline prequel in the middle of the show anywhere, right But they are canon adventure time animations That are not ever before seen and that is awesome.
Scott: that they're continuing to make these and they're on HBO max.
Rym: Yep, I I definitely watched it on HBO max and did I not sail a high sea anywhere?
Rym: All I will say is if you are not technologically savvy and you find this show somewhere and Your media player tries to tell you to buy a codec do not do that.
Rym: Just find a different file.
Rym: That's all I'm gonna say about that.
Scott: Anyway, but a point is HBO max does have Some good content.
Scott: Oh, yeah, like it's actually like You know like worth watching maybe if that's if that is the content you like the most, you know, it's got Studio Ghibli stuff.
Scott: It's got Cartoon Network stuff, obviously, right?
Scott: It's got.
Rym: it's got bits of the Criterion collection.
Rym: It's got it crunchy roll stuff.
Scott: There's all kinds of stuff on HBO.
Rym: man of our barbera Warner Brothers.
Scott: Yeah It is not a bad thing to subscribe to if that's the one you're gonna subscribe to.
Scott: but I'm on Netflix right now And I don't do two at a time.
Rym: Well - I'm on Netflix.
Rym: crunchy roll.
Scott: I actually have been watching the crunchy roll in a long time.
Scott: I should turn it off and turn out again.
Scott: The problem is they always get this annual crunchy roll to save money and I do use it every year.
Scott: I just don't use it every month.
Rym: I've actually used it recently to get screen caps of Anime, we've reviewed to make those YouTube videos Mmm, so it actually anyway out.
Scott: So yeah, but you know if you if you want to watch this legally you can pay for HBO max.
Scott: I don't know if it's available anywhere else at all.
Rym: You pretty sure it's HBO max exclusive.
Scott: if you have television Can you even watch this?
Scott: Oh just cape cable TV and you watch HBO?
Scott: No, like will it be on demand on your cable box?
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: I think it's only on HBO max.
Scott: That's interesting.
Scott: Anyway, the point is it's Adventure Time.
Scott: We watched it.
Scott: Let's talk about what we watch.
Rym: Yep We'll avoid spoilers.
Rym: at the very end we can talk a little bit about like our thoughts on what it revealed about the universe, but it is Really really cute because they introduced this rabbit girl character and it's basically this rabbit girl and BMO going around on a space Station that's falling apart
Scott: while a BMO is out on my
Rym: tries to destroy it.
Scott: BMO is out in space on a mission.
Scott: BMO ends up in a different world.
Scott: the world is basically not a planet but a space station sort of platform that has different domes that are connected and the different domes have different habitats in them and Clearly the people on the dome.
Scott: so there's like crab people and robot people.
Rym: There's crab people robot people bunny people and bunny people and then a whole bunch of like minor races that are also hanging out there.
Rym: It's definitely like a cosmopolitan space city.
Scott: Yeah, there's some you know, there's some like Those bug guys.
Scott: Yeah monsters.
Rym: I love the little bug guys.
Scott: Yeah, all kinds of space shit is going on there, right?
Scott: And so, you know BMO ends up there via circumstances and the shenanigans there that he BMO discovers that the people there are like fighting over like You know resources because they're stuck on the station and there's certain rare Resources that they're fighting over and BMO gets involved in saving the day because it seems like most of the people there are sort of just content or compliant with their situation.
Scott: and BMO is like, you know being BMO seeing the injustice and being like yeah Adventure and
Rym: but it's very interesting to show cuz you it's been in Jake or some other characters are the driving powerful forces and BMO is either a cute sidekick or BMO is a catalyst but they save the day.
Rym: obviously there's exceptions to that.
Rym: But in this case BMO is the catalyst But is also like the mentor driving forward the plot and dragging this other character along.
Rym: It's a different.
Rym: it's like an inversion of what often happens in Adventure Time episodes when BMO is involved.
Scott: Yeah, it's like BMO.
Scott: basically, you know sees like hey, there's some BS going on.
Scott: Let's fix it.
Rym: Yippee-ki-yay Kind of literally.
Rym: Yep You can sort of see like this is Sheriff BMO BMO literals like well I'm the sheriff of this town and I love how a lot of the people BMO meets are just like.
Rym: alright I guess you're the sheriff sure.
Scott: Yeah, and in typical BMO fashion BMO is simultaneously like playing while also You know not playing right?
Rym: Yep I love I love that duality of BMO.
Rym: all the time BMO is playing games because BMO is a toy, right?
Scott: So BMO is about playing.
Rym: Yep, but BMO is also special for the reasons We know from the show and thus BMO is a literal catalyst for good.
Scott: Yeah, I think if you haven't watched Adventure Time, I don't know This would guess you can.
Scott: I guess you can watch this but you would just some things would be lost on you one Big one in particular.
Rym: Well - lost.
Rym: I can think of a couple of big ones.
Rym: That would be lost as one.
Scott: I think that is vastly bigger.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but there's also little things like football like That.
Rym: yeah, you're right.
Rym: Football is portrayed very well in this and I really like how that played out.
Rym: I Think it would still work if you'd never seen Adventure Time, but it would work.
Scott: But yeah, you wouldn't.
Scott: you would be like, oh, I guess BMO has an imaginary friend.
Scott: whenever they look in a reflection.
Scott: This is yeah, but BMO's reflection is named football and BMO talks to it.
Scott: It's like but yeah, BMO does that a lot in Adventure Time.
Scott: football is like a whole character and here They just they don't bother to introduce football.
Scott: It's just like there's football.
Scott: It's like you're it's expect.
Scott: It's written in a way where you're expected to know Football and so I think it's just the fact that she's a thrown there would be might be a little If you didn't know Adventure Time.
Scott: possibly, yeah, maybe not It's not that big a deal to the.
Rym: I think what would happen is a small ball shows up a few times or like the things With the lards and all that like.
Rym: there's a lot of things.
Scott: that's true the lard Yeah, the.
Rym: this would feel a lot weirder and more Abstract and crazy if you hadn't seen Adventure Time.
Rym: But if you've seen Adventure Time a lot of the more crazy things that happen are pretty mundane features of the Adventure Time universe Right.
Scott: So lards are like these basically heads with big noses that float around that come in different shapes and sizes And they're kind of like mystical and immortal in regular Adventure Time like.
Scott: yeah It's like they have like a. they're like, you know, they don't play a large part But there's still Significant a significant and important presence and they sort of have a meaning to them and they show up at certain times and places.
Scott: Yeah, but here it's like, you know BMO lands and there's a guy like lard farming if they're gonna eat lards or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like if you haven't seen any Adventure Time, you're like.
Scott: that means nothing to you.
Scott: But if you have it's like oh shit, those are lards.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like now I kind of know the deal with large like.
Scott: more so Yeah, but it's like so that the impact of that same scene would be completely different for it wouldn't make it this a meaningless Watch to a non Adventure Time knower, but that the impact of that is like those are lards versus.
Scott: Okay, this guy's farming some space creatures.
Scott: All right, I get it.
Rym: So before we get into some spoiler territory the other notes I could point out is that there's a character another robot Kind of a broken robot seagull, you know voice seagull.
Rym: No, Simone Gertz the woman who makes the terrifying bad robots.
Rym: okay, they she was a huge fan of well is a huge fan of Adventure Time and The creators of Adventure Time were like we should get that person who makes bad robots to play our bad robot.
Rym: and the bad robot Person was like.
Rym: I've always wanted to be an Adventure Time voice actor.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: So they time seems to do that a lot, right?
Scott: I think you know John Hodgins been an Adventure Time voice actor and I think he voiced something in this because I heard his voice.
Scott: I think He might have been one of the people fighting against the crab people at that scene.
Scott: Maybe I don't remember but I definitely heard John Hodgman's voice in the in the show.
Scott: Yeah, and also who's the person?
Scott: who's the voice of?
Rym: Mabel and oh god, I always forget their name.
Scott: I just forget her name.
Scott: I don't know what their name.
Rym: She's an Adventure Time.
Scott: Yeah, I can look it up.
Scott: But yeah, please.
Rym: Well, I forget their names to one of Jake's kids.
Scott: Yes, exactly that person is.
Rym: but one thing I can't say is that the voice acting is all.
Scott: that's the person.
Scott: this is all.
Scott: Yeah, the boy were not.
Scott: I don't think I heard Kristin Shaw in this BMO thing But I definitely heard John Hodge.
Rym: the voice acting in this is really good.
Rym: Like the writing is good like everything about it's good.
Rym: It's a hundred percent worth watching.
Rym: It does a little bit of Explain the plot at the very end, but it's so short that part that well That was a big thunder that it doesn't really matter.
Rym: Like it's not a flaw I would say It just wraps up like it could have.
Rym: it could have had ten more minutes to wrap up its plot like a little more smoothly.
Rym: Instead it sort of accelerates toward the end and a few characters have their big Moments pretty suddenly.
Rym: but other than that like it's just fantastic.
Rym: It was laugh-out-loud funny at multiple points.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, it's it's what you expect from Adventure Time.
Scott: It's more Adventure Time.
Rym: It gives you a lot of BMO if BMO is your favorite Yep And it does nothing to undermine the perfect ending of Adventure Time like it's not like if they just made more cowboy bebop.
Scott: No, no, no, it's it's more good Adventure Time, but it's not.
Scott: you know, the the lack of length It could have.
Scott: you know, it's like they introduced a bunch of stuff.
Scott: They wrap up all the stuff they introduce and It's like it's more like okay.
Scott: You love Adventure Time so much.
Scott: You haven't had any in a while.
Scott: You want more.
Scott: Here's an Adventure Time snack and you're like, wow that tastes just like Adventure Time, but I wanted an Adventure Time meal.
Rym: Yep, I just want to know if they can make these forever.
Rym: I just keep watching them.
Scott: Well, they're gonna make three more.
Scott: I know it's like it's like you're getting four snacks where what you when you want a meal the snacks taste exactly what you expect Them to taste like right?
Scott: They're good.
Scott: You're not turning them down, right?
Scott: You should eat them, but you still want meal, right?
Scott: That's what.
Rym: that's what this is Alright, so spoiler spoiler spoilers because I want to talk about this assuming you've seen it That was definitely Finn's dad and 100% that is why he's in fucking space prison.
Scott: It is the voice acting of the same voice.
Scott: as soon as I knew I heard of the same voice actor I was like, that's Finn's dad.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Plus it was like.
Scott: it was like mr.
Scott: M and isn't Finn's dad named like Mert Marty or something?
Rym: Well balls of last name friends Mertens.
Scott: that's it, right?
Scott: Yeah plus I knew.
Scott: I knew.
Rym: as soon as he gets out of that car and you see he's wearing those short Shorts and like he's like man spread legs.
Rym: He's not.
Scott: as soon as he spoke a line of dialogue I was like.
Scott: that's Finn's dad's voice and I was like, wait a minute.
Scott: No, it's Finn's dad.
Scott: Yeah Immediately, I knew it and how.
Rym: he's kind of just a piece of shit.
Scott: the whole time He acted like he acted the way Finn's dad would act treated people the way Finn's dad treats me.
Rym: I like how it brought the guys in as soon as they would.
Scott: as soon as there was trouble.
Scott: He got out of Dodge just like Finn's dad does.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I don't know how the plot was.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: These were humans who escaped earth.
Rym: Yep, like that little bit was fun, too Especially because the villain literally is just like an Elon Musk who sent himself into space and is now just fucking shit up with capitalism Mm-hmm.
Scott: So the interesting thing that's it's not quite Completely answered.
Scott: Mm-hmm right if we're going spoilers is you start out beimos on this mission to plant potatoes on Mars and gets pulled away by the Maintenance robot that you do learn about.
Scott: why?
Scott: yeah, but the deal was with that.
Scott: But they don't explain beimos potato mission.
Scott: who sent him on?
Rym: Where did bemo get those potatoes?
Rym: or that was emo?
Scott: I was bemo still with all the other Mo's right did like mo send bemo on a mission to plant potatoes on Mars.
Scott: Who would send bemo on a mission to plant potatoes on Mars?
Scott: magic man?
Rym: Cuz this is becoming.
Rym: this is before magic man's transformation.
Scott: This is before Who would have who would have sent bemo into space right?
Scott: It's like banana man.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: what's the deal there?
Rym: It was a pretty good spaceship too.
Rym: Like it was right.
Scott: It was.
Scott: it was working bemo's clearly on a mission.
Scott: The mission was functioning.
Scott: He had the potatoes.
Scott: He was specifically.
Scott: he knew he was going to bemo.
Scott: I guess bemo's not here or she?
Scott: bemo, you know knew they were supposed to be going to Mars.
Scott: Yeah, right was headed towards it successfully was into.
Rym: it was like mission was totally cool.
Scott: Nothing about that setup was revealed.
Rym: That was the only unanswered Question which I like because it parallels at the end of real adventure time where you get the final Denim on.
Rym: other than bemo being the king of oohs you get bemo clearly launching that rocket into space.
Rym: Mm-hmm with their creator.
Scott: Yep Anyway, yeah, but I any other any other spoiler talk.
Rym: Mmm the Grays.
Rym: it was interesting in the sense that when Tree trunks is interacting with the Grays later and they're like trying to find a new home world It is very clearly clear that Elon Musk made the Grays turn him into an elf and then he basically fucked up their planet and left
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: like he.
Rym: there's a lot of catalyzing incidents that occurred in this.
Scott: Yeah So Yeah, I mean if you're if you're writing for Adventure Time and you're a good writer, right?
Scott: There's so many episodes and so much content.
Scott: you can easily find a thing that happened in Adventure Time episode Right and then leave it in right.
Rym: don't even need to shine a spotlight on it.
Scott: Just weave it Right, let it you can just and you can treat it if it hasn't been used already.
Scott: It's like you can treat it as a starting point for whatever you're gonna do.
Scott: It's like oh that time that You know, it's like okay that the infinity train episode right.
Scott: well You can write something about how that train got there or you know, someone escaped the infinity train.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like, you know, it's just like every episode is just like a fountain of ideas that you could go off into.
Scott: So that's what they do.
Rym: these side characters in this definitely are echoes of unexplained characters from Adventure Time that showed up in a few episodes like you can and that's You can take a parallel like draw them but like put them both side by side for every character you see in this thing.
Scott: And that's how you do the quality world building and the quality continuity.
Scott: You don't do it the way that you know.
Scott: Marvel DC Comics did or do or still do.
Scott: I don't even know anymore.
Scott: I don't know a new one in a long time where it's like if you didn't read all these different kind if you didn't read cats in America and Spider-man and this and that and the other thing.
Scott: you won't understand what's going on in secret Wars, right?
Scott: It's instead just a world building thing where it's like you can watch any random Adventure Time episode or movie or whatever comic and totally Be entertained, but if you understand the whole world Right, there's just hints and things that will enrich any particular thing that you consume, you know With your additional knowledge, right.
Scott: and each thing that they make while simultaneously Building on what already exists also is creating more for future things to go on Right.
Scott: It's like you watch this BMO thing and now we've learned about this place, right?
Scott: Well now think about how many more stories you could write with all the new things that have been created here, right?
Scott: You could write about those crab people.
Scott: you could write about or you know.
Rym: When did those humans leave earth and like what happened to them specifically?
Rym: Did they become the bunny people or the bunny people like the original hell?
Rym: like?
Scott: we don't know any of that Right, you can write about what Finn's dad was doing after this and before the other thing.
Scott: you can write about what happened to the Evil guy the well the evil bunny guy.
Scott: What's what's his deal?
Rym: I want to say that this is literally the specific reason Finn's dad was in space jail.
Rym: Yeah, probably I feel like that is the exact sequence of events.
Rym: is he was taken to space jail shortly after the incidents of the show.
Scott: quite possibly you could write about.
Scott: you know, there's the The the the non-mo that was in the garbage area.
Scott: you go so you go right you could write about that.
Scott: Yeah, there's all kinds of stuff going on there.
Scott: It's just like while taking the existing material They've also created new fertile ground, right which May or may not be explored in the remaining three movies.
Rym: I feel like the three movies will not intersect with each other at all.
Scott: I also feel that way.
Scott: I feel like they will all be standalone Dealies.
Rym: standalone, it's it's it.
Rym: that's the gravel of this episode of GeekNights.
Scott: Did you see the gravels that were on the?
Scott: yes I saw those I was like, those are fucking gravel people.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the GeekNights patreon.
Rym: patrons for this episode are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol.
Rym: Gotta expand the screen.
Rym: There we go.
Rym: Mardi Gras.
Rym: Yeah, just like a dude guy charts.
Rym: obviously Graham Finch You hold the key to my heart.
Rym: She gave me a kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Rym: Clinton Walton Jay Vance Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff the thirst for hydrated Ganon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Shervin Von Harl and a whole bunch of people who do not want me To say their name.
Rym: Yeah, there is a huge thunderstorm happening right now.
Rym: You probably noticed in the show that we got distracted by it Several times.
Rym: the Thunder was loud enough to rattle my windows and the lights flickered a few times.
Rym: So, uh, here's hoping that the power doesn't go out before I finish uploading this episode.
Rym: I guess I could get it together between laptops and old UPS's and things but I don't feel like I'd care that much now.
Rym: We just wait Though we've lived here a decade powers literally never gone out at any point.
Rym: So pretty confident.
Rym: But anyway, as we said stay tuned for a bunch of stuff.
Rym: We're working on and I'll leave you with.
Scott: You started off so much And I talk to your realtor.
Rym: and you're a kid and you wanna go wee but you ain't got drugs yet.
Rym: You hold on for your life.
Scott: Hold on to your little.
Rym: don't add any strike.
Rym: Don't add any strike.
Scott: Don't add any strike.
Rym: Go add some strike.
Rym: Go add in the lightning lightning in the rain.
Rym: Yo ive got my girl crossbox.