Rym: It's Wednesday, June 24th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're talking about online anime conventions and why that's really hard to do.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, we're still stuck inside obviously.
Rym: So a lot of the things like.
Rym: we can't just talk about how we're biking cuz we're not like biking to work every day.
Scott: I could talk about how I'm biking.
Scott: I just not going anywhere in one place without moving.
Rym: Oh, you gotta get a new trainer.
Scott: No, there's one in the in the the guy.
Scott: I'm in the building reopened.
Rym: Oh I think we might have already talked about this.
Scott: we did but something weird happened when I was biking without moving yesterday.
Scott: Oh So, you know how sometimes right, you know, like the muscle in your leg will be like doink and it's like You know a cramp or a charlie horse or who the hell knows that's moving on.
Scott: it hurts.
Scott: It starts moving on its own.
Rym: I know that feeling.
Scott: you got to stretch it get it back into where it belongs, right?
Scott: You know, who knows what the hell right?
Scott: You know, usually when that happens, it's like well, I got a. I got to wait a while Can't really do anything if it's a charlie horse.
Rym: I got sort of the specific technique to undo it.
Scott: Sometimes you look and you can even see like your leg going like blah blah blah or something.
Scott: Anyway, that hasn't happened in a long as time, but it happened yesterday.
Scott: I am biking in one place and suddenly my left calf goes like doink, right?
Scott: So I stopped paddling.
Rym: It's like you do.
Scott: My leg is attached to the thing right with the shoes, so I don't want to or I mess it up and Then somehow I managed to undo it very quickly.
Rym: No, maybe you've learned the technique.
Scott: I don't know it.
Scott: just undid very quickly, right?
Scott: So I'm like hmm and a cautious sleeve pedal again, right?
Scott: Like.
Scott: is it gonna re?
Scott: is it gonna re doink?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I know the fear of the re doing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm like, I don't you know.
Scott: And It did not re doink.
Scott: and in fact, it felt like like the leg had leveled up.
Scott: I was like what the fuck I was like Like.
Scott: it felt better than pretty that it did pre doing.
Scott: so I'm like a very brief doink that went away.
Scott: So he's got more powerful now suddenly leveled up this leg.
Rym: It's like burning.
Rym: will you fail it leg enough and your leg just gets stronger?
Scott: I've got.
Scott: I don't know what I think I just want to know what the medical explanation for that Cuz.
Scott: that's really strange.
Rym: Yep, so my only cuz I'm running a lot because of this Quarantine like.
Rym: that's a really good just thing I can do outside.
Rym: I can run where I don't really encounter people.
Rym: But I've been trying to replace my running shoes every two or three hundred miles because that's what my doctor said to do to prevent problems because I'd had some problems because I run so Much and the doctor
Scott: rather the Rym is found to do advanced technique rather than break his shit on purpose to excuse Consumerist material ways to buy new shit.
Scott: with his vest hordes of money.
Scott: He has now found a doctor to prescribe him to purchase new.
Rym: I went to a doctor new physical therapist a while ago Like you're ago two years ago at this point.
Rym: He's found a doctor who I got some.
Scott: Give you permission to spend more money and indulge your consumerist materialist way.
Rym: the doctor was literally I Solve you of your guilt.
Rym: how much do you run?
Rym: and I was like eh and then they were like How long you've been running in the shoes you own right now?
Rym: How long have you owned them?
Rym: you even know.
Rym: and I was like, I don't know like three years and she was like I will bet you that is the problem.
Rym: buy new shoes and I bet I'll never see you again.
Rym: and the PT was like Yeah, buy new shoes.
Rym: That is probably your problem.
Scott: They're in there in the pocket of big shoes.
Rym: So I did buy new shoes and it was like night and day and like I could even see my times.
Rym: I see they have put you in the.
Scott: I see they have taken you into their pocket of big shoe.
Rym: It was more that for the longest time.
Rym: My goal was I will wear shoes until they literally fall apart.
Scott: I have a shoe.
Scott: I'll wear it until it is so dirty or broken in some way that it is not no longer wearable.
Rym: So I plan to replace him like they said 200 miles.
Rym: I was pushing it to like 300 400 like fine Whatever like.
Rym: but I was only counting runs.
Rym: I did with Strava and because I messed up my synchronization when I looked at the stats I wasn't counting like treadmill runs all the other stuff I do that I track else in other ways.
Rym: So I thought I had some shoes that I'd run like 300 ish 400 ish miles in.
Rym: no I'd run over 800 miles in those shoes.
Scott: Well, did you get any problems?
Rym: Yep I was actually having some Sciatic problems on one side and also my feet were starting to give me some plantar fasciitis adjacent problems again.
Rym: So I got new shoes did some runs.
Rym: My times were way better with the new shoes.
Rym: They feel completely different.
Rym: I actually put him side by side and I tried to measure the inside the shoes I had been wearing.
Rym: the padding inside was half a centimeter thinner.
Rym: It had been compressed that much.
Scott: Well, it's got to be the shoes.
Rym: Well, we'll see.
Rym: it seems like all my problems have gone away once again Not only about new shoes.
Scott: all this means apparently you don't know the meaning of it's got to be the shoes.
Rym: Yeah In this case, it seems like it literally has to be the shoes but Google Google for it's got to be.
Rym: So it is anime day and one thing we want to talk about really briefly because it Ends on the 30th.
Rym: Today is the 24th.
Rym: There's still time.
Rym: Annecy the the animation festival went online this year.
Rym: I think we talked to me mentioned this a few times right?
Scott: if you don't know Annecy is basically, you know film festival wise Right, you know we're talking like, you know con like film festival, right?
Scott: Yeah for animation is pretty much the world's number one animation Specific film festival, right?
Scott: There are other ones for example in New York.
Scott: We always go to the New York International children's film festival.
Scott: that is a children's film festival.
Scott: It's not an animation film festival.
Scott: It just happens to include cement a lot of animation because it's a children's film festival, right?
Scott: Annecy is basically the number one premier world Animation film festival, right?
Scott: So if you submit your animation there and get it in and win that's a big fucking deal you get.
Scott: so when you put out Your DVD you can put some little some little.
Scott: uh, what are they called?
Scott: You know?
Scott: The little the the ferns with some words in between.
Rym: oh just get an award.
Scott: Yeah, you know, yeah, we buy a DVD and there's like all those little fern thingies Looks like the Caesars crown or whatever You know with some gold text in there that says winner Annecy 20, right?
Scott: So normally to go to Annecy which by the way is named after like most conventions in Europe like, you know Say Essen which takes place in Essen Annecy takes place in Annecy France.
Scott: So if you want to go to Annecy and see the animations in Annecy, you'd have to go to Annecy.
Rym: Yep, I don't plan to go to the city of Otakon anytime in the near future?
Scott: Yeah, no, but I'm saying is Annecy is not.
Scott: so, you know, it's like.
Scott: I'd probably like to go there But I don't see that on my horizon, right?
Scott: Well currently definitely not Yeah, so I didn't see it in my past either not even once that haven't been to France or Europe.
Scott: So Yeah So I've never been able to see the works of.
Scott: Anna said there were shown at Annecy with any amount of ease unless they Were shown somewhere else like you
Rym: get like a lot of times like goblin stuff Like you'll find YouTube channels where they post it like you could poke around but you definitely wouldn't get this full program by any stretch
Scott: Right.
Scott: So thanks to the physical Annecy being canceled they put it online and for 15 euro you can go to the Annecy online website and See all the films that would have.
Scott: you would have been able to see if you went to Annecy only From your house, which is great.
Rym: There's some good stuff in there.
Scott: The website's a little bit mad, but it works.
Scott: Yeah, they got subtitles.
Rym: I think it was like a limited access Netflix that has a whole bunch of stuff You're not gonna be able to see anywhere else.
Scott: The only problem is that there were some things that they were going to show at Annecy notably the Lupin the third CG movie that's coming and Because it's online they said well, you know, you're online the whole world can watch this 15 euro.
Scott: We can't really put the whole movie right.
Scott: if it was at Annecy physically in a theater They would have shown the whole movie.
Rym: but because it's online They're like, oh that is showing that the segment is often even at the physical film festivals.
Rym: That's the thing That's it.
Scott: But in this case they did yeah, they were gonna show the whole thing.
Scott: but instead Because it's online for only 15 euro Just showed some of the feature films most of the feature films.
Scott: they're not showing the whole movie They're only showing 15 minute.
Scott: Like you're getting the intro part of the movie, right?
Rym: The thing I can say about that Lupin film though is that I can't review it as a Lupin movie because you have to see The whole thing to know.
Rym: I've only seen the beginning but the animation looks a-plus like it looks great.
Scott: It looks like it looks like a Lupin movie.
Scott: It's that's I want to watch it.
Rym: Yep, and I get the impression if I had to guess based on the little bit I've seen it is a like Completely generic Lupin Reminiscent of like the era of Lupin that Scott and I have talked about a lot like those movies that were okay Not great not terrible not the like later 2000s Lupin's.
Scott: it appears to be a well based on the 15-minute segment.
Scott: We saw a extremely well-crafted But completely by the book Lupin movie, which is who doesn't want that?
Rym: Yeah, so maybe like around the level of a Fuma conspiracy in terms of like quality as a Lupin I don't know.
Scott: Fuma conspiracy.
Scott: It's something special going on.
Rym: Fuma conspiracy had.
Rym: there's there's generic Lupin There's generic Lupin with one twist and then there's bad Lupin.
Scott: Anyway, I've watched all of the official.
Scott: oh, there's also some work-in-progress Things.
Rym: oh my god, the wolf walkers one.
Rym: You can see.
Scott: there's a long segment about wolf walkers and a long segment about Inoue Which is Yuasa's next movie coming next year.
Rym: I didn't fit it watch the.
Rym: you know, you know one.
Rym: Yeah, but I will say is the wolf walkers one.
Rym: I was already at maximum.
Rym: Hype for wolf walkers.
Rym: But somehow after watching that especially when the animators talked about how they drew the town versus how they drew the forest I'm at a hundred and ten percent now, right?
Rym: I am more hyped for a movie that I'm already maximum hype for.
Scott: they're showing you.
Scott: It's basically those are works in progress.
Scott: They're basically somewhat sort of mini documentary behind-the-scenes interview things where they're showing you what they're working on and how they made it.
Scott: And then there's all the different short animations that are in the competition And they're split into different segments.
Scott: There's children's ones graduation ones, which I presume are student films.
Scott: There are these perspectives ones which I don't know what the deal is with those.
Scott: Maybe they're ones that have like something to say and watch those.
Rym: what I'd recommend is don't try to unless you're like an animator.
Rym: I wouldn't recommend going to the like buying this thing going in and just trying to watch literally everything in the order It's presented.
Rym: There's a lot.
Scott: I watched literally.
Scott: I watched literally everything in the order.
Scott: It's presented in the official Right, which is the like, you know the ones that are trying, you know I guess they're just shorts submitted for the official competition.
Scott: There are official selections of the whatever.
Scott: I don't know I don't know what determines what goes into my category.
Scott: But that was the biggest category of short animated films and I watched every single one.
Rym: But you've got until the 30th Tuesday next week.
Rym: So even though this has been going on for a while already 15 euros for basically almost a week's worth of access to this thing if you buy it today still worth it.
Scott: Think of it like a temporary Netflix with special stuff in it that will go away on the 30th with like, you know, so it's like.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: why not?
Scott: Yeah So this stuff isn't available anywhere else.
Rym: So in some other news This movie wasn't on a lot of people's radar for some reason, but it's just out on Netflix like as of last week I want to say June 18th.
Rym: It was released.
Rym: It's Junichi Sato's a whisker away.
Rym: the trailer looks good.
Rym: It's basically about a girl who well vaguely It's a trailer and the movie obviously has a lot of allegory and metaphor a girl who likes a boy and turns into a cat To be with him.
Scott: I think I heard that story, but I didn't hear the title or that it was a Netflix thing.
Rym: Yeah, the literal translation of the title is something like wanting to cry.
Rym: I pretend to be a cat but okay What are we always saying when it comes to it?
Scott: You want did you watch it?
Rym: Not yet?
Rym: Okay, but what I will say is that it's on Netflix like right now We always say if there's an anime movie that is not a sequel to an existing IP You should pretty much just watch it if you have access to it.
Rym: So I'm gonna say you should probably just watch this.
Rym: We're going to watch it at some point soon and do a review on it I'm sure.
Rym: But I didn't realize like I forgot Junichi Sato.
Rym: Uh So none of you will care except like one of you maybe that I guess he directed slayers premium Which is the last of the slayers.
Rym: like quote unquote movies Okay, but more importantly he's the mahout sky tie guy Okay, magic users Club.
Rym: So based on the trailer I think this movie is gonna be pretty good and I've seen pretty good reviews of it already.
Scott: Oh Sounds good.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: Alright, so since I've been trapped at home This giant wall of comics behind me right with most of which I've read in my life But some of which I have not had the time to read I've been able to get to spend time reading it because I'm not doing anything.
Scott: So I read all Twelve well twelve omnibus volumes of lone wolf and cub.
Scott: each one of those is like You know three to five Smaller volumes worth right?
Scott: Who knows how many but basically I read all of lone wolf and cub from those dark horse editions.
Scott: Oh, I have not read all of lone wolf and cub by even up right and seeing how that's rims probably unlikely to do So anytime in the near future Just getting geeked by it.
Scott: I mean, obviously it's legendary.
Scott: Do you really need someone to tell you that you should read it?
Scott: No, that's why I read it.
Rym: I guess I could bike over there with a backpack.
Scott: Good luck.
Scott: It'll take you a while this long.
Scott: So, what's the deal with lone wolf and cub?
Scott: obviously it's a samurai story, right?
Scott: you know nerds have seen the Mandalorian and It's a lot better than that.
Scott: Yeah, but there's a samurai in themes And he is the shogun's executioner, right?
Scott: But then the basically another group right in the another clan Wants, you know someone from their clan to be in that position.
Scott: So they do him dirty, right?
Scott: And he is a master of you know, the sword Lee arts.
Scott: So no one can really mess with him and His wife dies and he just had this kid and he's you know, the kid basically is Not old enough to talk real, right?
Scott: He's like, you know, basically zero but the kid decides to Go with the dead on their their journey through me fumado, which is the Buddhist hell.
Scott: rather than Be killed by his father mercifully He takes the kid with him on the journey throughout Japan and basically most of the chapters are Episodic, you know situations they get caught in right on their journey around Japan.
Scott: But all of these little you know episodes encountering different people and their troubles and whatnot Right are tied together by the larger plot of.
Scott: you know Lone wolf in club versus right that clan that did them dirty at the beginning, right?
Scott: And you know people who are who act in honorable samurai ways and those who don't right?
Scott: and such and such.
Scott: so it's Unlike other works of.
Scott: You know What's his name Oh Kazuo?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I was about to say Kazuo.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Is that what you're fumbling for?
Scott: Yeah that guy unlike other Kazuko IK works.
Scott: it does not get as crazy and The sex and violence like in a crying Freeman sort of way, but there's plenty of sex and there is no shortage.
Scott: It's just not as ridiculous At all times right?
Scott: It is only ridiculous seemingly like when it's appropriate for it to be so When when it you know the situation demands, right?
Scott: But yeah if you're wondering why you know all those other people Who are so inspired by lone wolf and cub right to to make samurai things and and?
Scott: Appropriative works in the West right.
Scott: you can find out pretty easily just by reading all of this.
Scott: it is well worth your time.
Rym: I was looking to see if we've ever actually reviewed it because I've read like the first volume.
Scott: Beyond that you know it does come to an end although towards the end It sort of devolves a little bit and like for briefly for a few chapters It goes sort of like away from lone wolf and cub to like these other sort of like.
Scott: it feels like time-killing Episodes showing you some other people mm-hmm, but then it actually comes together At the end and there's a big dramatic ending.
Scott: it was well Timed and nope at no point does it feel like it's dragging on.
Rym: That's a good sign.
Scott: You know towards the middle there is sort of like a dramatic confrontation And that dramatic confrontation does not finish things right.
Scott: so then they have to sort of Do it go all through a whole nother rigamarole before you can get to the final battle.
Scott: So it's sort of like fists of the North Star does the same thing right?
Scott: you see it a lot where it's like.
Scott: you know It's like it fights row in fists of the North Star like somewhere towards the middle of the story.
Scott: Right and they fight a whole bunch But not enough to finish things right and then they have to continue later And then it goes through a whole nother series of stuff, and then the final battle right.
Scott: so it's the same thing here.
Scott: And lone wolf income right the these fight the end boss You got you can't finish things you come back and fight the end boss again.
Rym: Yep, so apparently in July of last year What we were talking about a star is on my.
Rym: but in the middle of that we apparently Mentioned lone wolf and cub and repeatedly told people they need to read it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you it's like you know in terms of samurai stuff.
Scott: It's pretty much like You know it.
Scott: this Right it's like the best samurai comic.
Scott: There is you know if you like samurai movies?
Rym: but anyway things Of the day, so I don't know if any of you have ever heard of garum, but garum is our masala powder g-a-r-u-m.
Rym: it is a Basically a common table condiment from the era of ancient Rome like it was one of the most pot like it was the ketchup of Rome.
Scott: basically I guess yeah, I guess they didn't have Heinz 57 varieties in Rome.
Rym: Yeah, well I mean think of this.
Rym: did they have tomatoes?
Rym: Some of you might be surprised by the answer if you didn't learn anything about history, but I digress.
Rym: so garum is Not common anymore.
Rym: those things that are very similar to it are common common.
Rym: It's basically like a fish sauce like a fermented fish sauce.
Rym: There's a lot of fermented sauce on it.
Rym: Yeah But garum is a particular method of making fish sauce that was used in Rome.
Rym: that makes a particularly salty watery form of this and You can buy.
Rym: there's a bunch of people who sell garum But supposedly it's not quite the same as what people would have eaten in Rome.
Scott: So this is try cuz you don't want to eat something that's the same of what they eat in Rome.
Scott: Yeah, just what you just want the the good essence of it right what they probably had in Rome is probably like you.
Rym: Yep, well, it's like old IPAs like yeah You can drink in an IPA beer that is authentic to what beer tasted like made in that way and transported in that way in That era would not recommend it Unless you're a historian.
Rym: So in this case this dude who seems to know a lot about like food history And like his whole channel seems to be about this.
Rym: Basically, just like explains the whole deal with garum make some and then tries it.
Rym: He sips a little bit and tries to cook with it.
Rym: Uh I don't know if I want to try garum per se.
Rym: I get the impression that it tastes like Drinking like.
Rym: it tastes like roe like just fish roe Any.
Scott: I got the impression from the video that it's because I saw the video also that it tastes like fishy salt water like The way the ocean smells when you're driving your car to the beach and it's a really kind of low tide kind of stank.
Scott: Yeah, right you get that strong Ocean smell that you get right not from like the beautiful oceans where it's clear water But from like, you know, the New Jersey Ocean, right?
Scott: Yep, and I imagine it smells like drinking that like a face full of it.
Rym: Yep, but if anything else this video is worth watching because you actually get a lot of history about like how Condiments were used in ancient Rome and it's actually pretty fascinating.
Scott: I mean, it makes a lot of sense, right?
Scott: Salt makes things taste good.
Scott: So I don't imagine they had like, you know, diamond crystal table salt in Rome, right?
Scott: So splashing some salty fishy water on your food probably made it taste really.
Rym: Places that evolved that developed salt mining had salt a lot earlier.
Rym: other places like salt was still very common, but the salt mining or Salination old salt collection was I don't know Extremely labor-intensive and kind of just involved collecting seawater and letting it dry out.
Rym: Yep So what do you got?
Scott: Oh Thing of the day.
Scott: Yeah, so way back in the day.
Scott: Let me click on this.
Scott: I get the exact year here 1986 I think Right in 1986.
Scott: There was an article in New type magazine.
Rym: Oh your grand prophecy of anime.
Rym: 86, right?
Scott: Yes, and they asked a bunch of different.
Scott: Consider it right.
Scott: they asked 21 anime industry leaders including Miyazaki Isao Takahata Mamoru.
Scott: Oh, she Right all these like big-time anime people right from the day and they asked him their feelings on.
Scott: You know the anime industry like what was going on in 1986 and they published it in new type magazine.
Scott: They put the person's picture with a bunch of text next to it.
Scott: Just you know, hey How do you feel about the anime industry these days?
Scott: everyone was really honest and open and let loose their gripes or positive feelings and Seven years ago the old type new type person At least if this article was posted Recent when was?
Scott: that was the date when they posted this?
Scott: regardless some years ago, right?
Scott: Oh, yeah It's only posted a week ago.
Rym: Well, some of these are pretty brutal.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the person who runs if you don't know Takahata seems pissed in particular.
Scott: Yeah, there's an.
Scott: there's a. there's a tumblr called old type new type where this person publishes a scans from old new type magazines.
Scott: But they because this one is so interesting they paid someone to translate the whole article some years ago and the translation is here underneath the images of the article and you can see exactly how the top people in the anime industry felt about the anime industry in 86 and You can now apply your knowledge of things that have happened in the past 24 34 years 34 years.
Rym: Just talk on.
Rym: I think now it is the thing a lot of people working in anime forgotten is the excitement They felt watching adventure movies when they were kids.
Rym: Mm-hmm He goes this I'm gonna read this whole thing.
Rym: This is fascinating.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I have the good things of the day.
Scott: Yeah, look what mom ro she wrote.
Rym: We'll see what mama ro she wrote.
Rym: I'm gonna read all of these.
Rym: Yeah, you should in the moment stuck at home working on gig night stuff.
Rym: Maybe we'll start live streaming the show again soon.
Rym: Maybe the video that we're recording right now, but not live streaming will appear on YouTube.
Rym: Only people on YouTube will know if we successfully do that.
Rym: But for the time being really just make sure you follow us both on Twitter.
Rym: Make sure you subscribe to both our YouTube channels.
Rym: as we start to put together Stuff that we're working on and stuff that we're doing new projects are gonna start sneaking out bit by bit.
Rym: Also, I recommend you check out PAX online because there is an extremely high probability We will be performing at least one panel during PAX online.
Rym: If not multiple Mm-hmm, and I don't know what else we really want to cover in this.
Rym: join the discord.
Rym: Check out our forum forums.
Rym: getting a little more activity right now because people are stuck inside Black lives matter.
Rym: I highly recommend you donate to one of these charities that we're gonna link to Mmm anything else.
Rym: we're forgetting something That about it.
Scott: There's not much going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So one thing that's particularly not going on.
Rym: I don't know how long we'll actually talk about this.
Rym: You know, we used to go to a lot of anime cons like we got no other topic.
Scott: That's why we're doing.
Rym: I was looking at old GeekNights Like there is an era where we would do like three Separate Wednesday shows over the course of three weeks.
Rym: because remember we used to go four nights a week.
Rym: that were literally called Otakon preview part 1 Otakon preview part 2 Otakon preview part 3. then we go to Otakon and then we had Otakon the review and then we had Otakon the review part 2.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it wasn't three previews.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it was like one preview.
Rym: I'll find the exact one.
Rym: I looked at.
Scott: you're exaggerating a little bit.
Scott: I think it's like.
Scott: I think it's like Otakon preview and then like Otakon part 1 Otakon part 2.
Rym: Let's see it will.
Rym: so we did.
Rym: Otakon 2006 was the one we did the most.
Rym: we did Otakon preview Otakon 2006 part 1 Otakon 2006 part 2 and live at Otakon 2006 where we recorded something.
Scott: Yeah, so there weren't three previews that you just exaggerated right anyway.
Scott: But yeah, we used to do.
Scott: we used to break up, you know episodes on conventions and do a whole bunch of stuff, right?
Rym: We did two different previews for a PAX once but they were on two different things.
Rym: That was back in 2009 I think anyway We used to go to a lot of anime cons and we kept going to anime cons until a while ago when anime Boston was Kind of the last one we did and then we dropped out of that for reasons We've talked about don't really go to a lot of anime cons anymore.
Rym: But anime cons were still trucking along like Otakon despite moving losing it make on stellar trucking along.
Rym: Yeah, like anime Boston despite all its problems is still one of the best run anime cons.
Rym: It's huge anime NYC.
Rym: every year We want to go but it usually overlaps with something else.
Rym: We're already committed to and we just don't go This year.
Rym: it won't happen, obviously but Basically yawning on Sleepy sleepy time sleepy, baby.
Scott: I guess I'd need a nap after this.
Rym: Anyway, so Video game cons and generic cons like kinetic ons doing an online thing.
Rym: Bunch of gaming cons to do an online things packs is doing an official like big-money packs online.
Rym: But you're not seeing as many Online anime cons.
Scott: And why do that are happening?
Rym: Not that big and I'm not gonna name names in any of these cons, but a few that have happened have not gone.
Rym: Well, right.
Scott: Well, here's the thing.
Scott: So what does an anime con have right?
Scott: It has a a Dealers room.
Scott: Yeah, so for a dealers room to go online All those stores you see at a dealers room are typically have online stores 24 365 days a year.
Rym: Anyway, yep, like going to an anime con is mostly for them to offload merch that isn't moving otherwise to an impulse buying audience.
Scott: Alright, so it's like if you just want to shop for anime shit, you could do that online even pre pandemic, you know.
Scott: So there's.
Scott: no you can't really replicate the dealers room online other than What make a web page that lists what who would have been the dealers and so you can click through and go to their stores In case you didn't know.
Scott: it's like it's not something you buy a ticket for.
Rym: But also a lot of the people are buying stuff at anime con dealers room.
Rym: in particular they're they're buying swords, which Okay, I feel like I saw it online bro.
Rym: Exactly I feel like that is a like the the epitome of an impulse buy and I feel like a lot of those Sword purchases happen because the parents is not there at that exact moment, but the kid was given money to buy shit at the con.
Rym: But anyway, everything else at the dealers room Usually you can buy online cheaper anyway.
Rym: like sometimes usually It's very rare that there are exclusive things that an anime con dealers room that you could not have purchased online.
Rym: You might just not have thought to purchase it online unless you were in the context of an anime con walk by a booth.
Rym: It's awesome.
Scott: It fits to the North Star book and I wouldn't think to buy a sword But suddenly there's a sword store in front of me.
Rym: Yep I mean it takes me effort even in it when I would go to anime cons to not buy things that I see That.
Scott: so the biggest room at the anime con can't really isn't really point.
Scott: There's no point in having it online, right?
Scott: Okay, so the second biggest room is the artist alley.
Scott: So the artist alley you also can buy all that stuff online.
Scott: Well, all those artists have web pages.
Rym: This is where it gets tricky.
Rym: artist bodies drive moves to.
Rym: their sales are impulse buys Especially of things that are not available online often because of copyright issues, right?
Scott: So you're you're.
Scott: you could go to any of those people in artist alley.
Scott: They all have their own website so they sell stuff, right?
Scott: You can buy their merch whenever you want.
Scott: They're happy to sell it to you.
Scott: In fact, you know, they all have online shops, right?
Scott: So what do you go artist alley for?
Scott: like Rym said all their fan arts and things.
Scott: They're probably not selling them online because they can't because the online store will say hey You can't sell your drawing of Mickey Mouse.
Scott: That's Disney.
Rym: a lot of fan art and an artist alleys just gets under the line just because no one cares enough to go deal with In person at the event and even in the event that happens sometimes online.
Rym: you're just screwed.
Scott: so the the advantage of the artist alley is there are things for sale there that you can't buy online and Putting your anime con online doesn't fix that.
Rym: Yep And I think the other advantage is literally just the impulse buys again Which if there's if something is just available as a store online You're not gonna get nearly as much of that.
Rym: Oh That's a cool thing.
Rym: immediately purchase it when I saw it because if you didn't go seek it out and find it online Previously you're not gonna suddenly do it now.
Rym: I saw a lot of cons tried to do a thing where they did like a limited time virtual artist alley online where like Artists put up all their stuff and they all agree that it'll be exclusive to this online event Like this stuff lonely bees for sale for this time to try to get a lot of eyes on them all at the same time To drive that impulse by.
Rym: I don't have any data But I don't think a huge amount of sales happen because of that except for the very first Handful of anime cons that did something like that.
Scott: I don't think that sustains right because without the physicals.
Scott: because what a convention does to make money right or to make at least customers if it's not a for-profit convention right is?
Scott: it handles the Logistics of the the space the time.
Scott: You know the.
Scott: you know the the water and the panel rooms the technology right the facilities.
Scott: That is the work that a convention does.
Scott: all the content at the convention is just.
Scott: you know content at the convention that they've brought Together right.
Scott: so when you're online You're not doing any of this facilities work right.
Scott: that work is no longer necessary.
Scott: There's just internet work.
Scott: Which is a lot less work.
Scott: So all the convention has to offer is its brand and marketing power.
Scott: But the thing is conventions don't have internet brand and marketing power especially not anime ones because like you know They're the online followings of conventions are like Super small.
Scott: you show up at a convention and these most of the people there never went to the conventions website You know didn't even know.
Scott: they like they do follow the convention on Twitter deck like more than a decade of experience.
Scott: They're not in the conventions forum right there nothing.
Scott: all they did is figure out okay the conventions happening They bought a ticket, and they never interact with the convention in any way whatsoever online at all.
Scott: right They just buy a ticket and show up, and that's all the old the extent of the interaction They have with the convention as an organization.
Rym: Yeah But the showing up is the part that they're paying for.
Rym: because what an anime counter really does at least in America Like its primary purpose is all these people are into anime and interact with each other online Want to for a weekend be unsupervised and physically in the same place to get up to shenanigans.
Rym: That is the primary draw of anime cons and has been the next big.
Scott: the next biggest thing the anime cons have are like main events which are like cosplay contests yeah, or You know anime chess kind of thing.
Scott: All that's main event stuff.
Rym: right those things like one Those are already streamed online and almost no one watches them.
Rym: the audience at the con is almost always bigger than the streaming audience Because those events are not usually Good enough.
Rym: or even if the content is good enough the quality of the filming and production values is not good enough to convey that Feeling to the people who are watching online.
Rym: So it's an inferior experience to the point that people don't bother and people want to participate in it.
Rym: They want to yell and scream they want to get called up.
Scott: also You can't participate in it in your if you're cosplaying at your house.
Scott: Yep, you need it's cosplay as people coming together for those things, right?
Scott: It's like if people can cosplay at their house alone, but they could do that.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yep I've seen cons tried to do the same thing.
Rym: like they're Sally They try to put together like a hashtag or a costume contest.
Scott: like everyone submit a video everyone's like sir doesn't work because what the cosplay thing conventions is.
Scott: the Cosplayers get lots of attention from people that they can see and you're not just standing there in front of a camera They do it that on twitch every day.
Rym: Yeah most cosplayers or pros don't actually like they're not really there to be in the contest.
Rym: so much as they're there to show off their Cut their costume.
Rym: you're getting out with people in there.
Scott: Can you're getting several photographers who are showing up with their own volition to come around and photograph several cosplay people?
Scott: It's like well if you're a photographer, it's like well the photography has already been done.
Scott: You're already looking what a camera sees right because it's online.
Scott: Yep You're looking at the camera of that the web the cosplayer has.
Scott: right.
Rym: you're not going to the house yeah, so the whole photography aspect is just completely out and I feel like the cosplay community seems to be doing online costume contests kind Of on its own now without necessarily needing to be tied to any particular convention.
Scott: Right the convention only provides facilities right if there's no facilities involved.
Scott: They don't need anime Boston or Otakon All right.
Rym: What about the panels like the gaming cons the generic cons?
Rym: That's the thing these cons are doing online.
Rym: They live stream their panels.
Rym: people can watch them online ask questions.
Rym: I'm gonna be real with you.
Rym: This is like.
Rym: this is a problem.
Rym: That is specific to anime cons.
Rym: 90% of anime con panels could never be put online Right.
Scott: most anime con panels right at least the ones that people actually like going to and are well attended Right are usually involved showing clips from anime and talking interchangeably right and Displaying copyrighted materials on screen.
Rym: my most popular panel at anime cons ever anime openers around the world It's I talk for two minutes.
Rym: I show a clip that's gonna get a copyright strike.
Rym: I talk for two minutes.
Rym: I show a clip that's gonna get a copyright strike right.
Scott: so you could Stream such a panel and get away with it right.
Scott: so for example.
Scott: I see a lot of DJs on Twitch are Streaming DJ sets, and then they don't put they make sure there's no VOD.
Scott: Yep, is it's gonna get taken down anyway, so you could put up a panel live stream it With all sorts of copyrighted shit get away with it and be kind of fine But it's still not the best.
Rym: well There's a bunch of problems there when you lose that archive to a lot of panels that are not subject to copyright and don't have these problems from cons are already streamed and again Not a huge audience for that usually because of low production values.
Rym: A Bigger problem.
Rym: I think is that almost all anime panels that are not clip shows Go to questions from the audience right away And I have never seen a low-budget convention pull that off.
Rym: You don't want to take questions.
Scott: questions from the audience are bad enough questions from the internet audience.
Scott: You need some sort of thing there right?
Scott: either You're not gonna get any questions, or you're gonna get too many bad questions.
Scott: It's not easy to do yep.
Rym: even worse most of those panels are a bunch of panelists who don't even know each other that way.
Rym: Well, so if you want to put that panel online You've got four people living in four different states having to stream themselves simultaneously somewhere.
Scott: Put together four voice actors.
Scott: you somehow got them all to stream together to it in like a. you know a zoom Right you got you know five voice actors in a zoom, and then you want to take questions from the audience like man.
Scott: Yeah, it's gonna be not the greatest straight But here's the really real someone gonna pay money for that like if a pack enough that you can pay the voice actors.
Rym: if a pax has a Panel online let's say the people who tend to present at those kinds of conventions Have the technology or the professional resources to do it in a professional way.
Rym: I don't think the vast majority.
Scott: sometimes.
Rym: sometimes I've got some anecdotes that I cannot share in public.
Rym: But let's just say an extremely large multinational company was incapable of streaming to YouTube.
Rym: Like could not do it despite having the hardware the software and having hired people to do it for them.
Rym: Anyway, but ah when I go to anime cons The panelists tend to struggle with things like making their laptop display their slides In a way that does not happen nearly as often at most other cons.
Rym: Mm-hmm I am not confident those people could stream their panel to an RTMP destination To then be put in an anime convention circuit.
Scott: They could record their panel and the convention could then stream it.
Rym: They could.
Scott: then then you're losing your question-answer aspect.
Scott: It means the panel is going to be very short.
Rym: Yep Cuz that's the problem.
Rym: anime cons in particular the audience interaction is such a big part of those panels.
Scott: Very few of the panels at an anime convention will fill up the entire time slot with Presentation.
Rym: very few even good ones won't fill it up yep and the good ones that will are the ones that'll get hit by copyright strikes and Have problems and be very difficult to move into an online format.
Rym: And also there's this problem of even those panels when they're shown in the limited audience inside of a convention center where there's no like real cameras around a Lot of things they might say or copyright issues get glossed over because it wasn't broadcast anywhere.
Rym: It's one thing if some DJ is like doing a stream and then deletes the VOD But if a convention brand officially streams someone's panel that has a bunch of copyright problems, even if the VOD disappears That could still open them up to some liability that I don't think they're ready for.
Rym: They also know they also often there's an ASCAP license that applies to in venue entertainment.
Rym: That does not apply to streaming that shit online.
Rym: Oh You yawned it again.
Rym: We lost Scott to us.
Scott: Yeah, I was sneezing that time.
Scott: Oh, it was a sneeze.
Scott: Ooh, I know right.
Scott: So yeah, another thing you go to anime con for right is is gaming there.
Scott: There's always like a little gaming room.
Scott: Yeah That it's like.
Scott: it's like okay, whatever.
Rym: gaming cons are like desperately trying to figure out how to make Social gaming happen and gaming cons are uniquely equipped to do that.
Rym: I don't think you can get a critical mass appeal like who would want to Go to the online anime con to play board games with the ten other people who are usually in that room playing board games When they could just play a board game online without the convention.
Scott: Now maybe maybe an anime con, you know, they have concerts a make-ons.
Scott: Yeah, they'll put their concert online, right?
Scott: But it's like wait a minute.
Scott: So your anime con would have paid for This musician to come.
Scott: and again, you're providing facilities, right?
Scott: You set up a stage.
Scott: Yeah, it's lights and all the instruments you pay for audio Singing and sure.
Rym: in.
Scott: so now audience this musician that you're hiring.
Scott: They just say a band.
Scott: they're at home There's no stage.
Scott: Okay, you got no facilities.
Scott: So what are they gonna do?
Scott: They're gonna.
Scott: they're gonna just play in there in their living room And stream it and someone's gonna pay money for that.
Scott: when you could go on YouTube and See, they're just concert videos on YouTube that are legal.
Scott: actually Yeah, they're gonna be.
Scott: probably you could just watch like, you know, Regan, you know perfume live at Tokyo Dome.
Scott: So why would I watch if I'm a weave?
Scott: Why would I watch?
Rym: and even whatever the enemy God especially anime cons if it's Japanese acts that are performing?
Rym: You know how most anime cons when it's that kind of act they have very strict no camera policies.
Rym: There's a reason for that.
Rym: There is no way in hell.
Rym: Most of those bands would let the convention stream that concert.
Scott: No, especially not Japanese one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the final thing you do at a con All right is you hang out in the hallway with other people, right?
Scott: Okay, so the so the con makes a chat room.
Scott: Right, and here's the problem with the chat room and I think this is illustrate, you know Just the problem of real life versus, you know internet group socialization with strangers, right?
Scott: Is you know, let's say me and Ray Moran and anime con.
Scott: we're standing in the hallway chatting and we meet up.
Scott: We meet a listener.
Scott: We're chatting with the listener and all the wildest people around us also chatting, right?
Scott: But our human brains don't necessarily hear what the other people are saying right because they're around us.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: And let's say banana maraca comes down the hallway.
Rym: my boy I saw Right before this whole COVID thing.
Rym: He was last time.
Scott: I saw him at was it paxies a couple years ago?
Rym: He comes by and says hi every year cuz I'm always working the front of maine theater.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: I didn't see him at paxies this year.
Rym: Oh, he was there.
Rym: He was there.
Scott: Okay, I'm sure he was.
Scott: See what banana comes down the hallway.
Scott: so now I'm in this unique anime con experience of chatting with Rym and the listener in a little conversation and Banana maraca is adding to the atmosphere of this conversation.
Rym: Yeah You know creating a great nerd moment there or they and then like a second later Some cosplayer who is now naked and about to be kicked out is running down the hall screaming.
Rym: that also adds to the ambiance.
Scott: Sure, it does.
Scott: But now let's take that same scenario and let's put it into it to a text chat room.
Scott: Right in this text chat room.
Scott: I'm trying to talk to Rym and the listener.
Scott: But meanwhile, there's this maraca sound that just won't go away Alright.
Scott: and in the in the text chat these big banana emojis keep popping up and I'm trying to have to keep scrolling up to read what the listener just said because it's getting pushed up The screen by all these bananas and maracas.
Rym: think about any twitch stream that's even remotely popular.
Rym: You can't read anything anyone has typed at any points.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like that same behavior Right, that is like an antisocial behavior in real life.
Scott: Right could actually be acceptable under the right circumstances, right?
Scott: You know banana maraca guy he doesn't like get in your face with the maracas, right?
Scott: He doesn't like, you know, I've never seen him like, you know, you know hit anyone with a maraca.
Scott: He's always a chill dude and all these guys never seen him like amplify the volume of his maracas ears, right?
Scott: He just walks down the hallway shaking his maraca.
Scott: Right, you know but in a chat room shaking a maraca is the equivalent.
Scott: It is like there's no way to not be in someone's face.
Scott: You either shake it or you don't.
Scott: right?
Scott: it's you either post text and move the screen upwards or you don't or Everyone like no way to have like a little maraca on the side of the screen going like shaky shaky shake or what might end Up happening.
Rym: You have a big social space.
Rym: That's too big, but people they've either break it down You shard it off into like.
Rym: here's the area.
Rym: if you want to talk about this aspect of anime.
Rym: That's like you make like 20 channels to try to spread the load out to reduce that Volume and to get people at least vaguely talking about the same thing.
Rym: the more you shard it off the more you lose The whole point of people at anime cons of interacting with a variety of people and maybe having their conversation altered by that Context.
Rym: and if you get too specific, how is that different from all the discords that are already out there today?
Rym: Like how is it different the anime Boston discord versus the anime discord if there's no actual physical anime Boston to react to?
Scott: So too long didn't listen, right?
Scott: All the things that convention provides are literally just physical presence.
Scott: so trying to take a convention online is basically like okay, so Nothing, well Everything you provide.
Rym: I put it this way.
Rym: There is a struggle for all cons to do something online.
Rym: That is meaningful.
Rym: however, anime cons have Far fewer options that are feasible compared to other kinds of cons though other kinds of cons do have a lot of problems like packs.
Rym: Online is gonna be really hard to pull off But it is a thousand times easier to pull off than an anime online Right.
Scott: All you can really do I think as a convention online is a. if your brand is strong enough You can provide marketing push for people with weaker brands because that's one thing a convention does.
Scott: they say it's like, you know packs you go to packs and when you're at packs you see something that is not that you didn't know about right because they're They're paying to be at packs and ride on the bigger brand.
Scott: right.
Scott: you're getting promoted by something big just like if you know an Actual popular podcast that people listen to mentioned GeekNights, right?
Scott: It would be the same kind of big brand says something about little brand, right?
Scott: So if your convention actually has a brand you could you sell your marketing power to others, right?
Scott: But other than that, it's like alright, you know You don't have a community.
Scott: What do you?
Scott: what do you sell it?
Rym: Yep, and Also some of these other cons.
Rym: they have a lot of avenues that don't apply to anime cons.
Rym: like an anime con is not gonna be successful.
Rym: trying to run a Big like video game tournament as part of the anime con online because all the anime all the gaming cons They're literally like running video game tournaments online.
Scott: Like that's the main also the video game people just play in the same tournaments.
Scott: They always did right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like those people who are.
Scott: it's like, okay you go to An account a con that has a Street Fighter tournament, right?
Scott: All right It's like well the people were in that tournament or a Street Fighter people who happen to live nearby and they went for a tournament.
Scott: But those people were playing Street Fighter tournaments all the time Everywhere.
Scott: So if your con isn't providing that physical meetup space for them to have a physical Street Fighter tournament Then that day that you're that weekend that your convention would have been.
Scott: they're just gonna play in whatever Street Fighter They would have played on any other weekend.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The other thing that's happening This is sort of a meta to end it.
Rym: Most of the online cons that are big and backed by real money and are pretty serious They're.
Rym: they're gonna be free like there's no badge to buy because the goal is to keep the brand of the convention alive and to sort of like Keep everyone together until the convention can start up again, but anime cons in particular are mostly nonprofits.
Rym: I Don't think they can afford to pay for the things necessary to run an online con without charging money.
Rym: But I don't think there are many people on earth willing to pay for an online Convention of any kind unless they're very narrowly target experiences like NSE.
Scott: Yeah to pay that's basically all you can do is you can get exclusive content from somewhere, right?
Scott: it has to be content.
Scott: you can actually get yeah and get the rights to to do legally and Then charge money for that exclusive content and have it be content that people actually want and that's not easy to do.
Rym: Yep So I think you're gonna see a lot of online gaming cons over the next year You're gonna see a moderate number of online like generic nerd conventions.
Rym: Don't think you're see gonna see a lot of successful online Anime conventions specifically if anisee couldn't get a full Lupin movie to be screened.
Rym: Yeah, what chance do you have?
Scott: It's like Otakon can get full anime movies to be screened at Otakon.
Scott: Can they get it to be done online?
Scott: it like pay Otakon ten bucks and you'll get to see a Lupin movie, right?
Scott: No, they can't do it.
Scott: There's no way they can get them to convince them to do that.
Scott: Fantasy can't yeah.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce.
Rym: How do you make a marty ingredient just like a dude got your option?
Rym: Graham Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: She gave me a kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Rym: Clinton Walton J Bantz Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff sailor Vista the thirst for hydride again and dread lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Shervin about hole and a whole bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Like I said stay tuned for some new content.
Rym: where we've set up we're gonna restart the stream soon.
Rym: partly We stopped like I said because we didn't want to distract from the momentum of the protests.
Rym: But also we've been tweaking the pipeline to reduce some of these sync problems.
Rym: You might have seen in the streams We were doing previously.
Rym: So we expect the streams to resume sometime next week.
Rym: So stay tuned on that.
Rym: I Continued pre-production on a new ten episode.
Rym: I know I said that a while ago We got delayed by kovin some other things but that pre-production.
Rym: I actually began it and this weekend I intend to start actually Doing the beginning of production for a new ten episode.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: I'm not gonna post it anywhere I only said it here.
Rym: It's only people who listen to this moment heard that but I will post a work in progress of some kind this weekend on That project.
Rym: I know many of you been waiting for it.
Rym: But for now, I leave you with something that I actually listen to Almost every night when I was a very young child and You can listen to it all if you want as well because it's free on YouTube and a number of other places.
Rym: Who knows what evil lurks in the hearts of men.
Rym: Local presents the shadow a man of mystery who strikes terror in the very souls of sharpsters lawbreakers and criminals.
Rym: All signs point to a severe winter.
Rym: be prepared if you want to be sure of even the bendable helpful heat in any kind of weather.
Rym: incest on blue coal America's finest anthracite mined from the fields of northern, Pennsylvania But coal that is colored a harmless blow at the mines.
Rym: for your protection.
Rym: All Gordon listen I Can't see anybody who's that I am the shadow.
Rym: Stop we haven't much time.
Rym: We must hurry.
Rym: Gordon.
Rym: You're in the death house Charged with murder.
Rym: Yes, I'm innocent.
Rym: I'm innocent But nobody knows it.
Rym: take courage Gordon the shadow knows.