Rym: It's Monday, October 12th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are talking about bricking things.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, we went upstate this weekend to do a long hike in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: Like that's something I feel like I can get away.
Scott: It seems like I say that seems like a safe place.
Scott: Yeah, middle of nowhere.
Scott: There's no people you can't get sick right.
Rym: coronavirus doesn't grow on trees Yep, and and even then if it did somehow I'm not out there like licking trees Like I'm just walking through the woods long distance, but you know, the trees are Having sex with your face though.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but that's a problem I actually ran into.
Rym: my allergies have been weirdly worse this fall than they've ever been and I don't know why.
Rym: Like I've never had fall allergies before but I have them pretty bad this summer for some reason anyway.
Rym: So we're up by ourselves on a very long difficult trail.
Rym: like we figured the more difficult the trail is the fewer people we'd encounter which was correct and We're like 15 miles into this hike.
Rym: We're on our way back on this long trail from nowhere and we see two people coming up ahead.
Rym: So we pull our masks up and then pull their masks up but then they like try to flag us down to like stop us and we're like, oh and Then I realize the trouble.
Rym: one of them is holding a phone.
Rym: I can clearly see that they have Google Maps up and Google.
Scott: no, there is somewhere with service.
Scott: That's good, but Have Trails in it like not usually.
Scott: no unless you ask for like biking directions and the trail is bikable It won't give you walking trail direction like it might be like.
Scott: hey There's a trail here like some trail.
Rym: some very very popular big trails do show up if you zoom far enough in on Google But most don't.
Scott: so also some people.
Scott: you can if you take photos and submit them They'll show up on the on the map.
Scott: It's like you can click and see the photos people have taken from particular spots But it doesn't give you like a map you have to.
Rym: so basically they ask us like hey Did you take the loop?
Rym: and we're like loop?
Rym: There's no loop trail.
Rym: We just hiked like 15 miles.
Rym: we've been hiking literally for like seven hours and They're like.
Rym: and then like the one girl like looks really surprised and like her handshakes a little and the older woman is like I told you.
Rym: So we start talking to them and eventually like she holds your phone out and she shows it to us and They're trying to get back to their car.
Rym: They've been hiking for hours, and they thought they were doing a trail loop And they're like if we follow the blue trail.
Rym: It's a loop right and we're like no Who told you that?
Rym: do you have a trail map?
Rym: They didn't have a trail map.
Rym: They had nothing and I see their Google.
Rym: They have a pin where their car is.
Rym: it is far away from where we are and Google is just a green square like there's Nothing that zoomed in and they're not even looking at the topographical map.
Rym: They're looking at like the driving map.
Rym: They clearly have no business being out in the woods.
Rym: nevertheless not a trail like this.
Rym: So The more questions they ask the more concern we are that how many how many miles are they from their car?
Scott: this they can Just walk back right you know because they had been hiking so one.
Rym: it is like 40 minutes to sundown - we are easily hiking like three or four times faster than them.
Rym: They are not fast hikers.
Rym: They said they've been hiking for several hours, but the direction they came from Does not have several hours verse worth of hiking Unless where they came from is not where they think they're headed or they did something really fucked up.
Scott: We could just tutor only two directions to go.
Rym: no.
Rym: No.
Rym: This is a complex trail system.
Rym: There are lots of branching paths in this trail system, but how many parking lots could there be?
Rym: there aren't really parking lots.
Rym: There's trailheads and okay where they described they had come from there is no possible way that where we were headed Which was the only trailhead in that direction was where they could have come from.
Rym: so wherever their car was There is no way they could get back to that car before dark.
Scott: and well all they had to do is Get to the modern escape right to a road.
Rym: call an uber.
Scott: Yes exactly that's them.
Scott: They kept trying to ask for like help and at this point as much as uber is the worst thing ever and I've never used Them and hopefully never will.
Scott: if you it they do have the advantage over Taxis or old-school car services in the you know because in the old days Before the uber types if you tried to call a car service on the phone That would be like hey send a limo to take me to the airport.
Scott: You couldn't get someone to show up in the in a specific random spot to get you like immediately.
Scott: that wouldn't happen Right, but now it's like yeah Actually that is I think the one thing.
Scott: the one actually new service that those piece of shit gig economy Taxis provide is yes Those are in some any.
Scott: no matter if you're on a road somewhere if it's a road that a car can go on You could push buttons on your phone if you have phone service and a car will come quick enough.
Rym: Well, they give it this way.
Rym: those services are fine except for the fact that they're exploitative gig economy if they cost.
Scott: I mean, that's also.
Scott: that's also true, right?
Rym: So basically, I We give them our trail map because even though we I was using it to navigate like the rest of the way back to our Car I figured you're gonna get back.
Rym: Yeah, we're capable hikers We we know how to do this, but I think you're gonna make it back where you came from.
Rym: but when we handed to them it was clear that they didn't understand it and couldn't really read it and At that point we just bailed because we wanted to get to our car before dark.
Rym: So we wish them luck and I basically told them look follow this trail You're on until you see a green trail.
Rym: turn right and follow that because I knew that if they did that It would be really hard for them to miss that green trail and it will take them to a road.
Rym: There is no parking on that road Like there's no trailhead there, but there is an actual road with a real number on it.
Rym: So at least a passing car they could flag down in the dark or an uber could find them because I was confident there was No way they could get back to their own car on foot.
Scott: Isn't there a park person that you could call?
Scott: Well, they had no way to in a park because they had a phone that they were using Google Maps on.
Scott: They don't know who to call New York State New York State Park something.
Rym: They could call 911 I guess but it was Google.
Scott: it.
Rym: you have a phone Yeah, and they didn't think to so.
Rym: literally right before we encountered these people I was basically just bitching on the trail to Emily about like Like people just go out into these woods like not knowing what to do and that like almost all rescues in the woods are people Who just like walk out in tennis shoes with Google Maps and don't know anything Like never read a trail map in their life Don't know what trail markers look like have no business being out here.
Rym: And then we immediately encounter two people who are clearly in this situation.
Rym: So we get to the end.
Rym: we get to our car.
Rym: There's no other cars because there's like not many places to park except right.
Scott: So their car wasn't there.
Rym: there was one other car in that area.
Rym: if that was their car I Cannot imagine how they got to where they were from that place.
Rym: It was not a two-hour hike.
Rym: I think they just gotten super lost.
Scott: So it wasn't their car.
Rym: Yep, if it wasn't their car someone else was out in the woods and the Sun was about to go down.
Rym: I do worry that a lot of people are hiking because it is the one of the few.
Scott: Well, I mean, how long did it take to get from those people to your car?
Rym: our car about an hour if you are?
Rym: Extremely experienced at hiking because it was very rough terrain probably two hours for like an inexperienced hiker.
Scott: So you couldn't be like hey follow us to our car and then Yeah, also I didn't.
Scott: Well, I mean, but yeah, and then it won't be like, you know, we're gonna go this way.
Scott: Yeah, you know if you can keep up with us.
Rym: Yeah, there was no way but as they left they were Clearly had start beginning to have the fight that had started when they encountered us and the older woman said I told you Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I'm pretty sure we they had the phone numbers to call.
Rym: They had their phone.
Rym: that was working.
Rym: Worst case scenario some Rangers had to put on masks and go out in the middle of that Find them and take them to their car.
Scott: Oh, well I mean if you're a Ranger and That's the level of emergency is someone is alive and healthy standing in the woods lost.
Scott: That's way.
Scott: That's you're fine dealing with that.
Scott: It's your job.
Scott: You're working.
Rym: then anyway, it is actually most Emergencies on trails like that.
Rym: right people just walk here.
Scott: It's like if it's not someone bit by snake or You know fell out of a tree or they got in a fight with a bear.
Rym: it's just You're okay Someone?
Rym: it's like in tech.
Rym: We're Monday.
Rym: I'll tie it back before we get into the news.
Rym: Someone asked you a tech question and you don't think I will answer your question.
Rym: You think the fact that they asked this question is a warning sign that they are doing something incredibly wrong.
Rym: So you ask a follow-up question.
Rym: that then implies you just go down a darker and darker path as you ask more questions.
Rym: XY problem, like I'm trying to get my my battery to charge for my house and you're like your house has a battery.
Rym: Please explain tell me what this battery looks like Because it's a refrigerator.
Scott: I worry.
Rym: you were about to tell me about a room in your house filled with car batteries So you got any news.
Scott: Do I have a news?
Scott: All right, so this relates to our main bit today.
Scott: It's where we got the idea for our main bit.
Scott: But this person who is a wealthy person is probably not a good person because they spent their money on a Ferrari at a time Like this.
Scott: hard to be a good person if you own a Ferrari Regardless of where they listen, I mean Anyway, they bought a brand new Ferrari and they immediately took it to an auto place to have because they wanted to change the seat.
Scott: Right, they wanted to replace the seat that the car came with with a different seat, which is you know That's.
Scott: you know.
Scott: If you're already the kind of person who buys a brand new Ferrari from the dealership, right?
Scott: Then you're the kind of person who would like customize the car, you know, that's reasonable whatever.
Scott: And what happened was while they were at the dealer the the repair place The repair place was like an indoor Underground garage type situation.
Scott: It wasn't like outdoors, right?
Scott: so there was no cell service inside the place where the car is being worked on and As soon as they like took the seat out of the car, they believe that what happened.
Scott: All right Who know?
Scott: I don't know how true this is, but their understanding was that there is some sort of anti tampering system in the car and The anti tampering system in the car basically said well someone's messing with this car and they're not supposed to right.
Scott: It's a very expensive car.
Scott: So the car is now going to refuse to operate until You know the Ferrari has like, you know Confirmed right that yes that the car is, you know not been stolen or vandalized right Which is you know a fine security feature on something that cost two hundred fifty thousand dollars.
Scott: the problem was Ferrari, you know it cloud Ferrari wherever they are right couldn't Remotely disable the anti tampering system because the car was not in you know Cell signal area, right?
Scott: He was underground.
Scott: So I imagine they had to like I don't Get some dollies and like we or tow the car outside Somehow in order to give it give it signal and then somehow get Ferrari to unbrick it or something.
Scott: It's just a you can read in this It's you know the I don't know how confirmed this is because it's just a thread on reddit But it's a believable story and there's a lot of comments discussing it and it's very interesting Because at least I have not heard of.
Scott: I've heard of cars having you know various Problems with drms and things like hey, you can't repair your John Deere cuz the DRM and stuff like that.
Scott: but this is the first I've heard about a car just being Bricked by accident.
Scott: It wouldn't surprise cars being bricked remotely.
Scott: Well, if they have like a low jack style GPS theft detection where the owner is like my car is gone They just remotely disable it You know intentionally.
Rym: so a common occurrence of that where there's a failure that bricks a car is very specifically Inflicted upon poor people who have secured loans for a cheap car from a dodgy place.
Scott: where though Yeah, repo man installs a thing or they buy the car from a financier who everybody you make your payment It gives you a code.
Rym: you have to key the code into the car or the car or the car bricks itself And if the car leaves a certain geographic region, it also bricks itself.
Scott: Or you could disable that system.
Rym: Yeah, it's one.
Rym: it's usually against the terms of your loan and the car will be repossessed if you disable that.
Scott: How would they know if you had to disable it in some way?
Scott: where it you?
Rym: it knows That some of these systems are a phone.
Rym: They have a cell phone in them basically and they phone right to check.
Rym: so every right.
Scott: so it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's reporting correctly But you've disconnected it from the car so it can't actually brick the car.
Scott: Like you take the system out.
Scott: you put it like in your house.
Scott: It thinks you're just keeping the car at your house and the car works.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's hard to say that might be moderately difficult.
Rym: I also don't think the car didn't say it'd be easy.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's just possible.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But also the kind of person who is in that situation probably does not have the bandwidth to do that level of yeah.
Scott: if you were smart enough to yeah, if you had the the the Skills to do that then you have the skills to make money to pay for a car.
Scott: Yeah, right You could sell those skills to other people who need the services and then you don't need those services anymore.
Rym: but the moral in general was to get to.
Rym: the main bit is Generally if something requires any sort of communication or has like a security system that can be accessed remotely you are potentially very much at risk of that communication link failing in some way like if I'm on a trip and my creative cloud needs to Be renewed because I haven't logged in in a while.
Rym: I don't have internet.
Rym: I'm just effed.
Scott: So is any other news what is going?
Scott: so I just want to mention that tomorrow is you know Because we previously talked about Apple's iPad.
Scott: I watch event which was in September and there should have been iPhones then and there weren't.
Scott: and The iPhone event is actually tomorrow the the 13th of October which might be today for most of you listening If anyone's the one person listening.
Scott: So yeah, we thanks Apple for putting the Apple event one day after.
Scott: I need tech news twice in a row I should raise a complaint Apple.
Scott: You're really messing up the gig night schedule here But we'll see if I replace this iPhone 7 or not because it's still working Fantastically and I don't really go out.
Rym: I was about to say I feel like I'm not like even if my ancient ancient phone.
Scott: Alright, I mean there's a chance that the new iPhone has like all the features I want and it's perfect.
Scott: and it there I heard There is gonna be a smaller one.
Scott: So I you know, it might be.
Scott: if I am gonna get that one Why would I wait?
Scott: I would just get it immediately.
Rym: But if you're not going anywhere just wait a year right at the end.
Scott: the neck these the middle Right little update to exactly right exactly if they're not unbelievably perfect if there's like if there's any kind of a Say what's up for another year?
Rym: Yeah Like I feel like I if my phone broke I wouldn't even replace it until after COVID calms down.
Scott: Uh, I still need the phone.
Scott: There's some things.
Scott: the phone does that like the app iPad and I watch don't I guess navigating?
Rym: No, cuz my watch can do that without the phone.
Rym: Yep, yeah, I don't really need the phone right now.
Scott: Okay So I do use the phone.
Rym: So it's about there.
Rym: I mean I make all my phone calls online.
Rym: Oh, and I also have a Google Voice number that isn't even tied to the phone that I can just use directly on a computer.
Scott: So no, I use the phone to me.
Scott: I could make phone calls on the iPad though.
Rym: Yeah So I stumbled onto this while I was looking for an unrelated thing and it didn't make a lot of big news.
Rym: But basically what's going on here?
Rym: Spotify?
Rym: One of the all the different music streaming services are all Really fighting over market share.
Scott: like that industry is really locked in a race to the bottom for a lot of reasons And it's actually I just want to say as some you know, not speaking for my employer in any way, right?
Scott: This is my own personal talking just in case I don't think You know, I do work for a music publisher, right?
Scott: So the race to the bottom is a problem for Music people in the music industry because what you have here is, you know, we finally escaped mostly, you know Music piracy, right?
Scott: So now it's like musicians.
Scott: songwriters are getting paid when people listen to their music on Spotify or Apple music or whatever.
Scott: Right people are legally paying or this advertising supporting, you know people getting paid when someone listens to their songs, which is good You know because even if I don't believe in copyright laws, I believe that creative people who are making art should get paid for it By some mechanism, even if that mechanism is not the existing awful copyright
Rym: capitalism,
Scott: right?
Scott: Exactly However, what happens here is you have Spotify Apple music etc.
Scott: competing Right on features and also on price Right and by competing on price there.
Scott: They want to lower their price, right?
Scott: They don't want to charge a lot of money.
Scott: They want to have more users because Apple doesn't actually want to sell Apple music.
Scott: They want to sell iPhone Right.
Scott: Spotify does want to sell Spotify, but they can't if someone's undercutting them, right?
Scott: They're happy to lower their price to get the most users Especially since a lot of their money does come from the free users who are listening to ads.
Scott: Therefore more users is better because then an ad Spotify ad cost more because they will have more listens And that hurts, you know people always talk about Spotify not paying music people anything.
Scott: Well, guess what?
Scott: Spotify charging less hurts music people because now there's less money to divide amongst same reason.
Scott: writers.
Rym: Why the fact that a triple-a video game cost the same number of dollars today in 2020 that it cost in 1989?
Scott: exactly the songwriters the musicians the music industry wants Spotify to charge more money which You know and then therefore there would be more money to divide amongst everyone who has music on Spotify Which makes total sense from their perspective.
Scott: but charging 50 bucks a month makes no sense because I'm not paying that.
Rym: Yep Well, especially that's in the era when it became more difficult for me to pirate good music like around the time I left RIT.
Rym: there was like an era of I didn't pirate a lot of music, but there wasn't streaming services yet I just didn't listen to as much new music.
Rym: yeah, a lot of people are like that.
Rym: a lot of people music is a Secondary concern or a background concern.
Rym: They're not really gonna pay for the primary activity of listening to albums.
Scott: Like that is a much smaller, you know You know YouTube videos that are a song or a music video are still like the number one, right?
Scott: But those all have ads on them.
Scott: Yep I mean you can also choose not to see those ads but that's all separate conversation anyway And I'm pretty sure a YouTube view is gonna get you more money than a spot a Spotify listen.
Rym: So it's really hard to compete on price because what we just talked about.
Rym: It's also hard to compete on features because there's only so many features you can give someone around listening to WAV files Pretty much.
Scott: Yeah or mp3s or whatever kind of file you got listening to the modulation of air around your body.
Rym: There's only so many ways to make that experience more pleasant that are not even if there are newer better ways.
Scott: We haven't thought of them yet.
Scott: They're harder to think of.
Rym: Yep, but like make a playlist get Recommendations like that stuff.
Rym: everyone has that stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I can say though the Spotify recommendations are like I could switch to Apple music.
Scott: I have all these Apple devices, right?
Rym: It wouldn't you know, I found all the services Give me the same level of like high quality recommendations.
Rym: They're all very accurate.
Scott: Like I don't know what the Spotify recommendations have been better.
Scott: I think lately.
Scott: so it's like that's yeah.
Rym: Well, it's really like YouTube actually gives me the best recommendations.
Rym: But and I think that might sometimes I listen to more music on YouTube than I do other services.
Rym: So YouTube has more data about me.
Scott: So that's also true as I do list.
Scott: I have listened to more music on Spotify.
Scott: Maybe that's why it's bright.
Rym: So so the third way you can compete is lock in and that is where they're going now.
Rym: according to a bunch of articles I found Spotify is going after developers of apps basically threatening to cut off all API access if they violate the terms of service and one particular clause that says you cannot help people migrate Anything to another service Under any circumstances.
Rym: if you use our API's Not even like and I manually export my Spotify playlist Not that I have that many not easily like you can do a manual process.
Scott: Oh, here I go.
Scott: You can go to a You can go to a Spotify playlist and you can right-click and go to share and do Huh, so basically there's a time you can share it somehow.
Rym: Yep, here's a public.
Rym: that will basically be your single point of interface for all the streaming music services You subscribe to and do cool stuff and basically all of them now just recently Removed their.
Rym: take my playlist from Spotify and recreate it on another service because Spotify is cutting them off of the API's.
Rym: Spotify.
Scott: the point of those.
Scott: wouldn't the point of those third-party Services be that you would make playlists on those third parties and then they would?
Scott: that way you could mix like yes Exclusive and Apple music songs together in a playlist that would be on their service and not on Spotify.
Rym: Yes, but people have Exist.
Rym: a lot of people use Spotify for a long time Like I don't know Spotify account and made a bunch of playlists in there and they want to copy those playlists to a different service.
Scott: Yeah, and I had not realized that you there is not an easy way in the Spotify UI to Export a playlist.
Rym: and now that Spotify is going after the users of their API.
Rym: It's very clear why that's not easy.
Scott: Hmm I mean iTunes I'm pretty sure still supports like old m3u playlists.
Rym: in fact Their terms of service even specifically calls out you cannot transfer any content of any kind to quote another music service that competes with Spotify.
Scott: I You know.
Scott: while I agree, you know if I make a playlist It's kind of bullshit that they don't have a way to export it great except for obviously manually writing it down and retyping it Right.
Scott: Yeah But I do agree actually That if you have a playlist that was generated by Spotify's AI for example discover weekly release radar Right.
Scott: It's like you can kind of see a valid argument for like, okay, you're using Spotify to generate your taking advantage of the AI on Spotify to generate a really good playlist for you and all the data it has and then you're gonna listen to that playlist on Apple music and Spotify is not gonna get any money for it.
Scott: Yeah, even though they did all the work.
Scott: That's there's some validity to that Argument there.
Rym: Yeah, but I think most people have playlists.
Rym: They made themselves like mixed.
Scott: Yeah, if you make a playlist by hand, let me see if I made this playlist by hand.
Scott: I Did.
Scott: and yeah, it doesn't seem like there is a way to export it.
Scott: So, oh wait.
Scott: No, there's a download button.
Scott: Oh, no that just downloads all the songs into the cat.
Rym: So I found one app.
Rym: I think it's called free your music.
Rym: wonder.
Rym: there's a million apps that do this stuff and they Have a statement where they were like We're gonna keep offering the service because we don't use Spotify's API or SDK to make it work.
Rym: So they some sort of scraping Nice.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I'm sure if I really wanted to I could do it right now.
Scott: I know how to computer but I For the perspective of just a Spotify user I right-clicked on a playlist and there was no option to do it.
Rym: Yeah But I think it is a worrying sign when Spotify starts going after the third way the lock-in path Because the lock-in path usually is the sign of a failing service.
Scott: that yeah Well, I mean that works.
Scott: I don't think Spotify is a failing service But I do think that there's just.
Scott: there's just less things.
Scott: all the certain music services they're running out of things to to compete on because the they already went through this process of getting all the different musicians and major Artists to relent and have their music on the services.
Scott: So they're not really competing on library anymore.
Scott: It's like you're real.
Scott: It's really hard in nowadays.
Scott: It used to be like Beatles aren't on there Led Zeppelin's not on there.
Scott: I remember that now I did right and now it's like Everyone's on everything.
Scott: It's like it's really hard to think of a band.
Rym: That's you get you another situation.
Rym: There's enough content out there that where if a particular act isn't on one service the people using that service Just won't even know that band exists.
Rym: like welcome to the modern world Yep So in some other news Scott's always mad about Elon Musk and SpaceX.
Scott: Well, you know all rich guys, you know, but he's a particularly bad rich guy.
Scott: He's like as close to you know, real-world Lex Luthor's you're gonna get in.
Rym: He's getting real close to like the the company OCP in the Robocop Cinematic Universe.
Scott: Basically, I think that's what I think he does that on purpose.
Scott: I think it's like it's a goal.
Scott: I don't think it's unconscious.
Scott: I think he's like yes, that's what I want to be.
Rym: I just imagine at some point He's the one sitting in the room.
Rym: Whereas someone were you here in the background?
Rym: Somebody call a paramedic cuz the robot just fucking like burnt someone.
Scott: But anyway, that probably has happened Literally and already right effectively the same thing.
Rym: So we're not gonna talk about the billionaire problem and we're not gonna talk about like injuries at the Tesla factory and shit.
Rym: I think I heard so the news and there's a lot to this topic.
Rym: We're only gonna cover the top top top news.
Rym: But if you didn't see it The Pentagon is basically contracting SpaceX to do the thing that we always assumed it would do.
Rym: SpaceX and space exploration with humans, especially when the commercial side is involved is primarily not about exploration and research.
Rym: It's primarily about the military.
Rym: That is how it has always been.
Rym: That is how it likely always will be.
Rym: and now people are reacting to this news that SpaceX is going to deliver a rocket that is designed to deliver a military payload Anywhere on earth within an hour.
Scott: Well, I think what is clear, you know, what has happened, which we sort of realized years ago.
Scott: But I think other people are starting to realize.
Scott: as you think about, you know, the so-called Military industrial complex.
Scott: right you think of these companies like Lockheed Martin Boeing Dietoles, right?
Scott: Yeah, you think about these companies that make weapons defense machinery submarines, you know, right and they're all private companies that are in league with you know, the the Government, right and we give a lot of our tax money to them via corruption, but some legitimacy, but some not.
Scott: right mostly not and That's just been what the US is all about.
Scott: And now what's happened is SpaceX slash Tesla slash Elon Musk industries, whatever the fuck you want to call it, right.
Scott: at first Appeared to not be one of those companies.
Scott: It was like a. it was almost like a consumer facing thing like buy a Tesla.
Scott: you could buy a Tesla.
Scott: You can't buy fucking anything Lockheed Martin sells.
Scott: I don't sell a damn thing to you, right?
Scott: So you don't cuss people.
Scott: does normal people citizens right who aren't involved in directly don't view those companies The same way as they view SpaceX or Tesla or whatever the fuck he's got going on over there, right, but really there's no different.
Scott: at this point It's like yeah this SpaceX slash Tesla slash whatever just is one of those companies.
Scott: It's not really any different.
Scott: So this news is basically like if the news said Pentagon has contract with Lockheed Martin to make rocket that delivers weapons, right?
Scott: Yeah, I would no one would get no one would give a shit.
Scott: Well, this is that this is that news just different company.
Scott: Yes, the news should actually be SpaceX steals contract from Lockheed Martin, you know Lockheed Martin stock goes down and SpaceX stock goes up there.
Scott: Yeah, they're in the same industry.
Rym: There's a very important point people really need to understand about like NASA and space with the US government Is that NASA does not do everything on its own.
Rym: it never did at any point and these private companies are all involved on Government contracts and it's very complex how this stuff gets done, but all of that is valid.
Rym: There's a lot of valid criticism around the situation going on here.
Rym: Especially why would be should we be investing so much in the military industrial complex during a global pandemic and the rise of fascism, etc.
Rym: All valid points.
Rym: the only thing I want to point out to the nerds who are mad about this Is that you need to be mad about it for the right reasons.
Rym: the capability that they're describing is not Particularly novel and is going to happen Anyway, similar to how the internet arose from the military industrial complex and then became also a private sector thing.
Rym: If you talk about the US military in particular not all militaries on earth this primarily only applies to the US military because there are almost no other militaries on earth that have the concept of Real like global force projection capabilities.
Rym: the US military is primarily a logistics organization.
Rym: the violence doing is actually like the end stop.
Rym: there's like 50 steps before the violence happens at the end and The power of the US military and the value of it to the US as a entity.
Rym: and again, yes There are a lot of problems with the power of the US as an entity.
Rym: I'm not arguing that this is not the case right.
Scott: the main argument would be like yeah all these positive things It is doing we could just have that money go to a different nonviolent organization to do the same damn thing.
Scott: but
Rym: basically we could
Scott: have invented the internet at the Technological research found it or whatever, you know something like that some other institution that didn't have an end goal of violence Right and gave them the same tax money to invent the internet since the
Rym: beginning of the modern era like World War.
Rym: one Type war has primarily began been and operate an exercise in logistics.
Rym: So the most important part of the US military is actually probably transcom or u.s.
Rym: Transcom which literally just get shit from one place to another place very similar like the same technique.
Scott: Yeah, it's like We've been in like we've people talk about forever war right?
Scott: It's a great this forever war in Afghanistan.
Scott: It's true Yeah, you know how much we don't make anything in fucking Afghanistan.
Scott: It's not like Weapons factories there, right?
Scott: It's not a command and conquer where your factory is five feet from your tank.
Scott: The the tanks and whatever they're using over there is made far far away and we've been forever warring.
Scott: We are constantly delivering and retrieving people food staff equipment right Non-stop right that is the most of the operation is the moving of the stuff.
Scott: Yeah in fact There's only one difference big using of the stuff is Costing way less energy and way less money than the delivering and retrieving of the stuff.
Rym: there is basically only one difference between military logistics for transportation and Civilian logistics for transportation.
Rym: the latter the primary goal is low cost and or efficiency.
Rym: The primary goal of military is cost is not a factor.
Rym: get it there as fast as possible The military side Also safely.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well without anyone compromise.
Scott: Well, not only without anyone stealing it.
Scott: Oh, yeah securely, but not necessarily All right, not safe for the people doing the delivering.
Scott: they might get blown up But securely and that no one steals it now messes with it.
Rym: This is where it gets.
Rym: This is why this is such a complicated issue.
Rym: There is an overlap between those two.
Rym: when it comes to things like disaster response Like imagine if a Chernobyl happened today or a horrible hurricane big disaster.
Rym: The type of logistics you need to get help to people is the same logistics.
Rym: You need to get harm to people.
Rym: It's military style logistics not civilian style logistic, right?
Scott: Right UPS is not going to successfully deliver right water blankets Whatever you need.
Rym: ask someone getting paid that little to risk their life to deliver something somewhere But someone in a military type organization.
Rym: their job is to risk their life to do the thing.
Rym: So what this technology is fundamentally?
Rym: Basically, the c17 is like the way Cargo gets delivered in up like when you got to get it there fast and it takes a while.
Rym: It can take about a day.
Rym: This is a rocket that can deliver that amount of payload like one cargo container.
Scott: Oh a c17 is worth of payload anywhere on earth in an hour.
Scott: That's a lot of stuff.
Scott: Yes It's not.
Scott: that's not like a that's not like a box in pub G right that is like supply I guess the way.
Scott: I guess since it's going to space the weight also matters, right?
Scott: You probably couldn't deliver even though you could fit several tanks in like a c17.
Scott: Yeah, you couldn't.
Scott: you couldn't deliver tanks via space.
Scott: They're too heavy.
Scott: Yeah, but you could deliver.
Scott: you could deliver a planes worth of food.
Rym: now I do not know for all my food.
Rym: I do not know a lot about modern transportation infrastructure in the military.
Rym: I don't know a lot about how much they see 17 can deliver.
Rym: I do know the big the u.s This does not make c17s anymore and there's actually starting to be a crazy.
Rym: is now The existing c17s don't break any?
Scott: Okay But I mean they also use boats.
Rym: boats are good Yeah, but they don't serve the same purpose.
Scott: boats take orders of magnitude longer, of course, but they could deliver way more shit Yep.
Rym: But imagine a disaster where we need to get supplies to a town to survive the next week.
Rym: What before like a supply chain can be created to get through the disaster area to get there.
Rym: Military logistics is the only way to do that and this type of technology can be used equally to Deliver harm doing materials to do harm and deliver life-saving materials to save lives.
Rym: The problem is never the technology.
Rym: It's the priorities of the civilization that's funding it and how they choose to use those resources.
Rym: There are great.
Scott: there is a question.
Scott: there is a question though always to be asked though It's like, you know when you have airplanes how much is a rocket ever really necessary?
Scott: Like when is the airplane not good enough and you need to use the rocket?
Rym: So the difference is and this is where I'm being a little soft because I don't like.
Rym: I am NOT an expert That's at all at this point.
Rym: I'm an expert in like this type this technology from 50 years ago because I'm a nerd.
Rym: Basically.
Rym: Imagine you have to deliver Important supplies that only are available from certain places to somewhere on the other side of the globe like a remote location.
Rym: It could take 20.
Scott: how often does this happen?
Rym: Disasters and wars like.
Rym: rarely this is not.
Rym: you don't use this like every day like saying we're going to use this Technology is like on the level of we're gonna launch a rocket Literally because it's launching a rocket.
Rym: So this is a capability that it probably does make sense for humans to have.
Rym: The problems you should be railing at are all the problems We already talked about not the existence of this specific technology.
Scott: also Keep in mind the you know, the the military.
Scott: the budget is so ridiculous, right?
Scott: There's so much money.
Scott: most of these things these contracts They hand out to companies or whatever to develop this or that.
Scott: a lot of it is just pie in the sky Stuff that it's like.
Scott: maybe they invent it and don't use it.
Scott: It does never goes into production It never proves to actually be useful.
Scott: Maybe they try.
Scott: it doesn't even work, right?
Scott: Yeah, you know that they're constantly doing that stuff.
Scott: That's like every damn day.
Scott: if you go look, you know send some FYI requests or look at stuff That's already public at like.
Scott: what is the Pentagon spending its research money on?
Scott: what's DARPA up to whatever?
Scott: It's like you're gonna see a lot of crazy shit that they're working on and get mad.
Scott: So think about it.
Rym: this way though It's like the slowest way to do something is civilian boat transport and then there's faster but more costly not just in terms of dollars but in terms of risk in terms of climate change in terms of Societal
Scott: I'd say the slowest way would be civilian pigeon transport.
Rym: Well, it depends on where you're going.
Rym: Let's say it's like you're trying to deliver something.
Scott: I guess I guess a pigeon flies faster than a person walking.
Rym: let's say you're trying to deliver critical X like technological and human aid supplies from military based in the United States like a supply depot to like the Horn of Africa for some reason or Antarctica because there's some like us.
Rym: a science of the thing happened down there and we got to get some supplies down there.
Scott: Okay You know what the thing to steal?
Rym: That's great.
Rym: Now the thing has all of our guns And he learned how to use a. Anyway, it's time for things of the day.
Scott: The thing of our day.
Rym: Not that thing though.
Rym: It is adjacent to the thing Tenuously your thing of the day at least.
Scott: What was it again?
Rym: All right, so scale abroad.
Scott: Yeah, it's Halloween It's Halloween times.
Scott: So the skeleton energy is is back especially because the Home Depot skeleton exists.
Rym: Yeah, I want to buy that Home Depot skeleton.
Scott: so bad, I don't want to give Home Depot any money I know but I want that skeleton.
Rym: I want to just assemble it in the park courtyard behind my building in the middle of the night and never say a word about it.
Scott: I Think people would know because they'd see it get delivered.
Rym: I know I got to figure out a way to make this happen.
Rym: Maybe I should set it up in a public park in the middle of the night anyway, anyway.
Scott: so this person has a nice fake skeleton.
Scott: they got you know, and They put in a t-shirt on it that says What hide-and-seek champion or something about of 2020 of 2020?
Scott: And you think you're watching this video.
Scott: It's just a little Twitter video and you're thinking when this video is going They're just gonna hide the skeleton somewhere and I thought the video was gonna be like, okay Then they would play hide-and-seek with a kid and the kid would find the skeleton or right.
Scott: but No, the video goes to a much more hilarious place.
Scott: you can That I did not see coming.
Scott: and mad props to whoever made this video and thought of this clever idea.
Scott: You are a skeleton champion.
Rym: It is no spoilers to watch the video.
Rym: The video is 39 seconds long.
Rym: Like I think you can you can watch.
Scott: I think you have 39 seconds.
Scott: You're wasted a lot more than 39 seconds.
Scott: Listen to us.
Rym: We've talked about this video for well more than 39 seconds already.
Rym: I know right, but all I'll say is that this type of prank very much has good night for flying energy.
Rym: Mmm, like it's that level which is my favorite kind of prank on earth.
Rym: So, you know, you might have a house and if you have a house in the US, there's a decent chance at some point Raccoons are gonna get into your fucking house.
Scott: Like if you live in an area with our coons, there's no like raccoons in Florida, right?
Rym: Yeah, there are.
Rym: there's raccoons I think almost everywhere in North America.
Scott: I've never seen a raccoon in Florida.
Rym: raccoons are very widespread.
Rym: Do I need to pull up the map of raccoon habitat?
Scott: I've seen I mean there's raccoons clearly everywhere north of that right?
Rym: Let's see a map of where our raccoons in North America.
Rym: Let me find a map all of North America literally all of it except the alright.
Scott: Well, I've never seen a record.
Rym: also much of Central America.
Rym: Oh In fact what last time we were in Costa Rica.
Rym: but if I remember a great moment, we're eating dinner at this fancy outdoor place and Bunch of raccoons.
Rym: just kind of wander up and like I feel a tug at my leg and I look down and there's a raccoon Just like tugging on my pants and when I look down at him, he holds his hands up and starts begging.
Scott: All right, you know, they're smart.
Rym: Yeah, they know what's up.
Rym: So basically if raccoons get into your house like what do you you call an animal like rescue type plays they will show up and Deal with the raccoons.
Scott: That's not what we did.
Rym: What did you do?
Scott: We just locked the trash.
Scott: We just locked the trash cans harder.
Rym: No, I'm talking like if they're in your house like they're in in the house And they're living in the shed.
Scott: we kept them out that we did never let them get in the house.
Scott: they were always outside.
Rym: Yeah, there's like they don't get in your house unless you don't maintain your house.
Rym: But it happens like there's ways raccoons get in.
Rym: so when they're actually in your house.
Rym: What this video is is it's a channel that I subscribe to.
Rym: that is great called gates.
Rym: wildlife control these people.
Rym: there are Inhumane people who will just like murder them and like get them out of your house.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but there are much better places that usually charge less money to.
Rym: that will get rid of them But they'll do it in a nice way and this is one of those companies and this yeah I would.
Scott: my guess would be you get some sort of bait in a trap that doesn't hurt them and then you take the track Anything you do with like a straight.
Scott: It's basically the same thing you just supposed to do with stray cats is where you catch them.
Scott: you take them to get spayed or neutered Then you release them again.
Rym: So this video is that.
Rym: but what's cool about it is, you know, we're in our friend group.
Rym: We've been having a lot of fun talking about people failing to correctly fell a tree.
Rym: So this is a video that sort of explains.
Rym: here is how you safely and humanely Get raccoons and raccoon babies out of your attic.
Rym: Like what does this look like?
Rym: and the guy explains every step of the way like alright, I'm gonna do this I'm gonna do that.
Rym: and the best part about these videos is the baby box.
Rym: because basically what they do?
Rym: they scare the mom away and Then they get the babies out and they put the babies in a box that can't be open from the inside But could be opened by the outside.
Rym: They leave it outside The place they scared the mom out of because they know the mom is gonna come back that night Get the babies and take them somewhere else like and it explains in detail this whole process.
Rym: Not only do you get all that detail and you'll learn a lot But you get to see a whole bunch of really cute baby raccoons.
Scott: I think the key thing there obviously is you don't want to leave, you know, after you trap the raccoons You can't.
Scott: you can't just leave them there.
Scott: You got to make sure you get the trap Like failure mode.
Scott: I think that happens.
Scott: a lot is like people will trap animals and like forget and then that's about people will do that.
Rym: People will trap a mother raccoon leave release her in the woods somewhere But leave the babies in their attic and then that leads to a tragedy.
Rym: like that happens a lot because people are stupid.
Rym: This video just goes into all that detail and it's just fascinating and adorable.
Rym: In the meta moment we're not reading stuff.
Rym: cuz where we give enough time I don't know what you want.
Scott: and in the meta moment.
Scott: There are no conventions on the schedule whatsoever.
Rym: Thanks unplugged.
Rym: zero finally announced that they are canceled.
Scott: Thus we knew that they were canceled for a long time.
Scott: still pretty sure there are not even any online conventions for us to go to.
Rym: Maybe there are online convention.
Scott: Yeah, tell us or tell the convention to have us And maybe we'll go to it or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, we've done a bunch of stuff at cons.
Rym: I have the video from our panel at PAX online.
Rym: I have a director's cut of that.
Rym: that will be up on our channel this week.
Rym: So if you miss that panel and you don't want to watch it in the middle of like a nine-hour video of That theater from the day our panel happened to be I have a director's cut that actually Has a little more content and is edited a little bit differently and uses our overlays and our camera angles instead of the PAX Overlay and the PAX camera angle, so that'll be up this week.
Rym: I'm gonna do the same thing for our other panel.
Scott: if you are a chance If you're looking for a convention atmosphere and there's no conventions to go to you should come to The official GeekNights' discord.
Scott: you can find links to it.
Rym: I guess if you come to our website if I could come or our forum I'm gonna make an invite link right now while we're doing the main bit and I'll post it in the chat of the live stream.
Rym: Okay, it'll last like 48 hours sure.
Scott: But yeah, you should Go to our YouTube stream.
Scott: We stream all GeekNights episodes live and there's probably some things that you will hear there that will like a few sentences Maybe that are edited out of the actual mp3 that's loaded to Whatever service we're on every single podcasting service even the new shitty ones like Amazon Google's buy everything.
Scott: We're everywhere.
Rym: Also, I read your raccoon wounds.
Scott: Ah, yeah, I've been biking to nowhere.
Scott: I just finished a six-week bike to nowhere program in the bike to nowhere app And when I bike to nowhere I turn on the twitch stream because then I can talk to someone while I'm biking to nowhere.
Scott: it makes it much less sad.
Rym: also Playing a lot of Star Wars squadrons that if you're also playing that I'd be happy to suit up and fly with you.
Scott: Yeah, so if you want to come and talk to us you can come to our discord.
Scott: You can come to my bike twitch stream.
Scott: you can come, you know, we're every every single place.
Scott: We're there.
Scott: You're listening to this.
Scott: You already know.
Scott: Yeah, you already know where we are, right?
Scott: So come on down.
Rym: All right, let's just get right into it Breaking stuff.
Rym: We never really talked about this except tangentially talking about other things Like.
Rym: I think we even mentioned it recently.
Rym: we did that show on firmware stuff I'd wear.
Scott: I just talked about that.
Scott: that guy got a Ferrari's got exactly I.
Rym: but I think it's actually worth talking about.
Rym: like really what this means.
Rym: Because there's a lot of issues around the concept of bricking and some of them edge into society issues some of them edge into capitalism issues some of them edge into.
Rym: these are things you just need to know if you're gonna mess with your own technology like by so Mm-hmm.
Scott: So I mean as a popular Undwell, and I'm sure there's probably some example of bricking that's way older than you Imagine right even though I can't think of it.
Scott: but bricking is like a relatively new Phenomenon in like the greater.
Rym: I don't know world it did rose Yeah, partly with the what once we went away from using just raw circuits Like.
Rym: I'm trying not to use a bunch of electronics jargon here because I don't think all of you are super up on that.
Rym: But there was an error where to use analog circuits and analog logic like logic gates like put a bunch of and or nan gates together on a breadboard along with a bunch of relays and mechanical devices and you would implement the logic of your thing like a furnace in Quote-unquote code but the code was this collection of wires.
Scott: So yep, you can like a pinball machine.
Rym: Yeah, there's nothing like if you want to update it move the wires around.
Rym: if the wires break replace them.
Rym: You can look at the wires.
Scott: There have always been cases of things being broken, right?
Scott: Broken things go way back.
Scott: In fact now things are probably less broken than they've ever been.
Scott: Yeah things you used to need a lot more like TV repairmen.
Scott: and so when's the last time you heard of a TV or impairment?
Rym: Part of that is our disposable culture of if a TV breaks is cheaper to throw it away and buy a new one than it Is time it is and even look at it, of course, that is true as well.
Scott: But the point is things just break less often, right?
Scott: It's also it is that but it's also TVs used to break a lot and you'd need to get them repaired.
Scott: when's the last time you had a broken TV?
Rym: and also things have gotten cheaper and are more accessible to people.
Rym: and The part that a lot of older people like to forget especially people who complain about the durability of modern things.
Rym: Modern things do a lot more like.
Rym: then old things did old furnaces old thermostats.
Rym: There's like one fucking switch in there
Scott: Yep But anyway, so the point is is that you know things have always broken right, you know human-made devices of any kind I've always broken but they could then be repaired in some way right because the device in and of itself and Common tools and common materials were all that you required to repair the device and make it work again
Rym: In some cases a common knowledge.
Scott: Yes today we have many devices out there and those devices include general-purpose CPUs right and not a general-purpose CPU like that's a very powerful one like the one in your desktop computer But you know like a very small 8-bit chip, you know something that's like you'd find it any s you can
Rym: go CPU that runs it like a Few kilohertz and just does
Scott: some sort of Motorola something something or Texas Instruments some chip or whatever that can run Tiny programs, you know, we're talking like, you know similar.
Scott: It's like your Arduino, right?
Scott: It's something it won't be that exact architecture.
Scott: But there's a lot a lot of micro processors in the world that you can buy if you're making products Right and just about every product has micro processors in them.
Scott: Your car has probably arm CPUs in it right somewhere running different systems and Those systems have software.
Scott: and if you have a desktop computer or even a phone then you have consumer tools That allow you into some level to some degree Modify that software.
Scott: you can reinstall your OS on your computer.
Scott: Even if you don't know how it can be done Yeah, any.
Scott: so you can call someone to do it right and the software is available.
Scott: You can get another computer and download that software, right?
Scott: If you're I don't know, what's something else that has software?
Scott: you're well, I can't know.
Rym: a TV Has software like you can download an app onto it or like hit the factory reset button.
Scott: Right, but a lot of devices out there that aren't just personal computers.
Scott: Alright, say your refrigerator.
Scott: Your refrigerator has software.
Scott: It has CPUs in it.
Scott: Probably right if it's a fancy wine doesn't but it is not fancy.
Scott: No, I'm saying there are fridges out there that do have CPUs, right?
Scott: You know, maybe a better example HVAC are really good examples.
Scott: No, that's a good one.
Scott: Yeah, but there's plenty of just devices you buy that have CPUs in them.
Scott: They are computers.
Scott: They're computers inside and those computers are required for the device to function properly Sometimes required for it to function at all, right.
Scott: or for the advanced features of the device to function.
Scott: It might just work really stupidly if you don't have the computer parts working, right?
Scott: So you don't have access to that software at all.
Scott: There's not like they give you a copy of the software.
Scott: There's no interface on the device.
Scott: That is Customer accessible.
Scott: right for you to replace the software even if you did have the software.
Scott: It's not like there's an SD card slot and like a load from.
Rym: I was about to use an example Metaphor that I realized is actually too old for our audience probably around the the extra buttons ABCD on a phone that a consumer phone does not have.
Rym: but a telephone like a Telephone operations person a repair person has those extra buttons to do extra things on the phone network.
Rym: But I don't think anyone knows about that anymore.
Scott: Yeah People who work who produce electronics or make embedded computers or embedded devices There are certain computer interfaces that they use things like j-tag which like these debug interfaces Like if you're developing a circuit board You'll usually put like a j-tag connector on it and you'll connect your debug device, you know things to that and That way you can develop the circuit board.
Scott: But then when you go into mass production.
Scott: you either don't include that so there's no way to access those pins or You don't put the connector on or it's just hidden inside the vice.
Scott: You don't know it's there as a customer.
Scott: and even if you did know it's there as a customer and you found it and connected To it and were an expert.
Scott: you don't have documentation for it necessarily and you know It'll it's not.
Scott: it'll be very very difficult for you to actually, you know get any use out of you know the device.
Scott: So if anything at
Rym: all
Scott: happens to the software in the device if the place the software is stored is broken if the software becomes corrupt if You're doing a firmware update through an official channel and it somehow stops halfway through it doesn't finish or it doesn't work properly If you know literally anything happens to that software You now have no way to repair that software because you don't have the bits Even if the hardware is in perfect condition.
Scott: Condition hardware, there's.
Rym: it's almost like it's a black box Like literally there is a black box that you cannot interact with in the device And if the failure is inside of that black box, there is no way for you to open that box, right?
Scott: It's like it's theoretically possible for you to fix it, right?
Scott: It's not inhumanly possible.
Scott: But you do not have the information or the tools or the knowledge or whatever to actually do it.
Scott: The only people who could do it would be easily would be the people who made the device.
Scott: They would be able to access You know and flash into a firmware on it and you could send it back to them to have them fix it or something Right.
Rym: cars are a perfect example here.
Rym: modern cars have chips in them that do a bunch of stuff.
Rym: old cars.
Rym: There was analog logic and mechanical logic there.
Rym: So even if you didn't have specialized tools, you could physically mess with that logic if you had the knowledge.
Rym: But even if you have the knowledge you're not connecting to your car's computer unless you're an ultra nerd and A lot of the software you can download from the internet that does that's full of malware.
Rym: So watch out.
Scott: Yeah, some people do figure out some of these interfaces especially on more popular devices and create tools or publish.
Scott: You know black market or gray market ish or free ish.
Scott: You know somewhat trustworthy tools that can allow you to help fix or modify the software on devices sort of like how routers.
Scott: You can flash your own firmware on them.
Scott: But those are almost general-purpose real PCs with network cards and everything right.
Scott: they have an interface that is That you can understand right?
Scott: Sometimes they have SD cards.
Rym: So luckily breaking like a device rarely gets bricked unless the user has taken some action or The device had an underlying fundamental problem.
Scott: Like for example You might have us sometimes sometimes there's bad luck, but it's just rare, right?
Scott: It's like oh the the.
Scott: there is a some flash memory chip.
Scott: That's like 16 megabytes.
Scott: It has the OS on it and it got messed up and it's okay, right?
Scott: It's still working.
Scott: But because if it was actually broken, well, that would be broken.
Scott: broken, right?
Scott: But even if you replace that part, well, you don't you don't have the software to flash into it, right?
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't happen too often Like if my phone's like battery or like control like charging circuit broke and I just couldn't use it anymore I wouldn't say my phone was bricked.
Rym: I'd say my phone broke Exactly, but if I was doing a firmware update on my phone and the phone just like crashed and then power button didn't do anything Anymore, that's a brick device.
Rym: There's nothing wrong with that hardware Exactly.
Scott: Somebody could repair it if they could flash it.
Rym: so I would wager and I'm curious if you disagree.
Rym: I think there are three things that cause the majority of all brickings.
Rym: number one Power interruption during an update on a device that did not have proper protections built in.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's pretty common.
Scott: Number two, that's the cause.
Scott: that's the cause of a lot of other problems as well like losing save files.
Scott: I think maybe like lots and lots of data corruption is because of that exact problem.
Rym: Yeah, it's trivially solved.
Rym: if you just make the device is more expensive.
Rym: people just aren't willing to for a lot of reasons.
Scott: Well, I think it's solved.
Scott: actually Apple has a pretty good a lot and not only Apple But a lot of companies do this where the device will just refuse to do a firmware update if it's not plugged in.
Rym: Yep My phone won't do it.
Scott: You can't firmware update your Apple watch unless it's on the charger.
Rym: Yeah, my phone will say something like it has to either be on the charger or the battery has to be above 90%.
Scott: Yeah, the my gh5 Camera won't.
Scott: if you put an SD card in with a firmware update It won't install it unless the battery is over like 90% or something.
Scott: The other
Rym: thing to do that's common on more expensive devices is you have a second safe copy of the firmware embedded in the device in Non-rewritable memory that Can automatically bootstrap the system and replace whatever is in the broken memory, but that
Scott: that's always a good fallback You know, it's like oh, yeah, it adds to cost but it is very nice when it's like, okay My device is totally messed up.
Scott: I think the pebble watch I want to say had this it had something like that.
Scott: It had something cuz I remember I messed it up once and I held some buttons and did a thing and it was restored To the way it was when I got it in the mail and I had to re-update it.
Scott: That's what I remember.
Scott: I don't know that memory is.
Rym: I have a similar memory where I had to do way more like there was a reset and then There was like a no do this thing tough fully fucking reset it.
Scott: You'll see this lot where it says like factory reset.
Scott: Usually you can't do that if you're bricked because you have to access a menu A lot of times.
Scott: factory reset just means reset all the settings back to the factory settings.
Scott: Yeah sometimes devices do have a true factory reset whereby Pushing certain buttons and a hole in a certain configuration that you would never hit by accident Actually does load a known good firmware from way back and then you can try to update it.
Scott: Yeah number two That's always nice to have.
Rym: Yeah I think.
Rym: number two.
Rym: the second most common reason is hacker was fucking around with their software or their hardware and they broke it.
Scott: This is the one I call people out on all the time because it's listen if you want to mess with your stuff Um, that's cool, right?
Scott: It's like that's all it's all about but eyes open.
Rym: man Like do it?
Scott: eyes you want to run you want to run doom on your calculator?
Scott: That's sweet, right?
Scott: The only time I Wag my finger is when I see people and I see there's a lot which really shocks me like I would understand.
Scott: like if someone says man, I was having fun it trying to get doomed to run on my Toaster and I messed up and now my toaster won't toast.
Scott: I really messed up guys.
Scott: This sucks.
Scott: I need to buy a new toaster now, but it's like alright that makes sense.
Scott: If someone says fuck this toaster company, right?
Scott: I messed it.
Scott: Why was it possible for me to mess?
Scott: It's like you messed up.
Scott: You told you did it.
Scott: It's your fault.
Rym: Yeah, like I've messed like I messed with the firmware on my old camera My gx1 because that camera is ancient.
Rym: Like if I ruined it somehow not the end of the world Mm-hmm, of course, I didn't mess with.
Rym: so my advice.
Rym: what I want to do with it?
Rym: There's no firmware on earth.
Rym: That'll make it do it.
Scott: But right.
Scott: Yeah, my advice though is just don't mess with a Device Software in an unofficial capacity, right unless you know what you're doing or willing for that device to be bricked.
Rym: Yeah, that's okay with that's.
Rym: the second part is important.
Rym: as long as you Accept the risk that it might never work again, and there's nothing you can do about that Yeah, then it's totally cool.
Scott: Just go for it.
Rym: I bought that feel like I bought that ps1.
Rym: I Opened it.
Rym: I put I soldered a mod chip into it.
Rym: There was a chance I was gonna ruin that ps1 forever.
Rym: if I tried to return that ps1 would not have flown.
Rym: Because what'd you do?
Scott: You're crying might have gotten away with it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I would add to lie and like I don't know I open the box.
Rym: It didn't work.
Scott: That's the thing.
Scott: you that's the thing you would do.
Rym: that is exactly what I would have done.
Rym: I'll go right back to that Kmart and been like hey This ps1 didn't work and hope that by the time a human cracked it open and saw my bungled soldering attempt It was too late to track me down.
Rym: Uh-huh, but there is a new OS to this one though because sometimes That bricking is because you're doing something that you shouldn't have done.
Rym: that was dangerous and it broke the device.
Rym: You cannot expect the company that made that device to protect you from your own tomfoolery, right?
Rym: but but Nintendo will do things to like.
Rym: companies like Nintendo have a history of Trying to detect if you're running alternate firmware and brick you on purpose as a fuck you.
Scott: Yes, that's bullshit.
Rym: I it's a similar situation, but I do do not believe that company should have the right.
Rym: I think if you own hardware you could you can do whatever you want with it But it should be a two-way street in return.
Rym: that company does not have to support you in any way Exactly.
Scott: It's it's pretty simple.
Scott: That's with you know, I think we have done an episode on right to repair.
Scott: Yeah, which is a which is actually a recurring topic that's come back a little bit recently.
Scott: I think this is Massachusetts doing something right to repair.
Rym: I feel like Massachusetts has been doing something a right to repair my entire adult life.
Scott: I Think it might be on their voting this thing.
Rym: I feel like that's happened before though.
Scott: Massachusetts right to repair something something.
Scott: I can't believe I spelled Massachusetts, right, Massachusetts It's question one on their voting this year.
Scott: right to repair law vehicle data access requirement initiative.
Scott: Fuck.
Scott: Yeah So we do research to figure out if yes or no is the right way to vote on question one, Massachusetts I'm not sure because I haven't read it But you obviously want to.
Scott: you obviously want to vote in favor of the right to repair.
Rym: I see some text of it and the text of the law says starting with model year 2022 the law would require Manufacturers of motor vehicles sold in the state to equip such vehicles that use any blah blah blah blah blah systems with access.
Scott: So you want to make that law happen.
Scott: I assume voting yes is correct, but double-check read the whole thing.
Rym: We don't live in Massachusetts.
Rym: Yeah, I literally favor of the Springfield porno bill.
Scott: Make sure you vote in favor of repairing right?
Scott: So but that's the thing is companies.
Scott: Apple right is Loosened up on this as they've been criticized, but they still have problems.
Scott: John Deere is obviously always the number one Culprit that's.
Scott: cars are a big one but cars are huge but in which basically the scam is that people make a device and because of the Possibility of bricking right and the secretness of the software.
Scott: They're the only ones who have it.
Scott: They can basically hold you hostage and force you to use their repair Services and not use any other repair services even when there's no reason for that, right?
Rym: You know, there might be some legitimate reasons for you to only use certain repair service or there might be Some changes you could make to that software that are or should be illegal because cars use public infrastructure.
Scott: that's true also.
Scott: or there are changes you could make to that.
Scott: so that hardware.
Scott: that would Damage the business model of the person selling the hardware.
Rym: I don't care Business model dude.
Scott: Yeah, I could just load any old games.
Scott: I want on my Nintendo switch.
Scott: It's now a play everything machine.
Scott: It's got it, you know, every emulator known to man, but simultaneously you sold me hardware.
Rym: I'm running software on that hardware.
Rym: You don't get to say what I do.
Rym: I think They're like car right to repair like any mechanic should be able to interface with any cars.
Rym: electronics full stop, but There are definitely some things that an individual might do like making their car more performant but remove like reducing the emissions protections.
Rym: that should be illegal and We got to figure out the line there which might come down to.
Rym: When your car gets inspected and it's determined that you've turned off the emission control your car gets taken from you because you are Violating the contract of society independent.
Scott: That's that's a separate problem is I think, you know Just the penalties for car infractions are way too low.
Rym: Yep So general, I think not enforced Well, but anyway I think the number three thing that causes brickings is the one that I am the most mad about But I think it's a distant third for now, but I think it's gonna get worse and worse.
Rym: Company has sold a device hardware like a speaker or something.
Rym: company then wants to monetize said hardware in perpetuity and Forces like bricks the hardware if the licensing is not paid to continue using the software.
Scott: Oh That's similar to the right.
Scott: Well, I guess that would be the fourth one, right?
Scott: Yeah, is it?
Scott: it's still some sort of DRM thing, right it's it's similar but yeah where the company basically There's a device that they sell a washing machine, right?
Scott: Yeah, there is no once that washing machine is in place You know as long as you know for getting right to repair right assuming it works There's.
Scott: you don't need the company that sold it to you anymore.
Scott: I don't want to.
Rym: I don't even need to write.
Scott: I just wanted to keep doing what you you you pay them.
Scott: once you don't have a washing machine It works it's gonna work forever until it breaks.
Scott: by putting software in that washing machine they can artificially force Basically rent-seeking where it's like.
Scott: well because we put software in the washing machine We can make your.
Scott: it's like holding you hostage almost or blackmailing or extorting like.
Rym: well It might be like you have to let us collect data about you or we brick you.
Scott: right, it's like you have made you a washing machine, but we have software in there and Basically if you don't you know do what we say from now on and use your washing machine the way we want you to and Maybe buy a subscription service from us or who knows what right right?
Scott: We're gonna keep controlling you even though our transaction is complete right.
Scott: Oh, I see you've bought a music listening device.
Scott: There's no reason that it couldn't just play music forever until it breaks But you know oh you want to.
Scott: uh you want to use a battery from another third party, right?
Scott: We don't want to buy batteries from us.
Scott: Oh you want to you know listen to music from a company We don't like you know.
Scott: Oh you want.
Scott: You know it's like all right.
Scott: We're gonna shut you down.
Scott: We're gonna force you to you know stay with us.
Scott: We're gonna sort of keep a stranglehold on you because you bought our product.
Scott: obviously don't buy those products that are doing that.
Rym: But also there should be a buy.
Rym: you need some sort of rights of access and use like Those business models.
Scott: those business rent-seeking business models like that should just be outlawed straight up.
Rym: Yep You should be able to do it.
Rym: Well, actually we just need a very simple consumer protection.
Rym: that if you sell hardware and obviously this is not the legal definition This is the colloquial definition if you sell a hardware it must come with the minimum necessary software to operate that hardware if software is necessary and You have a right in perpetuity to use that software or to write build or derive Equivalent software in the event that that software becomes unusable something like that
Scott: and this and the company that makes the device is not allowed to You know remotely disable or hinder the device in any
Rym: way.
Rym: They might not let you use their app and all like all their fancy stuff But they have to let you do what the hardware did with that minimum software right exactly?
Scott: So if you're offering for example the GoPro right there's a GoPro app you can get on your phone.
Scott: Yeah, and they they.
Scott: but they make you get a stupid GoPro account, right?
Scott: You don't actually need the account but the account gives you access to like this cloud service, which is garbage.
Scott: You don't need that either.
Scott: but it's like okay the cloud service.
Scott: You're selling me some extra thing.
Scott: I get you right, but you can get the firmware updates without paying.
Scott: But imagine if they were like, alright, you know what?
Scott: Your GoPro isn't gonna even record videos anymore.
Scott: Right unless you join our pay for our cloud.
Rym: You gotta pay five bucks to use the HDMI out.
Scott: Yeah, it's like that would be some bullshit, right?
Scott: basically This is bullshit.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and may comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce.
Rym: How do you mean it?
Rym: I'm already grandia just like a dude guy Graham Finch The key to my heart.
Rym: I sprang with the quickness like lightning disappeared.
Rym: Clinton Walton J Bats for after New Zealand rhyme parent Chris midkiff dread lily tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn shirt about her and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: like I said this week the video of our panel from packs with Some editing like it'll be it'll actually like change camera angles and like zoom in on the slides and stuff like our normal videos As opposed to the format we had to put it in for packs will be on our channels.
Rym: You can check it out.
Rym: I'll also link to the time stamp in the super long YouTube video they posted.
Rym: that happens to include the original panel so you can see it either way you want.
Rym: and Yeah, otherwise, we are.
Rym: we're gonna review an anime that I am confident.
Rym: None of you have seen on Wednesday so stay tuned for that but for right now I leave you with.