Rym: It's Tuesday, November 17th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We are reviewing Ricochet, a Half-Life mod from the year 2000.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, as you know, Joe Biden did, in fact, win the presidency.
Rym: Like, we crossed that bridge.
Rym: But we still have to win that Senate race or we can't really do anything in this country until the year 2022 because of how messed up our government structure is.
Rym: So, because of weird nonsense, there are two Senate races that are deferred until January that literally determine which of the two American parties control our entire government, effectively.
Rym: So, unrelated to that, as many of you know, I don't open loot boxes in Overwatch, like, ever.
Rym: Mostly because it annoys many of you that I don't open them.
Rym: Like, every time I stream Overwatch, at least a couple people bother me about it.
Rym: Like, that number bothers them, that seeing that, like, unopened number just sitting there, 1,102, like, it just bothers them to them.
Scott: The loot box number doesn't bother me, but I am bothered, actually, when I look at other people's phones and I see all these red dots of, like, notifications that are unread and shit.
Scott: Oh, that bothers me, too.
Scott: It's like, if you're not gonna read your notifications or clear them or read all your email, just disable the notifications.
Rym: It's like, you know, if you don't want to read it, turn it off.
Rym: Way, way, way more than that is when I see a screenshot of someone's phone with, like, 1% battery left.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, why are you not, like, what are you doing?
Scott: that your phone isn't plugged in, like, that long?
Scott: I don't understand.
Rym: But, basically, I did a thing where I donated a dollar for every unopened loot box I had to Stacey Abrams' Fair Fight and then I played Overwatch with a bunch of our friends, listeners and friends, until we raised an equivalent donation of the number of loot boxes to Fair Fight and the deal was... So, reverse matching?
Rym: Yup, reverse matching.
Rym: If the listener matched however many loot boxes I had and how much I had donated, then I would just stop playing Overwatch and open all the loot boxes on stream.
Scott: We went way over the goal.
Scott: So, basically, you would play Overwatch until people paid enough money.
Rym: That was the goal, but people donated real quick.
Scott: But if you had to play Overwatch, if people weren't donating and you had to play Overwatch, you might still be playing now.
Rym: Yeah, well, the thing is, it was play Overwatch until people donated enough money to match my loot boxes.
Rym: Right, if people didn't donate, you would still be playing Overwatch.
Rym: I would have donated twice as much myself, so I could stop playing.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: I probably would have done that at some point.
Rym: But the listener actually went way beyond the target.
Rym: So, I ended up also matching any donations anyone made above my original match.
Scott: So, then you had a reverse-reverse match.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So, with all that combined, we raised a grand total of $4,006 for the Georgia Senate race.
Rym: Which, that's actually, that's real money.
Rym: That's enough money that could make a serious difference.
Rym: And I want to point out...
Scott: You could have bought a computer for somebody instead.
Scott: Two computers.
Rym: Yeah, but instead, this is not donating to their campaigns in Georgia.
Rym: There's plenty of people funding, like, rich people can fund the people actually running.
Rym: This is going to an org that focuses almost entirely on voting access and anti-voter suppression.
Rym: Which is way more important than any particular race.
Scott: That should also have effects on other races in the future.
Rym: But it just so happens that fighting voter suppression in America automatically helps Democrats in all cases.
Rym: For some magical reason that you can figure out if you read, like, a paragraph of any history book.
Rym: So, yeah, that rhyme is done.
Rym: Thank you all.
Rym: A few people donated a lot of money, and I really thank you for that.
Scott: People who have a lot of money donate more money.
Rym: A lot of people donated, like, 5 bucks, 10 bucks.
Rym: That's also totally cool.
Rym: Like, give what you can.
Rym: If you're poor, don't donate thousands of dollars to political campaigns.
Scott: No, if you don't have any, don't give any.
Scott: Like I say, even if there's a good reason, giving money to this is better than giving money to Rym's Patreon or whatever.
Scott: But if you got no money, even this, you should not be.
Scott: Yeah, no matter how good it is to give them money, it's like, you got nothing, bro.
Scott: Don't.
Scott: It's for you.
Scott: You need it.
Rym: But the thing I want to mention, really, about this is that it turns out it takes a long fucking time to open that many loot boxes.
Scott: Good.
Rym: God, did the stream take, like, five hours.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: At one point, I just balanced a Blades in the Dark book on the space bar and walked away, opening all my basic-ass loot boxes.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, we're going to actually talk about Hearthstone today and the news for the first time in a very long time.
Scott: But I remember back in the day, it's like the streamers would buy Hearthstone packs when new sets came out, and they'd buy hundreds of packs to sort of guarantee getting all the cards because they needed them all.
Scott: And even though they were, like, very tight with Blizzard, right, you know, to varying degrees, they still had to hold the space bar and open all the packs, and it took them forever, and some people would watch those streams because it would be like, you know, "Oh, you got a golden card!
Scott: Wow!".
Scott: You know, that kind of moment, but I guess, did you have any of those moments?
Scott: Like, wow, the ultra, ultra rare Amazing Skin came out of the loot box.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: The only moments I had, because the thing I do in Overwatch, there's, you know, you get voice lines and bind them to keys so your character can, like, basically play a wave file at everyone.
Scott: Circle around back, basically?
Rym: Yeah, and there's a lot of them.
Scott: So, what I did for-- Until now, you've only had the standard ones.
Rym: Oh, no, because I, so that 1100 loot boxes, I actually opened all the loot boxes I got for, like, the first six months that Overwatch was out, a little bit longer.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: I only stopped opening them one day when someone got annoyed that I had a bunch of unopened ones.
Rym: And I was like, "You know what?
Rym: I'm never opening them
Rym: again.".
Scott: Oh, okay, so you opened them at the same time.
Rym: I opened them for a while in the beginning, so I accrued over a thousand.
Rym: since that one listener was annoyed at me and I vowed to never open them again.
Scott: Yeah, that's easier than, you know, like, a Hearthstone pack is actually game affecting.
Rym: Yeah, these are 100% cosmetic.
Scott: These are 100% cosmetic.
Scott: It's like, you don't need any of those.
Rym: But, I got a few particularly annoying voice lines, because my only goal with those voice lines is to bind, for each character, the most annoying possible voice line to use at critical moments.
Rym: So, like, the Torbjorn, the little dwarfy guy, he has one where he's just like, "Hard work pays
Rym: off!"
Rym: And you can spam it to where he's just sitting there going, "Hard work!
Rym: Hard work!
Scott: Hard
Scott: work!".
Scott: Yeah, Rym's favorite thing, "Make annoying noises to bother other
Scott: people.".
Rym: Oh my god, there's one annoying one.
Rym: It's so long that I could actually spam it forever.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I look forward to using that in play.
Rym: So, speaking of Hearthstone, what's this news that everyone's mad about?
Scott: So, up until now, the way Hearthstone worked is that if you wanted cards or whatever, you had to fucking buy them, right?
Scott: And, when you played Hearthstone, you could get a certain amount of gold.
Scott: There was a certain amount of progression you could get by just playing Hearthstone, right?
Scott: A certain amount of gold you could earn.
Scott: I think if you got like three wins a day every day, and there's just a certain amount, and that was it.
Scott: You knew it wasn't very high.
Scott: You could play a ton of Hearthstone, and basically the amount of gold you could get was sort of capped, without spending real money.
Scott: But, you sort of knew what that amount was, and you knew how much you had to play to sort of get that amount that was coming to you.
Scott: So, they decided to change things up.
Scott: I don't know all the details of the new system, because it's been a few years since I played Hearthstone, and I'm very unlikely to play it again.
Scott: The coffin was already nailed shut.
Rym: The game is fun, but I cannot deal with collectible anything anymore.
Scott: The coffin on Hearthstone for me was sealed shut a few years ago, but this news is basically somebody coming into a dusty crypt, finding a nailed shut coffin.
Scott: That has not been opened, that no one has wanted to open, but it says on it, "Vampire inside do not open,".
Scott: and the guy goes, "Whoa, someone in the future might accidentally open this.
Scott: Let me weld it
Scott: shut.".
Scott: And that's what this news is.
Scott: So, what they're doing now is some sort of experience-based system, forgetting you reach certain goals during the season, week, whatever.
Scott: And also, when sets come out, they're releasing mini-sets and more cards over time.
Scott: I guess that's actually sort of a good idea, because it keeps things a little fresher instead of having a big card drop all at once and then sort of nothing for a long period.
Scott: It's like, "Here's a drop," and then a few weeks later, "Okay, here's some more.
Scott: Here's 20, 30 more cards," and then, "Okay, here's more," right?
Rym: There's pros and cons.
Rym: When I was a middle schooler with Magic, if there was a new Magic set every week, I would have been totally down for that.
Scott: That's sort of closer to one of the good parts about the living card games like the Netrunner, right?
Scott: More frequent changes to the game spice things up, right?
Scott: But the overall story here is that people, of course, dug deep and did the math on this, and it's like, "Yeah, if you are not spending money on Hearthstone with the current news system that is hard to understand, that I'm not going to invest much time in trying to understand it, it seems that it is most likely,".
Scott: they're not even 100% sure because it's such a mess, "it is most likely that you are, despite them saying that they would not decrease how much you could earn for free, it seems like, yeah, if you're not paying money, you're getting less cards and stuff for free.
Scott: And if you do pay money, it's probably going to cost you more to
Scott: play.".
Rym: This article goes into pretty good depth about exactly what's going on.
Rym: It has some preliminary numbers.
Rym: I guess what bothers me about this whole situation just generally is that half of what's going on with how this entire gold system works is just because of capitalism and they have to monetize this game somehow.
Rym: While also making it as addictive as possible.
Scott: And also, I think, as the popularity, it sort of mirrors what happens in a lot of nerdy-nish things.
Scott: We talk about this a lot in the comic book world, where it's like, "A nerdy thing has an audience large enough with enough money to keep it alive, but the audience is shrinking, so they need, instead of finding a way to expand the audience," from the people who are still playing Hearthstone, right?
Scott: The audience is smaller, let's squeeze more juice from the same fruit, right?
Scott: It just keeps bringing me back to that old idea of like, hey, just make an online card game, just like Magic Arena or Hearthstone, and just charge the flat subscription like, wow, and give everyone everything, and make frequent small updates to keep it fresh all the time.
Rym: The problem with that is that you can't make enough money with that model to actually keep a game going.
Scott: You could make enough money to keep the game going, you would just have a small dev team and just keep it going nice and easy.
Scott: Don't try to, you know, don't expect to be mega mega rich Blizzard style, right?
Scott: You wouldn't make enough money for it to be worth it for a Blizzard Activision level of company to keep it alive.
Scott: They'd be like, "What are the revenues on that?
Scott: Why are we keeping this thing around?
Scott: This isn't making any
Scott: money.".
Scott: But that amount of money, while being minuscule for them, would still be enough for like, a house full of devs and artists to make a living.
Rym: That all costs a lot.
Rym: And also, I think a lot of these types of monetization scams, I almost said scams because I kind of feel that way, they really prey on addictive behavior and variable reward schedules.
Rym: And I think the amount of money they extract from player bases, and I'm not saying that Hearthstone is specifically bad in this regard, this is an industry-wide problem.
Scott: I mean, it's bad, but it's actually one of the less evil, right?
Scott: And that's saying a lot.
Scott: That's how evil the other ones are.
Rym: But like, I am not really comfortable or cool with the variable reward schedules that are built into games to make them more engaging in this regard.
Scott: Especially when those variable reward schedules are related to money, right?
Scott: If you play an autochess-ish game, you're still enjoying that same luck.
Scott: variable reward schedule situation, because it's a random game, mostly.
Scott: But you are not paying money to spin the wheel.
Scott: You're just spinning the wheel like a free slot machine.
Scott: Don't put money in and money doesn't come out.
Scott: It's just points, you get points, and all you do, you don't put anything in, right?
Scott: Whereas a real slot machine into real casino, you put money in, and sure, money probably isn't going to come out over time, but it could.
Scott: It's a non-zero chance, and it's not rigged.
Scott: You could win the progressive jackpot.
Scott: And as a non-zero chance, it's like a one in a zillion chance, but it's a non-zero chance.
Rym: But there's also, there's this weird side problem of, I get the impression a lot of people who play games like this, and again, I'm not calling Hearthstone out here.
Rym: We just happen to be talking about Hearthstone.
Rym: It's better than other games in this regard, too.
Rym: I feel like there are a lot of people who, when they play these games, they're almost playing more for their completionist set-collecting model than for the game itself.
Rym: Because those are the people who care about this, "Well, I need X gold to get everything,".
Rym: and I wonder if my metric for if a game is ethical is, I don't know where the line is, but there's a line somewhere, what percentage of players without that variable reward meta system would not play the game at all?
Rym: Even if there's no money involved.
Scott: Who would not play without that automatic progression stuff?
Scott: Like I was saying, the Hearthstone and the other loot boxes of the world, you're putting money in like it's a real slot machine and nothing comes out.
Scott: And it's not even like an arcade game where you put a quarter and a Pac-Man.
Scott: It's even worse than that.
Rym: But I'm not really trying to get anything out of it other than the enjoyment of the activity.
Scott: But to your point, there are indeed people who play something like Hearthstone and it's like they probably log in and, you know, in the previous system at least where I think you had to get like three wins or something to get the gold each day or something.
Rym: They log in every day, they get the three wins, they stop playing.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: I think there were people who would do that versus the people who were playing it as an esport who would play it constantly in order to get better at it and improve and get their skills up and try to win the competitions and such.
Scott: But I think even those people would make sure to get three wins every day.
Rym: The problem is I think without this gold system, if there were not, like if Overwatch, Overwatch, if Hearthstone didn't have to be monetized to this degree and it was just the online digital card game, it would be crazy fun.
Rym: And I'd probably still be playing it.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: But I actually, I can't like keep, I just don't, I cannot engage with these loot box systems at all anymore.
Scott: I'm actually, you know, the Magic Arena has like drafting online, I think, which would be fun, I think, except it's not free, I don't think.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Scott: I said I don't think like 10 times, but I would love to play a game online where it was sort of like you actually do a real draft with other human beings and then play against them in like a tournament, right?
Scott: Sort of get that feeling I had.
Rym: That's a little bit like why Autochess captured us for a little while.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So in some other news of gamers mad about something, Twitch has also ticked off a whole bunch of, now this is not the DMCA thing, but it's actually more related to it than you might think.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: There's a music company, right?
Scott: It's like a record label, I think, called Music Something Cat.
Scott: What is it called?
Rym: Oh God.
Rym: It's buried somewhere in this article.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know the name of them.
Scott: I haven't heard of them before today.
Scott: Monster Cat.
Scott: So some record label or something called Monster Cat.
Scott: And Monster Cat made a deal with Twitch and the deal is, hey, you are a Twitch streamer.
Scott: You buy a Monster Cat subscription, right?
Scott: So you subscribe to Monster Cat's record label, service, whatever it is, and they're going to let you stream their music on Twitch and be safe, right?
Scott: And not have to worry about any copyright bullshit.
Scott: And it's like, oh, that's actually, you know, rather than have Twitch make the deal, right?
Scott: This is, first of all, Twitch should be the one paying the music license, not the streamer.
Scott: So they're basically shoveling off that cost, right, to the streamer.
Rym: The streamer paying would be a situation where there is a celebrity streamer with their own business around it.
Rym: Like, that's a very different world from the vast majority of Twitch streamers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But anyway, so you can pay Monster Cat and then you can stream their music in your stream.
Rym: It's only five bucks a month.
Scott: In addition to this, you will then also immediately achieve Twitch affiliate status.
Scott: So if people aren't aware, if you're a streamer on Twitch, you start out with no status.
Scott: So if you go to my Twitch channel, which has no status, basically I don't have any custom emotes.
Scott: You can't sub to me.
Scott: Like, you just can't.
Scott: You cannot subscribe to my Twitch channel.
Scott: You can't give me bits.
Scott: You can't do anything.
Scott: I cannot make money on Twitch.
Scott: I don't know if you see ads if you watch my channel.
Scott: You probably do.
Rym: It's a very different world from how YouTube monetization works.
Rym: They're, like, completely different.
Scott: If my stream gets popular enough, Twitch will then allow me to become a Twitch affiliate.
Scott: I think I'm pretty close to that.
Scott: Not that I would.
Rym: The bar's real low to get affiliate.
Scott: The only thing I don't have is average.
Rym: This fucking stream.
Rym: This YouTube stream is way above the requirements.
Rym: Like, just three nights live.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We're talking about my personal Twitch doesn't have five average viewers, right?
Scott: So, um, but yeah, even if I did reach that, I probably wouldn't take it because, like, I don't want it.
Scott: But that is what lets you, once you have that, it's like, okay, well now you can have subs.
Scott: Now you can take bits.
Scott: Now you get some custom emotes.
Scott: Now you get some stuff, right?
Scott: If you get really big, we're talking a whole bunch of other metrics, but the biggest metric, the hardest one to achieve is 75 average viewers.
Scott: That's average.
Scott: So, like, if you're, you know...
Rym: Average across, like, 12 different days and 50, like, 20 or 30 hours of streaming a month.
Scott: Right, so they take 12 whole days, right, worth of your stream, and they say where's the average viewership over this total thing, 75.
Scott: So that means when you start your stream and there's no one there and you wait for, like, people to see and come in, all those minutes of, like, 10 streamers, 20 streamers need to be counterbalanced by later minutes in your stream, which have 80, 100 viewers, right?
Scott: But anyway, so you need to have that, and then you apply, and if they approve you, you can become a Twitch partner.
Scott: And if you're a Twitch partner, then you can really make money on Twitch.
Scott: Like, you're not making big, big money relatively speaking to the world, but people live by being Twitch partners, right?
Scott: They can, like, quit their jobs and live in a low expense place.
Rym: Like, for a lot of people, being a Twitch partner is a big deal, but becoming an affiliate, not really a big deal.
Scott: No, but there are a lot of, if you look on Twitch, the vast majority of people with their Twitch streams, right, are struggling to reach even affiliate, right?
Scott: If you click on a game, think of a game that you like, I don't know, Smash Brothers, whatever, right?
Scott: Go to Twitch, click on Smash Brothers, and you'll see all the Smash Brothers streams, and at the top, you'll see a bunch of people who are Twitch partners, and then you'll see some people who are affiliates, like a few, and then you'll see a long, long list of people with 1, 0, 2, maybe, viewers, right?
Scott: A lot of people, and none of those people are even affiliate, they're all nothing, right?
Scott: And those people want to be affiliate, and here, you have a situation where you can pay money to a company that has a business relationship with Twitch, to instantly get affiliate status, even if you have no viewers, even if you signed up for Twitch yesterday.
Scott: And that's sorta shady, right?
Rym: Well, it's tricky, because on one hand, below that threshold, how much money could you actually even make?
Scott: Well, that's it.
Scott: The reason Twitch has this system is because, for them, how much money does Twitch make off of you if you're not bringing in the viewers, right?
Scott: They want to, A, both encourage people to, you know, try really hard to get more viewers, right?
Scott: So that they'll make more money, and they'll be able to make money, and then Twitch will make money off them because their stream is big enough and worth showing ads on.
Scott: But if somebody's stream is just so sad that no one ever watches it, you're actually costing Twitch money because you're not bringing in, you know, even if they let people sub to you, no one would sub to you.
Scott: You're just using their bandwidth for free.
Scott: So if you can't cut it, they actually want you to leave and stop streaming, which is why they have this bar.
Rym: There's actually a YouTube monetization problem a while back where people complained that YouTube wouldn't let them monetize their videos if they were too small.
Rym: But, like, yeah, if you have four viewers a month, no one wants to put an ad on a channel that has four people watching it.
Scott: Right, they actually want you to stop streaming, so they're purposefully discouraging you.
Rym: Or, at the very least, they don't want to pay you to stream.
Scott: Right, so this whole system exists to both encourage streamers to try to, you know, do what Twitch wants them to do, to control their behaviors.
Scott: And also here, again, it's like, okay, we'll let you make money off your Twitch stream and whatever, you're paying five bucks, so now we know we're getting money from you even if no one watches you, right?
Scott: Twitch is probably getting money from the record company.
Scott: in reverse, there's some kind of deal there.
Rym: It's interesting to me that people are so mad about this particular issue, because what you're paying for is Monstercat Gold.
Rym: That's what you're actually paying for.
Rym: The fact that Twitch lets you be an affiliate if you pay that money seems to be completely immaterial to anything except ego.
Rym: Because a lot of people are very small-time streamers who get that email, like, "Hey, you're a Twitch affiliate,".
Rym: like, they really frame it as leveling up.
Rym: And people really get excited about that and invested in that.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's like, look, you've been spending your whole life with no viewers watching big-time streamers subbing to them, and suddenly, alright, you have finally, after much difficulty and much time invested in streaming, guess what?
Scott: Now you can have people sub to you.
Scott: If you're living in the Twitch world, that's a huge deal to some kid who has no money and no job or whatever.
Rym: But at the same time, if you ignore that ego perception thing, the actual money that you could make is negligible at that level.
Scott: Maybe not negligible to some kid with no money and no job.
Rym: Yeah, but even below affiliate status, if you got any subs that could actually raise real money, you'd already be an affiliate.
Rym: You'd already get above that level naturally.
Rym: So it is interesting to me, like, the anger seems to be coming from the mass of streamers who are basically just running into all these problems because they're trying to make this a job, but honestly, this is not a viable job for 99.99% of all people who try to do it.
Scott: Yep, anyway.
Rym: And independently, Twitch is making a lot of moves like this recently.
Rym: We talked about the DMCA apocalypse that's happening over there.
Rym: I still suspect that Twitch as a business unit is in not great financial straits, but I do not have any evidence of that other than the behavior of Twitch in public over the last few months.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think that they're actually considering the business model of the 21st century of lose money, get a monopoly.
Scott: Once you've got a monopoly, you set the terms, right?
Scott: Twitch, I think, is definitely, in terms of streaming things online live for average people to just broadcast video to an audience and engage with them, is pretty much king.
Scott: No one else is really up there.
Scott: So they're closest to hitting that.
Scott: I guess YouTube streaming will never go anywhere, but it's not a thing, right?
Scott: So as long as it doesn't become a thing, and Facebook stream definitely isn't a thing.
Rym: Makes it die.
Rym: There's no more competition, so there's two players in this space, and that's that.
Scott: Right, so they're entering the phase slowly of continuing to leverage their monopoly position, at least in the parts of the world where Twitch is king.
Rym: Part of the reason why Twitch is getting so much flack for this is that YouTube, under Google, already went through a lot of these growing pains.
Rym: Like, YouTube does not monetize tiny channels.
Rym: YouTube has a lot of demonetization stuff that they did, and people freaked out about it, and now no one's talking about it anymore.
Scott: YouTube also pays music licensing.
Scott: If you put music in your YouTube thing, even with permission or whatever, YouTube pays the correct music licenses, and the money is sent to the songwriters and artists and whatever, appropriately, according to law, to the best of YouTube's ability.
Rym: Well, YouTube also has a DMCA counter-takedown system that Twitch refuses to implement.
Scott: Right, but the point is, Twitch doesn't do anything.
Scott: Twitch doesn't pay the money they're supposed to be paying.
Scott: And I think other services as well.
Scott: I think that, from what I'm aware of, possibly, the other things, I think if you make a TikTok with a song in it, that I think they actually are also paying appropriately.
Scott: You know, different services are paying and aren't, right?
Scott: And to different places they're paying as well, using different methods and different deals.
Scott: It's a messy world back there, but Twitch is not doing well in that world.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: I think it's partly that they, for whatever reason, like, YouTube built all this stuff around DMCA things, which actually gave them a lot of, like, a huge head start on avoiding the kinds of problems that Twitch is having now.
Rym: What was interesting to me is how the music industry went so hard so suddenly at Twitch.
Rym: I'd love to hear what conversations happened before that, if any.
Scott: Well, I think it really follows, you know, Amazon, right?
Scott: Amazon owns Twitch, right?
Scott: And it's really following the Amazon philosophy of that.
Scott: everything Amazon does is to the benefit of its customer, right?
Scott: And to the benefit of itself, and they always fuck over everyone else, right?
Scott: So Twitch really does things to favor Twitch viewers, and to favor, you know, Amazon and Twitch itself, and probably fuck over, right?
Scott: Streamers and, you know, partners, pretty much everyone else in the middle man area, right?
Scott: Twitch is not going to be friendly to.
Scott: Musicians getting their music played on Twitch, it's like Amazon's like,
Scott: "No."
Scott: Right?
Scott: The same way that Amazon.com itself, you know, hurts, you know, the sellers.
Rym: Well, remember all the fights between Sony's entertainment divisions and Sony's hardware divisions over the years?
Rym: Like, they basically, like, one of them could destroy the other one.
Rym: So, this is a space we'll just keep watching.
Rym: I feel like there's going to be a big story in this particular space every Tuesday episode for the foreseeable future, the way things are going.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Alright, one other news.
Rym: Kind of a big one, actually.
Rym: So, Star Wars, X-Wing, Legion, Armada, all that stuff is moving to, what, Marvel Crisis Protocol Studio?
Scott: Well, no.
Scott: So, it's not actually called Marvel Crisis Protocol.
Rym: Well, really, it's Atomic Mass Games, which is really Asmodee.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So, Asmodee, as a French board game company that's sort of becoming, like, the big, it is.
Scott: It's like the king of...
Rym: They're the second largest board game publisher in the world behind Hasbro.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All of the, you know, there used to be lots and lots of small to medium sized players in the nerd board game space.
Rym: Remember, Mayfair Games?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And a lot of those companies, we've done news on this, were basically absorbed, you know, bought out by Asmodee.
Rym: Z-Man, Plaid Hat, Philosophia, a whole bunch of German companies I've never heard of.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Pretty much every, like, games workshop, no, right?
Rym: Days of Wonder, Fantasy Flight.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, Fantasy Flight, we talked about that news when they got bought out, because Fantasy Flight... It was technically a merger.
Scott: Technically, kind of, right?
Scott: And what's been happening since then is, I think we last talked about it with Fantasy Flight's RPGs getting shut down, because not too many people actually bought and played those, really, right?
Scott: I think, like, I never heard of anyone actually playing them, and then when I brought it up, I think maybe one or two people were like, "Yeah, but...".
Rym: A few listeners came out of the woodwork and were like, "Oh yeah, they had some neat stuff going on, but they used special proprietary
Rym: dice.".
Scott: Yep, that's true.
Scott: Anyway, so, the news now is that, to my knowledge, the most profitable, highest revenue portion of Fantasy Flight's business was the miniatures business, right?
Scott: They had these X-Wing miniature, you know, they played X-Wing miniature games, you can even see that game on sale, like, everywhere.
Scott: Like, regular old Target, regular old Barnes and Noble, like, everywhere.
Scott: R.I.M.
Scott: even got some by accident for Amazon.
Rym: Yep, I still got them!
Rym: I saw them recently when I was cleaning out a closet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That is a, not only was that a very popular game, much more popular than people might realize, but it was also, it's a very high margin business.
Scott: You basically, you know, making these cheapo plastic minis that are already painted, and putting a few cards in a box, and charging an arm and a leg for them, and people out there who play this game are buying everything, right, that you put out.
Scott: And the margins are huge.
Scott: They made a lot of money on those miniatures, and now, Asmodee is basically like, "Yeah, you know what, we're gonna take all those Fantasy Flight people that are working on this game, goodbye, you're either fired, or you're gonna move over to this other company that we own, and this other company that we own is now gonna do all the development of those games, and the Fantasy Flight division isn't gonna do them
Scott: anymore.".
Scott: Sort of, you know, it's like, "Hey, you got your company that you work at got bought by a company that does a similar thing to you, and they took your work and gave it to someone else and let you go,
Scott: right?".
Scott: And so Fantasy Flight itself, I think, is, you know, clearly, slowly being dissolved, right?
Scott: I just like, what do they still do?
Scott: What games do they have left that Asmodee hasn't chopped up and given to some other, you know, or shut down, or given to someone else yet, right?
Scott: They're really tightening the strings on them.
Scott: I think they're already super tight, they're like as tight as can be.
Scott: And I'll be surprised if Fantasy Flight, I guess, continues to exist at all some years from now?
Rym: Yeah, because the brand Fantasy Flight, like the people who were like, "Oh, I'm a Fantasy Flight Games
Rym: fan."
Rym: Oh, they have the key, the key forage, whatever.
Rym: But that is an audience that is sort of niche and relatively siloed.
Rym: They're not niche, but they're like expanded market, relatively siloed.
Rym: I think it's pretty easy to pick that silo up and park it under a different brand name without losing people.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But yeah, there's so much.
Scott: Fantasy Flight is just like a big mess of stuff to discuss.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Every time we talk about Fantasy Flight, I feel like the correct response is to sigh a little bit and then start talking about them.
Rym: There's like so much good and so much just confusing nonsense that happens with them.
Scott: Right, but yeah, the strings were tightening from their owner, their new owner, and now they're extra tight.
Scott: And this is sort of like, "Oh, they got
Scott: broke.".
Scott: This is sort of like, "Wow, they're done
Scott: now.".
Scott: This is over the hill.
Scott: The rollercoaster has just now crested and is going down.
Rym: But think, we're now in a position where two companies publish the vast majority of all tabletop games on Earth.
Scott: Well, mass market tabletop games, right?
Rym: Mass market?
Rym: And I would argue the extended market is also covered by that.
Rym: Because in ASMO Day, that's a lot of extended market like euro games that have audiences in parts of Europe or among nerds that are packed.
Rym: But no one's going to buy that other Toys R Us.
Rym: Hasbro is edging into that space.
Scott: And people like us retreat into even more nerdier games, right?
Rym: Considering the 18XX game we're playing right now.
Scott: Exactly, right?
Scott: It's like, "Oh, well, I guess the whole world...".
Scott: We started out playing Catan just like everyone else in the year 2000.
Scott: And now Catan is in Toys R Us.
Scott: Yeah, so now I look at a Catan like the way I used to look at Monopoly.
Rym: Oh, what do we always say from that Jackbox reveal a long time ago?
Rym: "As I age, my predilections become increasingly
Rym: esoteric.".
Scott: Right, and it's like, "Well, now I'm playing some train
Scott: nonsense.".
Scott: It's like, "What are we going to play next?
Scott: Scratching out something on a piece of cartilage in the
Scott: back?".
Rym: What we've got is historical refereed wargames.
Rym: That's the end.
Rym: That's when you hit the bottom.
Scott: I don't know if that's the end.
Scott: I think there might be some new ends developed.
Rym: You know what's below refereed wargames?
Rym: Full immersion LARP wargames.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: That's historical reenactment.
Rym: You're going to grow a beard and put on a union uniform and carry a musket.
Rym: And that's what's going to happen.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah, that's a thing.
Rym: Yup, so really briefly, I think this is important news, but I'm not going to talk a lot about it because you should just go watch this.
Rym: But this year, this is relatively new.
Rym: The 2020 Video Game Accessibility Awards happened.
Rym: This is a very important thing.
Rym: AbleGamers is involved.
Rym: Alana Pierce.
Rym: And oh god, I forget the guy's name, but he's super cool.
Rym: I started following him on Twitter a while ago.
Rym: But basically, they did the live stream of the awards.
Rym: And this awards show was one of the best award shows I've ever watched because they actually spent time talking about not just like, "Oh, here are the winners," but why they won.
Scott: I know, right?
Rym: Imagine if the Oscars were like, "This movie won because of X, Y, and Z. This is best actor because of this
Rym: scene.".
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Scott: They can't do that.
Scott: You know why?
Rym: Because they don't fucking betray them.
Scott: Their system for selection is bullshit.
Scott: They can't explain why.
Scott: But here, the system for selection, the Eisner Awards could do that if they wanted to, but they like to, you know, not anyway.
Rym: Steve Spoon, that's his name.
Rym: But Alana and Steven, or Steve, did the stream.
Rym: It's like an hour and a half long.
Rym: This is really worth watching.
Rym: This is a space that does not get enough attention in games and game design.
Rym: Best practices are still only now starting to evolve and start to be accepted among the industry.
Scott: I do also think that if you're talking about game accessibility versus just like an Oscar award, which is more of a subjective thing.
Scott: It's like, you know, best actor or whatever.
Scott: Whereas if you're measuring how accessible a game is, obviously it's not 100% objective.
Rym: But there's a rubric to follow.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It's more like rubric scored Olympic events.
Scott: I think it's even more objective than that a little bit, right?
Rym: Well, here's an example.
Rym: The categories they had this year were things like house rules.
Rym: Games that support house rules that themselves allow accessibility to be crafted by players because they make a good point about how no game can be called accessible.
Rym: You can't say a game's accessible because there's such a long tail of very specific accessibility needs that might come down to one individual person with a specific problem.
Rym: So Among Us won that because the customizability of Among Us adds a huge amount of accessibility to that game.
Scott: If you've got someone with way bad reflexes and they have to use a really crummy input device because that's the best they can use.
Scott: I always remember this one dude at RIT who was in the CS labs and the only part of his body could move reliably.
Scott: I don't know exactly what the person's illness was, but basically they would poke the keyboard with basically a long pencil attached to their head.
Scott: And they were getting along just fine, but they weren't using their arms or legs.
Scott: And it's like if that person wanted to play Among Us, you could.
Scott: You would just make everyone have to move real slow and then everyone would basically be in the same situation.
Scott: You wouldn't, you know, because obviously there can't be too dexterous with that.
Scott: This is limits.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So Scott's made a big deal about pointedly doing things of the day that are not in the theme of the geek knight's knights.
Scott: Also, it's a fun thing to basically say, "Well, I couldn't find a thing of the day that's related to today, so I'll just try to make it seem like this is a
Scott: positive.".
Rym: Yeah, I do it because I have a long backlog of things of the day that if we went by geek knights' knights are really only Thursdays.
Rym: There's nowhere else to put those.
Rym: But I went down this road because this is a video I'd seen before, but I saw it again because someone uploaded it to YouTube.
Rym: And it's both incredibly banal and mundane and incredibly terrifying when you really think about what this is.
Rym: This is a training video and it's basically a... Imagine someone live streaming what it's like to launch a nuclear missile.
Rym: The actual for real procedure from start to finish, from someone calls you while you're sitting on your chair fucking around playing a game on your Switch because there's nothing to do in that job.
Rym: You're about to nuke people.
Rym: And it takes about 4 minutes and 32 seconds to launch a nuke.
Scott: Does it show the part where the people are winking at each other and not actually doing it and then saying they did it and it's not working?
Rym: I realize they're not allowed to face each other.
Rym: And in fact, for Minutemen, which are the more recent... Older missiles work differently.
Rym: But the Minuteman, which is the one that's kind of how things go today with a few minor differences, but not many as far as I know.
Rym: They can't see each other and they're actually strapped into chairs facing away from each other partly by design to avoid that possible problem.
Scott: Okay, good.
Scott: Then he can't see me when I'm... I don't know if the other guy's doing it or not, but I can say, "Oh yeah, I did it.
Scott: It's not working.
Scott: Oh
Scott: no.".
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, I'm not going to get into whether or not Scott's strategies work or not, but I encourage you to watch this video because One, it's a very good example of analog or non-computer workflows, like process design and workflow design, and how to make a very complex workflow able to be enacted under extreme circumstances.
Rym: Like, you know when you watch a construction site and someone blows the air horn and people are yelling back and forth at each other?
Rym: There's a reason for that.
Rym: And this is just a very... Like, the military of the United States, if you ignore the terrifying problems of the military industrial complex, something that the US military has been extremely good about for a very long time is user experience design and process design in the real world, not just on a screen.
Rym: And this is a very good example of that, but it's also terrifying how this extremely mundane and easy to follow set of steps leads to the deaths of millions.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: Alright, so a much better thing of the day than that does not involve horror.
Scott: So there is an anime that was actually... It started out as a little flash anime.
Scott: I don't know, because it's one of those things that only Japanese people know about, right?
Scott: It hasn't really spread around the world as much.
Scott: I imagine it's more of a Homestar Runner kind of category, or a Mad Magazine kind of area thing.
Scott: That's the gist I get from what I've read about it.
Scott: Because I've heard about it before, but not too often.
Scott: It's this thing called Eagle Talon.
Scott: And Eagle Talon is basically about... It's sort of like a reverse superhero thing, where it's like this group of villains is the main characters, and the hero good person is like a bully and a jerk, and it's definitely mostly a humorous kind of thing.
Scott: People in Japan, they all know it, right?
Scott: Even though anime fans at an anime con in, say, the US probably would never have heard of it.
Scott: And so Eagle Talon got hired once by a Shimane prefecture to do some PR work, right?
Scott: Because in Japan you're always doing mascots for trains and police stations and that sort of thing, right?
Scott: So what they did is they printed t-shirts, right?
Scott: Because this is a group of humorous people making short little animes, right?
Scott: And they made a t-shirt that said, "The Shimane prefecture is to the left of the Tottori
Scott: prefecture.".
Scott: So the people at the prefecture were like, "What the
Scott: hell?".
Scott: But it turns out that that was really popular, and it even got in the news because it was so funny and clever, right?
Scott: So what actually happened is Eagle Talon, with their skills of humor, got so good at marketing, what they started a tradition, I think it says it started in 2011, so it's a nine-year-old tradition already, is that every year the Eagle Talon staff would produce a Shimane prefecture calendar, and it's basically a funny... The Eagle Talon Shimane self-deprecating calendar, and it's basically a funny calendar that you could buy, and it would make money for the prefecture, I guess, I don't know.
Scott: And it was just sort of a funny tradition that's been going on for almost a decade, right?
Scott: Kind of nice, kind of humorous, very good.
Scott: They recently did a different thing.
Scott: This year, they said, "All
Scott: right.".
Scott: It started as a joke and then it became real, as things do, right?
Scott: And they said, "If anyone buys a thousand calendars, we will make a three-minute anime of
Scott: you.".
Scott: So the people who make Eagle Talon will make a you anime, so if Rym bought a thousand calendars, then Eagle Talon crew would make a Rym anime that was three minutes long.
Scott: And this married couple bought a thousand calendars, and they had these huge cardboard boxes stacking up in there.
Rym: That is big.
Rym: "bought the Home Depot's skeleton" energy right there.
Scott: It cost 1.2 million yen, which is still a lot of money.
Scott: How many is that?
Scott: Let's see, 1.2 million yen.
Rym: I feel like that would be worth it.
Scott: It's about $12,000, right?
Rym: I feel like that might be worth it.
Scott: Divide by a thousand.
Rym: A little less than
Rym: $12,000. $12,000
Rym: for three minutes of anime?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah, the husband says he loves Eagle Talon.
Scott: My wife saw the news that 11,000 calendars, and she thought it was a pretty fair deal if it gets you your own anime made.
Scott: The wife said with a grin, "I'm looking forward to this becoming a joke.
Scott: I can brag about saying that I
Scott: did.".
Scott: So I kind of want to see this three-minute anime this way.
Rym: Oh, 100%.
Rym: We've got to review this on GeekNights.
Scott: All right, so this is really awesome, and I hope that more awesome things of this nature occur, and I found out about them.
Rym: All right, in the meta moment, we have a new code of conduct.
Rym: You can read it.
Rym: It's pretty chill.
Rym: We've only banned one person since we made it go live, so everyone's pretty cool in the GeekNights community.
Rym: Maybe I read one more page of The Tale of Genji, but I have not gotten yet to a page I have not already read.
Scott: Well, I didn't get a message from you saying that you were reading.
Rym: Because I did not get past where I stopped.
Scott: Ah, I see.
Rym: I'm still rereading to remember what was going on.
Scott: I see, but you read a page?
Rym: I read a page, but it didn't take as long to poop as I expected, so I only read that one.
Rym: Well, one real page.
Rym: It was like three pages on my phone, but it was like one real page.
Scott: All right, maybe I'll read so I can send you the message.
Scott: Uh-oh.
Rym: It's gonna be a really slow race.
Rym: It's a game of chicken here.
Rym: Otherwise, like, we're still stuck at home.
Rym: I don't know what we could say.
Rym: We don't have any cons coming up.
Rym: There was just breaking news about MAGFest Online, and now there's gonna be a VR component of it.
Rym: We'll talk about that on the next Tuesday show.
Scott: The only other thing is I can tell you that for the rest of this year, I only have 1, 2, 3, 8... 3, 8, 13-ish... Not too many days left of work, right?
Scott: 1, 2, 3, 5, 8... Maybe, like, less than 15 days left of work this year, and then I do not have to work anymore.
Scott: And also, next week, I do not have to work at all.
Scott: So, obviously, I'm not gonna enter into the shit-talk territory and say all these great things I'm going to accomplish.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I'm not talking about anything except the Utena thing, because I have been making slow progress on pre-production for the next Utena episode.
Scott: However, I can safely say this.
Scott: The odds of me accomplishing something and uploading some sort of work to the internet for you to enjoy... ...are greatly increased between basically now, effectively, or at least this weekend, Saturday, right?
Scott: And January 4th, 2021, being the last day... The first day I have to go back to work, I guess?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, in that time span, you can keep an eye on the Scott channels, and you might see... There's a chance you could see a lot.
Scott: Who knows, right?
Scott: I wouldn't bet on that, but I would bet on seeing more than zero.
Scott: If you said, "Scott, are you going to do more than
Scott: zero?"
Scott: I will say, "Yes, I'll put money on
Scott: that.".
Scott: Are you going to do a lot?
Scott: Not putting money on it, but it's possible.
Scott: Maybe I could get in a run, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Those eight hours a day.
Scott: I can tell you, though, that I realized... I haven't talked about it too much on GeekNights itself, but I'm biking to nowhere lately, right?
Scott: Yep, like you do.
Scott: I can't go outside, right?
Scott: And I've been streaming my biking to nowhere on Twitch to not enough people to reach affiliate status.
Scott: I think if I reached affiliate status, I still would say, "No, I don't want
Scott: it.".
Scott: But I realized that I'm not walking.
Scott: I sort of had this realization.
Scott: I'm basically spending all of my time sitting or laying because I'm not going outside or even leaving the apartment.
Scott: So I realized, huh, maybe I should bike on the easiest mode every single day, no matter what, even if I'm not going to bike on the hard mode just to move my legs every day.
Scott: And if I'm not working for eight hours a day, there's at least an hour in there, right?
Scott: So expect to see at least more of me biking to nowhere on Twitch.
Scott: It's really just come and talk to me so I can do something besides move my legs and stare at the window.
Scott: So you can come talk to me.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: Just don't break the code of conduct or I'll just ban you with my phone.
Rym: All right, let's get right into it.
Rym: So in an Asian past, a game came out called Half-Life.
Rym: You could get it on a CD and there was a key on that CD that you had to type in when you installed the game.
Rym: The CD was just the game.
Rym: The key made the game work.
Rym: If you had a copy of the game and you had a valid CD key, one thing you could do is play Half-Life Deathmatch online and Half-Life had a way to make mods.
Rym: Valve, the company that made this game called Half-Life, had a modding system and they actually made their own mod for Half-Life that they released on November 1st, 2000, more than 20 years ago.
Scott: There were actually quite a few official mods they made or acquired, right?
Scott: People don't realize Counter-Strike was made by someone else.
Scott: Valve bought Counter-Strike.
Rym: Yup, I was playing Counter-Strike before.
Rym: it was an official mod.
Scott: I don't know who made Day of Defeat, if that was internal or not.
Rym: So on November 1st, 2000, one of these official mods was released called Ricochet.
Rym: We were obsessed with it.
Scott: So the thing with Ricochet is we didn't even realize it existed.
Scott: Before Steam, when you wanted to play Valve games online, there was a thing called WAN, the World Opponent Network, that you used instead of Steam, and that handled the server listings of how to find a Counter-Strike server.
Scott: The day Steam went live in 2003, we were in Colony at RIT, September 12th, 2003, 17 years ago.
Scott: The day Steam went live is also the day I made a Steam account.
Rym: Because Steam did one thing.
Rym: It updated Counter-Strike.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Steam did not let you buy games.
Scott: It was not a store at that time.
Scott: It was a system to replace WAN to help you find servers to play games on, to launch games, and to update those games, keep them updated, because the system before then was when there's a Counter-Strike update, you have to go to a website and download files and run them.
Scott: It was a pain in the ass.
Rym: But basically you had to type your CD key into Steam for Steam to work.
Rym: And you needed a CD key to play Half-Life, or to play Counter-Strike, or any mod.
Scott: There were no other games on Steam yet, right?
Scott: So I installed Steam, the original version of Steam, and I typed in my Half-Life 1 CD key, and appeared in.
Scott: Steam were not only Half-Life, but also Half-Life Deathmatch, Day of Defeat, and some other things, and Ricochet was there.
Scott: And that's when I discovered the existence of Ricochet in 2003, because I could just right-click and install it for free.
Scott: But today, apparently, if you want Ricochet, it's on Steam, it totally works, or else we wouldn't be talking about it.
Scott: They want to charge you five bucks.
Scott: Which, eh, might be worth it.
Scott: I guess you could technically pay five bucks for a Ricochet only and not even have Half-Life 1 now.
Rym: Can you?
Rym: I didn't actually look at Steam to see if that would work, because this is...
Scott: Yeah, I think it's its own game, right?
Scott: It's its own game.
Rym: I guess it comes with Half-Life 1.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: If you buy Half-Life 1 on Steam, I don't know if you get Ricochet.
Rym: What I don't know either, can I, with my Steam Half-Life 1, which I also own, could I just install the Ricochet mod directly?
Scott: That's a good question.
Scott: The point is, it still exists, and we still have our legacy copies that were grandfathered in from the original Day of Steam, right?
Scott: And having those Half-Life 1 CD keys means that I have Half-Life 1 on Steam as a game, right?
Scott: It's just that copy from 1990-whatever that I had a CD for.
Scott: It's just been grandfathered all the way right up to 2020.
Rym: I used a pirated CD key at the time, and it totally worked.
Scott: Oh, my CD key was not necessarily pirated, but some kid in high school gave me a CD-R copy of his actual CD, and he wrote his CD key on a piece of paper, and that's what I've been using this whole time.
Rym: Yep, I had a similar situation, because a lot of people-- I never bought Half-Life 1.
Scott: I didn't pay 50 bucks for it.
Rym: Because remember, back then, most people did not play games online.
Rym: So, the CD key, most people didn't need it after they got Half-Life working on their computer.
Rym: The CD key only became a problem if I used someone else's CD key to register a game online, and then someone else tried to do it, and Steam said, "No, that was already
Rym: done.".
Scott: No, it actually didn't, because you could reinstall the game with your same CD key over and over, right?
Scott: It couldn't tell if you had just moved.
Rym: Oh, that's true, but I'm saying if you tried-- You didn't have an account associated with the key or anything.
Rym: If you tried to register it with Steam on a different account, I remember there was a problem.
Scott: Once we had accounts, before then there weren't accounts, so the key was just the key, and as soon as I obviously typed that key into Steam before that other kid did.
Rym: Yep, same.
Rym: So, in RIT, we noticed this, and we're like, "Oh, Ricochet, what's that?
Rym: Let's play
Rym: it.".
Rym: And we played it, and we got kind of obsessed with it, and we played it a lot.
Scott: So, Ricochet, we did actually do an episode about this before, but we Googled, we searched our own database to try to find that episode, and I couldn't find it.
Scott: And then a good listener, Naito, was like, "Aha, I found
Scott: it!".
Scott: Apparently the episode was titled "Tron Games, Games of Tron," because we also talked about Disks of Tron, and GL Tron, Tron Bikes, right?
Scott: All the other games of Tron.
Scott: Because Ricochet basically is an unlicensed Disks of Tron FPS.
Scott: I don't know why there's never been an official one, it makes no sense.
Scott: I don't know why there isn't one in VR, it makes no sense.
Rym: Yeah, I want to just install the Unreal Engine, or even just Unity, and just make Ricochet 2.
Scott: Right, for whatever you want, I mean, you can probably go back to that episode on Games of Tron, I'm curious if I say the same thing in that episode, which is, by the way, I feel okay repeating that episode, because that episode is from like 2006, maybe?
Scott: It's like a super old episode.
Rym: Yeah, it was a long time ago.
Rym: In fact, it was from, no, 2009.
Scott: Oh, it's 2009, it's an 11-year-old episode.
Rym: Tuesday, August 8th, 2009, the news on this episode.
Rym: Tonight on Gig Nights, we honor the upcoming movie, Tron Legacy.
Scott: Which I rewatched recently.
Rym: By discussing various video games based on the world of Tron, so we did cover a ton of Tron games.
Rym: In the news, the slim PS3 is official, some MMO problem, and PAX is coming.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, I'm curious if I said this in that episode, which I haven't really listened to, but basically, for whatever else you want to say about Tron, you can talk about Tron for days, is that the games they portrayed in Tron the Movie are basically the greatest possible games.
Rym: They are legit good games.
Rym: I like playing versions of these games people have made.
Rym: I have my entire life.
Scott: I was playing the hell out of Snafu on the television.
Scott: For as good as they were at making movies, some game designer who worked on Tron the Movie came up with the Tron disc throwing game, the murder Hyli game, and the bike game.
Scott: Someone came up with those games as part of making a movie.
Scott: Those games did not exist before that movie.
Scott: And every one of those games is this genius, incredible game that is better than the majority of games that actually exist today, at least as far as competitive multiplayer games that couldn't exist in real life as sports exist and would require some sort of digital addition.
Rym: So before we actually review this game, what I will point out is that the only reason we're talking about it is recently, like last week, Scott just messaged me and he's like, "Hey, Ricochet is just on Steam.
Rym: I wonder if it'll just
Rym: work.".
Rym: And then a few minutes later, he messaged me and he's like, "It just works.
Rym: I'm in
Rym: Ricochet.".
Rym: It almost just works.
Scott: You have to adjust a few settings because there were some bugs with your mouse flipping out all over the place.
Rym: Mouse input to raw because this game is unchanged.
Scott: You go to the settings menu and it's like enable raw mouse input and then suddenly it works great.
Scott: And also you have to find a server that wasn't laggy.
Scott: I think the first server we... There were servers that were up.
Scott: No one was playing on them.
Rym: Dude, just before this, GeekNights, I logged in.
Rym: I just started Ricochet because I wanted to grab a screenshot.
Rym: And there were non-bots just playing on one of the servers, just regular human beings.
Scott: So it's not a completely dead game.
Scott: It's like there are ridiculously...
Rym: There are 11 servers in the browser right now that are all up and two of them have people in them.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there are not... There's like a very small handful of people in the world who kind of play... Like when I looked, when we played, there were zero people playing.
Scott: But there is people playing this.
Scott: You can get games of this going.
Rym: Well, we started playing with the listeners and then someone who wasn't one of us joined the game.
Scott: Yeah, it was like us and listeners playing and then suddenly player one joined and we were like, "Who is
Scott: that?".
Scott: And it wasn't anyone we were talking to.
Scott: So someone joined from nowhere.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: I imagine someone's just sitting there watching that browser just waiting for someone to join a Ricochet game.
Rym: That's their whole life.
Scott: So this game, which is 20 years old, right?
Scott: You said it came out in 2000?
Scott: Has more... Like if you try to play some other games online that have, you know, like, I don't know, Nidhogg.
Scott: Like when we tried to play Nidhogg online at its height, we would have trouble finding opponents.
Rym: When I played Nidhogg online a couple weeks after its height, when it was in the decline, it was at the point to where I fought one guy.
Rym: I beat him.
Rym: I fought someone else.
Rym: I beat them.
Rym: Then I fought the first person again.
Rym: Then the second person again.
Rym: There were only three people in the world playing Nidhogg.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So Ricochet, though, after 20 years, people are playing this game.
Scott: Not a lot.
Scott: But I would recommend if you're going to want to play it online, you find people to play with.
Scott: I also don't know if I'll pay five bucks.
Rym: There is a SuperPichu and the Ginkgoz Discord has posted a dedicated server for all of us.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So come to the Ginkgoz Discord and come play Ricochet with us.
Scott: So what's the deal with Ricochet?
Scott: Ricochet is a first person shooting competitive multiplayer game.
Rym: But with extreme minimalism.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It is.
Scott: I mean, it probably took Valve, right, 20 years ago.
Scott: Like not a long amount of time to slap this thing together.
Rym: The game design doctor, this could not be more than one page.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The hardest part about making a Half-Life 1 mod especially is the map.
Scott: And the maps are small and only have a few components and textures and they are repeated.
Rym: There are four maps and actually the fourth one I had never seen until this past weekend.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And what it is is it's basically Discs of Tron.
Scott: You are a Tron dude.
Scott: You can't even jump.
Scott: You have your controls are WASD to move, mouse to look around, and you can click to throw a disc.
Rym: Primary attack and secondary attack.
Rym: And while you can look around, you can only shoot straight forward like Doom style.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You can't crouch, right.
Scott: Your disc will, even if you're looking up at the sky, your disc will go straight at the same elevation at which you are standing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you're on a high up platform, it's going to shoot, you know, up there on that level.
Scott: If you're on a lower platform, it's going to shoot at that low level.
Scott: You can step on these arrows on the edge of the platforms and they will automatically bounce you.
Scott: You can't jump, they bounce you when you step on them.
Scott: And they are calibrated perfectly so that if you step on one, you're going to land on the platform you're heading towards.
Rym: As long as you don't touch any directional input.
Rym: We'll get back to that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you just use WASD, walk around, you'll go from platform to platform.
Scott: If you throw a disc while you're jumping, then it's unlikely to hit anyone because it's only people who are on that exact level.
Scott: Our people are also jumping and it's going to be really hard to hit anyone like that.
Rym: Yeah, but if you're good, you're good.
Rym: I've killed some people in midair.
Scott: The secondary attack, so the discs that you throw, right, if they hit someone, they don't kill them.
Scott: They just sort of nudge them and you're trying to nudge them off the platform so they die.
Scott: It's murder disc.
Scott: If you use the secondary attack, it uses all three of your discs.
Scott: So if you don't have three discs at the moment, you can't use it.
Scott: It throws a chainsaw blade that if it hits someone, decapitates them and they die instantly.
Scott: Yeah, so that's pretty good.
Scott: It's really good close up when you're not going to miss with that.
Scott: Because if you shoot it and miss, guess what?
Scott: You're out of discs.
Rym: So there's also little walls all around the map, but they're tiny.
Rym: Like they're just at the points where if you're standing on a platform, they will catch a disc and disc will bounce off of them.
Rym: You get two points per kill.
Scott: That's the ricocheting.
Rym: If you kill someone with a ricochet and you get three points for a kill if you kill someone with a two plus bounce ricochet.
Scott: Yeah, so that's where the name ricochet comes from, right?
Rym: That's where the skill is.
Rym: That's how you get good.
Scott: You want the disc to bounce off the wall and then hit somebody and knock them off the platform.
Scott: And it's like, not only do you have to calculate the angles like billiards of like, I throw the disc here, it's going to bounce off that, then bounce off that and then go there.
Scott: You also have to calculate, you look at someone and you don't want to shoot it where they are.
Scott: You want to shoot it where they're going to be.
Scott: Like in Space Invaders, right?
Scott: So you have to say, all right, well, there's Rym, he's moving, where's he going to be?
Scott: Throw a disc so it bounces twice and then is where Rym is going to be when he gets there.
Scott: That is ridiculous.
Scott: Like for such a tiny game, the skill to do that is the cap is so high.
Rym: Yeah, this is a dive kick situation.
Rym: There's so few mechanics and so little to engage with in this game.
Rym: Yet the skill barrier is immense.
Rym: You could practice this game for a long time and not be a god at it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And also just the awareness you need while playing to also dodge discs, right, is like this whole arena, but you can only see your FOV at once and discs are flying and bouncing and the other character is somewhere.
Scott: So you not only have to maintain the awareness of where you are, where your discs are going, what discs you have, if there's a power up in the middle that appears and gives you better discs occasionally.
Rym: There's like an ice shot, auto decapitator, a homing shot and a fast shot and a triple shot.
Scott: I think the homing shot is the ice shot or no, are they two different ones?
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: I don't think about it that much.
Scott: Anyway, the point is you got to maintain awareness of all these things.
Scott: with a very small FOV, right, and you could die at any moment.
Scott: So it's like this game as a game, like technologically.
Scott: does it hold up?
Scott: I mean, it still works.
Scott: It doesn't look great.
Scott: It looks like Half Life 1.
Rym: It looks janky as hell.
Scott: Yeah, but it still plays just fine.
Rym: It's a compelling game.
Rym: Like the game loop is compelling.
Rym: When we started playing again, we just kept playing for hours because it was super fun.
Scott: The game design is timeless and offers crap tons of replay value, right?
Scott: That's something that someone came up with.
Scott: I guess Tron the movie came out when I was born.
Scott: basically, right?
Scott: A game that someone thought of then is still an amazing game today, better than a lot of multiplayer competitive games you can get.
Scott: I think it's like maybe Rocket League is on this level again in terms of goodness, right?
Scott: Just based on the game alone, this is Rocket League level of goodness.
Rym: Now, part of what makes it so great is that it has a deathmatch mode where everyone is just in a map.
Rym: The map is for deathmatch.
Rym: Just free for all.
Scott: The deathmatch maps are big.
Scott: They have multiple tiers where you're going up and down to different levels of platforms.
Rym: The best map is the duel.
Rym: It'll just take all the players on however many people are in the server, divide them up into groups of two, and you all simultaneously on your own duel one other person for like a best of three or a best of five.
Scott: And then, once your match is done, you just watch other people.
Rym: Once all the matches are done, it rotates everyone like Swiss style.
Rym: Play again.
Scott: It's just like a round robin.
Scott: You get into one-on-one duels with everyone, and since the map for that is so small and so simple, even the Half-Life server can spawn several copies of the map all at once because it's such a tiny map.
Scott: You could spawn up like ten of those maps, it still wouldn't be as big as Dust 1 or whatever.
Rym: And it is such a game of concentration and bluffing and counter bluffing and anticipating your opponent and faking.
Rym: It's a really surprisingly intense experience for a mod of Half-Life from the year 2000.
Scott: And because the biggest thing is that this is not Counter-Strike, you click on a head and you got 'em.
Scott: You throw a disc, much more like another great game, Tribes 2.
Scott: You throw a disc.
Scott: The disc, you can see it moving.
Rym: Or Windjammers.
Scott: It's a lot more like Doom, where an imp throws a fireball at you.
Scott: You see it, you strafe to the left to dodge it.
Rym: But you strafe to the left, but they'd already thrown a disc in the other direction that bounced and is now headed for that position because they're good.
Scott: Right, they threw a disc, it's bouncing, then they threw a disc straight at you.
Scott: You dodge to the side and thus they control where you are moving.
Scott: And oh look, you've moved to where the first disc was going to be.
Scott: If I can't predict where a Rym is going to be, I can influence where a Rym is going to be to help my shot that I've already thrown previously.
Rym: Or maybe I see what Scott did, I'm bluffing and I turn around and threw a disc through one of those teleporters and I know it's going to come straight back into my face just as Scott comes to kill me.
Rym: But the thing, like, remember way back when we said you jump from these platforms and they're calibrated to take you to whatever platform they're pointed at, like that's fine.
Rym: If you move your WASD while you're in flight, you can control your flight.
Rym: 99% of the time.
Rym: if you do that you'll just die because you'll just fall off the map.
Scott: Right, if you touch an arrow with your feet and it goes bonk and you hear that bonk noise that indicates that it is now launching you through the air to the next platform.
Scott: You do not want to press any of the WASD keys because you will likely, if you touch any of them while you're in flight, will make you fall in the hole and die.
Rym: But this is where the skill caps start to come in and why this game's skill cap is so high.
Rym: Because if you are good, one thing you can do is bounce off of something but hold forward and land right back on the same bouncer.
Scott: Yep, it is technically possible that if you press the WASDs in the correct way with good manipulation, there's no jump button, you can guide yourself through the air and land in a place that is not the pit of death.
Rym: But a different platform.
Scott: Yes, not the platform you were normally supposed to go to.
Rym: It could be the same platform.
Scott: It could be, so you step on an arrow, it makes a bonk noise, your opponent sees where you were, they now think you're going to platform X, you actually land on platform Y, they threw discs that ricocheted over to platform X, they don't have discs right now.
Scott: You're on platform Y, looking at them, they're looking somewhere else.
Rym: That's subtle, different, the fact that you can with a high skill maneuver, it's not frame perfect, it's not that bad, but it requires a significant amount of practice and skill.
Rym: That opens up so many tactical possibilities, that alone probably quadruples the depth of this game if you actually try to get good at it.
Scott: You can even tell that the maps were arranged to allow this intentionally, at least I believe so.
Rym: I believe this too.
Scott: In the dual arena, there's the two central platforms with a little connector, if you go onto one and you just sort of naturally try to wrap yourself around off the jump to land on the other central platform instead of the outside platform, you sort of line up with the arrow on the destination platform.
Scott: It's measured so perfectly, and there's no way that that's just a coincidence, that performing this wraparound maneuver that feels like an accident of the game, the way that a rocket jump was an accident of Quake or whatever, lands you so perfectly on the other platform.
Scott: It's not like you're landing on the bare edge of it and managing to stay on with a trick or something like that, or a bomb jump in Zelda that you're jumping over a gap where it seems unintentional.
Scott: It feels intentional when you do it.
Rym: So what I would say, one, if you check your Steam library, there's decent odds.
Rym: you already own Ricochet, whether or not you even realize it.
Scott: If your Steam account is old, it is likely you have the game Ricochet.
Rym: And if you do, honestly, install it, turn on Raw Mouse, because otherwise it won't work, most likely, and then just play.
Rym: There's servers.
Rym: Come to our Discord and join the server.
Rym: It is worth playing this game.
Rym: For $0, this game is 100% worth playing.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if I would spend $5, not because the game itself is not $5 good.
Rym: Because it is $5 good, I'm gonna say that.
Scott: But will you actually be able to play it enough to make up your $5?
Rym: What I would recommend is come join the GeekNights Discord and maybe watch us playing, and decide if you want to join in on that fun or not.
Scott: How often are we actually gonna be playing Ricochet?
Scott: Like once in a while?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I could see myself playing this every few nights, but I don't know if I'll do that forever.
Rym: But it's gonna be a long, cold winter.
Rym: I'm gonna be playing a lot of online games, I think, during COVID times.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, like I said, I can't guarantee how productive I will be during these non-working periods.
Scott: But I can absolutely guarantee I'll be just playing some fucking video games.
Rym: So, if you are an aspiring game developer or designer, especially a designer, even if you don't own this game, buy it and play it, and really try to internalize how much it does with so little.
Scott: If you are working at a game studio that is making any kind of competitive multiplayer real-time game whatsoever, you should get your team together and play Ricochet for an afternoon or for an hour or something.
Rym: Like, if I was teaching game design in school, I would assign Ricochet to the class.
Scott: I would assign games of Tron.
Scott: I'd be like, "We're gonna split the class into three groups.
Scott: One group is gonna make Murder Hyli, one group is gonna make Ricochet, and one group is gonna make
Scott: bikes.".
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: And if you're interested, I'll link to the ancient episode we did on all those Tron games, and I wonder if we said anything different about Ricochet.
Rym: It'll be really funny if we said the exact same things.
Scott: Someone else go listen and tell us.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Green, Graham Finch, you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: So I yelled at the cab, "Yo holmes, smell ya
Rym: later!".
Rym: Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Parry, Chris Minkoff, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, just like a dude guy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Trevor Van Horl, and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: This is stuck in my head, so it can be stuck in your head too.
Rym: [Music].