Rym: It's Wednesday, November 25th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: Adventure Time, Distant Lands, Episode 2, Obsidian.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know, a consequence of these special post-ending Adventure Times coming out in this long format is we're kind of reviewing them like movies, even though they're really just long episodes.
Scott: I think we have to now, this is like the last one where we're gonna say we're gonna do a GeekNights episode about each one, I think.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Going forward, we should only do it about them if they're...
Rym: There's only gonna be four, at least officially so far.
Scott: Let's hold and see if that remains true.
Rym: I bet they keep making them because they seem to be popular and they're really good.
Scott: I don't feel like, you know, as much as we like it, we shouldn't dedicate a GeekNights episode to every single episode of another thing because that's instead its own podcast.
Scott: That's no longer, right?
Scott: We don't want Wednesday night to become so focused onto a single thing that so many of the episodes are about one thing.
Rym: Well, we should pick what anime we're gonna watch before the next Wednesday episode then.
Rym: I kind of want to watch Sleepy Princess in the Castle.
Scott: Is that available somewhere?
Rym: Oh yeah, I'll figure out where it's available because it looks really funny and people I trust have been saying that it's hilarious and not creepy.
Rym: So I actually have an obi-bit.
Rym: Something happened to me.
Scott: How did something happen to you in your house?
Rym: So a package came and it was a big package.
Rym: I wasn't expecting a package, like, in particular.
Rym: It was really big.
Scott: Is it another free monitor?
Rym: It was not, in fact, a bomb like last time.
Rym: So I opened it and it was my Valve Index.
Rym: It actually arrived way sooner than I expected.
Scott: Well, usually I think that happens a lot is when you are buying expensive things.
Scott: They tend to, like, include... This is so expensive, right?
Scott: They want to make sure it shows up, so they will just include the expensive, timely, you know, better shipping option.
Rym: It was in, like, this really fancy box layered in another fancy box.
Scott: Anytime I've ever ordered anything from Apple, any phone or iPad, it's always shown up immediately at the exact right time on the day that it was supposed to, right?
Scott: You know, the same kind of thing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now I'll say already, if someone... I'll geek bite this or review it on a Monday or Wednesday show or Tuesday show, but this is not a VR kit you should buy unless you are deep into VR.
Rym: This is literally the best consumer technology that exists.
Scott: It could be that you're just wealthy and you have a bunch of random stuff that you use a little bit each, but you don't care because you're a wealthy jerk.
Rym: Yeah, but if you're like that, just get the freaking Oculus for, like, 300 bucks instead.
Rym: Like, this won't work with the Oculus store.
Rym: This only works with Valve.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: You know those wealthy people, they got to measure their dicks, right?
Scott: And got to be like, "Oh, not only do I have... I have all these things that I barely use and I have the best of each one.
Scott: Look, I have the best pool table in the world that is used maybe once every two
Scott: years.".
Rym: No, because if you're wealthy, you don't get the index.
Rym: You know what you get?
Rym: You get installation VR.
Rym: This is the best consumer retail with an MSRP VR kit.
Rym: that's out there.
Rym: There is better VR.
Rym: There's a lot of better VR.
Rym: But that's the special VR you have to, like, buy directly with an invoice.
Rym: Get someone to install it.
Rym: Special sensors.
Scott: Yeah, I feel like getting software for that would be hard.
Scott: Usually that's the kind of setup you have in academia where you're developing software for it.
Scott: I don't think you're going to be like, "Buy a game on Steam and run it on
Scott: that.".
Rym: Some of those, yeah, you kind of can just do that.
Rym: Steam is actually really good at just seeing VR tech, even mixing and matching VR tech from different vendors.
Rym: And it kind of just works.
Scott: Pretty good job.
Rym: Yeah, like, surprisingly, that is not what I would expect from the same people who made the Steam controller.
Scott: So, like, you would be wearing an index face but then holding, like, the Oculus handle things?
Rym: In fact, the Valve Index sensors will work just fine with a Vive.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: They're even just better than the Vive sensors for a Vive.
Scott: So if you have a Vive and you don't want to spend all the money on an index, you could just upgrade your handles?
Rym: You could.
Rym: No, the sensors, not the handles.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: The sensors use laser tracking.
Rym: It's a different kind of tracking from Oculus.
Rym: It's just better in every way.
Rym: But yeah, it arrived.
Rym: And all I'll say about it now is that I've been so busy, it's been sitting there since two days ago, and I haven't even opened the box yet other than briefly to peek at it.
Rym: I haven't had time to, like, set this shit up at all.
Rym: But the hardware feels so good, and it solves so many, like, hardware UX problems of the cheaper headsets.
Rym: I'm pretty excited to use it.
Scott: So now, I hope so, considering the price and the fact that it's newer, that it would be better.
Rym: Part of the reason I got it was that I want to get rid of my Oculus hardware because of the whole looming Facebook crap.
Rym: So I got to do that soon because I can't even, like, reinstall some of my Oculus stuff without getting a Facebook account.
Rym: So, kind of locked in.
Scott: Is it, uh, is the the Index, I imagine, is not yet at the point where it's just a pair of sunglasses type device?
Rym: No, but it, uh, feels...
Scott: It's still a giant thing you put on your head?
Rym: Post-COVID, you got to try it.
Rym: Because I've used the Index before.
Rym: Like, not the one I own, but I've used a real Index before.
Rym: It fits real nice and is real comfortable.
Rym: Like, two or three times more comfortable than an Oculus Quest.
Rym: Or an Oculus Rift.
Rym: It's not...
Scott: I mean, you know, even if it weighs less than the old one, I still don't have a Henry Rollins neck here, so...
Rym: Yeah, it's not a problem.
Rym: But I will say, what you want, something that's basically just sunglasses, that is easily 15 to 20 years away.
Scott: All right, well, I'll wait 15, 20 years.
Scott: I'm not in a rush.
Rym: Yeah, there's some... You'll see.
Rym: You should play Superhot VR and see how you feel.
Scott: Okay, even if Superhot VR is so great...
Rym: It is not worth buying an Index 4 by itself.
Scott: It's how much money exactly, right?
Scott: I mean, I won't even buy a PS5 to play Spider-Man for $650.
Scott: I'm not paying $1,000 in who knows what dollars to play Superhot VR.
Rym: I am doing development and experimentation, so there's a reason why I have three VR headsets.
Rym: This is not just...
Scott: I think that VR is just in that realm, right?
Scott: Where it's like, if you are using it a lot, or you're developing on it...
Rym: Like 3D printing!
Scott: It's your number one thing.
Rym: Are you using 3D printing to do projects?
Rym: Or are you a 3D printing hobbyist, where 3D printing is itself your hobby?
Rym: Yeah, all by all means.
Scott: There are occasions where I would want a 3D printer, right?
Scott: For example, I kind of want to do some 3D printing to try to make... Because all of the choices for Raspberry Pi handhelds are not... Ah, yeah.
Scott: So I feel like, hey, the only thing I can't do... Because the electronic parts I have down.
Scott: I got everything I need for electronics set, right?
Scott: I could just buy a screen, buy a Raspberry Pi, buy some buttons, right?
Scott: And make the ideal Raspberry Pi handheld all on my own.
Scott: I just need a case for it, and I don't like any of the cases that are out there.
Scott: So I would have to make one with a 3D printer.
Scott: But I'm not going to buy a 3D printer for one project I have, and then it's going to sit there unused, right?
Scott: Occasionally, like what?
Scott: Once every couple years, if I break a piece on a Gundam model, I'll print one out.
Scott: It's like, that's not worth it.
Rym: That's why you got to have either a friend who has a 3D printer, or you just go to Shapeways and just like pay someone for a fancy, fancy printer.
Scott: Exactly, so VR is that same situation where, you know, if there really is, you know, like you got the Half-Life Alyx.
Scott: Don't want to play that?
Scott: Yeah, I do want to play that, right?
Scott: I played every other Half-Life game.
Scott: Of course I want to play the Half-Life game.
Scott: I don't... Thousand plus dollars want to play it though, so...
Rym: You know, you could borrow my Oculus Quest and just tether it to your PC.
Rym: It would just work.
Scott: Wouldn't I need to hook it up to my Facebook account?
Rym: Uh, we have a Facebook account linked to it that has not been deleted yet by Facebook.
Rym: That would probably just work.
Scott: Yeah, this is, you know, not worth the hassle, I think.
Rym: Yeah, you can...
Scott: I can live my life without...
Rym: In a life post-Covid, you can come over and use the fancy VR, because I can get three people going in this house right now with varying levels of quality.
Rym: Except I can't get a 3080.
Scott: Yeah, you'll get one eventually.
Scott: When 4080s come out, just get a 3080.
Scott: It's like, you know...
Rym: The 2080 is just such a piece of crap compared to the 3080 that... It's 3080 or nothing.
Scott: Right, but it's 4080... How is... How is 40... You know, 2080 versus 1080, I think, was... You know, I didn't look at the benchmarks.
Rym: It was a big leap in a lot of ways.
Rym: It was like the leap between the 980 and the 1080.
Scott: From 10 to 20?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Because I know 30 was way better than 20.
Scott: Didn't get the feeling that 20 was way better than 10.
Rym: No, 10 to 20 was not a big leap.
Rym: 9 to 10 was a big leap.
Scott: Right, so I'm saying 10 to 20 was not so big, 20 to 30 was.
Scott: So is 30 to 40 going to be a small or big leap?
Rym: I think it'll be a small leap.
Scott: If it is small, they're doing a TikTok situation, then get your 30s when the 40s come out.
Scott: Or whatever, you know.
Scott: I really want to know what they're going to do.
Rym: The thing is, they don't drop in price.
Rym: Video cards don't drop in price.
Rym: So my philosophy, scalpers and supply chain issues aside...
Scott: They do drop in price at some point.
Rym: Not really.
Rym: Not materially.
Rym: By the time the 1080 was cheap, 1080 is garbage.
Scott: At least for me, it's not going to be garbage.
Rym: Yeah, but my philosophy more is if I'm going to get a video card like that anyway, get it as early as possible to get the maximum use out of it during that cycle.
Scott: Think of it this way, right?
Scott: It's like if you've got a 4K screen and you want to play a game that's 60 FPS, right?
Scott: Nope.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: A 1080 can barely keep up with that.
Scott: Right, but I'm saying if you get a video card that can do 4K 60, right?
Scott: Like say a 3080, and you've got a 4K 60 screen, then you don't need 40, 80, 50, 80, 60, 80, 70, 80 until you get a screen that's better than 4K 60.
Rym: Or you're doing something like, you know what I can't do right now?
Rym: I can't drive the Index at full, because it runs at 144 and high resolution.
Rym: I can't outrun it at full off, right?
Rym: But also, even with my regular old Oculus, I can't stream VR while playing it, even with a 1080.
Rym: I run into serious performance issues.
Scott: Yeah, I think we feel like we've reached sort of like, not the end, but sort of a slowing down in terms of games demanding more from the GPU at the same frame rate and at the same resolution, right?
Scott: In terms of like, oh, we've got new features like shadowing this and, you know, shading that and all this stuff.
Rym: Overwatch runs fine in 4K 60, but Star Wars Squadrons, I had to dump it down to 1080 to get it to have a good frame rate.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Scott: But they've also got, you know, there's also, I think the time that that will change is when more things start using that real-time ray tracing stuff that they've added.
Rym: Or games get designed around the AI rendering stuff.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So anyway, in some animation anime news, real quick, Geek Byte, as you know, we reviewed Deca Dance recently.
Rym: Scott had finished it.
Rym: I now also finished it.
Rym: It's great.
Rym: Just go watch it.
Rym: It gave me exactly what I expected.
Rym: The same feels.
Rym: I got watching a show like Full Metal Alchemist back in the day.
Rym: Solid show.
Rym: Good stuff going on.
Rym: Satisfying ending, which actually is something that's better than Full Metal Alchemist was.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: Sick burn.
Rym: But it gave me like that level of feeling.
Rym: Like it was an anime where every episode, like right up to the end, I thought, wow, I want to watch the next episode right now.
Rym: But then as Scott warned me, I also thought, wow, that was the end of a normal anime and there are several episodes to go.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's exactly how that is.
Rym: You warned me and we hit the moment and I was like, okay, that was it.
Rym: That was what Scott was talking about.
Rym: What the fuck?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Episode nine feels like that would normally be the end of the show.
Scott: What are they going to do next to fund the next three episodes?
Rym: Sure enough.
Rym: They did.
Rym: They did stuff.
Rym: Decadence.
Rym: Watch it.
Rym: It's a good show.
Rym: We talked about it.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: I got also a tiny Geek Bite.
Scott: So I ordered the Wolfwalkers art book.
Scott: It's a coffee table book.
Scott: So, you know, unless you got a place to put it, don't buy it.
Rym: I look forward to visiting you post COVID so I can flip through this book.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This book is showing you, like, I don't know if there's anything in this book that's left out.
Scott: It feels like every single piece of, I guess, interesting to look at in any way.
Scott: Production artwork, right?
Scott: Is in this book somewhere.
Scott: Like, it's just like, is the whole storyboard in there?
Scott: I don't even freaking know.
Scott: It's like, there's just everything in there.
Scott: I don't know what they left out.
Scott: There's so much text explaining everything too.
Rym: It's like, that's the key.
Rym: That's what I really like an art book.
Scott: It's not just an art book.
Scott: This is like, this is basically like the complete behind the scenes commentary.
Scott: Like everything there is to know about this movie and how it was made is in this one book.
Scott: The most interesting thing, and this is probably boring because to animators or people who knew know about this, but this is a, an animation techniques that I knew all the parts of it existed, but I was not aware of this specific combination.
Scott: So, you know, the scene in Wolfwalkers or the scenes where they're following the wolf scent and it's sort of like the yellow.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Those were good scenes.
Rym: Very samurai Jack.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So specifically the one inside, uh, the scullery, right.
Scott: Where it's like, you know, going up the stairs, right.
Scott: Past the hallway, all that stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the way that was animated is they made the scullery right in 3d in CG on a computer.
Scott: And then they moved the camera around file, you know, first person view camera, right.
Scott: They moved it around the scullery and they had sort of like a yellow wavy line, right.
Scott: That was on the, on the screen there, right.
Scott: Representing where the wolf scent was sense were right.
Scott: That they were smelling.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: Uh, and then I guess I assume this is the, I don't know.
Scott: The movie was, must've been done on twos or threes or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But they print it out on paper, like dead trees.
Scott: The, the outlines of the, you know, the, the, the CG.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's, it's basically just like one color line, thin lines showing you, like, you know, like, you know, the walls, the, the floors, right.
Scott: All that stuff.
Scott: Just like the, the, like, if you were in like a counter-strike map and you said only draw, you know, the outlines of all the objects basically, right.
Scott: Of what you're seeing.
Scott: And then they took all those papers and they drew on the papers with pencil.
Scott: And then that is what's in the movie is the pencil.
Scott: Real actual pencil.
Rym: Ah, it's like, it's like a modern take on rotoscoping.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, it's not, it's not necessarily rotoscoping exactly, but it's like CG.
Scott: And then just to, and then you trace what you printed out of a printer with a pencil.
Scott: And that's how they made those, that, those, those cuts there.
Scott: And I thought I was like, whoa, that's sort of genius and awesome.
Scott: Uh, I liked that anyway.
Scott: Uh, so it was fascinating.
Scott: So if you love shit like that, get that book.
Rym: We'll get that book.
Rym: It's like 30 bucks.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's a big hardcover coffee till book.
Scott: It's next to my mouse guard art book.
Scott: Uh, okay.
Scott: What else we got in the news?
Scott: Tiny news, uh, Funimation streaming service, which, you know, competes with the C-roll and the Netflix and whatever.
Scott: Uh, they just got basically all the Gundams, not all the Gundams literally, but original Gundam, unicorn Gundam, Gundam seed, Gundam seed destiny.
Scott: Don't watch that.
Scott: Um, but yeah, if you want to watch some Gundams legally, uh, Funimation is the place.
Scott: Cause it was not necessarily easy to watch all of those legally.
Rym: You know, I'm really excited because I've actually been hankering to watch Gundam seed again.
Rym: It's actually my favorite non OAV Gundam.
Scott: Uh, non OAV Gundam, I don't know.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I mean, all the, all the like original Gundam, Gundam seed, Zeta, Gundam are all kind of, kind of equal as TV shows.
Scott: I guess those are the only TV, full TV series Gundams I've watched all of.
Scott: I know to stay away from double Zeta Gundam.
Rym: I got a couple episodes into unicorn before.
Rym: I just didn't care.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Unicorn's a little less than those.
Scott: Um, it's not, it's not double Zeta territory.
Scott: Uh, there is in slightly related news, uh, Right Stuff was putting out new HD Gundam seed, right?
Scott: Boores.
Scott: And what happened was is, you know how in Japan they'll put an anime on TV and then when they put it on DVD, they'll sort of fix it.
Scott: They just doing, they'll do it quickly to get it on TV quickly.
Scott: And then animation mistakes will get fixed before they put out DVD.
Rym: Remember Sailor Moon?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So apparently the Gundam seed HD remaster Boores that Right Stuff had, or I guess not HD.
Scott: They were HD, but they were from TV.
Scott: They were not the fixed, uh, you know, DVD release ones.
Scott: So apparently they're correcting that.
Scott: So I guess if you have shitty Gundam seed HD discs from Right Stuff, you can get newer better ones that are, have all the animation stuff fixed from, you know, for, I guess at no cost, I assume.
Scott: And going forward, I assume they're only going to send out, you know, good ones.
Scott: Um, they got the, they got the wrong materials and then they got the right material.
Rym: I mean, it feels like Gundam shows have had more problems with the, the putting something broken on the DVD than a lot of other properties for some reason.
Scott: No, I think it happens actually somewhat frequently.
Rym: But it might just be that Gundam fans notice and complain more and it makes more press.
Rym: I think that's true.
Scott: I think also it's only extreme anime nerds even pay attention to things like that or know about things like that.
Rym: Like how would a normal fan of a show even notice?
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: Uh, so yeah, and then that relates to the, the original news, right?
Scott: Cause the Right Stuff materials are sort of what's being used for some of the Funimation streams.
Scott: So a lot of the Funimation streams you're going to watch are just what is on the Right Stuff.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: So you might've seen the news a while ago.
Rym: I'm a huge fan of the Venture Brothers.
Rym: I think it is very important and very good animated television.
Rym: Like that show is fantastic.
Rym: Uh, it's evolved a lot over the years.
Rym: Like I could go on about it forever.
Rym: I'm not going to bother you with that.
Rym: Now the news was that it was canceled, which on one hand you might think, oh, that's a shame that shows been running for 17 years.
Rym: But on the other hand, you might think, wait, Venture Brothers was still running because it tends to take them a long time to make a season.
Rym: Like it's been running 17 years, but they've only done like what?
Scott: Seven seasons in a movie and the season in 17 years.
Scott: It's that old.
Rym: It's that old.
Rym: We were, it was already running for a while when we were at that one packs where all the universes were playing episodes from it, like in the theater.
Scott: 17 years is 2003.
Scott: We were still in college when it was a new show.
Scott: I don't remember it existing until like, you know, much later than that.
Rym: I didn't get into it until several seasons were already in.
Scott: And they've only had seven seasons in all that time.
Rym: But, uh, the first season hit or miss, like, it's not great to be honest, but it's like it like Adventure Time and other shows that evolved and evolved.
Rym: And, uh, it's made me cry.
Rym: Like it's a really fantastic show.
Rym: But getting canceled was kind of a big deal because the show, part of the reason why it takes so long to make it is that they are sort of perfectionist about it.
Rym: And they make sure that it's right.
Rym: Like it's always tight.
Rym: It's very well put together and they won't put out a season until they're done with it, which is, I thought it might be that they're just not, uh, you know, working ridiculous hours, right?
Rym: Everything I read, they're working.
Scott: We're not doing the South Park thing where they show up late at night and work nonstop to get the episode out.
Rym: It's more like they get the episode done and then they polish it for like 10 times the time they spent making it.
Scott: And they're only working eight hours a day.
Rym: Every day, polish, polish, polish, polish, polish.
Scott: And where are they getting the money for all this?
Scott: Uh, that's the problem.
Rym: You can't make money with a show like that.
Rym: So adult swim canceled it.
Rym: I can't imagine that adult swim has been making money on this show at any point in like the last five years.
Rym: But the show is a very large, very dedicated following and it's good TV.
Rym: There are serious, credible rumors that HBO, HBO max in particular is rumors, right?
Scott: It's not an official announcement here.
Rym: While it is not official, there have been statements, uh, talking about this exploration from HBO since like it's, it's credible and serious.
Rym: Like HBO max is talking to them about what it would take.
Scott: So if this rumor turns out to be false, the show is canceled.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: The show is canceled unless it's the canceling a new, is the canceling a new news.
Rym: That news was from not that long ago.
Rym: I just haven't talked like from September.
Scott: So did the show and it's, I guess you said the seven.
Rym: There is another season that is still in flight.
Rym: That is to come out.
Rym: If it gets canceled the next season, which will not resolve anything because it was not intended to be the last season will be.
Scott: That's what I was, that's what I was asking about.
Rym: It's like, yup.
Rym: So one more season would come out, which would be a shame because the last season ended on a really interesting note and also kind of a cliffhanger.
Rym: And the next season was setting up some really fun stuff that would probably take another 17 years to resolve.
Rym: But, uh, HBO max picking it up actually makes sense.
Rym: I mean, look at HBO max picked up adventure time.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, the pattern that I'm seeing these days is that Disney owns most of the world, right?
Scott: And then Netflix, they own some stuff and they're making some deals, but Netflix seems to really want to make its own IPs, right?
Scott: Mostly, um, you know, and then, you know, have those things succeed because then they get to keep all the monies.
Scott: They don't have to make licensing deals or pay anyone else.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like, just make as much original stuff as you can.
Scott: Maybe some of it will be so great.
Scott: No one can take it from you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You're just the master of everything.
Scott: And that's the Netflix realm.
Scott: Still keeping some deals that you have enough stuff that people would want to be your customer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, Apple sort of over there being like this dark horse hiding in the back.
Scott: And I think much like with everything else, no one's going to care about that stuff.
Scott: Um, you know, except for the few exclusive things that Apple gets, like a Wolfwalker situation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, does anyone care about literally anything else on Apple TV plus at all?
Scott: And then HBO max is sitting over there and HBO has their original stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they're going to keep making the original stuff that they make.
Scott: Um, you know, I guess what HBO is like Game of Thrones stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, they own that all the way.
Rym: But again, HBO max is making like the new adventure times that we're about to talk about.
Scott: Is they are also right.
Scott: They are going out and basically getting anything that Disney doesn't own.
Scott: Anything that's not nailed to the ground.
Scott: HBO max is like yoink, yoink, yoink.
Rym: Oh, actually no, that's subtly.
Rym: they're funding it.
Rym: But the production is still Cartoon Network and Frederator.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you know, anyway, you know, I'm just talking about getting stuff onto their via whatever means right to, to flesh out.
Scott: Cause if HBO max is literally nothing but the HBO original, you know, serial shows that they do.
Rym: That's a recipe for disaster.
Rym: That's how Showtime struggled.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Those are very huge popular shows.
Scott: You know, your games of thrones, you know, I guess Sopranos is like the one that sort of started all that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then going forward to Game of Thrones.
Scott: But there are enough of those.
Scott: So people will subscribe to HBO max, watch all of them if they're, even if they're the biggest fans of those things, and then they'll be done with HBO max.
Rym: I've been guilty of that kind of pattern before.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And even if HBO does come out with more shows like that, which they will, they don't do it in such a large like quantity.
Scott: the way that Netflix is right.
Scott: You know, Netflix is like new show, new show, new thing, new thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, and you know, some of their new things, they try to make a big deal, but it's like they still got, you know, how many seasons of dragon prince going on?
Scott: And it's like, it's like so quiet.
Scott: They're so quiet with the dragon prince, but there it is.
Rym: Even though that show is standout quality show, not enough people are talking about dragon prince.
Rym: Uh, but what's that?
Rym: So extra interesting.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Andy Forsell, who's basically the HBO max guy actually issued a statement saying we're working on it for real.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Uh, so I clicked on his Twitter cause I don't know a lot about him as a person
Scott: and I think
Rym: I am more fondly disposed toward HBO max now than I was before because the last thing he tweeted was bitching about how everyone wants giant phones anymore and he can't get a small phone.
Rym: And the thing he tweeted before that was I'm going to try to save adventure brothers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I have been feeling, you know, even before today, right.
Scott: That like, yeah, Netflix, I've watched a lot of stuff on Netflix recently, but I'm sort of running a little low on stuff to watch on Netflix and maybe it's time to cancel the Netflix sign up for HBO max for awhile and then switch back.
Rym: You know, of course Hilda is going to be on Netflix imminently season two.
Rym: That's one of the best animated shows I've seen in history.
Rym: You haven't, you didn't watch Hilda.
Scott: Why would I have, I don't watch things.
Rym: Do I watch Hilda?
Rym: It is one of the best things on Netflix.
Rym: I'm not kidding.
Rym: It is fantastic.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, venture brothers might get saved.
Rym: In some other news that's only tangentially related to Wednesday because comics can be covered by this depending, uh, there's a complicated structure around these publishing companies.
Rym: Like you might even know that, like know the parent company if you live in Europe, but in the U S you probably know them as their penguin or penguin random house.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's basically, uh, over time in the U S you know, book publishing companies have, you know, joined merged, right.
Scott: Bought, died.
Scott: And there was, I think I remember at one time hearing, I don't know, I can't remember it cause I, it's been so long since I had, I had a friend who isn't publishing and I haven't talked to them and who knows how long.
Scott: Um, but, uh, probably, I don't think they're even remember I exist.
Scott: It's so long.
Scott: So, but I remember people were talking, I think at one time I could be misremembering.
Scott: There was like a big five and now there's like a big three.
Scott: Are we down to a big two or big one?
Rym: Already we're talking about penguin random house.
Rym: I remember when penguin was its own thing.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: And basically the news is via com CBS, which is already, uh, has agreed to sell Simon and Schuster to penguin random house for actually small amount.
Rym: It's only 2 billion.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So here it is.
Scott: I figured it out.
Scott: So yeah, it was big five.
Scott: So as of 2019, right?
Scott: The big five were penguin random house, the biggest, like $3 billion, like over 3 billion, Hashet, right?
Scott: Almost $3 billion.
Scott: Harper Collins, one and a half billion.
Scott: So Harper Collins is already half less than half of penguin random house.
Scott: McMillan is about the same as Harper Collins.
Scott: Simon and Schuster was number five at less than a billion, 830 million.
Scott: So this turns the big five into the big four.
Scott: It puts penguin random house at over 4 billion, which is more than a billion ahead of second place, which is still Hashet.
Rym: Yeah, we need some antitrust.
Scott: So this turns the big five into the big one and the second tier three, right?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Whatever commentary we were going to have.
Rym: the second tweet in this thread actually says everything we need to say.
Rym: I'm just going to quote it.
Rym: New York times book.
Scott: The FTC should stop this.
Rym: Quote, the sale of the company will profoundly reshape the publishing industry, increasingly a winner.
Rym: take all business in which the largest companies compete for brand name authors and guaranteed bestsellers.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: The sale will lead to the loss of editorial and marketing positions, imprints, fewer outlets for new books.
Rym: This is kind of a catastrophe for the book publishing business.
Scott: Well, the real problem, and I forget who tweeted this, but it basically says everything, right?
Scott: Is like we are going to allow, you know, what is published, right?
Scott: If, you know, professionally published for money in the United States in English to be decided by a very small number of people, it's worse than that who are so not democratically elected people.
Scott: It is so much worse than that because that was already true, but it's even more true.
Rym: So Penguin Random House was actually big in the news today for some bad shit that's going down there.
Rym: The people who are now going to own all of this.
Rym: They are publishing Jordan Peterson, that piece of shit's book, and their staff are like freaking out, threatening to quit.
Rym: All the good people who work for Penguin Random House are talking about quitting because they're letting this Nazi guy publish his book.
Scott: Yeah, that sounds good.
Scott: I'd quit too.
Rym: I would quit if my company did something with Jordan Peterson.
Scott: Yeah, I know my company, you know, where is a music company, and I'm pretty sure that we don't sign anyone doing Nazi music, right?
Scott: I think there was like a discussion about that or something because I was like, yeah, if I was like, I would look, you know, people were tweeting, talking about it.
Scott: And I was like, yeah, if I found out that we did, I would raise a stink.
Scott: And if they didn't, you know, stop it, I'd leave and I didn't have to leave.
Rym: It's a bad situation and that is the company that is now going to own Simon & Schuster.
Rym: So, before we get into things of the day, someone pointed out in the stream that to try to get you to watch Hilda, you know what Hilda's got?
Rym: That rare quantity.
Rym: Remember how?
Rym: in Madoka, who is the best character in Madoka Magica?
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: There was a younger.
Rym: Scott would have said something very specific.
Rym: He would have said Madoka's mom.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, there you go.
Rym: So, basically, in Hilda, Hilda's mom is a Madoka mom situation, like to a T.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But anyway.
Scott: So, barely in the show and I don't remember them when I have to think.
Rym: But then has pivotal moments where you'll go, oh, that's a good mom.
Rym: That's an anime mom right there.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: So, I actually have an anime animation related thing.
Rym: This is a short animated film that is beautiful and creepy.
Rym: Animated by Shingo Tamagawa, who does a lot of work in anime.
Rym: It's just a short animated creepy film that is free to watch on YouTube.
Rym: And I think you should watch it.
Rym: The style reminds me a little bit of things like Oniyama's in terms of how the characters are drawn.
Rym: It's very simple, very creepy, very short.
Rym: But it's worth watching.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Here's the thing of the day.
Scott: It's a very Rym thing of the day.
Scott: So, the US Coast Guard, its largest ship that it has in its fleet, right, has several big electric engines in it that are many, many, many, many horsepower.
Scott: They are, as you would imagine, a boat engine.
Rym: Slapped aside, you can fit so many horses in this thing.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Like thousands of horses.
Scott: And you can read in the article more details, right, about that.
Scott: But they have to replace the engine.
Scott: So, they dock the boat and they cut a hole in the side of the ship.
Scott: And they're going to take one engine out and put the other one in.
Scott: But the thing is, they're publicly documenting all this.
Scott: None of it's like secret, right?
Scott: If you can, if you follow like a military warship.
Scott: No, if you follow the Coast Guard on like, you know, whatever their place you follow them is, Facebook, Instagram, I don't know, wherever they're documenting this.
Scott: I just read an article.
Scott: You can, they're giving out all the deets.
Scott: And the most fascinating thing is something that like, you know, because like a lot of the stuff is detailed, nerdy boat stuff that you can't really relate to, right.
Scott: But the thing I could really relate to so much was they put the boat into the dock, right?
Scott: Like the dry dock is not in the water anymore.
Scott: It's up on land in a big, you know, big hole in the ground, right?
Scott: That's boat shaped.
Scott: They had to put it in and put the boat as far to the right as they could.
Scott: To create room so that when they take the engine out of the side of the boat, they can lift it up, right.
Scott: And get it out of the hole.
Rym: I love hearing about those like very specific, practical challenges that are a reality for jobs that we never see.
Scott: And it's just like, how many times you're working on something and it's like, okay, I got like this screw out, but now it's stuck down there and I can't get it.
Rym: You know, like flashbacks to trying to like replace Ram and like old computers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you got to get in something into a tight space and it's like, you need to make the tight space bigger.
Scott: Move the, you know, it's like even with something this big, they have that problem, but they were so smart.
Scott: They a foresaw the problem to begin with, accounted for it.
Scott: And I guess they, they have enough room.
Rym: So they're barely look at these pictures.
Rym: Good God.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: This, the photos are showing you, like we moved it all the way.
Scott: Look how it's so close.
Scott: It is, you know, and plus when they were docking the boat, they probably like imagine having to like move it, just get it into just the right spot and not let it, you know, before you take the water out.
Rym: You know, this is always the kind of thing where like no one in high school ever told me I could be gigantic boat repair guy as a career because not many people can.
Scott: There's only one, like a few places on earth where you can be that.
Scott: It's not like a common job.
Scott: It's a rare job.
Scott: It's like a very select list of people get that job.
Scott: And usually it's people who a live near it to begin with.
Scott: So they know about it.
Scott: You know, coast guard people, you know.
Scott: I think that's the real thing is like, if you are not, if you don't like join something like the coast guard, right, they don't tell you necessarily all the possible jobs you could have in, in that organization.
Rym: A lot of these jobs are joined an organization or get an apprenticeship that no one will ever tell you exists.
Scott: And also, I mean, I remember when I was in high school and I guess, you know, slightly less against joining, say a military organization that I am now, right.
Scott: I was already extremely against.
Scott: I was like, whenever army recruiters, like the few times that I actually engaged with them, right.
Scott: In any meaningful way, I was like, I was like, if I joined the army or whatever, can you guarantee that I will not have to do any pushups and also that I can get a computer job guaranteed, not a killing people job, not a gun job, not, and not a computer that shoots bombs job, you know, some sort of other computer job that does not involve murdering people.
Rym: I'm sure that recruiters say, yes, I just lied to you.
Scott: No, they didn't.
Scott: They were like, no, you got to go to basic training.
Rym: No matter what is the Marine recruiters straight up lied to me.
Rym: It was really funny.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But they can't guarantee you that job.
Scott: So it's like, if you told me, oh, you joined the Coast Guard, your guaranteed job is engine replacer, right?
Scott: Maybe I would sign up for Coast Guard, but no, you joined the Coast Guard and then who knows what it's going to have.
Rym: But imagine if we had organizations like the Coast Guard that were paid better and like more managed by society and invested in to do other kinds of big infrastructure for our country, the train Corps.
Rym: I want to join the train Corps.
Scott: Well, imagine if you could just guarantee, join Coast Guard and not have to do pushups or kill anybody.
Rym: I mean, I'm fine doing pushups and the Coast Guard doesn't have to kill that many people.
Scott: One is too many is the problem.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: The best part of this article is, uh, the Coast Guard, the, the, the engine they're placing that they put in, they built that spare engine when they built the ship 23 years ago and they built a special building around that engine to store it until this day.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I don't know what they'll do if they have another engine problem.
Rym: I think they may build a new engine at that point.
Scott: They'll probably, they'll probably, the one they're taking out, they'll probably, you know, put in a building.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, so you always have one good one.
Rym: I'll admit, I, in terms of like the weird stuff I know about, I know a lot more about nuclear propulsion than about just non-nuclear electric propulsion, even though lots of the parts are very similar because Russia's got
Scott: some Russia except the plutonium part, Russian
Rym: equivalent ships to this are nuclear powered icebreakers and they're neat.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: But anyway, met a moment, uh, I've not blit the tale of Genji signal yet.
Rym: Nara Scott.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Our code of conduct seems to be working.
Rym: People have new people have come back into the forum or like, like there's more activity.
Rym: I feel like if you have stayed away from GeekNights, community spaces for some time, for whatever reason, come on back in and see what's going on.
Rym: We're trying to shape the community a little bit more specifically and it's bearing some fruit.
Scott: And also if you're a time of year, yeah.
Scott: Now is the time of year when usually you're with people, you know, we can't necessarily, it's not safe to be with people as much as we have been in a normal year.
Scott: You can be with fellow if you're listening to this, right?
Scott: I guess you are fellows in some way or, you know, you are, you should get along with other people who also listen to this, right?
Scott: So, you know, uh, so that's a thing.
Scott: Uh, what else?
Scott: Oh, uh, uh, so far during my not working time, which will, I guess I'm gonna have seven days of working coming starting next week, but most of my not working time I've been spending working on making the GeekNights website deploy itself with the press of a button and I've made a lot of progress.
Scott: It's almost done actually.
Scott: So if that is done, then working on the GeekNights website will be a breeze, right?
Scott: I'll be able to just be like, you know, making all kinds of changes, all kinds of stuff constantly.
Rym: You know, that's the pattern with you and me.
Rym: The part, the boring part that's necessary to get to the fun part is what slows us down the most.
Scott: Yeah, I'm telling you, it's like once you have, you know, like a, like a factory, right?
Rym: To make a thing, then suddenly making the thing becomes like, oh, that's why we have to make it a lot of video content because the factory has to be rebuilt every time we do it.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: Um, yeah, otherwise, but yeah, so if you, the, the, that was trying to say I got distracted by something, uh, is if you or someone, you know, or you just know of someone who is great at front end web action.
Scott: We're talking about, you know, real simple, like in terms of programming wise, all you're going to have to do is like, you know, call real simple APIs and get results.
Scott: And then the hard part is making a nice looking webpage, right?
Scott: Real nice looking, very, uh, meeting accessibility standards, right?
Scott: All that sort of stuff.
Scott: Um, not the actual programming part, the artsy part.
Scott: We do have a new logo and graphic design.
Scott: We just need, you know, the website at rest in peace.
Rym: Logos by Brando Kay.
Rym: They served us well for 15 plus years.
Scott: When I, I think I read what Brando Kay is up to these days.
Scott: He was on the team that did the RBs, uh, Twitter account, but I think they're doing something else now, but very talented person, uh, regardless.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Uh, we're going to, we're going to give up on our web 2.0.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: So if you know of anyone who is good at HTML, CSS, not too much JavaScript, right?
Scott: Mostly making stuff look nice.
Scott: Web page, right?
Scott: Uh, refer that person to us.
Rym: We will pay.
Rym: This is not, we're not asking for volunteers.
Rym: This is a paid like contract.
Scott: We are going to pay that person a competitive, perhaps even generous rate of money, uh, from mostly rims wallet.
Rym: Well, and the Patriot.
Scott: Steal Rym's money.
Rym: We, uh, yeah, we're paying for, well, this is a, this is a pretty good job, honestly, if you feel like you're up to it.
Scott: It's only a one time job though.
Scott: It's not an ongoing job.
Rym: It is a contract that will end.
Rym: We do not need someone to help us maintain the site after it's live.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Cause we can do that.
Rym: We're just, we could make the whole site ourselves.
Rym: One, we just suck at design and two front end development sucks ass.
Rym: And I hate it.
Rym: I hate doing it.
Rym: I never want to touch CSS.
Scott: It's better than it used to be.
Scott: Cause it's browsers today have things like CSS grid and whatnot, but that is true.
Rym: But I still just don't like doing it.
Scott: No, I don't like doing it.
Rym: I don't like thinking about it.
Scott: That's we're going to pay someone else to do it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Anyway, let's get right into it because, uh, this has turned into the adventure time show because we've now had two of these posts.
Rym: It's, uh, end of adventure time episodes on HBO max.
Rym: The first one was BMO, which we reviewed this one obsidian.
Rym: It's the Marceline and bubble gum show.
Rym: The biggest thing I have to tell you about this before we start reviewing it is that with the BMO one it's it stands alone.
Rym: You could watch it knowing nothing about adventure time and enjoy it.
Rym: Like it, it's, it's a story from start to finish.
Rym: This one won't make any goddamn sense.
Rym: If you have not seen all of adventure time to end it will spoil everything.
Scott: So I, uh, partially agree.
Scott: A you're right.
Scott: It will spoil many things.
Scott: B yes, you are right.
Scott: There was a lot going on here that you will not understand at all.
Rym: If you haven't seen all of it, but no, I see what you're about to say.
Scott: But see, it is watchable and comprehensible, uh, as a standalone thing.
Scott: You can understand what is happening in this within itself.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Like when Marceline is singing a particular song at a certain point, the way bubble gum reacts and then a flashback, you can figure out the context of that story enough.
Scott: You can, but I'm saying that the basic plot of this is that there is this glass kingdom, which is not in any other adventure time.
Rym: It's a brand new kingdom as far as we're aware of, but it is canonically foreshadowed, even if it's a retcon based on how Marceline was first introduced in the beginning.
Scott: Yes, sure.
Scott: Um, but yeah, this is not a kingdom we've seen before.
Scott: These aren't characters.
Scott: you've seen before this.
Scott: You find out the story of the glass kingdom is there's a dragon that lives down in the lava and they trap it there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then the, the dragons waking up and there's a, there's a kid and, you know, there's a princess goes off to find the ancient hero that saved the day the last time this happened.
Scott: It's like that.
Scott: the plot of this thing itself, you can fully grasp from never having seen any adventure time in your whole damn life, but there is much more fan service, you know, you know, plot stuff that you really probably shouldn't watch this unless you've seen all of adventure time enough, all the plot episodes of adventure time.
Rym: Like it'll literally spoil major points about the end of adventure time.
Rym: And it is set like at least a decade, maybe two after the end of adventure time.
Scott: And some things, you know, some things are, you know, references to the TV show that you will not get, and that won't necessarily subtract from watching this.
Scott: So, but some things, if you don't get it will, uh, you might, you'll miss something and it won't necessarily make the experience of watching it worse, but you'll basically be losing a huge bonus.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, there's a scene where someone throws a t-shirt at someone that scene.
Scott: It's like, okay, if you don't know anything about adventure time, that scene won't really cause you any problems.
Rym: It won't make this, you know, movie, I guess the one part that would make no sense to anyone is anything to do with Simon.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: That is not, they don't even try to make that make sense.
Rym: You'll just be like, the fuck was he doing with the freezer?
Rym: What's going on with that guy?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's just some guy, you know, doing weird stuff.
Rym: Like a lot of the emotional touchstones of adventure time, distant lands, obsidian really rely on you knowing the history of the show because you have all this context about the relationship between Bubblegum and Marceline from the show.
Rym: And it's not necessarily like, oh, now I know the answer as to X, Y, and Z. It's more like you get a complete emotional picture of those characters and their final arcs.
Rym: that would definitely be lost on you if you had not seen the show.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: They sort of fill in blanks.
Scott: That didn't exist.
Scott: So it's like, there weren't really like plot holes to fill in.
Scott: But it's sort of like Marceline's mother already in the show.
Rym: She came up several times and it was kind of left as is.
Rym: This doesn't reveal shocking new information about her mom, but it reveals a heartwarming and interesting emotional arc about her mom and the context of how she became who she was.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, okay, we already have this thing.
Scott: Let's just explain that thing some more than we explained it before.
Scott: It's like, okay, you know, A, B, and C. You know that you don't need to know more than A, B, and C. It's not a whole.
Scott: It's not lacking in the original show.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But we're just going to add some more details.
Scott: We're going to add D, E, and F just to flesh that out, you know, color in between the lines a bit there, you know, and now you'll know even more.
Scott: And it's not really any different or, you know, but it's just a thing that will make someone who's a fan feel good with some fan service, but also, you know, add more to the characters and whatnot.
Rym: It does also serve to do something that, as you know, the history of Adventure Time, they really weren't allowed to explore the lesbian relationship between Marceline and Bubblegum in the show.
Rym: Like they couldn't continue what they started with that one episode.
Rym: that sort of really kicked that off.
Rym: They weren't allowed to.
Rym: Like it was a different time and that sucks.
Rym: And they barely like got to the point at the end where they could have them kiss on screen.
Rym: Part of what this episode seems to do is revel in their relationship.
Rym: Like they don't have to dance around any of it.
Rym: They dive into their relationship like they're just living together.
Rym: That is just fine.
Rym: I feel like it is partly not a repudiation of the decisions that were made by the company previously, but more like a conclusion like this is how far we've come.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's pretty much just like, okay, we can do this now, so we're going to do it.
Scott: They don't like go overboard with it.
Scott: Like, oh yeah, we can do this now.
Scott: Let's do right.
Scott: But it's just sort of like, okay, we can do this now.
Scott: If we had been allowed to do this all along and this was a normal thing to do.
Rym: This is what it would have been.
Scott: This is what it would have been.
Scott: So we're now we're on HBO Max.
Scott: We can do it.
Scott: We must do it.
Scott: And they did do it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So Bobby's like, just go watch it.
Rym: If you haven't, unless you haven't watched adventure time, which case?
Rym: just go watch that because I just want to talk about the parts we liked, which means we're going to spoil this, but by nature of talking about this, we're going to spoil a lot of adventure time.
Rym: I I'm like 50 50 out of Jake is dead by this point based on just having that tattoo.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, the tattoo and the fact that, uh, come right.
Scott: Jake didn't come in the, in the bus.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Jake's daughter came in the bus.
Rym: No, that's not Jake's daughter.
Rym: That's Jake's granddaughter.
Rym: That's Bonwin.
Rym: The skateboard girl.
Rym: That's Kim Kilwan's daughter.
Scott: Oh my God.
Rym: How do you not remember?
Scott: Cause Jake's family's too big.
Scott: I can't keep them straight.
Scott: That is Kim Kilwan's daughter.
Rym: But, uh, I like how Finn definitely has a like Greg from Steven universe vibe going on now.
Scott: Well, I think the thing I like most is how, you know, clearly the voice actor for Finn got older.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's, they're basically just like, okay, he's probably like, ah, I can just talk normally now.
Scott: I not have to hide that I'm no longer a child.
Scott: Um, cause my character is no longer a child is the same character though.
Scott: I love all, you know, the voice, you know, he's got like what, two lines maybe, right?
Rym: The voice acting adventure time has always been a plus, but the voices in this one are particularly good, especially all the sort of catty, bitchy and like the side glass characters who were all being snide and mean the entire time are particularly funny in an LSP way.
Rym: that I appreciate.
Scott: To go back to the Jake dead story, we know for a fact, however, that, uh, Jake's voice actor, the bender guy, what's his name?
Scott: I always forget his name when I need to remember it.
Scott: But when I see his name, I'm like, that's that guy.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: As soon as I see that name, I know who it is, but I can't come up with his name when I need to.
Scott: Uh, we know for a fact that he is voice acting Jake in one of these, um, but we don't know when they're set.
Rym: Cause remember BMO, the first one was set way before adventure time started.
Rym: This one is set way after.
Rym: So he could be acting way after maybe like 10, 20 years after.
Scott: 10 or 20 years after.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's not too far after.
Rym: I mean, the first one is set 10 or 20 years before because BMO meets baby Finn.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So 10 years after, if something has happened to Jake, which they seem to be alluding to in that final brief moments of this movie, I think there's almost a guarantee that the before the episode, we're going to see that happen.
Scott: The fourth fin Jake episode will be about that.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Almost guaranteed high likelihood.
Scott: But I'm 50.
Rym: I'm literally 50 50 on that tattoo is because he is dead or that tattoo is just because that's how Finn rolls.
Scott: It could be just how Finn rolls.
Scott: It could also be, I don't know, you know, not dead, but like, you know, there's the whole Prismo sleeping Jake situation, which I kind of, right.
Rym: I did notice that you see one of those futuristic looking banana guards briefly in a scene.
Scott: I did not notice that.
Rym: Other times we see them are in Grebel's in the future.
Rym: After the fall of the candy kingdom.
Scott: No.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: There's a lot.
Scott: That is the thing, right?
Scott: Is that they, um, bubbling are living in a Marceline shack.
Scott: They are not living in the candy kingdom.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But the candy kingdom is still fine at this point.
Scott: There must, there must be because there's banana guards.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We assume it must be there.
Scott: No one, you know, there's no indication that it's not.
Rym: But there's the newer banana guards that we see later in the Grebel's in the, uh, and the lemon hope episodes.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Why can't episode three be lemon gray?
Rym: Uh, you know, as much as I want that, I'm still excited.
Rym: Cause you know, you remember what episode three is, right?
Rym: Baby Peppermint Butler goes to wizard school to relearn dark magic.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's a high, that's high up there.
Scott: Oh, so, uh, how could I forget to mention, right?
Rym: So the very beginning, I was avoiding bringing it up on purpose.
Scott: The very beginning of this fucking movie, right?
Scott: Glass boy is trying, you know, escape the glass kingdom and is going to go out into the world to try to find a Marceline.
Scott: They do it pretty quickly.
Scott: Actually, he finds Marceline pretty easily.
Scott: Um, but, oh yeah, we know the candy came to exist because Simon's in the bar singing.
Scott: Uh, I forgot about that.
Scott: Anyway, the first person that glass boy runs into in the woods, he runs into a mysterious figure hooded figure in the woods, right?
Scott: Who is that hooded figure?
Scott: And I'm thinking, I'm thinking like all the, it could be a LSP slicer.
Scott: It could be a lemon grab.
Scott: It could be, you know, they could go obscure.
Scott: Who is the bubble?
Scott: The bubble head guy.
Scott: Um, uh, what's his name?
Scott: Didn't he die?
Scott: The robot rattle rattle balls, rattle balls.
Scott: It could be like this could mysterious character in the woods.
Scott: It could be a freaking huntress wizard could be, I don't know anybody, right?
Scott: Instead, it was my favorite dude, the choose goose.
Scott: And I was like, Oh my God.
Rym: Small and floppy, but this was a tall and menacing juice goose with contraband.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And so the moisturizer was contraband.
Scott: I don't know what's up with that, but I missed the truth.
Scott: I was so a gas that that choose goose appeared.
Scott: I had to rewind to go back and listen to choose goose's rhyme a second time because I missed it.
Scott: I was so excited to see my boy choose goose.
Scott: So that was, that was nice to see choose goose still around.
Scott: Um, why can't we get a whole choose goose episode?
Scott: It tells the story of choose goose.
Rym: That's the big thing I wonder.
Rym: I feel like distant lands is very popular and I feel like it's doing well for HBO max.
Scott: Well, it's going to do well for them because I pirated it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I also might've sailed the high seas.
Rym: My question is, I feel like I have to pay for it now.
Rym: I'm going to be watching a venture venture.
Rym: If venture brothers makes it to HBO max, I will pay for HBO max.
Scott: I mean, I already said, I'm probably going to end up, you know, at some point.
Scott: I only have one service at a time.
Scott: I got to probably turn off Netflix and turn on an HBO max is my next move when I make a move.
Rym: But I wonder if they will just keep making more adventure time, or I wonder if HBO max will want to keep funding it, but the creative teams will not want to continue making it.
Rym: I don't know how this is all going to shake down on one hand.
Rym: This could just be like four episodes to try to get a bunch of people to HBO max with a popular property that's ended.
Rym: But on the other hand, it could be a situation where this is big and there's like a trial balloon.
Rym: And if it succeeds, they'll want to just keep making more.
Rym: Maybe because I would just keep watching adventure time.
Rym: Like so far, these two episodes have not disappointed if they made an adventure time episode as good as these every few months for the next decade.
Rym: I'd probably watch them all and never get tired.
Rym: Yeah, but there's not much else we could really say.
Rym: I mean, just watch it.
Rym: It ain't even that long.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think we'll do a GeekNights' episode on like each of the two next ones.
Scott: Let's try it.
Scott: Maybe do one for both.
Rym: Try to combine them.
Scott: Unless if there is the threat of too many of these happening, we risk turning GeekNights Wednesday into Adventure Time.
Rym: Yeah, Radio Free Equestria part two.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: I don't want to go down that road.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Greenia, Link Iggi, Graham Finch, You Hold the Key to My Heart, and I yelled to the cabbie, "Yo, holmes, smell ya later,".
Rym: Clinton Walton, Wren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Chris Mint Give Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Just Like a Dude Guy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Jervon Van Horl, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: So yeah, normally we wouldn't do a show on a night like tonight because usually we'd be doing holiday stuff, but it's kind of stuck at home.
Rym: Please don't fly anywhere.
Rym: Do not travel for this holiday.
Rym: It's a dangerous time.
Rym: But whatever you're doing tomorrow, we might poke around online a little bit.
Rym: You can hang out in the GeekNights Discord if you're alone and look for people to share some company or virtual video mails with.
Rym: But now, I leave you with... Do the Mario!
Scott: Swing your arms from side to side.
Scott: Come on, it's time to go!
Scott: Do the Mario!
Scott: Take one step.
Scott: And then again, let's do the Mario!
Scott: All together now!
Scott: You got it!
Scott: It's the Mario!
Scott: Do the Mario!
Scott: Swing your arms from side to side.
Rym: Come on, it's time to go!
Scott: Do the Mario!
Scott: Take one step.
Scott: And then again, let's do the Mario!
Scott: All together now!
Scott: Come on now, just like that!