Rym: It's Thursday May 21st 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are reviewing things.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: It's been a long time listeners.
Rym: We got we had a format to the show.
Rym: We have an open event where we talk about stuff and then we get into the news.
Rym: We have this whole thing going.
Rym: Uh Nothing happened in the last few days.
Rym: Like there's nothing there's no opening bit.
Scott: I Wake up I do work Eat food Sleep play games.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I Started making some cookies last night, but I had to chill the dough.
Rym: So I was too lazy to actually wait until the dough was chilled to cook and I wasn't gonna not chill the dough.
Rym: Cuz that's how you make shitty cookies.
Rym: So we make those cookies today.
Rym: That is the most exciting thing that's happened to me in the last since the last time we did a show.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, I guess we'll just skip that.
Scott: Similarly prosaic anecdote is a US holiday on Monday, but I already stay home every day.
Scott: So what's I don't know?
Scott: I guess I just don't have to do work while I'm at home that day.
Rym: I mean my company I might.
Rym: my days are at least structured to where my work is So busy like it's the same as normal except I'm not there.
Rym: So weekends and holidays mean a lot because it means I don't have to do work.
Rym: I can go like bike or something.
Scott: I mean, yeah, but it's like I still Don't do you know, I only do a few now that I'm actually at home, right.
Scott: so You know and I was I have to go to an office right, you know that the bad screen is there When you're when you go to work for you had to be there for a certain amount of time true can't do Absolutely anything there.
Scott: you can only do certain things right?
Scott: So it's like I could read.
Scott: go watch a YouTube during lunch.
Rym: Yeah, you know I could read some news, you know at other times They can't be like I'm gonna go do a lunch bike ride and then get back to work.
Scott: exactly I can be all over Twitter while I'm working on the second monitor, right?
Scott: You know, it's I can read reddit so I can do all kinds of stuff, but there's certain things I can't do.
Scott: I can't play a video game or I can't cook right like, you know this morning It's like I have bagel and I ran out of cream cheese.
Scott: Well, I cooked egg.
Scott: I didn't have any bacon either but Cooked an egg and I put melted cheese on it right and I put that on the bagel.
Scott: Like.
Scott: you can't do that if I'm at the office.
Scott: I got to pay someone to do that.
Rym: true office doesn't have a stove But I guess partly just because my job is so busy.
Rym: I don't actually have any more of that free time.
Scott: So like it's meeting see so I wake up and it's like yeah I'm doing you know the same amount of actual work.
Scott: work right on the work computer the bad screen which is over here next to me.
Scott: Yeah, it's closed right now.
Scott: It's not opening until next Tuesday.
Scott: But The Was I saying right.
Scott: but you know all that time that I was spending in the office not working doing other stuff Can now be spent doing absolutely anything.
Scott: I can play a video game at two o'clock I can cook of lunch I can you know, I just can't like go for a bike ride.
Scott: Yeah, because that would be.
Scott: I can't get too far away from the bad screen.
Scott: I have to stay close enough to it, but my option I can clean the kitchen, right?
Scott: I'd clean the kitchen a lot during work time, which I normally could When I'm in an office far away from the kitchen.
Scott: Yeah, oh yeah having a day off my company decided yeah, no one has to work.
Scott: not only do we not have to work Monday We don't have to work tomorrow.
Scott: It should be Friday the 22nd either.
Scott: So I'm basically today was Friday.
Scott: I'm done now until Tuesday.
Rym: Yeah, I do have to work tomorrow, but I do not have to work Monday.
Rym: So long weekend means a lot to me.
Scott: still even in these roads like I guess I can bike but I still You know Not a lot of other differences.
Rym: See any news because the world is still happening to a degree sure.
Scott: so all the sports, right are Separately figuring out what the hell to do because they all canceled.
Scott: Yeah, right NBA stopped NHL stopped.
Scott: I think the Bundesliga in Germany.
Scott: I heard is playing to empty crowds.
Rym: Yeah, I saw I saw a bunch of rumblings of like non-us sports doing the empty crowd thing for a lot of places.
Scott: Yeah, so that's interesting.
Scott: so it actually seems like you know perhaps out of a Desire to make money or greater need to make money because it's smaller League our favorite the NHL You know, they're.
Scott: they've been rumors swirling ever since they stopped over what this the comeback would look like.
Rym: Yep, because it's complicated because we were near the end of the regular season But exactly not close enough to the end to where they know who would officially be in the playoffs.
Rym: Like it could change the Rangers could have.
Scott: maybe NBA was in a similar spot though It is it doesn't seem to even be trying to come back.
Rym: Yeah But the at least as far as I can tell yeah, but it was this point where you couldn't just be like, okay Let's just do a playoff to eliminate the eliminate having to deal with all the teams because like Rangers can make the playoffs like who?
Rym: Knows what would have happened.
Rym: There's a lot of games anyway.
Scott: so All the rumors have been swirling.
Scott: but you know, the NHL has always just been like, yeah, those are all rumors.
Scott: Yeah, no of things.
Scott: we've just you know, we've discussed lots and lots of things and none of them are set in stone.
Scott: Well now as of like today yesterday There is one rumor that is still not some guaranteed official thing.
Scott: But is it is gaining strength as a more than just rumor like possible strong consideration, I guess.
Rym: Yep It's recent definitely because this is you sending me.
Rym: this link is the first I heard of it.
Scott: Oh, you didn't heard of it.
Scott: So I heard of it.
Scott: I heard of it like yesterday there.
Scott: the plan a possible plan that the NHL is strongly considering supposedly is to have a 24-team playoff and the way it would work is the top four teams in each conference.
Scott: So east and west they just go to the real playoffs like they don't have to do anything right.
Scott: the remaining eight teams Right would play play in series Best of five.
Scott: so supposedly the Rangers would play the Hurricanes best of five and if you win your play in series best of five.
Scott: So there's eight teams in playoff and in these playing games, right?
Scott: Yeah, so they obviously get cut down to four and Then those four that had to play in the best of five play in series would then go meet The eight.
Scott: the remaining four that said skipped it because they were the top four To form an eight.
Scott: so you'd have eight in each conference total of 16 and then you would have a normal playoffs with best of seven series and They would play these games supposedly in two different locations With no fans out somewhere who knows where.
Scott: yeah Just like take two cities two arenas.
Scott: play all the games in those two places.
Rym: You know probably do something like all the players go into special hotels their quarantine for a few weeks Then they play.
Scott: they can't leave that place until like they're eliminated like who knows Who knows if the Union will go along with it.
Scott: right who knows?
Scott: so even though you don't have fans there.
Scott: Right which greatly done, which does greatly cut down the number of people, but there's a lot of staff.
Scott: right when you don't have fans It's like okay.
Scott: Well.
Scott: You don't need hot dog salesmen.
Scott: You don't need merch salesman You don't ticket taker.
Scott: You don't need Usher.
Scott: You don't need the scoreboards only photographers trainers medics.
Scott: Yeah, you don't need music guy.
Scott: You know you don't need all this stuff.
Scott: But what you do need is like what Rym said you need the trainers you need the staff you need the TV crew.
Scott: Especially the TV crew is even more important.
Scott: They brought it to bring more people.
Scott: Yeah, because there's.
Rym: that's the only way anyone's gonna damn booty like you got someone on the Zamboni I got all the black around gonna shovel all the ice.
Scott: The refs gotta come right.
Scott: every NHL ref is probably gonna go to the one of those two cities and just stay there.
Scott: Yeah, right, so they'll probably split between the two And so we'll see if this happens how it happens if anything happens, so it's interesting.
Rym: I was reading it.
Rym: another thing I don't have a link to in handy but it was talking about how The lack of fans doesn't matter.
Rym: because no what they don't make enough money from the like the ticket sales to matter.
Scott: that well Depends on the league.
Scott: it does depend on the league.
Scott: so for example baseball Makes all its fucking money on ticket sales and TV is less in most markets depending on the market, right?
Scott: Although makes all its money from TV and advertising makes football makes like doesn't give a shit about losing his ticket sales.
Scott: the NHL Kinda does care about losing the ticket sales And I think that's not as much as a choice or like some friends not as much as baseball does But they do.
Scott: it does hurt the NHL not to sell the tickets.
Rym: yep Like MSG charges a lot for those tickets.
Rym: They make a lot.
Scott: MSG is one of them.
Scott: You know there's like a few that charge insane prices and the rest charge normal price.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: so I still remember when we Montreal.
Rym: it would have been cheaper for me to get a discounts flight to Detroit to see the Red Wings play the Rangers there.
Rym: Then it would have been to get two tickets to go see the Rangers at MSG?
Scott: Yeah, depending on where you sit.
Rym: Yeah, yeah See equivalent seats, but this was assuming things like we didn't have season tickets So I'd have to buy like scalper tickets.
Scott: it depends on a lot of things.
Rym: So uh it'll be interesting what happens because on one hand I really want to see hockey But on the other hand if the players don't want to do it like if the people involved don't want to do it Then I don't want them to feel like they have to.
Scott: I definitely do not want the players to play in an unsafe Dangerous way.
Scott: right what's the point of watching?
Scott: You know your team play.
Rym: if a a right lose and get sick They're already in enough danger of like breaking themselves just by playing the sport in the first place exactly Or even.
Scott: so it's like you lose and get sick.
Scott: That's way bad right you?
Scott: what?
Scott: why did you even go?
Scott: Yeah, you go.
Scott: imagine winning and getting sick, okay?
Scott: We won the Stanley Cup, and then I died.
Scott: right.
Scott: it's like that.
Scott: I mean winning.
Scott: the Stanley Cup is pretty up there in terms of things that are worth it to sacrifice to achieve But not dying.
Scott: dying is not something that is worth doing.
Rym: yeah, it's Lord Stanley's Cup.
Rym: It's not wizard Stanley's magic cup right.
Scott: It's like lose a finger to get the Stanley Cup.
Scott: Maybe right?
Rym: Yeah, lose some teeth.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I'll lose some teeth to get my name on the Stanley Cup.
Rym: I mean don't lose.
Rym: They're already.
Rym: they're paying teeth just to buy the lottery tickets to have a chance to get in the cup.
Scott: right.
Scott: It's like lose an arm is borderline dying.
Scott: No.
Scott: Yeah, not worth it.
Scott: I did see a thing a while ago that said fact if you could if my name was already on there And you said Scott we're gonna kill you or take your name off.
Scott: I'd say take the name off.
Rym: I saw a lot of talking about how they a bunch of US sports leagues were doing players union things where they were doing an anonymous ballot of the players Asking if what might would return.
Scott: that's exactly what my office did.
Scott: they sent out an anonymous survey to all employees.
Scott: Yeah to figure out how what we feel about doing yeah, which I think is the right way.
Rym: that way people can actually Say what they actually feel and I feel pressured.
Scott: Yeah I said you know what I said.
Scott: I said look the building we work in right has a little bike dock in the loading dock Right where you can hang your bike on the wall.
Scott: Yep And that's cool right you've been used.
Scott: I used it all last year right it was it was fine but I feel like if they let us come back to work people are gonna be using that thing like crazy.
Scott: and If there's no room on that thing Guy yeah, let me bring my bike upstairs in the office.
Rym: Yep, not taking the subway under any circumstances No, so that's what I said.
Rym: So the other sad and scary thing there was a 538 article and a bunch of buzz about this.
Rym: But it showed that different sports fandoms in America care more or less about the safety of the players based solely on whether or not they're a Democrat or a Republican.
Rym: and obvious and sports fandom in America is also tied very much to which side of the political spectrum you're on.
Rym: Fascists not news.
Scott: That's just common sense.
Rym: So you say that but there's a difference between saying something is common sense and having actual evidence to prove it.
Scott: The I mean I think it's been pretty well established that pretty much the two political parties in the u.s.
Scott: Regardless of what their stated You know ideologies are.
Scott: I mean there's the regular ones the true ideology that the only thing that you will find consistent between all of the Positions of the two parties that the bad ones are all on one side.
Scott: the democratic positions are we kind of care about other human beings and the Republican position is You believe these things if you only care about yourself Most close to you and you fuck everyone else, right?
Rym: Democrats are amazing ideas and bad ideas.
Rym: The Republicans are literally only bad ideas.
Scott: but the thing that all the ideas have in common is the Republican ideas are all ideas of someone who doesn't care about other people.
Rym: but the polling show.
Rym: Democrat ideas Like everyone who identifies Republican by and large want sports to continue even if it risks the players because they don't care about other People.
Scott: they say you other people you athletes die for my entertainment, right?
Scott: They only care about themselves, right?
Scott: It's like this gets me a penny but a thousand people die.
Scott: Okay, yeah, but and that gets me a million dollars and a random person dies hammer the button.
Rym: I just think of that comedy sketch for the person's like so this button will I think I immediately hits it just like that look like Kids.
Rym: it immediately and then he's like every time you hit that button It'll kill someone and he just starts hitting the button a few more times and he's like, does that mean I make even more money?
Rym: And the guys like wow, okay That's right.
Scott: So that's all there.
Rym: That's obvious that you know, since that's true Yeah, but they're like no one ever no one had ever done a poll trying to sort out the ideological divide in sports And the results.
Rym: it's that thing where everyone felt like they knew the answer.
Rym: but the evidence came out and the evidence said yes, you're Obviously biased.
Rym: worldview was in fact 100% accurate.
Rym: you were correct all along.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I have always been correct.
Rym: You've always been correct.
Rym: I feel like you've been wrong about things.
Scott: no, no, I'm saying it this thing.
Rym: Well, yeah this thing obviously.
Rym: So in some other news Twitter really seems to only want to release features for reasons.
Rym: You can probably imagine that protect brands and Fascists.
Rym: so they're not banning Nazis or pedophiles or anything on Twitter.
Rym: But what they are doing is now saying that whatever you tweet You can choose to say no one's allowed to respond to this tweet.
Rym: Okay So it seems like the sole use of this is for horrible people to say horrible things without anyone dogpiling on them and for brands to be able to post ads without People just dragging the brands for their ads as usually happens.
Scott: So it's all I mean.
Scott: So the first one I can see is a positive right because you have to figure the Twitter Algorithm is looking at tweets.
Scott: They get lots of activity.
Scott: Yep, right and then it is You know highlighting those tweets right and those users is like important or whatever.
Scott: so if you're a horrible person you post a horrible thing, right and Now there's nobody who can quote tweet you or reply to you because it's to argue with you.
Rym: I think you can quote tweet but not reply specifically.
Scott: Oh, it depends right?
Rym: That's what the Features does currently.
Scott: I guess then you could just quote tweet and you're not gonna.
Scott: but the point is is that if you can't Write interact with that tweet.
Scott: It just doesn't get replies.
Scott: Yeah, it's getting less activity.
Scott: It's getting less notoriety It's being shared less right?
Scott: You know, I guess you're gonna have the horrible people retweet it, but the good people right?
Scott: I see it as a lot of problems of good people retweeting horrible people.
Scott: shit Yeah, and that increases the numbers on the bottom of the horrible person tweet giving them greater.
Scott: You know analytics in the system and it's like don't it's up, you know, even when you're Counter-arguing a shitty person.
Scott: you're still amplifying their voice, right?
Scott: And uh, you know at least based on the way algorithms work I don't think that's a good strategy.
Scott: So making people forcing people away from that strategy I think is good and people can still I think you know sub tweet right.
Scott: the horrible tweets Yeah Which is the right way to go.
Rym: never get like.
Rym: if you want to call something out never link directly to the thing because at percentage of people will get tricked by the thing right you sub tweet it.
Scott: you say horrible person say, you know, You know, how many tweets do I see every day where someone you you know, they don't go at president right orange They say, you know, the orange guy said this don't you know this and this?
Scott: and this is the counter-argument I don't link retweet the original tweet.
Scott: They don't reply to it.
Scott: They don't link to it They don't like it right.
Scott: and that's what people will do if they can't reply to a horrible thing.
Scott: The second issue yelling at brands right when they are doing bad stuff.
Scott: I think that actually hurts the brands more than Right.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I think it definitely.
Rym: I definitely I've definitely seen like brands are Terrified of the replies to their tweets being people pointing out their bullshit.
Scott: Right, but okay.
Scott: So now no one's replying to you.
Scott: No one's retweeting you.
Scott: No one's cute.
Scott: You'll just be ignored.
Scott: exactly It's like.
Scott: it's like Any attention is better than no attention.
Scott: Even the negative attention is better than no attention.
Scott: Your whole point is your marketing right.
Scott: you want attention, even if it's bad, right?
Scott: If you make a mistake, you got turned into something good, right?
Scott: Trying to hide right is a either going to succeed which is not what you want.
Scott: If you're a brand successfully hide Or be Streisand effect.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, you can't.
Scott: there's no other way it can go for you.
Scott: So basically what they're?
Scott: this feature is simply adding a trap for bad people to fall into And it's optional.
Rym: Yeah, so yeah, that's that you kind of actually just got to the point.
Scott: I was gonna make this article if a good person uses it to avoid say harassing replies Great also seem.
Scott: that also seems good to me.
Scott: Yeah, I don't it's just.
Scott: it's.
Scott: as long as you know, they add optional feature.
Scott: Okay, so
Rym: yep My broader meta point was one more that Twitter tends to always add these increasingly esoteric features that may or may not have any Like may not actually do what anyone intends them to do rather than doing obvious things like banning Pedophiles or banning Nazis or banning races.
Scott: They still you know, this is nowhere near enough, but it's not.
Scott: this isn't necessarily bad or good It's just a thing.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, okay
Rym: But the reason why I think it'll be okay in the end is that the first tweet I saw from one of the few Twitter accounts that has access to this when they're trying it out was Officially from the official overwatch and they tweeted saying if this tweet gets a hundred replies We will make the next character in the game.
Rym: Jeff Kaplan himself.
Scott: Oh And you can't reply can't reply to it.
Rym: so That alone means I'm okay with this feature because if that is how the first people have access to it use it.
Rym: that all is Right with the world nice way.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: what he got?
Scott: What did I have?
Rym: you have not not the miracle on ice?
Scott: No, no.
Scott: No, this is the sudoku miracle.
Scott: So sudoku is not a great puzzle, but a listener In our forum posted this in the thing of the day thread.
Scott: Hey people, maybe you should join our forum and post things.
Rym: Our forums pretty rockin.
Scott: Thank you listener who did this?
Scott: because this is a great thing of the day the sudoku miracle.
Scott: It's a sudoku puzzle by a person named Mitchell Lee and it is on a YouTube channel called the Cracking the cryptic cracking the cryptic which is a YouTube channel about solving puzzles a lot of sudoku's.
Scott: And normally in a sudoku right you have a you know, it's it's nine by nine, right?
Scott: It's a big 81 square box separated into nine.
Scott: nine square boxes Right and in each of the boxes are the digits one through nine and in each full column and full row are the digits one through nine.
Scott: So you can't have two twos in the same vertical column two twos in the same horizontal column or two twos in the same box Because that would you know, and they would not be one through nine.
Scott: Yeah, and the way most sudoku's work is You get this empty box and they start you off with a few numbers Legally placed revealed numbers and it's up to you to use logic in the process of elimination To figure out where all the remaining numbers are and to fit to legally fill in the rest of the box because they're only.
Scott: There will be at least one legal way to fill in the rest of the boxes given those starting numbers.
Rym: Yep, and it's cross.
Rym: It's not necessarily the greatest puzzle, but it's very meditative.
Rym: A lot of people use it as a calming thing.
Rym: It's just a chill activity.
Scott: Yeah, it's just a chill activity.
Scott: You could you know, you just use presentation to figure out the puzzle.
Scott: There's.
Scott: uh, it's similar to the ones you see in in puzzle books that are like, you know Joe came before Jill, but Jill has green hair and you know, it's like a logic puzzle.
Rym: Yeah, but the answer to that one is easy because before all came the darkness, right?
Scott: So usually when you have a sudoku even a really hard one like a big one or something like that, right?
Scott: They give you quite a few starting numbers, right?
Scott: They can't just give you like, you know a couple because then there won't be enough right to solve Or there'll be too many possible solutions.
Scott: It'll be boring, right?
Scott: So here this sudoku has a Only two starting things is a one and a two and that's it.
Scott: And it's like this.
Scott: guy's like.
Scott: he thinks that this guy is an expert puzzle solving guy.
Scott: He was a YouTube channel about puzzle solving right with 600,000 views and 200,000 subscribers.
Scott: He's like this.
Scott: he starts off this video.
Scott: being like this is some bullshit.
Scott: This is just a practical joke.
Scott: I'm gonna call them up and give him an earful.
Scott: try to fool me with this bullshit, right?
Scott: He's like this is either like they're pulling my chain or this is a work of genius.
Scott: Of course, it wouldn't be thing of the day if it wasn't the latter.
Scott: So there's some additional rules on this sudoku.
Scott: Is that?
Scott: No number can be a knight's move like a chess From an identical number, right?
Scott: Also, no number can be a king's move from An identical number which is orthogonally and diagonally adjacent.
Scott: and no Number can be orthogonally adjacent to a number that is one away from it, right?
Rym: So that last one is what fucked me up.
Scott: that last one A one cannot be directly adjacent to a two.
Scott: a two cannot be directly adjacent to three or four.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So those that crazy combination of things.
Scott: you're thinking this is impossible.
Scott: But it just so happens that with all of those restrictions Right in place and those starting numbers one and two, right?
Scott: There's so many restrictions that actually this very few places you can actually put Numbers and in this video you can see how he solves the puzzle one through nine Which is obviously how you would do it and discovers that it wasn't a practical joke, and it's just a genius.
Scott: Sudoku too bad.
Scott: They're not all Sudoku's.
Scott: They're as good as that one.
Scott: Otherwise, you'd you know have fun doing them all day.
Rym: Yep, I love.
Rym: one of the YouTube comments right at the top is this is simply not humanly possible.
Rym: beats puzzle to death.
Scott: Yeah hands down.
Scott: This is the best Sudoku I've ever seen.
Scott: absolutely unbelievable.
Rym: Like this is basically the AGDQ of Sudoku.
Scott: Yes Yeah, basically.
Scott: Yeah, they should have an AGDQ where people solve puzzles.
Scott: That'd be pretty good at that kind of event.
Rym: Yeah, I would watch it.
Scott: Yeah Do some Nintendo pie-crossy like speedruns, you know, we always criticize games a lot.
Scott: You know ortho games that are like actually puzzles, right?
Scott: That's not to say that puzzles are bad.
Scott: It's just like hey you were supposed to be a game.
Scott: Why are you a puzzle?
Rym: Yeah, it's like if I order an omelet and I get a hamburger like not that I don't like hamburgers But that is not what I wanted right now, right?
Scott: We're talking about games here, but you know puzzles are a thing.
Scott: They're good, right?
Scott: I think you know, you gotta pay attention to the puzzle world.
Scott: The puzzle world is a cool nerdy world Very adjacent to the math and game worlds.
Rym: So recently I bumped into this thing that was called Star Trek intakes.
Scott: So, okay.
Rym: These are amazing because I've never seen I don't know if anyone's ever done this before and I want to see it done In non Star Trek things now, so huh what this is?
Rym: You know the concept of an outtake.
Rym: right like the actor flubbed the line like it's one of the takes before they finished the shot Like in a movie like the blooper.
Scott: Oh that kind of right.
Scott: So yeah, they cut it out of the movie because the guy messed up and you have to redo it.
Scott: but then you get you know, it's really fun.
Scott: you watch outtakes from Super super old movies.
Rym: Yeah, and they talk like normal people.
Scott: That's that's really the best They're like.
Rym: I do declare that my oh fuck me like.
Rym: they just sound like a normal person like from today.
Rym: It's exactly.
Rym: But so what the what Ryan's edits this YouTube channel has done is I don't know they invented this concept.
Rym: I do I cannot find an example of this.
Rym: They made an intake where instead of just having a blooper reel of all the outtakes which are great and funny on their own They take a scene from Star Trek.
Rym: That is normal like the final version that was published on TV But part of that scene.
Rym: they replaced the official version with one of the outtakes Not at the end but in the middle.
Rym: so you get a scene.
Scott: We're like so you're watching a full Star Trek episode and then the actor actually flubs the line And breaks the third wall in the episode that you're watching but they never break the fourth wall.
Rym: What they do instead is they just continue the scene and it actually makes it weirdly more human and real like it's a weird experience to watch these cuz like Picard will be giving this epic speech and he kind of flubs it and like loses his place and then someone reminds him like oh And then he continues and then they continue the scene like normal and it actually makes the dialogue a lot more natural Like how normal people talk in the real world.
Scott: yeah, I mean that's part of why I like.
Scott: You know I think I first encountered you know this style.
Scott: I think I've mentioned this before on like Korean variety shows, but I'm seeing it.
Scott: I'm seeing it in other places especially on YouTube right like my new you know everyone's favorite thing now Which has been my favorite thing for like maybe a year, so the Bon Appetit YouTube channel.
Scott: Yeah, and it's all about you know.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: There's not hiding that they're on TV right it's like yeah, so recording video, but it's like.
Scott: the people behind the camera are people.
Scott: They're not invisible right you're not.
Scott: not everything is scripted.
Scott: You know and in perfect and beautiful right It's showing you.
Scott: you know sort of what like.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's not Reality TV in the sense that we're spying and showing you every detail of every of someone's life.
Scott: Right with the hidden cameras and all that kind of shit like 24/7 Truman show.
Scott: But it's also not reality.
Scott: you know.
Scott: reality TV I think also got blurred a lot with competition game shows in especially in the US right, but it's actually more reality.
Scott: It's like okay this person's here making this TV show right, but we're not hiding the reality that We're.
Scott: what you're watching is the video of this person making the TV show.
Scott: you're not watching a produced TV show like from the 90s.
Scott: yeah right or earlier right you're watching.
Scott: Just cameras are on and a person is making a show.
Rym: yep, so watch these cuz they're just there.
Rym: I've never seen someone do something like this.
Rym: I feel like This could be a YouTube thing.
Scott: I think this could be applied to a lot of movie media and be interesting right, but I think it's Star Trek in particular Especially the long-running TV series is yeah, right happen to have lots and lots of outtake footage available.
Scott: Right something like a Star Wars.
Scott: There's only so much.
Rym: yep, cuz they don't give us all of it.
Rym: They put like and there's only a bit of it.
Scott: There's only a few movies.
Scott: you have to find a long-running live-action TV show because there's no outtakes of an animation.
Rym: yep.
Scott: And the other key I did is voice acted outtakes of an animation right like Thundercats famous outtakes.
Scott: Yep, not Semiflange.
Scott: Right you need to access to live-action TV shows that have tons and tons of content And I think even for something like a soap opera It's like.
Scott: I don't think it's gonna work.
Scott: eat that Because it also.
Rym: it can't be outtakes that like break the fourth wall or just like really like look at the stunt fails.
Rym: They have to be.
Rym: outtakes were like.
Rym: it's plausible But just weird.
Rym: what happens like the other?
Rym: because they because they.
Rym: it's like that normal normal the outtake Then it cuts to the character Reacting like everything was normal, and that's the moment of the humor.
Scott: right I think it's only gonna work if you do it to.
Scott: you know Star Trek.
Scott: I think is the one example That's kind of like different in a way, right I think it's mostly gonna work best if you somehow got the archives of like a family matters.
Scott: Oh, yeah a Seinfeld Full house Coach or any of those white people sitcom shows yeah.
Rym: But what I appreciate about this channel too is all these clips like where they put these together.
Rym: They're only like a minute long like they do their setup.
Rym: They do the joke and they're done.
Rym: You don't have to like.
Rym: watch the entire episode to get this Mmm all right.
Rym: metamoment We're hanging out.
Rym: not much has happened since the last time we did a metamoment.
Rym: Check us out everywhere on the internet.
Rym: like we got a forum We got a YouTube.
Rym: we got our videos.
Rym: like our reviews of board games are actually linked directly on YouTube from board game geek Like they're all over the place.
Rym: Our stuff is out there.
Rym: You can interact with us.
Rym: ah We're not going to any conventions anytime soon.
Scott: No Cricket cricket you should you know just so.
Scott: list again all the places that you can find us on the internet.
Scott: We have a website for our crew.
Scott: calm.
Scott: I got a Twitter Rym.
Scott: has a Twitter.
Scott: Yeah, we have a GeekNights' Twitter.
Scott: We have a GeekNights' Instagram.
Scott: I have an Instagram Rym doesn't.
Scott: yeah There's actually a GeekNights' Facebook page.
Scott: That is I guess they think the automatic posting to it stopped working.
Scott: Maybe I'll fix it.
Scott: It's the only reason I haven't deleted my Facebook is because I Go, and I check that page occasionally and apparently there are people there.
Rym: Yeah, so Weirdly like you know one thing that Comes up a lot that I find people actually do comment on our YouTube videos And they're usually good comments to like.
Rym: weirdly right.
Scott: so we have a Rym has a YouTube channel where most of our stuff is.
Scott: But I also have a YouTube channel where some of our stuff is yeah, and also personal stuff.
Scott: on both of those We have a discord that is like an unofficial official discord you can come chat in.
Scott: I'm pretty sure the IRC died a long time ago.
Scott: I checked on it recently is dead.
Scott: What else do we have?
Scott: those that those are the biggies.
Scott: yeah You know on our forum right and you can email us.
Rym: yeah, we do read emails.
Scott: We're calm like we read them all and as GeekNights' newsletter.
Scott: You can subscribe to yep.
Rym: The newsletter is a plus.
Rym: We got the patreon where there's extra bonus stuff in there all sorts of places.
Scott: You can find our biz and you can find GeekNights the podcast on just about every podcast platform.
Scott: That's out there Spotify iTunes Fucking everything in case whatever.
Scott: you're listening to it on now.
Scott: You don't like and you want to switch up.
Scott: I guess if you're listening to this you've successfully found GeekNights, so I guess You found it on some platform, but if there's some other podcast platform you prefer and for some reason GeekNights is unlistenable there.
Scott: Let us know via any of the previous methods.
Rym: yep Alright, so we'll get right into it.
Rym: We couldn't come up with an idea for this show that didn't require a lot of effort and We thought about bailing, but this I feel you have Thursday show ideas, which is pretty much anything.
Scott: That's not technology Science gaming or animation or art or comics related.
Scott: yep.
Scott: send them to any of the things I just mentioned in the minute moment Yeah,
Rym: and we will probably do a show on it Or we'll link you to where we already did a show on it And that's why we're having so much trouble right now
Scott: or reasons why we won't do a show on it.
Rym: yep, but our vague idea here is We're gonna try to just go through all the stuff We've bought recently like over some arbitrary period of time and review those things no matter what they are Right.
Scott: I had this idea recently because someone brought up QVC Which is the if I don't know how many ever.
Scott: everyone knows about that the old people tricking.
Rym: It's basically a TV network that tricks old people into giving them their credit card number.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's all done.
Scott: They mail them garbage before there was an internet to buy things on.
Scott: I think it still exists QVC.
Scott: But yeah You know you would.
Scott: you go on TV, and you watch this TV channel and people come on and demonstrate products in like an infomercial style.
Scott: But it's like a constant infomercial that keeps changing products constantly And you know what they actually do and the products aren't necessarily bad and the prices aren't necessarily bad either.
Scott: It's just this marketing method where you know you you sit at home You have nothing to do you turn on this channel, and you open your wallet whereas if that channel wasn't there You wouldn't have spent that time buying.
Rym: yep, but unlike say advertising which I despise I'm not that like.
Rym: I'm okay with the QVC kind of model because this is more.
Rym: It's more like I want to see ads to see if there's anything in there I want to buy.
Rym: it's like the old world equivalent of going to Amazon and just poking around.
Scott: Anyway, I thought it would just be kind of funny.
Scott: We had an idea the other day because something that the QVCs have sort of been famous for there's a lot of outtakes you can You can get from them when they're selling certain products Is that the people selling the products are not particularly that knowledgeable about the products especially?
Scott: When those products are in the nerdy realm right.
Scott: so it's like when they're selling a jewelry or something or or something like that.
Scott: It's like usually the people are pretty knowledgeable and can say things about it because they sell a lot of that on those networks.
Scott: but you know the in this in the 90s like they would sell computers and stuff on there like desktops and The people selling them would not necessarily be computer experts.
Scott: It would say dumb shit, so I was like hey How would it be?
Scott: it would just be fun and cute right even if it wasn't successful?
Scott: It could just be cute entertaining and fun to have say a twitch stream Right or any kind of stream on the internet where nerds who knew about the products were selling Right nerdy products.
Scott: they could not only sell them well right and and be honest.
Scott: But they would also be able to like respond to the chat because it's 2020 so people ask questions or whatever.
Scott: right like it would Be kind of a cool.
Rym: Yeah, like imagine me and Scott just got in a studio had a pile of board games and just QVC'd them for four hours.
Scott: Right that could be.
Scott: it could be a thing.
Scott: Yeah, you know even if it doesn't make any money.
Scott: It could be fun.
Scott: So it'd be fun to make even if no one watches.
Scott: so since I had that idea And we didn't have a Thursday show idea.
Scott: I was like hey even though.
Scott: We're not streaming or anything all right.
Scott: We're just podcasting.
Scott: Let's just grab random products.
Scott: We have around that no one's sponsored.
Scott: We don't have any fucking sponsors Right?
Scott: just shit that we bought recently ish or you know they haven't talked about on the show.
Scott: that wouldn't be stuff that we wouldn't Review right?
Scott: so a video game.
Scott: I'd review on a Tuesday.
Rym: I wouldn't talk about it now But I don't review like the sunscreen brand.
Scott: I tried Exactly, so let's just look around see what shit we got And just discuss it.
Scott: and that's it and you know until we run out of time all right.
Scott: Okay, you pick pick something go first.
Rym: I'm just gonna go in reverse chronological order in my Amazon purchases.
Scott: Okay, I just I got it.
Scott: I got a random assortment.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna skip.
Rym: obvious like I'm not gonna skip.
Rym: I bought some baking soda on Amazon because it's hard.
Scott: I get a review baking so not gonna be baking soda.
Rym: It's a chemical.
Rym: it just works.
Scott: It wasn't things that make sense to review right.
Rym: I mean it could have been like I bought this baking soda.
Rym: It was actually a different chemical.
Rym: Sure Or fuck baking.
Scott: it wasn't sodium bicarbonate.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: Yeah, I prefer cream of tartar.
Rym: I don't eat baking so anyway.
Rym: So uh I did buy some Coppertone sport SPF sunscreen because I was out of sunscreen.
Rym: I've tried a lot of different brands of sunscreen over the years like even you with your Neutrogena Which honestly it's not that good.
Scott: and the Neutrogena one I liked.
Rym: I like it unless I sweat at all because it's not actually sport.
Rym: even though it says like it's good for your face it Immediately melts into my eyes no matter what.
Scott: the thing I liked about the Neutrogena one is that it was dry touch.
Scott: It was way way less greasy than the other Sunscreens and that was why I liked it and used it for so long, but actually I have changed Sunscreens as well.
Rym: yep, so I have tried actually over the years many many brands of sunscreen, and I've settled Recently and I bought this now on just the basic Coppertone sport.
Rym: It's the best sunscreen.
Rym: I've ever used.
Scott: Oh United States.
Rym: Because the best sunscreen I've ever used is the Australian government sunscreen that I've got in Australia And I brought as much home as I could the last time I was there.
Scott: Which is the sunscreen that I got?
Scott: I'm not.
Scott: I got.
Scott: if I got to find it I think I bought it at the.
Scott: I'm not seeing so.
Rym: Coppertone sport sunscreen SPF 30 and SPF 50.
Rym: I use the 30 most of the time.
Rym: the only time I use the 50 is if I go to the beach, and I'm gonna lay there all day or If I already got a sunburn I'm gonna use the 50 on the places I have the sunburn instead of the 30, but I keep both that I generally use the 30.
Scott: I can't recommend my sunscreen brand because I don't see it online, and I'd have to get up and Get up and like go to the bathroom, and I'm tired.
Scott: I'm physically cabled into the computer.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: I reviewed my Coppertone sport sunscreen.
Rym: It was fine.
Scott: Oh, that's all.
Scott: that's all you have to say about it.
Rym: Yeah, it's great It just works.
Rym: the cool part is I get it all over my face And it does not melt into my eyes at all even after like four hours of biking.
Scott: That is a very important feature.
Rym: most sunscreens fail at that even the like super stick.
Rym: I am good for sports sunscreen now.
Rym: They're lying just a palace full of lies.
Scott: Alright, I can't find the sunscreen that I bought on the internet, so I guess I can't discuss it.
Scott: So we'll just move on what you got you.
Scott: I want to talk about an electronic device that I have purchased recently.
Scott: ish right.
Scott: so what I wanted to do Was you know I pretty much have like.
Scott: I have no need for additional Speakers or sound systems right I've got like a 5.1 sound system in the living room.
Scott: I got bookshelf speakers in the office.
Scott: You know I got iPad.
Scott: I got an iPhone.
Scott: those actually have amazing speakers in them Right they don't need it.
Scott: They don't need any help right or anything like that.
Rym: I mean I even got that Sonos and gave me just hanging out right.
Scott: I got tons of You know headphones right I don't need any additional headphones anywhere or anything like that right.
Scott: But what I did get recently.
Scott: Where is it?
Scott: I gotta get the exact right?
Rym: I love we've been doing the show long enough.
Rym: I can hear the tone of voice that you do because I have a similar tone of voice of.
Rym: I am actually killing time while I find a thing or remember what to say because we both do a lot in panels.
Scott: Correct all right, so the thing that I got that the one place right that I did not have any audio system Right was the shower, right?
Scott: I Was always taking a quiet shower right which is fine.
Scott: sometimes I still take a quiet shower right, but there's other times not so much lately.
Scott: But you know when I was working I would listen to some podcast in the shower because I lost a lot of my podcast Listening time when I would bike to work because I don't listen while I'm biking right we're subway times.
Scott: I would do a lot of listening to podcasts, but you know biking times no.
Scott: So it's like okay if I'm biking to work at least I can listen to some podcast in the shower before I go to work.
Scott: So I went looking for a waterproof Bluetooth speaker so I could have my phone outside the shower and the speaker in the shower.
Scott: You know it?
Scott: start the podcast get in the shower.
Scott: what podcast is so long that I'm gonna.
Scott: It's good for so short that.
Rym: well our podcast is really compelling.
Rym: you just stay in the shower for like 45 minutes.
Scott: Yeah, that hasn't happened.
Scott: So you know I kind of wanted a Bluetooth speaker before But it's like I just didn't.
Scott: I never bought one cuz.
Scott: like when would I use it?
Rym: yeah?
Rym: Yeah, the only place I could think of it is maybe if we went to the beach a lot more often than we do like.
Rym: It seems Prefer beach sound just quiet sound Exactly, I want to have a little music party like if I'm there for a week Right.
Scott: it just always seemed like a useful thing to have but when I thought about it It's like when would I actually use it?
Scott: I would probably end up carrying it everywhere I never use.
Rym: you know where we would have used it when we were at RIT instead of that boombox Right.
Scott: so the times that I end up you know these days like all the times where I would have used Bluetooth speaker I end up just Opening the iPad and using the speakers built into the iPad.
Scott: I don't really need a separate Bluetooth speaker yep, so I went, but I wanted the shower speaker, so I said aha Let's see what they got.
Scott: so I found this thing.
Scott: It's the ultimate ears wonder boom - it's like a little pod guy right.
Scott: It's just a big plus/minus on the front of it And it's a waterproof Bluetooth speaker.
Scott: It's been in the shower for like all year basically And it works like it was new.
Scott: I have only had.
Scott: I actually haven't had to recharge it but I have recharged it one time just because.
Scott: So yeah in a whole year of using it for showers I've had to recharge it one time right to keep its internal lithium-ion battery up to power.
Scott: It connects perfectly.
Scott: Bluetooth wise it's actually maybe the best Bluetooth audio connecting device I've ever had.
Scott: Wow like I turn my phone.
Scott: I turn it on it's connected.
Scott: I turn it off It's disconnected.
Scott: if I walk away with my phone and leave it on it figures it out and turns itself off.
Scott: The buttons on it for volume up volume down pop play/pause work perfectly.
Scott: it sounds great in the shower.
Scott: It makes surprisingly more bass than you would imagine.
Scott: It has a feature where supposedly you could get more than one of them to get stereo sound.
Rym: That's pretty common with those kinds of things.
Rym: the Sonos I got will do the same thing if I get two of them.
Scott: Yeah, I have not tried it.
Scott: I haven't bought a second one.
Scott: I have no reason to buy a set.
Rym: Yeah, you don't really.
Rym: I mean stereo in the shower.
Rym: You're already compromising a lot on the audio quality.
Scott: It seems pretty stupid to have two in the strike.
Scott: one is enough.
Scott: So yeah, if you are looking for a waterproof Bluetooth speaker for the beach.
Scott: That's portable right.
Scott: there's a long-lasting battery.
Scott: You know maybe it'll.
Scott: it could just be.
Scott: you're also Bluetooth speaker.
Scott: if you ever have non shower uses for one I I Recommend this one.
Scott: the ultimate ears wonder boom post a link whatever.
Rym: post a link to me in the discord.
Rym: one so I can link To it for the show and two because I kind of need one.
Scott: You can anyone?
Scott: this is the shower.
Scott: the shower it comes in it's 80 bucks, and it comes in five colors.
Rym: Yeah, just post a link there cuz I'm gonna link to all the things I talk about too.
Scott: Why why now send every time I talk about a thing?
Scott: I'll send you a link to the room.
Rym: Yeah, so I then cuz I actually also bought some speakers recently, but I did something very different.
Rym: I And for the longest time.
Rym: I had that giant mixer for gig nights And I had plugged into the like control room out of that mixer a bunch of adapters And then the same shitty computer speakers that I brought with me to RIT because I was lazy.
Rym: They didn't work that well.
Rym: They finally died.
Rym: I got rid of them, and then I upgraded all my equipment.
Rym: I needed real speakers.
Rym: I have real professional equipment in this room.
Rym: I needed real studio monitor speakers the kind that take a balanced input from a professional audio device.
Rym: These are not like normal speakers that I couldn't use.
Rym: the normal kind of speaker.
Rym: You'd like plug into your phone or plug into like your hi-fi system Because I don't have like speaker wire out on this thing.
Rym: And I've been a fan of PreSonus their tech their kit.
Rym: like there It seemed like they're really much ahead of the game on modern audio tech.
Rym: so I did the research and I bought PreSonus e4.5 near field studio monitor speakers.
Scott: Okay, they are.
Scott: were they?
Rym: they were 200 bucks total for the pair which was the right call because there is a step up from these.
Rym: that are individual speakers that are way more powerful and way better in every way and as much as I Wanted them because I'm a nerd and I wanted the much better speakers.
Rym: I was not stupid.
Rym: I did not need more than 50 watts of output in this tiny room.
Rym: So I buy smartly bought these smaller ones.
Rym: Holy shit are these things amazing?
Rym: They are crazy crazy high quality speakers.
Rym: They work automatically.
Rym: They do have Unbalanced input so I could plug consumer level stuff into the back of them in addition to my pro stuff and Like I cannot stress enough how?
Rym: Perfect these speakers are.
Rym: they even have configuration options depending on how close to the wall They are very or how close to the corner of the room they are so that they will give a flat frequency response.
Rym: They're not the normal kind of speaker you'd use like in your living room.
Rym: They're specifically designed to be arranged such that the sound that comes out of them is completely neutral and uncolored.
Rym: You use these to like master audio.
Rym: You don't use them to listen to a song you like.
Rym: so After buying them like they're worth every penny.
Rym: if you need Real like good studio monitor speakers, and you don't need something that's like crazy gigantic for like a giant studio This is probably the best value of dollar per quality you could possibly get.
Rym: like.
Rym: I can't write But these are.
Scott: but these are good for if you're doing audio work.
Scott: They're not for I want to enjoy music in my house.
Rym: Yes, you could.
Rym: you would not want to plug these into like your TV.
Rym: You would not be happy with them if you plug them into your TV.
Rym: a cheap Oh soundbar would probably do a better job than these plugged into your TV.
Rym: But if you make a podcast Yes, exactly.
Scott: but the You're basically using them instead of headphones when possible.
Rym: audio production, but the reason they're so good Is that all the other monitor speakers?
Rym: I've seen from other pro companies were kind of hard and fiddly to use or like like.
Rym: the UX was not great.
Rym: Physical objects have a user experience.
Rym: these have all these little minor niceties like.
Rym: there's a headphone jack in the front.
Rym: That seems like a good idea.
Rym: a lot of the ones I saw didn't have that.
Rym: they expect you to plug your headphones into a Headphone bus.
Rym: I don't have a headphone bus.
Rym: I want to plug these headphones right up in there.
Rym: They've got a line in on the front.
Rym: pros don't often need that but you know what?
Rym: That's super handy to have like.
Rym: I really like that.
Rym: There's that line in on the front.
Scott: Mmm, okay.
Scott: Seems good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: The next thing I want to review is not an Amazon.
Scott: You everybody knows the local businesses.
Scott: Some of them are actually doing better and some are doing worse in these times right of trouble Troubled times.
Scott: Yeah, so one such business, especially in New York City.
Scott: Usually most of the businesses are doing worse because they're getting no foot traffic.
Scott: you they're used to tons of foot traffic.
Scott: They're tourist attractions.
Scott: There's no tourists.
Scott: Yeah, right and There are neighborhoods where the people are not going outside and such and such and their rents are high high high very high rents.
Scott: So one such place that is a somewhat troubled is a place that even New Yorkers love which is called economy candy.
Scott: It's a candy store as you would imagine.
Scott: People like to buy there.
Scott: I see a lot of people wearing like economy candy shirts like is like they just it's one of the.
Scott: you know It's like a diner and they're selling shirts with like the diners logo on it and it's like.
Scott: I'm not gonna advertise your friggin diner right, but sometimes the business is You know a business that you actually like so much that is is itself a brand.
Rym: I mean I had that sure t-shirt that I wore until it wore out.
Scott: Well, I mean how many people wore Hard Rock Cafe shirts for how long?
Scott: yeah stuff like that.
Scott: So economy candy is that kind of place?
Scott: Except actually good.
Scott: So what they are selling is these candy care packs right now or their new thing?
Scott: Relatively new right?
Scott: So the way it works is you pay some money and they send you a fucking box full of candy in the mail.
Scott: So he purchased we purchased a candy care combo pack for 50 bucks.
Scott: Send a loved one or yourself a candy care, right?
Scott: Right?
Scott: an assortment of candies chocolates dried fruits and nuts.
Scott: Each care package will be unique.
Scott: so I guess they just they.
Scott: basically when the box arrived it looked like someone had Grabbed random shit and thrown it in a box From the candy supply.
Scott: there were small mini candies And a wide variety of them too, right?
Scott: So like there was like a tiny Butterfinger.
Scott: All right, whatever it was like a tiny There's.
Scott: a bunch of someone grabbed a handful of yuzu gummies in there.
Scott: It's like, oh great You know, it's like, you know, there was a full-size Milky Way.
Scott: There was also like a full-size.
Scott: was it called Halva?
Scott: whatever it is.
Scott: Is that the name of it?
Scott: You know that stuff?
Scott: I know that stuff Halva, right?
Scott: Yeah There was a bat a bag of nuts assorted nuts.
Scott: There was a bag of assorted dried fruits because that's the one we chose, right?
Scott: But yeah, it was just like someone filled like a. basically it looks like I think it was a UPS like You and that UPS USPS flat rate.
Rym: Here's a flat rate box filled with assorted candy, right?
Scott: They just fucking filled it with candy and we got it in the mail.
Scott: We opened it and now we have enough candy to last us until Halloween, right?
Scott: So You're gonna get some candies in there.
Scott: You don't want.
Scott: you're gonna get some candies in there.
Scott: You really want and eat really quickly.
Scott: You're gonna get some candies in there that are so good You hold out on them.
Scott: Like I got to eat that that at the right time, you know, so it's not just like, you know you know, I can't go down and buy candy at the you know, the Bodega as easily these days.
Scott: So yeah, if your your candy supply is low and you need some sugar You want some random sugar and not just a whole bunch of this.
Rym: can't be a super picky person Who's like I only eat the Mars bar, right?
Scott: Exactly You know, and we got some pop rocks All kinds of stuff.
Rym: I both love and hate pop rocks.
Scott: exactly We're gonna love and you're gonna love and hate the stuff.
Scott: I Think some of the stuff we got in the box is gonna sit there forever until a visitor eats it.
Scott: Yep And and some of it disappeared as soon as we open.
Rym: the trick is once we can get together again when we all converge on Your apartment for like a football game or something.
Rym: Well, you take that box right out.
Rym: Yeah But don't get any other food out.
Rym: just have that candy out first and then order pizza later.
Scott: People will get desperate and be forced to eat the candy and I'll only put out the candy that I know we're not gonna eat.
Scott: Yeah, so if you're looking for a box of candy, they're shipping.
Rym: So I ran into a conundrum the other day.
Rym: cuz way back like before the quarantine it in winter I was an REI buying some ski stuff and had a clearance rack and on the clearance rack There was some really expensive nice bike jerseys and like chamois and stuff that were like 80% off and There was one item on that entire rack That was not a stupid size and it was a really nice pearl azumi like racing Jersey.
Rym: This is really nice and it was like 80 90 percent off.
Rym: like it was a ridiculous cheap price.
Rym: I just bought it and I lied it looked great, but I buried it in the closet and forgot about it.
Rym: This is getting toward a review.
Rym: I'm not reviewing that bike Jersey though.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: During the quarantine I decided you know what?
Rym: I should get out that bike Jersey for when I go biking and I went to put it on.
Rym: I felt something weird on my Back and I took it off.
Rym: The anti-theft thing was still on it.
Rym: They forgot to take it off when I bought the fucking thing.
Scott: Don't don't don't.
Rym: so I needed a very powerful magnet to be able to remove it.
Rym: I did not own a very.
Scott: You get your own anti-theft removal bring it to the store and shoplift.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So those of you who don't know Most of those anti-theft tags are removed by just a strong magnet.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: That's the secret.
Rym: You don't need anything special.
Rym: So I went online and for $14.
Rym: I bought a DIY mag 40 by 20 millimeter super strong neodymium disc magnet.
Rym: Mmm, it was.
Rym: it was basically the smallest amount of extremely powerful magnet I could buy because I don't want to have a lot of extremely powerful magnets around my house.
Rym: Those things are dangerous as fuck Like.
Rym: I cannot stress enough.
Rym: powerful may habits are non obviously dangerous to you in ways You will not expect do not?
Scott: I have a. I have a like a little sleeve.
Scott: It has like, you know, five or six little neodymium disc magnets.
Scott: Yeah, and it's it came in like a little package with like, you know A foam sleeve and a box to help them in.
Scott: and yeah, if I can keep them in there.
Scott: Yep, so Mike so Mike's are they stay unless I absolutely need.
Scott: if I need them for something I'll take them out.
Rym: So my brothers were the biggest danger of those magnets is if you have more than one you can literally crush yourself with them Like.
Scott: yeah, they're set that each one is separated by a foam disc from each other.
Scott: so you could pry one off when you need It.
Scott: Yep, and when you put it back you have to make sure you don't get your finger in between them.
Rym: Yep, so I my parameters where I wanted one Neodymium magnet that was strong enough to remove anti-theft devices.
Rym: I did not want to have to get multiple of them because I don't want to have multiple of them in my house.
Rym: So I got.
Scott: I have the ones that I have sound weaker than the one you had.
Rym: Oh, this one's.
Rym: so this one's.
Rym: this one's four centimeters in diameter.
Rym: It's pretty big.
Scott: Oh, okay That's bigger than I think.
Scott: the ones I have are maybe two centimeters in diameter.
Scott: but yeah, they're they're.
Scott: they're quite strong like they could hold a Like a sizable stack of paper to a fridge or something like that.
Rym: Oh, no this one If I let it touch the side of my fridge, I would have difficulty getting it off.
Scott: Yeah, these I could probably like slide off the side of the.
Scott: my fridge isn't magnetic at least not in the front.
Rym: Neither is mine only the side.
Scott: I could slide it off the side and then like yank it off.
Rym: This one is powerful enough to where even in its box surrounded by foam It will hold.
Rym: I can hold a stack of paper to it with a piece of non-magnetic Metal just like on the outside of the box.
Rym: So it's off in the corner by itself significant.
Scott: So it sounds like it's stronger than the ones I got.
Scott: Yep, and I got more.
Scott: I got more of them and they're smaller.
Rym: It worked perfectly.
Rym: It was exactly if you if you were in the situation where you need to remove anti-theft devices.
Rym: This is basically the magnet to buy.
Rym: it's small enough to not be that dangerous.
Rym: There's only one so you don't have to worry about crushing yourself.
Scott: unless you're really well You can crush yourself between it and like a piece of iron.
Rym: Yeah I guess you could but it is.
Rym: this is the like Minimal safest option to be able to remove those things on your own if you need to.
Scott: so if you find you like holding it In your hand right and it's in your palm and you're walking down a hallway and there's like a nail in the wall and the Nail comes out of the wall into your hand.
Rym: It's not that strong.
Rym: Okay, it is it is not that strong like.
Rym: honestly It's pretty safe unless you like try to hurt yourself with it.
Rym: primarily though because I only have one of them I would recommend not buying two because one is enough to deal with almost any anti-theft tag you will ever encounter.
Scott: I don't know how we're doing on time, but I'm definitely doing this.
Scott: next thing.
Rym: Let's do like four more then we're done.
Scott: Okay, so in my previous apartment, I had my human scale freedom chair, which I'm sitting in right now.
Scott: It had these plastic casters on the bottom of it.
Scott: Just like every chair.
Scott: Yeah every chair comes with the same casters which are wheels right on the bottom of the chair.
Scott: and In the apartment we had in the house, we had in Beacon right there We were renting I had a plastic mat on the carpeted floor so that the chair would move because on carpet those casters aren't going Anywhere right.
Scott: you need especially not fluffy carpet, right?
Scott: Maybe it's a thin office kind of carpet, but not on a not in a fluffy carpet.
Scott: So you need a plastic mat to roll around in your chair And that was fine because the plastic mat protected the floor.
Scott: in my new apartment I had a hardwood floor and I just really didn't want to do the plastic mat.
Scott: I was just stubborn And I ended up damaging the floor a whole bunch with the the plastic Casters.
Rym: the floor under both mine and Emily's chairs are pretty chunked up because I also.
Rym: they were fine for like four or five years But over time by the time.
Scott: it's over time.
Scott: It's like I was just stubborn.
Scott: I didn't like the plastic mat.
Scott: I was on a hardwood floor the wheels worked and it was insidious.
Rym: like years went by and there was no visible damage.
Rym: So I felt like okay, I'm pretty good, but then more years went by.
Scott: Yeah, when I moved out the suit the guy looking at the apartment definitely noticed that damage to the floor.
Scott: But I got my full security deposit back.
Scott: so whatever not a problem.
Scott: I mean, it's not hard to fix.
Scott: you just sand it and you know stain it or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, or worst case if you replace a few panels in the floor like it's not.
Scott: it wasn't like insane damage But there was noticeably like this circle where the floor was worn out and the rest of the floor is shiny.
Scott: Yeah, okay Anyway, so in the new apartment, we got a we got a floor which is sort of I think like some kind of fake woodish Material right?
Scott: It's a more modern kind of floor.
Scott: It's actually not highest quality.
Scott: like these.
Scott: building is pretty new but some of the planks are like sticking up a little bit.
Scott: It's not the best floor.
Scott: They checked out on the see our building.
Rym: the floor is really good.
Rym: What they cheaped out on is all the fixtures.
Scott: Anyway, I mean they cheaped out on those.
Scott: Really not too much actually.
Scott: But anyway, so I learned my lesson.
Scott: I didn't want to mess up the floor again, right?
Scott: So I said, okay, I'll buy the plastic mat for the floor to not mess it up this time, right?
Scott: So the plastic mat is a plastic mat, it's okay.
Scott: It's not perfect.
Scott: Sometimes you roll off of it.
Scott: Yeah, it's not that big right it had.
Scott: the plastic mat sometimes slides around.
Scott: It's not perfect, but it does what it does.
Scott: I still have it under me at least at this plastic mat flattened out perfectly.
Scott: So it's not bumpy, but I don't want to talk about the plastic mat.
Scott: I want to talk about something else that I learned about after I bought the plastic mat.
Scott: And if I had learned about it before I bought the plastic mat, I might have not bought the plastic mat.
Scott: and what this is?
Scott: You can buy.
Scott: the ones I'm linking to are just the ones I bought but there are many many competing identical products.
Scott: I don't think it matters which one you get.
Scott: they're all the same.
Rym: Yeah And I think your mounts are all the same format too.
Scott: exactly almost every office chair that you buy Has the same exact mount mechanism for attaching the casters slash wheels to the chair.
Scott: You could just tip your chair over and yank them out.
Scott: There's no screwing involved.
Scott: There's no turning or twisting.
Scott: You just pull them straight out, and then you put new ones straight in and that's it.
Scott: That's all you got to do.
Scott: It's it's easy as pie.
Scott: It.
Scott: changing casters is the simplest thing ever and so you can get casters from anywhere from any furniture supply.
Scott: anything, right?
Scott: It's like you could.
Scott: probably if you have like I'm rolling file cabinet You probably take the casters right off of that cabinet and slap them on your chair.
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: It's probably gonna just work.
Scott: There might be a few that have weird non-standard ones, but you know whatever.
Scott: so What these are?
Scott: they're casters.
Scott: they have the same attachment that go into the holes in the bottom of your chair.
Scott: But the wheel part is not some shitty plastic wheel.
Scott: that stuff gets stuck in and all that garbage.
Scott: The wheel part is just a fucking off-the-shelf regular old rollerblade wheel which is brilliant like that's.
Rym: look shitty luggage Luggage has.
Scott: my luggage has skateboard wheels which are different.
Scott: The skateboard wheels make sense for luggage because your luggage is mostly going straight.
Scott: It's moving a long straight distance like a skateboard right.
Scott: the rollerblade wheel a skateboard wheel on the spinning Caster is gonna be very awkward.
Scott: I guess it could work, but it weird right.
Scott: the rollerblade wheel is centered right it lasts a long time It's cheap, and it's soft right.
Scott: It's made of this soft rubber that wears out not this hard plastic That's gonna pick up dirt and grind on the floor.
Scott: Yeah So I mean I guess you could wear out the floor even with these rollerblade wheels On your chair because they could pick up dirt, and then you know sort of rub that dirt around.
Scott: It's definitely a lot less, but definitely a lot lot less.
Scott: you roll a lot smoother.
Scott: They're way more comfortable just moving around.
Scott: They are quieter by a lot.
Scott: the plastic ones rattle like a freaking snake right.
Scott: the rollerblade wheels are smooth like You see in Japan.
Scott: every these people have like office chair races.
Scott: It's like man.
Scott: am I cheating if I slap these on my office chair?
Scott: is that man right?
Scott: Yes, probably But I see no reason that a why don't all office chairs everywhere come standard with these wheels?
Scott: They're better on literally every surface in a home.
Rym: Yeah Why do we know?
Rym: why did we settle on that shitty old caster format?
Scott: the plastic casters are better on exact zero?
Scott: Surfaces that I can imagine compared to the rollerblade wheels.
Scott: the rollerblade wheels aren't that expensive.
Scott: This is these are 40 less than $40 for a set of five.
Rym: I guess I spent a thousand dollars on the chair.
Rym: I can spend another $40 on some wheel right?
Scott: I guess if you have a really cheapo chair that was $40 then it might not be worth it.
Scott: But I think I've seen cheaper ones than this.
Scott: you don't have to get these ones right.
Scott: you can also Just buy like you go to the hardware store get casters And then get wheels at the rollerblades to a sporting goods store and put them together.
Rym: That'd be tough because rollerblade wheels have a particular mounting through their axel.
Scott: If you have an office chair because you're a nerd and you spend a lot of time in it you need these yep like yesterday Even if you and I bet those stupid gamer chairs don't even have this shit, and they absolutely should right Rollerblade wheels on your office chair.
Scott: it is Game-changing if you spend a lot of time in an office chair And it will protect your floor and everything's better.
Scott: the only thing is that make sure your chair is height adjustable Which every chair is fucking height adjustable?
Scott: But just in case because they're hot you're gonna lift your chair up.
Rym: no every game every damn gamer chair I'm looking at has garbage casters, but the casters have like Gamer mouse looking shit on the sides of them like rims, but they're still just casters.
Scott: Anyway, the point is it will raise your chair like a few centimeters up higher than the casters that were originally on there.
Rym: Yeah, so if your chair is all the way at the bottom you probably have to.
Scott: you'll have to lower your seat.
Scott: Yeah, if your chair is all the way at the bottom Then this is gonna make your chair higher.
Scott: if your chair is not all the way at the bottom You're gonna have to lower your seat a little bit, otherwise you'll feel higher.
Scott: It's like just enough to make you feel higher.
Rym: when you put these on all right I'll do one more cuz we've got a little over an hour here And then you can do one more if you want or it could end, but I'll see if I have anything.
Scott: That's that's as good as rollerblade wheels on your show
Rym: got power strips computers and everything And I when I was redoing this room I bought a bunch of cable channels And I really just like cable managed the fuck out of my computer desk like I was done with cake because I got too many audio cables everywhere.
Rym: But the power cables are always tough because power strips are always awkward and there's never enough holes.
Rym: there can't be enough holes for all Things I gotta plug in.
Rym: so I bought these Trond brand power strips.
Rym: but the deal with them is that one the Plug that goes into the wall for the power strip can rotate so you don't have to worry about awkward positioning And it's flat.
Rym: so it'll be flush.
Rym: nice - they are.
Rym: they have a bunch of USBs in them So they'll just charge USB with like a real like the same kind of thing that's in an anchor.
Rym: Which great computer.
Rym: I got a lot of USB stuff like the spotlight.
Rym: I don't need to plug that into the computer or one of my chargers like it's plugged into the power strip But three they come built into.
Rym: them are four holes to screw them into a surface permanently.
Rym: So I bought a bunch of them, and I mounted them into the inside of my desk.
Scott: Okay, so they're mounted above.
Rym: so all my power cables for the computer.
Rym: now Everything goes down onto the desk and never reaches the floor.
Rym: It's all plugged into the desk.
Rym: It's like there's power outlets built into the desk.
Rym: These are super cheap.
Rym: They're like 20 bucks like that's.
Rym: that's what a real power strip cost.
Rym: if you buy power strips that are $5 They probably don't have like surge protection or anything in them But these just work, and they're great, and I've had no problems with them.
Rym: They've been installed for like a year at this point with no problems.
Rym: they're not wearing out and I'd recommend these to anyone who needs to get more holes in their desk and Wants to clean.
Rym: do better cable management.
Scott: All right, that's it.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: They're great.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I'll do this.
Scott: this one won't take long all right.
Scott: So I used to buy dental floss which I still buy right.
Scott: but And then they came out.
Scott: you know all these like plastic toothpicks right instead of wooden ones.
Scott: And then they have a little piece of floss on the other end right.
Scott: so you get the floss end and then the pick end.
Rym: Yeah, I used to use those.
Scott: yeah I tried lots of different brands of those and you know with varying results the one I like the most.
Scott: they stopped making Right.
Scott: you know they got some of them.
Scott: They're all different varying qualities of plastic and floss on those.
Scott: But then I discovered this which is really just like beat everything And they're super nerdy and super great.
Scott: these are opal picks.
Scott: I guess is the brand name and what it is is basically little plastic swords.
Rym: the little plastic sword They have like a hilt and everything.
Scott: Exactly the little plastic swords, and they're super thin to get between your teeth And they are the best toothpicks.
Scott: I've ever had you get between the teeth.
Scott: they poke out anything That's poked in there.
Scott: the wooden ones compared to these are garbage the ones you don't need the ones with floss on the end because These can poke right between.
Scott: they're so thin.
Scott: they're cool swords I don't know you.
Scott: you buy them to give you a shit ton of them.
Scott: They come in these little plastic things.
Scott: so you take one of the plastic things.
Scott: There's like 20 swords in it.
Scott: you put it in your bag.
Scott: You always have a toothpick if you really need it.
Scott: But basically I've never.
Scott: sometimes you get across situation like you got toothpick And you just can't get that thing out of your teeth.
Scott: That's never happened.
Scott: that the plastic sword always succeeds in cleaning out the teeth the sake of world revolution.
Scott: I guess it could be considered wasteful or not environmentally friendly or not.
Scott: a good deal Financially based on how much money these cost or where you get them from?
Scott: It compared to other toothpicks, but in terms of effectiveness coolness and those other sorts of features Best toothpicks all right.
Scott: clean your teeth till your teeth of the sword.
Scott: Haha.
Rym: I think that was a show.
Scott: Okay, if you think somebody should make a twitch Stream or YouTube stream or whatever that is nothing, but this You Do the work to make that happen and maybe I will help you.
Rym: yeah Yeah, we're scared.
Rym: if nothing else as soon as we can meet together in person with maybe we'll do it ourselves with some board game Stuff we'll see all right.
Rym: Okay This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Heidi communicate with Marty green.
Rym: Yeah, just like a dude guy chartavish and linky G You hold the key to my heart But she packed my suitcase and sent me on my way.
Rym: Clinton Walton Jay Vance Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drove and ladder Nicholas Brando Chris mid give sailor Vista the thirst for hydrated Ganon Cassandra Valenzuela dread Lily Tenebra Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Shervin von Hurl and a whole bunch of people who don't want me to say their name.
Rym: I Don't have anything new to say.
Rym: It's only been two days.
Rym: I haven't really been outside.
Rym: Stay safe out there.
Rym: We'll see what happens with a lot of these conventions canceling and whatever online things we do.
Rym: Let us know if you're interested in us actually doing this like QVC nonsense idea we have because as soon as we can get together we will probably do it with some board games.
Rym: it'll probably be.
Rym: I Don't want to say good or bad or interesting or weird.
Rym: We'll just say it'll be a thing.
Rym: But anyway, I leave you with.
Scott: East is East and West is West and the wrong one.
Scott: I have chose.
Scott: Let's go where you'll keep on wearing those Buttons and bows.
Rym: Don't bury me where the puppy pee something.
Rym: la la la.
Rym: let's all go to a taco.
Rym: show My nose.
Rym: you like making buttons and bows.
Rym: I love you in buckskin la da da da da da da.
Rym: Everybody My bones denounce the fearful trouncing la la la la mold it grows.
Rym: But a soos a pom-ka-poo said I'll pad now ha and penny holes.
Rym: You look funny buttons and bow.