Rym: It's Wednesday September 30th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about the Thunder cats.
Rym: so If you listen to or you don't like live under a rock despite the world being on fire and the rise of fascism and everything Star Wars squadrons is coming out like in two days.
Scott: So this is basically a game, you know, it is a maybe is it the culmination of GeekNights' Unrealized potential?
Scott: where is we taught it?
Scott: We talked about every genre of game that had not been.
Scott: you know That had been dead for a long time and had no one had brought back like what on the panel to have not been able To record that like.
Rym: I wish we had a recording slides.
Rym: I do have the slides.
Rym: I. we should bring those slides out.
Scott: that panel follow up but unlike the that panel We can't redo because it's not true anymore.
Rym: No, no There is very little untapped space now in the gaming world and there are other reasons why things don't get made.
Rym: But yeah, the point of that panel was like there's all these obvious Guaranteed to make money games you should just make based on previous games that were popular.
Rym: That's just no.
Rym: one did for some reason and this is the penultimate one remake tie fighter x-wing x-wing verse tie fighter x-wing Alliance on modern tech.
Scott: and When did so?
Scott: the last game the last free.
Scott: there are some free space shooting games out there, right?
Rym: Yeah, some of them are just like.
Rym: they're really just more like MMOs or They're not good.
Scott: Oh, that's that one.
Scott: We're like docking.
Scott: is really it to be like really careful docking and stuff that actually does not narrow it down that much?
Scott: No, it's it's one people in the sky Man, oh, that's the scam Kickstarter one.
Rym: Yeah, but there is some flying around in that one.
Scott: Anyway, the point is there are some recent games that are technically free space shooters, right?
Scott: But they're not really free space.
Rym: They're not what we wanted.
Rym: We wanted x-wings anti fighters in a very particular way, right?
Scott: It doesn't have to be extra, you know, there are like.
Scott: there are some Flight.
Scott: there's like ace combat type games with your flight, but that's not in space.
Scott: Right?
Scott: That's air right?
Scott: It's not the same thing You know, so there were some games that were like Like sort of descent like remakes in a fashion right but descent is inside.
Scott: It's still free space shooter, but it's inside right?
Scott: You don't go outdoors in a big open area, right?
Scott: But anyway, yeah So it's been.
Scott: when did x-wing Alliance come out?
Rym: Oh my god x-wing Alliance is so old.
Scott: I don't even remember x-wing Alliance came out in 1999. so it's been 21 years since we have had a game in this series of Live out your fantasy of being a Star Wars fighter pilot for either rebels or the Empire.
Rym: I was like hyper obsessed with TIE fighter as a kid.
Rym: that came with so good.
Scott: Here we go Finally in Friday two days from the recording of this podcast.
Scott: tomorrow for most of you it comes out.
Scott: It's coming from EA which is bad, but somehow I don't know how this happened.
Scott: They if you look at all the information available about this game Somehow on paper EA has done everything right.
Scott: the game's $40 a reasonable price probably too cheap.
Scott: In fact, considering what it cost to make games these days There doesn't seem to be any DLC.
Scott: that doesn't seem to be any pay to win.
Rym: There's no microtransactions of any kind and the fact that they said that in the original press release like they knew People like like the people like us we're all watching that early press release just waiting for it to be terrible And they were like two minutes in.
Scott: they're like no microtransactions No, no, no appears to be a ski again a skill based game where nothing has been Simplified or dumbed down in any way shape or form and all of the preview teaser videos of the game Show things that only excite and do not disappoint.
Scott: So my expectations are still not high Because I've been burned how the world works.
Scott: But But oh, I'm still gonna pay $40 and try to find out on Friday.
Rym: So and this game supports VR like my dream was to have a VR headset and play the game.
Scott: optional optional VR support.
Scott: Optional hotels support.
Scott: everything is lining up perfectly.
Scott: So we're gonna play this.
Scott: come join our squadron.
Scott: I'm gonna play with mouse and keyboard But if it becomes a real thing and our squadron sticks together and keeps playing then I'll go buy some sticks.
Rym: This means you got to pull your weight.
Rym: so my problem is independent of that.
Rym: Microsoft had to fucking release a flight simulator and basically every hot ass which also Microsoft flight simulator has not been released in how long?
Scott: yeah, and you know what?
Rym: I really want to play that too.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I don't have a hot ass because they are sold out everywhere on earth.
Rym: Yeah, that's fine because until Microsoft flight simulator and Star Wars quadrants.
Rym: There was almost nothing.
Rym: anyone needed a hot ass for You could use like X plane or so those Simulators, but you said the word nerdy.
Rym: Those are not what?
Rym: not that many people cared enough to spend like hundreds of dollars on basically a joystick?
Rym: Yeah, and even if you did what games you gonna play with it the one game you cared about?
Rym: There's a reason why I only owned two joysticks.
Rym: So they were buried like deep under the bed like in a container Covered in dust because I have had not had a need for a joystick in Well over a decade.
Rym: so my what happened to me?
Rym: We're not gonna review Star Wars or talk about it because the game's gonna come out.
Rym: We'll talk about that on Tuesday.
Scott: Oh, it's endless space.
Scott: Is that the one that's one of them?
Scott: No, it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: that's a strategy game.
Scott: It's not though.
Rym: Oh, I'm think there's a game that has a name like that that I played and yeah That's the one I'm trying to think of.
Scott: I can't remember it right now.
Scott: It's probably my elite date.
Rym: elite dangerous That's one of them.
Rym: That's not good.
Rym: I did not enjoy elite dangerous at all.
Scott: Elite dangerous is the existing free space shooter where you have to dock very carefully.
Rym: So I go and take out these joysticks.
Rym: one of them just doesn't work at all.
Rym: It's USB like one.
Rym: That's how old it is.
Rym: It just didn't work.
Scott: It just doesn't work like just throw it out in the garbage.
Rym: Yeah, I threw it out in the garbage.
Rym: I plugged it in and Windows was like I don't recognize that device.
Scott: I don't think you just need a driver.
Scott: You just need driver.
Rym: Yeah, good that I don't think a driver existed for it.
Scott: That's not broken.
Scott: that just means that Windows can't automatically find the driver.
Scott: no, no, no No, nothing.
Rym: I got the warning of there's something wrong with this device too.
Rym: Like it was there was some problem with it.
Scott: I Have feeling if you did a driver it would have worked.
Scott: It also really has nothing happened.
Rym: It also only has two buttons on it.
Rym: So it wouldn't have even worked for this purpose.
Scott: Yeah, you need any quite a few buttons to put to play a Star Wars, but the other thing in that box was a mad cat v1 stick.
Rym: So I got that one out that one has twisting.
Rym: it has the throttle in it like that'll actually work like it's basically the Shittiest possible modern USB joystick.
Rym: It does just work.
Scott: However, I'm looking at a picture of this stick on the internet.
Scott: And yeah, that's it's the bare minimum.
Rym: It's the bare minimum.
Rym: It's the bottom of the.
Scott: it's got.
Scott: it's got a trigger It's got five buttons and it's got more than five buttons.
Scott: There's five gray buttons for the.
Rym: yeah, there's also a pinky button.
Rym: this had a fire button and a hat.
Scott: Oh, there's more on the front.
Scott: He has one hat in the middle there.
Scott: It's also got a. There's a pinky button.
Scott: Where's the pinky buttons?
Rym: throttles on the back?
Rym: You're just like a little lever.
Scott: Oh It's that little tiny thing that doesn't even look like a throttle that looks like a foot.
Rym: Yeah, but it is.
Rym: It'll be good enough.
Rym: The only problem with this thing.
Rym: It works like.
Rym: I tested it and I also fixed it.
Rym: However, it was so old because I bought this to play like x-wing Alliance.
Scott: What do you be better to just do?
Scott: mouse and keyboard?
Scott: No, fuck.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: You're gonna be awful at this game with mouse and keyboard.
Scott: keyboards got a lot a lot of buttons.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think you're gonna be able to hit me at any point in this game with a mouse and keyboard.
Scott: I mean if you use mouse and keyboard the control setup is use the mouse for the pitch in the yaw, right?
Scott: Yeah, and then you use your you know your triggers on the mouse for firing right and you know.
Scott: And then on the keyboard you got WASD basically for strafing left right up down right up down strafe.
Scott: And then you use QE for roll left and right.
Scott: And then you got to control your throttle maybe with the mouse wheel or the thumb buttons on the side of the mouse All right, then I can switch weapons like it starts.
Rym: Here's the real problem.
Rym: You're gonna.
Rym: Yeah, is it what do you want?
Rym: Do you want where?
Rym: if you keep moving the mouse forward you keep going like Turning forward like rolling down or whatever you're gonna do or do you want it to be where?
Rym: if you move the mouse a certain Amount it's like holding out at the top of a joystick because neither of those options works worth a shit.
Scott: That's true because like a joystick right is I think they're going And it's gonna be a problem.
Scott: Yeah, if you have an analog stick like on a gamepad, right?
Scott: It's like yeah, it re-centers.
Scott: You know if you hold it all the way forward It's gonna keep going right.
Scott: a mouse doesn't re-center Exactly.
Rym: So that's where I think you're gonna have a lot of trouble.
Rym: You're not gonna be able to maneuver very well.
Rym: You're gonna be like someone playing doom Without a wonder.
Scott: if I could play really shittily on this SN 30 plus you might be better off using a joy gamepad instead like use the Use the switch pro controller, but SN 30 plus has everything more than has everything right?
Scott: I wonder.
Rym: I think you'll be they do.
Rym: they did say that controllers are supported.
Rym: I think a controller.
Scott: sure they're supported but how good.
Scott: I'm trying to think like, okay So I have an analog stick right for a pitch in y'all, right?
Scott: I actually got two analog sticks I don't know.
Scott: I'll use the other one for and then I can just strafe with the d-pad.
Scott: How do I roll with LNR?
Scott: Accelerate and decelerate with the other LNR and then I got four more buttons for stuff.
Rym: There isn't really strafing in a game like this though.
Scott: the way yeah You when you're you're you move straight up like like you're like you're.
Rym: that's not something that's high fighter lets you do.
Rym: I don't think this game lets you do that either.
Rym: you had a for descent.
Scott: descent lets you do.
Scott: What does that?
Rym: none of these other games do?
Scott: Oh that makes it easier.
Scott: then that means four things.
Scott: I don't have to map.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, it's just forward and just straight.
Scott: let see but that's the thing is actually consider descent right that you need.
Scott: I consider having all those controls to be what a free space shooter is because if you actually had a Spaceship it could do all those things.
Scott: yeah But I have any free space shooters.
Rym: the genre usually means things more like Star Wars games where that is not true.
Rym: None of those Star Wars games had that kind of motion.
Scott: I thought you could move straight.
Scott: Actually just takes off.
Scott: it just goes straight up right it doesn't go off a ramp like a.
Rym: you know Valkyrie Did you actually play x-wing and tie fighter?
Scott: Watch Star Wars x-wing go straight up.
Rym: Yeah, but we're talking about the games.
Rym: the games did not have that.
Rym: They never had that.
Scott: I'll have to go look that up.
Rym: I think your brain is playing tricks on you.
Scott: Let's move on to the news anyway.
Rym: Yeah the problem with his joystick was it was sticky like the buttons made the sickening sound when I pushed them and I had to take the whole thing apart and like clean it with mineral oil and solvents and like air dusters and everything to make it not feel disgusting to use.
Rym: And That seems to happen with joysticks that don't have their buttons pressed often enough.
Rym: in general That was the only thing I was getting to.
Rym: the joystick was disgusting, but it does work.
Rym: So you got any news.
Scott: What was my news?
Scott: yeah actual anime news.
Scott: here we go right long awaited the movie Lupin.
Scott: the third the first.
Scott: That's a mouthful.
Scott: G kids licensed it as expected and they're releasing it in theaters In the u.s.
Rym: It's the 3d CG Lupin.
Rym: I'm pretty excited about it.
Scott: what I saw looked at rate Yep at the online and a see Earlier this year.
Scott: We saw like the first.
Scott: five to ten minutes of it looks terrific.
Scott: I've been eagerly awaiting this movie.
Scott: I want to watch it.
Scott: But the problem is yeah, New York unlike other states is wisely not allowing people to go to movie theaters.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so if I zoom in on this map here, there's like terrifying deadly showings all over America.
Rym: Do not go to these showings if you're listening to this, but if you zoom in There's nothing in New York Not anyone in the whole state.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: however While it is going to be in select theaters, October 18th dub 21st sub I guess if you find a movie theater, you can go to all alone safely.
Scott: somehow I mean, I can't stop you, right?
Scott: Don't go to the movies Do not go to the movies theater.
Scott: Maybe someone will do it an outdoor showing or something.
Scott: Oh drive-in Yeah, who knows anyway?
Scott: the point is That they are going to soon after I think possibly as soon as December.
Scott: it will be available on.
Scott: I'm not 100% sure of the date, but it will be available in.
Scott: You know bought to buy like, you know streaming or booray discs or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, figure out where and then you can watch it that way in your house yes, so No, you know, this will be like the first time I think G kids has released a Japanese animation and a distributed in the u.s.
Scott: That we will not see it in the theaters and immediately do an episode on it.
Scott: You're gonna have to wait a little.
Scott: you have to wait a little bit, but For some reason I think we're probably just gonna say my prediction of my judging anime by its cover.
Scott: It's going to be a cookie cutter By the book Lupin movie that is of high quality, but not legendary.
Scott: It's no food, but right now it will not divert from the Lupin formula But it will also not be.
Scott: it will be a excellent execution of the Lupin formula with terrific Animation and voice acting and such and Well worth your time because an excellent execution of the Lupin formula is worth everyone's time.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I'll even enjoy a really bad Lupin movie Like I'll go deep into the Lupin library before it's unwatchable to me.
Rym: So yep I'm a Lupin movie that's just right middle of the road.
Rym: That is a must-see anime movie That's right.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: So some other news.
Rym: I actually have watched most of the first season of the owl house Which is a I had never even heard of this.
Scott: and still you started posting pictures.
Rym: It was really big.
Rym: It's a Disney TV show.
Rym: Like there's a whole story behind.
Scott: I never even I didn't even know it existed until you posted owl photos.
Rym: Okay, that's I don't do that.
Rym: I think you might literally be living under a rock first.
Rym: You think that there's translating movement in TIE fighter and now you've never heard of this Disney show.
Rym: Anyway, it is a kids show.
Rym: It's Alex Hirsch.
Rym: Like it's a kids show about a girl who goes to a fantasy world to become a witch and sort of like lives with this witch who doesn't Follow the rules and a demon who's kind of her pet but also her friend and pretty standard kids.
Rym: you're like.
Rym: I'm not gonna really get into like what it's really about or anything but having watched most of it what I will say is that as a kids show it is really really good and Despite being a kids show.
Rym: I am enjoying it to a very high degree.
Rym: Like I would say it is Twice as funny as Gravity Falls and aimed at the same demographic as Gravity Falls.
Scott: Mmm, like I mean the people who enjoyed Gravity Falls are how many years older than they were when they watched Gravity Falls?
Rym: Yeah But the people who would have watched Gravity Falls when it came out like Gravity Falls kids show had some stuff for us had some Stuff for older people, but it was really in the end like a kids show.
Rym: But the Owl House is sort of you know, how like Simpsons earlier seasons like during the Golden Era We're just dense with jokes and dense with writing and like just like there was a density of Entertainment that is lacking from later Simpsons.
Rym: The Owl House compared to Gravity Falls is Extremely dense in that regard.
Rym: it trusts you to catch jokes.
Rym: It moves pretty quick.
Rym: It's Really really funny and the writing is really good.
Rym: and I would say like just watch the show go get it and watch it Without even listening to anything else.
Rym: I would say because I get that at some point Scott will watch it.
Rym: we'll do a full review.
Rym: but Not only is it really good.
Rym: It's also pretty gay just openly like characters just gay getting relationships.
Rym: That's totally fine.
Rym: it's very much a modern kids show and it's also continuing this trend that Gravity Falls was also a part of where Shows that are aimed at kids are aimed at kids.
Rym: without being Insipid or saccharine.
Scott: this show gets dark and weird like darker than you would expect and Weirder than you would expect and I mean Adventure Time already set that bar right and that probably wasn't even You know the start of it.
Rym: Yeah It definitely wasn't.
Rym: but we've seen this trend bit by bit.
Rym: more and more of more and more properties are Willing to be the level of dark and weird that actually resonates with kids.
Rym: Like when I was a kid like.
Rym: I watch shows like Thundercats.
Rym: They were okay But the darker and weirder shows were the more I was into them and a lot of adults especially in the 80s and early 90s really underestimated how Complex of a story or how deep a show could get?
Rym: For kids where kids would still enjoy it.
Rym: kind of like how kids like scary movies kids probably.
Scott: I don't think it's a. I don't think it's a trend anymore, right?
Scott: I think it's been just the way of things for quite a while.
Rym: I don't think it has been because for every show like Gravity Falls or our our Owl House.
Rym: There is a raft of just Completely saccharine insipid nonsense that like we're not gonna watch like what?
Rym: I don't go on Netflix and look at like all the kids shows that are out right now.
Scott: I mean the only time I really see stuff like that is like stuff for like preschoolers like Peppa Pig or whatever And that's not even Peppa Pig's actually not too bad.
Scott: Yeah, but I guess But you're not gonna watch Peppa Pig.
Scott: No, right, but it's not.
Scott: Peppa Pig isn't just like nothing, you know.
Scott: It's actually like if you have a preschool kid, they're watching Peppa Pig.
Scott: It's like I.
Rym: I do enjoy how the world of the Owl House is basically a City that was built in the decaying body of a giant who died at some point in the distant past Mm-hmm, like.
Rym: that's basically the setting.
Rym: So check this show out like.
Rym: I'm really enjoying it and it's sort of Infiltrating my like memetic life and I'm referencing it a lot even when I don't intend to and that's usually.
Rym: that's how Adventure time was when I first started watching it Scratching a very similar itch to how the early Adventure Time episodes sort of dragged me in the only kids show thing.
Rym: That is annoying about this show is that it has a moral in every episode.
Rym: But the moral is always the same even if it's very brief and doesn't get in the way.
Rym: and the moral is always one of the characters will face a moral conundrum and do the wrong thing like uppercase W wrong thing that will cause Extremely dangerous situations.
Rym: at some point that character will admit what they did wrong Apologize and then work to fix it.
Rym: and it happens Like it's like the utensil stairs that scene in every episode.
Scott: Mmm, that's a good formula.
Rym: Yeah, it works pretty well Like it's a good lesson for kids to learn while they're also like getting invested in these pixies that want to steal people's skin for undisclosed reasons.
Rym: but anyway things Of the day what he got What was my thing of the day?
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: So if you're listening to this odds are like nearly a hundred percent chance that you do not have to wait.
Scott: But we have to wait another two to three hours.
Scott: I imagine it for the release.
Rym: I mean, I've been waiting my entire life.
Scott: album of the century Neil's is sir.
Scott: Ega's sister Ega sister Ega's mouth dreams Right, so we had.
Scott: we had mouth moods Right.
Rym: Well if the first ones was mouth sounds which was a lot of smash mouth Matt like mix up mashup type things.
Rym: mouth silence was when the genre like this series of albums moved from.
Rym: I appreciate this music because it's weird and speaks to the weird things that I'm into and references the things I like to.
Rym: This is music that I will listen to even if it is not weird and memetic music like mouth.
Rym: Silence is a good album.
Scott: Yeah, mouth moods is legendary, right that is the most.
Scott: Masters is from what you have.
Scott: tiger the tiger.
Scott: Those are the two but like all of them are great.
Scott: But those two definitely stand out amongst, you know the rest.
Rym: Yeah for sure.
Rym: I still remember one.
Rym: so that was you were playing.
Rym: we were playing like music where people were coming into a PAX panel and Tiger played and we had like three different people email us after the panel to be like, you know, the panel was good, but whatever What the fuck was that sound song you played?
Rym: that wasn't quite eye of the tiger.
Scott: Oh, there's also the 300 megabytes one.
Rym: Oh, yeah, QVC person selling the computer Oh, but there's lots of problems.
Scott: They're actually all really good like yeah but anyway, so You know whenever someone who just puts out the hits right puts out the hits here.
Scott: It comes three years in the making Mouth dreams, there is a small trailer video you can watch but by the time you hear this The whole thing will be out for you to go listen to.
Scott: so there you go.
Scott: Just go listen to that album on repeat for however long the website has.
Rym: every time he releases one of these albums He always makes a website with some sort of animated gif thing.
Rym: But this one captures the aesthetic of a geocities page that is under construction.
Scott: Yep One other thing is that you know.
Scott: on my Twitter it's just been a we.
Scott: I love it the most when I see The different internet communities of you know, different cultures coming together, right?
Scott: Cuz that's sort of what GeekNights is all about right?
Scott: We got we got their tech We got your gaming we get your anime, right?
Scott: But when I look around at other communities, they're focused on one thing.
Scott: It's like oh I look at those people over there.
Scott: They're anime people.
Scott: That's all they are.
Scott: They go deeper on anime than we do way deep and I appreciate that and that's why I pay attention to them And I see what they're up to to get my anime feed, but you know sure they play some video games But they're not talking about like, you know Pareto frontiers over there video games, you know, they're playing fall guys in between their animes, right?
Scott: You know.
Scott: and yeah, they're talking.
Scott: I got computers over there.
Scott: Maybe they're trying to buy a video card or something, but they're anime people.
Scott: They're not you know.
Scott: rendering videos and programming anything in C and using CUDA cores to you know, do it, right?
Scott: And the same thing goes right in the tech community.
Scott: Yeah, they might watch an anime, but they're not anime people they're tech people.
Scott: But when it comes to if you look at the tweet Right announcing this album in the replies because you see I see replies When I follow both sides of the reply, that's how Twitter works, right?
Scott: I've seen everyone from like New York Rangers podcasters to like video game developers Comic book people like the web community is pretty deep in there.
Scott: yeah, like all these people across the spectrum of nerds and good human beings are all up and like Like.
Scott: where has this album been.
Scott: give it to me now?
Scott: Why do I have to wait?
Scott: Oh my you're right.
Scott: It's like, you know Neil is like the great.
Scott: He's like the secret, you know cultural phenomenon.
Rym: He's one of the most prolific memetic artists in human history.
Scott: Well, I don't think it's his.
Scott: I don't think it's really his prolific miss cuz.
Scott: he actually doesn't put out lots of stuff.
Scott: It's that he hits so many home runs and usually the people we seeing hitting so many home runs are people who are like, you know have like a formula and a focus like we talk about people like You know
Rym: Well like science Saru and they're just cranking out these anime movies like everyone.
Scott: It's just gonna be every single anime movie they make.
Scott: you know Miyazaki at least and not his son, but Good movie Right, you know, it's like certain people but they're they're making one kind of thing and they make it over and over.
Scott: Neil makes lots of different kinds of things.
Scott: He doesn't make them on a big Hollywood Level right with big budgets, but he hits the core like the core is perfect every time.
Scott: and that core He hits hits all the nerds.
Scott: It doesn't hit some of the hits everybody.
Scott: and then in our culture of millennial and perhaps younger nerder?
Rym: Yeah like you look you go back through like his body of work and you're like wait the same guy who made like Potter puppet pals made mouthmoods and Lemon demon the band what it's like.
Scott: then just go look at the list of things.
Scott: This dude is made and also His family is also Extremely talented, right?
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: Amis is there any work?
Scott: Yeah, didn't she work on the gravity falls?
Rym: Yeah, I don't.
Rym: even I should see if she's involved in the Owl House at all.
Rym: Cuz it's not out of the realm, but I don't actually know.
Rym: I didn't check.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like and I don't know who else is in their family.
Scott: What do I know about them, right?
Scott: I only know the two people in their family who are creative geniuses.
Scott: So it's Yep, definitely the other room.
Rym: Emmys is Erica is in the credits.
Rym: So she has something to do with the Owl House.
Rym: I gotta go see what she did Yep, but yeah, she worked on.
Scott: she did storyboards in season two of Gravity Falls, so so uh tonight my evening is just to sit down.
Scott: whatever those whatever they're the sister egg of parents.
Scott: I don't know what their family structure is.
Scott: raise those children needs to write a book on raising children.
Scott: It's home.
Rym: Say So my evening will pretty much be just sitting down with a nice drink some good headphones.
Scott: I'm just gonna listen to this album I'm sure that's what I'm gonna do and then and then two evenings from now listen to that album in my x-wing.
Scott: X-wings have stereos, right?
Rym: I assume so.
Scott: Yeah My thing is actually are to play Neil Cicierega.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So this is more topical to the world being on fire.
Rym: It's a comic.
Rym: I'll just link to it.
Rym: Nate Powell.
Rym: It's all one long web page.
Rym: You scroll down.
Rym: It's just a comic that just goes on and on and on all the way down to the bottom and what it's about is A lot of things.
Rym: but it basically at the top level talks about how the way military clothing is and police clothing is in the United States like the uniforms they wear and the perceptions of those uniforms and the codes around them and the intersection with white supremacy and the rise of like paramilitary nonsense and fascists in the United States and Sort of.
Rym: shows this like very slow and methodical progression toward where we are now in a really fascinating way.
Rym: This comic might make you think it's a somewhat disturbing and frightening comic.
Rym: That's on purpose because it's a disturbing and frightening world right now But I highly recommend you read this comic all the way to the bottom Even if you are made uncomfortable by some of the things that it's talking about.
Rym: I think it'll hit home in particular if you have police officers or Military people in your family because you'll be much more familiar with some of these things.
Rym: Okay At a moment GeekNights.
Rym: We're gonna be live today and yet another con this weekend on Saturday 7 p.m Pacific time 10 p.m.
Rym: Eastern Time.
Rym: play dirty to win.
Rym: We took us 55 Fifty nine point five nine panel and we scrunched it down to 24 minutes and 37 seconds.
Rym: and That's it.
Rym: It's gonna be in the main mag vest twitch stream.
Rym: We will be hanging out in that stream in some capacity answering questions and doing whatever.
Rym: It'll be a good time.
Rym: You should check out the rest of what mag West 2020 online has to offer because can't go to a real con Might as well go to an online con.
Scott: And also unless something happens to me that I do not know is gonna happen because life is unpredictable like that We will read the tale of Genji point some day and then we will discuss it in an episode on this show that will be probably not get that many downloads or anything, but we'll simply get a lot of laughs and jeers and sarcastic quips from the listener Because we finally we finally did it.
Rym: Just do not do not think that we are not reading the tale of Genji because we're reading other things.
Rym: We're just not reading right now.
Rym: This is not the world.
Scott: the last
Rym: time
Scott: the last book the last book that I have read a page of was the tale of Genji,
Rym: so yep, the last Fiction book that I've read a page of the tale of Genji I've been reading nonfiction but that is because that is in the service of either GeekNights projects or role-playing games.
Rym: I Read a big chunk of blades in the dark because we just started a new blades in the dark.
Scott: board game rulebooks Don't count either.
Rym: No, those are definitely do not count.
Rym: I've been referencing the 1882 rulebook to double-check some things that I forgot and I was wrong about a rule that I wasn't thinking about in my head that I should have paid more attention to.
Scott: but anyway I'm not.
Scott: I am not good at that one.
Scott: I am okay at that one That says I think it's the 18xx game.
Scott: I am worst at.
Scott: So Yeah, I got too used to that the speedy ones the slow one kills.
Scott: Yeah, the first time any ones I wanted us it's like when they were playing the speedy ones.
Scott: I was like too fast slow down.
Scott: Let me work my two trains and then it's like oh you want to slow down, huh?
Scott: And I'm like, no, I mean the one.
Rym: now We're in stock around five and there's still two three trades for fucking sale.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's.
Rym: I don't know how to navigate that shit.
Scott: I got no idea.
Rym: if I float FC, you know SC, you know, what happens?
Rym: a third three train appears.
Rym: That'll make sure the D never comes out.
Rym: so yeah follow Scott on YouTube.
Rym: follow me on YouTube.
Rym: we're doing stuff.
Rym: We're not gonna talk about some of the projects we're working on until we actually do them because they might fail like I don't know.
Rym: so Stay tuned.
Rym: We're working on stuff.
Rym: and now I guess it's just time to talk about Thundercats cuz We never talked about Thundercats at any point.
Rym: at most we did a show once about the shows we watched as kids.
Rym: I'm sure we mentioned Thundercats at some point in that but we definitely did not dwell on Thundercats Mm-hmm.
Scott: So Thundercats for me.
Scott: It's like you think about the the big 80s Toy selling cartoons that I watched.
Scott: a lot of right and you know, you get your human You got your Voltron you got your this GI Joe, but I didn't really watch that so much.
Rym: I watched a lot of GI Joe.
Scott: Yeah, I only watched a little bit.
Scott: Thundercats and what was the last one?
Scott: transformers?
Scott: Yeah, obviously she was like the big Yeah, but I'm talking about like, you know, the cheer.
Scott: I wasn't as popular
Rym: Popular I want to say
Scott: Yeah, anyway, there's a now there
Rym: was a limited set of like mass mainstream Mainstream kind of bad animated kids show from our
Scott: action adventure, you know violent ones
Rym: Like there's all these
Scott: other sci-fi robots warriors soldiers, you know stereotypically Masculine in some way kind of thing.
Rym: There were a lot of second tier ones that all had niche audiences like mask or I guess bionicles.
Rym: that might have been a little later even Bad ago, I think was way later.
Rym: I think it was later But there were all those detail shows.
Rym: but Thundercats was one of the a-tier shows for like when we were in the 80s as kids And not early 90s you go and you're in your elementary school or middle school.
Rym: Every kid knows the deal with Thundercats, even if they do not I don't know if Ghostbusters counts in the same category or not.
Scott: But anyway, I think I would.
Rym: I don't know I don't think it does.
Scott: I mean I'll say no huge show doesn't care Ninja Turtles.
Scott: Yeah Turtles was 90s though Ninja Turtles was night.
Rym: Yeah, we're talking 80s right here.
Scott: We're talking right?
Scott: So basically the things that were like post set like post Hanna-barbera pre Ninja Turtles that that's the zone right anyway.
Scott: See it for me at least Thundercats was actually like the biggest one.
Scott: I think I actually liked Aesthetically Transformers Voltron more but I had less access to them right.
Scott: the Voltron toy was very expensive And my parents did not buy it.
Scott: for me, even though my friend had it He-man right was a little bit too early.
Scott: So I had plenty he-man toys, but I didn't have like the big castle, right?
Scott: I didn't wanted a castle gray skull.
Scott: I didn't have.
Rym: well, you know, I was bigger like he-man.
Rym: I was a kid like weird like big big into.
Rym: that was my primary show.
Scott: I had a lot of he-man toys But I just didn't get to watch a lot of he-man because he just wasn't on TV.
Scott: a lot.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like I was still playing with he-man toys But I was hardly watching and he-man because it was not even I was watching a lot of he-man.
Rym: I guess it was just in syndication and where I grew right.
Scott: you're you're a victim.
Scott: in those days You were a victim of your local syndicators.
Scott: what programs they chose to run?
Scott: right.
Scott: so it's like they.
Scott: you know Voltron.
Scott: it's like I was able to watch some Voltron but Not that much I was.
Scott: you know transformers disappeared from the airwaves until I think eventually sci-fi channel started running it rarely Occasionally, it wasn't until like transformers DVDs came out when we were in college that like I could watch transformers again.
Scott: Yeah, but Thundercats was very syndicated where I lived and I watched a lot of it and I have a lot of memories attached.
Scott: I actually had you know The cat's lair toy with the flashlight in the head didn't my?
Scott: I think it's still in my attic somewhere I don't know.
Scott: Maybe it's gone now.
Rym: I had Lionel's sword like.
Rym: I know I had a toy like that and so I had.
Scott: I had a. I had a mumra where there would be a Little thing and you spin it around and he'd switch between forms.
Scott: I had you know a lot of thought I think at almost every Thundercats actually, you know, it's crazy.
Scott: I had no extra.
Scott: I had Star Lionel.
Scott: I had a snarf.
Scott: the snarf didn't move.
Scott: It was just like a figurine.
Scott: I didn't have Wiley cat and kit.
Scott: I didn't have them.
Scott: I'd have the kids.
Rym: So my weird accounting of my childhood.
Rym: I had all the action figures for he-man like every action figure And but I didn't have any like life-size toys.
Rym: But for Thundercats, I had like Lionel's sword and like play hit your brother kind of toys.
Rym: But I did not have any action figures not one.
Scott: Yep panthe rose action figures really good because he has this little sort of like Cat nunchucks and he actually like his arms have action so he can nunchuck around.
Scott: It's all cool.
Rym: my friend Joe Ogilvy had that those toys.
Scott: I actually remember like the day.
Scott: My brother was born Right.
Scott: I think my dad came to pick me up at like the nursery school and gave me Lionel action figure.
Scott: Anyway, that was most of in 1986.
Rym: what someone's selling the Thundercats sort of omens with the working for 500 bucks.
Scott: No, I could just get a new one or make one for the cosplayer can make a better one Exactly the one I had.
Scott: Yeah, that's boy.
Scott: There was only one.
Scott: It wasn't.
Rym: looks like there was a later one.
Rym: That's slightly fancier.
Scott: Okay, so Thundercats right was this TV series.
Scott: It had a few seasons.
Scott: You saw as much as you could in the day when it was syndicated.
Scott: Then there was like a remake much later in the 2000s.
Scott: Like we were already living in Beacon I think at the time or even later, maybe you were already living in New York that I remember being really excited about.
Rym: We were already in New York talked about it.
Scott: We talked about it on this show and we watched a little bit and then we're like meh because honestly I remember it was Crazy boring.
Rym: after the first few episodes like it started so strong and then it just got so boring that I didn't I just stop Watching it.
Rym: I just didn't care.
Rym: Yeah, like the characters Didn't go.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There's a new thing relatively new Thundercats roar, which is basically the same thing as Teen Titans go only Thundercats.
Scott: I really want to watch it.
Scott: I just haven't.
Rym: yet I'd same because I am Actually, honestly a big fan of Teen Titans.
Rym: go I do enjoy that kind of Comedic dense like weird zoomed in super deformed nonsense version of a show.
Scott: Yep Okay, so what's the deal with the original Thundercats?
Scott: So the thing about the original Thundercats is that you know people could argue about whether it's anime or not, right?
Scott: I think some Japanese people did some work on it to some extent right.
Scott: but in that Despite being a Show for American television, right?
Scott: It was originally, you know, the original language of the show is English, right?
Scott: It's for an English audience.
Scott: It's not like it was dubbed over.
Scott: Yeah, some original Japanese dialogue or anything.
Scott: Is that it actually has a somewhat serial plot?
Scott: It's not just some episodic thing, right?
Scott: Transformers also has the serial plot and sort of I get but not as much.
Scott: Thundercats actually has more.
Scott: You know, I think Thundercats Transformers some of the episodes engage in the serial plot, right?
Scott: But most of them are just like up.
Scott: there goes Megatron stealing some energon cubes.
Scott: fight him.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay the end Oh, he's you know who it's.
Scott: and it's pretty much like well, which Autobots are gonna fight Megatron this time.
Scott: Oh, there's a new Decepticon stealing energon cubes.
Scott: It's a different toy.
Scott: Alright, which toys are gonna fight over the energon cubes?
Scott: just episodic nothing.
Scott: and Thundercats does have a lot of episodic Nothings.
Scott: right monster of the week, right?
Scott: So there's like the burbles which are basically robot ewoks that live in the woods.
Scott: It's like well, the mutants are attacking the burbles again, right?
Scott: Guess the Thundercats are gonna roll out in their Thunder tank and save them, you know.
Scott: But like the second season of Thundercats is like it starts with like a six-parter.
Scott: That's like sort of like a movie.
Scott: I think it's six parts.
Scott: the start of Thundercats the well, there's the 1986 movie.
Rym: after season one just Thundercats.
Scott: Oh Yeah, well, that's the start of that's broken up into episodes.
Scott: That's the start of season two.
Scott: The season one starts with a multi-parter.
Scott: That's the start of Thundercats, right?
Scott: And while there are lots of episodes that are just fight a bad guy It's like the last season.
Scott: they're actually like leaving the planet and going to New Thundera and leaving, you know I never got that far.
Scott: I only saw those episodes on Toonami later in the day.
Scott: They didn't syndicate those episodes where I lived Talk about the the problem of syndication.
Rym: for me part of the reason why I was so much more into he-man Was that we got the episodes reliably.
Rym: Thundercats was either aired out of order or weird time.
Rym: So I saw Thundercats in such a like broken order that I couldn't find any plot thread.
Scott: as a kid I had I had VHS.
Scott: So I knew the plot and the thing about Thundercats.
Scott: that I think is not just that it was serialized right is that There's a lot of things that like as a kid.
Scott: as a kid I had them confused in my mind because Thundercats stole from them, right?
Scott: So if you think about it, right Thundercats has so much fucking Star Wars in it, right?
Scott: It's like, you know obi-wan appears to Luke is like a ghost.
Scott: Right as a kid I was confused cuz you had Jaga appearing as a ghost to lino, right?
Scott: Was basically just Emperor Palpatine Sort sort of mum rise a little different.
Scott: well depends.
Scott: Mumra invokes and I already mentioned the the burbles that are straight-up ewoks.
Scott: Mmm, right?
Scott: You have the the that same sort of Relationship between the mutants and Mumra that you have between Starscream and Megatron where it's sort of like the bad guys that don't get along right?
Rym: He man had that too.
Scott: Yep, you have this sort of like, you know Superman story, right?
Scott: So the story of Superman is that you know He comes in a and a. he's escaping an exploding planet and crash lands on earth, right?
Scott: Well lino and all the Thundercats are escaping it exploding Thundera and crashing on.
Scott: you know What's the?
Rym: Trying to find the name of this place.
Rym: I do not remember.
Scott: Yeah, they think or maybe Thunder is the planet they land on.
Scott: and but no they Thunder is the one.
Rym: I thought you were a fan of Thundercats.
Rym: Thunder is the planet that was dying.
Scott: Yes, they knew Thunder is the one they go to in season four.
Scott: What's the one that they that most of Thundercats takes place on?
Scott: where?
Rym: I'm trying to figure that out.
Rym: There are a lot of proper nouns in this Wikipedia article.
Scott: there sure are Right, but that's it's like Superman Plus.
Scott: you got this kid lino who's very young and they're in suspended animation when they're flying from the you know exploding Thundera.
Scott: And then when they land lino's in a way older body But it's still a kid in mind and heart and he sort of grows up emotionally Right, even though he's like a kid in an adult's body.
Scott: So that's the kid in an adult's body story.
Scott: you saw several times in that in that big, right?
Rym: So as a kid I had no idea that was a thing because I never saw any of the like plot set up episodes Until I only had that because I had v8.
Scott: I only had VHS of that beginning part that I was able to see it.
Rym: Yep, all I knew was oh the Thundercats live on this planet and they're fighting with the mutants of plundar and there's a mummy guy And that's that's it.
Scott: Even as a kid I was wondering how come the adult Thundercats didn't get older and suspended animation lion.
Scott: Oh did You've got some you know, and it's like all that serious kind of stuff, right?
Scott: You also have a lot of sci-fi kind of plots like space plots.
Scott: You know, there's like that are similar to like some Voltron ish Star Trek stuff almost right of like things they encounter in space or you know, People from space that happen to come and appear.
Scott: and you know You got fantasy sort of like holy grail kind of stories like Lionel goes like a vision quest out in the mountains by himself Kind of stuff right to consult with the the sword of omens.
Rym: Yeah, but that was the one thing.
Rym: that's all magical artifacts even not seeing enough plot like not knowing what the actual plot was.
Rym: as a kid part of what I liked about Thundercats compared to He-Man and everything else that I was watching was that The characters did seem to grow and change and there was a relatively rich world that was implied by things I saw in episodes as opposed to He-Man where everything's just empty and barren and like.
Rym: There was nothing like as far as I was concerned.
Rym: as a kid Castle Grayskull didn't exist because they never did anything with it.
Rym: They never followed those threads.
Rym: But like these characters were rich enough even to my kid brain to where I like had this impression that there was other Thundercats I hadn't seen.
Rym: that would explain a bunch of stuff.
Rym: And as a kid, I was actually weirdly obsessed with Sarah.
Scott: They're just really far away.
Rym: Yeah but like I wanted to know more about the world and about like Where they were going like a kid brain was starting to figure out that I wanted to watch serials.
Scott: Yeah, I mean transformers also had the world building with the Cybertron and stuff.
Scott: It's just a lot of transformers doesn't use that world building except for like the movie, right?
Scott: Thundercats a lot of the episodes maybe like even half of them.
Scott: Maybe I'd say use it and the other half are you know?
Scott: fight Mumra again.
Scott: Mumra's up to something.
Scott: go fight him Right.
Scott: He goes back to his mummy.
Scott: form the end, you know, whatever fight fight some mutants, you know, okay, go back.
Rym: Yeah, the mutants.
Rym: as a kid.
Rym: I hated the mutants because I always I was like, why are they so dumb?
Rym: why?
Scott: Right, so you have this serious sort of serial plot and you're sort of going back and forth with that to the less serious like silly stuff like snarf and mutants and these characters and set pieces that are just sort of like Corny children's television sort of like mixed together.
Scott: So it's almost like if you were watching Star Wars and Star Wars has some corniness already into it, right?
Scott: But imagine if like you took the Star Wars Christmas special and cut it and inserted those scenes into Star Wars.
Scott: I made one big law, right?
Scott: So it's like you're watching Star Wars and then suddenly it's a scene from the Christmas special.
Scott: then it's a scene from Star Wars Right,
Rym: I remember as a kid like that and it annoyed me the same way that the villains in like I for some reason as a kid I always saw Skeletor as being super competent and I hated all of his minions because they were so bad at this and Thundercats same thing.
Rym: It was like Mumra knows what's up.
Rym: Why does Mumra get better minions?
Scott: See the thing is about Thundercats.
Scott: that actually I thought was really awesome.
Scott: is I think some people don't like think about it too hard.
Scott: Is that the real villains?
Scott: are these ancient spirits of evil?
Scott: There's actually like a Cthulhu kind of.
Scott: you know, ask story going on here, right?
Scott: Mumra is just some dude.
Scott: He's the vessel right, right?
Scott: He's just some dude who's like a mummy Who has managed to live for a long time because these four basically elder gods Are keeping him alive with unnatural dark powers.
Rym: He's basically like Zelos from slayers.
Rym: He like pledged himself to them.
Rym: I got that as a kid.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: So and it's like he's not strong He's just a mummy.
Scott: if Lino could figure out getting that pyramid, you know, which I think they do try to do on occasion It's like you could just cut up that mummy and be that be it, right?
Scott: But the ancient spirits of evil are so freakin strong.
Scott: They turn Mumra into like, you know, not God's here But we're talking like Hercules tear, you know Like avatar of themselves right because they can't I guess directly interact.
Scott: So it's like they want Mumra to succeed But they also don't trust Mumra entirely because he's right gonna keep over on a short leash because he was definitely an ambitious individual.
Scott: Yeah, and they can't really do things direct like they can't like.
Scott: they can't just kill Lionel directly, right?
Scott: It's it they I guess.
Scott: they you know, they're they're too Ethereal and far away.
Scott: So all they can really do is you know?
Scott: Help Mumra magically almost like he's a cleric of them and he prays and then they get magic, right?
Scott: They're not looking too closely.
Scott: They got other shit going on in other places.
Rym: The one thing that did also stand out.
Rym: as a kid I remember I'm always just comparing it to he-man But I always.
Scott: the point is I always want I always wanted to see Like if the show were to go on like, you know They go out into and they find and they fight the ancient spirits of evil this four of them, right?
Scott: So like they could find where they are and they would be super creepy.
Scott: They could be a good fam.
Scott: Sure, there's a fanfiction of that right?
Rym: It has to be.
Rym: Is there a Wikipedia article on the Asian spirits of evil?
Rym: Cuz there's a whole Wikipedia article just on Mumra Ancient spirits of evil.
Rym: All right, here's the full story.
Rym: There's there is more lore about them in the later Incarnations of Thundercats that I'm not gonna read to all of you here, but they're basically a bore a vulture a crocodile and an ox.
Rym: I Even picked up on that as a kid.
Rym: I don't think I did.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, they're just for generally pagan images.
Rym: Yeah, I think it was partly ever said TV broadcasts were really bad.
Rym: Like I remember whenever he did the ancient spirits of evil thing The screen was always so dark that that's a tight and may moku shiroku of thunder.
Rym: Yeah, but it would kind of pan up to like these vague statues.
Rym: I'm just going from memory here, but it was always so dark that I couldn't see anything.
Scott: Okay, so I I guess I don't know if I had a better TV or yeah.
Rym: Maybe it was in the syndication and there was like a worst broadcast.
Rym: Like I have no idea.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: But yeah Thundercats, I think you know, I don't haven't watched Thundercats in quite a while years.
Scott: But at the feeling I get is that it would hold up, right?
Scott: I could I feel like I could skip over by looking at the episode list on Wikipedia The sort of monster of the week episodes that don't advance the plot at all.
Scott: I just dropped just right.
Scott: just watch the multi-part episodes and the plot Significant episodes and even though there might be some corny things in there like some snarf appearances or whatever, right?
Scott: You know, it's like snarf does have redeeming qualities.
Scott: He's not just completely annoying Yeah, start saves me a few times our fish.
Scott: snarf is way better than Jar Jar Binks by like a million.
Scott: He shares some qualities with Jar Jar Binks type character, but is vastly superior, right?
Rym: So one thing I knew as a kid was that the ancient spirits of evil can't like get out of the pyramid So they need mom or how to go out to do stuff.
Rym: yeah, but Apparently in one episode the episode called doom gaze.
Rym: I don't know what that episode was about But apparently there is some lore dropped in the episode that the ancient spirits of evil are Lovecraft's great old ones.
Rym: specifically and on purpose.
Scott: I Mean, I think I always had the feeling that they were in that vein because Marmara invokes in that episode by name to other entities not the And Cthulhu specifically, uh-huh.
Rym: So the episode is called doom gaze.
Rym: We might want to watch it Maybe.
Scott: oh, I mean, it's also worth noting The real Ghostbusters has an episode where Cthulhu comes and there's like, you know, yellow sign cultists.
Rym: Yeah Talking about shows that were ahead of their time the Ghostbusters cartoon was the scary like it was like the Owl House today And that that was the level of scary weird that kids actually resonated with.
Rym: I think a lot of parents didn't expect That cartoon to be as weird as it was because body horror played into like 75% of those episodes.
Rym: Yeah, I'm actually getting drawn into this.
Rym: I'm reading the Wikipedia lore to piece together all the stuff.
Rym: as a kid I could not figure out about the Thundercats universe because I saw it in random order.
Scott: and this one thing is I think that this growing up with the Thundercats that had this serial plot that drew upon right Star Wars Superman these other things right?
Scott: It's just so many it by.
Scott: It's like it's actually not very original when you look at it.
Scott: It's like an amalgamation of all the other nerdy types of stories that I'm into and I can tie sort of every almost everything else I like like you can see it in Thundercats and maybe it was I don't know for sure, right?
Scott: But I feel like it was sort of this reverse thing.
Scott: We're like.
Scott: I was so young watching Thundercats and that made me that you know made me like that.
Scott: So now I like all the things right.
Rym: well you know when I think about that you make a good point because I was born to he-man like at a similar age to you and The thing I was obsessed with in he-man, but the show didn't tell me about was what's the deal with Castle Grayskull?
Scott: I wanted to know that too, of course No, but because specifically what's what's?
Rym: one of the primary things that I am like weirdly into to this day specifically is Precursor technology the idea that there is magic.
Rym: that is actually science and people just forgot about it.
Rym: Thundercats definitely has that under case and he-man both had that in spades.
Scott: Yep Yeah, I think also part of what Thundercats does is that you have this, you know The Thundercats civilization that they leave is like a great civilization just like Krypton and Superman, right?
Rym: Though who escaped?
Rym: seems like only five like a few of them escapes like is every other Thundercat dead?
Scott: No, there are some others that are well that survive.
Scott: that you'll see in season four.
Rym: See, I never I never saw those episodes that I don't think I ever saw another Thundercat than the main crew.
Scott: There there's a few.
Rym: I remember snart.
Rym: there was a worse snarf that showed up at one point.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's also.
Rym: I do remember there's just there was a. there was a scrappy do to Scooby Doo.
Scott: Yeah, there's like.
Scott: it's like a symbiotic.
Scott: I considered like the snarf species is whatever species that is Are they are they snarfs?
Scott: Is that what they are?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: we could be sort of like.
Rym: the snarfs are a race of intelligent cat-like creatures that are plump fuzzy and kind.
Rym: they're Native to Thandara living in the valley of the snarfs and they act as servants to the Thandarian nobility.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: Yeah It's okay.
Rym: the one I remembered is literally named snarfer.
Scott: Yep, that's right.
Rym: Snarf's nephew Mm-hmm.
Rym: Okay, so now I'm disturbed because when snarfer appears it was thought that he died when Thandara exploded along with all of the other Snarfs and everyone was surprised that he survived Implying that all the other starts died.
Scott: They did.
Rym: Yeah, so the Thunder Cows Bring their servant class.
Rym: They had a servant class that they left behind on their dying plan.
Scott: It's a no I told you it's a Superman story, right?
Scott: It's like, you know Superman escaped from Krypton on his own in a true thing Right.
Scott: So when they if you watch those first two episodes of Thundercats that I saw many times on VHS You'll see that basically it's lion.
Scott: Oh, it's the Thundercats, you know, lion.
Scott: Oh pan throw, you know the two kids you know our Tigra and snarf and Jaga, you know basically dies.
Scott: He's the.
Scott: he's obi-wan Kenobi, right?
Scott: And it's pretty much just them in suspended animation and no one else.
Scott: No one else can fit in the in the ship And they basically Jaga knows that lion.
Scott: Oh is like the chosen one already.
Scott: Okay, and he basically takes the chosen one And he you know, he takes Paul of treaties With these guardians Right and the sword of omens and he sort of you know Gives him advice and he appears as a ghost to help him out and he sends him on his way, right?
Scott: So and everyone else, you know and Thundara supposedly bites it until you find out later that some survived right.
Rym: so Apparently at some point I never saw this episode.
Rym: snarf convinces the ancient spirits of evil to power him up and Becomes.
Scott: I never heard I don't remember that.
Rym: Now I'm looking at her.
Scott: Ah Don't remember that one.
Rym: apparently that appears to have happened.
Rym: I fold up a Wikipedia page and now a video.
Rym: snarf is in the temple and there is a super buff hot snarf.
Rym: Who is?
Rym: uh?
Rym: Yeah, that was the thing.
Rym: I guess we never slept in episode.
Scott: clip it.
Scott: I never seen that one.
Scott: Yep All right, I don't remember it.
Rym: season 2 episode 24 hair of the dog.
Rym: snarf convinces the ancient spirits of evil to give him power.
Scott: What that?
Rym: That's something that I think is universal to kids shows in the 80s and wasn't and maybe the 90s But it's not a thing anymore.
Rym: kids today when they watch a show they go to the streaming service And they just watch the whole show.
Rym: when we were kids like I would see some like set of episodes of Thundercats But other kids in my school saw different episodes.
Rym: so a big part of my interaction with kids when I was growing up was Sharing lore that we each knew to try to figure things out about shows like someone say oh There's the episode where like like we do just now when snarf gets the ancient powers of evil Like.
Rym: you didn't know about that.
Rym: That was like.
Rym: 90% of my interaction with other kids was talking about The shows we were watching and the end the lack of intersection of what episodes we had seen due to different syndication schedules.
Scott: Yeah See I think kids that I talked to is Basically, we wouldn't do that because I don't remember talking about like cartoons or anything with our kids.
Scott: We mostly talked about video games and shared, you know tips and things.
Scott: but the problem was is at least so many kids Would basically make stuff up right?
Scott: It's like so there wasn't a lot of trust between oh, you know kids.
Rym: I was about to bring that up because in those interactions kids would make up stuff about these shows that I could not disprove because I had.
Rym: I didn't know I hadn't seen whatever episode they Saw.
Scott: yeah, I was.
Rym: well, there's this kid Billy.
Rym: Well, this is flooding back to me.
Scott: He made up So much at Nintendo.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: he made up so much stuff about he-man in particular and I believed him for a long time until eventually My thinking who's my dad like some of my family but in my uncle was like no no None of that's true because he'd actually seen all the episodes of he-man and he was like now that kids making shit up.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: I remember, you know kids are making stuff up all the time.
Scott: There was a kid in fourth grade who was actually a Japanese kid like his parents, you know moved from Japan to my town.
Scott: He was in the class there.
Scott: He was right Obviously had gone to much better schools in the previous years of his life and was smarter than all of us Except in English, so we didn't talk too much.
Scott: But I remember we did a school activity where you would draw a picture of what you wanted for your holiday gifts for whatever holiday you celebrated and he drew a Super Famicom and we were like you're making that shit up.
Scott: There's no such, right?
Scott: Like there's no right he was making shit.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no that was the one time a kid wasn't making shit up.
Scott: He drew a perfect Super Famicom.
Scott: He tried.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: he knew they existed and we he had never heard of.
Rym: Mostly what kids would make up were crossover episodes.
Rym: that never happened.
Rym: like.
Rym: that's what I remember the most Like.
Rym: oh there was the episode where Thundercats and he-man were together.
Rym: like now that didn't happen kid now.
Scott: Yeah, the super the Super Nintendo came out in November of 1990 right so he would.
Scott: so it had probably just come out in 1990, right?
Scott: So I was.
Scott: I was what eight and I was yeah eight.
Scott: I was like in fourth grade Yeah, so probably in like November of 1990.
Scott: It had just come out.
Scott: He knew about it because he was actually Japanese.
Scott: He wanted it for you know Christmas in December Right, and we didn't even know about it because it didn't come out in the US until August 19 of 91, right?
Scott: So I guess a few months later.
Scott: We found out he wasn't bluffing.
Rym: Oh shit Snarf is like twice as tall as Mumra when he gets powered up and beats the shit out of him.
Scott: No, pretty cool.
Rym: They also draw him differently in every scene, but that's just how the animation was on TV back then.
Scott: I'm saying is that Thundercats is like has a lot of redeeming qualities.
Scott: It's not just like garbage unwatchable like he-man.
Scott: Oh, yeah Like.
Rym: I'd like the fact that I was so into he-man as a kid that that is just a product of blood syndication of my area.
Scott: He-man is objectively one of the worst kid shows from that era from and I think even I think even your shows like mask Which probably had much better toys than Thundercats, which just had action figures, right?
Scott: It's probably not as good as Thundercats.
Scott: Oh, definitely Transformers I think is like is arguable, but you have to.
Scott: there's so much more Transformers I think you would have to like.
Rym: I've admitted this on the show before it was a long time ago But I will admit as a kid.
Rym: I did not actually like transformers.
Scott: I mean, you know, it depends what transformers you saw how old you were when you saw it.
Scott: Yeah It's just what transformer is.
Scott: definitely is the king of toys like a transforming toy.
Scott: It's like you couldn't beat that.
Rym: Yep, I think that's why I was so into mask because the mask toys transform so much better.
Rym: Yeah, and my like of the show was a hundred percent from my like of the toys not the other way around.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, yeah, but no Thundercats holds up better than a lot of those shows from that era and I have I guess might be.
Scott: As a show, I think it may be the best one per episode divided by quality.
Rym: It's just weird to me that I have such strong memories of liking Thundercats a lot Yet can remember almost nothing specific from Thundercats.
Scott: hmm Yeah, also the music Thundercats are really good.
Rym: All right, I think we killed enough time on this episode.
Scott: Yeah, I kind of want to what I got to figure out where you can legally watch all of the tickets.
Scott: Oh, well, you can legally.
Rym: I'll send you a link to this clip or you can watch snarf beat the shit out of mumra Or I'll just go to yawn.
Rym: I don't know if I have time to watch all the Thundercats right now.
Scott: I think I said I'll ski.
Scott: I'm gonna skip the if I do watch it.
Scott: I will skip the nothing episodes.
Scott: I'll just watch the ones where stuff happens.
Rym: It's you know good I'm at least I'm gonna go watch this doom gaze episode because I want to see what the deal is with the reference to Lovecraft Because that is something I definitely I was.
Rym: I knew Lovecraft and was into it by like middle school But by then I was not thinking about Thundercats anymore.
Rym: So whatever that episode happened, even if I saw it, there is no way I would have recognized what Cthulhu was though my parents might have.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Hank McNichol Marty.
Rym: Just like a dude guy Graham Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: There was a dude looked like a cop standing there with my name out Clinton Walton J Banstrum from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris mid give dread.
Rym: Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn shirvin van are all in a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: Tonight is the night for some mouth sounds So I leave you with some of the earliest sounds that came from mouth Some some some some Some some some some some some Some some some some some some some Some Some.