Rym: It's Monday, September 14th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're talking about software updates, both from the consumer side and the publisher side.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So, uh, really hoped, like, I had a plan years ago.
Rym: When I moved to the city, I was like, "Well, I'll never have to own a car
Rym: again.".
Rym: And I made this pseudo-vow, like, my goal in life was to never own a car again unless it was a full self-driving car that I could just, like, call.
Rym: It would come and pick me up and drive me places.
Scott: Even that kind of car I would not buy, nor if there was such a car, it would be no good unless it was municipal.
Scott: And even then, it wouldn't be that great.
Rym: But, you know, the reality of America, those are things that are not easily fixed, and there's a lot of places you can't get without a car.
Scott: Too bad.
Scott: Fuck those places.
Rym: Yeah, most places on Earth.
Scott: Yeah, fuck 'em.
Rym: Okay, uh, I recall you've taken a certain car to conventions in the past.
Scott: Uh, yeah, this car's gone, bye-bye.
Rym: Okay, so, I guess you'll never want to ride, not that I would ever drive this car to a convention, but basically, we got a car for the sole purpose of being able to, like, do outdoor things until COVID calms down, because there's really, like, I'm not willing to take mass transit, like, that's not safe right now.
Rym: I don't really want to take mass transit, but there's no way to get to those places.
Rym: Like, I can't bike upstate in the middle of winter.
Scott: Maybe you should just not do those things.
Rym: No, I want to go outside.
Rym: I want to be able to continue the exercise.
Rym: Oh, you want to?
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: Also, there's no way to get to those places.
Scott: You're not going to sacrifice like the rest of us, you know?
Scott: Just be like, "Oh, you know what?
Scott: I got money.
Scott: Fuck the rest of you.
Scott: I'm going to go skiing in a pandemic.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: Not good.
Scott: I'm not willing to give up
Scott: anything.".
Rym: Hey, I mean, you're not biking.
Scott: Yeah, on the bike I already owned.
Rym: Yeah, but also, there's a lot of other reasons.
Rym: we'll use it just for this purpose, and the plan is to basically give it away at the end of the thing.
Rym: But when I rented a one-way car to get to the place to get the car, the interesting part was that, on one hand, the car rental places have really, like, changed their thing.
Rym: It was, like, this pretty well done, like, you don't interact with humans, like, completely contactless.
Rym: Like, the pandemic almost forced them to do the things they should have done all along, but on the other hand, because no one's renting cars, they didn't just give me a normal car.
Rym: They don't have a lot of cars.
Rym: Like, they're trying to get cars out of their space, and it was a one-way rental.
Rym: They gave me this monster car.
Rym: This car is, like, it should be banned, this car that I had to drive.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: Most of the cars that are, you know, allowed on the road in America should be banned.
Rym: This car, it was like this Cadillac SUV.
Rym: The top of the hood, like, came up to my shoulders in front of it.
Rym: I had to pick it up, like, at night.
Rym: They just gave it to me.
Rym: They charged me, like, the same rate as, like, the shitty car I actually wanted to rent.
Scott: That's why, if you're gonna rent a car, if you really have to, there's no alternative.
Rym: Put in the buy to get the shitty car.
Scott: Always pick the lowest, cheapest option, because if you go there and they don't have it, you just get some ridiculous car and you pay the one that you chose.
Scott: You don't pay based on the car you get.
Scott: It's not like, "Oh, you chose, you know, Fred Flintstone car, and we've only got Formula One
Scott: car.".
Scott: You get Formula One car at Fred Flintstone price.
Scott: They can't be like, "No, no car for you,".
Scott: and they can't be like, "You gotta pay Formula One price.
Scott: That's all we've
Scott: got.".
Scott: You get Fred Flintstone, you get F1 at Flintstone price.
Rym: So, years ago, I even ran into a place that- Always choose Flintstone.
Rym: They pulled a bait-and-switch scam where, when you go to pick up the car, they have in front of the rental place this tiny e-car.
Rym: You know those tiny, tiny almost fake-looking cars that seat two people and have a tiny trunk?
Rym: They have that out, and they're like, "Oh, this is the only compact car we have, but tell you what, for a dollar more a day, I'll upgrade you to this luxury car
Rym: instead.".
Scott: I say, "I'll take that tiny two-car.
Scott: Yes, that looks
Scott: awesome.".
Rym: So, we tried to take the tiny two-car, and if we actually took it, it would have ruined their scam, so they wouldn't give it to us, and they were like, "Well, the car isn't actually that safe,".
Rym: and they were like, "So, why?
Rym: You're gonna give us a car that's not
Rym: safe?".
Rym: And they didn't know how to deal with the situation.
Rym: I guess it had never happened at any point.
Scott: And I'd be like, "Yes, that's the car I want.
Scott: I actually want that car more.
Scott: If I have to have a car, I want that one more than any of these
Scott: ones.".
Rym: We opened the trunk to start putting stuff into it, and then the guy freaked out, and eventually was like, "All right, here, take this luxury car.
Rym: Discount rate, whatever.
Rym: Please go.
Rym: Please
Rym: leave.".
Rym: And they gave us a really nice car for like $20 a day because we called them on their scam.
Scott: Why not let you have that little car, though?
Scott: I guess they need it for their scam.
Rym: Yeah, because they only have one of that little car.
Rym: They clearly needed it.
Scott: So, basically, you could have taken the car.
Scott: It was fine, but they would have not been able to run the scam until you brought it back.
Rym: Yep, and I knew about the scam because, way back, remember when you and I were in Australia for PAXOS, and we rented that car.
Scott: Yeah, we just ran a normal car.
Rym: But the guy who was at the desk was super chill, and he was like, "Oh, let me just give you the cheapest
Rym: rate.".
Rym: Remember that whole conference?
Scott: Yeah, that seemed like a normal guy.
Scott: That was a normal transaction.
Scott: He's like, "You want the
Scott: insurance?".
Scott: We're like, "Yeah,
Scott: whatever.".
Rym: But that's where we learned that most car rental places, like all the big companies, there's a minimum rate, and everything else is completely at the discretion of the local branch.
Rym: Doesn't really matter.
Rym: So, if you know what that number is, or you're good with the people who actually are renting it to you at the desk, you can always get any car for almost nothing, except fancy luxury cars.
Rym: I also learned something else about this horrific car.
Rym: Because it's a luxury car, no one ever rents these luxury cars.
Scott: Yeah, because no one's choosing the most expensive option, right?
Scott: So, that even though you might show up and have paid for a cheaper car, they still give you the cheapest car.
Scott: So, the most expensive car at the rental place is driven very rarely.
Scott: Because in order for that to go off the lot, they have to rent every single car they've got, right?
Scott: Like, the busiest day in the universe.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing that most people don't know is, I was like, "Note all the insurance," and I paused for a second because I remembered something very specific, a voice from my past.
Rym: You know the automatic car insurance you get from credit cards with car rentals in America that almost no one knows about, but is still a thing?
Rym: It does not apply to anything classed as luxury.
Rym: Had I declined everything?
Scott: Even if you have a fancy black credit card?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Credit card insurance, at least the credit card insurance that I'm talking about, the automatic weird one, does not apply to anything classed as a luxury vehicle, and that is not obvious to most people.
Scott: Even if you've got a black gold Zazen Jotaro card?
Rym: I'm sure there's some credit card out there somewhere that, like, has special car insurance.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But yeah, like the normal stuff.
Rym: But then I realized it's weird that that insurance on credit cards still exists.
Rym: Like, no one cares about that.
Rym: Most people don't even know about it.
Rym: No one, like, picks a credit card because of it.
Rym: Almost every credit card has it.
Rym: Like, why is it still a thing?
Rym: And I can't figure out the answer to that question.
Scott: The reason it's still a thing is because, you know, let's say, you know, you go and you rent the car, right?
Scott: And something happens and you got to pay for it.
Scott: And you didn't choose the insurance, right?
Scott: Well, odds are, right?
Scott: A lot of people just don't have the money to even pay, you know, they didn't choose the insurance.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: You know, you didn't get fooled by the car rental.
Scott: So it's like, they don't have the money.
Scott: They can't afford.
Scott: So the car rental place is just going to be out, right?
Scott: They're going to have to use their own insurance.
Scott: The car rental place will go, "Hey, you know, your credit card might cover
Scott: this.".
Scott: And that way they'll get a payout.
Rym: But here's the crazy thing.
Rym: That is not on the kinds of credit cards that people who really don't have a lot of money have.
Rym: Like, from what I can gather, secured line credit cards do not have that insurance.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Go ask someone who works at a credit card company why credit cards continue to offer all these services that are, we think are unused or largely unused.
Scott: You know, I don't know.
Rym: But yeah, this car, I had to like park it on the street before I could like get rid of it.
Rym: But the good news is when I dropped it off at the other place, the guy who gave it to me was like, he basically was laughing.
Rym: He was like, "They're never going to give this to
Rym: anybody.".
Rym: Like he was, I think he was like doing it on purpose to get rid of this car.
Scott: I think they it's like, you know, people might be like, "How do you know that those credit card services are
Scott: unused?".
Scott: I don't.
Scott: But I find it interesting that most people I know don't know those services exist.
Rym: That's the part, like it's one thing if people don't use it.
Scott: We know, we know, right, but we know those services exist because we've been talking about it for years.
Scott: When's the last time you used one of those services?
Rym: Because I've never crashed a car.
Scott: Well, I'm just saying any of the, your credit card offers tons of other services.
Rym: Yeah, but like, I don't know, I guess they had, there's the warrant, warranty services against theft or things that are stolen.
Rym: I forgot about that one because I've never needed it.
Scott: There's concierge services.
Rym: I know about those.
Rym: I don't use them because they can do anything.
Scott: I'm just saying it's like, there are all these services that if you have pretty much any credit card, it offers a lot of, you get a bunch of stuff you don't even know about.
Rym: I tried to use the concierge once with the chase card.
Rym: I was like, "Hey, they claim to have like all these event things.
Rym: Can you get me Rangers
Rym: tickets?".
Rym: And they were basically like,
Rym: "No.".
Rym: And I was like, "Okay,
Rym: nevermind.".
Rym: Like the best they could do is like get the same StubHub.
Rym: I was going to go to myself and do it for me.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Well, that's, that's what, that's what it is.
Scott: It's like call the phone, call up on the phone and someone does a thing for you.
Scott: It's not a better inside line.
Scott: It's call someone on the phone and they take care of shit for you.
Scott: That's what it is.
Scott: But the point is, is that we know about these services and we never use them.
Scott: So I assume based on that and the fact that no one else I know, unless I tell them, knows these services are there.
Scott: I assume they're going largely unused.
Scott: Why did the credit cards still have these arrangements to have those services exist?
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're still paying that person that you called who couldn't help you.
Scott: That's still a job someone's being paid for.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, maybe it's all source aggregated.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: It costs someone's money though.
Scott: It costs someone money.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It might just be that because we don't work in that industry, like we don't know there's some specific reason why all these things exist.
Scott: That money could go into, go into CEO's pocket instead and no one would know.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I was thinking about that weird car insurance because it comes up a lot in my life because I know about it, but I realized that especially people younger than us just have no idea that exists.
Rym: That's not a thing.
Scott: Why would you know?
Scott: Your credit card doesn't tell you.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: They almost go out of their way to not tell you.
Scott: They'll tell you that they're giving you things.
Rym: If you Google for it, you find third party websites that are like, "This credit card covers these
Rym: cars.".
Scott: Credit cards only brag about, you know, their low interest rates and their whatever is right.
Scott: They don't brag about all the other stuff.
Rym: So yeah, that's, that was my weekend.
Scott: So there's big, big news like, talking about this on GeekNights for quite a while on and off.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I see.
Scott: I can't, I wish I could find the episode where I first mentioned it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But Nvidia, right.
Scott: Who makes all the GPUs that are the best.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is buying ARM holdings.
Scott: So if you don't know, the majority of CPUs in the world, I don't know if that's true.
Scott: There might be some like tiny ones people don't think about.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But most of the important CPUs in the world today are built on the ARM CPU architecture.
Scott: So you think x86 is the big one.
Scott: It's like, nah, that's only in PCs pretty much.
Rym: PCs, workstations, servers, but not all servers.
Scott: Nope, not all servers, but mostly desktop PCs, laptops.
Scott: That's where you find x86 and even ARM is creeping into those areas.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You see Apple is switching from x86 to ARM.
Scott: Already all iOS, Android devices already run an ARM.
Scott: Pretty much every car has an ARM, has ARM CPUs in it.
Scott: If it has CPUs at all, it's not just a mechanical car.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you have like a smart TV, that's an ARM CPU almost definitely.
Scott: So ARM, this company, right.
Scott: It's sort of a weird company and that it's sort of an IP holding company.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It doesn't like make CPUs directly.
Scott: For example, your iOS device has an A whatever CPU in it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, um, that CPU is made by Apple.
Scott: Apple doesn't, you know, own ARM, obviously Nvidia does now.
Scott: Uh, and SoftBank, SoftBank did before.
Scott: So why is, how is Apple making these ARM processors?
Scott: Cause they license, you know, things from ARM holdings.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So all these CPUs in the world, right.
Scott: All these people making ARM CPUs now have to license the ARM technology from the Nvidia corporation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, for most devices that you would think of as having a CPU.
Scott: That's a huge deal, right?
Scott: Uh, it's going to affect everyday computing for people years from now.
Scott: You're going to see, especially with the downfall of Intel, as I said before, you were going to see the all Nvidia computer.
Scott: it's coming.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Just a computer you buy.
Scott: It's got nothing, but I mean, all the, obviously not everything in it will be made by Nvidia.
Scott: I mean, even the, I, even an iPhone Apple doesn't make the screen.
Scott: They don't make, there's a lot of parts in an iPhone Apple doesn't make.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But we're talking the major chips, the big ones, right?
Scott: All the, all those little IO chips and radios and all the small bits.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Now this is right hot on the heels of the pretty like serious announcements about the new Nvidia graphics chips.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But that's just, you know, par for the course.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Just keep upgrading their GPUs.
Scott: But yeah, so now Nvidia is like, uh, by owning arm is now absolutely a bigger, more important company than Intel.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And AMD, right.
Scott: They're, they're like maybe the biggest and most important chip company there is now by owning this and all the GPU stuff.
Scott: Uh, Nvidia also has said that they're planning to sort of shift their GPUs to like an arm model almost right to where, yeah, they're still going to be making GPUs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you know how they don't make cards really.
Scott: I guess they do make a few, but not really.
Scott: You don't buy an Nvidia GPU card.
Scott: Someone else makes the card and buys chips from Nvidia.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's why you see all those brands.
Rym: Like you look at like GTX, whatever, and you'll see like a bunch of different types.
Scott: They're all pretty much from ACEs or, you know, they might look a little different.
Rym: They might be overclocked a little bit more or a little bit whatever.
Scott: But Nvidia is going to, in the same way that arm licenses out the arm CPU designs, architectures, APIs, all that, you know, IP related to the arm chips, right?
Scott: To other people who actually make chips.
Scott: Uh, Nvidia is saying they're planning to down the line license out their GPU technologies that somebody else who makes chips that is not Nvidia could pay Nvidia money and make their own GPUs within video stuff.
Scott: The same way that Apple makes an a, whatever CPU for the iPhone, right?
Scott: Even though it's an arm CPU, it, you code for it in arm assembly, right?
Scott: But it's made by Apple.
Scott: You could see Apple licensing, right?
Scott: Because right, Nvidia GPUs from Nvidia and they could make like the AN one GPU and it's a Nvidia GPU, right?
Scott: That's very similar to the Nvidia GTX, whatever number they're on, but Apple makes it and it's in Apple devices, right?
Scott: And it could actually end up being better.
Scott: Like it could end up being the best Nvidia GPU, right?
Scott: Like better than the ones Nvidia makes, but Nvidia won't give a shit because they'll be making all the licensing money.
Scott: They don't care.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: This could be okay with that.
Rym: This could bode well potentially for Apple, like actually having good GPUs.
Scott: Well, this, so there's also some shenanigans, right?
Scott: Because Nvidia, despite, you know, obviously making all their chips on the other side of the world, as all chips are as not all, but you know, right.
Rym: I mean, I worked in a fab.
Rym: We did not all our, we made chips to learn how to make chips.
Rym: We didn't make the bulk chips, the bulk chips.
Rym: Once the process was set, were made overseas, right?
Scott: Mostly Nvidia is still in America is a United States company, right?
Scott: It's, it's based in the United States, right?
Scott: It's not a, uh, obviously it operates internationally, uh, as, as, as does Apple, right?
Scott: But Apple's a United States company.
Scott: Uh, most of the arm stuff is the rest of the world, right?
Rym: So well, like SoftBank is the one selling arm to, uh, right.
Scott: So, uh, well, a lot of people around the world, right.
Scott: Are really upset about this, right?
Scott: So you might actually see, uh, potentially, right.
Scott: If Nvidia can't sort of keep the ducks in line and keep everyone happy, you could see people abandoning arm, you know, you could see like Chinese chip manufacturers being like, well, we don't want to send our money to Nvidia and the U S to keep making arm chips, uh, screw that shit.
Scott: We're going to do something else.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there are, there already has been rumblings of these nature, like as of like, you know, I mean, there's a lot of stuff like.
Rym: one of the notes in this article is SoftBank, you know, they're selling UK's arm holdings to the U S chip manufacturer for 40 billion, just four years after its founder bought the chip designer and said it would be the linchpin for the future of the Japanese technology group SoftBank.
Rym: So they bought it.
Scott: SoftBank is just, you know, they bought it.
Rym: It was going to be the quote linchpin of their technology.
Rym: And four years later, they're selling it for 40 billion.
Rym: I don't know what they bought it for or like how they acquire, like, I have no idea these relationships.
Scott: I never understood why arm was, the thing I didn't understand was why was arm for sale to begin with?
Scott: It's such a valuable thing.
Scott: Wouldn't it just exist on its own?
Rym: I mean, all things are for sale all the time.
Scott: That's true, but it was so strong, right?
Scott: Obviously people would want to buy it, I guess, but it's like, you know, it's like, yeah, Apple's for sale.
Scott: It's like, you can't buy it.
Scott: Good luck.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's number one.
Scott: So Microsoft is for sale.
Scott: No one's can buy that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I figured arm was at that level of you can't buy that, but I guess that wasn't obviously was not the case.
Scott: So yeah, I think SoftBank just wasn't in a position to capitalize, you know, on owning.
Rym: Well, so SoftBank, remember these things are very rarely.
Rym: Now again, I'm not going to like, I don't have inside information or anything, but very rarely, and you can read this article, are transactions like buying a big company, just here's $40 billion in cash.
Rym: Thank you for the company.
Rym: Usually there's trading of assets and things.
Rym: So the way this is working, SoftBank will be the single largest shareholder in Nvidia.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: Nvidia is paying.
Scott: Oh, but it's not going to, but it's not going to add up to 51%.
Scott: It's the single largest shareholder.
Rym: So I don't think there'll be a majority, but I did not check.
Scott: I guess I could look that up, but there'll be, but right, but there'll be no one else like, so they might end up holding 15% of Nvidia, but it's like, no one else individually has 15%, but there's still.
Scott: probably maybe like a group of people that collectively are, you know, have like our like-minded shareholders that have more.
Rym: video is paying SoftBank 21.5 billion in their own stock.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And so that comes, so who owned that stock previously, right?
Scott: Like the, the board of Nvidia, I assume, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Probably the company itself probably, you know, train game.
Rym: It's in the company.
Scott: They're there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: They haven't sold them yet.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And no one bought those IPO shares and $12 billion in cash.
Rym: So SoftBank's still in a position to make money from this investment.
Rym: There's probably a lot going on.
Rym: We don't know about, and we're not qualified to talk about.
Rym: the only thing we're interested in is what will this do to technology?
Scott: This is going to make, you know, this is just the next step in something that's been a long time rumbling, you know, chips move slowly as far as consumers see the chip world.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But chips, you know, microchips, Silicon underlies all computing, right?
Scott: That's everything else is just like boards and what, you know, input, output is like the chips make.
Scott: that's where all the action is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if something happens in chip land, you see that bubble over into everything else eventually.
Scott: So this has been brewing for a long time.
Scott: Intel's been having a lot of trouble.
Scott: They've been going downhill.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You started seeing that when they had their delays on certain new processes that were coming down the line.
Rym: You start to run into diminishing returns.
Scott: You're seeing Nvidia, Intel reorg, a lot of people leaving Intel.
Scott: Intel's having a lot of trouble.
Scott: They're going down.
Scott: Everyone AMD went up a little bit in the x86 space, but you can see the world moving over to ARM over the past 10, 20 years.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like world has been moving to ARM.
Rym: On one end, like you might say, oh, we're just talking about ARM.
Rym: and like laptops a long time ago, not work yet.
Rym: Consumer stuff is like direct consumer stuff.
Rym: Like a laptop is a totally different ball game.
Scott: And it moves really slowly because you can't easily like rebuild that software and like redeliver that software to the consumers of the world.
Scott: But industrial devices, software devices, embedded things, all those things are basically already ARM.
Scott: And it's much easier to, if you're actually, it's like you tend to build something and then it stays that way forever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The chips that are being made and produced are for new things.
Scott: So either someone's redoing all their biz or they're buying all new biz.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not like people are sitting there and upgrading and sticking what they got like consumers do.
Rym: So supposedly part of this, which I'm wondering about, is to make this happen, SoftBank also decided not to strip an Internet of Things thing out of ARM before the sale.
Rym: So all the Internet of Things stuff, which seems to be the thing that people are actually interested in, that is with ARM.
Rym: It's not going to like stay with SoftBank or be its own company.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's also like a lot of like AI and other sort of smaller concerns that fall underneath.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That Nvidia can now shift according to its interests.
Scott: And you'll see a lot of articles around talking about each individual sort of aspect of this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: From the different angles of all the different things that are affected.
Scott: And that's sort of the point is like, wow, there are so many things that are being affected by this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like even reading this article, you'll learn names of companies you've never heard of just reading this like really high level article.
Scott: All of those things down the line.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All of those different areas.
Scott: The AI area, the car area, the graphics area, all these areas.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's how big this is.
Scott: It's like this foundational shifting.
Scott: So, you know, someone was like, man, why didn't you buy?
Scott: talking about buying Nvidia's stock?
Scott: And I'm like, you know, I said this, like what's going to happen?
Scott: How many years ago?
Scott: But I was not, I'm not an evil money thinking person.
Scott: So I, if I thought at the time, if someone had just said, if you think Nvidia is going to own the world, why don't you buy Nvidia stock?
Scott: If someone had said that at the time, I probably would have.
Scott: I don't think that way.
Scott: And now it's too late.
Scott: So it doesn't matter.
Rym: I haven't looked at how Nvidia stock went since the announcement, actually.
Rym: I assume it just skyrocket, but I don't know.
Scott: It's and I'm pretty sure it's envy.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Cause I personally don't invest in technology stocks.
Scott: So envy up 17% today.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That looks about right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: That's a lot.
Scott: Oh no, wait, no, it's DraftKings.
Rym: Nvidia.
Scott: DraftKings up them.
Rym: It's actually only a 5% today.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Not significantly up on this.
Scott: Why is Yahoo finance?
Scott: Fucking this up.
Scott: I type in it.
Scott: Oh, it's NVDA.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It's up 5% today.
Scott: Why was DraftKings up 17% today?
Scott: I guess because football's back.
Rym: Maybe because football's back for now.
Scott: Why did, how come?
Scott: when I typed in envy into Yahoo finance and pressed enter, it brought me to DraftKings.
Scott: And when I typed in Nvidia and pressed enter, it brought me to some natural gas corporation.
Scott: Only I had to type exactly NVDA, the correct symbol to get it.
Rym: Wait.
Rym: Oh, I have to type in the correct symbol to get it.
Rym: Welcome to my goddamn job.
Scott: Why shouldn't it be fucking intelligent enough that if I type in Envy, like this is the number one stock that begins with Envy.
Scott: Is it really?
Scott: Why would it take me to DraftKings DKNG?
Rym: Why are you on Yahoo finance?
Scott: It's just the first thing I went to.
Scott: I went to Google finance.
Rym: If I type Envy, it says Envy does not match any finance or financial results.
Scott: Oh, Google.
Rym: And if I type in, it suggests some stuff.
Rym: If I type Envy, it suggests Nvidia as the first thing.
Rym: And then Novanax.
Scott: If I press, if I press enter, I expect it to go to the first suggestion.
Scott: That means I like the first suggestion.
Scott: Take me there.
Scott: I'm pressing enter.
Rym: No, I hate that UX.
Rym: because when I, if I love that, no.
Rym: Cause if I see a dropdown maybe, you know how often I type something cause I want to search for the specific string.
Rym: Some recommendations appear that are not like.
Rym: they're longer versions of that, that I don't want.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So yes, I agree with that.
Scott: When you're on Google, you don't want, but I'm on Google.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: This is Google finance.
Scott: If you, you basically, unless you type in a correct symbol, you don't get search results.
Rym: No, but it does.
Rym: It does do a dropdown of typed Envy.
Scott: The point is there's no search results.
Scott: If I type in video and press enter without clicking that first suggestion, it takes me to nothing.
Scott: So there's not like, it's not like, oops, I didn't want to do that.
Scott: It's like, there's no reason you would ever want to not pick the first suggestion when pressing enter on a Google search.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: You want to just go to your search results.
Scott: You don't want the suggestion.
Scott: Also there are, there are search results.
Rym: There are a lot of stocks.
Rym: Like, you know what the symbol for Ford is?
Rym: just F yeah.
Scott: But then Facebook, if I press F and press enter, actually I tell, Oh, but I that's cause it is the symbol, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It actually is the symbol.
Scott: So it's also the first thing.
Rym: Also globally, there are many stocks that have the same symbol or a C doll.
Rym: You want to do it the right way.
Rym: It should make you type in a Q-Zip or a C doll.
Scott: The point is there's no Envy.
Scott: So if I press Envy and Nvidia is the first suggestion and searching for Envy doesn't do anything, pressing enter should go to the first suggestion.
Rym: But I'm just saying there are a lot of different identifiers of stocks.
Rym: There are stocks that have the same symbol.
Scott: Well, no one's using those on Google finance, so they don't matter.
Rym: Google finances global.
Rym: So you never know.
Scott: No one's using that.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I remember way back trying to buy some stock that was not listed in America.
Scott: It's okay that we spent a lot of time on this cause.
Rym: it's a big news, but we didn't make it a move on because as much as there's a lot of news, we would just be speculating.
Rym: We're not actually like that.
Rym: Like I'm not an expert in our tech.
Scott: I know enough to know that this is huge and to have seen it coming, but I have not, I don't know enough to know all.
Scott: And also big, I can't.
Rym: frankly, the technology considerations are not going to be what drive this.
Rym: The corporate and government considerations are going to be what drive how this develops.
Rym: And we do not know enough about that.
Scott: I mean, the technology considerations, I don't think are going to change.
Rym: They're definitely going to change, but they're, you know, it's like, it's like there's the, there's the vector of where like computing technology is going in the world and it just turns slightly in a slightly different direction now, but down the road that'll end up being a big difference.
Rym: But like a year from now, it's now the world's not going to change dramatically because of this.
Rym: No.
Rym: So in some really brief news that just highlights a problem in technology where there are certain problems that are caused by humans and they seem trivial, but sometimes they have real world consequences, like time zones messing up can kill people if you're making the wrong kind of software.
Rym: So this is a story where a family in Spain was basically accused of child porn because an IP address dynamic that at the time was allocated to their house and like very few enough other people, I guess, to where odds were any communication on this IP was their
Scott: house.
Scott: Was this a shared IP on a NAT?
Rym: No, within one single family home it looks like.
Scott: Okay, so the ISP was tracking which dynamic IP was assigned to which house at which time.
Scott: That IP address got porn at that time.
Rym: It uploaded some child porn.
Scott: Okay, so it could have been.
Scott: they're guilty.
Scott: It also could have been a mistake, obviously.
Scott: Anything can always be a mistake, right?
Scott: Or it could have been like some malwares in their house uploading child porn using their computer.
Rym: There's a lot of ways that could go.
Scott: Basically the point I'm trying to make is I don't know the law in Spain, but in the US.
Scott: what I'm saying is that based on that evidence alone and my expertise, there is reasonable doubt.
Rym: Oh yeah, reasonable doubt.
Rym: So what happened was they got a search warrant to go to the house to try to reduce the reasonable doubt.
Scott: Okay, sounds good.
Scott: Yeah, at least I agree as a non-lawyer that with that evidence, although there's still reasonable doubt, if I was a judge and you brought that evidence to me, I would give you a search warrant.
Scott: Judge Scott says search warrant.
Rym: So Scott, reasonable doubt, remember, is only during the trial right now.
Scott: I know, but what I'm saying is that we're looking for probable cause.
Rym: is the term you're looking for.
Scott: I'm saying is that with that evidence, Judge Scott would give the search warrant.
Rym: Yeah, it would be probable cause for a search warrant to go.
Rym: just check it out.
Scott: Juror Scott would say not guilty.
Rym: So yeah, so the cops show up and they don't find anything and they do their shitty cop stuff and you can read them all out in the story.
Rym: They harass the family, eventually found nothing, but the family then fought back to try to figure out how the hell this happened.
Rym: You know why this family was incorrectly accused of child porn?
Rym: Because the report came from the United States with the United States date format.
Rym: The police in Spain used the European date format, month, day, year.
Scott: So if they had corrected the date and time, they would have gone after a different IP address.
Scott: That IP address would have, well, it's the same IP address.
Rym: No, it was the same IP address, but the family was not using that IP address on that day.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: It would have been the same IP address, but they would have found out, "Ah, that IP address wasn't assigned to this house.
Scott: It was assigned to someone else at that date and
Scott: time.".
Scott: They just had the date and time wrong.
Rym: So 10/11/2016 could be 10/11 or 11/10, depending on where you live.
Rym: And because America uses a different format from basically the entire rest of the world, and this investigation crossed international boundaries, they just fucked it up real bad.
Rym: And because the technology involved is so pathetic, it actually took the family a bunch of time to like sue and figure out that that was the problem.
Rym: And now they're suing for damages.
Scott: Good.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Moral is America, I use month, day, year because that's how almost everyone does it, because I live in America, but I recognize that it is utterly, utterly stupid to do month, day, year.
Scott: I don't do that.
Scott: I use, at least whenever I have the opportunity, I use year, month, day.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: If it's mine, I'm year, month, day.
Rym: Everything I do, all my files, year, month, day.
Scott: All of GeekNights is year, month, day.
Scott: It's like perfect order.
Scott: You can't go wrong.
Scott: It's always unique.
Scott: It's always exactly right.
Scott: There's never confusion, no matter where you live in the world.
Scott: If I go year, month, day.
Rym: In fact, I can use that string of numbers as my database key if I really need to.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It's year, month, day, as long as you don't have more than one thing happening on the same day.
Rym: Yep, exactly.
Rym: Which we do.
Scott: And you just go year, month, day, hour, million, minute, second, millisecond.
Scott: From big to small.
Scott: You can't go wrong with big to small.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right?
Scott: DNS, com, dot, com, Google, www.
Scott: Big to small.
Rym: And in one last really, really small news too.
Rym: Way back, we mentioned this.
Rym: We didn't really follow up on it, but I think it's newsworthy.
Rym: Well, way back.
Rym: Oh my God, this wasn't that long ago.
Rym: This was in July.
Rym: Let's see.
Scott: So basically, last year- You can't even know your own news.
Rym: Firefox, I was looking for the date of this news.
Rym: Last year in March 2019, totally different world, 1000 years ago, Mozilla, Firefox.
Rym: Firefox had a cool feature.
Rym: You can just send a file to anyone.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Firefox send.
Scott: It was this really cool website where- Because for some reason, you know, back in the day when you would just- You're on the internet, sending files should be the easiest thing in the world.
Scott: You have a computer.
Scott: The other person has a computer wanting to send a file.
Scott: It's a pain in the ass, right?
Scott: Because you have to form a direct connection and no one has their own- Like you have to open ports.
Scott: Everyone has a NAT router.
Scott: Just sending a file directly to someone else is hard, right?
Scott: You need some sort of intermediary.
Scott: Most people use Dropbox or Google Drive or something like that these days.
Scott: Back in the day, we'd use AOL Instant Messenger or ICQ.
Rym: You could just drag a file- I used to transfer a lot of files via ICQ.
Rym: That's how I did a lot of my piracy as a kid.
Scott: They don't let you do that anymore, right?
Scott: The peer-to-peer file sharing networks, those aren't too much of a thing.
Scott: They're still out there, right?
Scott: But sending a file directly to another person is not as easy.
Scott: It used to be email attachment.
Scott: You got limitations, right?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, Firefox made this cool thing.
Rym: It was encrypted.
Rym: It uploads the files, just like upload it.
Scott: It's completely anonymous, completely free.
Scott: There was a limit on size, but that's it.
Scott: You go to Firefox send.
Scott: You drag a file.
Scott: It uploads to a server.
Scott: You send.
Scott: It creates a URL.
Scott: You send someone the URL.
Scott: That URL lets another person download the file one time, and then they get rid of the file so they don't fill up their server, right?
Scott: With hard drive space.
Scott: You get that file out of here.
Scott: It's already been downloaded or whatever, and now you don't need an account.
Scott: You don't need anything.
Scott: You can just send files to anyone very easily unless your file is enormous, in which case you'll figure out something else.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So, 4,000 years ago on July 17th, 2020, they suddenly shut this service down, and we found out about it because Scott tried to send me a file, and he was like, "Oh, I think Firefox send doesn't work
Rym: anymore.".
Scott: Yeah, we used it to send GeekNights recordings back and forth because why not?
Rym: So, they shut it down basically because people were using it to send malware to other people to trick them.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: What you would do is you would upload a malware to Firefox send, and then you would send someone a phishing email or some other kind of email, trick them into clicking on this link.
Scott: You don't need to own any servers to host your malware.
Scott: There's no way you can be taken down, right?
Scott: You don't have a server to take down.
Scott: You're nothing, right?
Scott: You're just someone sending a message to someone else on the internet with a link, right?
Scott: You don't need any accounts for that.
Scott: You can't be traced in any way.
Scott: It's really hard to find out who did that.
Rym: And that was part of the goal.
Rym: Firefox send was partly a goal to be able to privately and securely just send files to people.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, now somebody gets an email or who knows what, right?
Scott: They click a link.
Scott: They download a malware from Firefox, a completely trusted website, and they run it, some exe, and it's a malware that messes up their computer.
Scott: And we have no idea who did it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And so Firefox is like, well, people, we have a service that's being misused for evil.
Scott: If we keep this up, evil will continue to abuse it and go unpunished.
Scott: So we don't want to continue to provide that service for evil.
Scott: Let's shut the service down because we have no way to provide this service without providing an evil shield.
Rym: Oh, so in this article, someone, they posted a link to a tweet that someone's like, hey, Firefox is being used for this malware.
Rym: Can you add a report abuse button?
Rym: But the account that reported it is called Lena inverse and it's ad inverted Lena.
Scott: Very nice.
Rym: That's cute.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But the problem is, how do you have a report abuse button?
Rym: The file is gone, but they don't have it anymore.
Scott: By the time you could send it, you could theoretically send them the URL of like, hey, this is the URL that sent me a malware.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then they could figure out like what IP address uploaded that malware.
Scott: That IP address just using some VPN service or who knows what.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, OK.
Rym: But they also like wouldn't be able to verify, like, was that file really on that link because they don't keep it anymore?
Scott: Was that a malware?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Was it a child porn?
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So clearly, and this has been the problem for all of time.
Rym: The reason this feature does not exist is that it is it will be used for very good, secure private things.
Rym: It will also be used for horrible things.
Rym: There's really no way to prevent the latter with a secure file transfer system ever.
Rym: They just can't do it.
Rym: That's why it doesn't really exist in a lot of places.
Rym: And Dropbox gets abused heavily as well.
Rym: So I was looking around.
Scott: The Dropbox at least is not anonymous, right?
Scott: The Dropbox employees and can look around and be like, oh, it is a Dropbox full of child porn unless we know who to send to jail right now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And we won't get it wrong like Spain or whatever.
Rym: So I'm looking at the Firefox website and they actually have like an update about Firefox send.
Scott: What's the date on the update?
Rym: I can't find a date.
Scott: Okay, great.
Rym: Doesn't actually show a date.
Rym: It's on support.mozilla.org.
Rym: What happens to Firefox send?
Rym: So basically they said it's temporarily down while we work on improvements and they're going to try to do two things.
Rym: One, improve abuse reporting.
Rym: and two, the requirement that users have a Firefox account.
Rym: I am confident, maybe I'm wrong.
Rym: I like to be optimistic here, but I'm pretty confident this will not solve the problem and that there is no way to offer this kind of service and actually solve that problem.
Rym: Because now the people who are sending malware just have to do an extra step, make fake Firefox accounts.
Rym: And if they make it hard to make a Firefox account, then people are going to get Firefox accounts.
Rym: If they make it hard to do the file transfer.
Scott: I think the Firefox account already has, you know, the same kind of protections that you have against making a Google account or a account, right?
Scott: Not like a Twitter account where you can just make them more easily.
Scott: Facebook, you can make them kind of easily.
Scott: Google is a little harder than that, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, the similar thing is you got to go through some captchas and you got to go see some other rigmarole.
Rym: I do have like five Google accounts when I think about it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, you know how it is, right?
Scott: You know, it's, it's, it's a pretty good, but not perfect shield against just someone, you know, just not having any account at all.
Scott: I was like, but it's interesting that imagine if you could tweet with no account, right?
Scott: Like Twitter, where any, you could send any HTTP request that the website receives at tweets.
Rym: So I guess that the moral of this one is one of the things that most people want on the internet and would use in good faith for good things like a killer app of the internet.
Rym: People were, it's been obvious from the beginning of the internet, barely exists and basically can't be offered.
Rym: unless society is willing to accept all the evil ways.
Rym: someone might use this very simple technology.
Rym: And there's almost just really no way around that.
Rym: Like you can't heuristically analyze the files people are uploading to see if they're malware because then you're violating the privacy and defeating the purpose of the feature.
Rym: So we'll see, I don't know if Firefox send is ever going to come back or not, to be honest.
Scott: And I've been really, you know, and since we've not, since we've been unable to use it, we've been sending back the files using Google drive, you know, and it's actually way, way faster.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It is actually a lot faster and easier and we're just using Google drive now.
Rym: Because we both have accounts.
Rym: It just works, but it doesn't serve the same purpose as just send a file to someone.
Rym: It's more like Scott has an online cloud account.
Rym: I have my own online cloud account.
Rym: Scott shares a file with me.
Rym: I can go to Scott's online cloud account and download that file from his thing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Which is fine for us, but imagine trying to explain that to your grandma compared to just tell them use Firefox and type my email address.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: So, you know, nerds often have this fantasy, especially nerds that live in a place where the selection of internet service providers is awful or limited to one or zero, or they live in a place where the internet service providers are offering very slow or crappy service or pretty much most of the United States, right?
Scott: The internet service providers are offering slow, expensive service.
Scott: They're too far away.
Scott: We have a friend who has a really good ISP.
Scott: That's a mile down the road who won't run fiber the one mile down the road to his house because it's only one, there's only one house, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, cut the amount of money that costs.
Rym: Close.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: Um, so this dude, Jared mouch, I hope I pronouncing your name properly.
Scott: Jared has a, as a little YouTube channel here.
Scott: Um, and Jared out in a rural ish looking location, right?
Scott: Um, you know, not too rural.
Scott: It's like, if you look at, he shows a map of where he lives.
Scott: He's like where his house is his farms, but like a couple roads away, but those are, you know, couple blocks away being rural blocks, right?
Scott: Not city blocks, right?
Scott: Are like, you know, suburban developments with, you know, cul de sacs and a whole bunch of cookie cutter houses, right?
Scott: So there's definitely people in the area, right?
Scott: They're just not right on his doorstep.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Um, he was mad because yeah, the only ISP he could get was slow as shit.
Scott: He was using like a wireless ISP.
Scott: That's all he could get really.
Scott: That was slow and meh, but you know, it's what he had, right?
Scott: He goes and he puts in several years of labor and pile and you know, a large amount of money, hundreds of thousands of dollars.
Scott: and he does the work and he learns his shit and he sets up his own internet service provider.
Scott: He lays fiber, he hooks up, he gets customers to sign up and pay in advance.
Scott: And then presumably once the things are up, they'll just have free service until that advanced payment runs out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But he needs that money upfront to get things going.
Scott: You know, he, you know, the support, the equipment, the hookups to the, to the actual internet, property owners to let you like run fiber through their property.
Scott: Dealing with the city and you know, getting a stop work orders and the other utilities, not accidentally busting the gas line when you're digging and like everything he gets it done.
Scott: He's online as of September, 2020 and here is the 34 minute YouTube video.
Scott: He breaks it down.
Scott: He breaks everything down.
Scott: He got it done.
Scott: So if you've got that many years and that much money to invest and you want to start an internet service provider, right?
Scott: It can be done.
Scott: You could do it right.
Scott: If I was in New York, it would be way, way harder because underground is way more of a mess than he's.
Scott: He's like, oops, I cut one wire in a dirt field, right?
Scott: It's like, yeah.
Scott: But yeah, buying fiber, having your, you know, machines that you left out at the work site, stolen hiring contractors to dig stuff.
Scott: It's like, you know, just the amount of shit you had to go through.
Scott: It's like, we knew that that was the kind of shit you had to go through.
Scott: And that's why we never even thought of, we're like, we started, we stopped before we started.
Scott: We ain't even going down this road, right?
Scott: We're like, we see all that shit in advance.
Scott: We're not even going to touch it.
Scott: We're just going to suffer with shit ISP or move to where this good ISP, right?
Scott: But nope, Jared here, he said he saw all those obstacles in the way and he put in so much time and effort to chop them all down.
Scott: Good job, Jared.
Scott: I hope this video paves the way for someone else to do the same because a world with many small Jared ISPs is way better than a world with a few big ones.
Scott: And it's amazing to see that like, when he started, he had a couple megabit right from his wireless, whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And he got his shit finally hooked up and he goes to like speed test and it's like 700 megabit.
Scott: And he's like, could you imagine that feeling of working on this, right?
Scott: Living in a farm somewhere where there's no shit, no good internet.
Scott: And you're, and you're an internet person and you're suffering with like two megabit for years and knowing that you just did it yourself like that.
Scott: You put in so much, you put in so much time and work and you have customers too, who are going to be using this, right?
Scott: And use one day you turn it on and it's just 700 megabit of real internet, not some garbo Verizon internet, right?
Scott: It's like, damn, that's some good shit.
Rym: So you can love this slide on like the cost breakdown because he has a little bit at the end.
Scott: That's like, maybe it's how he breaks it all down.
Scott: He breaks it all down, right?
Rym: But there's the line of this.
Rym: might've actually been cheaper than moving to a place with better internet.
Scott: Yeah, it probably was, you know, especially since he was getting income too, right?
Scott: It's not just all costs, right?
Rym: He's eventually going to get money from, you know, what's cool is this also really shows the, like a lot of nerds in particular, especially tech nerds.
Rym: They get this impression that things are pretty straightforward and easy.
Rym: Like building something big is as easy as building something small.
Rym: It like multiplication of concerns as you rise in scale of what you're trying to build.
Rym: And the fact that this video breaks it down, this is like, I, this is almost like required viewing for someone who's a sophomore in a tech school to be like, yo kid, just because you learn how to write, I'd like net code for a trivial game does not mean that you now understand why net code is bad on a steam game.
Rym: That's gigantic, right?
Scott: And this is how all projects go, right?
Scott: You have to realize no matter what you're working on, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, you make a Gundam on your desk, a little plastic one.
Scott: You want to make that giant Gundam that they have in Japan, right?
Rym: It's not just bigger.
Scott: That's one, one scale, right?
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: It's not just, it's not just the same thing, only bigger, right?
Scott: It's as hard.
Scott: And this guy's, Oh, this is only a tiny ISP he's made, right?
Scott: Imagine trying to be Verizon.
Rym: I mean, that's why that's a giant, giant, giant company without.
Rym: that's why Verizon charge.
Scott: That's why next time Verizon charges, not to say the Verizon's good.
Scott: Fuck them.
Scott: But at the same time, that there's a reason they charge you a hundred bucks a month for whatever answer or more for whatever service.
Scott: I pay that.
Rym: And you know what they give me a five.
Rym: there's fiber that comes into the front of my apartment and I'm connected to that piece of fiber and I get a shit ton of bandwidth over it.
Rym: I don't have to worry about any of it.
Scott: And I didn't have to, and I didn't have to do what Jared did.
Rym: Props to Jared.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Good job, man.
Rym: Try to get Jared on GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah, go ahead.
Rym: I got to watch the rest.
Rym: I haven't watched the whole video, so I got to watch.
Rym: It's worth it to the end.
Rym: So I think it is a real simple little cute thing, but I bumped into this channel.
Rym: It kind of like how recently we realized that a ton of these really good, funny animations were all from that one worth it.
Rym: Kids YouTube channel.
Rym: There's another little channel like that.
Rym: Uh, the Fernanda Diaz artwork, YouTube channels got like 260,000 subscribers.
Rym: It really should have more.
Rym: And it's all these short little like animated music videos to like snippets of songs and things.
Rym: But this one in particular I'm linking to is called.
Rym: it's from the song like Morena.
Rym: And it's just this series called Witch Bunny.
Rym: And it's this really well animated girl with like this magic witch hat.
Rym: That's a bunny and this guy that she's there's a relationship with and he's got like a cat familiar and they're just super cute and super beautiful and well done.
Rym: And they're just a little bright spot in your day.
Rym: And if you enjoy this video, the whole channel is just full of this stuff.
Rym: Like this is just really, really good, cute, simple animation.
Rym: I'm trying to do more fun, like things they like that where I don't have like a moral or like some big thing or screed or something.
Scott: This is just this thing of the day.
Scott: My thing of the day was just too good.
Scott: I could not put that on.
Rym: No, no, I'm saying yours is great.
Rym: I'm saying this is just like, it's the best thing I've seen since the last time I did a GeekNights, which was literally the words we wrote down in 2004 when we were trying to plan GeekNights.
Rym: We called, we came up with the idea of a segment called Thing of the Day.
Rym: And the literal idea was, what was the best thing you saw on the internet since the last time we recorded a GeekNights?
Scott: Met a moment, finally.
Rym: Yeah, met a moment.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the PAX Online is ongoing.
Scott: It is currently PAX Online.
Scott: We are at PAX right now.
Scott: We're literally GeekNights from PAX.
Scott: When does this happen?
Scott: So you can go to the PAX Online Discord.
Scott: It's open.
Scott: They got PAX Online on Twitch.
Scott: They got PAX Online on YouTube.
Scott: They got PAX Online on the PAX Online website.
Scott: There's PAX Online on Facebook and Twitter even, I think.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's PAX Online is on everywhere 24/7 until it's over.
Scott: Our panel is New York time this Friday.
Scott: 5 p.m 5 p.m.
Rym: New York time, 2 p.m.
Rym: Seattle time.
Scott: On the PAX 3 channel.
Scott: So go to the Discord and the YouTube or the one of those platforms where you can watch video and you'll see the panel then.
Scott: It is a 100% new panel.
Scott: If you know, if you hear that from me, that is true.
Scott: Actually new panel.
Scott: And that will be the first time you can see it.
Scott: There may be a VOD up available of some kind.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: We will be in the Discord.
Rym: We'll be in the PAX Discord like answering questions and chatting with you.
Scott: Yes, we will be in the Discord appropriate channel which I believe is the one entitled Goose Theater is the third one, right?
Rym: I'll double check.
Scott: Stream 3 Goose Theater.
Scott: and then when the panel's over the discussion moves to Stream 3 Continuing Discussions.
Scott: They got two channels.
Scott: So come to the Goose Theater Discord channel.
Scott: Chat with us.
Rym: I think you're even going to give us a special color on our names as the panelists.
Rym: It's basically the equivalent of the speaker badge we'd normally have during our panel and for like a couple hours afterward.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: And then also while you're there, you might as well join the official GeekNights Discord server.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you have Discord, you know, come on over.
Scott: The Twitch chat is going to be sub only.
Scott: So just be aware of that.
Scott: I might look at it, but I don't think I can chat in it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Just come to the Discord.
Scott: If you actually have a question.
Scott: I'm not using a Twitch sub on PAX 3, right?
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: I mean, back when I was a live streaming enforcer, I was on PAX 2.
Rym: I never touched PAX 3.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Other meta moments.
Scott: The book called Book is Still, Tale of Genji.
Scott: I have not read another word of it.
Rym: I wonder as the weather gets cooler and I'm doing more low key outdoor activities, I might spend time sitting under a tree reading.
Rym: So we'll see.
Scott: My urge right now is actually to build some of these Gundams that are piling up.
Rym: My urge is to deal with, we got other conventions we got to make panels for and announcements.
Rym: I'm basically stuck doing GeekNights shit all week this week.
Scott: I also got an urge to actually write some software.
Scott: So I might write some software, I don't know.
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: GeekNights website.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: There's a lot of GeekNights stuff in the hopper.
Rym: We will be doing a cool, I'll just tell you guys, I don't know when it's going to be scheduled, but it's super magwest.
Rym: We're technically going to have our first super magwest panel.
Scott: Because we've never been to magwest, we might not ever go to magwest.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But because it's online, hey, we can do a panel at magwest.
Rym: We're going to do, it's a variation on a theme.
Rym: We have our panel, we don't need to record it again because we did it like perfectly a long time ago, called Play Dirty to Win.
Scott: So you can just go watch that panel on YouTube right now, right?
Rym: Yeah, that one goes deep.
Rym: That one we'd like, there's like a 10 minute segment where we'd look at.
Scott: So if you're listening to this right now, there's no reason to watch our panel at magwest because it's going to be that same panel only shorter.
Rym: Well, it's a lot shorter.
Scott: A lot short, half as short.
Rym: 25 minutes instead of 60 minutes.
Scott: Half as long.
Scott: Yeah, half as long and, you know, half as deep.
Scott: So just watch the YouTube video and don't bother going to magwest.
Rym: Well, I think the differences, like the way we got to do this is the Play Dirty to Win panel really was more about like this broader picture of like being a player of games.
Rym: And we talk a lot with a lot of anecdotes and a lot of details and examples.
Rym: And we have this sort of meta conversation about like, where's the line?
Rym: The short version is just, you want to win?
Rym: Do this.
Rym: Fuck your friends.
Rym: Like.
Rym: it is more like the how-to guide without any of the ethics or morals or meta commentary.
Scott: Okay, well I guess we have to do it because it's only giving us 30-something minutes, right?
Rym: Yeah, I guess we'll record it like tomorrow or Wednesday.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Also, I'll tell you guys right now, we just watched Wolfwalkers.
Rym: We're going to talk about that on Wednesday.
Rym: If you want to watch Wolfwalkers in super high quality and you don't want to pay Apple, you can rent it on like the Toronto International Film Festival for like 15 Canadian dollar a dues.
Scott: Oh, I thought, oh, 19.
Scott: Oh, I paid less than 19.
Scott: I thought it was 19 was Canadian.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, Canadian is not as bad as it used to be like that.
Scott: This is an unexpected, very small, but still not nothing.
Scott: Silver lining of, you know, the, the pandemic is that things going online means we now have access to things that we never had access to.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like someone who could never go to packs ever.
Scott: They've never been to a single packs.
Scott: It wouldn't be able to get to one.
Scott: for, you know, for us packs online is a disappointment kinda.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But for them packs online is like, Ooh, I finally get more than zero packs.
Scott: So, you know, as someone who likes going to a film festival, but has only been able to go to New York ones and not that much right.
Scott: As much as I would like, anyway, suddenly I'm accessing films from film festivals all over the place.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, uh, yeah, if you don't see Wolfwalkers as part of the Toronto International Film Festival, which is available right now, as we're speaking until some undetermined time, when it's the film festivals over, you're going to have to wait until late October to supposedly get it on Apple TV plus or buy it on iTunes.
Scott: So yeah, that's a thing.
Scott: or buy a Booray or a DVD or whatever.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I guess it'll be in theaters and non-us countries to dangerously go to a us theater.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know how many us theaters it'll actually be.
Scott: And if I don't risk your life to see the movie, it's like, you know, not that it's not good, but no movie is that good.
Rym: And there is, there is a theoretical movie that would be that good.
Rym: That does not exist.
Scott: As far as we know, that could not, I don't think any movie could be so good.
Rym: I would risk my life to go see what if the movie just reprograms your brain via your eyes goes to the shell style.
Scott: It's just a, I'd watch it at home.
Scott: I'd wait.
Rym: What if it only works in the theater?
Scott: I'd build a theater.
Scott: Cause it's AK.
Scott: I'd build my own theater.
Scott: I buy an AK screen.
Scott: That's worth buying it, right?
Scott: If it's worth that, if it's worth risking my life, it's worth spending out the money for an AK screen.
Rym: But yeah, serious talk.
Rym: Like don't go to a theater, especially if you're in the us to see any movie for the foreseeable.
Scott: No one listening to this is allowed to go to a movie theater until I go to a movie theater.
Scott: No one also, no one can go to a sporting event until I go to a sporting event.
Scott: That's the rule.
Rym: But that means you, if you take, if you take an evil and dangerous action, I'm assuming that you're all, uh, more risks takey than I am.
Scott: That is the assumption.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You are pretty on risk taking like you'll bike, but you won't buy fast downhill Rym skis.
Scott: I don't ski.
Rym: That's how come, you know, well, like Scott has a much better bike than me and can bike faster and further than me, but like on long distances.
Rym: But if there's a downhill, I'll always pass Scott because he will slow down a little bit for safety.
Rym: I basically never break on a downhill.
Scott: Well, I mean, my bike just, even if I don't pedal goes faster downhill, that Rym's bike, regardless of who's on it, just cause my wheels are better, but I hit the brakes and therefore like that's how it is anyway.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So software updates because we realize we never really talked about this in like a generic way.
Scott: I think you deleted the episode.
Scott: I have a vague memory of doing it.
Rym: The way we come up with new episodes for gig nights is I look for a show we already did.
Rym: That would be easy.
Rym: I deleted from the database.
Rym: I purge all records of it.
Rym: And then tell Scott, Hey, turns out we've never done a show on anime.
Scott: So from the perspective of a user, right?
Scott: There's a lot of people out there, right?
Scott: Let's get to the, let's not, let's cut to the chase, right?
Scott: So there's a lot of people out there who like, don't like to update their software.
Scott: They install it, they like it.
Scott: It works.
Scott: And they're like, I don't want no updates.
Scott: They turn the updates off.
Scott: They refuse to install updates.
Scott: They let the updates build up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the, you know, because, and it's understandable why some people would feel that way.
Scott: There have been times where updates have burned people.
Scott: just recently.
Scott: There was an update to Lightroom that caused a lot of photo data, uh, photos.
Scott: If you were doing things a certain way to be irrecoverably deleted, um, if you didn't have your own backups separately, right.
Scott: Uh, the recent, you know, a lot of people get mad when software updates and changes the user interface, right?
Scott: They, I like old Microsoft word.
Scott: I don't want to use the new one with its ribbons or whatever the hell, right.
Scott: They don't want those updates.
Scott: Um, and so people refuse to install updates and they've never noticed getting burned by not updating.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But even though they have been burned, right, there may be new features that they've missed out on.
Scott: that realize they've missed out on.
Scott: And there may be security holes or other bug fixes that come in those updates that they're not aware of.
Scott: Maybe because they don't, uh, see the bugs.
Scott: Maybe they got used to the bugs.
Scott: Maybe the security threat, you know, happened and they just didn't realize it.
Scott: Or maybe they just got lucky and it was never exploited.
Scott: Um, and so people have this attitude of not updating.
Scott: I think that's stupid.
Scott: I, if I get updates, I install updates immediately and always to everything.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like my windows.
Rym: So the only thing I'll do is like windows updates.
Rym: I will schedule them or defer them.
Scott: If I'm like in the middle of something, like obviously you restart your computer while you're in the middle of a GeekNights episode.
Scott: If an update comes up now, I'll run it tonight, tomorrow morning.
Rym: Let's say I'm editing a four hour long panel to upload to some crazy new convention.
Rym: Like it's a big deal.
Rym: And the deadline is like Saturday at midnight.
Rym: I'm not going to let any window up windows updates happen during that week when I'm finishing all that editing just in case.
Rym: But yeah, once I upload that video, windows update happens immediately.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: But most people who make a claim like that, what they're, they don't actually have like a serious thing that they're waiting for.
Rym: Or like they just like, they have this weird, unreasonable unwillingness to let Microsoft update their stuff.
Rym: Windows updates don't actually break things that often.
Rym: It's pretty rare unless you're in enterprise, in which case it's someone's job to deal with that.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And if you got burned once, it's like, yeah, there's a chance of being burned by some updates as a user, but if you want to avoid being burned, right, you know, the lesson to learn is not don't update anything ever.
Scott: The lesson to learn is if you really, you know, are that concerned, every time there's updates, go and look at the change logs, do your research, figure out what those updates actually do, what they don't do, have other people deployed them or not.
Scott: Are there any known bugs in them?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then decide whether to install the updates, right.
Scott: Or not, right.
Rym: Of course the or not is tricky because one thing that can happen, like I used to manage this stuff in an ancient time.
Rym: It's funny nowadays, I don't know shit about how Windows subsystems work anymore.
Rym: Like I'm Googling like everybody else because I don't like have to deal with it much except on my workstation at home.
Rym: But there was a time when that was my job.
Rym: So I had a situation once at an employer where there was a Windows update, that Windows update broke some critical software that's old.
Rym: There's no way to make that update not break that software.
Rym: And the software would have to be fixed or Microsoft would have to change something about the nature of that update.
Rym: The latter is not going to happen 99% of the time.
Rym: So in that situation, it can be a tricky decision.
Rym: Like I couldn't just say, well, all the Windows machines in this factory will never get a Windows update again.
Rym: That is not the right answer.
Rym: But that seems to end up being the answer in many cases.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: The problem is what is the right answer is highly specific to you and your exact situation, but generally it involves come up with something clever or make a VM.
Scott: Another thing is, you know, when I say install updates immediately, right, you have to remember I'm talking about updates that are stable, you know, release updates.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Don't subscribe your production like Linux server that you do stuff on to like the bleeding every commit someone, a lot of large software projects, you know, have different levels of updating windows.
Scott: For example, you can get regular standard updates.
Scott: You can get like, you know, I think there's like two or three levels of like, I want the new hotness update windows every night with the brand new code that hasn't been fully tested yet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, don't do that unless you're a windows developer, right.
Scott: You're working on windows itself, and then you need those updates, you know, good for your windows software.
Scott: But you know, if you're just a user, always subscribe to the stable updates, the most tested ones that other people have already put through their paces or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you know, people might be like not trusting someone who's sending down updates, but it's like, well, but you're using their software.
Scott: You trusted them enough to put their software on your computer.
Rym: That's the people I don't get the most.
Scott: They're already all in like, it's like, okay, you don't trust Chrome to auto to send some, you don't want to turn on the auto updates because you don't trust Google to like not do something evil to Chrome.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you trust them to put Chrome on your computer already.
Scott: You're already in the hole.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You're already in the hole with that.
Scott: There's no point in turning off the updates.
Scott: Now you're already, you already gave into them.
Scott: If you don't trust them, you shouldn't install that Chrome in the first place.
Rym: Then you have the people who then at least you're consistent, but then you have the people who like the UI or UX of something and they don't like changes that were made to it.
Rym: And they just decide arbitrarily from this point forward, I will never update my software again.
Rym: And those are the people that today are still asking questions in forums.
Rym: Like how do I get Adobe premiere CS4 to like not crash when I export this video?
Rym: because I have all that.
Rym: So there's a little difference there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So we've been talking so far about just like patches to your existing software.
Scott: It's like, I have Windows 10, you know, but like someone who has Windows 7, Windows 10 is not just an auto update.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you have, you know, I don't know what's not an auto update these days.
Scott: A lot of things these days are just auto updates.
Rym: Especially like consumer software, like your Twitter app on your phone just updates itself.
Scott: But I guess Microsoft, I guess the office even now is like office 365 or whatever.
Rym: You can't have the like regular installed office too.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They're worse.
Scott: There are still some software projects out there where there is a clear division of like, okay, you know, this is this version and it is updating, but now here's a new release.
Scott: It's actually a different sort of updated, better, different thing, but it's still the same thing.
Scott: The way that, you know, Windows 95 is not Windows 3.1 the way that Adobe CS4 is not CS2.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So for those situations, it's like, do you upgrade?
Scott: Because now upgrading is not some automatic free thing that you just get.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's a, you have to actively choose to switch from the one you're on to the next one, pay money possibly.
Scott: So doing that switch, I think is basically, you know, especially if it costs money, you have to consider that as just, you know, not an update, but as a new thing.
Rym: And the question though is where is the line between like, when do I replace my, when do I replace my car?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, if your car, you know, if you're getting a free radio, that's better than your current radio, that's an update.
Scott: But it's like, I drive a 2000 X Honda, whatever, and I'm going to switch to a 3000 X Honda, whatever, because the car was managed to last a hundred years before it broke.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, look at Adobe software now, because now that a subscription, instead of paying for it, you basically just subscription versus, you know, uh, pay for the one thing is, or is a completely different topic.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: But when you're subscribed to it now, it is just like little updates come over time forever.
Rym: And there are people who still resist those updates the same way that they resist the Microsoft updates.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Those, once you're like, you know, we can put off the subscription versus not discussion to some other episode, but once you're in the subscription zone, it's like all those updates are what you're paying for.
Scott: You're you have it, you're paying for it already.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You're turning off those updates.
Scott: You're basically throwing away your money.
Scott: A and B like, most of those updates are new fancy features, not bug fixes.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, um, you want those updates.
Scott: They're.
Scott: all they're doing is making shit better.
Rym: Now it's funny when I think back, like I used to toy with Linux and run servers and stuff more often, I tended to curate updates a little more, but I think that was just my younger brain, like trying to have more control, even though it didn't really matter.
Rym: And I tended to separately because I was a nerd trying to do stuff that wasn't super stable.
Rym: I usually often needed to jump into less stable versions of updates to make things work.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Scott: I mean, that's just a Linux world thing, right?
Scott: Is that, you know, you have lots and lots of small packages that all interact and have dependencies on each other.
Scott: That doesn't exist with monolithic software packages.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so, especially if you're, you know, messing with your computer as a hobby, right?
Scott: Like using a gen two or an arch Linux or something like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, yeah.
Scott: It's like, you want to, you know, here's a program I actually want to use.
Scott: Here's all its dependencies is another program I want to use and all its dependencies.
Scott: And there's a lot of overlaps and mismatches and, you know, there are ways to manage those.
Scott: But yeah, it can cause, it can cause some issues.
Scott: It's like, you know, if you want to change the default Python on your computer from two to three, and now this other thing that only works with Python two is looking for the default Python, you got to go fix it.
Scott: You know, you can run into problems there if you're just always updating everything, which is a good reason to, if you actually want to use your computer and not play with your computer, that you should use a distribution like say Ubuntu or Debian or something more stable.
Rym: Use one that's stable and has like semi-monolithic or at least like automatic updates that are just binary distributions, not source distributions.
Scott: And just run the auto update.
Scott: And unless you do weird stuff, it's going to take care of everything for you.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Now, listener pointed out, I was going to get to this.
Rym: There is even more complications here.
Rym: We live in New York with fiber and like everything, but there are people who have devices that can't get online often or that have metered bandwidth.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Or unreliable internet.
Rym: And sometimes you can't update or you like have to go through a rigmarole.
Rym: Like I remember I knew someone when I worked at IBM, they'd like had basically an ISDN line at their house.
Rym: So they couldn't actually update.
Scott: That used to be the shit though.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It used to be awesome.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I think that old website is down where the guy's using AOL and the tech guy's like, what the fuck's wrong with you?
Rym: We have like a corporate OC3.
Rym: It costs like $10,000 a month.
Scott: When I'm at home, iOS apps have a lot of updates.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Especially some of the more popular ones, you'll get updates maybe like once a week even for some of those things.
Scott: So every once in a while, my iPhone, it'll either auto update the apps on its own or I'll go into the app store and I'll just push the button that says update all the apps.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And sometimes there'll be like 10 plus updates in there, like on a regular basis.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I tell my phone I can only update when I'm on wifi.
Scott: If I go on a trip, like say to a Pax, if I could do such a thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I don't, you know, the internet that I have when I'm not at home is airplane, internet, air, uh, hotel, internet, maybe an internet limit on my phone.
Scott: I am not updating the apps.
Scott: I know my, yeah, my data on my phone.
Scott: I'm not using any of those to download all the updates.
Scott: When I get home, it's like 40 apps need updating.
Scott: It's like, all right, let's do it all now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Which is also kind of a good thing because like, it's similar to the example you said where you're editing the thing for a week and you don't do updates.
Scott: Then it's like, I'm on a trip.
Scott: I can't afford to have anything break on my phone while I'm on the trip.
Scott: I need all this stuff to be working.
Scott: And then when I get home, I can do all the updates.
Rym: In fact, I was on a trip where the, uh, I think the jet blue app stopped working on my phone because the new updated version doesn't work with a whole ton of Android phones for some reason.
Rym: And they didn't fix it.
Rym: And I don't fly jet blue anymore.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: That was before COVID.
Rym: But literally I flew somewhere with like the electronic, uh, like, uh, ticket.
Rym: And then when I've tried to go fly home, the app wouldn't work on my phone anymore because it updated on the hotel wifi.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So let's, you know, there's a lot more to say on this, but let's go to the other side, right?
Scott: So you're a software developer or a software publisher of some kind, right?
Scott: You have, you have clients, users, be it inside a company, I guess we'll have to talk about a company or, you know, enterprise versus, uh, enterprise is its own world.
Rym: Like that's, uh, and also there's less and less deployed enterprise software.
Rym: Increasingly a lot of enterprise stuff moves to a software as a service or SAS model.
Rym: You hear people where there's a website that you go to and the website is the program.
Rym: So, right.
Scott: So there's nothing to talk about.
Scott: The reason we didn't mention those things, you know, updating Twitter is because as a user, you have no choice, right?
Scott: There's no decision to make.
Scott: It's like, you're stuck with what they give you.
Scott: On the user side, if you have a cloud app, right?
Scott: It's like, if Google updates Google docs, it's like, guess what?
Scott: You're using the newest Google docs.
Scott: Tough shit.
Rym: Maybe if you're lucky, they'll be like, here's the new version.
Rym: Try it out.
Rym: Give us feedback.
Scott: Reddit lets you use old Reddit if you want.
Scott: Right.
Scott: For example.
Rym: But there's usually a time limit on that.
Rym: Like eventually the old YouTube studio gets shut down.
Rym: They did.
Rym: I actually, every time the new one came up, I said, no, I'm not going to use it because it's missing this one feature.
Rym: And eventually they added that feature and then I used it.
Rym: and now the old one's gone.
Rym: The feature was upload more than one video at the same time.
Scott: So that's why we're not talking about that from the user side, but from the developer side.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So when do you update, right?
Scott: Your software.
Scott: So, you know, you're probably putting bug fixes out on a daily basis, right?
Scott: So if you have a, like a SaaS situation, right?
Scott: It's like, maybe you've got a really good development workflow with the testing.
Scott: We've talked about, I think the nights episode and like CI/CD before, right?
Rym: We did that relatively recently, I want to say.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that you can go listen to that.
Scott: That is the good way to do things in a, in a software service model where things are just constantly being deployed all the time.
Scott: Users don't even realize it, but bugs are just getting fixed constantly.
Rym: You can even do fancy stuff like deploy an update to some of your users and then scale it up later.
Rym: There's all sorts like that.
Rym: That is a different world of updates.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And it's kind of an exciting world.
Rym: Like I like that more agile, lowercase a agile.
Rym: I like that.
Rym: I like that more agile, like idea of software.
Rym: Like software is a little fluid.
Rym: Like I feel like there are fewer people though.
Rym: There are still people who will see like the UI change slightly and they freak out.
Rym: There still are people like that, but there are fewer of them because that is sort of the default model for most things people use nowadays.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's also, again, a separate topic I think we've granted about before.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But let's say you're not that.
Scott: Let's say you're making a product that's still delivered to users, you know, set up that EXE.
Scott: They got to download it and run the update or there's an auto update.
Scott: You're making a web browser when, you know, people only are going to get auto updates when you push one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When do you push one?
Scott: So like we talked about with the user side, you have these different tiers.
Scott: Maybe you allow users to opt in to getting, you know, untested nightly builds or more frequent builds.
Scott: You can test on them.
Rym: I'm a fan of that UAT sort of model.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And then if those users aren't complaining and sending in, you know, bug reports and something after a certain amount of time, then you mark those as being ready for the next go and you send them out to the rest of the users.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, you also have to look at, you know, the severity of what you're pushing out.
Scott: Like, oh, it's a security fix.
Scott: Better push it out right away after you've tested it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, but if it's a new feature, you got, you should wait for that new feature to be like really solid before you go with it.
Scott: You know, it's not as important that it goes out so soon.
Scott: You know, you can wait to get, you know, like you'll see Photoshop.
Scott: They don't put out the new features in Photoshop until they're really solid.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're not like, here's some brush thing that barely works that we just came up with yesterday.
Scott: But if it's a security fix, that shit goes out the next day.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And in terms of like auto updaters, you have to think about like, it really comes down to if your audience is big iron enterprise or like smaller shops in terms of does your updater itself have to support those enterprisey type of workflows, like let the administrators in a firm like control the deployment settings of updates via a registry setting or something like, do you make that easy?
Rym: Do you support it directly?
Rym: Do you support it directly in your app?
Rym: Or do you just make it a monolithic install and AXEs and MSIs and let them use generic tools?
Rym: Like that really just depends on who's using your software for what, where, how, why, et cetera.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So if you're doing some enterprisey biz, right.
Scott: You got to realize anyone getting your software as a customer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So now, and like, they're paying a lot of money, not, you know, like, yeah, the users of your, you know, $50 software customers too, but you have supposedly a lot of them when you have a few enterprise customers, right.
Scott: Even few could still be a lot, but much fewer than, you know, customers of a consumer product.
Scott: And they're paying more money each.
Scott: Now the concerns.
Scott: it's like, there's similar concerns, but the weight on them is very shifted.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, okay, we got a new update.
Scott: This is a security update.
Scott: We need to push this out right away because if any of these systems are compromised, that's devastating.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Sometimes there's SLAs that you have to worry about.
Rym: Like if Google makes a mistake, people want their money back.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Clawback clauses are a thing in certain kinds of software.
Rym: Like, Oh, if the software has certain kinds of problems and you don't fix it within X hours, I get a refund.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: That is important.
Scott: You also have to think about keeping, just keeping the users happier.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Cause they're using this every day at work, eight hours a day, supposedly maybe.
Scott: You know, it's like, you got to make sure those people are happy.
Scott: Right.
Rym: To a point, there's a weird situation.
Scott: It's like, you can upset like Twitter makes, like we just said, Twitter makes updates to its UI.
Scott: that makes people upset, but they just have to deal with it.
Scott: And eventually they shut up about it and forget about it.
Scott: Enterprise people, that doesn't happen.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: You have to keep them happy.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But you also get into this weird situation where the users sometimes aren't actually the people.
Rym: you have to keep happy.
Rym: Sometimes they're unhappy no matter what, especially in big enterprise.
Scott: You keep the purchaser, whoever makes the purchasing decisions.
Scott: That's the customer, not the user.
Rym: The person who signs the check.
Rym: Well, the person who authorizes the signing of the check, the person who actually says spend that money.
Rym: That's the only person you actually have to keep happy.
Rym: But if you piss off the wrong users with a poorly planned update, that person is going to be unhappy and now you're screwed.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Now also when you're doing enterprise software, you got to realize that the old models of the old day, if you're not doing the SaaS thing, right.
Scott: Even if you are doing the SaaS thing, right.
Scott: They still exist.
Scott: So when you're making a new feature, not a fix, but a feature, right.
Scott: If you're doing the old model, it's like, well, do we just give all our existing users this feature for free to make them happy?
Scott: Or do we hold off on this feature and sell it as like an upsell?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the next time we send our vendor to go visit them, right.
Scott: Our salesperson, right.
Scott: And they consider the salesperson a vendor anyway.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You say, oh, we got this new feature.
Scott: You want to pay us 20 more bucks a month for it or 200 more or 2000 more, right.
Scott: It'll make your life easier.
Scott: You sell them on it, right.
Scott: Versus just giving it to them for free.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Also, if you got the SaaS thing going on, right.
Scott: Where everyone's just accessing your software from the cloud, you develop a new feature.
Scott: Well, is this feature for all users?
Scott: Is this feature for only the people who are pro level?
Scott: They're paying more per month per user.
Rym: Well, do a real analysis.
Rym: Is this an option for existing users or is it a feature targeting new users?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is it a steering wheel?
Scott: It's like, all right, all cars got the steering wheel or is it the air conditioning that not everyone gets?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you know, you suddenly, you got to consider those things, right.
Scott: And that actually an engineer, you develop the software and they're like, yeah, we're only going to only going to get like 10 people using this because we're only going to let them use it if they paid a hundred zillion dollars.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Then like the update process to like get that feature can be kind of onerous because it's like a one-time like, well, they get the special version of the software.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: There's a lot to discuss there and it bleeds into like, look at what you said, what we were talking about now bleeds up into like the business planning and also bleeds down into like the DevOps.
Rym: Like it starts to cross a lot of lines in big companies on both the publisher side and the user side.
Rym: It gets really complex.
Rym: Like it's really hard to talk about this in detail, especially considering like a lot of this has been my job over the years.
Rym: I can't share a lot of anecdotes, but there is a third space I want to touch on briefly in this episode.
Scott: Firmware updates.
Scott: Then I got to eat food.
Scott: Oh, firmware.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Firmware is a little bit different.
Rym: Because firmware updates are an interesting thing because there are software updates that can effectively brick software.
Rym: Like there I've seen updates to software that change a database in a non-reversible way.
Scott: I've had sometimes updates for iOS apps where the app, you try to open it and it just immediately crashes.
Scott: And that's like, well, I shouldn't have updated that one, right?
Scott: It's all it does is immediately crash.
Scott: Now I restart my phone, I delete and reinstall the app.
Scott: It's like, nope, it's just, it's just crashing.
Scott: They need to fix it.
Scott: And usually they do fix it, but it's like, well, that software is bricked.
Scott: It just won't even launch until whenever.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Now occasionally there have been situations.
Rym: I had some software like consumer software a while ago where the auto updater itself broke with an update.
Rym: And the only way to fix that was to update the auto up with an auto update.
Rym: There's no auto update for that.
Rym: You had to go get an exe to fix the auto updater to then get the rest of the updates.
Rym: But the trouble they had was telling their users to go do this, convincing them that it wasn't a lie or a scam or malware.
Rym: It was, that was, I've seen that happen a few times.
Rym: My advice to you as a publisher, you're going to have auto updaters.
Rym: It had better be able to recover itself.
Rym: Like focus on that first.
Rym: If an update fails, it had better work its way back to where it was before the update tried to apply without any weird problems.
Scott: I like the software architecture of if you have an auto updater or updater in your self updating software, that you also have a backup updater in your software.
Scott: that is like, you can invoke that one if the other one fails.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: To sort of reinstall the whole schmageggy.
Scott: But also publisher, you got to worry about security because your updater, what if the updater is often the, it has where the security holes are.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Attack someone.
Rym: The updater has a way like a fallback mechanism.
Rym: Someone figures out the way to get that to turn on and they start like publishing their own updates.
Rym: They point the auto updater is often the security hole that all the stuff better be signed or point the auto updater to different IP and magic comes down the pipe and stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Make sure you're not installing updates from some not official source for anything ever, because that's basically how you get ruined.
Scott: But no matter what.
Rym: Firmware updates are the one place where I still do not recommend people just blindly install the newest version of firmware on all their stuff.
Rym: Cause firmware updates don't like they can break your device permanently.
Rym: They're fiddly.
Rym: They're often difficult to install.
Rym: That's getting easier over time, but like, eh, depends on what you're updating.
Rym: My phone's firmware pretty easy to update my hard drives.
Rym: Like I'm never going to bother with that.
Scott: Oh no, no, no, no, no, no, but yeah.
Scott: So firmware isn't, people think firmware is kind of magical and mysterious.
Scott: Uh, I could find you, there's some resources online that sort of demystify firmware, but basically firmware is just software.
Scott: It's not special.
Scott: The only difference is that instead of being written to your hard drive, right.
Scott: Where it's sort of, you know, uh, it feels like it's malleable.
Scott: It's written to like some flash storage inside of a device where you wouldn't think of there being storage, right?
Scott: So it's not really a big deal to update firmware.
Scott: The problem is, is that if firmware is bad, right?
Scott: The it's sort of part of hardware and it's hard from a user interface way to interface with it.
Scott: Um, so if a hardware has bad firmware, that hardware appears completely broken, even though it may be fixable.
Rym: Like if I apply a firmware update to my printer, it might just not power on anymore.
Rym: Now what?
Rym: Good luck.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna, uh, yeah, you'll, there is a way probably to fix it, but it's not going to be obvious.
Scott: It'll be annoying, tedious, difficult, right?
Scott: You'd like get the printer to launch into debug mode and do a thing and maybe put a file on a USB stick attached to the printer.
Rym: Set up a TFT, a lot of, a lot of firmware updates involve running a TFTP server on your local network.
Scott: Uh, I don't, haven't seen that one.
Scott: I've seen that one in the past, but not recently.
Scott: I saw that one a lot, a lot in the past.
Scott: I've seen that one a lot in the past, but not recently.
Scott: Um, but yeah, so when you're going to install firmware updates, it's like, oftentimes there can be good firmware updates.
Scott: For example, I update the firmware in my camera pretty regularly.
Scott: I check the change log first, but all you do is put a file on an SD card, put it in the camera, turn the camera on, wait, don't touch anything.
Scott: Wait for it to finish.
Scott: I've never had a problem doing it.
Scott: It's always worked, but I checked the change log and most of the time it's like, yeah, this lens will auto-focus better or, and it's a lens I have, or we added the, a feature so you can use your camera as more of a webcam kind of, right?
Scott: It's like there's meaningful updates in those.
Scott: They don't push those out for just any old thing, right?
Scott: It's like they push them out when something's significant in there.
Scott: Um, you know, sometimes they'll have to add extra pages to the user manual for the camera cause they've added new features to the firmware.
Scott: So it's like, those are good.
Scott: Um, but like, yeah, update your bios.
Scott: It's like, well, what did they change?
Scott: It's like my bios is working right now.
Scott: My EFI, my computer's turning on and functioning, right?
Scott: What did they add, right?
Scott: That I'm going to risk breaking my motherboard, right?
Scott: If it's not something good, I'm not doing it.
Scott: You know, why would I do it?
Scott: What's the point?
Scott: if there's no point why it's not, you know, you're not risking as much updating Chrome as you are updating your EFI bios firmware.
Rym: And over time, some firmware is sort of auto updating just like software would, and some firmware is just going to be fiddly forever or for the foreseeable future.
Rym: And just honestly, don't worry about it unless you have a specie or told to worry about it and have a specific reason to worry about it.
Scott: Well, I think it's like, I think you actually should worry about it.
Scott: You should go, you know, know all the hardware you have and seek out if there are firmware updates for the hardware you have.
Rym: Oh yeah, but not like super like I probably, I do that like once a year ish.
Scott: Yeah, no, you don't do it all the time, but just saying those things are not pushed out to you.
Scott: They don't like raise alarms and like say, hey, update.
Scott: Then no one's notifying you of that, right?
Scott: You have to go out and find it.
Scott: But go out and find it, see what it does.
Scott: If it does something meaningful, go ahead and do it.
Scott: If it doesn't, don't just let it go.
Scott: It's like, you didn't even know about it.
Scott: If you hadn't searched anyway, right?
Scott: There are some systems though that are auto updating firmware.
Scott: For example, my work laptop is this Dell latitude, whatever.
Scott: And it's actually surprisingly came with a perfectly clean install of windows, which I was like, oh, that's very nice.
Scott: There's no Dell garbage on here, but there was actually one piece of Dell garbage, which is this app called Dell command update.
Scott: Dell command update, uh, gets driver updates for the laptop hardware and also firmware updates for stuff in the laptop automatically.
Rym: Actually, that's a good point.
Rym: Laptops in particular often have a bunch of firmware and some app like that.
Rym: You should probably let that auto update or run.
Scott: when I, when they first, right, when they first gave me this laptop, it was slow as balls and all kinds of broken and kind of meh.
Scott: And after I ran Dell command update, it actually was now that became operating normally.
Scott: So, uh, it did make a huge positive difference to actually run that separate updater.
Scott: It's not, it's not a replacement for windows update.
Scott: It only updates like laptop specific things that windows update doesn't know about.
Scott: Um, but that's an example of like, sometimes the laptop will reboot after the Dell command update and like, it'll say like updating firmware, do not power off laptop, beep, beep, beep, beep, right.
Scott: Um, yep.
Scott: So that's what does annoy me though.
Rym: Firmware updates oftentimes still have the problem of it says don't update, like don't power off during eh, and it will just break if you power off during eh.
Scott: Well, yeah, there's no, that's just a matter of how computers work.
Scott: There's nothing you can really do about that, right?
Scott: It's like, it's like, it's flashing data into a piece of flash memory.
Scott: that will not, that flash memory will not be able to be written to or read from if there's no power.
Scott: If you cut the power now, it won't finish writing the software to the flash memory.
Scott: And when you try to turn it back on now, that device won't operate.
Scott: There's nothing you can do about that.
Rym: And there are technological solutions to that, but they're not feasible.
Rym: Like having backup flash memory.
Scott: Put twice as much, put twice as much flash memory in the device, making it more expensive.
Rym: That's not going to happen for like your low end monitor or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, um, that's the thing.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So we've gone long enough and I'm hungry.
Rym: So good times.
Rym: See you guys Wednesday.
Scott: Update.
Scott: Update your shit.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this Monday episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichols, Marty Green, just like a dude guy, Chartavish, and Graham Finch.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart.
Rym: Well, the plane landed and when I came out, Clinton Walton, Jay Vance, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Nicholas Brando, Chris Midkiff, Dread Lily Tenebrae, Chris Rymer, Finn, Shervin Von Harl, and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: So funny story, Scott's preamp might have literally blown up about a minute after we cut off the stream, so we might have to tweak some audio pipelines for the Wednesday episode, so stay tuned on that.
Rym: That'll be a fun thing to fix, especially because we also have to, luckily, we use a different set of equipment when we record the panels, so our MagWest panel that I mentioned will not be affected by this, but we might have to hack something together to record GeekNights on Wednesday, so see how that goes.
Rym: But anyway, for now, I leave you with something that I don't know if anyone will actually remember but me.