Rym: It's Thursday August 22nd 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight, Australia part dude.
Scott: It's not fresh.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: I'm feeling a lot more energy now that we've been back from Australia for a while.
Scott: I'm feeling pretty good energy today because when I biked to work this morning in New York the things we talked about biking in New It was gonna rain and I got it only rained a block away from the office and I got in the office.
Scott: So I barely got rained on and then it was raining all day until I was leaving work.
Scott: The Sun came out.
Rym: So I know I know I was good.
Rym: I went to work right.
Rym: take that rain.
Rym: I was like I should bike.
Rym: look how nice it is outside.
Rym: But I had some other stuff had to take care of.
Rym: so I didn't want my bike at the office cuz I had to come back home anyway.
Rym: So I didn't bike and then I got to the office and because of the timing it would have rained on me.
Rym: Had I biked at the time I would have left.
Scott: So on top of that I'm waiting for my new shower head to come because my previous one broke.
Rym: You didn't buy a water pick.
Rym: Did you?
Scott: I bought the top rated one in Amazon?
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: Well, was it a water pick?
Rym: I'm really not feeling the water.
Scott: Let me see what it is water picks.
Scott: It's basically the same kind of thing We've always gotten.
Scott: oh, you know, it's a plastic shower head with you twist it in his mode.
Rym: Ah, but so what I've?
Rym: I did a lot of research into shower heads because I replaced my water pick with a different brand Not as commonly known brand as a Delta 75 700 WH 7 spray.
Rym: I know that one because that one was actually one of the ones I looked at because it is born in the top rated.
Scott: It has four and a half stars in Amazon after 491 reviews, that's a lot.
Rym: I looked at that one.
Rym: I ended up getting this dual head one, but now I thought about getting one of those.
Scott: They're way more money.
Rym: Uh, yeah, so I got a dual head one.
Rym: That was only 60 bucks.
Scott: That's the way.
Scott: that's way more money.
Scott: this one is only costing me I. I forget it doesn't have the price right now.
Rym: Yeah, you're gonna feel really silly if you use my show.
Rym: 20 20 26 how absolutely fantastic my show It is.
Scott: I want to talk about not how fantastic good shower heads are but how shitty.
Scott: I reverted to the shower head that came With my apartment.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you want to get me started?
Rym: I got something to say about that because it's broken.
Scott: I reverted to the shower head that came with my apartment.
Scott: low flow does not even begin.
Scott: I would have more coming down on me if I went outside in a drizzle.
Scott: It's like there's two lasers of water that are like sort of going in.
Scott: It's like it's like a baby is peeing on me and that's it.
Rym: No, that's it simultaneously.
Scott: How can I clean myself with that if anyone out there?
Rym: if you take the ad the sort of legal flow limiter out of your?
Rym: Shower head you're kind of a dick because I don't think you understand how much fucking water you waste if you take that out.
Scott: But I used to take it out to increase the flow.
Scott: But then I realized like oh if you have a better shower head you can leave it in and still get the flow Exactly.
Rym: If you take it will remember and then you won't waste water.
Rym: We moved a beacon.
Rym: We were like, hey Let's take it out.
Rym: We took it out and then we're like, oh one shower empties the hot water heater.
Rym: That's stupid.
Rym: and we put the flow limiter back Because we were used to RIT where the water pressure was just low and that's when you're supposed to take it out.
Rym: If the water pressure is low if it's high like in New York Imagine just turning on the faucet.
Rym: Just letting it go.
Rym: Just bam open faucet.
Rym: Yeah But What the fuck is up with anyone who has lived in a place for?
Rym: More than a month and has not replaced the default shower head with one that is on Some sort of rope or chain mechanism?
Scott: Maybe they live in some sort of luxury place that has an awesome shower head or maybe High-end showers that just blast you from all sides.
Scott: It has like electronic.
Rym: Yeah, but seriously, how do you wash your asshole?
Rym: Effectively if you don't have the kind you can pick up and hold down by your asshole Maybe they just bend over and show their asshole to the sky.
Rym: I mean, I understand I think it's a health related thing in hotels because people might put it in place.
Rym: They shouldn't put it.
Rym: So I'm kind of okay with that though I note every country I travel to that isn't the u.s.
Rym: It has the same kind of shower head Rym.
Scott: think about this.
Scott: Until those things weren't fucking invented until till when what where what year.
Scott: they didn't have those.
Scott: They had those my entire life, right, but I'm talking like in the 50s.
Scott: you think they had those.
Scott: probably I don't know.
Scott: you ever see one in an old movie.
Rym: How often do you see the inside of a shower in an old movie?
Rym: Psycho, yeah, I was gonna say name another movie.
Scott: So I couldn't have one.
Scott: Yeah I'm just.
Scott: I'm just telling you that.
Rym: but I guess I just don't get humans who live in a place Where they don't get a real shower head.
Rym: It's like dude 20 bucks.
Scott: It is 20 bucks.
Rym: 20 bucks for one.
Rym: that is a thousand times better than what you've got.
Scott: seven modes.
Rym: Mine only has three modes and two heads.
Rym: now if I turn on two heads at the same time, that's stupid That's that's gonna waste so much water.
Rym: dumb dumb, but the way mine set up, right?
Rym: I have a head that's fixed up there that actually has a really good sort of angle mechanism.
Rym: So I can get it like angled perfectly and then I have the one I hold.
Rym: I can switch between them the way It's set up.
Rym: the angle one that's fixed Uses way little water, but it gives me this nice spray.
Rym: So it's keeping me warm.
Rym: It's doing the basic washing but then I take the stick one and switch to that and it's basically It's basically super powerful asshole cleaner.
Rym: Sure, but the key is it's super powerful.
Rym: So it wastes water.
Rym: But I only use it for like a minute in my entire shower and the rest of the time I'm standing there with the normal one Using way little water and not getting cold cuz I'm like soaping up my stuff Mmm.
Rym: Yeah shower heads.
Rym: We should do a whole show on sour shower heads Okay, so yeah, that's not a bad idea.
Rym: That's a pretty good show.
Scott: ideas already already done.
Rym: it We've done have we?
Scott: we just did it right now.
Rym: now I got a lot more to say that I'm holding back low flow Jerry.
Scott: Okay, so I got some news here.
Scott: It's just a tiny gaming news, right?
Scott: But there's.
Scott: the Elder Scrolls online has been an MMO people are looking forward to right up maybe because you know MMOs are waning so and not too often a big one comes along.
Scott: So, of course one based on the sky rims and oblivions and the Maro wins is gonna be pretty hot, right?
Scott: Yeah, so they decided to charge 15 bucks a month, which is a lot Right, but people are crazy for this fucking thing.
Scott: So they'll pay it.
Scott: Well, I Know it's a month for Counter-Strike and they know that this thing is going free-to-play Eventually, so they're basically they're clearly gonna milk everyone for what they're worth and then go free-to-play, right?
Scott: Here's the.
Scott: here's the real catch.
Scott: here's the real cat.
Scott: there's a catch They're gonna put in the free-to-play buy stuff store to buy, you know in-game shit at the same time That it's still 15 bucks a month.
Scott: So you pay 15 bucks a month and you pay to win and then eventually when it's free to play It'll just be paid away.
Scott: All right without the monthly fee.
Scott: Listen assholes Thing you're paying 15 bucks a month to get nothing and then you buy a sword in the store with real money again, I Understand why the industry is going in this direction, but I also hate it.
Rym: I don't know what.
Scott: you don't catch me playing this even Counter-Strike right my pure game.
Rym: They added drops and they added you can get a I guess an mp5.
Rym: that's orange and it looks to everybody.
Rym: but The you know what they added, you know what.
Rym: two of the items are the Silenced m4.
Scott: Wait, you have to pay for that.
Rym: Well you everyone got it for free, but it's an item.
Scott: Okay, an optional item.
Scott: So there are people who won't have it.
Rym: I don't know if anyone will not have it.
Rym: Like if I buy the game today, I wonder if I get it or not and the silenced USP.
Scott: Does everyone have that?
Rym: Everyone who's currently playing.
Scott: Well, I mean you don't just have it you have to buy it with in-game no strike dollars, right?
Rym: It's what?
Rym: will you get it for free I guess cuz it was like the first item like, you know It's like you have it available to purchase like I have Kevlar available to purchase But I don't know.
Rym: I haven't tried it yet because I've been too busy since packed.
Rym: But I think you have to equip it outside of the game instead of your regular m4.
Scott: Oh Fuck that bull.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I have not played Counter-Strike since they announced their crate bullshit.
Scott: I mean, it's one thing if I can press B and then choose between the two and one cost more or something.
Rym: Well, this is why I'm worried because when kind of one round I want one and one round I want the other.
Rym: when Counter-Strike go came out.
Rym: It was great and I had literally One complaint.
Rym: and that one complaint was how come my m4 and USP don't have silencers?
Rym: And then when those were added through the steam bullshit item bullshit bullshit.
Rym: That's bullshit.
Scott: NS2.
Rym: Yeah, but I like you know, I like NS2 I like Counter-Strike more.
Rym: that's my game.
Rym: well, that's a problem and I have to keep a close eye on this because if this gets out of hand one I'm just gonna have to Sit down and edit my servers such that it's the way I want it to be.
Rym: at least dota only has to its credit only has And make using these items a bannable offense, but more importantly might just have to go back to one six one six At least one game that never dies.
Scott: You know one six is kind of awesome in that like people don't play quake one really but you can go back and play One six which is you know, I think it's partly because one six was one of those games that still kind of worked on the internet.
Rym: Yeah, I mean quick one.
Rym: You got to know IP addresses.
Rym: Yeah, like what's the IP address of this server?
Rym: You want to connect just to wrap up this gaming news?
Scott: I do want to say I'm thinking about trying the new ever quest only because it seems to be a combo MMO Minecraft and just the idea of that seems cool.
Scott: So I might go for the free trial on it.
Rym: I'm going to wait until you bite that bullet.
Rym: It's a free trial.
Scott: It's gonna take me like an hour to figure out if it's worthwhile.
Scott: Most of that hour will be spent downloading.
Rym: I spent money in Leviathan warships because no one seemed to know if it was bullshit or glad I did not spend money on that.
Rym: Yep, that's the show.
Rym: We keep forgetting to do.
Rym: we got a review Mario Tennis and all those 3ds games the way we want games Because they're not no one reviews the news over there, uh, so I got it, you know, it's Thursday, it's the lounge.
Scott: No, that's your mom.
Rym: We can talk about whatever we want.
Rym: So one We live in New York If you can't tell no from listening to GeekNights and we have a big mayoral election coming up.
Scott: So yeah We can actually vote an election.
Scott: that matters where the votes are counted mostly honestly and the votes are close and it's not.
Rym: And because the Republicans just don't matter here because they don't the primaries are all that matter.
Rym: so as a result It's not like I have to choose between a gennaro right-of-center Democrat and an ultra right-wing or ultra religious Republican.
Rym: I get to choose between two or three Democrats all of whom have slightly nuanced positions on things.
Rym: So it actually kind of matters.
Rym: so a lot of our listeners do live in New York and if you're not paying attention to the Local elections where you live That's why your shit sucks.
Scott: that shit matters a lot a lot more to your day-to-day life.
Scott: Then my current election my current City Council person vologna who is good and bad, right?
Scott: He's responsible for the gentrification of my neighborhood, but also other things which not so good But anyway, he is trying to become the Queen's borough president.
Scott: So there's all these people like trying to run to like take his spot if he wins or whatever.
Scott: It kind of matters.
Scott: For me at least yeah.
Rym: But pay attention because Bloomberg is on his way out and there's been the firing.
Rym: the mayor's office of New York has been kind of Funny lately because
Scott: I just run for mayor
Rym: racist stop-and-frisk thing And basically the New York mayor's office has been having hissy fits on Twitter like the City Council basically shut down their racist stop-and-search policy where they'd go to neighborhoods and Stop black people and see if they had guns.
Rym: and they say that yeah, we found a bunch of guns.
Rym: We're stopping crime, even though they don't citation Cystic show.
Rym: crime going down after stuff is right, but the City Council was like, alright, we passed some laws You can't do this anymore.
Rym: Yeah, and the mayor was like veto and the City Council was like, yeah over Roger veto.
Scott: That's how democracy works.
Scott: Yes, it works only in this tiny area.
Rym: But listen, this is New York.
Rym: Do you know how many people live here?
Rym: and yet still are my individual piddly little vote?
Rym: Actually statistically significant.
Scott: Yep, because not everyone votes.
Rym: What about all of you who live in like, I don't know.
Scott: Gary, Indiana How many people vote is not you know, and Gary, Indiana, I read a story.
Rym: actually There's been a bunch of stories about Gary so poor.
Scott: they sold a bunch of houses for really one dollar.
Scott: Ice cold keep piece of shit.
Scott: house one dollar.
Rym: Yeah, those houses were only available to people who lived there already in the area.
Rym: I would have bought all twelve or twelve bucks make a minimum income of like $35,000 a year and they have to live in the house for five years or they lose it not doing it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No one's doing it.
Rym: But Gary's been in the news a lot for a lot of reasons.
Rym: But if you live in a place like that, how many people do you think vote for like the comptroller?
Rym: Like how many people do you think vote in that?
Rym: they go to the place they vote They look at a list of names of people who want to be the comptroller and they pick one.
Scott: your vote matters a fuck ton.
Rym: So I got one other cool thing is this Thursday.
Rym: well, not really cool kind of sad but also cool.
Rym: so The Nuremberg trials.
Scott: what you got winning this show?
Rym: It's not even half over, you know, the trials were we.
Scott: What does this have anything to do with August 22nd 2013?
Rym: the victors of the of the of the Second World War?
Rym: took all the Nazis and Tried them for crimes against humanity and executed a whole bunch of them on August 22nd.
Rym: No now it's not the anniversary.
Scott: How is this?
Scott: how is this relevant to anything in any way?
Scott: Why bring this up randomly?
Rym: because there is something that you all might not know about the Nuremberg trials, right?
Scott: But how is it relevant to today or now?
Rym: It's not it's just Thursday bringing random.
Scott: I'm bringing up a cool random history fact up from Rym.
Rym: Well, because I kind of I kind of ran through the course of my Civil War interest lately and I got back into World War II.
Rym: uh-huh, so Here is the cool thing.
Rym: You did not know about the Nuremberg trials.
Rym: They were basically the first time in history that modern simultaneous Translation was used anywhere.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: This was the first time IBM set up all these systems.
Rym: You know the UN all?
Scott: yeah, they took all the ones they used to count the dead Jews with and they reprogram them.
Rym: But you know the idea like we think oh a big court trial or a big, you know Anytime there's a thing going on in the United Nations Everyone's got those earpieces in and there's simultaneous translation and things like that.
Rym: that did not exist until the Nuremberg trials.
Rym: that had never been done before and It caused nervous breakdowns in the people doing the translation Because no one had ever been trained to do that before.
Rym: There was no school of here is how to listen to someone speaking in German and and talk English at someone else back and forth.
Rym: That shit's actually really hard to do.
Rym: No, and the whole field of study and the profession of simultaneous translation like we do today basically began with the Nuremberg trials And I thought that was a cool interesting history fact.
Scott: come random history fact from Rym.
Scott: That's your new segment Rym.
Scott: No, I'd be random Unrelevant unrelated to anything.
Scott: history fact.
Rym: that hereby is what I'm gonna do on every lounge show from now on.
Rym: the random history fact The history minute is nothing to do with anything rims history minute.
Scott: It can't.
Scott: if it's relevant to the day or time or any recent event in any way and allowed to do it It has to be completely unrelated to anything that's going on.
Rym: Well, actually this one is completely relevant to Things of the day.
Rym: Yes it is.
Rym: So this is a CollegeHumor video And I found pretty hilarious and I haven't linked to CollegeHumor in a while, so here's the deal.
Scott: I haven't gone to CollegeHumor in a while.
Rym: I still go because you know what it is.
Rym: a gold mine of great videos It is but it's a good filter if you Want to see funny videos on the internet to be perfectly honest and you don't want to spend a lot of your time Trolling for them on the internet.
Rym: CollegeHumor's video feed is actually a pretty good subset of all the worthwhile videos.
Scott: They have people there who gets videos submitted to them and their job is they see watch them all and pick out good ones.
Scott: So shitty job, but someone does it.
Rym: this is a short skit We're in.
Rym: someone finds out by going through his attic that I guess his grandpa's a big fan of Wolfenstein.
Scott: I'm a big fan of Wolfenstein.
Rym: Yeah, well apparently that look at not the way is.
Rym: well.
Rym: this guy grandpa was really into this.
Rym: look at all these autographed books.
Rym: Oh my god cosplay.
Rym: Great.
Rym: what's this picture of people hanging out with the final a guy dressed as the final boss from Wolfenstein?
Scott: I like how grandpa is peepa.
Rym: It's a good video.
Rym: you should watch it and then think about the tragedy of World War two and the Nuremberg trials.
Scott: So here is the thing of the day that is getting away from God Godwin's law.
Scott: This is a blowback rubber band gun shaped like a desert eagle It doesn't say replica down the side of it even though that's what it is.
Scott: it's made of wood.
Scott: it's amazing.
Scott: I would pay monies for this.
Scott: it shoots rubber bands and it also has these little wooden shells that shoot out the side.
Scott: It's reduced amazing all over the place.
Rym: That's the kind of thing.
Scott: if you look at the side of YouTube you can see as a whole geekery of making guns rubberband guns that look like real guns and function like real guns.
Scott: But this one I think is the current best of that.
Rym: That's the kind of thing that I would like to have on a little stand on my desk.
Scott: Yeah, kind of thing.
Scott: I wouldn't bring to the airport.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, it doesn't have an orange tip, okay We're gonna be at pecs prime.
Scott: that's pretty much all that fucking matters right next weekend.
Scott: Oh shit on Thursday.
Rym: We're going to arrive and go to a fancy party For charity, I don't believe it's sold out yet as of when I checked a few hours ago.
Rym: We will be there.
Rym: We're gonna be in the VIP section.
Rym: We will be running games for People who attend who are not VIPs.
Rym: We'll be hanging out.
Rym: if you want to hang out with us for several hours with dinner and drinks in I think the tallest building in Seattle and Have all the money you pay for this go to charity check this thing out because we will be there on Thursday.
Rym: It's gonna be cool.
Scott: Also dog sled events dot-com.
Scott: D-A-W-G.
Scott: Were you willing to?
Scott: Yo dog sled events dot-com.
Rym: and on Monday Fax is four goddamn days.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: We're gonna be presenting a brand new lecture.
Rym: Bad games in the Wolfman theater gonna be so bad at noon.
Rym: Oh, I should bring a power glove.
Scott: Do you have one?
Rym: in Arizona You know, I never had a power glove contemporary to when I wanted one.
Rym: not ironically sure.
Rym: So book club book is Stasi land.
Rym: I'm almost done with it.
Rym: Scott hasn't started it yet.
Rym: Y'all should read it.
Rym: This NSA shit is not cool And I think you really need to really cuz.
Scott: I'm totally cool with it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, yeah 40% of Americans are totally cool with it.
Rym: Apparently.
Scott: I don't know about that guys.
Rym: You got to get mad.
Rym: Seriously, Stasi land is a pretty.
Rym: it's the book club book.
Rym: It's pretty good has a few flaws, but there's this one story in it.
Rym: I'm gonna try to sell you guys actually reading this book.
Rym: Basically this guy worked for the Stasi.
Rym: He was like a low-level function area And he had his like department had won this like bullshit award.
Rym: So I had this plate on the wall this plastic place that Stasi and the plate was like, you know best department something something.
Rym: I forget the details.
Rym: So Eventually, he was kicked out of that office for insubordination Good job.
Rym: and as he left he was sitting in the office ready to leave and he was like I Fucking stole it.
Rym: Yeah, and that's when the Stasi and the GDR instituted the I think stolen plate recovery Initiative and sent agents to track him and try to find the plate that he hid somewhere.
Rym: And the story goes on from there And that guy there's at the very end.
Rym: He's like like having that plate.
Rym: He has the plate to this day Yeah And he is like.
Rym: this is the symbol of everything that I fought for.
Scott: that plate should be in a museum.
Rym: Well, it's in his house now and I feel like he deserves to keep it in his house till he dies of old age And then it's going into museums or maybe they'll bury him with it.
Scott: Either way, whatever Other meta things we have this email newsletter.
Scott: It's kind of works.
Scott: people actually read it.
Scott: It has content that you won't that I write.
Scott: it's really funny Probably gonna send it out like tomorrow or maybe this weekend.
Rym: It has its own things of the day.
Scott: Yeah, it's got.
Scott: so if you go to our website you can sign up for that.
Scott: You can also follow us and all the other internet places that exist, you know, Twitter's Facebook's iTunes is YouTube's.
Scott: so go to all those places and follow us and all those places to get if you like us.
Scott: Apparently you like us enough to waste your goddamn time listening to this worthless podcast.
Scott: So Scott, you should at least go to the other places and you'll get even more of the shit you like.
Rym: How does one sign up for our newsletter?
Scott: you go to front recruit calm?
Scott: All right, and you go down to the footer?
Scott: Right.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It says newsletter.
Scott: you click on that.
Rym: I got that shit.
Scott: You type your email address and you push subscribe.
Scott: Alright, that's it.
Rym: You guys should all subscribe.
Rym: It's hard.
Rym: It's pretty cool.
Rym: stuff happens in there Australia.
Rym: cuz we didn't quite finish talking about.
Scott: we were there a long time To say we only said a show's worth.
Scott: so we got maybe another almost shows worth to say Yep, cuz you know, but I forget what we already said.
Scott: So Rym Please go down the list of notes.
Scott: We made about things we did but did not talk about.
Rym: Alright, so the biggest thing that I can say that happened is we went biking.
Rym: Oh, right, so we decide, you know, cuz Emily and I did this a while ago.
Rym: We went to Japan for a power and we stayed in Nagoya, which is kind of a chill.
Rym: Not it's not like the kind of city you think tourists would go to.
Scott: someone said it was the Philadelphia of Japan.
Rym: I've heard a lot of people say it's the Chicago of Japan.
Scott: sure But it's what do I know?
Rym: a chill place and Emily went to school there.
Rym: So we're like, hey, let's go.
Rym: So we stayed there for a few days and we rented bikes one day and bike just all around the city like everywhere We went like this is a pan mad hilly.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, and I can bike.
Rym: I'm just saying yeah There's no trouble at all.
Rym: Biking was difficult there though, partly because everyone bikes super slow and bikes on the sidewalk with terrible bikes and the bikes are shitty.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, we saw a few cool people biking in the street with real bikes, but we could not rent real bikes.
Rym: Kind of like we couldn't rent real bikes in Melbourne.
Rym: Well, so we decided we were going to rent bikes One of the days and just bike around Melbourne all day and like biked up and down the coast because the coast is right there.
Rym: So we tried to find a place to rent bikes and it was actually kind of hard.
Scott: They have the city bike equivalent the bike share program.
Rym: It's the exact same physical bikes that we have in New York with city bike.
Scott: It's a system.
Scott: It's just a way cheaper and be.
Scott: helmets are mandatory, but they just sell helmets fucking everywhere for five bucks.
Scott: Yep, there's like a Melbourne City helmet You can buy for five bucks to any 7-eleven and people just like leave these things on some of the bikes because they don't give A shit.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So it's cool.
Rym: Look at the difference in New York.
Rym: The argument was we don't have a helmet law in general for bikes and the argument was that we shouldn't because studies show that when there's a helmet law people bike way less like way less and Statistically supposedly the average rate of deaths due to obesity When people are not active is worse than the average rate of deaths due to people not wearing helmets when biking Adults not children and we do have laws about children having to wear helmets.
Scott: One person did finally give me though a good argument for why there should be a helmet law because my opinion is basically look Breaks you could kill someone else if you don't have breaks.
Scott: Yep, but a helmet It's like if you want to kill yourself be my guess.
Scott: It doesn't hurt me if you have no helmet and the guy was like well when you have socialized medicines, right?
Scott: Not only I've heard that argument It was a second argument.
Scott: Not only can it cost other people if you get hurt more, right?
Scott: But let's say a driver hits you right?
Scott: Well, if you were wearing a helmet, maybe you only you know break some bones.
Scott: another driver is responsible for hurting you But if you don't have a helmet and you die now the driver is responsible for manslaughter.
Scott: Ah, so you're hurting that driver.
Scott: here driver didn't do anything differently.
Scott: He hit you but because you weren't wearing a helmet.
Scott: the consequence is more severe Even though the driver did the exact same drive mistake, but it is not the victims Responsibility to protect himself from crime.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: and Pretty much all the time when a car hits a bike pretty much the cars fault.
Scott: New York is 50/50.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is like.
Rym: I read a lot of the reports of like when there are bike incidents in the city is something I just follow because I'm
Scott: It's pretty important
Rym: but a lot of them end up being road rage or things like that As opposed to biker ran a red light and got hit.
Rym: it's often car ran a biker off the road.
Rym: Hmm, but I digress the.
Rym: what about the the eggshell thing that if you punch a dude and he just happens to be mad That's what it is.
Scott: That's what it is.
Rym: And though in the u.s The rationale is fuck you you committed a crime.
Rym: if the consequences were worse than you expected You shouldn't have committed that crime in the first place.
Rym: You were.
Rym: you should have been aware that as soon as you do something dangerous or stupid the consequences could be unlimited Depending on circumstance.
Scott: I think I just tapped a guy on the shoulder and he died.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: Yep, ah, but were you tapping him with intent to injure?
Rym: No, then it does.
Rym: that rule usually doesn't apply.
Rym: Okay, whatever anyway, but in Melbourne They have a helmet law but helmets are super cheap because they're subsidized by the government in New York.
Rym: There's no helmet law.
Scott: There are actually free helmets you can get but it's a little tricky to get them.
Scott: They're not just in every store in bundles.
Rym: Yeah, and honestly I don't wear a helmet.
Rym: often when I take a city bike in a very short trip I don't see anyone wearing a helmet on the city bike.
Scott: I only see you wearing helmets who have other bikes.
Rym: I'd say half the people I see on city bikes are wearing helmets.
Scott: I almost never see a city bike rider with a helmet.
Rym: the city bike people.
Rym: that's because you're in tourist town where you work.
Scott: Where I am the people who are riding those bike city bikes are people commuting to tourist town who also work there.
Rym: Most of the people I see downtown are commuters and people using them to go out to lunch like to go to the good food truck and back and they About half of them have helmets.
Rym: the ones who don't have helmets are the tourists.
Rym: Mm-hmm but apparently all the traditional bike rental places Went out of business pretty much as soon as their equivalent of city bike was put in place.
Scott: Yeah, all the New York people all the New York bike shops are we're like We're gonna go out of business when the you know We can't rent any bikes because the city bike is gonna make you know, kill our rental business And you know what it turns out.
Scott: that's true But bikes there's so much biking there.
Scott: in general bike shops didn't have rental businesses anymore, but they call bike shops.
Scott: They were still plenty of bike shops making plenty of money because there was so much biking going on.
Rym: So it really only hurt the bike rental industry.
Scott: It didn't hurt the bike shops in general because they made.
Scott: they did indeed still make plenty of money Doing other things besides renting bike.
Rym: we were talking to the guy at a shop really Hey, can we order a bike?
Rym: and he's like hell.
Rym: no, why would I rent bikes?
Rym: yeah, but there's a chance that actually bike shops are doing better because more people start biking because of these programs and Then they go buy a bike and and a better helmet than the $5 shit.
Rym: Yep, and also city bikes suck.
Rym: So if you like biking you're gonna eventually buy a real bike for $100 a year.
Rym: A real bike will pay for itself very quickly compared to city bike Anyway, but it was really interesting that it did in fact destroy the bike rental industry and I have zero sympathy.
Scott: Yeah, so so we wanted to get so.
Scott: you didn't want to get the city bike equivalent because it's a pain in the ass.
Scott: Well, it would be shitty.
Rym: They would have been great If our intent was to use them to go from place to place in the major downtown area like go to the museum on the Bike go to a restaurant on the bike go to a museum on the bike.
Rym: But no we wanted to bike like fucking down the coast.
Scott: Wanted to go to where the Grand Prix track was, you know, which because it's they.
Scott: you know It's a road course where they have the Australian Grand Prix.
Scott: So it's like well, it's just roads But the same roads f1 cars go on but you're basically biking.
Rym: we wanted to bike way out into places like New York.
Scott: How cool would that be to bike around the f1 track?
Scott: That's just currently normal roads.
Scott: Yeah, it's not currently an f1 track.
Rym: So we needed real bikes to do this because it's gonna be an all-day thing.
Rym: somewhat real bikes Yes, and we found a tourist place that still they rented out like date bikes like 40 bucks.
Rym: Here's a mountain bike for a day perfectly serviceable.
Rym: Yeah, not great, but not terrible work.
Scott: It worked.
Scott: It was a you know, the low bar step through.
Scott: I was like, you know, it went.
Scott: it had gears which you know The city bike thing only had three in a hub year.
Scott: This had real gears.
Rym: now the bike guy saved us from First catastrophe because we're about to leave.
Rym: she's like wait wait wait Americans right and we're like, yep, and he's like Front brakes on the right.
Scott: and we're like, wow Yeah, they had you know, the walking on the left the driving on the left the switching of the brakes.
Scott: But they didn't switch the gears.
Scott: the gears switching was still the same.
Scott: Yep But the brakes it's like the right hand brake brakes the front.
Rym: if he had not told me that I might have had some trouble I might have hurt myself Early, yeah, cuz we got right away around these hills.
Rym: I'm like up wrong brake up.
Scott: So we get going.
Rym: we get Maybe a mile out.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I'm basically super paying attention.
Scott: I'm like don't get hit by a tram Don't get hit by a car.
Scott: the whole time.
Scott: I'm thinking let's lay on the left side of the road and stay on the left side of the road.
Scott: Use the correct brake lever stay on the left side of the road.
Scott: Don't get hit by a tram.
Rym: I kept almost like turning right and like oh nope left left stay on the left and I almost went into the right bike lane.
Rym: Like three times I was like no left bike lane.
Scott: So then something happened I did not expect at all.
Scott: Right, the trams are on tracks that are in the road as opposed to sticking out of the road.
Scott: for obvious reasons Right.
Scott: I just put both wheels right into that track cuz the track would just go.
Rym: because basically we had that.
Rym: We were biking in a bike lane.
Rym: There was a car like kind of derpy.
Rym: so we had to go, you know go around the car and I think we were both just really focused on left left left and The tram track was had a switch there.
Rym: So it's kind of like at an angle.
Rym: So unless you saw it and purposefully went over it at the at a good angle your tires would go right into it.
Scott: So and it's okay.
Scott: So both wheels are in this indent in the road.
Scott: I should have just been able to go forward and stay in the grid.
Rym: I think what didn't help was that the bike our bike tires were like a Millimeter wider than the train tram track like if we've been in a road bike.
Rym: that would have sucked.
Rym: But you could have just stopped you would have kept rolling inside of the track.
Rym: But because we had these wide mountain tires that stuck your bike basically just did a full stop.
Scott: Yeah, so I basically I went.
Scott: I you know I was basically I was veering to the left because I wanted.
Scott: that's where you know I wanted to be on the road.
Scott: So I just basically fell over on the left like wham right on the ground
Rym: I I hear a commotion and I kind of stopped and I see Scott on the ground and a heap and I'm like, ah great Great, so I pull over and
Scott: I'm like really really I bike.
Scott: how many years when biking in New York, right New York City Manhattan.
Scott: I've been biking here since oh nine it's current it's almost Oh 14 almost every day biking like five ten miles minimum usually more and zero literally zero accidents of any kind including falling over hitting anything or being hit by anything in Manhattan where people are fucking afraid to death to bike.
Scott: and if I get in Melbourne on a weekday Basically sort of in between the city suburb area where there's really nothing going on.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Wham right in the ground immediately.
Rym: So I pull over and I turn back around because you know bike accidents happen.
Rym: I'm thinking like alright, whatever come on Scott.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: I get up.
Rym: So I go over there and he's still laying on the ground by the time I bike back to him because I had to bike back Up the hill.
Rym: so I go back up there and Scott just lay in there.
Rym: So I kind of start waving cars out of the way.
Rym: I'm like Scott.
Rym: Are you okay?
Rym: And I think you hit your head hard enough.
Rym: I don't think you had a concussion but you were doubly.
Rym: you remember much of this initial bit.
Scott: I remember putting the wheels in the thing.
Rym: What's the next thing you remember?
Scott: just Thinking about oh shit.
Scott: Don't let my head hit the ground.
Scott: Yeah, and then Basically sliding on the cement with my gloved hands Yeah, and then my helmet sort of hitting the ground slightly and then kicking the visor up Yeah, and then laying on the ground going Blair and then going really really.
Rym: so I come over there.
Rym: I'm like Scott get up and he's like no He said no, I was way tired.
Scott: I was like Scott.
Rym: Come on like can get out of the road Are you okay, and he was like just let me lay here for a few minutes.
Rym: Yeah, so he's laying there like in a heap like the bikes still kind of on top of him.
Rym: So I kind of pull his bike and I wave cars Yeah, and I'm like I kind of drag him sideways to the edge of the throw like I just got.
Rym: can you get up?
Rym: And he's like, yep, and he stands starts to stand up and then I was mad dizzy.
Rym: He's like, nope, and he slides back down.
Rym: And I'm like, okay.
Rym: I think you're hurt and at this point he's bleeding Profusely from his chin.
Rym: I didn't want to tell him yet I couldn't really.
Scott: I thought I was cuz I'd my chin definitely hit the ground.
Rym: Yep Did you notice you kept like trying to rub your chin on your shirt?
Rym: I was like Scott Just don't rub you just wait because I know you you're.
Scott: I couldn't like feel or see if there was blood But I was like, yeah, I think I cut my chin but didn't really hurt.
Rym: Yeah, I figured because I know you and you can watch easy the killer and you're fine, but real blood Blood is fine.
Scott: It's not like I was looking at an open wound.
Rym: I was looking at an open wound.
Rym: It was it was toys that it was.
Rym: it wasn't really a cut.
Rym: It was a gash great like four millimeters long but like two millimeters wide and the flesh was kind of like Dirt like hanging out.
Rym: I'm great.
Rym: Yeah, so I Get you up and you get way dizzy and you're like.
Rym: and that's when you started saying really really really So I walk you over to this.
Scott: really I came all the way here and I was gonna bike around the whatever.
Rym: and yeah Yep, and I was like, are you okay?
Rym: Like you just dazed.
Rym: I figured he was just dazed at this point and he seemed fine.
Rym: other than that He was dazed.
Rym: so maybe you know minor head injury, whatever and the cut maybe some stitches no big deal.
Rym: So I'd lean you against this fence and I turn around and then you drop your water bottle Just like it falls out of your hand and you start sliding down the fence and then you're sitting down.
Rym: So I was like Scott think I need to call triple zero which we remembered to look up what that was.
Scott: When we got there and I got the SIM cards, I was like, what's the emergency number for this fucking country?
Scott: He's like three zeros a pair.
Scott: open up to call an operator because it's Apparently most phones.
Rym: if you have a SIM card and you down 911, it'll route it to triple zero.
Rym: interesting Yeah, so I call the ambulance and they were one they.
Rym: I had to pick what kind of emergency It was with this little menu and then I got to someone immediately.
Rym: They were super friendly.
Rym: They were super polite.
Rym: They were the nicest I have ever Had a 911 or triple-zero operator ever be in my life because I've called 911 a bunch of times over the years in New York for various things and The person on the other end is usually super surly.
Scott: Yeah, they're like, all right, what's the emergency?
Scott: Okay, really?
Scott: Tell me your address.
Scott: Where are you?
Rym: Is anyone dead or are they just bleeding?
Scott: Is this really an emergency?
Rym: how agitated is that homeless man who keeps attacking people.
Rym: Do you really need a cop to come or will he just tire himself out?
Rym: But no, they were like super polite.
Rym: so they're like all right, look we're gonna send someone and they asked me all these good questions and Scott's just kind of sitting there kind of dazed.
Rym: and Then an ambulance comes and I go wave it.
Scott: Well, we hear some sirens and I'm like really you don't need sirens for a guy who fell off a bike and it's Conscious and sitting here.
Scott: It's not necessary.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So I waved the guy down and he pulls over slows down.
Rym: He's like sorry mate had a cardiac arrest.
Rym: Someone else will be along for you shortly.
Rym: and then he drives off again and it's like wow Well that made sense that was polite.
Scott: You never see her in the ambulance in the u.s.
Scott: It's not gonna pull over and talk to someone who's waving at them.
Rym: They had three EMTs and they immediately are hilarious.
Scott: They look at Scott and they're like, oh, that's the second ambulance that actually showed up without Sirens.
Scott: Yes,
Rym: the main the main woman who was kind of the leader of the group I guess comes over to me and she asked me all these questions while the other two were poking and prodding and Scott and checking his neck to Make sure nothing was
Scott: crazy my neck so many times.
Scott: It's like seriously you already checked that neck.
Rym: Well, they have to be.
Rym: they asked me a bunch of times.
Rym: Remember when I dragged you out of the street?
Rym: remember when I kicked your leg a bunch of times.
Rym: I was making sure that you didn't have any like obvious neck or Back injuries and you just had your normal injuries pretty unlikely.
Rym: Yeah, I want to make sure cuz I before I didn't want to Severely jostle your Jimmy's until I was sure that there was no danger of further Jimmy jostling.
Rym: So once they determined that he was not dying they were like, so yeah, we'll take him to the hospital.
Rym: We can take his bike too.
Rym: If you want to keep going on your trip They were totally like yeah, you should just keep biking We'll deal with this.
Rym: and they took my phone and they're like we got to take some pictures of him.
Rym: So you can make fun of him later.
Rym: and I was like no And she takes the phone and takes all these pictures of him in the ambulance.
Rym: She actually took his bike and just put it in the ambulance and they were like, yeah well, uh, you can come collect him later and then they drove off and I just kept biking and I spent the rest of the day biking all the way up and down the coast along the beaches and saw a crazy jellyfish and I saw a Luna Park, which is basically the Coney Island of Australia.
Scott: I'm great.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't see any of that shit.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So what did you see?
Scott: I saw an Australian Hospital.
Rym: How was that?
Rym: I think they took it was the the Alfred.
Scott: Yep So I'm sure you know, I don't want to say it's the best hospital ever But basically I will say it's more likely US hospitals are shit.
Scott: I mean we knew that already right but to the degree to which they are shit is now very clear.
Rym: Yeah, let's go back in time.
Rym: Rym cuts the front of his fucking pinky off.
Rym: Like I cut it off It's dangling by a thread.
Rym: No, I can see nerves.
Rym: It is pulsing blood.
Rym: I hit my bone with the knife.
Rym: I go to a hospital and after four hours of no one helping me I walked out without treatments and got stitches from a clinic.
Rym: then actually I didn't get stitches because it was too late.
Rym: I got superglue and iodine from a clinic the next day Mm-hmm, and in fact had I gotten stitches they probably I probably wouldn't have lost all the sensation in the tip of my finger.
Rym: But now American Hospital didn't want one fucking second to work with me, right?
Scott: So they take me in the hospital and Immediately, they're making me fill out the forms.
Scott: and you know as soon as I hand in forms They come and talk to me right away and it's like there was busy.
Scott: No waiting.
Scott: I waited Effectively almost zero not exactly zero but almost zero.
Scott: right like as soon as I was done They're like, all right Scott come this way.
Scott: I'm like, all right, and then like in a minute someone's checking me out and then You know, he's talking to me ask me questions check on my neck and again Stitching me up right?
Scott: It's like there's no waiting here.
Scott: I just immediately emergency room and then it's like, okay We're gonna x-ray your arm.
Scott: you fucked up.
Scott: follow the black lines of the x-ray room.
Scott: So I follow the black line on the floor and there's an x-ray room.
Scott: I just walk in they x-ray me immediately I walk back then I waited maybe 10 15 minutes and then they looked at the x-rays and then you know, it's like it took basically no waiting.
Scott: I was maybe at the hospital for a total of three to four hours and then as soon as I was done and walking out It was coincidentally good timing Rym was there getting the bike at the same time.
Rym: Yeah, basically I biked around all day and because Google latitude still worked I actually have a nice map of everywhere I buy.
Scott: but I hope you know I'm pretty sure in all the other good modern socialized medicine countries like, you know, maybe Canada UK Japan probably that hospitals are probably equally as good as that an emergency room situation.
Scott: I was actually on the fast track, which I think means yeah, we know what's wrong with you.
Scott: It's probably really simple.
Scott: We're just gonna treat you and send you on your way, but BAM and that's the fast track, right?
Scott: Which is me which and it was indeed a fast track.
Scott: There's no such thing as a fucking fast track in the US.
Rym: Yeah, there's the slow track and the slower track.
Scott: I think part of the reason for the The good emergency room speeds was that you know, since they have socialized medicine poor people went to the regular doctor For their regular stuff.
Scott: Oh, we were only there for actual emergencies.
Rym: Wait a minute Are you implying that if we had universal health care that we would solve a lot of our basic infrastructural problems with health care.
Scott: All I'm saying is Australian Hospital good US Hospital not good.
Scott: Yep It's all I'm saying.
Rym: and you know, you might say oh, well our hospitals are good.
Scott: If you're rich, you know, it was really not so much going to hospital never a good thing.
Scott: Seriously get a good tourist experience out of it that time and I cut my finger off.
Rym: I had Ridiculous rich person insurance and tons of money and still could not get good treatment.
Scott: You went to poor people Newburgh Hospital.
Rym: I went to.
Rym: yeah, I would have had to want like hire a helicopter to go to the rich hospital.
Scott: Hey, I wonder where the rich people like Garrison go if they have a problem.
Rym: I know of a few fancy hospitals in New York like New York City that you can go to.
Rym: Yeah, but they're not quick emergency dream.
Scott: Well, you know Mike my my mom's cousin the crazy Orthodox Anesthesiologist, right?
Scott: I think he was working at was a Columbia maybe.
Rym: so I'm a reform anesthesiologist.
Scott: His dad had my great-uncle had cancer Basically, he got him into like the rich people floor and I got to go.
Scott: I was visiting and there's basically a rich people floor in the hospital, which is basically like a Tiny Mandarin hotel that takes up a whole floor and each room is sort of a hospital room, right?
Scott: But outside the hospital room, it's basically luxury hotel and the food is way better and everything is way better.
Scott: So if you're rich, you can go to that kind of place if you have problem.
Scott: So, yeah All right.
Rym: So other Australia things that aren't hospitals Well, I'll say this so I biked over because down down in Melbourne in the place that Scott wanted to go There was the old racetrack.
Rym: There's not an old racetrack.
Rym: It's old.
Rym: It's because it's not used anymore.
Rym: It's gone.
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: So the the racetrack that was left was basically just a road that doesn't go and use it every year.
Rym: Yeah, and right now it's old because there's nothing going on there.
Rym: There's no Road it's a road course.
Scott: Yes race on regular roads.
Rym: So basically it well, it's a regular road closed circuit.
Rym: It's a regular road that no one would ever use because it doesn't go anywhere.
Scott: Doesn't it go around the lake?
Rym: Uh Yeah, no one would go around that lake.
Rym: Really?
Rym: There's no reason to okay.
Rym: It's literally there's nothing there.
Rym: There's a bunch of bike paths.
Rym: they go around the lake and there's a road around the lake that no one appears to drive on ever Mm-hmm, and then I kept going along the beach.
Rym: And the one thing I realized as after I realized how far I'd gotten biking We could have just fucking biked all the way to Phillip Island.
Scott: It would have taken a while.
Rym: But yeah, I Would have taken that long.
Rym: Maybe a day.
Scott: Yeah half a day and three quarters of a day six to eight hours, maybe.
Rym: Yep It would have been a pretty good ride too, but I got a decent ways down.
Scott: We didn't need better bikes and we would have needed a way to keep the bikes.
Rym: the cool thing about the beaches in Melvin Is that it was winter, right?
Rym: The water was warmer in the ocean there in the winter because I was crazy close to Antarctica to Antarctica that I've been in my whole life.
Rym: That water was warmer to the point that I would almost consider touching it and maybe like surfing in it.
Rym: Then the water and Wildwood in late May or the water in Lake Superior.
Scott: Well ever water in any Great Lake ever.
Rym: Lake Erie is actually really warm.
Scott: when?
Rym: Most of the summer.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It actually is sure.
Scott: It's also the lake you least want to go in.
Rym: why dirtiest it's?
Scott: it's been cleaned up substantially I'm just saying like Ontario telling me name a great lake that is dirtier than Lake Erie.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Okay So I took the bike back to the place cuz the guy who ran the bike rental place Obviously didn't want to stay there that long.
Scott: He had no business.
Rym: He seemed kind of annoyed that we rented bikes cuz it meant you had to stay there all the way until his closing time.
Rym: So I come back, you know a little while later with one bike and I'm like, I'm gonna drop this bike off and I'll come back later with the other bike.
Rym: and he expressed zero interest in what happened to Scott.
Rym: so later I can.
Rym: I took the tram to the hospital and then I took Scott's bike back and I get there and I give him the stuff for that bike and I'm all done.
Rym: and he was like, all right great.
Rym: And then he immediately just locked up the shop and left.
Rym: Mmm never at any point expressed any interest in what happened to you.
Rym: Why it was just me why I brought back both bikes.
Scott: So yeah, a non-curious person.
Rym: Yep, but it was Melvin's really bikable because I biked around the downtown area.
Scott: Yeah Yeah The tram tracks are more dangerous than the tram.
Scott: It's like if the tram hits you.
Scott: yeah, you're dead, but that's very hard to get hit by it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so it turned out.
Rym: your arm was broken.
Scott: It's fractured.
Rym: Yeah, what's up Scott?
Rym: fracture broken?
Rym: Yeah broke bone.
Scott: Well broken is usually only used when it's broken all the way through And fracture is the word you use for a partial braking.
Rym: Yep, so it wasn't broken off.
Scott: No, that would have been very wasn't sticking out.
Scott: That would have been.
Scott: I would have been not.
Rym: you would have been sad if you looked out and there was bony I'm sticking I would have been barfed and passed out.
Rym: Yeah, so I have a bunch of pictures of biking up and down the coast The Scott hasn't seen.
Rym: I guess they'll look kind of the same.
Rym: the beaches are so ridiculously clean No, and so nice and the dunes are so tall.
Rym: I want to be in that area in the wild.
Scott: the beach is pretty clean after the common But it's not clean in the same way.
Scott: non non Australia related thing, right?
Scott: So here my work is NBC.
Scott: It's around the corner.
Scott: Yep, right and a lot of time is basically musicians come there I think for the today show or for other shit and One of those boy bands, I guess the One Direction was gonna be there for something.
Scott: So all these girls have been waiting there since like last night when I biked home from work I saw them waiting now had like these 1d signs and stuff and today when I biked past basically I think they were clearing them out like I guess their shit happened and There was still those fenced in areas where they sit and wait, you know for I guess 24 plus hours to see their whatever boy like.
Rym: we should have done that time.
Rym: We went to the Nintendo store.
Scott: Yeah, basically They littered the fuck out of those little pendant areas And if I was that One Direction I would have been like we're not doing the show for you people who littered all over the Street fuck you, but they're just a boy band.
Scott: They got to do whatever the contract says and they probably even know or care.
Scott: But that's what I would have done if I saw that my fans had lured the fuck out of whatever the way I'll show you the picture.
Scott: I took my guys.
Rym: So if they let the line into our panel at PAX, we're gonna go outside and look if there's litter all along that line.
Rym: We're not running the fucking panel.
Scott: It's never happened ever.
Scott: Yeah, cuz but I know if there was like a panel and the people were just like clearly like, you know Not good people in the audience and they didn't you know, I'd be like, oh fuck you not doing it.
Rym: Yeah, like one of it like one of them has a MOBA shirt.
Scott: I've never had to do this.
Scott: obviously It could theoretically happen, right?
Scott: But yeah, I'll show you they made a disaster of that that little area.
Rym: So the hotel That has the big casino in Melbourne has a thing the crown and the thing is that they have these big columns That have water popping out of them like fountains and every night on the hours they shoot fire out of the top.
Rym: Mm-hmm, that sounds like a really lame thing.
Scott: But but they have a whole bunch of towers and they sort of shoot the fire in a sequence and it's a big fire.
Scott: So it's like doom doom.
Rym: That's the thing.
Rym: It sounds really lame when people describe it, but people kept describing it and kept mentioning it.
Scott: It's not bad.
Scott: So like alright, it's kind of what they do in Vegas.
Rym: who tried to go over there, but it was also fucking cold.
Scott: We were really hungry so we went into the dessert place inside the casino right near the edge Which is actually probably the best dessert place.
Rym: Oh my god those pies.
Scott: They had these pies and cakes in there.
Rym: Like I was like, alright, I'm gonna get your cake pie.
Rym: They had this like you get a slice of pie and some ice cream and whatever.
Rym: but the pie selection was off the hook.
Scott: It was basically we're like looking for a place where you just get like a slice of cake and it's like there's the only place You could find.
Scott: but it was crazy good.
Rym: So we go in there, but then because we got the fancy pie it took too long.
Rym: So we hear the fire thing is starting up outside and we're inside.
Scott: we can barely see it.
Scott: We can see like the reflection of it off the.
Scott: we see some reflection.
Rym: So like whatever.
Rym: Alright, so we're just eating.
Scott: I clearly seemed cool.
Scott: We should check that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But then the fire got bigger and bigger to the point where like outside was lit up like there was a tiny Sun And this was night.
Rym: Yeah, and like you can only you can feel the heat like and we were inside.
Scott: We could feel the heat through the wind.
Rym: We're like, oh, I guess that thing is actually kind of cool.
Scott: Yeah, probably worth seeing because it's only like 10 minutes long.
Rym: so the next night we go back over there.
Scott: I think it's two nights later, but it doesn't matter.
Rym: We went back another night and we got cake and pie early.
Rym: Then we stand there.
Scott: actually I got a croissant filled with chocolate.
Rym: Oh you did what.
Rym: did I get something?
Rym: That was too much food.
Rym: It was like this white shine was just the right amount.
Rym: I got this like white chocolate truffle thing that I couldn't finish because it was just the richest thing I've ever tried to eat my entire life.
Rym: Okay, so we're standing there.
Rym: It was really windy and it starts up and it's like a little putt putt of fire.
Rym: a little putt putt of fire And then it just fucking turns off.
Scott: Yeah, clearly.
Scott: It's somewhat manually controlled.
Scott: Yeah, some guys because it was too windy.
Rym: some guys obviously had a keyboard of.
Rym: make the fire come out.
Rym: Yeah, and he probably sits there watching it on like a closed-circuit TV and decides like I'll make this one go I'll make this one go I'll do a cool thing.
Rym: and Obviously they have one of them that they can attest with to see if it'll work.
Rym: and the mechanism looks pretty simple.
Rym: They just have a pilot light and they just dump gas out onto it.
Scott: The thing just sprays a fuck ton of gas right into the pilot light.
Rym: Yep Apparently when they first built it it roasted a whole bunch of pigeons And now it looks like they have it set up to warn the pigeons before it starts.
Rym: Or the pigeons that were not leery that thing are all dead and the rest of the pigeons notice it.
Rym: a fuck away from it.
Rym: The pigeons have learned, yeah but that whole downtown area at night was kind of It was I don't want to say fake because it wasn't fake.
Rym: It was like people were there doing their normal business But it was the kind of place that could not exist in a city like New York without being filled with homeless people and trash Because it was just.
Rym: there were benches and little secluded areas that were kind of quiet and out of the way
Scott: Like water
Rym: like you could sit on the water Basically out of sight of anyone in the middle of the night Eating your cake or pie or whatever and There wasn't a homeless person living there.
Scott: There were some homeless people's we saw.
Scott: they're mostly seem to be crazies But but the city because of socialism's.
Scott: really those people are just crazies or people who have you know Refused to accept the welfare or whatever.
Rym: There were areas along the waterfront where you could sit Quietly where no one else could see you and the city did not have a problem with this.
Rym: They didn't have like spikes to make sure people don't lay down.
Rym: They didn't have like those areas that are designed almost like panopticons where you can't actually be anywhere private because if people are somewhere private they'll be up to shady shit or at least the city's afraid of that.
Rym: there weren't a lot of cops around and No one really seemed to bother anybody.
Rym: It was just.
Rym: it was weird.
Rym: It was pleasant kind of like.
Rym: Providence has areas like that.
Scott: Yeah, not New York.
Rym: Not New York.
Rym: New York can't have places like that.
Scott: Well, maybe in some outer boroughs.
Rym: So we went to a bunch of museums and we went to the zoo the Melbourne Zoo.
Scott: Yeah So the museums we went to were.
Scott: we went to a lot of free places for example the Parliament House the Parliament of Victoria Which is the state government house, but it used to be, you know worked originally.
Scott: they were before the United into Australia.
Scott: They were just colonies like the same way Connecticut.
Scott: It was a colony of Britain.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Victoria was a colonies.
Scott: It was actually the colonial Parliament originally And you know is the Australian state parliament now And it was crazy royal and shit, which you know, I sort of had been used to by that point after seeing the government house.
Scott: Yep, but yeah way royal like at to the point where they have like gold maces.
Scott: They had to carry around.
Scott: Yeah, we're sitting there conduct business.
Scott: We're saying like air for the fucking queen slash king to sit in.
Rym: we're in the the House of Lord Whatever thing the Opera House of Lords equivalent.
Rym: Yes, because they went into.
Rym: they went into a lot of explanation of parliamentary procedure and I guess cuz I only know sort of like ghetto parliamentary procedure.
Rym: I never think about it in terms of what the British government Not just a parliamentary because yes parliamentary procedure.
Rym: and at one point she's like Yeah So like she's talking about how they renovated everything and the gold.
Rym: and then I'm thinking I look and there's all this gold Everywhere and yeah, it's all real gold.
Scott: They just put gold By the way, all of this stuff that looks like gold paint is actually real gold everywhere.
Rym: Yes, all of it.
Scott: Also all that gold that looks shinier than the other gold.
Scott: That's new gold We repainted when we renovated but the old gold is under that gold.
Rym: Yep, and we're in there with basically a bunch of tourists and They're tourists in these stereotypical sense.
Rym: So every two minutes in the middle of her talk.
Rym: She'd be like, please come back Don't wander off come back here.
Rym: you come back.
Rym: you stop touching that.
Rym: you come here Like don't take the gold like seriously you fucking tourists seriously.
Rym: I hate you all everywhere in the world that you go like literally.
Rym: she'd like get everyone together and like cajole them into all sitting down and then start talking.
Rym: she'd turn her back and half these people would just get up and wander off Into the places that they're not supposed to go because there's business going on back royal business.
Rym: Yeah But it was pretty cool.
Scott: I think I was.
Scott: I really wanted him to sit in the Queen's chair.
Rym: I might have gotten in some trouble.
Rym: I would yeah boot.
Scott: What are they?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Why didn't you sit in the Queen's chair?
Scott: I was.
Scott: I'd already been to the hospital.
Scott: You was your turn to check out the jails, but we went to all these.
Scott: We went to all these sort of like the weird Museum the old Treasury building which is now a museum and we saw where they used to keep the gold.
Scott: Keep the gold somewhere else now, they like gold there, but that had all this stuff about Ned Kelly.
Scott: Oh my god, Kelly, Ned Kelly Kelly's basically the I guess famous criminal of Australia.
Scott: And this dude is a badass war fucking armor and shot people Badass also, he might have been the first weeaboo.
Rym: He cosplayed his armor was based on quote oriental armor that he learned about like samurai armor and He was a fanboy of Asian culture in a general sense and apparently models little gang after it and His last words were something to the effect of one of those.
Rym: oriental is worth more than a hundred of you assholes.
Scott: He was just really into Asian culture, I think it wasn't his gang full of like Chinese people.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I think some Japanese people - maybe I Worry because the a lot of the literature we were reading in the museum was like contemporary news articles.
Rym: So they used the term oriental a lot.
Rym: So it's hard to tell Which type of Asian cultures they were talking.
Scott: Australia so racist which brings us to the Immigration Museum.
Rym: the Immigration Museum was great.
Rym: It was basically let's try.
Scott: Yeah, it was a museum for Australians.
Scott: So it was weird being there is not Australians, but it's basically saying Australians you so racist Stop being racist.
Rym: We're trying hard to not be race.
Scott: We're less racist than we used to be but you're still fucking racist.
Scott: Jesus Christ, look at how racist we used to be.
Scott: Holy fuck.
Rym: Yep, the white Australia policy Luther King jr.
Scott: Here seriously into the modern era.
Scott: so we have this museum instead.
Rym: I think my favorite of the ridiculous racism was why forget the guy's name, but there was one Article in that whole museum and one of these newspapers about an initiative to take all the aborigines and send them to Africa Africa.
Rym: yeah, it really takes a moment to sink in just how fucking stupid that idea is.
Scott: I loved it was a thing there where you.
Scott: it was sort of like papers, please But it was sort of like a you know, just a video, you know kiosk thing.
Scott: I'm like, would you let this person in and it's like, you know ask this person questions.
Scott: It's like little videos of people talking to you and it's like would you let them into the country?
Scott: and it's basically like yeah I would let all these people in because I'm not a racist asshole But basically I'm supposed to be role-playing some jerk from the olden times and it's like of course, I'm a racist jerk.
Scott: I'm not letting this person in.
Scott: Yeah, cuz they're not white and from the UK, you know, they're otherwise perfectly.
Rym: Okay, it's good.
Rym: it reminds me of a lot of the stuff I'd see in museums as a kid like in the mid 90s where the Like even the big Melbourne Museum the main one we went to which is the biggest museum in the southern hemisphere.
Scott: Yeah, so I don't need to go to the southern hemisphere museum.
Rym: They're definitely really pushing the angle of Exposing the bad stuff from the past to remind people that we got to stop doing.
Rym: the museums are mostly about Yeah, but my favorite exhibit actually not.
Rym: our lab had nothing to do with Australia.
Rym: I think we talked about far lab.
Scott: Did we did we?
Rym: maybe far lab was the biggest and best.
Scott: god damn He repeated something from our previous Australia episode.
Scott: We can't remember.
Scott: Yeah shows you how much we listen to GeekNights.
Rym: Far lab we go in.
Rym: we see this stuffed horse.
Rym: It looks fake because it's too big to be a normal horse and it's so like perfect and magnificent.
Rym: It was too big.
Rym: like I know horses I better on horses and I'm like, that's a that's a big model of a horse.
Rym: I get up there.
Rym: Nope taxidermy.
Rym: Nope real horse.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Maybe the fastest racing horse ever.
Scott: Yeah, fuck you secretariat.
Scott: Oh murdered by the mob Like for real reels the mob poison the horse because it was winning before it got a chance to go to the US and try To Kentucky Derby.
Rym: it Oh far lap.
Scott: Yeah, good name to pH AR lap.
Rym: But my favorite exhibit was the treasures from the Taliban.
Scott: Oh, yes Okay, so is it?
Scott: that was the like the temporary exhibit that they really it's a traveling thing.
Scott: No, we weren't allowed to take pictures of it, right?
Scott: but we went in to see.
Scott: that's like that.
Scott: you had to pay extra money to see it because the temporary hot exhibit sort of Like when they have the Tim Burton exhibit at the MoMA is like the temporary thing.
Rym: That's more money like we went to that Silk Road thing that one time.
Scott: So the deal was basically some awesome dudes Rescued all these artifacts from Afghanistan when the Taliban was taking power.
Rym: a bunch of a bunch of the museum staff Bravely took a bunch of these exhibits that would have been destroyed because the Taliban was destroying any Non-islamic artifacts in the museums.
Scott: Yeah, the same guys are like, you know dynamiting giant Buddhas and shit.
Rym: So they took all these artifacts as many of them as they could and they hid them in safes In I believe like under the government house like I forget the whole story.
Rym: they found safe places Yeah, so they hid all these artifacts and once the US and the war liberated Afghanistan from the Taliban they found them.
Rym: they found these things and they're like, oh fuck then they were actually filling in huge gaps in our History of that region.
Scott: now that we get what was Afghanistan like before right?
Scott: Cuz Afghanistan is basically, you know shit.
Scott: It's been a really bad place for a long ass time right decades and decades.
Scott: So knowing anything about it from olden times is like what fucking Alexander the Great type.
Scott: shit.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of Greek artifacts and Greek diffusion in that area.
Scott: It's like who is that?
Scott: You know, we don't know too much.
Scott: Well now we know from these artifacts and there was all kinds of interesting stories within all of that one.
Rym: There was this amazing collapsible crown.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that thing was great.
Rym: that thing you could like take the end the Mongols I've read have some similar type of.
Scott: a lot of this stuff was like yeah Nomad group here and this trading Silk Road group there.
Rym: This is obviously a Greek coin that got here at some point Yeah, and all kinds of like Marco Polo shit going on.
Rym: But there was one bit where they they excavated this tomb and it looked like it was a king of some nomadic tribe And he was buried with a bunch of his wives something like that.
Rym: But the diagram and the artifacts showed that you know, it was all about him, but they buried him in the side of a hill.
Rym: What they didn't realize was that that hill was actually an even more ancient temple that we know.
Rym: fuck all about.
Scott: that'd be like if you buried me in the pyramids in Egypt and then a Long time passed and then people came and said oh this must have been a tomb to Scott.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Scott: Scott is nowhere nearly as old as this fucking pyramid.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: That was just a really interesting exhibit.
Scott: So Look at for if it travels to your country or if you live there that's worth paying to check out.
Rym: Yeah, I'll try to find a link but it was like the treasure.
Rym: lost treasures of the Taliban something something It's it wasn't.
Scott: lost treasures.
Scott: the Taliban lost treasures.
Rym: Afghanistan lost treasures hidden from the Taliban.
Rym: Yeah made a big deal about how it was saved from the Taliban.
Scott: very worth seeing.
Scott: the rest of the museum Kind of worth seeing at least the Australian history for us non Australians.
Rym: But yeah, I like You know when we go to the museum part Both science museums, we don't need to see that.
Scott: Yeah, I don't.
Scott: any part I really wanted to see which is the Aboriginal stuff.
Scott: renovation closed.
Rym: Yep, wah-wah, but like when I go to the museum's here like the Natural History Museum in the art museum, especially the art museum has areas like here's a whole bunch of silverware From different eras.
Rym: Mm-hmm giant racks of it.
Rym: I usually kind of ignore that stuff.
Rym: I love that stuff it depends.
Rym: but Australia they had sort of Artifacts of culture from like the 20s 30s 40s 50s 60s and that was fascinating.
Scott: Well, that's I'm as you go to a modern museum as well as an ancient music exactly But it was.
Rym: it was all a lot like the stuff in the US but cooked slightly.
Scott: So look as you're looking at like that silverware stuff is in the Met which is all old stuff.
Scott: Yeah, if you go to other museums, you'll see more newer stuff.
Scott: Anyway, do we have anything else to cover on our little things?
Scott: We forgot things.
Rym: we forgot.
Rym: Let's see people say no worries a lot.
Rym: I think we covered that up.
Rym: Oh Spiking you.
Rym: we went to the zoo.
Rym: The zoo was actually super well designed pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, I was very impressed with the Melbourne Zoo probably better than the Bronx.
Rym: Ooh, maybe I think maybe I think it might be Because it was built more recently and maybe renovated extensively also because the selection of animals was different.
Rym: But the zoo was just arranged in a really good fashion to get people to go from exhibit to exhibit to exhibit Rather than having sort of like main walking areas.
Rym: And then here's the side path to exhibit a in and out of that exhibit It was more like to go anywhere you walk through exhibits to get to other exhibits.
Rym: So even if you no matter what you do You're gonna pass by a lot of interesting things and I think it was designed To make people see things that they probably would enjoy but wouldn't think to go see.
Rym: Like if you want to go see the Tigers you had to go through a lot of other exhibits to get to the Tigers.
Scott: Those Tigers are mad sad there.
Rym: Well, yeah Zoos are always both fascinating and sad at the same time like yeah brown bear You're probably way more bored here than you would be if you were out in the wilderness, but you know, you're not doing too badly.
Scott: It's not like they're mistreating you.
Scott: But yeah, you're bored and some of the animals are having a good time.
Scott: Butterflies are having a good time.
Rym: We realized something that we thought about off and on.
Rym: but being at the zoo because you know, I've been to a lot of zoos.
Rym: I'm 30 something years old 31 years old.
Rym: Zoos take on a whole different character.
Scott: When you are now also into photography Yeah, the animals are actually sitting still.
Scott: this is way easy.
Rym: I mean when I go to a zoo now It's like I'll go to the place where there's penguins.
Rym: and it's like all right penguins You're cool.
Rym: and two minutes later.
Rym: I walk away now.
Rym: It's all right.
Rym: I'm gonna stand here for a full five minutes trying to get pictures of these penguins with all my different lenses.
Rym: And oh look at that one.
Rym: He's behind a thing.
Rym: I can get this shot.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: That was moving click.
Scott: Yeah, photography is a complementary geekery.
Scott: It is the kind you know, if you try to pick up a new geekery say I don't know being a techno DJ, right?
Scott: Well suddenly that's its own thing.
Scott: That doesn't really partner well with other things as it may be conventions Really, you know, so you can't like do it while you're doing something else you have to dedicate time to it.
Scott: It takes away from other geekeries.
Scott: But if you do photography you basically just combine that with every fucking thing you do.
Scott: Oh video games and photography.
Scott: Yep board games and photography peeping photography conventions photography Just you do it all the same.
Scott: you combine it with everything so it doesn't take up any time Other than editing the photos, which I don't do.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I don't enough.
Rym: I don't do any retouching.
Rym: All I do is I go through Lightroom and I basically like yes all my pictures.
Rym: I do one pass of all right I flag all the shit ones as shit.
Rym: Then I go through the ones that aren't shit and I do some cursory Metadata on all of them.
Rym: like.
Rym: these are all from this thing and these are all from this thing.
Rym: And I go through one more time and I star the ones that are actually good pictures and then you upload them.
Rym: Then I upload almost all of them because whatever Flicker I got to do some uploading soon.
Scott: I haven't uploaded a long time.
Rym: Everything up to the Australia trip.
Rym: I have uploaded.
Scott: I got to check out.
Scott: I got a lot of old stuff.
Scott: That's unuploaded.
Rym: Yeah, I got a bunch of video and stuff that I haven't uploaded but whatever anyway, um we went to all the game stores.
Scott: Yeah, we checked out all the nerds in in Australia the game store.
Rym: People are super chill.
Scott: like we went to The main story went to his games laboratory, which is funny because they were closed during packs They only signs in the window like closed blame packs.
Scott: It was mostly a magic the gathering store, but they also had a board game selection and support game events and Mostly the store was just tables.
Scott: It was the exact opposite of a New York game store, which is mostly Merchandise stacked to the ceiling and no tables.
Scott: this place was like 90% tables with like a super good system of like showing you the tournament Status on the monitor these TVs and you know and very little merchandise for sale except magic cards.
Scott: And the guy was actually giving.
Scott: not only were they trying to sell this dude magic cards when I was there They're actually giving like deck advice and it's like whoa, this is kind of crazy.
Scott: But yeah, I played a netrunner tournament there after Rym left.
Scott: It was a beginner's tournament So I came in third place.
Scott: cuz that's you know, I can only come in third place as well see beginners.
Scott: Yeah And I actually lost to some beginners.
Scott: He was great, you know, whatever.
Scott: but Yeah, it was a it was a good time.
Scott: Lots of nice Australian netrunner players, you know, it was a. you know, that was it.
Scott: Yeah, I have to say that the nerds we ran into were generally all super chill and everyone who's a nerd is busy super Desperate because yep, not enough nerdery like we went to them.
Scott: That was it minotaur which is sort of like the big fancy conflict store the Midtown comics I would say or the Newberry comics of Melbourne and everything there was way expensive.
Scott: and Yeah, everyone there was super desperate willing to pay that much money.
Rym: But at the same time that store in terms of its breadth of geekery Was way more than an equivalent store in the u.s.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: it had about the same kind of stuff as a Forbidden Planet would have.
Rym: yeah forbidden planet.
Rym: But that's kind of an exception.
Rym: go to like.
Rym: look at uh, what is the Newberry comics?
Scott: It's about the same.
Rym: Yeah, Newberry comics does not have the breadth of this place.
Rym: This place didn't?
Scott: they had the The quantity of inventory, but I think I had about the same breath.
Rym: I think I think the breadth is wider because there were a lot of sections for things.
Scott: The anime was definitely heavier because anime is just big there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: There was a pony section like.
Rym: there's an area That was basically all pony stuff.
Rym: There was an area that was basically all Adventure Time stuff.
Rym: There's an area that was all horror movie stuff.
Rym: There was an area that was like trauma you kind of stuff separate from all of that.
Rym: Like it was all nerd stuff together.
Scott: Everything was a zillion dollars.
Rym: Yeah buy anything, but they were Australian dollars which cost.
Rym: they're worth about the same as American dollars.
Scott: So yeah, yeah, and there's nothing I couldn't get because I live in fucking New York City, and I have amazon.com.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't an eBay.
Rym: That's why I didn't buy many souvenirs.
Rym: I bought that cute little Melbourne Zoo Bowl that has the cute little elephant on it, but my mom magnet cuz she likes refrigerated magnets.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it's her thing.
Scott: whatever all right.
Rym: I think we've talked enough about Austria.
Scott: I'm sure there are other things we could mention But the show is long.
Rym: those anecdotes will come up bit by bit as thing.
Scott: any other anecdotes I mean we went to a jazz club, whatever you know not so significant or interesting.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there are things we do in New York anyway like in New York.
Rym: We'll go to Williamsburg and go see weird concert somewhere in Melbourne.
Rym: we went to Fitzroy which is hipster town the Williamsburg of Melbourne.
Rym: Yes, everyone's riding fixies there like it.
Scott: if you dropped someone from Williams the French restaurant I wouldn't give us a seat even though it was mostly empty.
Rym: Yeah, either that a big reservation, or they thought we were poor went to the Afghanistan a restaurant.
Rym: pretty good, Afghanistan e yep I would just say Afghani, maybe it went along with our Afghan exhibit.
Rym: But yeah Fitzroy all that a lot of the things we did we're really cool and all but there's nothing Particular to say because they're the same things we do in New York.
Scott: just crook slightly, so we tourists did the end.
Rym: yeah Australia would go back, but expensive Australia will go back if For work or our Kickstarter succeed.
Scott: both of those are.
Scott: if someone pays for yes, that's not me Advertise going to other places not because Australia is bad But because I haven't been to other places and I'd rather go to a new place.
Rym: So here's the thing.
Rym: this is kind of a meta and will end the show because you know with packs next week I don't think we're gonna do a lot of shows again.
Rym: No if I go back to Australia I don't have a lot of interest in visiting cities again.
Scott: I definitely want to go to Outback because the coral reef.
Rym: I travel a lot for work and the more you visit big cities They're all the same.
Rym: there are big differences But not enough to be worth traveling.
Scott: I want to see old shit.
Rym: Yeah, well There's not a lot of old stuff in Australia.
Scott: That's I got is the only things to see in Australia are natural shit.
Rym: if I go back to Australia for Reaps and animals in the Outback after packs.
Rym: I'm gonna go to Wilson's fucking promontory.
Scott: I was already there.
Rym: No you weren't.
Scott: Oh right that thing you.
Rym: yeah that thing That was our.
Scott: we went to will whatever.
Scott: I don't know well.
Rym: Will am I yeah?
Rym: Am I right now, and I'm gonna go to Tasmania hmm and New Zealand.
Scott: I'm gonna go to the coral reef because fishes warm water.
Rym: But I have no desire to visit Canberra And I actually don't really want to bother going.
Scott: no one wants to visit Canberra.
Scott: rather than going to Sydney I go to Sydney like as a stop and go to an opera and then leave yeah something like that.
Rym: I would not stay in Sydney for that a couple days.
Rym: Yeah But what I really want to do is arrange ahead of time and do like a week-long Trek through the Outback.
Scott: I don't know if I gonna go there for a week.
Rym: Ah if I go back With Kickstarter, I'm gonna spend the same amount of money.
Rym: I spent going on my own on extra fine.
Scott: I'm going to the I'm going to the Outback for like maybe a day just to see up.
Scott: I seen the Outback and then I'm gonna lay on the beach near the coral reef and also go in the coral reef for like A week, I don't want to do too much laying on beach because I can do that in South America much more easily.
Scott: That Beach does not have a coral reef.
Rym: There's some beaches down there right.
Scott: imagine if you're like you're in wildwood land on the beach.
Scott: Ah only it's warmer and nicer.
Scott: ah and the people are more beautiful.
Scott: ah and when you look at the water It's blue and this beautiful multicolored fishes and not this dark green nasty water.
Rym: Scott I can go to Turks and Caicos and have that.
Scott: Turks and Caicos is like the super richest people on earth at it.
Scott: You can't go there.
Rym: Yeah, it's pretty.
Rym: you can go there as tourists pretty cheaply.
Scott: It's a lot of monies cheaper than Australia.
Scott: Well, maybe because it's physically closer I'll go to the Bahamas.
Scott: Yeah, Bahamas have other problems.
Rym: Yeah, all these places have problems.
Rym: Yeah I'm just saying I'm not that interested in beach time.
Scott: I'm super interested in all coral reefs I want to like.
Rym: I want to hike out to fucking iris rock and then wait and do crazy stuff out there And I want to see the iris rock, but only I want to see the coral reef.
Rym: I want to go to New Zealand and go skiing there.
Scott: You know any other good coral reefs to check out?
Scott: The Great Barrier Reef, I guess that's the one.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: Any other ones not that I can think of that are bigger and better well-known than the Great Barrier Reef.
Rym: Well, then maybe I should go check that one out, but you're not gonna go scuba diving.
Rym: So what's the fucking point?
Scott: Why wouldn't I?
Rym: I thought you were the one who was like a scuba?
Rym: You just want to snorkel.
Scott: snorkeling is good, too.
Rym: Yeah, if you're gonna go to the Great Barrier Reef, you got a scuba dive.
Rym: I mean, it's not that deep.
Scott: You can probably just see it from the edge.
Rym: Yeah, you can see more if you scuba dive.
Rym: maybe anyway This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.