Rym: It's Tuesday, May 14th, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: passwords and cheat codes.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So apparently I've been summoned by the queen.
Rym: I guess the queens.
Rym: I guess we have multiple queens I get to.
Rym: finally after all these years I'm called up yet again to be kicked out of jury duty.
Scott: well Didn't we already have a whole episode about jury duty?
Rym: we did and you know what.
Rym: I've never actually been selected And New York is so much different and fucked up than the rest of the country in this stuff.
Rym: basically they send you a thing That's like hey You're gonna have jury duty at some point in the next I don't know decade.
Rym: So fill out this form.
Scott: you fill out the form.
Scott: that means you're gonna have it real soon.
Rym: No, so I filled out the form two years ago.
Scott: Oh, okay?
Scott: I know that my form like a week before yeah, so literally that.
Rym: so that's that's the main form.
Rym: so then Remember packs PAX East.
Rym: we only went there and did our stuff two days before PAX East.
Rym: in the mail I get a summons to start calling in the Friday of packs.
Rym: So I was like nope and I deferred that shit.
Rym: Now the cool thing is you get to pick another day to defer.
Rym: so I deferred.
Rym: I was like anytime after May 31st.
Rym: so Yesterday I got a notice saying that on May 31st.
Rym: I gotta do it.
Scott: there you go.
Rym: So basically the weekend after anime Boston, so that's not a lot of notice.
Rym: And I like.
Rym: how on the thing it says I've already deferred it once in big letters.
Rym: So if I go try to defer it again people will give me a hard time.
Rym: probably yeah, probably.
Rym: So we'll see how this goes.
Scott: I'm college.
Scott: You're just calling in you don't actually to go.
Rym: yeah I'd rather I don't know.
Rym: I called into a federal court like every day for a week And they said nope I would like to go in because I want to do my civic duty.
Rym: And if it's some like marijuana thing I'd love to just let the guy off.
Scott: You're not gonna get into the courtroom you're not gonna pass the voir dire.
Scott: If you even get to the voir dire I've never even gotten that far.
Rym: These people are gonna take one look at me like they always do when I was called up in the past and other places And be like get this guy the fuck out.
Scott: You should just make a jpeg.
Scott: That's like jury duty picture a Rym.
Rym: nope I don't always serve on juries, but when I do I got my nullification ready.
Rym: sure the problem is I know if I ever get on a jury It's not gonna be like some low-level drug dealer who got busted for pot.
Scott: Who knows something.
Rym: it's never gonna be something where I'm gonna want to know they don't have trials for stuff.
Scott: That's not for serious these days.
Scott: It's all plea bargains and shit.
Scott: so then the only time there's a trial is if it's somewhat of a big deal ish Maybe I'll be lucky in it.
Rym: I'll get on like some defense distributed like federal trial.
Rym: That'd be awesome.
Scott: It's not a federal court is it?
Rym: Let's see what I got called up for.
Rym: I got called up for.
Rym: I might get called to any number of courts depending on what they say when I call this number.
Scott: Oh, yeah I had two separate ones.
Scott: one was for Queens Court and one was for federal court in Long Island And it said specifically there were two different ones.
Scott: So what does it have a name of a court on it, or does it say New York State or what?
Rym: It doesn't say yet.
Rym: I have to call in to find out.
Scott: That's interesting.
Rym: I'm a juror for all courts state or federal in Queens County.
Rym: very interesting, so I'm just a standby juror for everything.
Scott: Okay, Oh standby, so it's not even selected.
Rym: It means I call in yeah, yeah, all right, so I'm confident I will not serve on a jury anyway, and in my entire life It can happen.
Rym: So yeah doing pretty good at hockey You know not doing pretty good at hockey game seven in the first round what we're not Rangers ago.
Rym: Nowhere.
Scott: Hey, we just won and it was fine.
Rym: You and I did not win.
Scott: You said we includes you.
Rym: you know what we did.
Rym: win because the Red Wings are also moving on after their six or seven games.
Rym: The thing is the Rangers and the Red Wings are seated about the same meaning last.
Rym: So the only chance they will play each other is if both of them make it to the Stanley.
Scott: Oh, well the only reason for that is not because we're seated last It's because we're in the east and you're in the West.
Rym: it's not just that it's also because there's no way we can ever Both seated last because within our divisions we didn't do so.
Scott: well So happens, but in the playoffs any team can happen.
Scott: anything is possible.
Scott: You know the first the seat.
Scott: top-seated teams haven't won the Stanley Cup in a long-ass time.
Rym: I think that's because of the old divisions actually and because of the old conferences.
Scott: We got new divisions next year.
Rym: Yeah, this is I'm really curious what's gonna happen because the Red Wings have always been a little bit of RIT for a long time.
Rym: I mean they basically were not playing against the best teams So they'd win every year and you know even if they didn't.
Rym: actually you know they get swept in the first round of the Stanley Cup, but yet they'd make it there with the top seed.
Rym: Yeah, anywho I?
Rym: Kind of want to go to a Rangers game.
Scott: Can you afford it?
Rym: Well?
Scott: Yeah, can you get a ticket actually?
Rym: Yeah, you can buy tickets from the Rangers website.
Rym: They've got sets of two for about 200 bucks a ticket in the outer ring.
Scott: You can't see you better.
Scott: I'm watching on TV.
Rym: They have.
Scott: have you been to the garden.
Rym: I've never been to the garden.
Scott: Well, let me tell you the outer ring.
Scott: You're basically watching on TVs up there.
Rym: No.
Rym: It's interesting.
Rym: in the old days I would go to hockey games because you couldn't watch hockey on TV.
Rym: You couldn't tell what was happening And then they added all those graphics to make it slightly better like they'd highlight the puck so you could kind of see it.
Rym: but now with HD Unless I'm sitting in the front row my TV is actually way better.
Scott: I'm on StubHub for Let's see this game is on Tuesday, May 21st.
Rym: There's a game on the 25th.
Rym: I think that I saw tickets for.
Scott: Okay, anyway.
Scott: This is for a game a week from today.
Scott: Alright, let's see actual worthwhile seats.
Scott: Okay, so sitting next to the glass or in the section next to the glass guess how much per ticket per ticket is.
Scott: it is slightly off-center ice.
Rym: I'm gonna say 480 a ticket 1150 a ticket.
Rym: Wow, that's About double what I thought.
Rym: okay.
Scott: We're gonna go one section behind that.
Scott: so level in the middle area recalibrating farther away from the glass one section worth.
Rym: all right one section worth, but more close.
Rym: I'm gonna say 680.
Scott: yeah 650 all right.
Scott: I almost said 650 okay, so now all right, so now we're going up.
Scott: Right we're in the mezzanine, but we're in like the front The mezzanine by the front.
Scott: the level gallery was for sale.
Rym: legit not StubHub for 250 mm-hmm.
Rym: that's what I saw.
Scott: so the pet wall which was that like Center or not quite Center.
Scott: yeah I'm looking in the more Center ice area.
Rym: Yeah for 170 you can sit in the worst possible seats, okay?
Scott: Let's see worst possible ticket on StubHub that I can find is in the West balcony West balcony OBS It's they're all 250 up there.
Rym: Wow Okay, yeah, you can get worse tickets just by buying them because they're I guess for whatever reason they're available.
Scott: Yeah, these StubHubs are all people with season tickets reselling them.
Scott: the garden is ridiculously expensive.
Scott: to go there I'd pay.
Scott: the thing is if it's like Stanley Cup finals like the cup could appear I'd probably pay whatever ridiculous.
Scott: Yeah, I used to see games like that hasn't happened since 1994 when I didn't have any money I couldn't go to New York City really just on my own.
Rym: No, that was the error when the Red Wings got so close so close every time it didn't quite make it.
Scott: It was the one year.
Scott: We made it.
Rym: I remember it was.
Rym: was it 95?
Rym: I think it was the year before the Red Wings won the Stanley Cup And I was watching the game with my brother.
Rym: my parents had just bought a huge TV non widescreen CRT.
Scott: they didn't exist.
Scott: I know this TV was Gigantic.
Scott: Well, they were tiger LCD.
Rym: not we bought it specifically for hockey watching and nothing else.
Rym: Like I remember I was mad at my mom because I wanted a computer instead Mmm, but the computer was still like ten times the cost of that TV.
Rym: but anyway And my brother was upstairs watching the game on his own TV and Fedorov scored on our own goal Mm-hmm, like it was an accident.
Rym: It got him a hat trick And when he and we were already down by one I think I don't remember the details But when Fedorov scored on our own goal, I hear my little brother go ah, and then I just hear things breaking Speaking of own goals.
Scott: right today was actually at work.
Scott: I watched the natural selection to European finals of evil team versus silly team.
Rym: Wait a minute can own go cuz.
Rym: in old NS the own goal was anytime you use babblers anywhere near your fucking high.
Scott: But evil team won again.
Scott: But there was a funny moment.
Scott: that were own goal reminded me of where basically the funny team bit, you know destroyed the IP made a little base rush and They killed the commander of the evil team.
Scott: So someone who wasn't the commander the evil team got in the chair to build an IP Yeah, accidentally dropped a few armories that they then had to destroy.
Rym: So there you go Not just leave him sitting there hanging out.
Scott: And yeah, you don't need three armories in the base.
Rym: You can have a strategy around that.
Scott: What is the strategy?
Rym: I mean, I remember my my old NS.
Scott: all OC strategy OCs don't really exist like that anymore.
Rym: I know thing is back in the day before they added the anti lameness filter and There was no limit on what you could put anywhere.
Rym: I remember we would make walls of OCs for high and they would just be behind them would be a wall.
Scott: Yeah, but they are in those days.
Scott: You had a freaking HMGs to cut them down.
Scott: There's no HMG anymore.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, anyway, and this is fun.
Rym: Yeah, so you got any news?
Scott: Yeah, so apparently People on the forum are telling me that there was an Adventure Time video game for the 3ds MDS called Adventure Time Colon.
Scott: hey Ice King exclamation.
Scott: Why'd you steal our garbage?
Scott: And apparently it's a Zelda 2 game.
Scott: I remember when I got it very very short apparently, but very good but short.
Rym: I remember when that came out.
Rym: all of our friends who were in the know or in the game Were going crazy about it, right?
Scott: I don't think it's worth any, you know the full price of a 3ds game.
Scott: But anyway, they're coming out with a new Adventure Time game called Adventure Time colon.
Scott: explore the dungeon because I don't know.
Scott: Exclamation point and I don't know is in all caps Much like the last game.
Scott: it'll be developed by the same people and Have oversight by P Ward.
Scott: So I'm assuming this is pretty much gonna be like Pokemon Adventure Time mystery dungeon, which is a roguelike basically and it says players striving to save the candy kingdom by exploring the mysterious secret royal dungeon deep beneath the land of And you can play as like freaking every character.
Rym: so I'm digging that.
Rym: yeah, I Don't but I remember our friends all going crazy about it and the soundtrack and everything.
Rym: We were not adventure time people.
Rym: It's that way.
Scott: Yeah, the difference is is that the last Adventure Time game was DS 3ds.
Scott: This one is Wii U 3ds ps3 Xbox and PC PC.
Scott: Is it?
Rym: I did not know.
Scott: there you go.
Scott: So new game is actually gonna be on all the platforms with its roguelike ness.
Rym: You know, it's funny.
Rym: You mentioned that because I got a sort of personal news.
Scott: I'm guessing it's for hook likeness.
Scott: It's a dungeon.
Scott: Come on a couple days ago.
Rym: I got an email the email Microsoft.
Rym: Your Xbox live gold is going to expire and auto renew.
Scott: I thought yours was already aspired.
Rym: so I guess I bought a year ahead way back.
Scott: I still have mine still going but it's not.
Rym: I bought a gift certificate that was discounted on Amazon.
Rym: that was cheaper than a year and I used that to get my year Way back, so I forgot about it.
Rym: My Xbox hasn't been turned on in like five months.
Scott: I used mine for Netflix only because the surround sound works As opposed to the PC where it also works, but not quite so Microsoft.
Rym: Thanks for sending me that email.
Rym: It reminded me to go shut off the auto renew Because Xbox is dead to me.
Rym: It exists solely to play Street Fighter 4 and Pac-man Street Fighter.
Scott: you can get on the PC.
Scott: I know but I bought it already But I didn't even upgrade it to the arcade version.
Rym: I'm not gonna read.
Rym: I got the arcade one Yeah, so I'm not gonna re buy it.
Rym: But yeah, my basically I. It's funny because it wasn't that long ago We said PC gaming was dead and it was back then.
Rym: don't don't think that I'm gonna retract my statement that it was dead at That time.
Scott: the seas of change are change.
Scott: Oh, it's the winds of change.
Scott: Yeah our change, but it is It's PC gaming season and I basically has been for years, but it wasn't when we started GeekNights Which shows you just how fucking old GeekNights.
Rym: It's only Nintendo games that aren't really PC.
Rym: And I think the answer is I'm either gonna play those games that exist on DS's eventually, I'll buy a 3ds light 2 But otherwise all PC.
Rym: So if a game only comes out in Xbox, I'm just gonna assume that'll eventually be on the PC.
Rym: I mean mark the ninja.
Rym: I've been playing on my HD PC just fine.
Scott: Thankfully, there is not even one Wii U game yet that needs to be played.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Nothing.
Scott: Nothing critical zero Wii U games.
Rym: So, uh, yeah I let that expire and it was funny because it was kind of convoluted the process.
Scott: to turn it off You log in xbox.com you go to your setting account settings and you turn off auto-renew with a checkbox.
Rym: Not quite.
Rym: So first I had to go into like change manage my subscriptions and there were two options.
Rym: What option was like Change auto-renew settings, but under there was not an option to turn it off.
Rym: There were two options and then there's a button that said don't see what you're looking for.
Rym: So I clicked on that and I dug around and eventually I got to the page.
Rym: Let me turn it off and actually the account I set up can log into two Different Microsoft websites that have slightly different options.
Scott: I ran in a lot of weird.
Scott: you think about it, right?
Scott: All this Xbox stuff is really helping people out who don't have computers attached to their TV.
Scott: It is well There's a and all this stuff only really seems pointless to us because we fucking attach computers to our TV and it's it's really.
Scott: all It is is an HDMI port.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: Well when I shut it down it popped up a thing and it's like are you sure you're gonna lose access to?
Rym: and it was Multiplayer online gaming Netflix on your TV.
Scott: and I'm like, yeah Ten other things to get Netflix on my TV kinda.
Rym: I had a Roku when they first came out.
Scott: apparently the Roku now can do a million things including video games.
Scott: Yeah, it's crazy but none of them do as much as a Computer.
Rym: Well, it's good and bad because it just shows that.
Rym: Don't realize they can plug a computer into the TV.
Scott: Make computers just buy, you know parts in bulk like just normal PC parts.
Scott: put together computers like we do.
Scott: You know like Dell did when Dell started, you know, Michael Dell in his dorm or whatever putting computers together selling them HDMI ports and we'll be like these are specifically computers for plugging into your TV.
Rym: Well, we pre set them up with drivers with the right interface with steam and everything already installed.
Rym: Yeah, exactly To sell them as appliances Don't be like.
Scott: hey These are you know, the like ultimate set-top box does everything every other box does for free no monthly fee.
Scott: Just buy the box set forever.
Rym: Well, you know, this is a common trend because do you know how many times especially now go looking at convention stuff?
Rym: I see people who do panels or talk about things like Halo the Revolutionary like multiplayer game.
Scott: if you never it's like.
Scott: yeah, you never get quick before.
Rym: I mean if you have you've never had a computer before played games on them.
Scott: It's a lot of people.
Scott: they just they're in a world and they don't see the whole picture.
Scott: They only see their part of the picture.
Rym: well remember to this day services like Hulu give you different content on a phone as opposed to a Computer as opposed to a set-top box because they think that those three are actually distinct use cases and distinct devices.
Scott: Anyway, we've gone over that a thousand times.
Rym: We have so I have a much more interesting news.
Rym: Okay, and this has been around but a lot of people weren't talking about it until there was the sort of financial disclosure And then suddenly there were a bunch of articles in mainstream things about it, but basically World of Warcraft lost 1.3 million subscribers.
Scott: everyone knows World of Warcraft is losing players.
Rym: Yeah But no one.
Rym: most people did not have the numbers because they weren't public and to a lot of it was speculation Division Bob Blizzard.
Scott: those numbers have to sort of be public because that's the where they get most of their money from.
Rym: They lost 1.3 million users.
Rym: out of how many out of like 8 million?
Rym: it says here 8 points That's how many you know.
Rym: 8.3 million is all that's left which includes games and everything.
Scott: So they had about 10 million and now they're down to 8.3.
Scott: Yeah, so there's 1.3 million.
Rym: It's still a lot of players just in the first quarter of this year.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: So that's just January February March.
Rym: Okay, it's already late May.
Rym: hmm, so People are talking a lot about this and it looks like even as you know in 2012 they had a big drop in subscribers, but not nearly as much as now.
Rym: I Think what's going on here is not what a lot of people are saying so I'm gonna posit something to you Scott.
Rym: I want to see if you think this is an interesting theory.
Rym: I think the primary reason for this is a combination of Cellphone browser free-to-play games.
Rym: Yeah, but that's not the primary thing.
Rym: It's that coupled with MOBAs.
Rym: So here's why I think that There are.
Rym: there are two classes of people I guess three classes of people who play World of Warcraft.
Scott: now One MOBAs, I mean MOBA is the biggest game right now.
Scott: League of Legends Doesn't mean the people who were playing World of Warcraft.
Rym: There's a very specific reason why there's three types of people who play.
Rym: Wow People who haven't ever played an MMO before and they hear about them and that's the one they probably will find and play.
Rym: It's like EverQuest used to be.
Rym: so they're just like the MMO noobs and they're gonna be.
Rym: you know, people get addicted.
Rym: I got addicted to MMOs the first time I saw an MMO the realm.
Rym: I I sat killing guys for one experience point.
Scott: I played muds in high school.
Rym: So the second class of people are depressed middle-aged housewives and all that assorted.
Rym: You know type of person the people who play for the grind and they socialize but they're not really hardcore about the game But they keep playing it and keep grinding and it consumes a lot of their free time.
Rym: Maybe they RP in there with their other friends.
Rym: The third group of people who continue to play Wow are the people who are into the raid clan guild culture.
Rym: They were the ones where they leveled leveling up and going through the story They can give one fuck about.
Rym: they had their characters at the right level to then meet with their guild and do raids and that Experience of here is my team with our voice chat.
Rym: We're gonna go raid Leroy Jenkins style.
Rym: That was a whole class of World of Warcraft players where the raids were their thing and everything else about the game was just fluff And and basically ready rooms.
Rym: Those people are the people who are leaving Wow to play MOBAs because MOBAs give them that same feeling Without the World of Warcraft stuff all around it and they fee.
Rym: it's much more competitive For them.
Rym: it rewards their skill and their coordination as a clan or a team much more red.
Scott: I think you're thinking too hard about this.
Scott: You know why people aren't playing Wow, cuz it's just fucking stale It's day.
Scott: You know, that's just all there is to it, right?
Scott: No game No matter how much you keep updating it right no matter how much new stuff you keep adding to it Eventually any individual person right is like I've played this enough even if you you know Pretty much maxed it out for as long as you can get someone to stay.
Rym: But so here's my counterpoint to that.
Rym: This is still just a theory.
Rym: I got to do some more research.
Rym: I want to ask a lot of people who have quit.
Scott: I'm sure there are people who have stopped playing Wow and now our League of Legends players.
Scott: That doesn't mean that like League of Legends was like.
Scott: if League of Legends didn't exist if MOBAs didn't take off you think people Would still be playing Wow.
Scott: No, actually, yes I know I think that Wow would have lost these players no matter what because there's also other games that would have taken them Away.
Scott: what game pretty much whatever game existed at this time would be?
Rym: no I don't think so.
Scott: No bigger.
Scott: Look Wow is stale.
Scott: people are leaving it because it is just old and they're not you know Into it anymore.
Scott: They're gonna go to whatever game is out there to go to.
Scott: they go to tf2 some of them go to the other MMOs that are free to play.
Rym: So Scott I don't think there was any significant shift of people who quit playing Wow in order to play tf2.
Rym: But I think there was a significant shift of people who quit Wow specifically to play League of Legends.
Scott: No, I think people just quit Wow and These other games happen to be coming up at the same time as Wow is going down And people are leaving Wow.
Scott: before the MOBAs went up.
Rym: They were but not at this rate.
Rym: There's been a rapid increase in the rate of decrease Yeah, just recently and part of my hypothesis is that if you look at the history of MMOs It's a correlation.
Scott: There's no causation.
Scott: People aren't saying fuck Wow because League of Legends exists.
Rym: I think they are.
Scott: What evidence do you have for that besides the correlation?
Scott: so that happens to be the hot game now and Wow is less hot.
Scott: So
Rym: in the past when people left an MMO as opposed to just keeping their account kind of active It's because they went to another MMO and like I said There's different classes of players the people who are all guilty and would really only do the raids and that's all they cared about that like pseudo competitive circuit.
Rym: They as a group played Wow only for that.
Rym: I was reading some other game that provided that to them unless they went over to like Eve and that's not their kind of game.
Scott: So I was reading articles recently and it was about you know It was written by the one of the hardest core rating people because like the hardest core rating group was breaking up and giving up And it talked about like the hardest core rating competition at the top levels yeah, and pretty much everything they said were they were just talking about Wow and how Wow is all kind of blend now and They had didn't say anything else about another game pulling them away.
Rym: Here's why I think Wow feels bleh because one The rating people eventually get too good and look at the differentiation and skill in MOBA's for example Where the guy who's just a little bit better and studies the game more gets a reward.
Rym: Wow and kind of really leveled out at the top in terms of skill.
Rym: And I think the guilds and all the other reasons like the core like social Enablers in those guilds were leaving for other reasons because they were bored with Wow or because they were just playing free-to-play Browser games or whatever.
Scott: I think you're just seeing a correlation of.
Scott: these are the hot game now and that game is losing players.
Scott: Therefore make it jump to a conclusion, which is not one.
Rym: I didn't say that's all of them.
Rym: I I Scott.
Rym: I suggested something pretty small.
Rym: I suggested that of One of the classes of players a significant number of them are playing MOBA's instead of what they used to do.
Scott: But what I'm saying you're right is not a causation.
Scott: League of Legends didn't pull people out of Wow if League of Legends didn't exist.
Scott: Right if MOBA's weren't hot right now, maybe fighting games were hot right now.
Scott: the people who stopped playing Wow Maybe they'd be playing fighting games.
Rym: I guarantee that's not true.
Rym: Okay because the mentality of people who play these games is not to go from.
Rym: the people who play the game for the guild stuff are not gonna Quit it to play a single-player game.
Rym: Fighting games not a single-player game In the sense that they don't have a team with them of five people on their vent server.
Rym: They play for that coordination.
Rym: planetside could take some of them.
Scott: You're assuming that these people were taken from Wow.
Scott: it's they left Wow because Wow is stale.
Scott: Person that left stale.
Scott: Wow fell wherever they fell onto whatever game they fell into.
Scott: yeah No I'm saying a lot and there are many games to fall into.
Rym: just stop playing Wow because it was stale and there Happens to be the biggest bucket right now.
Rym: I don't think.
Rym: I don't think the fact that it's the biggest bucket has anything to do with people shifting to it.
Rym: I think it's because of the guild culture and not really.
Rym: I think it's almost a hundred percent ago.
Scott: There are really League of Legends guilds.
Rym: Yeah, there's teams and most and most it's a team of five people yeah, and they're the sharding into these small teams gives them the same game feel as they would have gotten from the raids that were increasingly becoming stale and Trovertrodden Whatever, okay.
Rym: I think it's a no evidence whatsoever.
Scott: If there's any game when League of Legends becomes unhot right and people start leaving it because it's old and stale and another game is Hot you're gonna.
Scott: Just say oh that game stole all the League of Legends players.
Scott: No, it didn't.
Scott: it's.
Scott: one game is losing five Larry another gains some players.
Scott: You're taking whatever that happens.
Scott: of course You're taking the kind of bullshit view Evidence to prove that the people were pulled out as opposed to you know or that the majority of the Wow people leaving Wow are Now playing.
Rym: that which is not what I said.
Scott: There's no Causational thing there whatsoever.
Rym: You're really making this weird assumption that People that games are completely fungible that oh I quit playing counter-strike because I don't know.
Rym: Dungeons and Dragons 5 came out.
Scott: No, they're left.
Scott: They stopped playing Wow because wow was boring.
Scott: now There's no connection to any other game whatsoever.
Rym: God wow had been boring for a long time.
Rym: and how many people bitched about how boring while was But kept paying and playing anyway.
Rym: Why just recently has the rate of quitting accelerated so rad?
Scott: the rate of quitting has been going on for a lot longer.
Scott: I just didn't know about it.
Rym: No, they released these numbers and all their reports Scott, yeah, and they've been that large for a while.
Rym: No, and you can look that up.
Scott: Yes Wow has had tens of millions of players and now it's down to less than 10 million.
Scott: It's you're like, oh my god, they lost 1 million.
Scott: Whatever they lost a millions in the other quarters.
Rym: Also Did they really do you know that?
Scott: Yeah Wow has been going downhill for like a year or two.
Rym: Yes, and the rate has rapidly increased just recently.
Scott: It's it was already the thing that triggered the going down was long ago.
Scott: You're assuming that something that happened right now has caused it to go it.
Scott: No, it's because it's been a snowball.
Scott: This is just the middle of this Was pushed a couple years ago, I think that this that the mobas caused a the mobas snowball.
Rym: the mobas are just Finally had.
Scott: some are the pile of snow at the bottom of the Snowball Hill.
Scott: I don't think they are.
Rym: No, okay, I Disagree with you strongly and I asked the listeners what they think.
Rym: Okay, cuz so far every time we've ever had a discussion like this.
Rym: They always side with me.
Scott: All right, how about this?
Scott: I'm all right.
Scott: Here you go.
Scott: We'll go.
Scott: anecdotal cuz you know, you have no evidence anyway, so I'll go with my Have is I was trolling around a bunch of old Wow forums.
Scott: Okay, cool ready?
Scott: Think about all our friends.
Scott: a lot of our friends played Wow, right?
Rym: Yeah A lot of them right and a lot of them are playing dota.
Scott: now how many of them?
Scott: Who do we know that played Wow?
Scott: is now playing mobas Wyatt one?
Rym: Yeah, and all his friends?
Rym: I think John this is playing them too.
Scott: Who's that John?
Rym: Okay, maybe yeah, right as a percentage of our friends.
Rym: So you guys?
Scott: so but the thing is okay.
Scott: So who used to play Wow, Scott Johnson Pete, you know, Lisa James all these people All quit well a long time ago and none of them playing mode because they're not part of this wave at all.
Rym: They're the ones who quit for the stale reasons.
Rym: They were they were playing it.
Scott: I think that's most of the people you don't have.
Scott: those rating people are not the millions of people.
Scott: I think there's a very small community of mere hundreds of people who are the crazy raid people.
Rym: Because I think like those people all our friends who quit was a combination of one people who only played because of social pressure from their other friends who actually were into the game and the other people who played Played because they were depressed and/or addicted to the grind.
Rym: Yeah, that's that.
Rym: check that other class of people I can.
Scott: only that's most of the players that is most.
Scott: the rating people is maybe hundreds of people maybe a handful of thousands.
Scott: Yes, not one point.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: I do not disagree that the majority of the players of Wow are the depressed addicted to the grind people.
Rym: They're one of the significant class of players.
Rym: They're the over.
Scott: Legends never existed.
Scott: Wow would still be losing players the same rate right now.
Rym: I think the gilding people would have stuck around longer.
Rym: No, I think they would have because they wouldn't have anywhere to go with to get their vent fix on Coordinate my bullshit.
Scott: Anyway, let's I need those deeps.
Scott: Let's continue.
Rym: So I ride a bike in New York City And everyone seems to complain we not talk about the same thing.
Rym: We had a bunch of listeners who were like all you guys ever talk about is New York City and how awesome it is now?
Scott: Well, it kind of is.
Rym: it is but - I don't think you guys realize that we lived in Beacon.
Rym: We talked about Beacon just as awesome often.
Rym: We just didn't talk about how awesome it was because it was not but stuff happened.
Rym: I think you guys forget how often we would Talk about how every year there was that crazy st.
Rym: Patrick's Day pub crawl that would ruin our city for a day.
Rym: Yep, or the various shenanigans anyway, you know old ladies in the basement getting mad at us about Obama.
Rym: Okay, so yeah, this is a video that summarizes a kind of person who really exists.
Rym: he lives only in major cities.
Rym: he rides a fixie bike and You will see people who act exactly Like this without exaggeration or hyperbole at all.
Rym: if you go to any major city and look for bicyclists You'll see one within a few minutes Really?
Scott: They got to make fixies illegal and they got to have a cop stand there and he sees a fixie stops him and says you attached this brake to your bike or I throw it in this pickup truck and if you don't put the brake on your bike he Throws it in the pickup truck and puts a sticker on it and says come you can pay 200 bucks to get it back and you Can't ride it on the road again.
Rym: brake and a belt.
Scott: what I really don't need a bell You need the brake you need lights.
Rym: Culture is how anti-authoritarian it is to the point that those dudes, you know in the video The guy's blowing a whistle and shouting all the time That kind of dude Literally will not put a bell on his bike Because there's a law that says you have to have a noise-making device to warn of danger.
Rym: That has to be loud enough and a certain, you know There's all these rules about it.
Rym: That dude is just so mad about authority that he won't put a bell on his bike or a horn and instead It's a more important.
Rym: instead He insists that he can shout loud enough and will argue violently with the cop who tries to give him a ticket by shouting and then go to court and shout in court to Prove that he is loud enough on his own to not need a critical and basic safety feature of a bike Mm-hmm.
Rym: So yeah, those these guys exist.
Rym: This video is not a comedy sketch, but a documentary.
Scott: You got a thing of the day, oh, I guess I have one of those.
Scott: It's hockey related.
Scott: Okay, check this out.
Rym: Is it an own goal?
Rym: No fight.
Rym: No own goal fight It's close.
Scott: So in we're about to play the Bruins.
Scott: next it's gonna be rough, right?
Scott: At least the Bruins don't have theirs, you know piece of shit goalie anymore.
Rym: They're seated pretty high, aren't they?
Scott: Yeah, we'll see how this goes.
Scott: Yeah, our goal is a brick wall though So we'll see whatever.
Scott: but this is from 2009 at a Bruins Jets game.
Scott: Actually, it was the game was in 1987. the video was uploaded in 2009 On youtubes.
Scott: basically some dude Jumps over the boards and gets on the ice and tries to mess with the game.
Rym: I have never seen that happen.
Rym: Yeah, and Well that happened at a minor league game.
Rym: after a fight broke out a bunch of people in the audience jumped over.
Rym: Well, they jumped over the glass and started fighting with the players.
Scott: Yeah, so he suffers the You know consequences there for his his actions.
Rym: There's only one thing you can say when you see what I'm assuming happens in this video happen, and that's uh, that's a shame.
Scott: It's not a shame.
Scott: It's deserved.
Scott: Don't go.
Scott: I mean if you're gonna run onto the field in some sport do the naked soccer thing, right?
Scott: They're sort of used to that.
Scott: Yeah, do not in the last choice.
Scott: The last choice is the hockey ice.
Scott: I would do football before I do hockey exactly and football is a really bad fucking choice.
Scott: It's like right, but do not go on the ice in hockey, you know You can throw an octopus out there if you really want to.
Rym: the Blackhawks are actually doing really well this year Like the best team I know kind of worried.
Scott: they're really great last year too.
Scott: if you didn't notice I know games tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah Okay, so kick this out.
Scott: I'm checking.
Scott: I met a moment met a moment.
Scott: We're gonna be at anime Boston like fucking next week.
Scott: Jesus Christ Gotta finish our fucking five time done so far and start to watch me pros island and push the mark button a bunch of times.
Rym: I love how we're both in the world now between GeekNights presents utenna and all the other shows we do and now these panels.
Rym: We both will watch shows in premieres so we can click marks to go back and edit stuff out later.
Rym: So, uh, yeah We're doing how to run an anime club anime openers for around the world.
Rym: all anime are the same.
Rym: Judge an anime by its cover and how to recommend anime.
Rym: that last one is crucial you fanboys.
Rym: Jesus.
Scott: Jesus Christ.
Rym: Okay, Emily is doing a panel.
Rym: our friend Judith is doing a panel.
Rym: nice Exciting times.
Rym: I assume Charles Dunbar will be there probably doing his thing.
Rym: My tools probably gonna be there doing his thing.
Scott: Definitely.
Rym: I don't think Darryl and all them are coming.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I like Darryl stuff.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm saying it's like why would you come from Florida?
Rym: Maybe Would you come from Florida if it were packs?
Scott: Well packs is different.
Scott: I may Boston.
Rym: Yeah, well, what if I would have had?
Rym: what if anime were to us?
Rym: what games are?
Rym: Yeah, that's still not happening.
Scott: Other meta moments that account.
Rym: don't fucking submit your panels.
Rym: The deadline was a while ago.
Rym: We're almost done with the schedule.
Scott: tough shit.
Scott: Also packs.
Rym: Australia, we're gonna be there doing beyond Dungeons & Dragons But a completely rewritten and reimagined one also aimed at an audience that doesn't quite know these indie games as well as you guys all Do well, we assume Australia doesn't know about them as well as we do.
Scott: Yeah And the book club book is the player of games by E&M banks.
Scott: I finished it and I'm actually reading the book that came before it considered Phlebas the book that came before.
Scott: I mean cuz you know It's you know player of games is second in the culture series is the second book But it's not like freakin Lord of the Rings.
Scott: They go in order, right?
Scott: It's basically a bunch of books that are all in the same universe But there's not any sort of serial storytelling.
Scott: so you can just read player of games.
Scott: No problem.
Scott: But the first book which I'm now reading Really, you know it teaches you more about the setting that you know.
Scott: And it's sort of I think both books.
Scott: having reading the second one first It's sort of like you learn the setting from either one, you know, you know It's not like you're reading either one of them.
Scott: You're like, oh, I don't know the setting It's like.
Scott: no you read player games.
Scott: You're fine You figure out what the deal is with the culture and you read the first one.
Scott: It's like oh you figure out what the deal is with the culture either way.
Scott: You're good.
Rym: So I remember a time my youth long ago where a friend of mine typed in the blood code and Sega.
Rym: There was no blood code in the Super Nintendo.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And I remember he did that and I was like, oh my god, and I was like, how do I do this in Nintendo?
Rym: Can't ride?
Rym: I couldn't because the buttons don't quite match up.
Rym: and then I looked in magazines and there wasn't one.
Rym: and then about all Those.
Rym: everyone had that dipshit friend who would make shit up about video games.
Rym: and he was like, oh, yeah There's a blood code and you just make some fucking bullshit up.
Rym: He's like, yeah, you got hit up up down down down up up up down down up down up down B. And then you got a hold.
Rym: select and press start.
Scott: Do you know what the blood code is?
Rym: I Don't remember.
Rym: I didn't have a Sega.
Rym: I wasn't.
Rym: I was one of the smart kids.
Scott: It was a b a c a b b.
Rym: Maybe it's just anecdotal but where I grew up Anecdotally the kids who came from nice homes who were smart in school and got good grades and didn't get in trouble all at Nintendo and By and large the kids who didn't get good grades and came from broken co.
Scott: broken homes had Sega Where I came from.
Scott: the kids who are really good had fucking both.
Rym: Who had both?
Rym: and he also had a neo geo.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: No one had neo geos rich.
Scott: We only saw that in video game magazines.
Rym: I. the thing is he was one of those kids who would invite you over for like cuz he's rich.
Rym: He's got like his fancy game, but then he wouldn't actually let you play it.
Rym: He would just play in front of you and then eventually he'd like it'd be time to go home Mm-hmm.
Rym: I stopped hanging out with that kid.
Rym: Yeah, his name was Dave.
Rym: I think I don't even remember.
Rym: I literally don't remember that guy's name.
Rym: Okay, my friend Joe had a Nintendo though.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, so, uh passwords like that Don't exist anymore because they've been replaced by DLC Save games.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, there's two different kinds, right?
Scott: I mean, you know Zelda had a battery in it.
Scott: But back in those days having a battery in the cartridge was sort of a big deal, you know It wasn't cheap to do that.
Scott: So games that didn't have a lot of save data or a complicated save couldn't really, you know Make the game cost more money to stick the battery in there with it with the you know Small amount of you know, I guess read write memory
Rym: Seventy dollars for Zelda 2 when it came out and that's in dollars from a long time ago.
Scott: Yeah, so You know event what it was is every other game that didn't have Didn't couldn't cost that much would use a password for the save game and basically when you were typing in the password you were typing in The save game data encoded as text.
Rym: Yeah guys gonna blow your mind If you didn't know this stuff kind of like the MMC chips and all that crazy stuff in Nintendo.
Rym: The password was just you writing down the data.
Rym: It was saving the game to you, right?
Rym: And the only way you know You couldn't really cheat and game it too much because a lot of games had pretty good checksumming to where It pretty much had to type in a password the game gave you but some games didn't.
Rym: so remember Kid Icarus How they're like a million passwords.
Rym: Yeah, that's just because the checksumming was so weak.
Rym: Maybe it was even non-existent.
Rym: I forget the details.
Scott: I'll look it up while we talk It just let you put in anything that was valid almost anything.
Rym: So that's why the most famous password in all of NES history I think is 8 followed by a stream of lowercase u's Yeah, then that made you like invincible and put you at the end of the game with infinite everything.
Scott: It's like the game had its own game genie built in.
Rym: So that's where Icarus fights Medusa Angel or packing packing packing packing.
Rym: game from.
Scott: yeah I mean, you know, there's the other kind of cheat code though, which is like Konami code.
Scott: Yeah up up down on the left right left right BS like start right?
Rym: It's not actually I like how you say the select because people who had friends as kids just say the select they assume it.
Scott: That's right people who didn't?
Rym: It was always this unspoken thing of whenever like we'd all sit down and someone put in Contra Everyone would go silent and whoever held the player one controller just had to do it.
Rym: And if it didn't work if you started the game and you didn't have 30 lives, that was the equivalent of a doorknob.
Rym: That Was like.
Rym: that was the faux pas equivalent of in the modern-day cell phone battery runs out.
Rym: I was gonna say your DS light.
Rym: No, okay, or I guess 3ds.
Rym: Anyway, your battery running out.
Scott: All right, but those codes you're not actually like writing the savegame memory You're just the game has a thing in it.
Scott: Like if someone pushes these buttons do this.
Scott: if someone pushes this do that like NBA Jam and a million of them.
Scott: Right, like unlock big head mode unlike mascot head mode unlike, you know, always on fire.
Scott: Unlock all this kind of crazy shit.
Scott: Yeah, every game goes really fast gingers really slow, you know.
Rym: what's interesting is that those really only existed in an era when there wasn't an internet to look them up because they added this sort of Mythology to gaming.
Scott: Well, I think there's a few reasons right.
Scott: number one Game.
Scott: game developers would put them in.
Scott: it all started with adventure with the secret room, obviously, right?
Scott: But you know game developers would put them in and sort of like to help debug the games.
Scott: right even once they got you Know off development machines, right.
Scott: number two They would put them in because then they could sell strategy guides and stuff that told you about them and video game third-party people who sold that shit.
Scott: Magazines also Nintendo hotline also, you know and it you know that whole kind of thing going on.
Scott: You know Really?
Scott: It was just a way to get people excited about games and to have they basically created information that had some sort of value and then they could extract value from it.
Scott: and Three it created this mystique, right?
Scott: Mortal Kombat with all like, you know, especially Mortal Kombat 2 with all the babe alities and friendships and people, you know Create all these rumors.
Rym: The kid was always like yeah, if you do the the nakedality, they'll be naked.
Rym: then they have sex.
Scott: Yeah, all that stuff came later on when game companies are really just trying to take advantage of it.
Scott: You know NBA Jam and Mortal Kombat 2 are really the biggest ones who did that.
Rym: A lot of the earlier ones especially like level skips and stuff probably just came out of easy testing.
Scott: Yeah, it's what I'm saying.
Scott: developers.
Rym: They were.
Rym: there is sort of advanced, you know people who play the game enough.
Rym: It was basically a way to force someone who bought the game to kind of play through it to a point.
Rym: But eventually they look up the cheat code.
Rym: they can skip levels.
Scott: There may have also been a game or two That was basically like hey if we just put these in our game that'll put those freaking game genie assholes out of business.
Rym: Game genie, I remember I was obsessed with game genie because I didn't like I Understood the basics of programming and I understood what the game genie was doing.
Rym: But because it was so poorly Documented and that's partly because there was no good way to document.
Scott: game genie themselves wanted to make money from codes.
Scott: That was their whole idea.
Scott: It was like hey, we'll sell you a game genie.
Scott: and then well, you know We were publishing these game genie code books for all the new updated games.
Rym: You have to buy those books Yeah, but it was also that you couldn't really predict what they would do because all it would do is change values That were being passed around in the game.
Rym: So like set an integer or something to be a different number.
Rym: Yeah I mean all sorts of bullshit.
Scott: nowadays Emulators have much better tools to help you figure out where like.
Scott: for example, if you open up your SNES emulator You can say hey look for the number 254 and tell me if that number changes or like, okay Look at the memory.
Scott: right now I'm gonna do something.
Scott: you pick up a coin and it says tell me what changed in the past.
Scott: You know just then and it'll say memory location this just changed and you look at that memory location And it's exactly one higher than what it used to be.
Scott: and you say aha That's where it keeps the coins.
Scott: so you then type in a new value for how many coins and you notice links money just goes And your wallet fills up and you're like gotcha All right, so you had a game genie didn't have tools like that.
Scott: You just didn't know the memory in the game.
Scott: So only like the game genie people would like, you know Like attached debug tools to the NES and like examine the memory state, you know.
Rym: and because they gave instructions in the back of one of the game genie books that talked about like.
Rym: So this dump they'd be like F is more powerful than a. yeah like for real.
Rym: So I just said they're fucking.
Rym: I found this page.
Rym: I'll link to that.
Rym: Yeah on the last two digits are the checksum and it's really simple.
Rym: and get Icarus.
Rym: This guy breaks down how the passwords work pretty pretty deeply.
Rym: Yep So what's more interesting is that as a kid for some reason a lot of people?
Rym: I knew had a lot of trouble with passwords like they could not write them down.
Scott: They couldn't write them down.
Scott: I mean, sometimes you can't remember him if they're complicated but can't write them down.
Rym: I think a lot of us maybe they're younger kids like or if they write them down But then they don't remember if it was a one or an L or an I.
Scott: What the fuck is wrong with you?
Scott: You had really awful password said to keep writing down and they sucked.
Rym: I think Metal Gear was the worst metal.
Rym: It was pretty bad because Metal Gear on re-inputting them You couldn't backspace so you'd be and you're like moving around like a click click click click click click click click click one Click click click up fuck.
Rym: and you just got to start over like reset the game.
Scott: Mega Man 2 had a good one with the grid Right.
Scott: The grid was Mega Man always had clever ways of entering the password.
Scott: The grid was cool in one way But it was really easy to enter and really easy to remember.
Rym: Yeah, but I had to like draw it if it was complicated.
Scott: Yeah, you just write down like A3, B4.
Scott: You didn't need to write, you know, draw a picture of it.
Rym: Even A3, A4 That's that's.
Rym: I think that is more difficult than just typing a string.
Scott: What like you got to remember eight battleship locations?
Rym: The thing is you don't remember anything.
Rym: you write it down and I can write down one five four five five five five and just remember it.
Scott: Anyway, I like the Mega Man system.
Rym: it was a. The trouble I had with it Really was that I remembered the way to give myself a shit ton of e-tanks and I pretty much always do that.
Rym: Okay, because I sucked at Mega Man and had I not just remembered that password.
Rym: It was so easy.
Rym: I might have Gotten better at Mega Man when I was younger.
Scott: See every Mega Man password I had I got.
Rym: so Yeah, no, I would just get him from like, you know, it's like.
Scott: yeah, I had a password for startup Dr.
Scott: Wily's level with four e-tanks.
Scott: cuz I got to the start of dr.
Scott: Wily's level with four e-tanks And then I kept using that until I beat the game.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: Oh some games I would cheat in and some games I would like Contras always cheat because I couldn't play that game for shit.
Rym: Otherwise, but like I don't think we gave I didn't cheat in Gorilla war you could continue forever.
Rym: So it didn't really matter.
Rym: But at the same time you can hit like a B up.
Rym: I forget what it was.
Rym: But if you hit something like that, it would just bring you back in without having to actually mean Akari warriors a BBA.
Rym: It might have been that in.
Rym: I don't know if it's actually the same or not in Gorilla war because they're not the same game.
Scott: No, but Akari warriors was every time you die I press a BBA and you keep playing.
Scott: Yep, because there's fuck up you go you kill yourself.
Rym: I don't know if there's any way in real life to beat that game without cheating.
Scott: There isn't?
Scott: it's an arcade game Where you're meant to just die constantly.
Rym: It's interesting that when that like when Gorilla war got ported to the NES they didn't make it any easier.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night You.