Rym: It's Tuesday March 5th 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Why you can't find a gaming group.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Was that short enough?
Scott: That was the exact right length.
Rym: So you realize Scott I could have.
Rym: this could have been a trap for all.
Rym: you know I actually did.
Rym: I'm gonna after you go home Edit a really long intro and it'll sound like you were sent into that intro and because you don't listen to GeekNights You would not know.
Scott: So I can buy the thing you are saying right now.
Scott: You will probably will not edit out because it's the only opening bit you have.
Rym: actually I do have an opening bit.
Rym: So our good friends Phil and J We're back from their adventures around the world and Phil is a ski patrol dude wasn't an adventure around the world.
Rym: It is an adventure on the other side of the world around the world in the colloquial sense that you're going around to different Places in the world.
Scott: two places.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well on a macro scale two places If it's not friggin Day.
Rym: I went to Crescent Street, I went to cream Queensborough Plaza twice.
Rym: I went to the second and third levels of Queensborough Plaza.
Scott: Is that around the world?
Scott: Yeah, they're Around the world.
Rym: is Magellan Rym not Magellan around the world is a song in initial D.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: Hey ready?
Scott: Watch this.
Rym: See you didn't actually move.
Rym: You're in the same location.
Rym: your vector is hardly moved.
Scott: I Just gone around the world.
Scott: if you consider if we move the North Pole or something to right here because it's in an arbitrary spot It's a globe, right?
Rym: I mean in fact Scott if I were if someone were to say around the world in the sense that you're describing what they should Say and would say is Circumnavigate the world.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That is not what I say.
Rym: circumnavigate is a synonym of go around anyway, so The cool part of this is that we went skiing and I for the first time in years got to ski with someone who's Not a similar level of ability.
Scott: So far greater level of ability.
Rym: Well skill is skill.
Rym: So I'm a pretty confident Competent semi-expert skier.
Rym: Phil does ski patrol is kind of badass at skiing, but he hadn't skied in like two and a half years.
Scott: Oh, I thought he had skied often.
Rym: He did until about two years ago.
Rym: So we go skiing and the one thing I can say is that it took him all of Ten seconds to get all his skill back and two.
Rym: he doesn't ski with poles, which is interesting in three.
Rym: He skis Way Faster than I ski like.
Rym: I consider myself pretty fast and reckless.
Rym: I kind of just go for it and I led around the first several runs because I know the mountain and he doesn't.
Rym: then I was Like all right you lead now, you know your way around and yeah, we just go down this.
Rym: he's just gone.
Rym: I'm like struggling to keep up.
Rym: I'm pushing myself in ways.
Rym: I've never pushed myself.
Scott: You don't really have to push.
Scott: It's gravity.
Rym: Uh, so it's not just gravity.
Rym: For example, if you there's the fall line, right?
Rym: So per say you say there's the mountain.
Rym: right.
Rym: the straightest down line per gravity on a slope is the fall line.
Rym: If you just don't edge at all your skis just naturally point that way and you accelerate at About the fastest.
Rym: you could possibly accelerate unless you were dropped.
Rym: Mm-hmm But one you can't actually go that way or you'll go too fast and there'll be things in your way trees.
Rym: So instead you will go kind of crosswise the fall line.
Rym: You're swooshing back and forth across the fall line.
Rym: He took a much tighter and more aggressive Course and I was thus forced to ski similarly aggressively Thus putting myself into compromising in difficult situations.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It was great fun though, but I worked some muscle.
Rym: I've never worked before.
Scott: I don't know how you goes.
Scott: no sticks though.
Scott: Even the pros and the Olympics use sticks, right?
Rym: Well, yeah, but you don't need them actually Alright, then why are they there?
Rym: For a lot of things.
Rym: they're useful if you need them to pick turns Which if you're really good skier, you can do that without.
Rym: the pole doesn't actually make you turn It's the motion of planting it that kind of gets you to move the right way.
Rym: to make the turn - they're useful to kind of like push yourself off the lift, but you can just muscle through with your legs.
Rym: They're useful to pop your bindings off But if you're strong, you can just reach down and pop them off on your own.
Rym: so they're useful But they're not necessary.
Rym: In fact good modern ski schools don't give kids ski poles for their first several lessons.
Scott: Well, I've seen yeah, I've seen people not use poles in their learning.
Scott: But I mean every Olympic slalom II person has sticks all the time.
Rym: Yeah So but if you're just skiing around on your own, you're not in a competition.
Rym: The poles are not necessary.
Scott: Also cross-country.
Scott: You definitely need the sticks, right?
Scott: Because then you are pushing yourself.
Rym: Yeah, we use different special skis Super long sticks - right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, if anyone wants to go skiing at Killington or Hunter in the next couple weekends I think I'm gonna run out the rest of the season soon before PAX.
Rym: I don't think there'll be much skiing after PAX Probably not.
Scott: It's gonna be a bunch of biking.
Rym: Yeah, I almost bike to work this morning.
Scott: No, it's warm enough It's too cold.
Rym: I dude.
Rym: I don't even need a jacket anymore.
Rym: The only reason I didn't bike is that I woke up late.
Scott: I'm still wearing a hat.
Rym: So Saturday is gonna be like 48 degrees too cold and sunny.
Rym: So I'm gonna get the bike out and get it ready and I'm gonna try to bike to work next week.
Rym: too cold Unless I go to Colombia too cold.
Rym: So you got any news Catherine?
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: one of the two games I play and as to I like how we don't talk at all about the PlayStation 4.
Scott: Who gives a shit?
Scott: Anyway, I mean what it's okay.
Scott: So a more powerful machine that has a different slightly different controller that will play not based on cell appears to be x86.
Scott: We'll have the next Gran Turismo game and the next Metal Gear game.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: No next.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, the next look a little big planet game will also be on there I don't know.
Scott: and the same all the cross-platform games that are also an Xbox will be on it as well.
Rym: I'm just.
Rym: I don't see any reason for there be different kinds of consoles anymore.
Scott: consoles.
Scott: There are going out anyway.
Rym: I don't think you're going out.
Rym: I think there's no need for different consoles.
Rym: the idea of a console that somehow has exclusives from another console just seems Ridiculous.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, so one of two games.
Scott: I play natural selection - it, you know, they're updating it quite often.
Scott: They just had a big update.
Scott: The update was known as the gorgeous update.
Rym: gorgeous I was I I wasn't paying attention because I play NS2 off and on but really Counter-strike has been my current wheelhouse.
Scott: That's also a fine game anyway.
Scott: So in the gorgeous update, they added many things.
Scott: they added railgun exos.
Scott: Oh, man, they added What else?
Scott: Trying to remember anything.
Scott: they added Oh they added the gorge Assholes.
Scott: a gorge can now basically put an asshole on the ground and then put an asshole somewhere else and then the aliens and Marines Can go through the asshole.
Scott: It's like a. it's a busy a wormhole from one place to.
Rym: people are calling them assholes.
Scott: in the game It looks like a giant butthole.
Scott: There's a little bit of lag when you go in and out of them and Marines get hurt if they're in them.
Scott: Also, if it somehow gets destroyed you buy Marines shooting at it.
Scott: while people are inside they all die.
Rym: Those are that's the kind of thing that in the original NS1 I would like have fantasies about.
Scott: so like a bunch of Exos are in there and then it gets closed and they're all just dead.
Rym: Yeah cowboy bebop style be epic.
Rym: But anyway, the most important thing the thing you were obviously waiting to say something about holding off to last just now the return of The babbler.
Rym: that is my first memory of the handlers.
Scott: They're kind of not the most useful But you can do it ever were in old NS babbler served two purposes.
Rym: one You could get them stuck in yourself and then they would kill you or two.
Rym: You could accidentally kill your own hive with them.
Scott: Anyway now they work but they're you know, basically the best thing you can do with babblers now is number one.
Scott: You can you know, you command them sort of the same way.
Scott: you command the antlions and half-life, too.
Scott: All right, only they're a little smaller and weaker.
Rym: They have a few more things they can do.
Scott: You can make them stick to yourself as armor.
Scott: You can make them stick to a friendly alien as extra armor, which is nice.
Scott: But the biggest thing you can do is you can have them sort of go out there and they don't do much damage.
Scott: But they distract the Marines by basically filling their shit with all sorts of crazy babblers everywhere.
Scott: So the Marines will often especially noobs will shoot at the babbler.
Rym: I've already seen videos of gorge rushes that don't win the game.
Scott: It's just people being dumb But it's a gorge rush and it's just all babblers and the Marines will shoot at the babblers and then not shoot at the gorges And then yeah, they're in big trouble.
Rym: Ah See, it's fun cuz in old remember I mean the early days of NS when it was, you know NS one.
Rym: the matches would last like an hour plus Always and they were so slow and there was such a long game.
Scott: There was the one top period where they had.
Scott: the version of NS was such that the skulk rush could not be beaten.
Rym: So every game was just an invincible skull crush Yep, or if they pulled out the skiff you've survived the skull crush, then it was an hour and 45 minutes.
Scott: Second skull crush that was guaranteed to work.
Rym: Well that was when the skulks were the p90.
Rym: Yeah But the way during the era of the long game when babblers were still around too and also towers of lame.
Rym: Yeah, I would build like 40 OCs block it.
Rym: I I Don't want it.
Rym: It wasn't a good game when it was like that But I really enjoyed it for some reason like that that type of gameplay of the super long game Where I could just kind of buy myself as a gorge just fucking make an invincible asshole wall of death and just be a jerk Like I'd build one of those right side outside of the marine base.
Rym: They wouldn't notice till it was too late.
Rym: But my favorite thing in that game is the harass.
Rym: I would sit in the vent just spraying gas as a lurk Into their spawn for an hour.
Rym: I'd never get tired of that or Babblers for an hour.
Scott: I mean you can still do that now.
Scott: You can stay as a lurk and just sort of shoot at people from really far away like a pussy Yep And it is kind of fun because you're doing some small amount of damage and you're not really getting hurt.
Scott: But there's a big opportunity cause it's basically you're fucking over your team because you spent all these team resources and an entire player.
Scott: I'm basically doing nothing Just bullshitting.
Rym: to be fair in the old game at what that kind of harassment was much more effective And it's new.
Scott: Yeah, you could if you're a lurk gassing from a vent into marine base in the old NS Yeah that you could hurt him pretty bad with that.
Rym: But with babblers I can play my gorge harass Which I have not been able to play in years.
Scott: You can't really gorge harass at the current babblers right now.
Scott: They're not strong.
Scott: They're really weak.
Scott: Really if you're a gorge you have to be the battle gorge and just bile bomb.
Scott: Bile bomb is still so powerful If I've got bile bomb.
Scott: It's all about sneaky bile bomb.
Rym: anyway If you're not playing NS you really should be.
Rym: Seriously, if you're playing counter-strike it's okay, but I think as much as I like counter-strike I'm thinking about going 50/50 with the NS as opposed to my current 80/20.
Rym: So a kickstarter recently launched and I saw it like right away just randomly.
Rym: I didn't.
Rym: I didn't have any announcements set up.
Rym: I didn't have any notifications.
Rym: I just randomly went to kickstarter like I should kickstart a bunch of shit and I saw kobolds ate my baby All hail King Torg and that brought back Memories, in fact, it's against one of those games that we've talked about in many of our panels and lectures.
Rym: We haven't talked about it in a while Yeah, like in our old beyond Dungeons & Dragons like in the early days.
Rym: We'd mentioned this game.
Rym: Yeah, and it's one of those toy RPGs.
Rym: It was you know, it's the old Was basically use D&D rules like second-ed.
Scott: not even it's way simpler than that.
Rym: No, no use those rules, but you're a kobold.
Rym: You basically don't have any skills or any way simpler than D&D rules.
Scott: It's not even close to first your stats or single-digit.
Rym: the options you have available to you're basically nothing and it's really a board game In that you're just trying to steal babies and take them back to be eaten.
Scott: Well, yes But in at the same time it's sort of a role-playing game as if you're a kobold trying to steal babies and you enter these Situations with like some chickens or dogs or some people trying to swing brooms at you.
Scott: And then what do you do?
Rym: it fits this?
Rym: You can't play this game a hundred percent by the book like you would old D&D because then it's not fun at all.
Rym: But if you play this the same way you would run a convention one-off paranoia game.
Rym: It is great fun.
Rym: So this game is largely forgotten.
Rym: people didn't really know about it.
Scott: Not a no and it's just sort of you know, it's forgotten.
Rym: Only people like us know about this.
Rym: a lot of people know about not enough people, but well, I guess yeah enough people.
Rym: So basically it got Kickstarter to be re-released with a bunch of stuff and I saw it right away.
Rym: I was like one of the first three or four people to kickstart it and Within a day they hit their $11,000 goal and it's already done 28 days to go.
Scott: Told you the only problem nobody.
Rym: I don't this.
Rym: don't have that many people in the grand scheme of things Especially because a lot of people for an RPG that's not D&D dude They got ten backers at which is the max at a hundred bucks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, seven is 75.
Scott: What do you get for a hundred bucks?
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: What do you get at a hundred bucks you get?
Rym: It's the Kovalik stalker.
Rym: You get everything in the endless buffet package plus the art pack and John Kovalik will sign and personalize your book with the special Cobalt drawing.
Rym: I don't really need the special cobalt drawing Kickstarter for just the book and the random horrible death table.
Scott: What's the random horrible death table?
Rym: Look up a random horrible death.
Scott: All right Kickstarter exclusive.
Scott: so it's not a table.
Scott: You can play the game on its table to look up.
Rym: I don't think I want to own a random horrible death table.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: Kidding me if you're looking through the dick IKEA catalog horrible death table you want to make that is the best-selling table.
Rym: make an absurd and Surprisingly specific lookup table for RPGs for something really archaic.
Scott: We should make a book that a Creative Commons book to go with the name book the absurd lookup table book We could make that.
Rym: we could make that as a group.
Scott: I'll add random horrible deaths funny items stabs of power stabs of not so much power.
Scott: Yeah random dispositions of corpses yeah, you know locations dispositions of zombies Towns Anyway names of planets planes of existence.
Rym: I Resolved to tell everyone about this Kickstarter, but since it's already backed whatevs if you back it you back it.
Rym: if you don't you don't.
Rym: but Cobalt saved my baby.
Rym: if you've never played it Find one of the old-timers in your group and by old-timers, I mean people over the age of 24.
Scott: Let me tell you let me tell like this, right We didn't play test this at all is to board games as couples ate my baby is to role-playing games.
Rym: That is a very good way to put it, but anyway things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: so me this I saw this video, and it sort of felt like something I had seen before.
Scott: But I looked at the YouTube date, and it said oh I clicked away from the date the day Uploaded on February 28th 2013. so I guess I hadn't seen it before.
Rym: it might be a re-upload.
Scott: No, because it's a video of some sort of you know talent TV show in Japan of some sorts right yeah.
Scott: And this guy has this really sort of artistic performance he does where he balances a whole bunch of things and there's a feather at the end and It's uh it's 12 minutes long, but it's pretty gripping.
Scott: you should watch this.
Scott: It's you know it's one of those things like oh snap that guy How long did he practice and prepare all the stuff to make that happen?
Scott: and it worked?
Scott: He did it on stage one chance to get it right and carrots, and he did it right and it's like oh snap That's pretty amazing right there.
Rym: So all I got is way back.
Rym: well not that way back We did our book club book of the Greg Gatsby by F Scott Fitzgerald and our friend Judith showed us a while ago And I've been saving until after the book club Someone made a sort of retro straight-up NES game.
Rym: That is the Great Gatsby.
Rym: And it is done in the style of how movie and book properties were translated into NES games in the era when that Happened.
Rym: so well it
Scott: reminds me of Barbie the NES game only not as bad yep,
Rym: or uh toys Mmm, but toys was on the SNES, but same thing It's just there's a certain style of NES game that is based on some other property where they're generic
Scott: Platformer where you collect stuff and then in between levels they get
Rym: cut scenes that may or may not actually match and
Scott: all the items You collect bad guys and backgrounds are related to the intellectual property that which is licensed.
Rym: But if you've read the Great Gatsby, it's actually kind of funny to play through this game.
Rym: Yeah, Oh spoilers I guess if you haven't read the Great Gatsby sure whatever.
Scott: All right this time for the meta.
Scott: so the book club book is the player of games By Ian M. Banks.
Scott: it is the most GeekNights book a book can be.
Scott: you need to read it Especially if you're a player of games that you probably are if you're reading listening this episode in a few weekends.
Rym: the penny arcade Expo East is happening.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: We're gonna be there Scott, and I and Emily are all Enforcing.
Rym: we have taken up the black.
Rym: it is a hundred percent official.
Scott: It's the red.
Rym: Well now they still say take up the black because it's blue.
Rym: Yeah, it's blue on one side and red on the other side, but the badge is black It's red.
Rym: that was the rationale that an enforcer explained to me when I said the same thing that you just said to me.
Scott: They just want to keep saying black You know?
Rym: yeah Well look look at the history of video games.
Rym: if there is a garment in an MMO The black ones the most expensive one.
Scott: that was true in puzzle pirates that was true in the realm.
Rym: So we are going to be at the penny arcade expo East not just enforcing But we are presenting at least two lectures in the tabletop theater on Saturday March 23rd at noon.
Rym: We are doing mastering game mechanics.
Rym: Oh shit We're talking about from the design side and the play side Core game mechanics how they work what they mean how to be good at them how to design them and then at 1 30 PM same room same day.
Rym: We're doing practical game theory so pretty much.
Scott: We have the room back-to-back.
Rym: Yeah, we talk a lot about game theory on GeekNights Saturday afternoon.
Rym: So basically we're gonna take all that game theory and explain the important parts without the math Because actually the important parts are more important than the math parts to people who play games as we say often But never actually dwell on much more than saying that and then showing math or something stupid no one cares about.
Rym: So we're going straight into the practical side of game theory.
Rym: ConnectiCon symmetry panels.
Rym: we're currently scheduling so the longer you wait the less likely it is.
Rym: I'll give you a good slot.
Rym: Yeah, Scott's got a grand prix going on.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: So there is a grand prix.
Scott: that is happening.
Scott: if you want to prove that you are the best gaming listener of GeekNights You've got until Thursday at midnight Eastern Standard Time to submit your first round score.
Scott: Yes, cannibal is the first round.
Scott: you can submit your score.
Scott: all the instructions are in the forum.
Scott: There's two threads a main thread and then another thread just for round one.
Rym: She said there's only gonna be one like four rounds.
Scott: This is gonna be I don't know, you know, I can change it at will Right.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: I thought four rounds would be enough and now I'm reconsidering.
Scott: but it doesn't really matter right?
Scott: how many rounds are?
Scott: You don't need to know that now.
Scott: all you need to know is that register and do as well as you can in each round and Then you know victory will come right?
Scott: I mean, it's like I could change the scoring system, right?
Scott: It's like we're keeping we know who had the original scores, right?
Scott: So we can we can change it up to fit to figure out what is the best and the most fair and in fact It's sort of good that it's.
Scott: you know, it's I know it's sort of annoying and I'm professional that it's so fluid and changing But at the same time it's not first one It's the first one.
Scott: and also by changing it and try and experimenting with different, you know methods of you know Running this thing we can really hone it in and perfect it and come up with something really great.
Scott: So it's like the open source under development grand prix.
Scott: And even though it's sort of like well you're participating in the sort of beta test one.
Scott: You someone still wins legit and there's gonna be a legit real prize forever wins.
Rym: So yeah, we'll see if I can compete.
Rym: it might be next week that I go to Columbia.
Scott: Yeah I mean the only reason I don't.
Scott: I thought of only doing four rounds cuz I was like well if it goes more rounds than That this thing's gonna take for fucking like half the year, right?
Scott: It's like how long do we want it to be ongoing forever, right?
Scott: And it's like to make it accessible to all the different people, you know And who don't have money or live in a different country.
Rym: see what your other game picks are.
Rym: But I did I have a gut feeling but again, I'm letting you run.
Rym: It's all you.
Rym: I'm just.
Rym: I'm just a competitor.
Rym: I got nothing.
Rym: Scott doesn't even tell me what the games are.
Rym: No, but I think I would back off like 5% on the accessibility just to open up the scope of games available that might be necessary.
Scott: That's what I would do, you know, and in fact since we're experimenting, you know It's some rounds might be more accessible than others, right?
Scott: Especially since it's hard to find a game That's so accessible like like cannonball was like the most perfect game in terms of.
Scott: you can play it and almost anything.
Scott: And it's so cheap Yeah And it's so direct and it's just score who's the best.
Scott: and it's also kind of good even though Rym doesn't like it cuz he sucks at it.
Rym: I'm not good at it.
Rym: I'm not gonna pretend I am but I don't like it Because you suck at it.
Rym: not to review the game.
Rym: But as a kind of an aside, I never liked one-button platformers because Usually I have seen everything the game has to offer Within a few minutes of playing and any close to kaboom.
Rym: if you think about it It is and you know what?
Scott: I would have almost no if you turn it or if you rotate it 90 degrees.
Scott: No, you can think of it.
Rym: almost no boom because kaboom has two directions and a bun.
Rym: It's kaboom with gravity to the right And could lateral control as opposed to a one button.
Scott: platformer, right?
Scott: I mean you could control kaboom with one button if you figure that the The buckets stay to the right all the time and holding down the button moves them to the left and letting go of the button Moves them back to the right.
Scott: only the difference in cannonball is that?
Scott: Go back to the right.
Rym: that's a ridiculous argument because they're fundamental analogous mechanics are different.
Rym: if you make that argument and I'm gonna tell you that Megaman 3 and Metroid are the same because they have the same basic controls I'm saying that.
Scott: I'm not saying they're exactly the same same genre.
Scott: There is a. there is one key difference between them And that is the only is that is rotated 90 degrees and that there is gravity to one side.
Rym: No, it's not just that because that's a pattern in two dimensions.
Rym: now one Also, it's not procedurally generated That's true.
Scott: kaboom is is stored, right?
Scott: It's the same exact thing.
Rym: Boom has three lives and the option of getting more lives.
Rym: kaboom has a final score in a victory condition.
Rym: There's lots of differences.
Rym: I just get really bored playing games like this.
Rym: super hexagon is pretty much as low as you can take me down.
Rym: the Minimalist mechanic.
Rym: generate flow game genre possible before I get bored.
Rym: I love super hexagon.
Rym: one step more minimalist I don't give a shit.
Scott: Well round two is gonna be not even anywhere close to cannonball, but Okey-dokey, perhaps he's gonna be a masturbatory contest.
Scott: It is even more accessible.
Rym: Perhaps masturbation?
Scott: perhaps it might be the most accessible game of mostly skill that I could find.
Rym: singing or masturbation?
Scott: No, really?
Rym: Cuz you can.
Scott: neither of those are games of skill.
Rym: I Would argue that the latter is a game of skill.
Rym: Anyway, I mean is it gonna be hit a target?
Rym: Is it gonna be quickest?
Rym: No So we've talked about a lot of topics similar to this.
Scott: off I feel like we've done this before.
Rym: Nightpiece Boonie, you could have said something before we started the episode.
Rym: if you had doubts captain I did say something.
Scott: you didn't you never see.
Scott: you didn't say that but I didn't actually search to find out.
Rym: But I don't want to talk about the things we've talked about tangentially related this before.
Rym: I don't want to tell you how to find a gaming.
Scott: No, we've definitely discussed that.
Rym: Yeah That's not we're talking about here because this is a separate problem.
Rym: That's similar.
Rym: It's in the same wheelhouse.
Rym: My goal is a wheelhouse in every episode for the rest of the year.
Rym: But it's the problem of how come so many of you gamers out there.
Rym: I'm talking to you directly Have trouble finding a.
Scott: yeah, this is a meta question, right?
Scott: Cuz it's like something you see in every single online discussion podcast anything having to do with gaming Especially tables up RPGs, but also board games and others.
Scott: never mind every convention has a panel or ten on it Is people can't find other people to game with.
Scott: now we could go over the same discussion again of how do you find people to game with but we're not gonna do that because that's been done in every forum and every message board and Every convention and every podcast and every game.
Rym: now never mind the fact that that universe usually actually wrong.
Scott: Many times the advice is wrong, but it's a discussion that's been had everywhere.
Scott: But the real question is the meta, right?
Scott: Why is this discussion never-ending and why is it everywhere?
Scott: Why do people keep asking it over and over again?
Scott: And how come people don't solve it and how come?
Rym: because meanwhile, for example, let's look at like anime fandom, right?
Rym: There was an era way back before digital fansubs before you know The internet was really accessible where if you were an anime fan you were alone in that fandom.
Scott: You had to ask not only Where can I get animates?
Rym: How do I know?
Rym: more importantly?
Rym: how do I find someone to talk about anime with like?
Rym: when I was in middle school and I met a dude at one point and he had an a Rama one-half t-shirt on and I was like, oh my god, you know what anime is.
Rym: and Here's the problem.
Scott: He didn't Know he did.
Rym: he totally knew what anime was.
Rym: He had such a caustic poisonous nerdy personality That despite the fact that I wanted anyone other than my parents and my brother to talk about anime with I Chose to never engage with that person again.
Rym: And I think that happens to gamers a lot Because I heard an anecdote in the last week from someone who had a gaming group.
Rym: So, you know you have like gaming groups in your town in your school, whatever.
Rym: But a lot of people like us if you're you know, it's one something out of college or in college You have your own private or semi-private gaming group Like you invite your friends over every week or every month to play games And the anecdote was that these people had someone where they basically cancelled the game night And then started again and quietly invited everyone except one person.
Rym: I think a lot more gaming groups need to do that.
Scott: Yes But that is answer number.
Scott: one of reasons why this thread keeps showing up is because this guy is the guy who was Asking.
Scott: that disgusting annoying fanboy nerdy person is one of those people who keeps asking How come I can't find anyone to play games with because you yourself are a person No one wants to play games with.
Scott: so even if you live in nerdy town in a nerdy college or there's nerds everywhere No one wants to play with you.
Scott: unless you change your annoying and caustic personality and your BO problem and you're all Stereotypical nerd things that some people do exhibit that guy.
Scott: now that's reason number one.
Rym: I have a corollary to that because if you notice that in these discussions, there's a secondary discussion of Gaming group falls apart.
Rym: every RPG discussion I've ever seen on the internet That wasn't among like RPG designers has the secondary discussion of yeah, we were playing in a D&D game But the guy playing the fighter was an asshole and the dungeon master sucked and there was drama and eventually it fell apart.
Rym: Those groups are formed by all the people who can't find gaming groups showing up at the local gaming store and It's the same reason why everyone rage quits in Left for dead.
Rym: It's the group consisting of the bottom.
Scott: Yes, so what do you do about this?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Oh, we're not gonna talk about what you do about this, right?
Scott: That's the whole point.
Rym: is just there's sort of a meta discussion could be had about.
Rym: what do you do about the what like?
Rym: The caustic individual.
Rym: that brings everything down because in gaming that is a huge conversation.
Rym: recently Remember we just talked about you know, the so-called fake geek girls or fake nerd girls and that you know People.
Rym: but there is the problem and while it exists in many other parts of society it is surprisingly prevalent in Gaming more so than a lot of other places.
Rym: Yeah, or at least we notice it more.
Rym: but there is the that guy problem.
Rym: Mm-hmm even think us all the way back to our IT.
Rym: We go to our wag which was like there's like a hundred people at this club every week playing games.
Rym: people playing D&D playing shake geek play Play it.
Scott: every game wanna play shake geek.
Scott: Yeah, so that was one of those guys.
Rym: We as the crew now the front row crew at RIT would basically sit down at a table like me and Scott and maybe one other person be waiting for other people to show up and legions of people would walk up to the table like hey guys you want to play X game and We turned Telling them no without telling them we didn't want to play with them into an art.
Scott: We had a lot of practice.
Rym: we was to the point where we'd like be setting up a game that can take five players There are clearly only three people sitting at the table.
Rym: dude walks up.
Rym: Hey, can I play?
Scott: and No, we're full bro.
Rym: We'd be like, yeah.
Rym: Well, actually we're full.
Rym: We can't fit any more people in.
Scott: so that game takes five players.
Scott: two more people are coming then.
Scott: meanwhile later on they see that We're clearly playing with only four players.
Rym: Yep, and The only reason?
Rym: well Usually we only got away with that because they'd be too afraid to come over and confront us and then the next time they'd be More aggressive and we'd have to come up with a better excuse.
Rym: But usually we'd have secondary and tertiary excuses.
Rym: now Scott really wouldn't lie.
Rym: so it was often on me to Scott would just like put his head down and just start like Messing with the pieces or like set up the board or whatever.
Rym: They'd be like, oh, yeah Oh, he started to play with him But then they left and we had to like rejigger the game down or whatever.
Rym: if something happened We lost.
Rym: we don't have enough pieces in purple so we actually couldn't play with five.
Rym: So does that make us the popular kids who were also jerks and in clicks in high school?
Scott: No, it makes us smart.
Scott: That's why we have a gaming group because we are you know, we found good people.
Scott: we held on to them Like, you know, there was no time And we prevented any invaders who would cause the group to break up, right?
Scott: It's like not only does that one caustic person could destroy your group as a whole and then you've got.
Rym: Yeah, let me give you an example all of you out there.
Rym: second person not you Scott.
Rym: so there was a person who we won't name who.
Rym: he was an interesting conundrum because Guys would just play with him and he was good at games.
Rym: He you couldn't really talk to him about much other than the game you were playing But he would play the game competently take his turn understand the rules.
Rym: He was a perfectly enjoyable person to play games with.
Scott: I know this person.
Rym: Yep, but his eyes left with someone's mom.
Rym: yeah, so well he.
Scott: He totally real not joking.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: He's not exaggerating.
Rym: the dude caused a circle of Sex upon sex whereupon he linked a person we knew to his own mother in a relatively short number of sexual hops, but I digress.
Rym: So the problem with this guy is that his eyes were soulless and dead.
Rym: they looked through you like death itself.
Rym: There was clearly nothing back there, but an evil dark abyss.
Rym: Guys just would be like whatever, you know intellectual whore.
Rym: Let's just play our game.
Rym: I don't care if you eat babies.
Rym: We're just gonna apply.
Rym: need someone to play shake geek with.
Rym: meanwhile Every girl who would ever play games with us would not even come over to the table if that guy was there.
Rym: So we had to make sure he never played games with us or else Easily five or six other people would not come over to play.
Rym: that sounds like silly drama, but no, it's that guy.
Rym: It's knives and Trigon.
Rym: one person can ruin the entire dynamic.
Scott: Yep, so a lot of the people looking for game online are that guy?
Scott: What is another reason so many people are looking for game online?
Rym: They don't live in a major city.
Scott: That is right.
Scott: A lot of people live in the fucking sticks.
Scott: and even if I say, you know You're like I don't live in the sticks if it's.
Scott: and you know We sound like jerks when we say New York City isn't the sticks.
Scott: But really if you're in a suburb the population density is so low the percentage of people say it depends on the suburb.
Rym: I mean I grew up in a subdivision a suburb even there and you have two hundred thousand Sure people.
Scott: sure even there even today where board gaming and such is getting more popular.
Scott: What percentage of those people are the nerdy type?
Scott: people who you could play games with?
Scott: that are not only nerdy Not only then you still got to subtract the people who are too young.
Scott: Yeah, it's attract the people who don't get along with you Scott.
Rym: I had two regular gaming group.
Scott: You got to subtract that like those ten people who are like they get together and game by themselves But it's like, you know some families or like some you know Some couples that get together in game and they don't want to be.
Rym: Actually, I had two Semi-separate gaming groups.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You got to subtract those people who they're gamers But they're into a specific game that you're not into their war gamers.
Scott: They're not into your board.
Rym: I'm about to make a much more subtle point here.
Rym: So yes, I had two groups of friends that would get together and play games but we were Invisible to all other gamers because we did not advertise our existence.
Rym: Yeah, we did not go like.
Rym: hey We're forming a gaming group.
Rym: Does anyone want to join it?
Rym: No, we were all just friends and started playing games and Meanwhile all the other people who might not have a friend group already to play games with looking for gamers.
Rym: They're primarily only gonna find that guys.
Scott: Yeah, it's the.
Scott: there are very few.
Scott: even if there's plenty of gamers around enough They are not visible right there.
Scott: Very few of them are visible.
Scott: only when the population density is very high Will you be able to find?
Scott: visible gamers Advertising looking for others.
Scott: All right, so there's a close geographic space that are not that guy Even.
Scott: we go to nerd NYC board game night.
Scott: How many people are there?
Rym: Oh Between 20 and 40.
Scott: in the biggest goddamn city One of the most important cities in the world 40 people show up.
Rym: Well, they should but that's the thing 40 people.
Rym: and it's a rotating group of different people showing up at one event.
Scott: You go to a similar event in Typical suburbs say where I grew up Trumbull, Connecticut, right?
Scott: How many people you think are gonna show up for?
Rym: Yeah, if you're lucky three of them are that guy exactly, but it's a little more subtle than that.
Rym: It's it's the one.
Rym: the gaming groups that are healthy aren't soliciting other people So you'll never find them unless you're friends with them.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but to there aren't as many focal point public groups that have Organization sure.
Rym: Yeah, it's true.
Rym: There aren't even in New York City.
Rym: There aren't that many gamers Yeah, and we went to Mars.
Scott: We were lucky.
Scott: Despite that.
Rym: there's nerd NYC which meets once a month and has you know a sort of community and it has a Management layered as people who run it as an organization.
Rym: They put on events they run a forum.
Rym: So there is a place to congregate and aggregate all those gamers and then sort them into groups.
Rym: So there is a social scene for gamers.
Scott: In fact, there are multiple such, you know board game groups in New York City, right?
Scott: There's the naive and there's a couple other one.
Scott: There's a d20 store boy.
Rym: You go to those net runner meetups.
Rym: There's a net runner meetup.
Rym: This guy like there's meetups at the complete strat.
Rym: There's individual gaming events little mini conventions.
Rym: North Jersey has like ten little gaming conventions Yep.
Rym: So there's a ton of places for you to go and be social with people and find gamers.
Rym: but even there The people who meet other really good gamers at those events tend to pull away and make their own private event Even if they go to the public event.
Rym: and again those events are all off the radar.
Scott: And so let's say you live in someplace, you know, let's say our friends in Albany, right?
Scott: They've got some gaming stores that they can go to right and they have each other obviously.
Scott: But those gaming stores you have a gaming store that and it's just sort of a public event like that.
Scott: Who's showing up at that?
Scott: It's not the person who already has friends to play a game with.
Scott: they don't need to go to the gaming store It's the creepy guy.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So if you're the non guy Remember when we moved to art rock art Rochester when we moved to Beacon.
Rym: Yeah We because we needed people to play games with we would drive all the way up the road to Poughkeepsie to Mars.
Rym: Which is this board gaming group?
Rym: Mm-hmm, and it was like that one of the bigger board gaming groups in the area that maybe eight members.
Scott: You had a lot of people.
Rym: Yeah Considering three or four of them would show up at a given meeting.
Rym: but we went up there because we were desperate Yeah, but as soon as more people we knew moved into town, we just literally never went back.
Rym: Yep, because now we had enough people to play games on our own.
Rym: We didn't need to go find more people.
Scott: and really Mars didn't do advertising.
Scott: very much.
Scott: I had to seek them out hardcore Right in order to actually find they existed and get in contact with them and they use like an old busted like just email Everybody kind of thing and not really a listserv and I made
Rym: them a whole website That was a thousand times better and gave them the keys to it
Scott: and they didn't use
Rym: it.
Rym: They didn't use it.
Rym: Eventually.
Rym: We just shut it down.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, but so if you're and that was in Poughkeepsie, which is still you know A tiny city like there's stuff going on if you're outside of one of those places There just aren't that many gamers and more importantly there aren't.
Rym: there isn't a social scene that caters to gamers.
Rym: So you're kind of like shooting in the dark looking for the guy on the Rama shirt.
Scott: The other thing is a lot of those people who are looking for game, right?
Scott: A lot of them are.
Scott: just there are people who don't have a car maybe or they're kids.
Scott: A lot of them are like high school kids and it's like mate, you know if they're in a small school I mean the school I went to at hundreds of kids the one you had wed way more Yeah, but like where Emily went to school it was like a tiny ass school, right?
Scott: Yeah, but even there Pete went to school even Smaller right like the smallest schools.
Scott: It was like what are the odds that even one other person in the school is gonna You know be as nerdy as you?
Rym: but then again being in school Especially nowadays and my nowadays mean the last 20 years is a great place to meet gamers.
Rym: middle school I would play magic with one of like 40 other kids over lunch every day, but how many people were in that middle school?
Rym: Oh, I don't know 300.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: See when I was in middle school We played magic at lunch with like four other dude.
Rym: There was the magic wait like in the cafeteria.
Rym: There was like a set of four tables like the long ones.
Rym: That was just all magic players.
Scott: Yeah, that was that was four kids at one table.
Rym: not for You know also, you know being near a college campus all those things, but we lived up in Beacon I mean even way before Scott.
Rym: when I lived up there by myself I was so desperate for gamers that other than driving back to Rochester, which I did almost every weekend I tried to go to like Marist or Vassar to check out their game.
Scott: We went to their gaming for hope and there were plenty of gamers.
Scott: No scope was cool But the thing is a lot of those gamers they're in the college.
Scott: those people in the college are never gonna look outside the college For games and it's kind of weird for an outside of college person to look into the college.
Scott: You know, you can my anecdote.
Rym: my anecdote was I went to one of those colleges and I went to their gaming club Which was open to outsiders.
Rym: I showed up.
Rym: There were like 14 people.
Rym: not bad club was the gaming club.
Rym: It was also the Wicca Club the anime club the science fiction club all in one and those people were Horrifying.
Rym: Yeah, I never went back.
Scott: Right when you go to a super nerdy place like RIT MIT, you know Caltech something like that Yeah, or CMU sure.
Scott: There's gonna be enough nerds that you can separate those clubs.
Scott: But if you go to like state school It's pretty much gonna be one nerd club with 14 people and you don't want to go to it.
Rym: It depends on the state too, but we're generalizing.
Rym: but it seems like really, you know, we're talking about all this stuff again but it really just comes down to the fact that there's a sort of adverse selection that in general and Obviously, I'm not saying all of you are like this but many of the people who are looking for a gaming group are that guy.
Rym: Thus if you're not that guy and you're looking for a gaming group It is very difficult to find a group that does not consist entirely of that guy Because anyone who has a stable gaming group falls off the radar.
Rym: The only places gaming groups are on the radar are if you're in a college that is nerdy.
Rym: You're in a school at a convention or your or you go to conventions.
Rym: But then great you go to a convention.
Rym: and so Scott how come this?
Rym: you go to a PAX you go to a kinetic Con you go to any gaming con.
Rym: There's still the panels and the meetups that are all like how to find a gaming group.
Scott: Yeah, there's one other reason that I can think of why it is hard to find game.
Scott: All right, there are people where even if maybe they're lucky in their general area They found each other and in their general area, none of them are that guy.
Scott: but yet they still can't get the gaming group together.
Scott: It still sucks.
Scott: And the reason for this is they get together because on paper, they're all gamers.
Scott: They should game together.
Scott: They live in the same area.
Scott: Why wouldn't they game together?
Scott: But in fact, they look for they are not the same kind of gamer and they're gonna spot it.
Scott: Yeah, their gaming ways are not compatible.
Scott: even you know, people look at gaming is like this one thing It's like no, no, no, no, no.
Scott: that guy.
Scott: He's a war gamer and his the thing he cares about is the historical accuracy He's geeking out about like yeah, that tank was actually used in World War two on in the in this front You just want to play shaky Yeah, you are into.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: maybe you even like war games, but you care about you know, trying to win What is the way to win this game?
Scott: and of course you're doing.
Scott: you're trying to figure out the smartest thing to do possible and the other guys getting upset because Oh my god, that is not even close to what happened historically.
Scott: What is wrong with you?
Scott: You're so crazy.
Scott: Now it's like, you know, sure both of you are legit geeks.
Scott: Maybe you're both socially not inept, but you can't.
Scott: you're not compatible in terms of this game.
Scott: There's no bull who they might just want to play games.
Scott: You know, they're the kind of person who plays games for fun.
Scott: their favorite games are like apples to apples and you know dicks it and these kinds of games where it's just you know, You know cards against humanity.
Scott: Those are their favorite games.
Scott: But they also like to play games like Agricola or settlers because they like to trade with people.
Scott: or they like cute little animals You know and they like to have fun with the game.
Rym: They don't really care about winning.
Rym: Well in my experience again not compatible.
Rym: the most common sort of poisonings because you know That guy is one of a whole set of poisonous people when it comes to a gaming group.
Rym: now Poisonous person doesn't mean bad as a person.
Rym: It just means they're the kind of person who will be able to destroy a gaming group.
Rym: For example the person who is into gaming but brings someone with them who isn't and that person wants to do other things.
Rym: Or the person who doesn't actually want to play games but shows up anyway.
Rym: Though all those different kinds of people destabilize these groups But in my experience the most common one are just the people who take too long on their turns.
Rym: That's also a big one because that is what people complain about the most which amazes me because the people who complain about it are People I complain about behind their backs.
Scott: I heard a story from someone the other day.
Scott: They talked about how they had a person in their group who is a good person in fact a smart person a lawyer But they took too long in their turn so they did the same thing.
Scott: I just you know you said earlier where they sort of you know didn't invite them back to gaming night.
Scott: the person asked hey When's gaming night?
Scott: I'd like to have board games again.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: It doesn't exist anymore.
Scott: Yeah, it does.
Scott: It's not with you and the person took too long in their turn.
Scott: and Here's the real problem right is that there was a game.
Scott: I think they were playing talisman.
Scott: Which is that you know?
Scott: the?
Scott: oh yeah the dungeon Crawley?
Scott: Games workshop game.
Scott: I think right and the somebody was playing talisman for the first time and they were playing it when slow guy was There.
Scott: all right that slow guy had been kicked out a while ago But that person who had only played talisman once with slow guy Didn't want to play talisman again, and they said that game takes forever, and they're like no no no no It's just because you played it with slow guy.
Scott: Right but meanwhile that person is now ruined the game.
Scott: now that person is another person is seeing the game differently because They played it with that person the only time that they played it.
Scott: So now they had a false belief that the game was the cause of the slowness when in fact I mean the game is not the super fastest, but they played it with us.
Scott: really really slow guy.
Rym: now What's funny is if I think back to RIT anime, and I posted about this in the forum a long time ago.
Rym: But anime clubs kind of had the same problem.
Rym: if there'd be the few people who were toxic to the culture of the group And would scare girls away to be perfectly honest They scared girls away from the club But they'd be hey.
Rym: so we as the leaders of the club actually had to pull some sort of Nefarious Machiavellian sort of mean Shenanigans to prevent that from happening.
Rym: we would actually have people stationed at the door to Be the first one.
Rym: so the first person who engages a new girl who shows up is not one of the creepy Toxic dudes, but it's one of our plants or we would have someone go and distract the fanboys and pull them away from Conversations with the new girls who arrived
Scott: even in even in a fandom like anime.
Scott: Maybe you want to get an anime club together right?
Scott: there are people who would enjoy different animes in different ways Right and enjoy different aspects.
Scott: there might be someone who just really Likes robots and wants to see them explode and someone else who really likes a romance stories and someone else who is a pervert and Even though they're all anime fans They're not really gonna get along as an anime club.
Scott: so even though they were lucky enough to have three whole anime fans in A tiny ass town they don't go together.
Scott: It's just right.
Scott: so all of them go to the internet and say looking for animes in tiny town And they see each other.
Scott: and that's it now.
Rym: I have this really sort of sad suspicion that it's possible.
Rym: This is primarily an American phenomenon in gaming.
Rym: I don't know because Luke Burrage when he visited us a while ago Made the comments that his experiences in America led He to paraphrase him very loosely.
Scott: remember.
Scott: He's in a big city of Berlin Just like he was playing games in New
Rym: York with us at
Scott: a nerdy yet together Yeah, but
Rym: even then he's basically like how come all the gamers in America are the scary dudes who don't know each other's names and Really only use each other to play games.
Rym: Well.
Rym: How come everyone's so socially inept?
Scott: Because not like that in Berlin right because their games are more mainstream.
Scott: Just everyday people will play a game casually and not as a focused hobby.
Scott: right?
Scott: there are people who you know like my mom Will play a board game if you try to make her play it or I
Rym: remember trying to get your family to play up And anagrams that
Scott: right you can get my family to play a game, but of their own initiative They will not go and seek out Any game more serious than like mahjong or scrabble or whatever.
Scott: and even then while they those are games They like they will rarely seek them out.
Scott: I think my aunt plays rummy cube with some people every week.
Scott: right and they play mahjong, and that's about it.
Scott: right so You know.
Scott: but in other countries.
Scott: It's like people hang out in a bar and just play a game and especially Germany, right?
Scott: That doesn't happen here right?
Scott: when is you know?
Scott: There's I think a couple bars in town that have board games there and usually not super serious ones.
Scott: There's one snakes and lattes in Canada.
Scott: There's one.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: I mean, it's crazy.
Scott: that place is awesome and packed ever and I have to make reservations to get there.
Rym: But again, there's one as a gaming club with a cover charge.
Rym: right about that.
Scott: You would not blink twice.
Scott: I think I haven't been there right, but I'm guessing Tell me if I'm wrong that seeing a copy of settlers in pretty much any bar in Germany would not be a strange sight.
Rym: Not nearly as strange as seeing it here not nearly now.
Rym: They're all interestingly here.
Scott: you get here or at least this much at least this much.
Scott: if someone if you put settlers out Place in the United States in a random bar, especially not in a major city people might come up and ask you What is that thing like when those prostitutes asked us what it was that that anime would be a big attention-getter?
Scott: Yeah, you did that in you know.
Scott: Perhaps we were able to.
Rym: those prostitutes were more interested in this weird game with hexes and cubes than they were in their job.
Scott: Yes, if you did that in Germany, you know even at a bar where board games are not common I doubt you would turn many heads Guessing it's it's a rarity to even see like the scrabble set or the trivial pursuit.
Scott: Yeah, every someplace, you know coffee shops Especially a lot of them seem to have a scrabble or checkers or a chest sitting around But it's rare to see it get used.
Scott: It usually sits there and gets maybe used like once a week.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: so I still think that the that guy problem is the biggest problem because Just colloquially even at conventions if I'm looking for strangers to play games and by that guy It's not just the that scary guy It's the social interaction stuff in general when I'm at packs the hardcore hat Like it's the gaming con in America and even there if I find a stranger who's kind of milling around like hey You want to play a game?
Rym: 50/50 odds on them having some problem with the game or not being able to play it because they're Socially awkward or can't interact with me.
Rym: Yep I mean we were running a game.
Rym: I forget if this was a. I think it was at PAX.
Rym: Might have been.
Rym: at that mag fest the dude wanted to play burning wheel with us.
Rym: So we ran burning wheel with like these three dudes and then ten minutes in the game one dude Just like I. I can't do this and he just walked away.
Rym: Yeah, we're like what?
Scott: What at mag fest?
Rym: Yeah, it was mag fest.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It was the first mag fest we went to but I I hate to say this but I blow a lot of Strangers off because it is within a second of talking to them.
Rym: I realized that I will never be able to enjoy playing a game with them because I can't interact with them socially comfortably in or out of the context of the game and the gaming culture and the taking the turn stuff is secondary to the Person just doesn't jive with me culturally on a fundamental level.
Scott: Yep, but also the geography and the People who aren't actually after the same thing that you are after even though you both want to play games.
Scott: Right, you both actually want something completely different from the experience and thus you are not compatible and cannot achieve that.
Scott: your goals together.
Rym: I think we're like that.
Rym: Look at what we just said a little while ago about the soulless guy Who was fine to play games with if you didn't care that girls were afraid of him?
Rym: Yeah, and wouldn't come near your table even girls who didn't know him.
Rym: It's just he had this body language.
Rym: He's a creepy dude.
Rym: Don't get us wrong.
Rym: We still would play games with him occasionally because we wanted someone to play games with.
Scott: it was basically an AI and he could play Games properly - yeah, he understood the rules.
Scott: He played quickly.
Rym: This is a Woody Allen intellectual horror situation.
Rym: We were using him for his gaming AI and nothing more.
Rym: Yeah, we would not interact with him outside of the context of a game of settlers.
Scott: Nope I guess sometimes he might have followed us to dinner And we wouldn't really talk to him that.
Rym: God, you know How many times we would like leave a gaming night and a bunch of people would follow us and we we all had this code Of being able to say yeah, we're all gonna go home.
Rym: We're done.
Rym: going back to my dorm.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna regroup in that quad over there reconvene in the quad like exactly an hour later.
Rym: I remember one time a dude was there waiting for us like he'd figured it out.
Rym: That was a bad day bad day.
Rym: so yeah, I don't know.
Rym: the moral is other than Seriously, look at yourself.
Rym: Don't be that guy.
Scott: I mean if you are that guy you can un be that guy.
Scott: and the thing is you might not be that guy.
Scott: overall.
Scott: You might be just a little bit that guy but in all honesty, but being a little bit that guy is Incredibly irritating to people who are not at all that guy.
Rym: So if you find yourself, I'm being perfectly just I want to I want to give good advice.
Rym: if you find yourself Looking for gaming groups regularly finding them and it never seems to work out You need to be really introspective and really honest with yourself and try to figure out why.
Scott: and if you can't find people at all move.
Scott: and If you find people and you know, it sort of you know, it's it's like, you know You had to determine.
Scott: is it really you being that guy which is actually more likely?
Rym: If you're if the gaming groups having problems and you cannot identify That guy cuz 90% of the time there is a that guy?
Scott: if you cannot find him He's probably you know, and if you think you've identified him really think hard.
Scott: Is that guy you've identified actually that guy or is he someone who you just really don't like because he notices You're that guy and is really antagonistic?
Rym: An RIT anime?
Rym: all the that guys hated Scott Hated him because they thought he was that guy.
Scott: But no I was the guy who's noticed that they were that guy and went down on them and said you're that guy.
Rym: Scott's job Which he was very good at was to drive those guys out of conversations when they were being creepy to save everybody else.
Rym: Scott was perhaps an expert at this gray shade Because we played good cop bad cop and I was the nice guy.
Rym: I'd laugh at the jokes and you know Man we were mean.
Rym: Yeah, but no seriously in all honesty being that guy It might not be.
Rym: I mean, you know, you're probably all imagining that guy as the smelly awkward guy who wants to play shit geek.
Rym: It's not necessarily that you might be that guy in the sense that you want to play hardcore games for serious And no one else does to that group.
Rym: You're that guy even if you're not a bad guy.
Scott: Yeah, you might actually play the games.
Scott: fine play them quickly play by the rules, but that's not what they want, right?
Scott: But you or even you know, you might play the way that they play But you just might not like have anything to talk about or say weird things.
Rym: They're all if they talk about nothing, but I was skiing in Milan last weekend and You just don't intersect with that culture.
Rym: It's fine.
Rym: I can work out if you go skiing in Milan every weekend.
Rym: I don't even know if there is skiing in Milan.
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: I don't know where that is.
Rym: Anyway, if your culture doesn't line up you're that guy even if they being that guy is not bad It's not bad to not go skiing in Milan.
Rym: It's just you're that guy for that group.
Rym: But you might also be the smelly guy.
Scott: Check check your breath You can always ask.
Scott: the problem is most people just can't deal with drama and they can't tell you honestly You think you're that guy?
Scott: Come see me at a convention and I will tell you how much of that guy you are.
Rym: if you actually honestly want to know Be warned we're probably gonna be pretty accurate and you'll either you're really gonna feel great after you talk to us or You're gonna feel really you can trust that we will be a hundred percent honest.
Rym: I think we'll leave it at that.
Rym: I don't think anyone will ever take us up on that offer.
Rym: This Has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live With no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night Because don't say because again Say because again motherfucker say it again.