Rym: It's Thursday, June 13th, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight on the GeekNights Book Club, The Player of Games.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So I guess Reddit liked our anime panel from Anime Boston.
Scott: That's really weird.
Scott: I don't expect anyone to like any of our shit.
Rym: We'll do a PAX panel for a room with like a thousand people in it.
Rym: It's this giant deal.
Rym: And after PAX, there's not a lot of discussion.
Rym: It's not like we said anything particularly controversial.
Scott: Yeah, we put all our panels up and people, some people watch them and some people like them.
Rym: But there's no like community, like crazy discussion around them.
Rym: No one has like a 300 comment thread on Reddit about our Dungeons and Dragons discussion.
Rym: If anything, the discussion is like, "Oh, they made some good points about D&D.
Rym: I have some additional points that I'll
Rym: make.".
Scott: I was surprised.
Scott: I thought that would be mostly that guys, but it's mostly not that guys.
Rym: I think that is why that video was popular.
Rym: Because it was, you know, for you non-anime people, we basically did this thing called "Judge an Anime by its
Rym: Cover."
Rym: Where we took a bunch of shows and we reviewed them just based on a single picture and a paragraph of summary.
Rym: And basically there's a silent majority of anime fans who are kind of sick of the perverted crap and the kind of annoying people who like the perverted crap.
Rym: And they overwhelmingly seem to take this video as their rallying cry and banner.
Rym: And meanwhile that that guys took umbrage with the fact that we called pedophilia shows out for being about pedophilia.
Rym: No.
Rym: I'm enjoying this.
Rym: So I guess we need to do more provocative anime panels that just piss off fanboys but are generally the consensus of everyone else.
Rym: Could we do the same thing for gaming?
Scott: Yeah, let me go off on all the stuff I usually go off on.
Rym: Yeah, but what do we call it to do this?
Rym: To bring attention to it?
Scott: Okay, well what are the things I usually go off on when it comes to gaming?
Rym: Alright, so how about?
Rym: our panel will be "Microtransactions are a cancer.
Rym: A literal cancer that kills people in the real
Rym: world.".
Scott: That's a little too far.
Scott: But I mean, things that I say a lot, right?
Scott: For example, "Walk around and hit things.
Scott: Games are bullshit crap.
Scott: Why do you like
Scott: them?".
Scott: Two, "You actually just like games for the theme.
Scott: You don't actually like games.
Scott: You are not the same as we
Scott: are.".
Rym: Alright, alright.
Rym: So here's what we call that panel.
Rym: "That's not a game.
Rym: Semi-colon.
Rym: You're not a
Rym: gamer.".
Scott: That is the title.
Scott: How about, "Failed to get into Hollywood.
Scott: Stay away from game
Scott: industry.".
Rym: "Gaming, the bastion of Hollywood
Rym: washouts.".
Scott: Oh snap.
Rym: Burn!
Scott: Boom!
Scott: There was the dynamite.
Rym: Dynamite!
Rym: So, we were talking about Kickstarters because Scott found a really cool Kickstarter project.
Rym: And before we talk about the Player of Games, the GeekNights Book Club, it's the lounge.
Rym: It's Thursday.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: It's book club.
Scott: Book club and lounge don't mix.
Rym: I believe if I was going to have a book club in the physical world, I would have it in a lounge.
Scott: The lounge would be too noisy with music and drinking to have a good book club discussion.
Rym: There are lounges that have nothing but quiet, tasteful piano music in the background.
Scott: That's not a lounge.
Rym: Those are lounges.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: You need a lounge singer.
Rym: That's a different kind of lounge.
Rym: That's like a bar lounge.
Rym: Anyway, I want every lounge, and more importantly, I would be lounging.
Scott: That's not the kind of lounge this is.
Rym: On a Chase lounge.
Scott: This kind of lounge is the kind with the singer in it.
Rym: You're going to sing?
Rym: Is that what you're saying?
Scott: No, Richard Cheese is coming in like ten minutes.
Rym: But yeah, so we're not going to belabor the point, but we're going to talk a little bit about some Kickstarters because we've Kickstarted a lot of cool stuff.
Scott: I Kickstart way too many things.
Rym: I've only Kickstarted one, two, three, four, five.
Rym: Well, you talk about some things you Kickstart.
Rym: I'm going to count how many I've done.
Scott: Okay, so I'm going to go for the most recent.
Scott: First, I'm going to do the three that are still in progress.
Rym: Like fifteen.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: I have way too many more than that.
Scott: Okay, so the most recent ones that are in progress still, plus pool, tile by tile.
Scott: These people are going to build a pool, a swimming pool, in the East River down near Brooklyn, Brooklyn Bridge area, sort of off the park.
Rym: Now, you might be thinking, and you're probably rightfully.
Rym: So what is this, an experiment to murder children?
Scott: Yeah, it's not, to their credit, it's not a pool in the Gowanus Canal, right?
Rym: I imagine they sink this thing in the Gowanus Canal, and there isn't enough water through the filter to fill it.
Scott: They're using technology similar to what was used in the Beacon Hudson River pool, right?
Scott: Why do we keep living in places with these river pools?
Scott: But they think it's the first, the first, the world's first water filtering floating pool.
Rym: Now that's bullshit because I know that they put one in the river in Beacon.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I spent, I kickstarted it for 150, which gets me a tile in the pool, one of the white tiles that I can write on it.
Rym: Now there are only two things you could write.
Rym: It either has to be "look ye mighty," which is, for those of you who don't know us, been our catchphrase for a decade, plus, or the pool is mightier.
Rym: Because anything else I would write would be copyright infringement, trademark infringement, or obscene.
Scott: Anyway, so, also I get passes to go to the pool like a week before it opens to everyone else, which means that it likes to be a pleasure to swim in it.
Scott: And after the public is let in and it's full of poop, I will never go back, but they'll see my name there.
Rym: I guess you'll be able to take your GoPro in the water and get a really good picture of the tile.
Scott: I'm going to be doing all kinds of stuff like that when I go, because I think it's a whole, it's not just like a day of going, it's a week of pre-going.
Scott: So I go like every day that week.
Rym: Now the cool thing, and I'm not sure what they mean by this, is they say it's going to filter the water, so you're swimming in the water, but the pool itself has filtered the water, so it's just water.
Scott: I don't think the water goes straight from the East River into the pool.
Scott: I think the only way water from the river gets into the pool is through this machine that cleans it and makes it nice.
Rym: Well, that's what I'm saying.
Rym: Well, the one they did in Beacon, what it did is the pool itself was a filter.
Rym: The walls of the pool were the filter.
Rym: And they just sink it and water just osmoses in through.
Scott: Yeah, this is some sort of active filtering.
Rym: Well, I'm not sure.
Rym: It seems active.
Scott: They have a picture of the filter machine.
Rym: No, that is the test tank.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: What they're kickstarting to start is funding to build the test pool.
Rym: that's 35 feet by 35 feet.
Rym: That's going to be sunk in the water to see if it works full scale.
Rym: It's going to sit in the water.
Rym: Water just goes through the filters from the sides and I guess the bottom into the pool.
Scott: This is the thing I want to exist, so that's why I'm giving it money.
Rym: Now what I'm curious about is they say that it will actually clean the water in the East River itself.
Scott: Very barely, because it's going to spit out the clean water.
Scott: that's excess and it's going to keep dirt in the filter.
Scott: You empty the filter, you're slowly cleaning the East River.
Rym: I'm assuming that's how it's going to work.
Scott: Very small, but you're cleaning at the end.
Scott: If you want to really clean it, you have to clean it up top.
Scott: You can't clean it at the bottom.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: I think the technology is cool.
Rym: Imagine if we start building these en masse and just putting them in every shithole of polluted water.
Scott: If they put them all around the river all the way up top, then it would help, but it's not helping down there.
Rym: This is just a really cool project and it's finally...
Scott: You know, if you talk for this long about each one...
Rym: We're not going to talk long about the other ones, but it's finally a project that is doing what Kickstarter is ostensibly for.
Rym: Someone wants to do a cool thing that wouldn't happen unless they got funding for it.
Rym: Kickstarting it is to make it happen, not really a pre-order for the thing.
Scott: As opposed to these other things, such as Double Fine's massive chalice.
Scott: I think everyone knows about that.
Rym: I funded this awesome belt with really classy buckles that is cut to size and has no holes.
Rym: It's got this ratchet mechanism in the back and if anything is up my alley, it's ratchets.
Scott: This is already funded, but they're going to make a documentary movie about the Straits Matzah factory in Brooklyn.
Rym: The only thing I got in progress is this plume sort of recoil... Basically, you know those snap bracelets from the 90s?
Scott: It's a steel one of those that is sort of a pull-out mudguard and fender for your bikes.
Rym: You don't have to have a dorky, annoying fender on your bike, but if it starts raining, you've got a fender for as long as you're biking in the wet.
Rym: I commute a lot of my bikes.
Scott: Limited edition translation of Osamu Tezuka's The Crater.
Rym: And then Shovel Knight.
Rym: Oh, I got this cool titanium G2.
Scott: Yeah, Shovel Knight.
Scott: I'm on there.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Because I don't want to carry keys in my pocket anymore.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: And it'll match the belt buckle on that fancy belt I kick-started.
Scott: B9 Kingdom pretty much kick-starting everything they do.
Scott: Penny Arcade.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Cobalt's Ate My Baby, of course.
Scott: I didn't do that one.
Scott: Cucumber Quest Book 2.
Rym: Oh, I forgot to do that one.
Scott: Torchbearer.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: The 10-Year Hoodie.
Scott: I'm waiting for that to show up.
Rym: Eh, I'm not a fan of that one.
Scott: I need it for work.
Rym: But really, the one that I got that's important is this U-Arrange Wallet.
Scott: I also got that one.
Rym: The Jimmy wallet is dead.
Rym: You can't get it anymore.
Rym: It was the best wallet.
Rym: The guy emailed us way back in GeekNights.
Rym: We reviewed that wallet.
Rym: And the dude emailed us immediately and was like, "Oh my God, all these people are buying the wallet because of your radio show.
Rym: How many Jimmy's do you want for
Rym: free?".
Scott: And I was like, "Zero.
Scott: I already bought
Scott: some.".
Rym: I was like, "Yeah, we all already own a
Rym: Jimmy.".
Scott: I should have taken up that offer because now, not enough Jimmy's.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, what's funny is, no one has a solution for the wallet.
Scott: There's so many wallets in Kickstarter.
Scott: None of them are perfect.
Scott: This was the least bad.
Rym: It's the best one.
Rym: The only fault I see with it is that it is not butt-sweat-proof like the plastic one is, which is the primary benefit of the Jimmy wallet.
Rym: It is butt-sweat-proof because leather wallets start to smell like a butt the longer you own them.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And the last thing I just want to mention is, I kickstarted this, I think it's done, is the Neo Lucida, a portable camera Lucida for the 21st century.
Rym: That is such a hipster Kickstarter.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: Do you know what a camera obscura is?
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So, what's a camera Lucida?
Rym: Isn't that the one where it makes the outline and then you draw on it?
Scott: So, this is basically a prism and you put the prism on a stick above your paper and you put your paper on the table.
Scott: You look, you aim the prism at like an object and then if you look down at your paper, you see, you know, literally that object on the paper and then you can draw whatever the object is.
Scott: So, you like aim it at a person's face and then suddenly you look at your piece of paper and there's their face.
Scott: It's, you know, it's like the light bouncing off their...
Rym: Instead of a piece of paper or a camera.
Scott: It's a little faint, but yeah, you can do that.
Rym: You're missing my point.
Scott: But it is, right?
Scott: But the point is that you draw, you have a pencil and a paper and you can draw while there's basically a picture of someone's face on there, but you draw right on it.
Scott: You don't need like a light box or tracing paper, any bullshit like that.
Rym: That's a cool thing.
Scott: Yeah, so it actually, it comes with, I've got it for only $47.
Scott: It actually, I get a full one that I can use and actually two extra prisms so I can make my own.
Scott: So we can have three.
Scott: All right.
Rym: But yeah, I'll just link to them if you want to see what we're...
Scott: It's the only way I'm ever going to be able to draw anything nice in my life.
Rym: One time I used tracing paper to trace this really good picture of a fighter jet and then I kind of penciled it in with some shading.
Scott: I also have the idea to basically aim it at a piece of paper and the piece of paper is on a Wacom tablet and then I can digitally draw someone or thing.
Rym: Ah, so you're going to get a Wacom tablet?
Scott: After I saw that video of that guy, he wasn't using it to draw, he was using it to, you know, touch up photos.
Rym: You know, you could bug out with it because she's got her old Wacom and it's pretty good, but she's thinking about upgrading.
Scott: That one's way big.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I need a way small one.
Rym: Why not just get the big one?
Scott: How am I going to carry that anywhere?
Rym: Oh, you're going to carry it around with you?
Scott: What would be, I mean, come on.
Scott: What's the point of something that can't move?
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: This is exactly what Tumblr is like.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: That's all I got to say about this.
Scott: That's it?
Rym: This is, we were driven, the only thing funnier than this was something I'm not going to link to from our previous YouTubings.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So I think I might have done this as a thing of the day a long time ago, I'm not sure.
Scott: But it's something new is, you know, combination remixes of Beastie Boys and Beatles.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So the first album was Let It Beast.
Scott: The second album was The Beastles.
Rym: I know we've talked about it, but again, I don't know if you use it.
Scott: There is now a brand new third album, Ill Submarine.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: 20 tracks, all new.
Scott: You can download all three albums on this link I'm giving you right here.
Scott: These are going to be filling my iPod and probably getting rotated for a week or two.
Rym: I'm checking that.
Rym: Even though I, because I'm finally.
Scott: Ill Submarine, come on.
Rym: I'm finally almost over my Chrono Jigga.
Rym: I'm not constantly listening to it.
Scott: You're not over, you're still Chrono Jigga-ing?
Rym: Well, like I said, I'm just moving beyond the Chrono Jigga.
Scott: I should go back to Chrono Jigga.
Scott: I know.
Rym: But no, I've gone back into Russian music for a while.
Scott: I've gone back to my summer K-pop.
Rym: Well, after that to everyday.
Scott: Everyday I'm drinking.
Rym: Everyday I'm drinking.
Scott: It's summertime, so I got all the energetic music.
Rym: I'm noticing some people we know getting into or getting back into Super Eurobeat just on Twitter.
Scott: That's always good.
Rym: And that is, I think, going to get me back into Super Eurobeat.
Rym: I forgot how much I like Super Eurobeat.
Scott: It's the best.
Rym: So yeah, Metamoment, the Book Club book.
Rym: We're doing it right now.
Rym: I have not chosen the next one yet because there is something I did want to choose, but Scott will be really mad if I choose it.
Scott: If you choose that, I've got a legitimate argument for why you can't choose that as opposed to just it's bullshit.
Rym: Oh, because it's obscure?
Scott: Because no one can fucking get it.
Rym: So, I'm going to look into how easy it might be to pirate it.
Scott: I'm searching for it on Amazon right now.
Rym: Amazon, Pirate Bay.
Scott: It's not too easy to get on Amazon.
Scott: You can get volume two.
Scott: But volume one, there's only 14 copies, I think.
Scott: Oh no, here it is.
Scott: You can sort of buy it on Amazon for $8.06.
Scott: Only three left in stock order soon.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: I'm kind of invested in reading this just because of the little art inside of it.
Scott: Yeah, we can go ahead and read it and even review it on GeekNights, but I don't think you can make it a Book Club book.
Scott: Oh, actually there's 59 copies, but even that's not enough.
Rym: Is it?
Rym: Because these kids don't read the books anyway.
Scott: A lot of those are used shady copies from who knows where.
Scott: They're not from Amazon.
Scott: There's only three that are from Amazon.
Rym: I ordered that used shady copy of The Prince of Nothing, and it was fine except that it smelled strongly of lox.
Scott: Yeah, you're going to pick a book.
Scott: It should be an in-print book that people can get.
Rym: We're going to be at Connecticut.
Rym: We're going to be at PAX Australia.
Scott: Really soon.
Scott: It's like a month away this year.
Rym: I know.
Rym: We're going to be probably at PAX Dev and PAX Prime.
Scott: Oh, snap.
Rym: And then MAGFest in PAX East.
Rym: And I guess Animate Boston, 2014.
Rym: And yeah, check out our internet.
Rym: There's lots of it.
Scott: We have a lot of internet to check out, and apparently some people like it.
Rym: Yeah, people have been joining the forum.
Rym: Though, if you submitted a submission to join our forum and we rejected you, that means whatever you typed in that field, I was personally not convinced you were not a spam bot.
Scott: Yeah, if you write something like, you know, I want to join the discussion.
Rym: No, that's a spam bot.
Scott: Yeah, you have to write something that convinces us that you're a human being.
Rym: Write like, I don't know, big old dick or something, or Rym and scot or gang.
Scott: Something that there is no chance a spam bot could have written.
Scott: For example, like, one guy wrote, "I went and saw your video of your, you know, 'Judge an Anime by its Cover'?
Scott: panel on YouTube, and I really liked it, so I wanted to check out your other
Scott: stuff.".
Rym: Yeah, probably not a spam bot.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think any spam bot in the universe will write that.
Rym: Yet.
Scott: Yet.
Rym: Right now, no.
Scott: One day, AI spams.
Scott: Someone will make an AI that his goal in life is to spam.
Rym: Then what?
Rym: I imagine in the culture, there could be spam.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: So, let's talk about the culture.
Scott: Alright, so you picked the book.
Scott: Right, so this book, I picked this book because, basically, why is my Kindle not turning on?
Scott: There we go.
Scott: When you read the description of this book, right, it is the, based on the description alone, the back of the book, paragraph, it is the most GeekNights' book.
Scott: a book can possibly be based on the description.
Scott: I cannot imagine a book being more GeekNights than this book, right, based on, you know, the bare summary of what happens, right?
Scott: There is a society called the culture that is pretty much GeekNights' paradise, and there's a guy in it whose only thing in life is to play games, and he has to go somewhere and play games in this weird other society where gaming, playing this one game, determines who will be emperor.
Rym: So, wait a minute, it's about two equally utopic places for people like us to live.
Scott: Precisely.
Scott: And what happens when the two come into conflict?
Rym: You know, I've read a lot of books that had utopias or futures, and very few fantasy worlds and science fiction worlds are places I would actually really want to live.
Scott: Yeah, there are many aspects of the culture.
Rym: I mean, Ghost in the Shell, maybe, but you know what, we're on that path anyway.
Scott: Yeah, I know, Ghost in the Shell is too real.
Rym: Yeah, Ghost in the Shell is like, wow, we're doing worse than that in a lot of ways.
Scott: Yeah, we are.
Rym: Or like, the Prince of Nothing, yeah, don't want to live in the world of the honey of unwashed anuses.
Scott: Yeah, no.
Rym: Lord of the Rings, yeah, everything probably smells like poop there too, unless you're elven.
Rym: Yeah, you know what, fantasy worlds, if I get to be an elf, I would rather live in them.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Rym: Granted, the elves always get overrun by some horrible thing and eventually after the rest.
Scott: Fine, Prince of Nothing, if I get to be the No God, I'll live there.
Rym: What do you see?
Scott: I see awesomeness because I'm a fucking tornado.
Rym: How awesome is that?
Rym: Well, no, you are an iron sarcophagus surrounded by a tornado.
Scott: Tornado's part of me too.
Rym: Maybe, we're not sure.
Scott: Dude, I have, either, we're evoking, fine, I have a pet tornado.
Scott: Not complaining.
Rym: That's not bad.
Rym: Tornado Mon, I choose you.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So, we're assuming from this point on that you have read Iain M. Banks' The Player of Games.
Rym: We're going to spoil the ever living.
Rym: fuck about it and we're not going to summarize the plot.
Scott: Let me summarize the plot for you.
Scott: Awesomeness happens, followed by awesomeness, followed by more awesomeness.
Rym: My immediate impression was that the main character is kind of a dick.
Rym: He reminded me of you.
Rym: To be perfectly honest, he reminded me of you in a kind of direct and immediate like, wow, this guy's kind of like Scottway.
Rym: Because he's kind of a dick, kind of a loner, really good at games, dedicated his life to games, doesn't like most games.
Scott: But I wouldn't cheat.
Rym: Yeah, he also wouldn't cheat and he only, he cheated once and even then when he cheated, he didn't cheat fully and his rationale for cheating was actually a really good rationale.
Scott: Eh, he's cheated.
Scott: I still wouldn't have cheated there.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Right?
Rym: Well, the reason I wouldn't have cheated there is because I wouldn't have trusted that fucking bot because that bot also reminded me of you.
Scott: Right, that was the weirdest thing is like, why?
Scott: What?
Scott: Obviously, they set up this drone to be a clearly obvious bad guy and it's like, why does he still hang around with it or even talk to it?
Rym: That was very clear.
Rym: He kind of liked that bot because Marwin Skell was more of a dick than him and would say the things to other people that he, for whatever reason, wasn't willing to say.
Rym: So he would just sit there and laugh as that bot just pissed everyone else off.
Scott: Yeah, but it also pissed him off too.
Scott: He wasn't immune from its attacks.
Rym: Yes, however, he enjoyed the bot messing with other people and he enjoyed pissing off the bot.
Scott: That's also true, yeah.
Rym: But Marwin Skell, I kind of like him.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, once you read the rest of the book, I mean, I kind of like him, but I didn't like him before the rest of the book.
Rym: But seriously, I called it that he was the narrator pretty much as soon as he said the word maestro.
Rym: Yeah, because he said maestro before.
Rym: And then when that interjection where it's like, hey, I'm the narrator at that first interjection, it was like, oh, there's a narrator.
Scott: And I was like, that's the freaking robot, obviously, drone, drone, not a robot.
Rym: But when he said maestro and in the past, immediately, I was like, all right, that guy is clearly also that other bot, especially because it was foreshadowed elegantly that the other bot was wearing a fake bot around it.
Rym: And then it turns out that yo dog, the bot was wearing a bot, wearing a bot, but that Ian M. Banks, I wish I had known about him before he died.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not like, you know, we're going to get the same number of books either way.
Scott: So from a selfish perspective, it doesn't matter.
Scott: It's just, you know, sad that a, a, we didn't have like a chance to maybe go meet him or email him or anything like that.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I'm sure he was at a convention we could have gone to.
Rym: touches were just elegantly done.
Rym: The foreshadowing was, I think, extremely apt and extremely subtle and extremely elegant.
Scott: I mean, everything about this book was done so elegantly in a way I didn't expect, but was so pleased with, right?
Scott: Like when he gets to the plan, he's playing all these games.
Scott: You don't get this.
Scott: He doesn't like devolve into a boring play by play of any games.
Scott: He doesn't like drag you through all this monotony in between.
Scott: He's fast forwarding over boring parts.
Scott: You only get the parts of the story that matter.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the way he describes the playing of the games, he really just really, you can get a feel for what's happening in the game, even though he didn't bother to make up any rules of the game.
Rym: He clearly took a full page from CS Forrester because he was like, he was like the progenitor of that style of writing about a thing.
Rym: You'll read a whole chapter and you'll feel like, you know exactly what happened.
Rym: But if someone asked you, you would be hard pressed to say anything that happened.
Scott: And I love how all the really great ideas he puts all over in the book, right?
Scott: I mean, he already had these culture, the ideas of the culture society from the previous book, you know, but it still counts.
Scott: He still came up with the great ideas, but there are other things that are introduced in here.
Scott: Like he talks about how like the triple sexed, you know, the three different genders and how they interplay in the society and how like the game has biotics in it.
Rym: So there's like biological physical pieces you play with in the game that you have to control specifically did serve one purpose to really drive home how complex and important to that culture that game is that they would devote that level of integration into a game.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But it's like just all throughout the book, this stuff like that, like, you know, just like the ideas of things to put into this world are things I wouldn't even come up with if an RPG was egging me on to come up with them.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Well, like it was such a tiny example.
Rym: The ship names and the names of people are the best.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's just everything is just so crazy.
Scott: It's like he maximized the creativity.
Rym: friends that are ships.
Rym: I like how ships are just people.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You're sentient.
Rym: You're a person.
Rym: But shotless is two friends are just read the instructions.
Rym: And of course, I still love you.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Rym: And then there's the other ship they meet later.
Rym: Kiss my ass and so much for subtlety or you're a ship.
Scott: What would your name be?
Scott: Oh, well, it should be your culture ship name.
Rym: So well, I need a generator thinking your culture ship name generator.
Rym: Well, I've been thinking at length about what my name would be in the culture and I haven't come up with it yet.
Scott: No.
Rym: But so I'm hard pressed to say, why do you have one that you're ready to rock on?
Scott: No, no, not at all.
Scott: But my favorite listeners tell us what our culture ship names are.
Rym: Well, I think people have similar names, really, because the different components of their names all mean something.
Rym: But notice how in our own real world history, there'll be names of things that mean something.
Rym: I like how in this world it's contemporary.
Rym: The names are in the contemporary language.
Rym: So gunboat diplomat.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, I mean, think about it.
Scott: You know, we have this weird thing in English, at least like someone's name is like something goldsmith or, you know, something, you know, carpenter.
Rym: You can bet your ass that at some point in that.
Scott: Yeah, that dude's ancestor was, you know, like someone baker.
Scott: It's like, yeah, your ancestor must have been a baker when you got your first surname.
Scott: And now Baker is just a surname.
Scott: People don't even think about the baking aspect.
Scott: It's completely separated in their mind.
Rym: But also it kind of implies that in the culture, parts of your name are given to you based on things you've done.
Scott: And you can make your name whatever you want, because it's a super free society.
Rym: But at the same time, basically hedonism to the man, people might not call you by one of your names if they perceive you differently, because if you're a dick, maybe they just start calling you shameless El Dico.
Scott: What are you gonna do about that?
Scott: Nothing, nothing you can do.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, and it's like, yeah, there's no laws.
Scott: You can just kill people if you want to kill someone.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like the blackmail.
Rym: Notice how the only thing he could blackmail him with, like the idea of social failing, the idea of being murdered by that bot basically didn't even enter his mind.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: He was just like, I hope he doesn't tell people about this.
Rym: But there was.
Rym: it's not like there.
Scott: And it's like, OK, yeah.
Scott: How's he going to prove I did it right?
Scott: He tells everyone he could just be lying, nobody, you know, and it's like anyone could manufacture evidence for anything because we have such high technology.
Rym: But then that bit was well done.
Rym: But that bit is why I assumed that that little bot was set up purely to be able to send him on this journey and make him do it all along, because so many of the pieces fit way too well,
Scott: especially when the when the bot and when whatever it more in scale, you knew he was like the troublemaker.
Rym: He was foreshadowed so heavily to be the troublemaker beginning when he was going to be the troublemaker who follows the guy with him, which is right, but not for the right reason.
Scott: But as soon as he disappeared, quotes disappeared and stopped making trouble.
Scott: You know that that was the set up and that the other.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: You know, now, at that moment, I didn't think at that exact moment that he was the bot for the rest of the story.
Scott: I thought it could be.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I wasn't.
Scott: I wouldn't have bet on it at that point.
Rym: I thought the contact just fucking killed him.
Scott: Could I?
Scott: That was a possibility.
Scott: I would have believed at that time.
Rym: And I like how when Morag got home at the very end, they had put that bot's body like on a plaque over the fireplace.
Rym: Yeah, shotless, I think, has the best sense of humor and it seems like the most pleasant dude to hang out with.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What do you think about the character that's barely in the book?
Scott: The Yay character is too awesome.
Scott: Yay seems like someone who is way hot and awesome.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's like, what was her purpose?
Scott: Her hymns, right?
Scott: Because everyone's gender changing in the culture whenever they want, because it's so awesome.
Scott: What was what was the purpose of that character in the book?
Rym: Yay would not have a physical or romantic relationship with Morag, because Morag was not interesting enough.
Rym: Morag had a hang up.
Rym: He had a problem.
Rym: He couldn't interface with people in a genuine way for whatever reason.
Rym: You know, all the stuff in the book after he the hero goes on his journey and comes back, he has changed and now they can get together.
Scott: It's a simple part of the story.
Scott: One thing I thought was really interesting is that opening scene where it's him and Yay basically playing advanced laser future tag.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which I really want to fucking play.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: And, you know, he was sort of looking down on these physical games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I was like, hey, you're like that nerd who looks down on sports.
Scott: This is the very beginning of the book here, like page one.
Scott: And I'm like, he's a nerd looking down on sports and she she respects sports as games.
Scott: I see what's going on here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'm like the end of the book.
Scott: I read page one already.
Scott: And I'm thinking the end of the book, he's going to have to play a sporty game and he's not going to like it, but he's going to pull it off anyway or something.
Rym: Yeah, but no, that's not what happened at all.
Rym: When that awesome diplomat who I imagined is being exactly like that elven ambassador in Ogloff.
Scott: Oh, that's exactly who I thought he was the whole time.
Scott: We thought the same thing because he is that guy.
Scott: He is that guy.
Rym: I love at the end.
Rym: They're like, yeah, he's not culture.
Rym: He's just this guy we know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: He's going to lead the revolution.
Rym: And that made me remember, remember way back when he first gets to his aunt and that girl is just like when like takes him aside and you never see her again because she's dead.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But it was all a setup.
Rym: Clearly he, this was all a setup to take down these out.
Rym: Right now.
Scott: This is the thing that gets me so even more excited about the culture, right?
Scott: Because like, yeah, the culture on the face value is an awesome paradise for people like us.
Scott: There's basically no laws.
Scott: that technology is super advanced.
Scott: Anyone can basically change gender, make anything.
Scott: There's just, there's.
Scott: no, you know, there's abundance of everything like that discussion.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: But the one is very similar to the star track where the guys like, but what if someone asked for something ridiculous, like their own planet and he's like, yeah, sure.
Rym: We'll give him 10 who cares?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's, it's very similar to the star Trek society, but perhaps even beyond that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, but right.
Scott: It's also Prince of nothing society because the minds that run the show are basically so advanced that they come before everyone else.
Scott: So even though they're all living lives of perfect freedom, hedonism, they're not, they're totally under the control of these minds in a perfect brave new world way where it's, you know, it's, it's the paradise of tyranny as opposed to the 1984, you know, uh, evil tyranny.
Scott: That's just overbearing and controlling you with fear.
Rym: But at the same time, a strong world person can still do whatever they want.
Rym: So they have total effective freedom.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Or at least total perceived agency.
Scott: The minds are so much more advanced than you are that unless you are one of those advanced minds, when I first read, you're not going to be, you know, I first read Hyperion and that was, that was the first sci-fi red.
Scott: What's the name of that thing?
Rym: And where the super advanced AI, whatever it is, forget the strike that bullshit where the super advanced AI and the humans got along.
Rym: Granted, we know how that turned out here.
Rym: Yes, they do get along and they augment each other actually.
Rym: And they work to each other's advantage.
Rym: They have different levels of perspective and they basically treat each other as equals.
Rym: And I love how the ships all just like talk to each other and they're just totally kind of chill and they just like playing games with the ship and just hanging out.
Scott: It's also, it's a little bit weird though, how they have these drones, which are basically manufactured people, right?
Scott: They're completely sentient.
Rym: Notice how they clearly have a sort of non-deterministic guided process for creating them.
Scott: Yes, but they also, each drone that is made has a purpose of like thing is supposed to do.
Scott: And even though they're free willed and sentient, they still do the task that they were built to do as if they were robots and they sort of like to do it and were made to like to do it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like, you know, he's calling up on his, on his, uh, what's it called?
Scott: His terminal, like, which I guess is an iPad, right?
Scott: Uh, you know, like, Hey, I need, I'm climbing a mountain.
Scott: Help me.
Scott: Or I'm falling.
Scott: Catch me before I die.
Scott: Or Hey, can you come check my house?
Rym: But it's implied that a lot of the lower level drones are not that intelligent.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: So there are still higher level drones that are saying, okay, I'll do this work for you.
Rym: But at the same time they sort of like doing it, but they're all cool, quirky and cool.
Rym: Like the, uh, the mind on the, on his, uh, where he lives, it's just like, yo dog, I was totally listening to that.
Rym: Sorry.
Rym: Uh, so what was that all about?
Rym: What's going on?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: We call what's up mind.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: How you doing?
Scott: And it really, the book, I wish I had my computer was a mind.
Scott: How awesome would that be?
Rym: The book shows you all these things about this world, but like the prince of nothing, it does not stop and force it on you.
Rym: It just on re it just unravels and reveals it over time by using the words contextually and just letting things go.
Scott: You know what it is?
Scott: It's the light that came before.
Scott: That's what it is, right?
Scott: The light that came before.
Rym: So is it just me or was the emperor empire of Azad, not just a thinly veiled allegory to modern day human society.
Scott: I think it was an unabashed allegory to modern day society.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: It was pretty failed.
Scott: There was no veil on that shit.
Rym: It is litterable.
Scott: I think there ever was a veil.
Rym: It was tossed on the floor.
Rym: The veil for less apt readers is, Oh, but they have three sexes and they're aliens.
Rym: It's totally different.
Rym: And they have this game.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But no, it's just human.
Scott: We have a game too.
Scott: You know what the game is called?
Scott: Democracy.
Rym: I did enjoy that scene where at the end was like, yo dog, I know you're going to go play this game.
Rym: So, uh, I'm going to show you just how fucked up this planet is.
Rym: just so you, uh, don't push out on the end.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And at the same time, it's obvious they were grooming him to win the game.
Rym: And then at the end, they're like, yeah, we want to take that empire down because they're assholes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, that's another great idea you put into the book that was just so creative.
Scott: The planet where the fire goes around the planet.
Scott: Who comes up with the idea like that?
Rym: Like in Hyperion, the planets with all the different cool, weird things.
Scott: But in Hyperion, how many could you come up with if I forced you to sit there and come up with them?
Rym: But in Hyperion, those kinds of things go nowhere and I'm disappointed in this.
Rym: It was awesome.
Scott: Well, you knew as soon as they described the fire planet and tell you what the situation is, you know they're going to get hit by the fire, right?
Scott: That's foreshadowed, but then they actually get hit by it and it's like, Oh yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But notice how there's, there's one thing I want to bring up about the game itself and how he was bored because games didn't mean anything and he could like playing a game with no stakes doesn't mean anything.
Scott: Well, and also he's probably playing settlers, which he had solved, but then, but he hadn't solved the game that he cheated at.
Rym: Oh, whatever.
Rym: Possession web.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, but then he goes to this planet and he's still not playing for any stakes except for recognition.
Rym: And he starts suddenly caring about the recognition they didn't care about before for a while.
Rym: But then when it gets to the point where they're like, yo, you can keep playing, but we're going to tell everyone in the world you lost.
Rym: He's fine with it anyway.
Rym: And he's now completely, just like he was before when he was unsatisfied playing the game for nothing, but yet because there are no stakes, he doesn't realize there are any actual stakes involved because no one will ever know.
Rym: In fact, at that point, he even knows that the people he's playing with know the deal with the culture.
Rym: So there's nothing happening.
Rym: And yet now he's wholly fulfilled as a person still playing the game for zero stakes.
Rym: And the fact that it actually was for the biggest stakes and they didn't tell him that, but yet the only way to get him to play was to show him how fucked up this world is.
Rym: So he finally realized he was playing for a personal stake.
Rym: I think he was playing for the personal stake of proving that he is better than these people.
Scott: Well, no, it's not only he is better than them as an extension of the culture and his philosophy is better.
Scott: It's like we are better than you.
Scott: The way your society is a bad society.
Scott: And he was.
Scott: he wasn't necessarily trying to prove it to them.
Scott: He was proving it to himself.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That is what I was getting to himself.
Scott: that, yes, the culture I live in, right, the way art, the philosophies and ideals our society stands for and the way it operates are better.
Scott: And I am proving it by winning this game.
Scott: And it goes and they go into describing, you know, they don't you don't know the rules of his odds still.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But he describes it like, you know, he is playing.
Scott: he's moving his pieces in a in a fashion that matches the way the culture would move those pieces, you know, like the top culture, you know, the way the the way the culture moves and expands throughout the galaxy is how is the same way?
Scott: he's expanding across the board and conquering territory, whereas the emperor is doing the same thing.
Scott: The emperor is trying to prove to himself he knows what the culture is all about.
Scott: He is proving to himself that no, except way as odd is is better.
Rym: That is not what the emperor was because he was playing.
Rym: He's moving his pieces the way as I know, but he was moving the pieces in that way, because remember how invested in the game to this almost erotic point Marat was?
Rym: And then the emperor comes to talk to him and the emperor didn't experience any of that.
Rym: The emperor was literally just playing so the culture wouldn't fuck his shit up.
Rym: He was playing as a representation of a Zadian culture solely because that is the culture that birthed him.
Rym: The earth peoples Azad Azad's.
Rym: He was not thinking in those terms.
Rym: Only Marat was thinking in those terms because Marat had nothing to win or lose, nothing to gain or lose.
Rym: He was playing to prove that he is better because he was the embodiment of the culture and the culture was the embodiment of him.
Scott: And if Marat had known what the stakes were, right, would he have played differently and perhaps failed?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Which shows, you know, the coming before of the minds in the way they played him, right?
Scott: The minds of the culture are playing a game that is the culture and they are doing the same thing to Marat that Marat was doing to pieces on the Azad board.
Rym: The book at multiple points makes it clear that they don't come perfectly before because they do leave things to chance on several occasions.
Rym: Now it's often inconsequential things, but even then they let the Zadian empire be bullshit for 70 years because they tried a bunch of other ways to take down other empires over these millennia and they were like, well, this one's weird.
Rym: Let's hold out until maybe we come up with a weird way to bring it down.
Scott: And that's how, right.
Scott: And that's what I'm saying is that, you know, he was playing Azad.
Scott: He's like, oh, make an attack here.
Scott: Oh, you know what?
Scott: That's a weird thing.
Scott: he's got going on over there.
Scott: I'm going to hold out and see how that develops before I make my move on it.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: It's like, oh, what's he, you could even think about this in terms of games we play in everyday life.
Scott: Like, what is Rym doing over there with that kingdom in T&E?
Scott: He's got like two greens, but he's only got his red leader in there.
Scott: No, this is something, the way he describes- I'll wait to see if he builds a monument or something.
Rym: The way the book describes playing games is, at least for me, exactly the way I feel when I play games.
Rym: That was so accurate to the feelings I have in my mind while I'm playing a game.
Rym: And like, Scott, you brought up those situations where I'm watching you do something that I don't understand and I'm trying to figure out, is he stupid or brilliant?
Rym: What the hell's going on over there?
Scott: Let's talk about some of the other games besides the big one against the emperor.
Scott: How about the one where he played against the guy for like the high stakes of castration, right?
Rym: And he was sort of like- I like how they were zero stakes for him.
Rym: Yeah, it's sort of like- In fact, the only concern with the culture was don't leave your dick behind.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: They might study it.
Rym: And he's like, whatever, I'll go back.
Rym: I mean, it's not a big deal.
Rym: And then you think he almost considered.
Scott: But the thing is he could have left his dick behind.
Scott: We found out later because they already knew.
Rym: Well, no, only the fewest, fewest people knew.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But who would have taken the dick if he had left it behind, right?
Rym: One or two tears down, you get the impression.
Scott: Oh, maybe.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Either way, right?
Scott: That was really interesting because at that point, he was so torn.
Scott: He's like, I could beat this guy who's not the worst guy.
Scott: You know, he had good parts and horrible parts.
Scott: He enjoyed playing with the guy and the way he described- But the guy was also a horrible person, but he was also good to play with, but he was also a good person.
Rym: The way he described his feelings toward that guy.
Rym: And I'm going to sound horrible is the way I feel towards certain people.
Rym: I play good games with that are not in my inner circle.
Scott: Oh snap.
Scott: It's so true.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You've had that experience.
Rym: You're playing a game with, let's say some guy at a convention or at a game night, or let's say at our wag, who is a perfectly capable player of games.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You can sit down and play a game with them and they will not disturb or upset you, but you know that when they go home, they are an awful human
Rym: and again, but while
Scott: they're sitting at that game tail, they are, they were completely personable and they play quickly and well and are a pleasure to have at the game table.
Rym: But it's another point where this book spoke directly to me personally, just because these are the experiences I knew when I read that description, this is the most GeekNights a book could be.
Scott: And it was right, a hundred percent right in that assessment.
Rym: I know.
Rym: But in terms of the games themselves, I mean, obviously I forget the order of the games, but one of them was basically- against the team with the cleric.
Rym: Well, we'll get back to that.
Rym: Oh, you're talking about the subsets of his odd or just the games in the beginning of the book where he's just talking on the train.
Scott: He plays.
Rym: one of them is clearly just basically Euchre and they're all just sort of, they're all the kinds of game theory games that we talk about in panels.
Rym: It doesn't matter about the details of them, but then notice how in those games, none of them involve to use a game design term from that Garfield book.
Rym: We, uh, fell eight.
Rym: so often he did.
Rym: the politicking doesn't exist.
Rym: All the games that the culture likes are the super pure games that we talk about.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But Azad, especially when Azad is that game, when it's one-on-one, but a lot of the rounds of Azad had the multiple players and the politicking came big, especially with that cleric who like came back and he was in and out, right?
Rym: Clerics played with all.
Rym: I noticed how he won all the individual games and then all nine players ganged up on him.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And then the girl talks about how everyone gangs up on the girl.
Rym: But in terms of the descriptions of the games themselves, it really came into stark light and they made a really good point at the end.
Rym: And this is something that bothered me the entire book until the end when something was said.
Rym: And then suddenly I realized that they'd strung me along the whole way.
Rym: So in the beginning he's playing these game theory games and he's pretty much the greatest gamer.
Rym: I mean, there are people who are better than him.
Rym: Like there's the chess master, but he's only really good at chess.
Scott: This guy is the games master.
Rym: He's good at games at their core.
Rym: But then they're describing Azad and he's having doubts and the game is so complicated.
Rym: The AIs are way better than him.
Rym: There's so much going on.
Rym: They set it up in this fancy world as being this ridiculously complex magical game.
Scott: Like you need a whole room to play this game and with multiple boards and things, you walk around the pieces and I said biological pieces, which I want to make a game of biological pieces.
Rym: At the very end, the robot with him was just like, yeah, we knew you'd win.
Rym: because I mean, all games are just made up of the simpler games and you've played all those simple games.
Rym: So duh, this game isn't actually that hard.
Rym: And it wasn't.
Rym: I like how the game actually, no, anyone who's reasonably smart just crushes everybody in that game.
Rym: I mean, he beat all the nubs and he only was challenged by the actually good players.
Scott: There was a little bit of initial D going on in there, right?
Scott: Or, you know, general Shonen fighting of like, yeah, he's Kenshiro.
Scott: He always wins.
Scott: But seriously, this next guy is the emperor who's won like fucking all the time.
Scott: And the only person he didn't beat was the previous emperor.
Rym: Yeah, because they keep setting you up.
Rym: He keeps thinking, am I missing something?
Rym: Am I missing something?
Rym: Which we've had that experience.
Rym: You're playing Puerto Rico and suddenly someone's doing something way different.
Rym: You're like, oh, am I missing something?
Rym: Am I missing something?
Rym: Then you win by like 30 points.
Rym: You're like, no, no, nothing.
Scott: I am just better than these.
Scott: But it's like, wow, that emperor must be really fucking good at this game.
Rym: I noticed that moment of doubt he had when the emperor is like, I'll have a surprise for you tomorrow.
Rym: He's like, what?
Rym: But I won mathematically.
Rym: What surprise?
Rym: Is he just stupid?
Rym: Did I miss something?
Rym: And then the surprise was, I'm just going to fucking flip the table over and shoot you.
Scott: Oh, and by the way, we have shields and our technology, you can't even shoot me.
Scott: We're so over that much better than you.
Scott: You can't even shoot me.
Rym: I really enjoyed the disparity in technology being not what happens in our world where the superior technology is just raping and pillaging and destroying everything.
Rym: The superior technology was also the good guys.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is very technology.
Scott: And it's, it's so superior.
Scott: It's basically just like laughing.
Scott: It's not like in the real world where it's like, yeah, we can bomb the hell out of someone who has weak technology, but we get on the ground and yeah, they kill a fuck ton of us with bombs and guns, right?
Scott: This is so laughable.
Scott: Like this culture could just walk around without any fear of any harm whatsoever.
Scott: Just mowing everyone down.
Scott: Like even more dangerous than like terminators in judgment day.
Rym: He has such a hard time just even experiencing fear.
Rym: He's like, should I be afraid now?
Rym: I wonder if I could die like, Whoa, dying.
Scott: Could that even happen?
Scott: And it's like dudes try to like give him drugs.
Scott: And he's like, I'm built in bypassed it.
Scott: I got drugs built in dude.
Scott: I wasted your drugs, man.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And also how he's so worried about, you know, the culture and this whole thing about, well, he's glanding and maybe that's cheating, but they'll let him use them anyway.
Rym: And then he gets there.
Rym: He's like, Oh, everybody's just using drugs, like injecting them.
Rym: Awesome.
Scott: It's like, they're all on roids.
Scott: I have a roid factory in my guts.
Scott: I don't need to eat roids.
Rym: Now, aside from the obvious social commentary that we're going to skip, because you should be smart enough
Scott: about gender and poverty and such and such,
Rym: how well it showed that even the gamer utopia, the perfect meritocracy of here is an objective 100% fair game that will perfectly test your skills.
Scott: It had politics in it though.
Scott: Right.
Rym: That was the main, but it is a society where politicking should matter in some sense, the game of facade, right?
Rym: As a whole.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But the fact that the game that you have, you have ostensibly a perfectly fair game that anyone who's smart enough could win, except that Pete, you know, women are, can't even get in the game.
Rym: Well, they can get in the game.
Rym: This is the problem.
Rym: No, they can, but here's the problem.
Rym: Everyone just that the game, this book does a good job of explaining to libertarian gamer grognards don't understand what privilege means that.
Rym: yes, everyone has a perfectly equal shot.
Rym: Even if you remove that politicking because Marat's like, why don't you just remove the politics?
Scott: I guess if that girl was as good at the game as Marat, she got into it.
Scott: She could have fended off nine at once.
Scott: All everyone ganging up on her.
Scott: Or
Rym: even then he makes suggestions like maybe you could remove ganging up and still have just the two on the one-on-one,
Scott: but
Rym: it doesn't matter because only the people already in power have access to the schools and the life where they can spend their entire for the, basically their entire life training to play the game.
Rym: The person who's working for a living does not have those advantages.
Rym: The game is still unfair.
Scott: And this is why, and the thing is this game is odd in particular.
Scott: It was not a game you could just, you know, you needed a whole court to learn how to play it right.
Scott: And all these advanced pieces and things.
Scott: So to even get a set of it.
Scott: It's not like chess, even New York City, a homeless guy can play chess in the park, right?
Scott: With basically some sticks and rocks.
Rym: And he has access to all the chess books in the library.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But in, you know, Azad, it's like if you were a homeless guy in Azad who is, you know, you couldn't even learn the game of Azad.
Scott: There was no way to even get pieces or anything.
Scott: You would just watch it on TV like it was.
Scott: It's like us.
Scott: Imagine if the game for America was NFL football.
Scott: It's like, yeah, I can watch it on TV, but I can't learn it from TV because you don't see the full picture on TV.
Scott: They don't show you the whole camera, the whole field, right?
Scott: Because that'd be boring, right?
Scott: You don't get to see what the coaches are saying.
Scott: You don't get to go on the field.
Scott: You need a ton of equipment and a giant piece of grass and all this referees and stuff to even try to play it.
Scott: There's no way to learn that game unless you are privileged enough to be like, go to high school and get on a team or go to a college and get on a team and so forth.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And as, whereas the culture, everyone has all goddamn day to do whatever the hell they want.
Scott: If they want to learn games, they can do that, which is why the culture is the best.
Rym: It's the situation of the Azadians by and large are the kind of the typical kind of gamer that doesn't really understand the core components of gaming.
Rym: It was kind of clear that when the politicking came up, they didn't really understand what politicking was, but Marat did.
Rym: And that's part of why he was able to win.
Rym: because he understood that that is a factor in multiplayer games because he understood what a game is.
Rym: And this whole culture basically didn't in the same sense that the real world, no one I play Puerto Rico with understands the lefty righty and the paper, rock, scissors, and the drafting.
Scott: That's how I played Puerto Rico.
Scott: Like Adam, let me have the role I wanted that he should have taken.
Scott: And I was pretty much at that.
Scott: As soon as I took that role, I was like, probably going to win because I'm gonna get a factory no matter what now.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And I got one and I won by a ton of points.
Rym: Good game.
Scott: And I sort of shut my mouth, even though you sort of said what was going to happen, but, but I wanted to let it happen so I could win.
Scott: But then it made the rest of the game boring.
Rym: You started to lose this before, then we kind of backed off of it, but I really enjoy more than all these personal touches, but on a more generic sense that the culture is willing to just fuck with other cultures.
Scott: Well, that's the contact part, right?
Scott: It's sort of like the inside the culture itself.
Scott: How much drama is there really that you could tell a story?
Scott: I love the story he gets when he's back home and they change sex and change back and made babies and had a party and someone got a full web and a few people were killed because there was this crazy accident and whatevs.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, no.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: You know, like, you know, when, uh, the drone is like, you know, threatening him, it's like, that's the most drama you can have here.
Rym: is someone being someone you cheated at a board game, right?
Scott: It's like inside the culture.
Scott: You can't have a story, which is why I think he introduces this contact aspect, which is basically the game the minds are playing with the universe.
Rym: I don't think that's why he introduced that mechanic to.
Scott: the contact is also in the first book, right?
Scott: It's all about, that's what I'm almost done reading the first culture book.
Scott: This is the second one.
Scott: You don't need to read any, any particular order.
Scott: And it's all about the stuff contact is doing.
Scott: Cause that's where the stuff.
Scott: you can write an interesting book for the real world that we live in.
Rym: It doesn't have to be because that's how you tell the story.
Rym: Another way to look at it is that look at the star Trek kind of scifi that most people read.
Rym: the super advanced benevolent culture always has this non intervention policy.
Rym: And a lot of people think that, uh, certain kinds of liberalism or progressivism in real world, current day politics means cultural relativism and letting everyone do what they want out there.
Rym: No, but no, the culture has a strong personal sense of morals that it recognizes is arbitrary.
Rym: And nonetheless feels perfectly willing when it sees something abhorrent, just fuck it up.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Which is the kind of they see some poverty and they're like, that shit is wrong.
Scott: Your culture is an awful culture as odd.
Scott: We are going to work to replace it with the cultures.
Rym: And we're going to try to replace it or at least bring it down.
Rym: So something good can take root in the least horrifying way possible.
Rym: We're going to try to minimize damage.
Scott: I mean, they obviously set up this whole resistance movement ready to go and they're willing to take their sweet ass time because I'm pretty sure those minds are immortal.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They got.
Rym: chambliss is ancient.
Rym: No one even knows how old he is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, he, she, it, you know, whatever he is in English, because we're not speaking their language.
Rym: He is the technically correct gender, neutral pronoun, whatever it is.
Scott: It's a drone, right?
Scott: It's, it's a sentient electronic being.
Scott: I wish I was one.
Scott: That'd be awesome.
Rym: There was some pretty horrific violence in this book though.
Scott: Well, I mean, you're talking like, you know, mostly castrations and people getting lasered.
Rym: I think the two points that really stood out were when, uh, the drone just unlocks the level three channel and doesn't even describe it.
Rym: He describes level one, level two and level three really leaves it mostly to your imagination.
Rym: And I love how he makes that point that Marat just kind of sat there watching it and then watched it a whole lot, but wasn't invested in it in that sexual way that the Azadians were.
Rym: He just watched it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But also when the vizier is the only way I'm going to describe that guy, Hamlin Jafar, when that guy's, when he's describing like that music might not be that good, but if you know what those instruments are made out of, you'll really appreciate it.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But Marat is, this is why I like the culture.
Rym: He is so horrified, but he's a gamer and he, that whole end section when, when even the drones like, yo dog, you're not, uh, you're not going native.
Rym: Are you like, maybe we should start speaking our real language again.
Rym: Cause seriously, but he just is smiling and pleasant.
Rym: When the guy says the thing about, you know, the femur extracted from the still living woman and he's like, so I guess they come in pairs and he's shooting at those animals, but he's missing on purpose and he's
Scott: just that
Rym: whole end, you get the impression he's just smiling at them and putting up this face in his mind.
Rym: He's thinking you fuckers, I'm going to beat you all your own game and then leave with my two middle fingers held high.
Scott: It's sort of what he does.
Rym: I'm going to win just to prove that you're all assholes.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I really liked this book.
Rym: What else can I say?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, you should read the one that comes before it.
Rym: Already going to read all the books that Ena Banks wrote.
Scott: So the book, the other book, just to give a preview of it, because obviously consider FLEBLIS consider FLEBLIS.
Scott: Basically what it's about is it's from, obviously it's a culture book one.
Scott: So it's still a completely separate story, separate characters.
Scott: There's no connection other than the setting, right?
Scott: So you don't, what order you read these in, I think has no, doesn't matter at all, right?
Scott: It's just how much you already know about the culture, right?
Scott: Going in.
Scott: So you assume going into this one, consider FLEBLIS, you know nothing about the culture.
Scott: And it's actually told from the perspective of, uh, an alien shape-shifty guy.
Scott: Who's not in the culture is philosophically opposed to it and is working for an alien race that is at war with the culture.
Scott: And it tells you, you know, basically he's on this mission to do something, uh, to basically recover this mind.
Scott: That's that like escaped and is trapped on a planet.
Scott: And he's, he's going to try to steal this mind, his culture mind for the aliens that are fighting against the culture.
Scott: And you learn about the culture from the outside, mostly interacting with, you know, contact and the war parts.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there's some culture people he interacts with and this whole thing goes on and on.
Scott: And it's pretty fascinating coming down to that.
Scott: You introduced everyone to the culture from the outside, as opposed to from the inside, like we got by reading books too first, but totally different.
Scott: look at it that way.
Rym: But I think in both of these books, the implied argument that the culture is superior is not hammered over your head.
Rym: It's just demonstrated by the course of events.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I think the other thing is it's really nice to read something that's utopian.
Scott: That's actually utopian.
Scott: It's not like all the cultures of dystopia.
Scott: The only dystopia of the culture that is shown in player of games is you may not have free will because the minds come before you, but that is no different from the real universe.
Scott: If physics comes before you.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So what's the worst thing that happened?
Rym: I mean, people die, but that's just reality.
Scott: Culture is only a dystopia for conservative people or more at was slightly bored.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It could be a dystopia in that way, but not for me.
Scott: Not for me.
Scott: Jesus Christ.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I'll say this.
Rym: I would have very, I feel like I would not be friends with anyone or probably I'm not friends with anyone who, if they read these books, would think anything about the culture, but hot damn.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I might be friends with you, but you know, yeah, but I might be leery to understand that I am very right.
Scott: I am philosophically right.
Scott: in line with if I could make a universe, the culture is extremely close to the universe that I would make and the society that I would make to live in very, very close, if not exact.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you disagree with that, then we have philosophical differences.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And hopefully someday we'll learn about ultra space.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: Well, there's a lot of ultra space.
Rym: He was like, yo, uh, I kind of don't actually know.
Scott: Consider Phlebas has a lot of ultra space going on and even ultra space, like, you know, the grid bombs that blow you up from ultra space.
Scott: And so, yeah, fascinating.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: For the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website@frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.