Rym: It's Wednesday, November 6th, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights coming to.
Rym: you live from ice cream prison.
Rym: Tonight we talk about the possible anime Renaissance that may or may not be happening.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: That sounds like something out of an adventure time.
Rym: what ice cream prison?
Rym: I Just.
Rym: I get this impression that you're clever.
Scott: the banana guards take your clever pump-and-dump stock scheme Clever.
Scott: it's an of the oldest scheme in the book.
Scott: I Suspect that it would only be clever if I somehow came up with something new that they didn't already exist laws to prevent.
Scott: I just get this impression that minimum security prison is not quite as fun as ice cream prison, dude I heard stories that are totally true about like you know white-collar criminals go into the lowest security prison.
Scott: We're basically you play ping-pong eat ice cream.
Scott: Just hang out.
Scott: all day You can even just like walk out and walk back in like there isn't even like bars or anything to keep you in and It's like being a house arrest in a kind of nice house.
Rym: Yeah, but what if you want to go to PAX?
Scott: You got packs probably not.
Rym: They're not gonna let you out to go to PAX.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: I'll just have to go to jail from between the two paxes.
Rym: I have a feeling if you go to prison as opposed to jail you're not gonna be there a short enough span.
Rym: do not miss At least one of the paxes.
Rym: four months All right.
Rym: So when you go to the sentencing be like look I'm guilty, but I can really only stay Serving my sentence in April and get out in August.
Scott: Thanks.
Scott: That'd be nice.
Rym: So yeah, it's Wednesday, and I just noticed that there is yet another initial d-movie coming.
Rym: it looks like Pilot video for something.
Rym: No one else is LD the new initial d-movie.
Scott: Is the initially manga still going?
Scott: is it over?
Scott: I actually don't know if I actually bought every volume of the initial d-monger released in English But they didn't finish it.
Scott: so I didn't finish it and I didn't go get scans lations or anything.
Rym: Oh the manga ended a couple months ago in July a few months ago, so there's.
Scott: no oh, that's nice But how am I supposed to get the rest of it scans lations or something?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: yeah I didn't even watch all a fourth stage like I as much as I didn't even watch the first movie.
Scott: I watched the initial state the first stage in the second stage, and I read all the manga that was officially legally released.
Rym: I watched that awful live-action movie.
Rym: It was.
Rym: we should review that on good nights, you know what reviewed it right now.
Rym: It sucks.
Rym: It is so bad.
Rym: But But the reason I bring this up is that I like initial D a lot because it's super dumb And it has eurobeat and cars.
Rym: Super eurobeat not just eurobeat.
Rym: I'm not gonna watch some eurobeat trash.
Rym: It's got to be super eurobeat.
Rym: I don't care.
Rym: This trailer or this pilot I guess Does not have super eurobeat music, but some other kind of music.
Rym: And well now while how is that?
Scott: it's not initial D.
Rym: now while the trailer does show this really cool manga looking shader that actually Looks real like the cars look really cool.
Rym: Unless someone makes some sort of fan edit that just plays running in the 90s on a loop in the background instead of this music I'm not gonna watch this movie.
Scott: The only reason to watch initially anime is eurobeat music.
Scott: without eurobeat music I don't even consider it to be initial D.
Rym: It's some sort of imposter D and to be honest all the initial D after season one.
Rym: No, unless you're really like me and Scott.
Rym: It's not that great.
Scott: Wasn't that great in season one cookie cutter bad animation.
Rym: season one at least has a Pretty good story arc for the main character.
Rym: It has that scene where he washes the car.
Scott: Yeah, that's about that bit.
Rym: at the end it season one is almost a show.
Rym: doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Scott: Okay, anyway, I'll miss it.
Rym: And one other very small thing for any of you who are dumb enough to not see Wolf Children yet in the theater You can go see it in the theater.
Rym: I'm linking to the anime news network thing.
Rym: But the tug is selling a bunch of tickets to showings with the idea that a certain percentage of the tickets have to be sold.
Rym: Or the showing doesn't happen.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So there's showings everywhere in New York in New York, but not oh my god, even Montana even fucking Wauwatosa, Wisconsin, Omaha, Nebraska, so literally the fuck middle of nowhere.
Scott: This is your chance.
Scott: people who live in the sticks.
Scott: the one time a city folk Will give some of our Kansas, Illinois.
Scott: Where the hell is that?
Scott: Delah, I never even heard of that place.
Rym: Oh, there's one in Huntsville, Alabama, but there's no tickets for that one.
Scott: Yeah, definitely don't go there.
Scott: Yeah, if you live there, I guess even if you live there just kill yourself.
Rym: I've been to Alabama was like when were you in Alabama?
Rym: I went to space camp.
Scott: That was in Alabama.
Rym: Yeah in Houston There's multiple space places.
Rym: I thought it was in Houston anyway, anyway, so Wolf children dub subbed and you can go see in the theater.
Rym: It is an amazing movie and you if you're an anime fan at all You should see this movie and it's worth seeing in the theater.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I think we reviewed it at one point.
Rym: Go listen to that episode.
Scott: Sure Okay, so, you know normally I don't just like to do kickstarters for news or whatever or something like that because it's sort of just Too easy and you could just do that all.
Scott: goddamn day.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I'm wearing my kickstarter belt and I gotta tell you it really sucks for all of you who didn't kickstart this belt.
Scott: Sure, but there is a particular kickstarter that is particularly fascinating right fan of graphics One of the best comic book publishers in the United States Publisher of graphic novels and books and all kinds of good stuff.
Scott: They I buy a lot of fanta graphics things that you do.
Scott: They are doing a kickstarter and it's strangely enough.
Scott: There's nothing on the kickstarter I actually want.
Scott: so I'm probably not gonna kick it but maybe I'll do the $1 situation.
Rym: I have never done the plus one kickstarter before.
Rym: I've only ever kickstarted to get a thing.
Scott: Yeah, there's really nothing I want.
Scott: Maybe I'll just do one.
Rym: I got to give a lot of money to be in puppycat even though I don't need any of those things just to give them More money.
Scott: Yeah, they're doing basically their entire 2014 spring season Kickstart 39 graphic novels and books.
Scott: So they're trying to fund right their Entire season of publishing via Kickstarter.
Scott: They have currently have 90,000 out of a hundred and fifty thousand with 28 days left.
Scott: I think they're gonna make it.
Scott: guys Yeah, you can get a lot of comics that you cannot get anywhere else or you know pre-order basically a bunch of stuff that may be signed or Who knows what right pretty much anything in the spring catalog?
Scott: So highly recommended if you are someone who cares about the indie comics in the u.s and you want I think fanta graphics had like a situation where like one of the top people passed away and That's the reason that they're basically doing it this way or something.
Scott: Oh, we'll see All right, so Yeah, this is like one of my favorite publishers.
Rym: So speaking of Kickstarters, it's close to its goal, but not there yet.
Rym: So since I mentioned it the bean puppycat Kickstarter one.
Rym: if you haven't watched be in puppycat.
Rym: It doesn't need a whole GeekNights episode to review.
Rym: just watch it.
Rym: It's on YouTube.
Rym: the whole thing.
Scott: It's good.
Scott: I like it.
Scott: I just don't like it as much as adventure time Or bravest warriors.
Rym: I if I had to put them in order for me it's adventure time being puppycat.
Rym: Bravest warriors.
Scott: the bravest warriors has this totally freaky.
Scott: What the hell is going on with this emotion?
Rym: Oh, don't get me wrong like Warriors horse other dimension.
Rym: We're talking about if this is a terrible secret of space.
Rym: if this is the graph of things I like they're like millimeters apart from each other.
Scott: I'm just saying being puppycat is behind for me because it lacks the terrible secret of space.
Scott: if it somehow gets a terrible secret of space then maybe It'll elevate so the terrible secret of the monster inside of Puppycat and the warlock quite as mysterious as the emotion Lord and he's it's himself from the future Coming back to visit in there.
Scott: Yeah, they're where their parents go.
Rym: That's really really straightforward.
Rym: Anyway, these things are all great.
Rym: Refrigerator is great and the bean puppycat Kickstarter as of now is about four grand shy of its goal and only has about seven days Left to go.
Rym: Also.
Scott: What is up with them and combining animals?
Scott: puppycat cat bug.
Scott: What's what's next?
Scott: What's next seriously?
Rym: Whatever the series they come up with next is well Scott you realize that was a big part of the original avatar.
Rym: Fuck it.
Rym: You never watched avatar did you?
Scott: bravest warriors has two of them and has cat bug and impassa bear Impassa bear.
Rym: I like the best simply because of his gas-powered stick But you never watched avatar, right Because in that world every animal is actually to a combination of two animals every single one to PB.
Rym: So there's one point.
Rym: I forget what I think was a bear.
Rym: They're like, oh that's a bear and someone's like a bear.
Rym: what like?
Rym: I think it's just a bear and they're like, that's weird.
Scott: So if every animal in their whole world is a combo of two animals Why would how could they even know about a single animal?
Scott: those would be single animals to them?
Rym: Ah now in the past I would have pointed that out just like you have but having watched all of it and having thought about It there's a pretty easy answer if there's bear cat bear wolf bear lion and bear owl as opposed to all bear Then
Scott: from
Rym: that set of combined animals you can extract using Algebra the bear part.
Rym: So you could you could basically Reverse engineer what a bear is from the fact that there are so many animals that are bear something By Kate taking the combined and median of those animal.
Scott: Okay, sure, but let's let's pretend in the real world right eagle?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, so let's say you see an animal somewhere.
Scott: What animal would you consider to be?
Scott: an eeg?
Rym: But that's just one animal Right, but it Alright, but to you right to them It would also be one animal because I live in a world where every but they noticed that bear lion bear cat bear dog And bear rat have these sort of fundamental similarities.
Rym: So they gave them all the same name bear something as opposed to cat something.
Scott: well eagle and Eeg.
Rym: At some point you should watch that show.
Rym: it's actually worth watching.
Scott: catfish and catfish and goldfish have similarities.
Scott: so what would you consider to be a gold?
Rym: What about sea lion?
Scott: Yeah, what about sea lion?
Rym: Not much like a lie.
Scott: Anyway, what would a sea look like?
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: Our good friend Judith you may know her from the internet shared this with us.
Scott: Normally, I saw it before she shared it.
Scott: cuz I'm all internet II.
Rym: I saw it from her and other.
Rym: because I don't check my Twitter Constantly.
Scott: I check it constantly.
Rym: I saw it from multiple sources My brain and I did not analyze where it came from first.
Rym: But this is kind of amazing in that if this were a show I would watch it only if one The characters never spoke dialogue and two music like that was playing the entire time.
Rym: This needs like a 26 episode treatment.
Rym: This is just my little pony.
Rym: friendship is manly and That slow-mo walk in and then when Pinkie Pie like makes that gesture with his hand hurt its hand enter my door.
Rym: It's.
Rym: it's so perfect.
Rym: Few things are in my wheelhouse as much as this thing is sure.
Scott: Okay, so anyone who doesn't know Recently was like a week ago.
Scott: ish maybe a few days ago was the YouTube Music Awards the first ever, right?
Scott: I guess they're trying to compete with the Grammys or something like that.
Scott: Who knows every award show is the high school award show, right?
Scott: That's how they say it.
Scott: But the YouTube Music Awards was somewhat unique in that number one.
Scott: The award show itself was even more high school award show and if you'd actually watched any of it Which I watched barely any of it a lot of cringe-worthy activity going on there just sort of like it.
Scott: but The awards were not given out by some sort of record industry vote or anything like that.
Scott: It was primarily done by fans sharing videos and the way it worked is for each nominee in each category You there was a specific video uploaded to YouTube and the more that specific video was shared that basically counted as a vote.
Scott: So if you went and found the video of the one you wanted to vote for and shared it on Twitter or shared it on Google+ with the YouTube share button that counted as a vote.
Scott: so we're gonna see basically who has a the biggest fan base or B who has the craziest most dedicated fan base.
Scott: that is going to you know, vote the most times and interestingly enough right girls generation 1 by a Hojillion share.
Scott: if you look at the numbers that people have posted in various places they won by some gigantic enormous amount compared to like super famous people who are actually known in North America Yeah like Lady Gaga and whatnot Right.
Scott: and this video is hilarious because she Tiffany goes up to get the award and the audience is like what?
Scott: Like they're not even clapping.
Scott: They don't even know what?
Rym: I remember a time when this crazy Korean song about Gangnam style was making the rounds and normal people.
Scott: Funny enough sigh was a competing nominee with his gentleman video.
Rym: Yeah, which not as good as Gangnam style though Good.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: I like it too, but not as plus that video.
Scott: the girl in that video is song got in.
Scott: who is the awesomest anyway?
Rym: But remember when Gangnam style became the most popular video on YouTube or the most watched video on YouTube By such a ridiculous margin.
Rym: normal people who noticed that it finally got past all these Bieber videos Didn't understand they were like.
Rym: what the fuck is this Korean thing?
Scott: Those are TV people not internet people.
Scott: right the kpop has the sort of unique thing into where it's like sigh.
Scott: Why did he become crazy popular?
Scott: because he put his video on YouTube his YouTube channel, right?
Scott: It's like these people.
Scott: they just put all their shit on YouTube and they don't give a fuck.
Scott: you can embed it Unlike that vivo nonsense, right?
Scott: They can do everything.
Rym: Yeah, Gangnam style has got almost 2 billion views.
Rym: Yeah billion.
Scott: something interesting is that you know the What's it called this this particular girls generation video.
Scott: while it's not like their best song or anything even fans will tell you It's not their best song or anything, right?
Rym: Or anything.
Scott: Yeah, the it was in terms of the rate of watches like when it first went up.
Scott: It got like something like the rate of what you know.
Scott: views immediately I think is the fastest ever to like, you know reach some point or something, right?
Rym: Well, that was the most.
Rym: it was the fastest whatever to something something basically people were.
Scott: so I forget the statistic was because they can't find it right now.
Scott: I was typing in and trying to find it and I couldn't.
Scott: but basically in terms of you're measuring like how Rapidly all the fans immediately watched it, you know in terms of the time it went up, right?
Scott: They all jumped on it to watch it immediately, right which shows, you know, the fan base for the kpop is so rabid right.
Scott: And that's why they won this.
Scott: because basically people are sitting there spamming shares.
Rym: Yep, but the reaction Scott and I were looking at this before the show the reactions of people who were like what some Korean thing What the fuck?
Rym: What about my Bieber?
Scott: Yeah, basically the YouTube comments are hilarious because you can see.
Scott: basically these North American people have no fuck clue What this is because they don't internet.
Scott: but it's like look first of all, you don't internet So you don't know what the hell this is.
Scott: and to you realize that you know, they're bigger in Asia than beaver is here.
Scott: Yeah in Asia, there's like three people to every one person in North America.
Scott: Nevermind welcome to the world.
Rym: never mind the fact that there's not a worldly human.
Rym: There's a not insignificant number of people in America and North American English speakers who also do know what it is.
Rym: Yep, because they're internet people and are probably more fans of that than they are of Miley Cyrus or whatever.
Rym: This reminds me so much of Mike tool.
Rym: whenever soccer is on TV in the u.s He retweets because what happens is it?
Scott: basically what happens in the u.s Is if football is on but where you live doesn't get any football games or an NBC only has a football game at night.
Scott: So during the football times on Sunday between 1 and you know 8 or 7 Certain channels NBC and even CBS or Fox if you don't have a football game in your area Where it's blacked out or who knows what you're gonna see soccer.
Scott: That's what they show.
Rym: but Mike tool will retweet these people who are saying basically the fuck Soccer on TV.
Rym: What how oh my god, like they can't believe that soccer is on TV.
Scott: Yes Why don't you come person who lives in the sticks and has never seen soccer to the park near my house?
Scott: Over in the flushing where oh my god It's completely 100% filled with people playing soccer every moment where no one is working All the time every day all day and they're gonna even build like a soccer stadium there They want to anyway because there's so much soccer this
Rym: moment.
Rym: that Scott's thing of the day is actually kind of important because it should.
Rym: basically, we know that there's a disconnect between sort of standard pop culture and internet pop culture, but it Really shows the Extreme starkness of that divide that I don't think.
Rym: is that apparent to a lot of people?
Rym: No, I mean a lot of people I know Literally had never heard of Miley Cyrus.
Rym: Like there's this.
Rym: there's no connection between and actually when we watch the contenders and these awards I actually did not recognize some of those groups.
Scott: No People or whoever they have that video you watch didn't show all the nominees.
Scott: But this what this I think to keep in mind this is the top award video of the year.
Scott: This wasn't like one of the you know, there's a prestigious award.
Scott: Well, it was the top award at the show like winning, you know best movie at the Oscars Like it's the was the top award you could possibly get at this place.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: But yeah, it's relevant to you know The anime people because anime is much like kpop almost entirely an Asian but also Internet, you know fandom.
Rym: So think about the things you learn from this one.
Rym: Anime is still made primarily for Japan not for you, right?
Scott: But despite the fact that anime is busy hidden from the normal pop culture, right?
Scott: It's as hidden in the pop culture as much as kpop is right it is Ginormous it.
Rym: anime is bigger than you think it is But it's only big in the sovereign nation of the internet and Asia.
Rym: Yes And parts of France perhaps.
Rym: so in the meta moment, I got two auspicious emails just now Ogre shipping one of them.
Scott: I noticed cuz you didn't have your ogres.
Scott: That's what the only thing could possibly be - am I right?
Rym: Well - am I right?
Rym: You're right.
Rym: Oh One of them is a FedEx notification saying that a 28 pound package is on its way.
Scott: to my other one says Rym Here is your word delivering to you a table that will take up your entire living room.
Scott: So you can actually use that.
Rym: I'm just waiting for my doorman to call and be like, yeah, there's uh, there's a tank down here.
Scott: Actually, it's a box full of tanks.
Rym: You need a you need a hand cart You need a Humvee.
Rym: you want it?
Rym: Do you want to purchase a storage room just to put it in without taking it?
Scott: Is gonna let you borrow the thing that moved the space shuttle so you can move these tanks around?
Rym: I don't know if I'll ever even open or play this game.
Rym: This was like the Legacy.
Rym: I know I bought this because there wasn't much on Kickstarter back then.
Scott: I didn't buy it on purpose cuz I knew better.
Rym: Ah, we'll play it at some point.
Rym: Yeah, what maybe?
Rym: yeah, and also I got my invite from Scott for Google Glass just now.
Scott: Oh nice.
Scott: Yeah, so you get it.
Rym: I'm gonna get it even if if the prescription thing doesn't work immediately I'm gonna do.
Rym: I saw a bunch of facts on people who wear normal glasses and the titanium band like on top of them as Just a ghetto hack until the prescription lenses arrived.
Scott: They would told me that they would email me when they invited you and I don't have any.
Rym: they just emailed me like Just now I should get this automatic email.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: together I only have seven days like you've got seven days to click on this and give us a giant pile of money.
Scott: I only had 14 days to click on the invite thing.
Rym: Yeah, but I also might just go get contacts.
Rym: Just I've never done the contacts.
Scott: Can I poke you in the eye?
Rym: No, you cannot poke me in the eye.
Scott: I'll poke you in the eye.
Scott: Anyway,
Rym: you know, it's kind of a crazy aside but I realized recently cuz you know, I bike a lot and bike in my whole life and that's got bikes and Emily bikes and I Realized that I've never in my life Had to deal with the problem of going so fast that there's wind in your eyes and you can't see like.
Rym: I never even thought Of that as a problem.
Scott: I don't deal with that problem.
Scott: I deal with the problem of there's shit getting in my eye from going too fast.
Scott: Well, especially in like Brooklyn even like, you know, just small bits of who knows what right?
Scott: Well, like just get on my face and whatever.
Scott: So I that's why Google glass comes with shades and shields.
Scott: The shield is a piece of just clear plastic.
Scott: You can put on the Google glass to just shield your eyes So that that doesn't happen.
Scott: if you want to say bike at night when sunglasses would not be a good idea.
Scott: You know the shades.
Rym: Oh Looks like seven train just went down too.
Rym: So great news everywhere.
Rym: Anyway metamoment the book club book is I do do By William Gibson.
Scott: I've already cyberpunk classic of all time greatness.
Rym: No, all right.
Rym: I'm on easy mode cuz I already read it.
Scott: I got it up on my Kindle.
Rym: I'm gonna continue The the sixth of the books that I read while I was waiting for Scott to read Stasi land And after I finished that I'll probably read it.
Rym: I think Well, yeah, it's idle right as in virtual idols, so don't Japanese people say that as I do.
Rym: Yeah, but read the book.
Rym: Okay, you read your show read your show.
Rym: Other metamoment we're gonna be at mag fest doing a bunch of stuff.
Rym: Actually, let me look at these schedule and see if anything is set in stone.
Rym: yet We are also going to be at PAX East I assume.
Rym: Oh, yeah with a brand new lecture.
Rym: If you wanted badges, it's already fucking sold out.
Scott: don't even try all bad He's just only talk about conventions you can go to and the only one you can go to that You should go to in the immediate future is mag MAGFest MAGFest MAGFest mag.
Scott: If you're not at mag fest, what the fuck is wrong also?
Rym: Connecticut is not for Australians might have an excuse not to go to mag fest while Connecticut is a long ways away.
Rym: Panel submissions are open.
Scott: motherfuckers I'll be a last submission.
Rym: if you enter your submissions now, and I just got three of them a little while ago Me and Scott and another person the eggs will be looking at them like now.
Rym: We're already thinking about what.
Rym: why don't you read one of those submissions?
Rym:  all right here are the last three submissions.
Rym: Oh God God, okay, okay, so guys I really need your submissions.
Rym: We got the homestuck deathmatch.
Scott: I hope there knows people aren't listening to this podcast.
Rym: We got the homestuck dating game Oh, and we got Oh Sherlock Holmes to the ages.
Rym: I was pretty cool.
Scott: That sounds really good.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: We so one-third of our submissions are quality.
Scott: Please submit three times as many submissions as you sent in last year.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: The homestuck deathmatch is literally Our barge episode.
Rym: are not not the barge episode our deathmatch.
Rym: remember we did that nerd fanboy death.
Rym: Yeah So it's that but just homestucks And I can't.
Scott: I don't think we can see yesterday.
Rym: and also if you want us to do the most epic homestuck panel ever Tell Zenkaikan to accept it.
Scott: Oh, no All right, that's all Rym.
Rym: Scott and I Rym all Rym Have a homestuck panel we put together.
Rym: We just need our friends at zinc icon to accept it and we will totally do it all.
Scott: Rym.
Rym: It's a what I want to have a conversation about.
Rym: homestuck great who?
Rym: why?
Rym: why would that worry?
Rym: You at all?
Rym: Yeah, also check out our awesome new forum and all our videos.
Scott: This is on the internet.
Scott: Our forum is pretty all the places that we live on the internet.
Rym: our forum is pretty badass and you really should be a part Of it and you should help pay for it.
Rym: Yeah, we'll figure out how you can pay for it soon.
Rym: We haven't quite put that together yet.
Rym: So we noticed something and I'm not sure if it's a real trend or not But I think it's worth talking about because so many other people are talking about it.
Scott: This is Rym show idea.
Rym: So I remember I'd I would happily defer at any point to your show idea.
Scott: my non I have no show ideas.
Rym: All right, so we'll just sit here for another 30 minutes doing nothing.
Rym: So when Madoka Magica came out it caused this sort of Rekindling of interest in anime but only among a certain subset of anime fans Like.
Rym: I noticed that people like me and Scott and people who either have a sort of professional interest in the anime industry Because they're journalists or something or people who are just like really into anime and watch a lot of anime.
Rym: All of those people who might not have watched a lot of things very recently Watched Madoka and it's sort of like they watched it when even though they weren't otherwise watching anime.
Rym: But then after Madoka was done, they pretty much just spent the next year Complaining that nothing good came out since Madoka and re-showing Madoka to people who hadn't seen it yet.
Rym: So it caused this like it was like a tinder but then it faded out didn't even smolder.
Rym: Then attack on Titan happened and I ignored attack on Titan like I ignore all new shows that come out.
Rym: But people kept talking about it.
Rym: people kept saying it was good people kept watching it.
Rym: I kept getting Fullmetal Alchemist vibes.
Rym: So we watched it and it was exactly what people said It was.
Rym: it was actually pretty awesome.
Rym: You might remember a review of it.
Rym: And what I've noticed is that a lot of people Who used to who say they used to be anime fans and I hate the other this whole idea that Anime as opposed to other kinds of media, but I digress a lot of people who said that they used to be into anime But then they stopped watching it for whatever reason Started watching it again because of attack on Titan like they went and got accounts on crunchyroll to watch attack on Titan because all their friends told them to watch attack on Titan and It started causing this cycle and suddenly a ton of people were watching anime again.
Rym: And I think a secondary thing happened to where I think a lot of those people Started watching crunchyroll to see attack on Titan and as soon as it ended They'd kind of gotten used to watching anime again, and it just so happened that there's quite a few not terrible shows Also coming out on crunchyroll that they could just watch
Scott: right?
Scott: It's like if you and this isn't like, you know, a lot of people posted like, you know about the moe Plague or whatever red specter right and they were showing stuff like well, look, this is always existed.
Scott: go Here's an example of you know, horrible moe from a long time ago.
Scott: It just looked different, but it's always been there.
Scott: It's not a new trend, right?
Scott: That is not true.
Scott: go and look at like, you know, the season sheets, right all anime from a particular season All on one piece of paper, right?
Scott: You know the same way those they make those JPEGs and look at it for years in like the 70s and the 80s and you Know what you're gonna see.
Scott: it won't be mostly filled with moe.
Scott: There might be something on there that you can consider an old moe or something like that, right.
Scott: or you know some old fanservice show.
Scott: they existed but What you will find more often is legit shows that might have a little fanservice like some tank police And you'll find mostly kids shows.
Scott: if you look at the season sheets now There's only a few kids shows and some things that look like kids shows may also be moe shows.
Rym: You may recall our episode.
Scott: Number of shows that are purely fan service and whatnot are Greatly increased right and the number of shows that are of interest to anyone who's not a pervert are greatly decreased.
Scott: But if you compare say this season to a few seasons ago There is a noticeable slight increase in things that you know.
Scott: People who are not small children or perverts might actually care about and might actually be good.
Rym: now There have been little bumps like this and pretty good.
Scott: It's not it's not a complete like oh my god All anime is great, but it's like oh, there's actually some animes to watch.
Scott: now, you know for a cute few years They were basically no anime that I that were new that I cared about at all.
Rym: now There were a couple of years a couple of seasons where there were a few good shows like we have now We have this trip like a show and then another show right is like Monica.
Rym: That's a show but there was a perfect storm.
Rym: Monica came out but there wasn't a lot else coming out around the same time.
Rym: that would Continue to smolder or there'd be a cluster of pretty good shows, but no blockbuster.
Rym: But suddenly we had this perfect storm where attack on Titan happened.
Rym: It got it was in a wide enough appeal to get a lot of people watching anime again, and then a lot of those people stuck around Because there were places for them to go.
Rym: I mean remember Monica ended and we were like, oh my god Let's watch more anime and there was nothing good.
Rym: and then we started watching old anime again.
Scott: But there is still.
Scott: there is some B tier shows that are sort of hiding underneath that are getting some views, right?
Scott: So people come for the attack on Titan in the kill la kill.
Scott: rich are saving anime.
Scott: Space dandy is gonna follow it up.
Scott: So yeah, we see some sustaining going on here, right?
Scott: They're keeping the will alive with a few shows but in between it's like well look how long space brothers have been going.
Rym: Oh, it's actually really good.
Rym: Yeah this eccentric family.
Rym: Wow, that's not like anything I've ever seen before.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there's these like second level of shows underneath to sort of wait around in.
Scott: you know While you're waiting for the these top tier shows to sort of keep the spirit alive.
Scott: The thing is will it keep going after space dandy?
Scott: space dandy is gonna come out in the u.s Before it's gonna come out in Japan.
Scott: How crazy is that shit?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well that happened with big o2 I guess sure and the Trigun movie really only happened because of the international audience.
Rym: But it's it's interesting right?
Scott: Trigun movie never saw it.
Rym: Yeah, I have it okay I've had it since it.
Rym: when it came out I got a copy of it with translations immediately and I never felt the desire to watch it that much Even though I really like Trigun sure.
Rym: But what's really you know, I the reason I thought of this and I was thinking about more and more like why this happening right?
Rym: Now is that I have a lot of friends, you know We have people in the front crew and people we know really in anime.
Rym: Like we all went to RIT which is like the anime epicenter and you know The biggest anime club.
Rym: like there's a lot of really big reasons why anime fandom had a huge sort of stronghold in Rochester, New York because of the RIT anime club and Most of the people I knew had weren't watching anime anymore who were a big part of that.
Rym: They were as into anime as we were like that deep every weekend marathoning shows like Ava and Eska and all these things and they kind of just stopped watching and They didn't know Madoka existed or was good.
Rym: This past weekend two good friends deeply into anime Never didn't even know the the deal with Madoka.
Rym: So we showed it to him.
Rym: They're like, oh fuck.
Rym: Oh, hey Maybe we should watch anime again.
Rym: But the reason that they they they they didn't say oh where you want to watch Madoka like, oh, let's watch Madoka.
Rym: I showed that to them the anime they brought up.
Rym: They're like, yeah, we're gonna start watching anime again was attack on Titan.
Rym: Yep, so why your attack on Titan get such a wide appeal that Madoka did not Mmm, like.
Rym: what's the difference?
Scott: Just the way it looks right Madoka.
Scott: I you just look at you.
Scott: It's a magical girl.
Scott: Sure You're not gonna watch that.
Rym: I mean we ignored it until people we trusted said guys It's not what it looks like.
Rym: lots of people said I mean my little pony guys.
Rym: It's not what it looks like.
Scott: Watch it Yeah, but now there's a lot.
Rym: kill is right.
Scott: exactly what attack on Titan space dandy You don't need to tell someone it's not what it looks like.
Scott: It is what it looks like.
Rym: Exactly, right?
Rym: Kill-by-kill.
Rym: you watch the first five minutes of that.
Rym: You're like this show is exactly what it professes to be.
Scott: Yep It's like you don't you know?
Scott: and you know people who aren't there's.
Scott: there are people who like anime.
Scott: they will watch it All right, they watch the big shows, right?
Scott: They don't they're not gonna.
Scott: they're not those crazed anime fans that actually like our anime is our primary geekery and they watch all The animes no matter what it's like.
Scott: they just like anime and they watch the big shows and we're sort of in that category.
Scott: We're a little deeper than that.
Scott: But most people I know, you know, anime is not their primary geekery, but they all like it They all know about it.
Scott: They're fans of it and they watch the big items, right?
Scott: And if there aren't any big items, they don't watch anything.
Scott: and now there is actually.
Scott: you know It's like you don't want to start saying that like three to four items is suddenly a trend But sadly three to four is bigger and more than we've had in the past year or three.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we've been watching a lot of anime lately and while we've watched all the big shows that were important that have come out Along I'm actually not paying for Netflix anymore, but I am paying for crunchy roll.
Rym: Yeah, who would go back to Scott a year ago two years ago?
Rym: That would not have been the case.
Rym: Hell no And I'm curious where this is going to go.
Rym: Yeah, that's really all I got.
Rym: I think it's worth paying attention to the fact that just recently and I think attack on Titan is the Primary academia Kickstarter.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of things happening, but I think attack on Titan is the cause.
Rym: I think it is the spark that caused this interest even though there were better shows that came out Not that long before attack on Titan.
Rym: attack on Titan had that full metal alchemist sort of.
Rym: People don't like.
Rym: they like the characters.
Rym: the characters are iconic But the world building and the secretive space or what they're there for the cliffhangers They they gotta know what the fuck happened.
Rym: So they get drawn in and they watch every episode just to know what happens next.
Scott: I don't want to go overboard on it and be like anime is saved But I just want to say there's some rays of hope shining through and that I have not seen for a while.
Scott: It has been a cloudy sky Right.
Scott: Let us see if these rays continue to shine or if the clouds just cover that shit up in a year.
Rym: But I think I can express why attack on Titan had the effect.
Rym: It's like I was saying.
Rym: it's got the cliffhangers the driving driving pace, but unlike other shows that have hooked people in before People care primarily about the world side of it and it's actually pretty accessible.
Rym: There's nothing too deep or difficult to figure out about what attack on Titan shows you.
Rym: Yeah, there's no complex adolescence allegory going on.
Rym: So it's accessible but simultaneously at the end of every episode.
Rym: All you're thinking about is what happens next.
Rym: I gotta know what happens next.
Rym: So it got people to not just watch it.
Rym: I mean a lot of people would watch Madoka later and just watch the whole thing.
Rym: It got people to watch episode 5 and then wait until episode 6 and watch it immediately.
Rym: the day it came out watching it live mattered.
Rym: and the reason it mattered is because it had this critical mass of Anime fans and anime fans are mostly on the internet.
Rym: The whole spoiler Discussion culture is a big driver.
Rym: people want to see the show as soon as possible.
Rym: one to avoid spoilers But two more importantly the real reason to be involved in that conversation Every week of whoa.
Rym: So what do you think's gonna happen to Levi now?
Rym: And that's the thing that we used to get at RIT anime because we'd all watch these old shows together that now You don't get with anime fandom because you tell someone hey, you should watch Madoka I've already seen it a week later if they've watched all of it and then you talk about it But you never have that.
Rym: it's very rare to have that moment where you and someone else are watching an anime that has a driving plot at the same time and have seen the same number of episodes and then Debate and discuss what's going to happen next.
Scott: All right See the same thing going on as all those HBO shows that everyone watches.
Rym: Yeah, Game of Thrones has the exact same thing going on.
Scott: That I don't watch.
Rym: So, uh, I hope you all continue to watch Kill La Kill and I hope if you haven't watched Attack on Titan you go watch it and Seriously, if you haven't watched Madoka Magica, no anime has come out since it.
Rym: that's better than it.
Scott: Also, please come to our forum and suggest an old anime that we have not discussed on the show For us to discuss on the show.
Rym: Yeah, if if you guys suggest something interesting or if enough of you suggest something bad, we'll watch it and we'll review it.
Scott: Don't say something stupid.
Rym: Well, we've already reviewed Apocalypse Zero.
Scott: Well, they might be like A Road to Godotula Blue Girl.
Rym: I would not be opposed to reviewing those.
Scott: I haven't watched either one since forever.
Rym: So we'd have to watch them again, I guess.
Scott: Don't really want to do that.
Rym: No, but I think it might be funny because as you recall I'm sure it'll make a great GeekNights episode.
Scott: It just won't make a great 90 minutes of my life spent watching either one.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special Thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.