Rym: It's Thursday, February 21st, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight on the GeekNights Book Club.
Rym: It's The Great Gatsby by F. Scott Fitzgerald.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So for once I'm sitting down to do GeekNights and I have a plethora of things I could say, an opening bit perhaps, some anecdote from my life.
Scott: I got one of those.
Rym: I had the thought I realized, you know what I should do?
Rym: And we've had this thought often on the show.
Rym: I should tell one of them and save the rest for some dry time in the future.
Scott: You'll forget it.
Rym: And then I was going to instead make my bit about how I forgot about all these things.
Rym: And then I actually, in the last few minutes, legit forgot one of the three things I wanted to talk about.
Rym: Like I literally cannot remember it.
Scott: That makes room for mine, which I remembered.
Rym: So instead I want to talk about centaur bondage porn.
Scott: Okay, let's not talk about that either.
Rym: So I swear this all links together.
Rym: So let's back up a bit to February 20th.
Rym: Yesterday.
Scott: Why are you backing up with your centaur bondage?
Rym: So my friend.
Rym: Your friend, the centaur.
Scott: That's backing up.
Rym: If I knew a centaur, that'd be the chill ones like in a bleach.
Rym: That's okay.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Everyone just fast forward.
Rym: Heels are our good friend.
Scott: Heels on the centaur.
Scott: I thought they have hooves, not heels.
Rym: And the quote is conversation.
Rym: I just had at work.
Rym: Is that a horse hanging from the ceiling in your area?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yes it is.
Rym: And he tweets a picture and it's looks like it's a horse suspended from the ceiling in like their office.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So let's go back like a month.
Rym: I was unrelatedly because I had found a, a little mashup of all the, my little pony characters, the centaurs.
Rym: that was really well drawn.
Rym: I thought it was funny because Applejack was carrying a kind of fan shit.
Rym: So Applejack's here in like this X, X, X jug and like a NASCAR thing.
Rym: It was just, it was fun.
Scott: Triple X porn pony, my little pony centaurs that are backing up with your friend.
Rym: I didn't say anything about backing up anyway.
Rym: So I was looking for a, I wanted to find a frumpy centaur.
Scott: Like I needed like, the fact that it was centaur, my little ponies wasn't good enough for you.
Scott: They had to be frumpy.
Rym: So I had this idea to make a little mashup, like one of those like fantasy reality things.
Rym: So I wanted a dog headed girl, badly drawn equivalent of a centaur where spooky goes helping you with these internet searches.
Rym: And in the course of looking for that, I saw what could only be described spooky ghost as a centaur in bondage.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So that would, that just got filed away as, yeah, that's the thing that exists.
Rym: Probably should have expected that that exists.
Rym: Probably should have expected that for right there.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, uh, there's probably porn of, let's see everything.
Rym: Let's go with a Chain Chomp and Sonic the Hedgehog.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Here we go.
Rym: Oh, you're actually going to Google it.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: All right.
Rym: Chain Chomps and Sonic the Hedgehog.
Scott: I searched for Chain Chomp porn.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Let's go with just Chain Chomp because the Sonic part might be.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So here's actually princess Toadstool getting all porny and there's a Chain Chomp there.
Scott: that's looking pretty angry.
Scott: She's sort of holding its chain.
Scott: I guess she's using it in a dominatrix fashion.
Scott: Like it's her dominatrix tool is this Chain Chomp.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I'm glad we know that exists.
Scott: Oh, here is a womanized Chain Chomp.
Scott: that is all sexy.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Rule.
Scott: And in fact it says right here, rule number 34.
Scott: If it exists, there is porn of it and Chain Chomp.
Rym: So yes, should have expected that.
Rym: And in general, point of advice, you look for anything related to centaurs.
Rym: is stuff out there.
Rym: So anyway, I didn't find a frumpy enough centaur and I gave up on this gif I wanted to make.
Rym: And in the course of that, I saw this like a centaur hanging upside down, like suspension style, like ready to be in porn.
Scott: Ah, Rym.
Scott: This is a great opening video.
Rym: So I remember this and then I see this tweet.
Rym: So I'm like, I basically tell the tale of that.
Rym: if I found this picture, I can't believe true facts.
Rym: So he responded link please.
Rym: I have a conundrum.
Rym: You see, I saw this one.
Rym: I can't, I don't, I can't find it again.
Rym: I don't want to search for it.
Rym: Cause remember I was searching for frumpy centaurs.
Rym: I was not searching for like bondage centaur.
Rym: Do not want to search for that.
Rym: So if anyone has a picture of a centaur hanging upside down and what can be described as something like could be described as bondage gear, I need you to send that to our friend heels.
Scott: Why don't you just make one?
Rym: Because it'll be just as good as the drawings of Lamy as we did the other night.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Anyone who is fast forwarding as instructed, now is the time to stop fast forwarding.
Rym: You realize you have to say that really, really slowly or they won't hear you.
Scott: If you are fast forwarding as instructed, this is the time to stop and return to the normal playing speed.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I remembered my other two opening bits.
Rym: One of them is I ate at a restaurant that's really good called Benoit.
Rym: It's French place.
Scott: I know about that place.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I liked that place a lot.
Rym: I went there last night.
Rym: So I had a dessert that can only be described as one of those ridiculous things that rich people eat.
Rym: It was bread, like angel food.
Rym: It was almost like angel food cake, but like a bread.
Rym: And they brought it to me in this huge silver platter.
Rym: And then they opened the top and just sit in there and then they poured Armagnac over it, which seems to be the bread.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And then they covered it in this like whipped creme fraiche.
Scott: So the king's poo.
Rym: And I can't say that it was necessarily good, but it was weird.
Scott: Well, creme fraiche sort of unadulterated like that is a little, uh, it's got a weird taste to it.
Rym: I think it was creme fraiche whipped with sugar or something.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But creme fraiche, you know, is basically sour cream, but it has this extra sort of little aftertaste.
Scott: It's sort of, you don't want to go straight with it, but if you cook it into something, it disappears.
Rym: But sour cream, like I'll just eat a whole spoonful of that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Sour cream is the best.
Rym: The third thing I've been updating my tumbler.
Rym: I think I've updated my tumbler in last week.
Rym: More times than I've updated any blog I've ever had a moment now because it's not GeekNights.
Rym: Anyway, this is like the stuff that doesn't make the GeekNights cut.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So my opening bit is, uh, you know, we did an episode a long time on battle lore, which, you know, Rym hated a lot more than I hated.
Rym: terrible game.
Scott: Uh, but of course it's a two player war game.
Scott: That's not so complex, but then again, not completely simple.
Scott: It's, you know, sort of a middle of the road war game and I paid a lot of money for it and it was hot for a few minutes and they made a bunch of expansions and it disappeared.
Scott: And the only game in that series that seems to still be around is memoir 44, which is basically the same game with a different theme.
Rym: Uh, however, having read the rules to both, I think memoir 44 would be fun.
Rym: I'm thinking about getting a copy of it.
Scott: It's the same game.
Rym: Not quite what's different.
Rym: The core mechanic is not the problem with battle lore.
Rym: The problem with battle lore is that the magic system and all that stuff they put on top of that magic system.
Rym: we did.
Rym: We didn't.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We played the base game and the scenarios were so simple.
Rym: It was pointless.
Rym: We did play two games of it with the magic and it was just stupid.
Scott: I don't remember playing with the magic.
Scott: Anyway, so the game got was not played even if I wanted to play it and it takes it.
Scott: Even if I did want to play it, the setup takes a long time so it wasn't really worth it.
Scott: Uh, so I tried to sell it.
Scott: Finally I got off my ass and tried to sell it and someone in New Zealand wanted it and I was like, but then they said they, I was like, are you sure the shipping's going to be like a fortune?
Scott: And they said, okay.
Scott: And they PayPal'd me a fortune.
Scott: So I said, okay.
Scott: And I went to the post office to mail it and I expected to go to the post office and have this be a pain in the ass.
Scott: And of course it was a pain in the ass.
Rym: Ah, you set that up like, and it wasn't.
Rym: And everything was awesome.
Scott: It was, I went there, I needed a box to put this in.
Rym: You didn't already have a box.
Scott: They didn't have a box of appropriate size.
Rym: Wait, here's your problem.
Rym: You went to the post office expecting them to have the box for you.
Rym: You should have, you go to.
Scott: the box is there.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: God, you go to the post office with just like a fucking letter and you're like, Hey, can I get an envelope for this shit?
Scott: They have envelopes.
Rym: You don't do that.
Rym: You, you package up ahead of time and you show up anyway.
Scott: So they had boxes.
Rym: You're the reason there's lines at the post office.
Scott: They were not out there.
Scott: They were out behind.
Scott: They, I had to wait like, and this other guy was also, he was trying to mail camera equipment to Brazil.
Scott: He bought like a Canon EOS.
Scott: He was trying to send to his friend in Brazil.
Scott: We had to wait for them to go and find boxes.
Scott: It took like 15 minutes.
Rym: Bring your own goddamn box.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Where's he going to get one?
Rym: The box store, which is UPS stores have box.
Scott: I go to UPS.
Scott: They're going to want me to mail my shit from UPS.
Rym: You can just buy boxes.
Rym: There's staples has boxes.
Rym: Office Depot.
Scott: Anyways, there's one next to my office.
Scott: That's far away from my office.
Rym: There's probably one near your office too.
Scott: There's one here in Queens.
Scott: Anyway, then right.
Scott: I had to fill out these forms.
Scott: No pens, no pens to fill out the customs form anywhere.
Scott: Not one pen.
Scott: I felt like doing that thing where you go to the bank and grab a fistful of pens and bring it in the post office.
Rym: So you know what?
Rym: The chase mag near me doesn't have any accessible pens for people.
Rym: Any.
Scott: then they make you buy some tape because they don't just give you tape.
Rym: And then I got to have four friends to play the D the DS game.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And then had to wait in this incredible line.
Scott: That was ridiculous.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: If you already have it boxed, there's machines.
Scott: No, the machine was out of order.
Rym: If that machine's out of order, whatever I'm attempting to mail doesn't get mailed.
Scott: And I was mailing internationally.
Scott: And when I finally got up to the counter, the person really had a hard time figuring out what to type into the computer to make this thing send and such.
Scott: And I was like, this is all you do all day.
Scott: It's like there's 20, there's 10 people here now who are sending international things and you don't know what to do.
Rym: Not your first day here.
Scott: One employee of post office.
Rym: that at a post office, the only people who are in that line are people who are there doing something complicated or need help dressing themselves.
Rym: One of the two.
Rym: There is no person in that line with an easy trends.
Scott: I was just sending a standard international package.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's already crazy.
Scott: Which costs how much?
Scott: Guess how much it costs to send the package to.
Rym: So is it just battle or were they expansions or with the Epic board in a box?
Scott: I didn't even put peanuts and shit in there.
Scott: I was just like, I'm assuming you said customs.
Rym: It's a gift.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Did you, you're not going to pay a duty though.
Rym: You're going to pass that through to who you're sending it to.
Scott: I didn't, I, they stay accepted it and they're mailing it.
Scott: I don't give a fuck what happens.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But you said gift, right?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I'm going to say $74.
Scott: You're pretty close.
Rym: It was like, remember when we had for sale, I shipped them and I learned a lot about how to ship shit.
Scott: It was like 70 something.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Cause a lot of money.
Rym: I know what's up.
Rym: I FedEx shit around the world all the time for work.
Scott: FedEx is way more than post office.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But you get a lot of things.
Scott: The price is actually all even out in the end, but yeah, there are international flat rate boxes, but, and battle or meets the weight requirement, but they don't have a flat rate international box that battle oral fit in.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The point of the flat rate box is that you can only fit so much into it, but if the board gate, I could probably fit fucking Puerto Rico and one of those motherfuckers fit just a bunch of polonium in there.
Rym: Just fill it up.
Scott: Well, that would exceed the weight limit.
Scott: There's a weight limit and a size limit.
Scott: The size limit is the box and the weight limit is a number.
Scott: They actually did have a scale there that was surprisingly easy to figure out, to calculate the price.
Rym: Scales are not generally complicated.
Rym: You need no, but the two buttons, maybe tar and calibrate they all the scale.
Scott: Also you could type things in and it would tell you how much money it costs to send to different places.
Scott: So, and that was pretty, it wasn't exactly accurate, but it was pretty accurate.
Scott: You could choose it.
Scott: They had a little piece of paper that told you all the country codes in case you didn't know, and you type it in and you choose the kind of postage you want and then it tells you the number.
Rym: You know, this is an aside when it comes, you know, there's country codes for phone numbers too, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: In my experience, people in the entire rest of the world know that country codes exist.
Rym: Most people in the U S have no idea that country code is one.
Rym: No, they don't realize that's a country code.
Scott: They think Alexander Graham Bell's an American.
Scott: Therefore America is number one.
Rym: They think either that the one is just something you type when you dial long distance, because they don't realize long distance isn't a thing anymore.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Or, but that's it.
Rym: They have no idea why that one is there.
Scott: It's phone numbers are, uh, they're the way DNS is supposed to be calm dot country dot kind of lore low area.
Rym: Well, you saw that XKCD.
Rym: nowadays it's country dot where you lived in the year 2000.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: But it's, you know, it's, it's DNS calm dot whatever, you know, well.com dot, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It goes from, but the thing is addresses go from most specific to least specific.
Scott: We should Scott Rubin, no, no, no, no, no USA as opposed to USA.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: It's got Ruben.
Scott: You know what I'm going to say?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: My phone number is really Rym at frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: Cause if you're going to call me, what the fuck?
Rym: I mean, seriously, what are you going to send me a fax?
Rym: What year?
Scott: What year is it?
Rym: Are you going to send the pony express?
Rym: Or I guess the center.
Scott: If I go to an old school fax machine and I faxed to your Google voice number, will it show up as a PDF or something in your Google voice?
Scott: Fuck.
Rym: If I know what the fuck is a fax.
Scott: Try it.
Rym: The last time I faxed something was in 2006.
Rym: I faxed one thing.
Rym: Sometimes I will use a fax to purchase order.
Scott: in like 2008, a few years ago, I basically used, I didn't actually send a fax.
Scott: I use sort of a fake fax work around as a way to scan from a scan from a fax machine.
Scott: Well, from a copier, which then sent an email to a fax number, which then went through a fax system and ended up in my work email box as a PDF.
Scott: So it's sort of a scan from a copy machine and it turned into a PDF in my outlook.
Scott: So yeah, that's all I got.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So at any rate, it's time for things of the day.
Rym: I've been looking around the internet looking for the best anime music videos.
Rym: If you're not an anime fan, you don't care about that stuff.
Scott: And you're pretty much just picking the ones that we already knew from back in the day and you're reliving the nostalgia.
Scott: You haven't seen any good ones since we left college.
Rym: Actually, I've added a good portion of ones that I've seen in the last week that are relatively new.
Scott: Since you started looking.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Since I started looking.
Scott: So you got a few, you got a big gap between say '05 and '12.
Rym: Actually, one of the ones that I found that was good was a contest winner from like '08.
Rym: But anyway, I do this in this episode because guys, it's GeekNights.
Rym: The whole point is to get the anime geeks into the video games, the video game geeks into the neckbeards and cross pollinate.
Rym: This anime music video is to a show called Panty and Stocking.
Rym: Just watched the video.
Rym: Imagine a dirty adult Powerpuff Girls.
Rym: and this video just makes the show look probably more awesome than it is, but the video is awesome.
Scott: It's more of a dirty adult Powerpuff Girls.
Scott: Gatekeepers, really.
Rym: Yeah, but I didn't think anyone listening to this show would know what Gatekeepers is.
Scott: No one probably does.
Rym: Dude, anime fans don't know that show.
Rym: Get open!
Rym: That was the biggest show for like a month and a half.
Scott: It was a big show for three weeks because it was the first DigiSub that you could just download from that one website.
Scott: Anime Keep or Anime Factory?
Scott: AnimeFactory.net.
Rym: Meanwhile, the first big DigiSub before that was the Escaflowne movie.
Scott: Those are pretty much the first two digital fansubs that were like...
Rym: Scott and I almost got kicked out of the RIT Anime Club because we told people they could go download the Escaflowne movie.
Scott: I don't remember that.
Rym: You don't remember that?
Rym: No.
Rym: That's Scott Johnson about that.
Rym: They saw we had that DVD and they talked about kicking all of us out of the club.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: They had an e-board meeting about it.
Rym: That was with Tape Nazi.
Rym: I didn't want to say his full name on the show, but I almost did.
Rym: The first Tape Nazi.
Rym: The original Tape Nazi.
Scott: I don't know how it's any different from the fansubs they had already.
Rym: Because it was digital and that's how anime types are.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: Anyway, so check this out.
Scott: There are a lot of things in the world that people think are impossible, but if you go to Zombocom, we know that the impossible becomes possible at Zombocom.
Rym: Before we go any further, as soon as you watch this, you're going to try to make noises with your throat.
Rym: You're going to be sitting there after you watch that scene today.
Scott: Don't hurt yourself unless you go to Zombocom first.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I already hurt myself.
Rym: We didn't go to Zombocom first.
Scott: It was a big mistake not visiting Zombocom.
Scott: I didn't clip.
Rym: The limiter kicked in.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: Anyway, so this girl, her YouTube account is Disney Diva Seven.
Scott: I guess she's an opera singer.
Rym: She's the seventh one.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: She made this YouTube video of her singing the opera song from the fifth element, which is supposedly impossible.
Scott: I mean, the original was sung by some opera person.
Scott: You can look it up on the internet with what I assume is a vocoder.
Scott: Oh, the original singer's voice is sung by Albanian soprano Inva Mula.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But Laura in this YouTube video sings it without any digital enhancements.
Rym: I've not tried to verify how 100% that is, but it looks legit to me.
Scott: It's pretty legit.
Scott: And you can hear her singing over the originals playing like on the track.
Rym: She didn't get like, she didn't get a karaoke track to be able to hit those notes and know you're hitting them because it's crazy.
Rym: Wait, there's a whole bunch of videos of people trying to sing it that are linked.
Scott: Well, only this one, which is actually successful because of Zombocom is the thing of the day.
Scott: The other ones watch at your own risk.
Rym: After this episode, I'm going to watch this one called me trying to sing the diva dance from the fifth element.
Rym: And it's uploaded by some dude.
Rym: And it's the picture of a dude trying to sing.
Rym: He's got the same pop filter that I have.
Scott: I wonder if anyone does it like pretending to shoot themselves at the end, pretending to get shot at the end.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I'm done making stupid noises.
Scott: So the great Gatsby, I hope you guys met a moment.
Rym: Oh, you want to do a meta moment?
Scott: Well, we got to do a meta moment.
Rym: Well, maybe because we're going to be at PAX doing practical game theory, doing, uh, mastering game mechanics, doing possibly a third event and also enforcing.
Rym: So we're going to be all over the fuck place.
Rym: This is PAX East, by the way, 2013.
Scott: It's actually in a few fucking weeks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We got to finish those panels.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'll get to mine this weekend.
Scott: Um, other meta moments.
Scott: If you did not listen to the last episode, we, I am holding personally, this event that I came up with and decided not to shit talk, it's going to be pretty easy for me, but probably hard for you.
Scott: The front row crew official GeekNights game grand Prix 2013.
Scott: Here's how it works.
Scott: We are going to compete and Sue see who is the best gamer amongst the listeners and forum people.
Scott: If you want to sign up, all you have to do is join the forum or sign into the forum, go to the thread.
Scott: It's the top thread.
Scott: post a comment before March 1st that says you're in, I will add your name to the Google doc.
Scott: We have almost 40 people on this thing.
Scott: It is going to be fierce.
Scott: Uh, we are using an F1 scoring system.
Scott: The top 10 positions in any particular round or Grand Prix, uh, will score championship points.
Scott: Uh, whoever has the most points.
Scott: after however, number of rounds I'm thinking four or five.
Rym: now guys, things like this champion, even super aguri is awesome in F1.
Rym: So even if you suck at games, if you want to try for this, the right around for so long, I know I've watched F1 since super aguri was around.
Rym: It's the longest.
Rym: I know if you get even one championship point in this thing, you'll have a lot of bragging rights over everyone who didn't participate and the majority of people in this thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, and don't worry about, I mean, every round is going to be skill games.
Scott: I'm never going to pick a rent, you know, a luck game or coin flip game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I never, and if there is some luck in the game, which there could be, there will be luck mitigation rules.
Scott: The rules for each round.
Scott: I will be determined by me, judged by me, proved by me, everything master and may the odds be ever in your favor.
Scott: You can, you're going to need to do this.
Scott: probably a computer, uh, probably some sort of camera or other evidence gatherers.
Scott: So you can prove to the best of your abilities that your score is legit.
Scott: And then we might have some sort of challenge system.
Scott: If someone thinks you cheated, which I don't think will be really foresee this.
Rym: The first task is like some Mario three thing and you get 40 identical stolen from YouTube machine assisted plays.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think we'll be able to tell.
Scott: Um, and yeah, you just, you know, if you don't want to participate in a round or can't, you just don't and you get a zero, which you're probably going to get even if you do participate because even with the current number of entrance, 75% of people are going to get zeros.
Scott: Um, and oh, I'm going to try to make every round will be as accessible as possible.
Rym: I'm not going to do things which will, like, for example, if one of them is a feat of, you know, physical, like a running thing or something crazy out in the real world, it wouldn't be because some people don't have fucking legs.
Rym: I was about to say, but that, but are you going to go, how much are you going to include?
Rym: What if someone's blind?
Scott: Uh, well, I mean, if they're playing video games and reading the forum, they have something, right?
Scott: I mean, yeah.
Rym: So by not having legs, you're just counting a huge swath of games, many of which are actually eminently accessible to a lot of people.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But for example, DDR would require people to buy equipment, which they may not have a, you know, I wouldn't pick like a PlayStation three exclusive cause not everyone has a PlayStation three.
Scott: I wouldn't pick a game that requires a bad ass PC cause most people don't have a bad ass PC.
Rym: But you could, for example, do a hundred meter dash.
Scott: Uh, we could.
Rym: I'm not saying that should be one.
Rym: I'm just saying it could be some sort of physical thing.
Rym: Like how many fucking pushups can you do?
Scott: You're not doing that.
Scott: Um, it's, it's definitely going to be bored and video game related.
Scott: It is not going to be, you know, though there may be dexterity games.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: But yeah, sign up and we'll.
Scott: March 1st is when I will announce around one.
Scott: I've already planned four rounds.
Rym: Also, Connecticut panels submissions are not only open, but we are currently scheduling.
Rym: So if you want to do something at Connecticut, submit sooner rather than later, good spots are disappearing in our private schedule that we're going to start sharing relatively soon.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: I should do something about that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You still need to send me your, the info so I can make your fucking account for the backend.
Scott: What's different than you?
Scott: What info do you need to know?
Rym: Uh, I sent you an email asking for some stuff.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I didn't do it.
Scott: What do you not know about me?
Rym: I need you to make an account on the regular Connecticut website and send me the username you used.
Rym: Uh, you couldn't, you couldn't manage that.
Rym: You couldn't Connecticut websites really bad before you say yes, it is.
Rym: There is, depending on whether or talking absolutely or relative.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Regardless, we're here tonight, 25 minutes into the episode to talk about the great Gatsby.
Scott: All right.
Rym: The best thing about this book.
Rym: This is the book club one.
Rym: We're not going to summarize the plot.
Rym: We assume you've already read it.
Rym: We're just talking about it as though we're a bunch of friends.
Rym: We've all read it.
Rym: Way to repeat this every time because people don't seem to get it, especially you who insist on summarizing the entire plot of the, of the book.
Scott: Only to piss you off.
Rym: The best part about this book is that cover from the first edition.
Rym: That art is one of that art.
Rym: is that art is so famous that that art is such a famous and iconic.
Scott: I even see that if you go to a Barnes and Noble, they got that shit on the wall.
Rym: I kind of want to get a nice poster of this and stick it out.
Scott: It's trivial to do because it's so famous.
Rym: I know it's just it.
Rym: The thing is, it's not just this great art.
Rym: It actually really well encapsulates kind of the feel of the book and the feel of the era.
Rym: The book was written in and about.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You know, before reading this, I had no idea what it was about other than there was clearly a character named Gatsby who was either great or sarcastically great.
Scott: So I had a, and I didn't know that it was about the twenties written in the twenties and they start going in long Island and I'm like, Whoa, I really, I love this.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You know, I wasn't alive in the twenties, but I totally under, you know, New York hasn't changed.
Rym: There are things about the thing about this book that haven't changed.
Rym: Like there's the scene with when they're driving the cars really fast, like right before the shit goes down in the end and they're going from long Island, like, Oh, let's go to Manhattan.
Rym: You know, as they're driving into the city and they like drive through Astoria and then they stop their cars to talk to each other.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You know where the mechanic is with the sign, the glasses, that's all the mechanic shops out behind Shea state wall, city field, you know, in the Rover there.
Scott: I know exactly where that is.
Rym: It was startling almost to read a book like this, not really knowing what to expect because I didn't know a lot about the book 90 years ago.
Rym: The geography was pretty similar, but not just the geography, but the culture of like commuters and what different neighborhoods are like.
Rym: in some senses, though, in other senses, they changed a lot, but like going to grand central, the scenes written about going to the hotel.
Scott: It's still there.
Rym: Not only is that hope that hotel is still there, but past the hotel all the time in the summer, that scene could happen today and it would be the exact same scene except everyone has a cell phone.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, but they were using regular telephones all the time.
Rym: They were, but at the same time, I think.
Rym: as a result, I think this book resonated with me a lot more having read it now than it would have had.
Rym: I read it as a kid because I was a Michigander.
Rym: I'd never been to New York city, let alone New York state until I was like 16 or 17.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So I had never like, I had no idea other than from watching Seinfeld, what New York was like being in New York person.
Scott: Really?
Scott: This book was like, whoa, I know exactly what's going on here.
Rym: And people here are still kind of like that.
Rym: Like this book is pretty relevant.
Rym: People are kind of like that.
Rym: I, what bothers me about this episode is that this is whether or not you like the characters, whether or not you're not supposed to like any of them.
Scott: None of them are likable.
Rym: I kind of like Gatsby.
Scott: I kind of like the main guy a little bit.
Scott: I like the main guy because aspects of the main guy, but not other aspects.
Rym: Uh, what aspect of the main guy don't you like?
Rym: Because what I, what I, when I see about him, why I liked him is that he was in a way kind of like.
Rym: he's like the, like he moves here and he's like working like in a, like in financial, he's basically doing the kind of work that I would do.
Scott: I liked that.
Scott: he was a re.
Scott: he's reasonable, you know, not crazy, not stupid person.
Scott: He's from a rich family, but he's trying to like, just go on his own and he has the admirable, you know, his main thing is his admirable ability to, you know, forgive and put up with people.
Scott: But what I don't like about him is it's like, all right dude, you have basically no balls.
Scott: You're just sort of like, so in the same time where he's putting up with people, he also just takes all shit from people and just isn't see,
Rym: but that was already
Scott: shit because he makes
Rym: a point pretty early on in the book where he starts talking about that crazy party you went to, you know, the first one where all this other stuff is going on in his life and that the, the events of this book are a tiny percentage of what's actually going on and how
Scott: most of his day is spent doing his bond selling and going to
Rym: dinner, cooking, they just go, whatever.
Rym: But he makes the point that this book is just about that crazy bullshit.
Rym: So it's, I wouldn't really say he doesn't have balls and these people are putting upon him so much as more than he's living his normal life.
Rym: It's like if we're living our normal lives and then once every week or so we end up at a party with just crazy people with crazy drama and he's kind of just watching it like, wow, wow.
Scott: So it's just a story of his once a week crazy parties.
Scott: Also, he didn't handle a hot tennis girl very well.
Rym: I like her a lot.
Rym: I also, yeah, she's pretty cool because she is, she knows she's cool in the literal, not the literal sense, but in the sense of cool.
Rym: She is calculated, sophisticated, calm, nonplussed about everything.
Scott: She's cool and probably way hot that that word is not.
Scott: tennis girls are way higher.
Rym: Well, she's described as being incredibly attractive and the way she dresses tennis skirts way hot when she's wearing those like riding boots.
Rym: That is ace also ace.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: She is, if anything, the only problem with her is that she's too cool for school.
Rym: And in fact, our main character really couldn't deal with her.
Rym: And I like how she's.
Rym: a matter of fact, she's like, you know, actually I could've, I could've done a thing with you, but, uh, you didn't really follow up.
Scott: So yeah, that's the problem with him.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But whatever, this was a tiny part of his life.
Rym: At least he made out with her.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But this is a simple story about a bunch of shitty people doing their shitty thing and a few cool headed people just kind of watching the train wreck.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean, what the story, the real car wreck?
Scott: in this case, obviously as with any great, you know, work, right?
Rym: There are many messages, but the core number one message, I'm curious what you think the number one messages, right?
Scott: It's it's the East egg and the West egg.
Scott: And it is comparing the old money and the new money, the old money of the East egg and the new money of the West egg.
Scott: You have, you know, Tom and what's her face, right?
Scott: Are the old money.
Scott: And on the one hand, the old money, it's like, did they really earn their money?
Scott: Oh, they kind of inherited it, right?
Scott: But they sort of, you know, act at least outwardly, respectively.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They sort of have all these airs and ways about them and, you know, things they do.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You know, they have a veneer over the reality.
Rym: They have the same crazy childish drama that normal people have, but they, but they put it all, they cast it in this completely different light in their, in their personal lives.
Scott: They're sort of shitty and evil, right?
Rym: Not evil, just shitty.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Scott: I mean, not super evil, like Hitler evil, but you know, not exactly nice.
Scott: Right?
Rym: Well, like, yeah, she's cheating on her.
Scott: I mean, the dude is mad racist, but he wasn't right.
Rym: So he was racist in that really derpy way.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But then on the other hand, you have the Gatsby new monies, right?
Scott: These people who, you know, how did they earn their money?
Scott: Crime and stealing and not good things.
Rym: But it was, it was relatively cool crime.
Rym: I mean, world series and bootlegging.
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He earned his money illegitimately.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, in terms of his ideals and, you know, the way he conducted himself in his personal life was actually, you know, kind of a good standup person.
Rym: It's like, if I had to say anything about Gatsby, it's that he was incredibly naive and entirely too genuine.
Scott: It's sort of, in fact mirrors, uh, you're going to love this sanctuary, right?
Scott: You have these people, it's like, you know, these, these two young good guys, these new monies, right.
Scott: And, you know, they want to come and fix the government and make the world better and create a sanctuary.
Scott: And they're all idealistic and young and spirited, but how did they get there?
Scott: Yuck is a crime in, well, what about those old guys who are already in charge, right?
Scott: There's the quote in sanctuary.
Rym: I joined the Yakuza because I can do in a week, what a normal man takes 10 years to accomplish.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Is, you know, well in sanctuary, at least those guys were Yakuza also, but some, you know, then they were corrupt also, but some of them weren't.
Scott: and they got there, you know, the legit non-crime takes 10 years away, but you know, of course they were up to no good.
Scott: Their ideals were not right.
Rym: Oh, here's the random aside.
Rym: Apparently Ernest Hemingway hated the cover of the great Gatsby.
Scott: Ernest Hemingway hated it.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: When Fitzgerald lent him a copy of the great Gatsby that he read, he immediately disliked the cover and Scott told him not to be put off by it.
Rym: And that it had to do with a billboard along the highway in Long Island.
Scott: It does have to do with the billboard along the highway in Long Island.
Rym: But Gatsby was just, he was too naive and genuine that he, it's like he held onto this pure image of the past.
Rym: I'm not going to allude to all the tennis stuff I would reference because no one listening to this episode will get that, but same thing.
Rym: We just talked about that, but again, he carried that naive sort of innocence, like he's doing all these things to make right and get with that girl.
Rym: And he has this sort of fairytale idea that if he just gets noticed by her, she's going to leave her husband and get back with him and everything's going to be awesome because her husband's a putz.
Rym: How many nice guys do you know who think that exact same thing?
Rym: If I'm just around, she's going to ditch that biker asshole and date me in the end.
Rym: And she wanted to have an affair with him because she's, you know, she, I think she probably had designs on our main character.
Rym: If that wasn't obvious to all of you.
Scott: But weren't they cousins though?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But the way she interacted with him was creepy.
Scott: And it was a cousin that she didn't see often until then.
Rym: And read it again.
Rym: She flirts with him and it's kind of creepy actually.
Scott: It was pretty creepy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But so he, she probably wouldn't like seeing Gatsby again.
Rym: She was all about having an affair.
Rym: But then when he was like, come run away with me for real, let's do this.
Rym: She refused to do it.
Rym: She refused to back away completely.
Rym: And she basically just became a passive character and stood there doing nothing until catastrophe happened.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The other thing is I can really relate to this sort of, you know, old money, new money, East egg, West egg contrast.
Scott: That is the core of this book because it's something I see, you know, in everyday life, not just in New York, but just sort of everywhere.
Scott: Right.
Rym: If anything, it's getting worse.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, look at like, you know, in terms of, you know, internet generation versus not, you know, in terms of thinking on different issues like copyright, it's like old people think this.
Scott: new young people think that, you know, and it's just, that's just, you know, young people like the rap music and old people say the rap music is the devil.
Scott: And it's all that kind of stuff that we see everywhere in, uh, in our lives every day.
Rym: And this book really sort of shows it to you, but it also really hits that aspect of the main characters about our age.
Rym: Like he's going, he's actually similar to us.
Rym: He's similar to us.
Rym: And especially because the book pointedly avoids the details of his personal life and just shows him interacting with these people.
Rym: I find that I actually identify with him to a surprising degree because I picture myself in his situations, reacting in many ways, similarly, not in all ways, because I am much more willing to interject in someone's bullshit.
Scott: Yes you are.
Scott: But at the other, at the other hand, also the guy who will smile and chuckle and pretend to be paying attention to what some creepy fan boy is saying.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which is what this guy will do, which I do not do.
Rym: But in a way, that's how I also identify with Gatsby because I like Gatsby, but then when I realized that he was really just a naive man-child, I liked him a lot less.
Rym: But if his internal drive had matched the surface, he would have been the most awesome dude ever.
Scott: Well, that's why the title of the Great Gatsby is, you know, this title, right?
Scott: It's like on the one hand you see the Great Gatsby and in many ways he was not great, which makes it like, oh, the Great Gatsby derp.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, he was great except no one went to his funeral because no one even knew who he was.
Rym: They just showed up at his house.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: I mean, at least if I have a party, I know every single person at that party mostly.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I hate it when, you know, like you'll go to like weddings and it's like the people who are getting married don't even know all the people there because like their parents invited somebody and it's like, I will never have that shit ever in my life again.
Scott: It's like, if I, if it is a party for me, I will know every single person there.
Rym: The little touch that the owl looking guy, owl looking guy is the best guy in the whole actually liked Gatsby and was actually missed the funeral.
Rym: Like he'd be like, he wanted to go and he just had something come up for real.
Rym: The fact that he actually missed Gatsby and actually cared about him.
Rym: I thought that was a really nice touch because I remember that character, the whole book.
Scott: That was my favorite guy.
Rym: I like the beginning.
Rym: I've Scott Fitzgerald guys is one of the better authors in English ever.
Rym: There's a reason why people talk about him.
Scott: Well, this is what I think, right?
Rym: Well, I want to make a point.
Rym: Look at what he did.
Rym: The book is titled the great Gatsby.
Rym: We don't meet Gatsby.
Scott: If you read on Wikipedia, there was a, he had a hard time picking the title.
Rym: I'm reading the same paragraph.
Rym: Those other titles are all stupid.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, under the red, white and blue, really?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Gold-headed Gatsby, the high bouncing lover Tramocchio in West egg.
Scott: Well, actually when I read that Wikipedia, I read what Tramocchio was.
Scott: I forget, but it was once you see what Tramocchio is, you're like, Oh, of course.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Gatsby among Ash heaps and millionaires.
Rym: That's, that's the worst title of the bunch.
Scott: So there was apparently some great controversy in our forum about whether this was book was good or not.
Rym: I want to get to everyone who said this book was bad.
Rym: If I read between the lines of what you said was bad about it, you didn't, I like the characters.
Rym: You didn't identify with the characters.
Rym: You were mad at the decisions the characters made and you couldn't identify with the setting and you couldn't glean the morals and messages.
Rym: No one had any criticism of the style, the presentation, you know, the things that literary criticism is about.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So the thing is with this book is that, you know, why is it great?
Scott: I'll be honest.
Scott: You know, there are many things, you know, it's not a bad book, right?
Scott: But in terms of my personal enjoyment of it, it was slightly above me, right?
Scott: I really enjoyed it.
Scott: I didn't have a ton of fun reading it.
Scott: It wasn't thrilling.
Scott: I wouldn't like go and read it again, you know, enjoyment wise, but in terms of recognition of quality, it's like, ah, ah, well, right.
Scott: If someone was going to write a textbook with instructions on like how to write good novel, this is like a plus.
Rym: Finally, our character goes to the party and he's like, I wonder what's up with the Gatsby.
Rym: Like he's actually like, they set the stage.
Rym: You're really wondering like, what's the deal with Gatsby?
Rym: And you get all, first you get all these rumors.
Rym: He hears what other people say about Gatsby and it's all over the place.
Rym: And then he goes around and he runs into a few characters in a row where you, as the reader think, I'll bet that's Gatsby.
Rym: You expect it to be Gatsby and it's never Gatsby.
Rym: You, everyone thought the guy was Gatsby.
Rym: And then Gatsby talks to him for like five minutes and then he's like, oh, uh, I'm Gatsby.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Sorry.
Rym: I guess I should have introduced myself.
Rym: The way that was executed was brilliant and perfectly constructed.
Rym: If you do not recognize how well that was all put together from a constructive construction standpoint of a novel, you haven't read enough novels and pretty much the whole, everything in the book is like that.
Scott: You know, the, the coincidence of the, the big scene, which is the car accident, right?
Scott: And how he, he goes back and forth between the different people and the different cars and the timing of coming back and how they stopped on the way there.
Scott: And the, the timing is getting dark.
Rym: Tom is interacting and he pretty much is going to send the crazy, the old sad guy off to murder Gatsby.
Rym: Like he, he's going to make that happen.
Rym: And he basically starts to get animated with a guy.
Rym: And then there's a scene where the cop who's interviewing someone unrelated sort of notices that there's a little bit of commotion and how Tom like tries to back that back off to let his plot happen.
Rym: But it's subtle.
Rym: And I think a lot of people miss it, but Tom was premeditating the murder of Gatsby from that point onward.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: But anyway, it's just in terms of if someone was going to, you know, it's usually right.
Scott: Things that get a lot of attention, right.
Scott: Are things that, you know, don't follow, you know, the textbook, they do something weird or they throw in the twist or they do something clever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, Ooh, look at that clever thing they did in this book.
Scott: Like for example, Hyperion does a clever thing, right?
Rym: But this does a lot of clever things too.
Scott: It does, but it does a clever thing.
Scott: So it stands out.
Scott: This book is pretty much how to write good novel by the book, right?
Scott: Textbook straight down.
Scott: And that's why it's considered like great American novel.
Scott: It doesn't do anything fancy or special.
Scott: It does everything you're supposed to do at an extremely high level of execution.
Rym: Now, case in point, the little bit at the end where Tom is confronted with you fucking murdered Gatsby, basically don't pretend you didn't.
Rym: And his response, that little scene, and it's not even said explicitly, but what he says translates to, I found that dog dead because no one went to check on it.
Rym: The little subtle bits like that and how that counterbalances the fact that Gatsby was murdered and someone else died.
Rym: And yet the fact that the main character knows that Gatsby didn't even do it, that it was Daisy's fault.
Rym: It's just, it's also delicately interwoven and brilliant for such a short little book.
Rym: It's just perfectly constructed.
Rym: It's like a symphony that's just written by the book.
Rym: It's a perfect symphony.
Rym: You have no complaint about it, except perhaps that it's not avant-garde.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: But in a way, right, that can actually come out.
Scott: kind of boring is, you know, that, that, you know, you did something so plainly, like imagine a bat.
Rym: Well, in the same way that Citizen Kane seems really boring to most people.
Scott: Imagine if you had a basketball game and you won by a zillion points because you played so well, but all you did was just take shots and make layups.
Scott: No fancy dunks, no fancy trick plays or behind the back passes.
Scott: Just, you know, take it the whole layup every time.
Rym: The most boring football game is run, pass, run, march up the field, touchdown, run, pass, run, march up the field.
Scott: No Hail Marys, no onside kicks.
Rym: You want to see the onside kick, the two-point conversion, but there's nothing fancy going on here.
Scott: It's straightforward, but it scores a zillion points and runs up the score and the opponent's got nothing.
Rym: But meanwhile, our listeners had none of this umbrage with the King Killer Chronicle, both sexy Rops through the world.
Rym: That's the XFL.
Rym: You're going to tell me that you prefer the XFL because it's so exciting.
Scott: No, it's because, you know, like I, I keep bringing this argument up.
Scott: It's the same thing we've been discussing since the beginning of internets.
Scott: And, you know, time really is that most people, they read, they have a piece of entertainment media.
Scott: They have a feeling, a reaction to it as all people do.
Scott: If that feeling is positive, they rate it as good and they like it or their favorite or whatever.
Scott: And if they get a bad feeling from it personally, they say, that's not to my taste.
Scott: I don't like it.
Scott: It's bad.
Scott: And that's there.
Scott: That's the limit of their critique abilities.
Scott: I, you know, I think it's more subtle than that.
Rym: I think it's more specific.
Rym: I think there's a very, very specific problem that I see among, not to stereotype, but younger people who happen to be our listeners or nerdy like this.
Rym: You don't identify with a character or a setting.
Rym: And therefore you somehow translate that into saying the work is bad.
Scott: I don't identify.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: is they had a negative feeling towards it.
Scott: And like I said, my feelings toward it, weren't extremely positive.
Scott: They're only slightly positive.
Rym: I cannot identify with the in the Prince of nothing.
Rym: I'm not a fat old sad wizard, but I can still recognize the work.
Scott: as look at this craftsmanship.
Scott: It's a miracle.
Rym: It's like all things considered, but you know what?
Rym: I don't identify with Katniss, a teenage girl with teenage girl thoughts.
Rym: But when you tell me it's a bad book, because you can't identify with the teenage girl, because you're a 30 year old dude, that's not a criticism of the work.
Rym: That's a criticism of you as a person who would enjoy that work.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, yeah, it's not for you, but you should still be able to recognize whether it's good or bad, regardless of whether it's for you or not.
Scott: I mean, see, you know, uh, Reagan C spot run isn't for me, but I can tell whether it's a good kids book or not by reading it and checking it out.
Scott: Uh, I mean, I can go to the museum and I can look at a statue and I can, you know, I don't know that much about sculpture, but I know a little, and I can tell, oh, look at how well this was crafted.
Scott: This was made by a freaking Greek dude centuries ago with a chisel and a hammer and only shit.
Scott: It looks like fucking real person.
Scott: That is fucking unbelievable.
Scott: What?
Scott: I want to put it in my house.
Scott: No, I don't really like it, but I can recognize the, basically the miracle of craftsmanship.
Scott: And that is what this book is.
Rym: Uh, like remember when he goes, uh, the main character goes home for me to hang out with his family for a little bit, that whole description of like the train ride and every description of everything is, is off the chart.
Rym: It's just, and I think the reason this book has endured so well and is remembered separately and above other works that describe a similar time in a similar place or have similar motifs or similar sort of morals and themes is that this one in particular really spoke to this sort of generation of 25 to 35 year olds from major cities or who have lived in major cities.
Rym: It also really spoke to a generation coming out of world war one.
Rym: And I think that just kind of cemented it in American culture, but also the fact that it really is timeless piece.
Rym: I mean, I live in the place where this book supposedly takes place, like parts of it.
Rym: I mean, long islands, not too far away.
Rym: They drove right through where Scott and I live and it's still like that here.
Rym: Like I can see those places and I can see people who are just like these characters, people commuting on the exact same mistakes in their real life.
Rym: They're only different.
Rym: I think a lot of people are making these mistakes that might be made uncomfortable by the book because they don't recognize that because the, you know, the book is kind of saying whenever
Scott: a book has something to say to a person and that person is reading the book, that person never recognized that it's them.
Rym: How many fedora fedora wearing brony?
Rym: nice guys don't realize that they're just a sad sack version of Gatsby.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, literally you are a sad sack version of Gatsby.
Rym: If you're that fedora, nice guy, because Gatsby is the fedora nice guy.
Rym: The fedora is his mansion, his affectations.
Rym: The nice guy is just his weird unrealistic expectations about this girl and her relationship with him and her relationship with the people around her.
Rym: She's dating that biker asshole.
Rym: And that biker assholes racism is.
Rym: there are people like that today who are exactly the same kind of racist.
Rym: Like that is not changed.
Rym: I know people like that.
Scott: You want to hear a funny racist story from today?
Scott: What is one of those guys outside my work?
Scott: He's trying to, you know, give CDs out.
Rym: Right.
Rym: The typical.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And he himself is a black person.
Scott: And he's obviously trying to get tourists to, to trap them and give him money in exchange for his bad rap CD that you do that he made.
Scott: And he calls out to this one tourist and he's like, Hey man, where are you from?
Scott: And the guy was a tourist, so he couldn't resist.
Scott: And he said, Norway.
Scott: So the guy says they got Negroes in Norway.
Scott: That's the end of the story.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's great.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: There's people like that.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So I don't know.
Rym: Well, I mean, not to get into a deep, literally literary analysis of the themes and maybe I could summarize the plot for you, but I don't know.
Rym: The book really spoke to me.
Rym: It did get, I think it really speaks to, you know, people in their late twenties, early thirties who have gone beyond the point where they can do anything to having to pick something and actually do it.
Rym: And there's a little bit of ennui there.
Rym: I don't think we're at the point of, it's not that the, you know, a lot of people say this is the book about like the American dream collapsing in that era.
Scott: There's clearly the ennui of like, Hey, you know, we should probably hang out and do something.
Scott: What do you want to do?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Let's go to the hotel and get drunk.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Maybe you should put on some music and dance.
Scott: No one really knows what the fuck to do.
Scott: Or board games or anything, but we do the same thing today.
Scott: It's like, Hey, let's go to Manhattan and do, we should go to Manhattan and do something.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: What should we do?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean that drama of they're all in the uncomfortable situation toward the end and they all decide to go to the hotel and the girl basically, uh, Tom's like, wait, why are we going to the city?
Rym: And Daisy's like, yeah, let's go into the city.
Rym: He's like, fine.
Rym: And he does all the bullshit to organize them going into the city.
Rym: And then at the end of all that, when she's like, well, there's your idea anyway.
Rym: And his reaction to that, I have lived that.
Rym: I have lived that exact reality.
Rym: In fact, Scott, you and I have been in situations like that.
Scott: There is an unstated drama, not a hundred years after this book is written the same thing is still going on.
Rym: In fact, I recall a specific time.
Rym: We all ended up at a restaurant, a whole bunch of us with a person that would be a source of drama.
Rym: Everyone's uncomfortable.
Rym: No one will account.
Rym: We'll do it directly.
Rym: One of our friends got speed and we lived through everything but the death, including the drive home, the separate cars, who goes in what car, the two people who aren't dating.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Uh, I won't name names on the show because some of these people might listen, but we know two people who each were dating other people who ended up with each other later, who had that situation of they rode in the car together, home from the thing.
Rym: This book is a hundred years after the book.
Rym: It's exactly what happens in American relationships today.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So if you can't identify with this book, read it again when you turn 29 and you still can't identify with it.
Scott: Move to a city and stop being a provincial stick liver.
Rym: I defy anyone to live in a major city like New York, hit the age of 35 and not be able to identify with this book.
Scott: And not be, you can't be a shut-in either.
Scott: Shut-in won't understand it.
Scott: It's hard to have some social life to understand.
Rym: It is hard to move to New York and still be a shut-in.
Scott: There are shut-ins here.
Scott: They get delivery for everything.
Rym: Ah, but then you have to be independently wealthy or have a sugar daddy.
Rym: In which case, but you still feel to afford rent.
Scott: Telecommute living.
Rym: But then you're not living in the city.
Scott: No, they telecommute and they live in the city.
Rym: Where do they live in the city then?
Scott: In some shitty apartment.
Rym: Yeah, some shitty apartment, probably far enough away to where they're not going to be interacting with all this.
Scott: Yeah, they're not long island taking the train.
Rym: It's a rare person who is going to be able to live in a city, be 35 and not realize how directly relevant everything that happens in this book is to real life.
Rym: I don't know what else I have to say.
Scott: I mean, I know there's a whole bunch of symbolism you can talk about.
Scott: Like if you were going to give an exam on this book, you would talk about like, what's the green light?
Rym: Why does it symbolize what it does?
Scott: You're talking about the green light.
Rym: The unattainable dream versus the reality.
Rym: His desire for her was only pure when she was an unattainable thing in the distance.
Rym: The reality actually destroyed the dream.
Scott: Or you can talk about the eyeglasses on the billboard across from the mechanic shop being like the eyes of God and watching everybody.
Rym: If we wrote The Great Gatsby today.
Scott: And how the owl-eyed guy matches with the owl-eyed doctor optician poster.
Rym: Scott, if we wrote this book today, you know what those eyes are?
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Zizemore.
Scott: It's Dr.
Scott: Zizemore.
Scott: That would be skin and not eyes.
Rym: That is the thing I would use if I was writing The Great Gatsby today as something that if you live in New York, it's like, yeah, everyone knows.
Scott: But I think this is a made up optician and not a real one.
Rym: But you need that kind of detail.
Rym: Because when I read this book and he described that, I can picture a thing like that because there are things like that.
Rym: People who live here know those things.
Rym: The thing doesn't actually need to exist.
Rym: The idea of that kind of thing needs to exist.
Scott: But I mean, and I can totally get that feel of, you know, the feeling of billboard sort of watching, even if it doesn't have eyes at work.
Scott: I'm in Times Square.
Scott: I'm on the seventh floor.
Scott: It's friggin billboards right outside the window.
Scott: And it's like, when you sit near one of those windows, it's like friggin.
Scott: whatever's out there is like upon you all the time.
Scott: You know, so it's like.
Scott: I bet this mechanic looking out his window was a lot like me looking out the window at work on my desk was in the other position.
Scott: You know, seeing that billboard sort of imposing on your space all the time, you know, sort of watching him and the way he treated his, you know, wife, I guess technically wife, right, and all the things that went on there.
Scott: And anyone who came across, you know, but yeah.
Scott: All right, do you have anything else to say about this book?
Rym: No, so what's the next book?
Scott: What is the next book?
Scott: So here we go.
Scott: Usually and recently I had a policy of pick a book that I own that is on my shelf that I have not read so that I can read it and get it and eventually have read all the books that are already on my shelf and not buy any new books made of paper.
Rym: So did you do just that?
Rym: I
Scott: was about to do just that and then I had selected a book from the shelf that I had not read yet,
Rym: but
Scott: I discovered the existence of a previously unknown to me book that is such a I swear
Rym: to god if you say some book that everyone's read
Scott: now that is such a GeekNights' book.
Scott: there could not be a more GeekNights.
Scott: scott rubin book.
Scott: i've only started reading it.
Scott: i'm like in the second very early on.
Scott: my kindle is only less than 20. so far nothing.
Scott: no.
Scott: uh it might even be more GeekNights than prince of nothing.
Scott: huh i haven't finished it i don't know yet but here you you're gonna you know okay.
Scott: so anyway i was told of a series of books uh by our friend alex.
Scott: do you know this?
Scott: yet?
Scott: uh we mentioned it maybe the last book club a little bit or maybe in a recent episode i forget.
Scott: there is a series of books written by a person named ian m banks about a thing called the culture which is apparently i don't know too much about it.
Scott: uh because i'm only partially through one book.
Scott: uh that is some sort of far futuristic utopia of awesomeness and high technology.
Scott: that is exactly the kind of place we would want to live to be awesome for us.
Scott: and the second book in this series we're skipping over the first book which is called flavors.
Scott: consider i forget what it's called something like that.
Scott: the second book in this series which i've been told you can read without having read the first one is called player of games and it is about a guy who is pretty much the best game player there is in this utopian society.
Rym: and according to the small the text on the back of the book i could search through my email and find how many listeners have emailed me to say wait i should read this book over the last.
Scott: yeah according to the back of the book it's about how he supposedly gets entangled into some civilization where you play games to become the emperor or something like that.
Scott: so i could not imagine just based on that summary alone and the partial bits i the beginning that i've read so far.
Scott: this is like someone wrote this book thinking like oh let me write a book for Rym and Scott here those those nerdy cyberpunk progressive utopian game player guys.
Scott: let's write a book for them and that is this book.
Rym: so no benjuka there's.
Scott: they play other games besides benjuka.
Scott: that might as well be fucking benjuka already been like three or four of them.
Scott: um yeah so that is the book club book.
Scott: it is player of games by ian m banks.
Scott: you can just get it almost anywhere.
Scott: it is the second book in the culture series.
Scott: so if you want emily is very excited about this book.
Rym: if you want to read it you can.
Scott: maybe you can read the first culture series book if you want.
Scott: i'm probably gonna go back and read that too because i can't because the the only thing i tell you so far is that not having read the first book in the culture series i'm not sure how much i'm supposed to know about the culture.
Scott: a lot of it you can just pick up on as you go along but it's like.
Scott: you know.
Scott: they just sort of have an.
Scott: it's sort of like reading a marvel comic not knowing the marvel universe.
Scott: right it's like yeah okay who's you know?
Scott: daredevil he's a lawyer.
Scott: i didn't know that you know.
Scott: and it's like oh the culture there's.
Scott: no you know there's a thing called contact that finds alien civilizations and it's sort of secret and awesome.
Scott: okay i didn't know that you know but you pick up on it anyway.
Scott: that's the book all right.
Scott: then i will go back to my other policy.
Rym: watch our watch our videos read the book join the forum join scott's grand prix join the grand prix.
Scott: if you have balls or want to measure them come see us at pax.
Scott: that's it.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening cat lee for web design and brando k for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.