Rym: It's Wednesday October 23rd 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Take the x-train.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: I can't believe we haven't done a show on this movie But at the same time you can't believe nobody's even talked about this thing in a zillion years.
Rym: But there are.
Rym: there are relevant anecdotes that there is a history of this movie and us There are there.
Rym: there are reasons why we're talking about it.
Rym: We've said for years around Halloween.
Rym: Oh, we should do a Halloween special Why don't we do?
Rym: take the x-train and then you tonight's anniversary special and then we just never Did.
Scott: yeah, it's Halloween, which means let's see It's o 13. so 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 3 we can count like that.
Scott: This would be beginning our 8th year.
Rym: 8th year of GeekNights.
Scott: We nights was a little kid.
Scott: It would be an 8 year old kid be like, hey kid.
Scott: What's up?
Scott: How's it going?
Rym: and also while we started on Baby instead, right?
Scott: Hmm instead of making GeekNights.
Scott: We could have made a bad V Maybe not together.
Scott: In so, you know, they got technology.
Rym: these we did start on October 31st.
Rym: But here's the deep secret of GeekNights for many.
Rym: We have a lot of new listeners from recent conventions.
Rym: one We actually started months before that doing beta episodes that we only let our.
Rym: we only gave links to our friends.
Rym: We were like, hey, we're doing this dumb podcast thing.
Rym: insert explanation of what a podcast is because that didn't really exist in a As a thing back then.
Scott: it just come into existence.
Scott: So, I mean it what did did exist for a while before then but it didn't come into popular existence.
Scott: It's like I do our day.
Scott: the iPod nano was released.
Scott: They updated iTunes and added podcasting in the podcast directory and that is the flyers we brought to.
Rym: Otakon 2006 had a section that was like what is a podcast?
Rym: How do you listen to them?
Rym: Good good old days.
Scott: don't need an iPod.
Scott: Yeah, you can play mp3s.
Scott: You can listen.
Rym: I think I have the flyers around somewhere.
Rym: I can go find exactly what text we wrote but regardless.
Rym: So we did all these beta episodes before that.
Rym: it seems like our listeners kind of obsessed with finding them and they're out there.
Rym: I checked.
Rym: you can just go download it.
Scott: There's not that many of them.
Rym: There's a decent number.
Rym: I think all the betas are up there.
Rym: I don't think there's any unreleased GeekNights at this point.
Scott: Mmm, but Yeah, the reason we never did a show some lost episodes, but those got deleted by accident or some shit.
Scott: So there's no way to bring them back.
Rym: Yep And then there's some collections of outtakes and there's a lot of beta episodes.
Rym: we recorded but didn't put up because they were shitty.
Rym: And then I think we just deleted them, but we put a lot of them online.
Rym: So, uh, yeah News time.
Rym: well news time very briefly because anime people tell there's a big overlap.
Rym: Yeah packs is sold out.
Scott: Oh, that's a shame.
Rym: Thanks East 2014 in April is sold out.
Scott: That's a shame.
Rym: It went live today.
Rym: We I can't.
Rym: there's no point in even saying Oh, well, we you know We warned you whatever because the thing is warning doesn't even help.
Scott: any people seem to have heeded the warning this time And it was just who got in and who didn't.
Rym: it's a crapshoot.
Rym: There's nothing you can do to have a better chance of getting into packs.
Scott: unless one exhibit be a loser Every day that is not packs and all you do is reload to enforce.
Rym: Try to be an enforcer.
Rym: if you can't.
Scott: cool enough be cool enough that they let you be an enforcer.
Rym: three submit Panels and lectures.
Scott: be cool enough that they accept them granted the the longer we do this.
Rym: There's sort of this if they ever turn us down and they're like no Rym and Scott.
Rym: You can't do a lecture this year Fuck that would like.
Rym: that would ruin my day at this point Like I couldn't even go.
Rym: like I don't have a badge.
Rym: unless they let us in to do that They don't let us enforce either.
Rym: I know they're like, yeah, we don't need you as enforcer anymore.
Rym: And yeah, we don't need your very popular panels anymore.
Rym: You guys are too mean.
Rym: Oh too smelly.
Rym: some reason.
Rym: Oh, I would be so sad.
Rym: But yeah, if you wanted badges you can pretty much up.
Rym: There's still some Fridays left and there's still some Sundays left, but there aren't hotels.
Rym: But just to reiterate their hotels on the other side of town, ah, they're rapidly selling out.
Scott: I was poking around in this area even the ones over in the good in the.
Rym: you know It's not sold out.
Scott: the Midtown Hotel the one that's far away from anime Boston Let alone you can get a hotel like maybe you know on the tee dude.
Rym: The airport hotel was sold out of Thursdays and Sundays.
Rym: yeah, but If You need a hotel and you can't get one and you try to complain about this There is literally nothing anyone you could complain to can do about that.
Rym: Like it sucks that it's hard to get hotels find someone wait for someone to cancel and yeah No.
Rym: so I have actually I Talked to the hotels and the Westin at length and I have two emails from them from a year ago that I have the numbers.
Rym: Not.
Rym: as in 2012 95% of the people who booked a room for Pax did not cancel it by the time Pax.
Scott: no No, but there might be someone who's like hey I need someone in my room or they can't it off to someone.
Scott: or you know that wasn't a Cancel at the hotel level but that person may have canceled on.
Rym: Pat, you know stuff like that happens But it the people the the less than 5% of people who have a room Cancel it at any point and the hotels do not let you transfer a room to someone else's name.
Rym: in most cases.
Scott: No, they don't but how many times do you hear the story?
Scott: like all my friends bailed on me so I can't go now.
Scott: I hear that story every pack.
Rym: Oh, yeah I hear that story too, but a lot of those people don't have a room in the hotel block in the first place.
Scott: Maybe but you know what when that story happens That's your one chance and then all the other people who failed to get that one chance.
Scott: Well, no chance.
Rym: Yep But yeah, this is a convention that's occurring in April next.
Scott: we even mentioned this news.
Scott: every time it happens I feel like it's gonna be a two time a year news no matter what forever.
Rym: Yeah The only reason I mention it is just because it seems like no one remembers everything I said when this happened for Prime and it Sold out super fast guys.
Rym: It is a physical impossibility to make this better.
Rym: There is literally nothing that can be done.
Scott: There is something that can be done.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yes, the government could build a gigantic Convention Center and a hotel complex.
Scott: There's something else that can be done, huh?
Scott: You could have the Pax's simultaneously.
Rym: Uh, if they were simultaneous, I think I would go to Pax Prime me too and I Think we would send a DVD to Pax's like I don't think Want our DVD.
Rym: they might our DVD be good.
Rym: We could do a telepresence.
Rym: Oh That would actually be cool would be good.
Scott: They could.
Rym: they could alternate every year like one year.
Rym: They go to you know, Mike and Jerry actually go to Easton prime back and forth, but they're simultaneous and then they just Simuls cast to both conventions maybe on a delay because of time zones all the big events.
Scott: Hmm another thing they could do is Some crazy crazy crazy rich person could just build a hotel Convention Center because you know, they want to yeah But it would be it would lose money.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't say that they wouldn't.
Rym: I just said so we need an eccentric crazy rich person.
Scott: Well, you mean crazy isn't enough.
Rym: Well, did you mean crazy crazy or crazy rich?
Rym: as in he is crazy rich.
Rym: because if you say crazy rich He's just really rich crazy crazy.
Rym: I'm a crazy rich crazy comma rich person.
Rym: Okay Yeah, but if he's just rich he might not be able to make her crazy and also mega rich person.
Rym: The the plan for that convention mega rich crazy person in flushing was something like 14 billion dollars.
Rym: So you'd have to be pretty fucking rich.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: So maybe crazy fucking rich.
Rym: No, because that still doesn't imply crazy comma mega rich crazy person.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yes that works.
Rym: Okay So in the news, you guys might remember Ayumi Hamasaki.
Rym: I was a huge fan of her J-pop stylings in the early 2000s as well as I as I still am.
Rym: I am also still a fan of Hamasaki.
Scott: she has an album called I am.
Scott: yeah, that's what I'd say I am
Rym: It just ever mind, you know There's a news about her and it kind of took me back to that era because when I got into anime When in when I was in you know, I was fourth grade I was a young kid and then later I found Japanese music once MP3s existed and I downloaded some music from Megumi and I was a big fan of Megumi.
Rym: But then I found out that there were more j-pop people than her because she was the only person Americans knew about back then.
Rym: Like even hardcore anime fans would be hard-pressed to name anyone who was a j-pop idol other than Megumi Hashibara.
Rym: And then Ayumi kind of got popular right when MP3 stuff.
Rym: yeah to mix but that there's two vitals.
Rym: and Anyway, there were they really j-pop?
Rym: are they more?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: It's Japanese.
Scott: Genaro J-tech No, whatever.
Rym: regardless Ayumi Hamasaki is singing the opening to an anime and she hasn't done this in over a decade.
Rym: hmm and The anime happens to be Buddha - I didn't even see Buddha one.
Rym: I did not either.
Scott: I recommend reading the manga Buddha.
Rym: It's probably one of the best mangas there is Yes, and the anime looks pretty good too at some point.
Scott: Well when the maybe after the second I'd probably if I had to rank all-time best mangas, it would probably be Best or favorite Phoenix Akira then Buddha.
Scott: so third best manga ever.
Scott: What about wounded man?
Scott: In the top part it's on the bottom.
Rym: So Yeah, Buddha movie - is coming Tezuka's Buddha, so it's got all the Buddha and all the Tezuka.
Scott: How much Tezuka made it to the movie because they removed a lot of the Tezuka from the Phoenix anime that they did which the Read away made the anime work better, but it means that now they're basically two separate works.
Rym: Then you need to consume both of them.
Scott: Yeah, if you want the wacky Tezuka shit.
Rym: Yeah, I enjoy the wacky Tezuka shit.
Rym: It has its place in Buddha.
Scott: It's a little bit out of it's crazy anyway.
Scott: So news this is sort of a really narrow news, but People out there.
Scott: They may be reading the webcomics Right and one webcomic that we have been reading for a long ass fucking time is anime news Nina.
Scott: yep, we've we've talked at length about why we like anime news Nina, and it's on the anime news network website and Today they posted the penultimate strip of anime news Nina ever.
Rym: This is the second time I've been surprised by something like that ending without me paying attention and not realizing it was ending.
Rym: But it's all politics that podcast.
Rym: I really like one day.
Rym: I just listen to an episode.
Rym: They're like yeah, it's the last episode at the end of the show.
Rym: and then like the credits rolled I just thought it was a joke.
Rym: and then the next week like there wasn't another episode.
Rym: yeah in the next week There wasn't another episode.
Scott: Yeah, so there's gonna be one more anime news Nina, and then there's gonna be zero more anime news Nina's.
Scott: It's so sad.
Rym: I know.
Scott: But yeah, you should read that webcomic.
Rym: well now you know that it ends.
Rym: They're just read it all the way through and you know what the read.
Rym: the way I would sell anime news Nina to you is thus it Makes fun of anime and anime fans in a way that is hilarious to anime fans, but also offensive to the kinds of anime fans we don't like.
Rym: That's the best way I can put it it.
Rym: It is it portrays those guys in the way that those guys need to be portrayed.
Scott: also hot news elves.
Rym: Is that the main reason you read?
Rym: no I am an elf in games.
Rym: I don't like elves.
Scott: in fact everyone get your audio editing software.
Rym: Dude, I played I was talking to tar about this at burning con.
Rym: if you take all the role-playing games I've played in my entire life all of them every session and add up the hours having played different races in all games I've easily surpassed 70 or 80 percent elf.
Rym: Okay, and price 60% fruity elf with a sword and possibly dancing and gold flecked eyes And all that yet.
Rym: I play elves is what I do.
Scott: You're not a news off them now.
Rym: News elves are far more powerful than I ever was but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: so there is an amusement park called or hotel and attract the park Wonderland called car.
Rym: it's in Germany.
Rym: I guess yes.
Rym: It's in Germany, and there's an interesting thing about this nuclear power plant.
Rym: It's an amusement park.
Rym: This is an old abandoned nuclear power plant that was turned into a family amusement park with rides.
Scott: That's the best thing ever like.
Rym: look at this.
Rym: That's just a nuclear power plant straight up.
Rym: Yeah, and there's the park in the background.
Rym: They made rides inside of the cooling tower and the entire outside of the cooling tower is a rock climbing course.
Scott: And it's all not radioactive anymore.
Rym: I'm assuming.
Rym: It's not radioactive.
Scott: That's the best thing ever.
Rym: yeah check out this photo archives.
Scott: It's probably the cheapest as land ever.
Scott: cuz probably no one wanted it and some genius Figured out how to build a music park for cheap.
Rym: Yes, probably raking it in the 130-foot tall Condensation cooling tower has rock climbing.
Scott: Right you're not gonna sweat your brains out.
Rym: Well there would be an updraft.
Scott: I guess yeah Yeah, you know what's really awesome is how you notice amusement parks are always built.
Scott: I'm like really cheap.
Scott: weird land like Disney World was built like this fucking swamp that no one wanted.
Rym: So should we make Paxton in like some godforsaken place exactly?
Rym: ah so maybe I don't want to be like the old Trini Underground rocket bunkers.
Scott: those are popular.
Rym: those aren't big enough Don't?
Scott: they have giant rooms down?
Rym: I'm not big enough.
Rym: out next to the silos My mom and stepdad and I were exploring the entrance to one of those that we found out in the desert.
Scott: It's like the silos are too tall for a fax, but this I thought this giant control rooms They're not.
Rym: they're not that big and they're all.
Rym: the space is kind of echoey.
Rym: They're better places.
Scott: I think Detroit You know what it's centrally located.
Rym: yep, they're one of the biggest airports in the world is why do you transportation hotels?
Rym: Tons of gigantic convention centers that fucking put it in Cobo Hall.
Rym: It's better than be more Yeah, it's a lot better than be more main events Joe Lewis like now that Otakon has left be more.
Rym: Who's ever gonna go to Baltimore again?
Rym: Here's a nerd unless they live there.
Scott: Oh, who's a nerd?
Scott: nobody, but yeah Ravens fans Orioles fans Ravens fans are already there.
Rym: I'm just saying they can't get out otherwise they wouldn't be.
Scott: some of them live you know slightly far away from yeah But they're in their craft in the gravity.
Rym: The sad part about this article is that part of the reason this plan exists is that Germany's decided to phase out nuclear power Like a lot of countries are doing Reactively, which is just gonna fuck us down the road, but that's a. that's a Monday topic.
Rym: Maybe a Thursday topic.
Rym: I won't ruin your precious anime fan sensibilities by talking about it right now.
Scott: Hmm all right anyway.
Scott: Yeah thing of the day.
Scott: So it's almost Halloween the anniversary of GeekNights.
Scott: Halloween is what is is a big nerd holiday these days the day of spookiness and So of course in celebration of Halloween you know one of the ghosts came out of wherever ghosts come from early And he wanted people.
Scott: he wanted to get his party on so he went to rob the liquor store.
Scott: so check this out.
Scott: It's a video.
Scott: You know this guy Whoever took this video should go call James Randi because he's gonna win his million dollar prize for supernatural currencies.
Scott: There's a ghost robbing his liquor store.
Rym: I Wonder I gotta check right now.
Rym: I wonder if anyone's ever made a video of the ghosting prank that people would do at RIT Because if not I know we need to do okay.
Rym: Oh a lot of different kind of ghost a lot of people call have ghosting different things, so I'm gonna explain to you.
Rym: Here's my Halloween gift.
Rym: RIT had a particular prank that might just have been a thing and I never saw it happen for happen on my floor once.
Scott: Well your floor was.
Rym: my floor was fish be.
Rym: Fish be was a special in the crazy place.
Rym: There's a reason I spent most of my time over at Peterson 3.
Scott: like that place is infamous And then it's.
Scott: I learned later like Oh Rym lives there.
Rym: fuck yeah Why do you think I was remembered?
Rym: sometimes like you come down to the lounge in Peterson?
Rym: I'd already be there.
Rym: So I also that roommate who I didn't know his name the whole time I lived there in your room was like the only room.
Rym: yeah, because it was me and quiet, dude I literally I lived there was the guy a whole year Set my I would be work playing counter-strike.
Rym: and because the room was so small He was sitting next to me looking behind looking in the opposite direction.
Rym: I never knew his name never said a word to him other than once.
Rym: he told me I think something blew up in your fridge, and that's when I found out that my wine bottle exploded and ruined the carpet, but I digress.
Rym: Ghosting is as such.
Rym: you're in a college dorm Hopefully a dorm other than your dorm floor.
Rym: You make a ghost costume by cutting two holes in a sheet and putting it over your head.
Rym: You walk onto the floor you walk into someone's open door going You wait for them to kind of laugh.
Rym: Then you suddenly knock everything over that you can knock over as fast as possible and then run And they don't know who did it.
Rym: because As long as you get away And you will likely get away because they won't think to chase after you quick enough and as soon as you get into a stairwell And there's no camera you ditch that sheet and maybe possible deniability.
Rym: yep, so I'm not saying that you should do this prank That I actually advise you should rob a liquor store because you're gonna need some booze on Halloween for your party.
Rym: so yeah, I met a moment.
Rym: There's a big change happening to the GeekNights forum.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: so big news.
Scott: Basically since we've had some forum issues where people couldn't join and there was spam and all these things that are hurting this community.
Scott: Now right we decided that we're gonna go and basically pay to have vanilla host our forum for us Which will make the forum way better and have better searching and all the things that people wanted.
Scott: The problem is our forum is so popular it's gonna cost us $150 a month which is a lot of monies Even though we have monies.
Scott: We don't have that much monies.
Scott: That's a lot of fucking monies.
Scott: That's like three times my internet bill.
Scott: so one You ungrateful fuckers you're right, so we're gonna probably you know put like a little donate button on the side And maybe give some bonuses to people who give us monies.
Rym: But don't worry because you might recall from our new bonuses not bullshit bonus.
Rym: you might remember from our numerous lectures on such topics.
Rym: We understand that changing the rules of a community changes the community and are not stupid people.
Rym: so trust us also.
Rym: this may Predicate the return of merchandise because I want to recoup some of this money.
Rym: But the main reason we have to do this is that you might have noticed We've never had an ad on any YouTube video or GeekNights thing we've ever done other than the ad you block on the side Of the forum.
Scott: yep, and so that ad you block on the side of the forum will still be there.
Rym: yes But we're not going to change that.
Rym: we're not going to start putting ads on our YouTube videos even though actually Based on the YouTube numbers we get we could get a reasonable amount from that.
Rym: I refuse no and I refuse to put ads in GeekNights.
Rym: You don't be ungrateful fuckers and stay tuned for other changes related to this so we can make.
Scott: toss us a dollar instead of giving It to that homeless guy who's just gonna buy booze with it.
Rym: should we get someone dressed up like a preacher man and do a Revival at the end of every one of our panels and then pass the collection basket?
Scott: We would not be allowed back at conventions up.
Rym: some conventions would not notice or care.
Scott: some some some.
Rym: I've had some conventions we could charge at the door and no one would notice right.
Scott: other Meta things the book club book is Stasi land.
Rym: I have now read six six books.
Rym: in the time It's taken Scott to read this book.
Scott: I was reading torch bear and Torch bear.
Rym: it's gonna be seven when I finish torch bear, and I've been reading Some deep 3ds games.
Rym: I'm now in fact an expert on the culture.
Rym: Yeah, so oh yeah, and the new luck Lamora book powering through that.
Scott: Also, we'll probably do that book.
Scott: I'll probably do the episode.
Scott: if we just say right now that we're gonna do the episode next Thursday No matter what I guess I'll read it enough.
Rym: Okay, okay?
Rym: It's next Thursday Halloween.
Rym: I don't think we're doing a show.
Scott: why not?
Rym: because I'm gonna go to a fancy party.
Scott: Let me check my calendar.
Scott: It's Halloween.
Scott: It is you want to go.
Rym: I'm going to a fancy party.
Rym: I'm gonna do a video game party.
Rym: Maybe we'll record a Halloween special ahead of time.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: yeah unlikely.
Rym: well.
Rym: So the next Thursday after Halloween unless I'm in Istanbul or something we'll do Stasi lens to four Thursdays from third tomorrow.
Rym: Whatever kids we used to do four shows a week for you.
Scott: You've been way lax on Thursday episodes and Mondays like we are missing them all over the place.
Scott: We might as well.
Scott: just why don't we just only do Tuesday's whatever?
Rym: I have found that when we do fewer episodes We have more lists more listens early on of the episodes.
Rym: we do do Mmm, but we have more total overall in the long run if we do more episodes.
Rym: Also, there's a tumblr that is auto-tweeting occasionally I'm still tweaking the format to get it right But it is a curated collection of interesting and notable old episodes of GeekNights because there are a fucking ton of them.
Scott: Someone actually told me they actually use.
Scott: there's a. there's still an RSS feed that puts out a random Episode every day, and they said they still use that.
Rym: where did we make that?
Scott: I made it.
Rym: I didn't know that existed.
Rym: you fucker.
Rym: I'll just use that to populate my tumblr.
Rym: Jesus Christ I thought you but your tumblers curated it is, but I'd rather it be random.
Scott: Yes Completely random.
Rym: I got you actually.
Rym: maybe I'll make that.
Rym: I'll have a random tumblr that doesn't tweet and a curated tumblr.
Rym: You're making too many things because these things are all trivial to make and they're driving traffic.
Scott: people like them All right.
Scott: anything else to say.
Scott: meta wise.
Rym: uh there there is.
Scott: at least go to magfest dumbasses.
Rym: Yeah, the Gaylord is here.
Rym: He's sold out Pax.
Scott: what the hell are you not going to magfest?
Rym: yeah, Jesus half our friends are.
Rym: even You were.
Scott: if you wanted to buy Pax East tickets and could not get hotel and or badge Why the?
Scott: and you're not going to magfest which you can easily get hotel and badge?
Scott: what the fuck is wrong with you.
Rym: magfest is Better than Pax in a few narrow specific ways in fact.
Scott: I'm gonna tweet right now.
Rym: one.
Rym: It's 24/7 hotel con.
Rym: Pax is not 24/7 like that - it has an arcade the literal size of a football field Physical arcade with all free-to-play.
Rym: three the tabletop space in the con is 24/7.
Rym: Otherwise, it's pretty much worse than Pax and every other way, but those things are better than Pax and also you can actually get badges And also the staff don't enforce a lot.
Rym: so a lot of people are really drunk and doing crazy crap and the culture is kind Of weird and it's not like other cons.
Rym: someday They're gonna get sued in my non-professional non-lawyer opinion after something goes down, but I'm just a panelist I don't.
Rym: I'm not a staff so it's super funny.
Rym: You should go so many.
Scott: many years ago We were in the RIT anime club And they liked to choose things to show based on certain factors and one time was Halloween.
Scott: So they wanted to pick something scary or supernatural horror based.
Rym: and now When the when we chose shows when the exact this is before we were - yes but when?
Rym: but when I was on the executive board and I saw the process we Pointedly did not show the club what they said they wanted to see because that actually drove away the majority of people.
Rym: So we pointedly
Scott: if I remember the thing that drew the most people ever was like Matt cross plus the movie
Rym: Yep one of the other biggest showings we ever did was the first four episodes of gravitation because we did a joint promotion with the LGBT acronym clubs on campus and it was crazy huge.
Rym: This was not one of our more popular showings No, so what was chosen was a movie that even then in the RIT anime club significantly more hardcore than your average bear Nobody knew what the fuck this movie was and
Scott: all the people who fans of did Which were some of the people right at the time?
Scott: Some of the people who ran the anime club were like in the fan sub rings and circles.
Scott: Yes and they like to choose the things to show that they fan subbed and then Not distribute those fan subs in any way shape or form it.
Scott: So it was like some of the early.
Scott: they'd like to feel all high and mighty because they would fan sub something show it at The anime club and then you would never be able to see it again and like yeah, aren't we awesome?
Rym: Yep, some of the early marmalade boy fan subs were shown at our club and were not available anywhere else.
Rym: Gatekeepers and then the drama around.
Rym: gatekeepers 21, but we've talked about some of that in the past.
Rym: So notable line.
Rym: the first There is a man in the credits of the fan sub Ken Hashimoto.
Rym: the blur.
Rym: Ken Hashimoto was a friend of ours at RIT.
Scott: He was he was his.
Scott: was he the treasurer.
Rym: I don't fucking know where the secretary was.
Rym: the blur.
Scott: the blur He is.
Scott: the blur is on the internet.
Scott: mega Tokyo.
Rym: He was in mega Tokyo friends with those guys and to this day We know for a fact that he overheard us making this elaborate joke Discussion about mosh mosh revolution and it appeared uncredited in mega Tokyo the next week Mm-hmm,
Scott: and he was sort of friends with what's-his-face
Rym: Yep, and there was a. there's a long and some of the stories around him get into his name.
Scott: who makes mega Tokyo?
Rym: Fred Gallagher?
Scott: Yeah, he was sort of friends with that guy.
Rym: Yep, and there's other dramas around this guy.
Rym: There was there was a fun drama circle around the fan suburbs and this guy and mega Tokyo some stories.
Rym: We've told some stories we can't tell ever publicly fun stuff and he's credited for Translating the missing lines.
Rym: We were watching the movie again and Scott saw that line and I was like what Really?
Rym: But we this was shown at the RIT anime club and there was always a talk at the beginning of the RIT anime club Explaining what the show is and why they were showing it and it was described as being scary and weird.
Scott: Rintaro Which I didn't know who rentaro was back then we met rentaro sort of we did at anime next and no one was there to See him, but us that was the saddest thing in the world.
Rym: sitting in that panel room That was basically empty wall sort of actually saw him by accident.
Rym: Yeah, cuz we didn't know he was in the schedule.
Rym: we walk into this room Like what's going on in here and it's just rentaro being awesome answering Frank questions and just telling great anecdotes.
Rym: So, uh This movie starts.
Scott: Well, I think.
Scott: first of all, you gotta realize this is a 50-minute OVA movie So made wet like the late 80s, I think right, I Made in 87. so this is during the time when there was tons of monies for anime Right, and they were making all the sort of weird experimental animes OAV style and whatnot, right?
Rym: Yeah, so notable things.
Rym: screenplay director rentaro Madhouse.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So this was a pretty high production value thing.
Scott: The animation of this thing is pretty great for its time If you read reviews of still pretty great.
Rym: The interesting thing is that many people say something to the effect of I don't know who this was made for other than Rentaro.
Rym: Yeah, it's made for him by him pretty much.
Scott: It's one of those sort of artsy thing Like it should be in a museum, right?
Scott: You know, it's that kind of anime that kind of thing That would be on sci-fi channel late at night that kind of thing where you watch it late at night and it's all quiet and weird and you sort of fall asleep during it or so touch up.
Rym: the Cool thing is that it's rated kind of highly on anime news network with 41 ratings But - there's a news item linked to it.
Rym: The news item is a fan-subber update from November 18th 1998. whoa, I was in high anime news network.
Scott: Is that old?
Rym: Yes I'm gonna read an excerpt from this news update.
Rym: quote Two fansubbers this week announced the completions of projects that couldn't be distributed first.
Rym: already.
Rym: We're learning things about the culture.
Rym: back then Lupin gang announced golf force two
Scott: and three and
Rym: three and Lupin the third Castle of Cagliostro But did not but did have the public news report that the group had solved their equipment problems and would therefore be able to complete Dan Cougar and bewitching Nozomi and possibly Zeta Gundam in relatively short order.
Scott: and they're just cranking him out.
Rym: Yeah, they managed to find one generation copies of the laser discs of the Lupin the third TV series.
Rym: So they're going to resume work on that shortly.
Rym: It then goes on to talk about gen locks and violinist of Hamlin.
Rym: I Would be hard-pressed.
Rym: All right, I'm gonna name other anime.
Rym: they're listed here high-speed Jessie Cyber formula GPX.
Scott: I know that is Zetsui 1989. never even heard of that.
Rym: take the x-train which yeah blue comet SBT lazer Part of that the Dan Cougar oavs you wrote in samurai troopers Goldfish warning.
Scott: never heard of goldfish warning.
Rym: Yeah, so, uh That is the era of Take the x-train in American fandom the early late 90s is American fandom Early 90s hardcore American fandom late 80s.
Rym: This anime was made.
Rym: It's on YouTube.
Rym: we're gonna link to it.
Rym: you just watch it.
Rym: that's how we watched it again.
Scott: so the anime club showed this and I would say that 3/4 of the audience doesn't walk out fuck out in the first five minutes cuz it was just weird and not Exciting and it didn't really have anything to hook you into it at all.
Scott: Sort of like watching one of those French movies with the clowns crying and what.
Rym: this is the kind of movie that You either have to be into.
Scott: I watch the whole thing at the time and I still like what.
Rym: at the end though I remember feeling sort of, you know, watching people walk out and thinking what the fuck guys, come on It's it's anime and it's weird.
Rym: at least watch it.
Scott: I remember.
Scott: well, I remember feeling at the end like what did I just watch?
Rym: I remember feeling at the end.
Rym: Oh fuck Yes, it was all worth it for that moment.
Rym: No, the moment at the end makes it worth it.
Rym: Also, this is really an anime for someone as if you're.
Rym: if I'm talking to anime fans This is for you If you're the kind of person who has watched a lot of anime.
Rym: You are into anime.
Rym: anime is a big part of your life and you want to see something different or something interesting.
Rym: Something odd because I've noticed that anime fans who get really into anime go to one of two directions they either start watching like all of a show like Naruto or one piece like.
Rym: they'll just watch these ridiculously long kind of bad shows forever or They'll seek out increasingly Strange and off the off the beaten path anime just to find something different from what they've seen before.
Scott: That's what this is.
Scott: That is
Rym: exactly what this is and the people who stayed to the end are Mostly the kinds of people who like the kinds of anime that I like Even though this is not necessarily something that I like but I watching it again now it having been More than a decade since the last time I saw it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I Remembered more about it that I thought I remember - and I actually kind of liked it.
Rym: And I think I like it more now than I liked it back then.
Scott: I do like it more now than back then I wouldn't?
Scott: it's not like my favorite or I don't care about it.
Scott: I don't actively like want to watch it, but it's like it was not offensive to me.
Scott: It was like, okay Yeah, it's a weird dark anime.
Rym: All right Well, I guess what I like about it is that one it gives you that experience of the super slow Oshii movie that goes nowhere, but you don't like that in the Galactic Railroad, even though it's pretty much the same damn thing.
Rym: I Do not like the Galactic Railroad, but I do like sky crawlers same thing Also, which is similarly ponderous and I could talk about why but but this is only 50 minutes.
Scott: this move They managed to make it feel goddamn long.
Scott: This would be only 50 less than an hour.
Rym: if you want to experience one of those super long atmospheric movies that you always fall asleep during.
Rym: You can get that experience in 50 minutes.
Rym: by watching this.
Rym: you'll get the experience of the two-hour interminable movie But you won't have to spend a full two hours.
Scott: All right, so what the hell is it about?
Scott: you have this guy?
Scott: I don't remember his goddamn name.
Rym: a guy who's into trains finally comes of his own.
Scott: Well, he's not that in the trains He just sort of works for a guy who's into trains and that guy he works for is like trying to sell the railroad company Like a new ad campaign and the ad campaign revolves around this one particular train.
Scott: It's really old and like the Emperor wrote in at once.
Scott: Well, it turns out that one particular train is Sort of rusting away in a warehouse unused and is probably gonna be scheduled to be dismantled.
Scott: So this guy he just works for this other train guy.
Scott: He's just do you know?
Rym: Taku he's not a weirdo.
Scott: He's just like a normal boring salaryman kind of means, you know He's got a little bit of punk kind of attitude.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: He's loaded in he's got.
Rym: he's got some personal.
Rym: I'm not saying he's boring as a character But he is definitely not the kind of character you see in a lot of modern anime.
Scott: No So, you know me just living his life doing whatever and then that train disappears.
Scott: and then that train starts driving around town in the form of a ghost train made of electricity and It passes by this guy while he's on the subway platform and he's like what the fuck.
Scott: and so is everyone else.
Scott: cuz just everyone Sees it.
Scott: it's on the news.
Scott: Everyone's looking for it.
Scott: There's no mystery whatsoever.
Scott: It's like yep, that train car disappeared and there's a ghost train Now.
Rym: I'm a big fan of ghost trains Now from this point the movie gets increasingly weird Yep, and the government gets involved and this guy is probably psychic.
Rym: Oh, by the way When I asked you guys what my Twitter avatar was dressed up as and nobody knew take the Rym train.
Rym: Yes, that's that's the guy That's the main character.
Rym: That's mine.
Rym: That's my Twitter costume this year.
Rym: Okay, so Don't want to really spoil much because there's not.
Rym: you've got to experience this movie.
Rym: telling you what happens beyond this does not help.
Rym: What I will say is that I think the whole movie is worth it.
Rym: One because you can say you've seen it and you can recommend it to people and two for the final scene.
Scott: Mostly, I think it's worth it.
Scott: just for the animation There's not too many things animated in this way with this level of quality.
Rym: All of them like a lot of scenes remind me of Akira.
Rym: Yeah the character designs are cool too because the characters are all Really unique and really different and really especially the government guy with a weird mustache.
Rym: And I love the character designs in this movie because there's so every character stands out as being so different Even that baby that is on the train tracks.
Scott: Yeah Almost gets hit by the ghost train.
Scott: Yep, and then it doesn't.
Rym: and But the movie all leads up to.
Rym: there's a moment at the end where a character says the phrase Alright, and I remember the few people who remained in the screening at the RIT anime screening Yelled and cheered when that happened.
Rym: because that is not.
Scott: I remember that.
Scott: I remember you were walking out quietly like in a daze.
Rym: Yeah, because the movie keeps going after that a little bit.
Scott: I thought that was the end.
Rym: No then there's more.
Rym: he says, okay, baby Let's get going.
Rym: Oh, and then there's the skull bit.
Scott: and then right?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yep No, and then there's the long credit sequence that everyone always sits through because that's just what you did at anime clubs.
Rym: You sat through credits.
Scott: Well, I mean especially after watching a weird one like that.
Scott: It's hard to get up.
Scott: It's sort of like whoa.
Rym: Well, I remember when they showed the cowboy bebop marathon when the last episode ended and then the credits rolled.
Rym: everyone just sat there silent the credits rolled rolled rolled rolled rolled and then the credits ended and then It just was quiet and everyone just sat there.
Rym: No one would move people slowly.
Rym: And then like a minute later this fanboy broke the silence.
Rym: he was like, well that was pretty good and then everyone was like Everyone wandered away.
Rym: this movie is Great at being what it is.
Rym: There isn't really other anime like it.
Scott: If you it's one of those situations or a director just gets to do what they want for what they want And usually we say yes, I want that to happen.
Rym: But that's what you get when you see.
Rym: Oh, she's live-action movies, right?
Rym: You don't always want what you wish for?
Rym: no but at least with this it's short enough to where it is not worth watching.
Rym: if you don't want to see weird stuff and Not weird like kill la kill but weird like sad clowns crying.
Rym: but if you are if you call yourself an anime fan and you know the names of directors and you Actually care about anime and the history of anime if you know who Fred Schott is people like that You're the kind of person who needs to see this movie.
Scott: I'm sure other people who know about anime are gonna be all who know more than us about anime are gonna be talking about all the history of this thing OVA and all the stuff about it That we don't know.
Rym: Ah, but the you know what.
Scott: we don't know that stuff.
Scott: that's why we didn't say it.
Rym: the people who know that stuff are not in the modern anime community because the anime news network has Nothing on this movie.
Rym: It just lists the director the creator Production house and nothing else.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, there you go a hidden Anime dredged up from the past that you never heard of also a horror anime.
Rym: This is horror sort of.
Rym: I would say it fits in.
Rym: It's not
Scott: hard the way that you know American movies are hard or the way the ultra gory stuff in Japan is hard But
Rym: it is in the genre of horror and there are things that people like to say are horror in the anime world that are Not by any definition, but this.
Rym: this is the same genre of horror that is often seen in Modern short horror fiction like if you listen to pseudopod.
Rym: Mmm, that is that's the kind of horror it is just like a pseudopod not mainstream horror, but sort of Horror fans.
Scott: horror like it is just like a pseudopod.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: This is horror for people who are Invested enough in horror fiction to have gotten beyond Jason and Freddy being horror.
Rym: Really if you're an anime fan you call yourself an anime fan and you listen to GeekNights.
Rym: you should see this movie if you like Naruto in one piece and kill a kill and don't really and like Attack on Titan and Fullmetal Alchemist and you really really hate things like Akira or sky crawler.
Rym: You're not a good person and you probably would hate this movie.
Rym: If you're like us, you'll find the movie interesting and you'll remember it and it'll be worth watching.
Rym: But I'm not gonna say it's great.
Rym: I'm gonna say it's worth watching.
Rym: Also, it's free.
Rym: it's on YouTube.
Rym: just watch it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.