Rym: Hey, it's Wednesday June 5th 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Emily Scott's a butt and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're gonna review from the new world Shinsekai Ori.
Rym: Let's do this.
Emily: So we're doing kind of the same thing we did with the wolf children reviews that Scott just doesn't watch anime anymore.
Emily: I guess yeah, you don't read comics right?
Rym: I have rice boy somewhere.
Rym: Did you move it?
Rym: That's the one for my mom.
Rym: oh Because Scott suggested that I should read it.
Rym: so you can.
Emily: you can read it on the web.
Emily: like it's a webcomic It's all free on the internet.
Rym: I'll take that book and read it so we can do the show Like all of Evan's stuff is so amazing.
Rym: Well, yeah Scott I had jury duty today and Scott did.
Rym: he was.
Rym: he hinted that maybe he wanted to bail on the show.
Rym: Yeah, and I was busy and it was nice out.
Rym: So whatever.
Emily: It was national running day today.
Emily: So Yeah, so, I don't know.
Emily: so I'm sitting here and I feel it all good.
Emily: I was like I have such a hard time Getting started when it comes to exercising and I always have like it's like my mom would always be like Emily go to track Practice and I'd be like no I'm tired And then it would be like go to track practice and I'd be like, yeah And then I come home and be like that
Rym: was the best
Emily: thing ever.
Emily: So yeah, that's kind of how I feel about jogging.
Emily: And so luckily I have a exercise part.
Rym: Everyone's like me.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just gonna go run like all morning.
Rym: See it's an acquired taste though, cuz you used to hate The worst until I lived in the mountains by myself and I ran out of sheer anger.
Emily: Yeah He's just like no one's around.
Emily: Wow this see this is what we need to do to make people not fat.
Emily: We just take away their internet and put them in a room and be like the only way you could get out is to run.
Rym: You know, I was gonna say maybe they just masturbate but that would one be some exercise calories.
Rym: No internet, so they might not be able to wait.
Emily: who can't masturbate without internet?
Rym: I have the impression that a lot of people would have difficulty without the internet.
Emily: good imaginations.
Emily: I don't know.
Rym: So Shinsekai Ori from the new world relatively new show based on a Somewhat I wouldn't say erotic but definitely sexually charged novel.
Emily: Well, I started reading the novel and actually the novel is very similar to the show, you know I think a lot of people have the wrong impression about this work because they like the novel.
Emily: It's you you keep calling it a light novel.
Emily: It's not a light novel.
Emily: It's like it doesn't have illustrations.
Emily: It's written in the style of you know, much more traditional.
Rym: How many pages is it?
Emily: it's like three volumes of 200 pages each.
Emily: I've got the first volume but you know, it's.
Emily: it's really weird because You know people see the manga which was made kind of after the show is like this crass cash grab.
Rym: It's like the eska flow Or the brave story.
Rym: manga are awful.
Emily: There's so bad Like, you know, we saw brave story and that's another one based on a novel has a pretty good anime adaptation.
Emily: Actually, I like the anime of brave story better than I like the book.
Rym: the brave story Anime movie is actually one of my favorite animated movies.
Emily: It's really fun.
Emily: And I still have the.
Emily: I don't know.
Emily: I went and saw it in the theater when I was an exchange student And so it was like.
Emily: I also associate it with a lot of like very nostalgic memories and you know having a really good summer break and stuff like that, but No, the the manga was just really dumb.
Rym: It's porn goog.
Rym: if you do a GIS for the shinsa kiyori manga Yeah, basically see the most ridiculous butts Looking lesbian sex.
Emily: Yeah, so part of it is because you know.
Emily: taking that into account the book does feature like a very in-depth description of a Future society and this is a society where they kind of explore all these different aspects of it.
Emily: And so sexuality you know in regards to culture and actually in in regards to like societal conditioning is a big part of the this world that they're trying to create.
Emily: and so there's there's Everybody's basically bisexual in this show, but the relationships they portray in the anime and I'm assuming you know I haven't read too far in the novel are very complex very well fleshed-out complicated relationships and very satisfying to watch.
Emily: but I don't know.
Emily: I think the The manga they just were like, hey, what do you mean?
Emily: Everybody's gay.
Emily: That's awesome.
Rym: The further OAVs of El Hazzar Kind of like that delightful.
Rym: the second one step shy of porn.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, but it doesn't have one really good scene.
Emily: so, you know, I recently listened to a show.
Emily: I don't remember whether it was the drugs one or whether it was like.
Emily: I Forget what show you geek-bited this on but I don't really know how much I can add except that like there's this This show where everyone well certain members of the population suddenly manifest psychic powers.
Rym: Here's the story.
Rym: This is like a you're ready to give a full accounting because I know I've invited this before is a show set in the distant distant Future after what can only be described as a psychic apocalypse in the modern era one day x-men powers happen But it's a very basically squishes everyone around.
Emily: Yeah, it's it's not easily controllable x-men powers cuz like in in x-men You know, there's a lot of prejudice and everything and actually the mutants are relatively downtrodden despite their powers.
Emily: Well, this is the opposite.
Emily: These are people.
Emily: they can't control their powers and they'll just like lash out and then everyone in a like mild radius is just dead.
Emily: Well, like
Rym: I was getting this is basically what Magneto wanted after this apocalypse and you get hints of the Sort of prehistory of the show and the precursor technology and like the old nuclear wars and everything Now society is kind of rebuilt around at least in the place we're looking at a sort of neo Shinto neo Ancient Japan.
Emily: I actually really really like the costume design for this show because it's future.
Rym: it like future of Like ancient Japan.
Rym: Yeah theme and style and Aspects of religion brought forward into a modern setting with some technologies very advanced Some of its still like banned or you know, that's ancient precursor technology.
Rym: I'm not allowed to use that kind of electricity.
Emily: They have electricity like they have waterwheel that generates electricity and stuff like that But they're not allowed to use it for very many things.
Emily: Like most people don't have access to electricity.
Rym: But basically society has rebuilt itself in a way to sort of allow humans who have psychic powers to exist.
Rym: So now we have a world where there are small communities of humans Each of whom is basically a bomb.
Rym: Yeah, and they have a sort of Subservient race of mole rats who do all of their manual labor and sort of worship them as gods.
Emily: They're like these really really ugly buggers and like the whole time.
Emily: I was just like, oh, they're so creepy.
Emily: And then I realized well, that's kind of the point.
Rym: You definitely get the impression that there are other Villages and other societies around Japan and around the world that have done a similar thing.
Emily: Yeah, it just focuses.
Rym: you get they.
Rym: you see from a couple of flashbacks later in the show that it's.
Rym: it seems like every nation or every culture went back into its past and found Some sort of I don't know means to control the population or like way to organize their lives.
Rym: Yeah able to deal with this great and terrible power that they have.
Emily: I mean really the show is pretty zoomed in.
Emily: it really focuses only on that one village and they'll go to like that ring village.
Emily: It's like kamisu 66 is the village where they're all from and they'll go to these other villages in the immediate vicinity.
Emily: But it basically takes place all within like a few kilometer radius around this one town.
Rym: Though you do get a point later in the show where you get a sort of zoomed out view of Japan in the world.
Rym: and what?
Rym: Might be out there and you know old precursor stuff.
Rym: I mean Tokyo.
Emily: Yeah, they do go to Tokyo at one point in the show.
Emily: You see what Tokyo is and it's basically Just everyone's Subconscious has made Tokyo kind of this nightmarish place.
Rym: What's what's cool is that that's just the world.
Rym: That's not the show itself.
Rym: It's core concede really is that you've got a bunch of kids who grew up in this world and It's a psychic 1984 the they sort of Accidentally discover some information that they shouldn't have a zebra storyteller situation.
Rym: They find this adorable old library.
Emily: It's funny too.
Emily: Cuz when it like that threw me for a loop because they're they're looking for this creature That they call the false mino shiro and it looks kind of like a sea slug horse thing.
Emily: It's kind of like a pony.
Emily: It's very cute.
Rym: There's like.
Emily: It's like I'm a library.
Emily: I'm branch of Tokyo library and I'm like, whoa It's a library and that makes a lot of sense in in future Episodes.
Emily: you're like, oh I see what's going on there.
Rym: but basically they learn all these things like.
Rym: they learn that human behavior has been modeled on bonobos and when humans are stressed they will actually feel Sexually charged rather than other kinds of stress.
Emily: So this gets teenagers.
Emily: They're like, okay teenagers go make out with your best friend of the same gender and then you won't like Blow up and kill everybody.
Rym: but now these five kids because they've learned some of the history of the world Is conscious of it they start to notice these things happening to them.
Rym: well second-guessing if Anything anything that they ever want or do is something they truly wanted or something that was conditioned into them or genetically implanted in them and The adults are up to shady bullshit.
Rym: Well, they're and kids disappear and you get all these sinister hints that hurt.
Rym: like the main character her mother.
Emily: basically She overhears her previous children.
Emily: Yeah, she overhears her before she manifests her powers because the powers tend to like get stronger and manifest at puberty.
Emily: And so she hears her mother Freaking out because she's a late bloomer and talking to the father like I can't lose another child Kind of that you're like, whoa, she had sisters and she doesn't remember them.
Emily: And so that that's kind of a freaky thing.
Emily: And so I don't know.
Emily: I think 1984 it's Mean like.
Emily: it's all about social conditioning and the use of Propaganda, but it's even deeper than propaganda.
Emily: It's not just the way they're raised.
Emily: It's actually Their genes have been modified.
Rym: Well, there's also a lot of sort of brave new world of Everyone's just living in this sort of.
Emily: we are gods and this is paradise world, but there's a dark side to it Yep, and nobody's conscious of the dark Impression like there's there.
Rym: there's the education committee and there's all these committees of adults.
Rym: that yeah things.
Rym: and the librarians and I mean It's obvious once.
Emily: it's the sinister utopia that like once you appear too close It's not actually utopia.
Emily: something something really unpleasant is going on behind the scenes now.
Rym: We'll spoil in a second.
Emily: But yeah, we'll cross that spoiler line.
Rym: The show is great.
Rym: I would call it a solid b-plus anime.
Rym: It's a little bit above like the scrap princess level But it falls short of the Ava level in terms of message and his production.
Rym: and honestly my only complaints really with the show are that the soundtrack is Really repetitive and not terribly know where.
Emily: also sometimes it gets a little talky, you know It will be like an entire episode will be like a conversation.
Emily: That's something adapted You know, it really would make sense as a novel.
Emily: you Let me tell you the history of the Sam a flash.
Rym: words words words words.
Emily: Yeah It's like I'm not a lot of animation.
Emily: a lot of people standing around being like, whoa That's what was going on.
Rym: Also do that thing and you see this in Hunger Games and books like that where they will Sort of explain their plan to another character because that's how it was narrated in the book.
Rym: Yeah, but really that dialogue didn't need to be there.
Emily: Yeah, but you know characters will clarify things to each other and it tends to be a little bit of a wordy show.
Emily: But all in all like already shows.
Emily: Yeah Artistically, it's it's pretty well done.
Emily: The animation is fairly consistent.
Emily: one thing it is at points incredibly disturbing Like on a psychological.
Emily: it's also very gory.
Emily: It's like you're like a lot of people get killed in this show, which is really juxtaposed with these sort of cute like anime standard characters and Ridiculous costumes.
Emily: Yeah But yeah, it's it's got moments that are very like yay But then a lot of moments that are pretty pretty grim.
Rym: my only other complaint really about the show other than these basic things the soundtrack being weak is really my primary complaint.
Rym: but it Would be that early in the show we get all these flashbacks to sort of like vignettes of the history of this world.
Rym: one of the things the kids find out is that you know human societies after this apocalypse sort of moved in a bunch of different directions and One of those directions was a period of basically emperors and slaves and psychic slavery and all this.
Emily: Basically, the Emperor is like I would kill anyone who stops clapping.
Emily: the first hundred kids are like what.
Rym: which one were we?
Rym: And it's kind of the smarter kid is like well, isn't it obvious?
Emily: Yeah, we're the psychic people.
Emily: What happened to the normal people?
Emily: That's a big plot of the show.
Emily: It's like everyone's psychic.
Rym: So what happened to the normal people are great and they really put the show in the context that this is a far future.
Rym: And if they had kept that up the flashbacks basically stop happening a few episodes in and don't recur.
Rym: But had they continued through the whole show you'd have this great parallel Progression of the current plot sort of evolving in time.
Rym: But simultaneously if you had the flashbacks becoming closer and closer to present day throughout history through the Dark Age Like I was all this other stuff that happened would have made sense.
Rym: That would have that alone.
Rym: that detail would have made this an a-show if that had been done.
Emily: Well, I would have liked to see stuff like, you know For example the death of shame.
Emily: if a psychic tries to kill another human they basically have a heart attack and die.
Emily: It's it's like a thing a feedback mechanism that physically prevents Psychics from just flipping out and killing everyone even though that happens.
Emily: Sometimes there'll be rare exceptions.
Emily: They call them Oni like demons who are just psychopaths who can kill without any repercussions.
Emily: so But I would have liked to see how that sort of stuff developed, you know They did it all in dialogue and said yeah, this is how they could have shown us.
Rym: Keep doing it chronologically from there.
Rym: Why didn't they have the the the weapon of mass destruction precursor technology stuff that comes up near the end of the show?
Rym: Get foreshadowed in one of those flashbacks.
Emily: So do you wanna like step the spoilers?
Rym: We're gonna do a final thoughts as well because we haven't covered much more ground than my geek bite.
Rym: Other than that now that I've seen the whole show I am comfortable saying this is a solid b-plus anime.
Rym: if you're an anime fan, you should probably watch this show.
Rym: It's one of the better shows to come out in recent memory.
Rym: It's not better than Madoka no, but I can't think of a Very recent show that I think is better than it currently.
Emily: It was weird though.
Emily: It didn't really.
Emily: um, I Wasn't moved in the same way.
Emily: I've been moved by shows like Madoka or cowboy bebop or something like that.
Emily: Like it didn't affect me Emotionally as much.
Emily: it was more interesting on a cerebral level.
Emily: but You know, there were sometimes there were scenes where I was like, oh man Oh man, and that's kind of my feeling was just kind of like.
Emily: I feel so I. that's really disturbing.
Rym: Yeah, if you look at these other shows like Madoka the characters themselves react to the situations around them Extremely viscerally.
Emily: Well what the whole character the main character?
Rym: Final thoughts we're gonna spoil the fuck out of this show.
Rym: Seriously don't keep listening until you've seen all of Shinsekai Ori.
Rym: the main character that we follow is by birth Not affected by this stuff and able to keep a cool head and we see everything through the lens of her.
Emily: I mean, she's empathetic and everything like she cares about her friends.
Emily: She's not like this emotionless sociopathic person.
Rym: height of her emotions in the show to See what covers.
Rym: that's that time Madoka cry.
Emily: Yeah.
Emily: Well, that's the thing She.
Emily: she recovers from stuff.
Emily: she's very pragmatic and she's like she'll pick herself up.
Emily: and part of that also I think has to do with like memory erasure and stuff like that.
Emily: like there's this scene.
Emily: that's very sad.
Emily: when when Shun his name was Shun boy with the mass.
Emily: He he basically has this thing where His power we can assume everyone's On has already seen the show.
Emily: He's he's a karmic demon.
Rym: So they're Basically gives up and kills himself.
Rym: Yeah, basically admitting that he loved her.
Emily: yeah, so there are ogres and there are karmic demons and ogres are like serial killers and they'll Psychically explode and just like kill anybody who's in their path and they won't die of the death of shame.
Emily: But karmic demons actually I think are the more tragic Form of like psychic Like deformity, I guess you'd call it is that somebody's power will start to leak from their subconscious and so they'll start to like mutate everything around them with their mind.
Emily: So like the plants and their house and their pets and their family all will get like twisted or die Or it's like their ID kind of takes over.
Emily: but they're still like this normal feeling person.
Emily: They're just like Causing they're almost like radioactive people.
Emily: They're like psychically radioactive.
Emily: And so one of their very close friends from childhood, he basically this happens to him.
Emily: he's a very powerful psychic, but he can't control it and he dies, you know, he kills himself.
Rym: and Well, I do like.
Rym: how?
Rym: after that Yeah There's this other just derpy kid hanging out with them and they they all are still kind of zebra storytellers Remember and they're just like yeah derpy kid We're gay.
Rym: We don't really want you to be around as we try to solve.
Emily: Not you did not talk about Mamoru cuz he was originally was just there.
Emily: He's just like.
Emily: yeah We've always been a group of five right and I totally dated you.
Emily: and he's like, yeah I dated this other main guy and the other main guys like yeah, I think we dated what's going on with my brain.
Rym: It skips Boring parts and why?
Rym: every time the show is about to get into a rut it'll time-skip or Immediately escalate to the next significant plot point.
Rym: So it time skips twice.
Emily: figure out their major Pretty quick.
Rym: they realize their memories all been edited and you don't have a long drawn-out.
Rym: Well, maybe it's not happening.
Rym: Like they all pretty much agree almost right away Like yeah, like something is up with our memories of this event.
Rym: But seriously what this show is about is that children?
Rym: Often do not understand the seemingly cruel and Arbitrary way that adults in the world manage the world.
Rym: and then they become adults and they realize I mean did.
Rym: the more of the show is that everything those adults did is basically Completely justified.
Rym: not all of them that world not all of it.
Emily: She feels really bad about the moats and she knows.
Emily: she knows their deal, you know.
Emily: And so I think it's one of those things where children become adults.
Emily: and children when they're teenagers They'll fight the adult world and be like, you know, everything's wrong and I'm gonna revolutionize the system.
Emily: but once they become adults, they actually kind of are the system and they start to become more like Incremental change like they're not exactly like the generation before them.
Emily: But there's a great scene where in the beginning.
Emily: There's this monster called an impure cat and it's like this huge Hulking.
Emily: you can assume everyone's.
Emily: yeah You see it's all like shadowy and scary.
Emily: Yeah, he's got like little kittens by the end.
Emily: You actually see them like for real without any shadows or without any aggression and they're just like hanging out.
Emily: They're just actually kind of cute.
Emily: and that I think is interesting because something that was this huge menace Early in the show becomes something that's almost benign.
Rym: Normal is set up in the classic trope of these.
Rym: people are up to evil.
Emily: There's the mystery in the committee and stuff and at the end she is the head of the ethics committee I remember.
Rym: she say what before shouldn't becomes the karmic demon.
Rym: She say like goes over to him and then freaks out and runs away.
Rym: And yeah with the eggs with the eyes really sinister.
Emily: what's going on happening?
Rym: but no the retroactive abortions the age of 17 are probably the best way to handle that world and Not killing the people who have these problems is way worse than letting them live.
Rym: but the show Makes the point you mentioned of the incremental progress.
Rym: Extremely well because Tomiko the sort of the person who saved all of them from extermination and groomed The main character sake to kind of grow into her role.
Rym: They basically had similar experiences.
Rym: They both dealt with effectively.
Rym: an ogre.
Rym: They both go through all these same things.
Rym: She's the protege.
Rym: she basically does everything that Tomiko wanted to do with one exception She spares square as life.
Emily: Well, not really he became like.
Rym: well spares him the pain of continued life.
Emily: Well continued life.
Emily: she let him go for like a year as a suffering lump of meat.
Emily: basically Oh, that's the worst part of the show.
Rym: but she needed her excuse to talk to him alone which he couldn't do right away.
Rym: and Then she needed to be alone with him to be able to get away with it.
Emily: How could she like he couldn't understand her by that point?
Emily: He was I don't know.
Rym: I just assumed he would have to be able to understand or else the pain is meaningless.
Rym: Oh, it's so fun.
Rym: They made a big deal about how much care they put into that.
Emily: So fucked up like they torture him infinitely and it's basically the day like regenerate.
Rym: And I like Squealer Because Squealer was smart and canny.
Rym: That's the only other complaint I have about the show but not really the show just the story.
Rym: They didn't see this shit coming from the beginning.
Rym: when Squealer started pulling his bullshit early on Started making concrete and lobotomizing the queen mole rat.
Rym: I mean they eliminated entire colonies of rat people for way less than what Squealer was up to.
Emily: But that's the whole thing.
Emily: He's an incredibly sympathetic character and like you see him and he's like this brutal dictator.
Emily: But at the same time a lot of the stuff he does you're like, wow Well, this is fighting for a humanities freedom.
Rym: This is a show where the gods are real where the gods of Shinto are real and they're just kind of dicks Because the the mole rats everyone around them even their own children can't.
Rym: their motives are inscrutable.
Rym: Their power is untouchable.
Rym: But it seems like people always rebel against that idea of the inscrutable untouchable power.
Emily: But I mean it like Story with squealer.
Emily: squealer was Prometheus and he even ended up almost identical fate to Prometheus Except that Prometheus didn't get well because I think that was very intentional.
Rym: and this is a world where the The gods motivations as humans because we see it from the main from Saki's perspective and these kids perspective the Motivations in the end of the show make perfect sense from that world and from that viewpoint.
Rym: yeah, but from the viewpoint of the rat of the mole people, it's basically just subjugation and callous Laboratory exterminate.
Emily: Yeah, it's just like suddenly the gods will be like, oh you stepped out of line whoosh You're all dead, you know, and so it's.
Emily: it's basically like punishment from heaven Zeus throwing his thunderbolts down and I think the thing with squealer is I. That's a part where I felt really bad in the show.
Emily: when he was he was defeated and brought in chains.
Emily: before that You know before the jury and and the council to be you know to be tried and he says, you know Well, they're like, well, what should we call you?
Emily: and he's like we're human and you feel so bad for him at this moment and you feel what he has fought for.
Emily: you know even though he is he is like kidnapped babies and brainwashed them and like done all this shitty stuff and killed a whole mess of human like superhumans you.
Emily: He was basically like the savior of the mole rat people.
Emily: He was trying to lead them to freedom and you're like.
Emily: you really didn't deserve that maybe.
Rym: But I mean in the end the show just has a nice Complex message and it's not the message you expect for a show like this No one expect.
Rym: and the what.
Rym: I was no bringing down the system because we did this as a geek Book way back or maybe we just reviewed it before we're doing the book club.
Rym: I don't remember but the difference engine Yeah, I would say they're very similar works because this show leads up to a big climax.
Rym: That is actually just an incremental evolution, but is not in fact a revolution.
Rym: No, it's like because that's how the world actually works.
Emily: You kind of wonder like in the beginning are they gonna bring down the system?
Emily: Is it they're?
Emily: they're going to expose the false veneer of their utopia and they do they.
Emily: they figure out the utopia.
Emily: But yes what every single adult knows what's going on in this utopia.
Rym: It's She let the end when she's like yo, so since there's that ogre here's the map to the weapons of mass destruction.
Emily: We know about yeah, which was anthrax, which I thought was I was like, yes that That's why I wanted more flashbacks.
Rym: The fact that the anthrax was in that weird vial Yeah, I was like, what do you deal with?
Rym: zero sense?
Rym: And also I'm like, okay, so the anthrax Was gonna kill takes a while to kill you.
Rym: Yeah, I'll bet it was a modified anthrax.
Emily: So it's interesting too because it's like, okay So the death of shame doesn't hit you if you kill somebody with a disease because the disease killed them.
Emily: Where's the line like?
Emily: if you feel like you're directly responsible Purely psychological?
Emily: remember at the end when I didn't kill him.
Rym: I didn't.
Rym: yeah She had to talk herself because the the child who has brainwashed beginning the monk that was taking them back to the temple to Basically murder them.
Rym: Yeah, he That that minasura turned into an image of a woman in the last second of its death and he had a hard time dealing with.
Emily: Yeah, he was all like sweating and he was like, you know heart rate up and basically like they have to talk themselves out of Heart attacks if they feel guilty for someone's death.
Rym: There's also that great moment where and it's like visual these main these characters all know this crap and so do all the adults that We as viewers interact with.
Rym: but then there's like this normal monk guard near the end like guarding one of the cool guys.
Emily: Yeah, what's his name?
Rym: The awesome mole rat?
Rym: Oh Already forgot his name.
Emily: It was like inu maru or something like is like awesome?
Emily: Yeah, it I think he had like inu in his name and he also looked kind of dog-like.
Emily: so I forget.
Emily: or kiro Maru that's what it was.
Emily: Yep, cuz yako maru was squealer and kiro maru was.
Rym: He was a the man.
Rym: some reason I thought it was inu maru But him and she say wrote my favorite sort of strong characters.
Emily: He don't matter I felt bad for kiro maru.
Rym: Yeah, he did his thing.
Emily: Yeah, he was.
Emily: he like sacrifice, but I mean, I don't think the humans Really deserved his sacrifice.
Emily: No, but then again, this is he bartered the life of his colony.
Emily: He said I will sacrifice my life if you will save my mother that it's obvious that the normal people the normal adults Don't know everything.
Rym: They just know enough to be able to serve their function.
Rym: and that trial was just a show trial.
Rym: but yeah, the adults in the know the committee's just know everything is a great scene where the kids and Everyone else knows the whole deal and this one guard is like what the fuck you talking about?
Rym: Oh the monk who is like down guarding To him and the the guards just like they're like something something death of shame and the guys like what what?
Emily: Yeah, and he's all like.
Emily: we must keep the mole rat down here because he is filthy and they're like shut up and remove his Chains, you don't know what the heck you're doing kind of thing.
Emily: So that was that was funny.
Rym: So yeah, the show is complex dark show.
Rym: But I love the fact that it had that anti-climax that the end was just an evolution of culture.
Rym: It was just one step beyond.
Rym: one thing changed.
Emily: So would you classify this?
Emily: Like?
Emily: do you think it's partly a horror anime?
Emily: I don't think so.
Emily: It's feel like horror anime.
Rym: I think of it more as Sci-fi.
Emily: Yeah, but like there are parts of it where they're like going through the old hospital and it's dark and you're like Oh my god, there's something in there.
Rym: I would definitely not call that.
Emily: when the thing is coming in after them in the boat And they can see it's aura and you're like, oh my god the ogres in the boat all of those scenes I would call them suspense and not horror.
Emily: What's the difference?
Rym: Suspense can be used in other films or in other things.
Rym: There are suspenseful scenes there.
Rym: there could even be suspense movies, but a horror is The core of the show.
Emily: if it's a horror show I thought I thought it's like Suspense is like will the spy get found out with a spy not get found out with a spy?
Emily: But this was more like.
Emily: I feel horrified.
Emily: I feel terrified of this.
Rym: I guess I would never call something genre horror unless the horror aspect is the climax.
Emily: But it had horror elements.
Emily: Yeah I think they were more suspenseful than but it wasn't a horror show.
Emily: It's kind of like a movie.
Emily: I feel like it can have elements of horror without being of the horror genre.
Rym: This might partly be that I've been listening to every single pseudopod for the last several years.
Rym: So I've been assuming Ridiculous amount of modern horror fiction.
Emily: You're kind of a horror buff.
Rym: Anyway, like you're big into the first big boy book I ever read was The Hobbit and the second big boy book I ever read was Stephen King's skeleton crew.
Emily: I'm actually I was.
Emily: I don't know why I've been thinking a lot about The Hobbit lately.
Emily: I want that new movie to come out.
Rym: It'll come I want it.
Emily: Oh my god Katsu showed me something really cute like this weekend.
Emily: It was a gender swap Bilbo Baggins.
Emily: She was very cute.
Emily: She had hairy feet.
Rym: But yeah Shinseki Ori great show, uh I hope you didn't just spoil everything by listening to this.
Rym: But yeah, I liked it.
Rym: I like its message.
Rym: I like that.
Rym: It didn't have the typical tropes.
Rym: where it ended was such a different place from where it began in terms of like the View or the angle like your perspective on this world.
Rym: the world didn't change you change it was by growing up Mind blown.
Emily: it was legit hard to predict where the show is going and I wasn't expecting the time skips.
Emily: Actually, the first time skipped was spoiled for me because somebody was like, oh my god The show gets super gay.
Emily: and I was like what.
Emily: and then I watched.
Emily: I was like, yep Everybody became a teenager and started making out with you.
Emily: well every
Rym: time a time skit happens the show is
Emily: very different very different and the whole plot and and Politics have progressed like, you know in the second time skip they deal with the mole rats more But they're also dealing with this other stuff like the karmic demon stuff.
Emily: But in the third time skip the mole rats.
Emily: It's like everything is different now and they're like all attacking each other and stuff like.
Emily: but there's a war going on.
Rym: It's it's a new world only because you see what is basically the same world From an adult perspective and a gnostic perspective instead of from a childlike perspective.
Emily: Yeah So I'm probably gonna read at least parts of the book so I'll at least read the first volume which I have and and then I can give you the pros and cons of The book versus the the movies.
Rym: but Seriously, don't read the manga the manga.
Emily: I mean, I haven't read the manga.
Emily: All I saw was a few scans of it.
Emily: I'm like no and it's like real light-hearted - it's like Light-hearted fan service cheesecake.
Emily: What what how is this even possible on one hand?
Emily: You've got like this deep show about.
Rym: You know this incredibly complex Like the rule of and of manga that are made for shows after the fact It's more the rule than particularly agreed to.
Emily: and Scott Scott like, you know, he was like, what's this porn manga?
Emily: You know now he thinks it's all porn.
Emily: I'm like seriously guy.
Emily: It's not all porn.
Emily: I swear to you, but Yeah, there's only a few moments in the show and they're handled really tastefully.
Emily: They're enough to make tumblr go crazy, but well, I mean everything's enough.
Rym: to me This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Rym: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Rym: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and a comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Rym: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night.