Rym: It's Tuesday August 20th 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight to board games village and Innovation.
Rym: we didn't like either of them that much.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I guess spoilers.
Rym: so up.
Rym: the other day Emily and I ordered some Indian food and the Indian food delivery man who himself appeared Indian arrived and handed us the food and Said two words that I've never had a delivery man Tell me before that were in the context of food being delivered unnerving Mm-hmm.
Rym: Can you guess what those two words were?
Scott: It's poison Good luck.
Rym: Yeah We looked at the food like And then we ate it anyway because we were really hungry.
Scott: Yeah, that's how it's gonna be.
Rym: Though we've been sadly busy lately one of our rabbits the little brown one Mookie has been sick.
Rym: So we've been Jamming food down his mouth with the syringe and forcing him to eat greens.
Scott: How do you even notice he was sick?
Rym: Uh, you know, it's funny.
Rym: Everyone I have told this to has asked that first question.
Rym: How do you tell if a rabbit is?
Scott: Yeah, I imagine if you're taking care of it Like you need to be a fucking attention to detail right to even notice this kind of stuff.
Rym: So a dog or a cat or other animals like that.
Rym: if they're sick They they tell you they like vomit everywhere exactly.
Rym: They they're like, ah like a dog.
Rym: I should come up and be like, I'm hurt like a baby human.
Rym: so that's because they're predators and omnivores and animals that are traditionally prey.
Rym: animals tend to Evolutionarily not display illness so they will look perfectly fine and then suddenly die.
Rym: Because think if an animal like if a rabbit in the wild looks sick Foxes are like, oh hells.
Rym: Yeah I'm just gonna walk over and bite right?
Scott: Otherwise, I'm too tired to chase a rabbit right now.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not hungry yet.
Scott: So
Rym: if you own a rabbit and you pay attention to animals It's pretty obvious when they're sick But you have to know like they sit a certain way and they don't have a high enough fecal output and they're not eating as Much of their food or they stop eating.
Scott: and I think you would notice like if one rabbit you went to clean the poop It's like huh?
Scott: The other rabbit didn't poop.
Rym: But somebody who doesn't know rabbits might think huh?
Rym: Well, I'll wait cuz you know, I don't poop every day Sometimes Yeah, but sometimes I just don't poop.
Rym: Sometimes the dog just doesn't poop.
Scott: I mean you had to be cut it down there?
Rym: No, no, but a dog getting constipated is only a medical emergency if it goes on for a while.
Scott: That's true Same with the human.
Rym: Yeah There's just a story on FARC about a guy who basically couldn't eat food and was having some sort of gastrointestinal distress.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: the article wasn't into those.
Rym: He didn't go to the doctor until the third day Because he didn't want a colonoscopy.
Rym: Okay, he's really afraid of that.
Rym: So he almost died.
Scott: a lot of people that you know Get sick or whatever because they're afraid of the doctor.
Rym: I know I'm a not afraid of the doctor.
Rym: I'm pretty the dentist not really.
Rym: but That is just way sadder than go to the doctor because the doctor will be like, yeah I'm gonna check your blood do the whatever.
Rym: but the dentist is always like you should floss more Every day.
Rym: but black dynamite Anyway, so yeah, we're taking care of the rabbit and it's been a lot of work because rabbits do not like to be force-fed.
Scott: You know, it's good not having any pets.
Rym: You know, what's good having pets?
Scott: not having pets.
Scott: Imagine having a baby not having one of those either.
Scott: Oh, I'll take the pet.
Scott: You know all the pets no babies.
Rym: So yeah, we're mostly doing GeekNights again.
Rym: But of course we got packs coming up like right the fuck.
Scott: now We were just out of packs, but yet two weeks from to now The packs not our packs the packs.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's like packs of four-day packs.
Rym: It's like yeah, there's not those or trace.
Rym: Quattro Dios, there's North Africa.
Rym: There's you know Ravensburg or whatever.
Rym: There's all these other towns Ravenna, I guess but then there's Rome.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: That's what Pax is.
Scott: What this is.
Rym: that's what we're doing.
Rym: four days of this bullshit Which means after the next round of GeekNights disruptions?
Rym: We will probably be fairly undisrupted until magfest until holidays.
Rym: Yeah holidays and met.
Rym: what magfest is a holiday?
Scott: it sure is Ring in the new year with alcohol.
Scott: Everyone does that.
Rym: I believe you mean who are in the new year Like as it's New Year's it's like 2014.
Rym: Oh, I think that's what we're gonna do New Year's party because the entire New Year's party is just going from New Year's to magfest.
Scott: How could you not?
Scott: but what everyone's New Year's is?
Rym: I know I?
Rym: Assume that everyone else leaves the exact same lifestyle that I do.
Scott: Otherwise, how are you if you're listening to this seriously, and that's not your New Year's?
Scott: what the fuck?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: We have a lot of listeners who play mobas.
Rym: so So I've been playing a game.
Rym: a lot of our friends play it a lot of you play it and a lot of people For many years have tried to tell me so there's no more advanced wars games But Rym you should play some fire emblem.
Rym: you.
Rym: they're almost the same.
Rym: It is a turn-based Strategy game.
Scott: yeah now.
Scott: We're like square grid.
Scott: Just like advanced wars.
Rym: I used to say yeah, whatever I played crystal warriors on the game gear.
Rym: I don't need to play another game like that and well would say play on a fantasy tactics.
Scott: advance Yeah, but you eat.
Scott: despite your complaints.
Scott: You did play it a lot.
Rym: I played it a lot in that I played it until I beat it to make sure I wasn't missing anything right.
Scott: well final fan Fire emblem is much similar more similar to fun fancy tactics.
Scott: It is that it is to advance wars, but basically I they're not even in the same category.
Rym: Nope fire emblem is literally just crystal warriors on the game gear which came out pretty Contemporarily to the original fire.
Scott: remember yeah fire emblems pretty old right.
Rym: yeah like crystal warriors was basically a fire emblem clone.
Rym: They came in Japan.
Scott: they were directly competing the same way that Duke Nukem 3d and quake were competing.
Rym: They appear in fact to have been doing just that.
Rym: maybe you should research that shit But it I did and I've been researching it more because I want to talk about crystal warriors But if answer is pretty it's both those.
Rym: the problem is when I say oh, that's just crystal warriors people don't say nah They say what's crystal warriors right?
Rym: Oh a game on the game gear.
Rym: What's the game gear?
Rym: game put out by Sega?
Rym: What's Sega?
Rym: But I played fire emblem awakening because it's the newest one and Complex game.
Rym: no it is not a difficult game.
Rym: It is in fact a very easy and very grindy game.
Scott: Did you play it on hard?
Rym: I played it on normal difficulty classic mode
Scott: Mm-hmm
Rym: because the higher difficulty I tried it is basically Memorize and grind
Scott: mmm
Rym: and worry a lot about your classes and bullshit But not in a tactical sense it just in a make sure you level up your characters through this exact Progression to make them optimally strong in these particular ways.
Rym: oh and memorize when different monsters appear in different parts of these different maps Mm-hmm.
Scott: that's the one thing that always got me I played.
Scott: I never beat a fire emblem But I think I played a GBA one maybe one or two GBA ones and the ds1.
Scott: I didn't play the 3ds1 at all I don't even buy it and the experience.
Scott: I had with all of them was pretty much the same like fun fun fun fun fun.
Scott: Okay, there's not a lot going on here tactically, but it's kind of fun.
Scott: And I'm playing and I'm seeing.
Scott: I don't really care about the story too much But I like doing these missions kinda right, and I'm not really gonna pay too much attention all the ancillary bullshit Just gonna beat the missions and forget all the other nonsense.
Rym: I paid a lot of attention to the dating part.
Scott: Well, I didn't pay attention to that at all.
Scott: that part is the best part of the game That's the part I ignored the most Except.
Scott: and then what would happen is eventually I'd be on some mission and basically my strategy was always the same wait wait Let me guess let me guess.
Rym: one of your winged units gets killed out of nowhere, and you start over.
Scott: Yeah Basically I would group all the people together in a blob so that they were protecting each other.
Scott: I would always do the rock-paper-scissors of axe spear sword right.
Scott: yeah I would kill all the bad guys in one hit you know and I just keep moving forward very slowly and safely.
Scott: I would heal guys that were damaged.
Scott: I would cast magic spells the guys are against weak against magic right and then I'd move forward like no bad guys would attack Me for a couple turns.
Scott: so I'd move forward a bit and then out of nowhere a bad guy would appear from the fog of Come zooming across the map with a greater distance than I thought was possible for any unit be right next to a unit He's super strong against and kill it in one shy
Rym: yep,
Scott: and it's like well.
Scott: What could the fuck have I done about that?
Scott: nothing Restart and not me.
Scott: in next time.
Scott: make sure that winging unit is Not near that place.
Scott: that guy's gonna appear out of nowhere.
Scott: So and that bit when I got to those missions where that bullshit would happen it Became less fun because I wouldn't just beat the mission in one shot like I did in all the previous missions it would actually.
Scott: Suddenly I was spending as much time to beat that one mission as it took me to like just fly through three other missions.
Scott: so the fun disappeared of just Blasting through the game really quickly beating everything and I was like well fuck this and I put it down and then the ds1 same Thing.
Rym: so so I want to basically talk about about the highlights the overview the pieces of the game that frustrate me or had issues because the Reason the game is the way it is is Kind of due to the way the combat is designed.
Rym: one Tactically the game is completely mindless.
Rym: The rock-paper-scissors is obvious to the rock-paper-scissors doesn't even fucking matter for you.
Rym: It only matters when you get attacked because your guys look pretty much one shot everyone.
Rym: If you've grinded a whole bun If you just play the game and don't level up any other Characters than a core set.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you're gonna be super fucking high-leveling.
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: There's no reason to level up anyone else.
Scott: There is if you want to do all the dating shit and whatnot.
Rym: Ah, yes So - the dating shit seemed really interesting until it turned out that it's not actually that interesting.
Scott: So I never did it.
Scott: So I did it because I'll be making my tactical decisions on the battlefield about who's gonna live and die based on.
Scott: I need these People to stand next to each other what?
Rym: no I need you to stand far away from that unit who's strong against you Because you get him next to each other and they level up to their s-rank or whatever And then when they're next to each other, they're basically invincible.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Rym: Uh, yeah, they support each other.
Scott: Maybe I had that that was dying all the time stayed next to someone.
Rym: Yes, so my Pegasus unit is.
Scott: why is it always the Pegasus?
Rym: Actually, what's far more vulnerable is the rabbit girl because she's a beast.
Scott: I don't have a rabbit girl.
Rym: She's all well in Fire Emblem awakening.
Rym: I have her.
Rym: she's also a dragon rider.
Rym: now She's got that dragon type on her and she's a flying type.
Rym: So she's weak against fucking everything.
Rym: But uh, I have a. I have my Pegasus person Married to a guy who can basically protect her one of the super guys on a horse.
Scott: anyone on a horse is basically invincible Excepts to the anti horse weapons, right?
Scott: But it's pretty much.
Scott: horses are pretty much like, you know, medium tanks and neo tanks in Fire Emblem, right?
Scott: The night especially and they always at the beginning they always give you a guy and a horse with armor.
Scott: That's just better than the other horses.
Scott: Yeah, it's like that guy is even better than your main guy.
Scott: He's like the guy of guys.
Rym: But anyway, my point is that technically there's nothing going on other than oh fuck you didn't pay attention to something.
Rym: start over Yeah, which is very similar to the s-rank mode in the original GBA advanced wars.
Rym: Yep, so that was actually kind of an annoying and bad part about that old advanced wars game.
Rym: But I digress to.
Rym: the combat is meaningless primarily because level matters.
Rym: but more importantly Units do not have zones of control.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: You cannot have Interesting tactics because units can just walk right fucking past other units and around and everywhere.
Rym: Yeah And the maps are so small and the terrain is so meaningless and the units moved so far That nothing you might be thinking Oh, I'll take my wyvern riders and send them down to the south and around into a flanking mover.
Rym: No, just make a big fucking grid blob and slowly move it forward.
Scott: Well, you know the healers are in the middle of the blobs And I think you can get next to them or turn your healers into axe healers.
Rym: Then they can fight with axes and heal and are basically invincible.
Scott: Ah, you're the her, you know, that's like second at D&D.
Scott: I want to be a fighter mage.
Scott: Yep, so I can do everything.
Rym: That's why my favorite class other than blade singer in second at D&D was the arcanist Which was a kit that was basically a multi-class not dual class multi-class half-elf That is half wizard half cleric.
Rym: That is some fucking bullshit, right?
Scott: All right, let's move on.
Rym: so the other the other points the relationships themselves Really superficial and more importantly the flavor.
Rym: text.
Rym: It with one exception was not that interesting and it gets minus a million points for being creepy.
Rym: and pulling the Sasami paradox.
Rym: for those of you who don't watch anime Sasami is a young girl in a show called Tenchi and I had a scary motherfucking fanboy a long time ago who was trying to explain to me and other people to
Scott: the anime club
Rym: That it is okay to like this character in a sexual way because technically she's 9,000 years old.
Rym: yeah, no and Fire Emblem awakening does that.
Rym: there's a dragon girl who's basically a nine-year-old technically a thousand or whatever.
Rym: and yeah, she got married to my creepy noble Archer guy.
Rym: and Yeah, everything about that was creepy.
Rym: Okay, but the relationships themselves.
Rym: the game forces you to make these decisions because you can only marry one person With each character so you can't see everything unless you grind through the game a billion times and there's a billion characters But none of them matter to the core gameplay.
Rym: You'd might as well just watch all those relationships on YouTube and level up one core set of characters.
Rym: I'm gonna keep playing the game until I beat it and then I'm gonna give it away.
Rym: I want to see if at any point the game is challenging in a non shit way.
Rym: Oh and items and all that stuff don't matter.
Rym: You can just auto optimize it and it's fine Unless you plan on normal difficulty.
Rym: and if you play it on the ludicrous difficulty, then it's just super tedious and still not interesting.
Rym: It's just micromanaging but not interesting.
Scott: Okay, so here's the news, right?
Scott: So, you know, we love the steam and people be hating on origin Which is EA trying to compete with steam and cuz?
Scott: it's kind of shitty.
Scott: Yeah, but origin whoever's at EA I think is trying to make a comeback.
Scott: They did this humble origin bundle thing where you would buy all these games in a bundle for you know Just like humble bundle price, right and the games ran an origin though.
Scott: So you have to sort of get origin and they were trying to get people into origin but to their credit all the money Just went to the charities of humble bundle and didn't go to EA Supposedly.
Scott: so.
Scott: basically EA was giving away free games on humble bundle just to get people to start using origin to try to fight Steam and not a bad move Strategically.
Scott: now they're doing another move then and this is real news They are offering ahem quote an origin great game Guarantee, I guess they did.
Scott: they did this after Sim City, right?
Scott: Yeah But basically they're saying hey look if you freakin You know download a game from origin for PC or Mac right within 24 hours after you launch the game Within 77 days of when you purchase it or within the first seven days after the game's release date.
Scott: if you pre-ordered it You can return it for a full refund the remove it from the origin account and give you your money back.
Scott: So, huh?
Scott: Maybe the game doesn't run with your video card or it's super laggy or that is what I'm always been really bad at is Right, so it's like look they probably looked at what happened with Sony and the Xbox and the whole used game fiasco And there must.
Scott: they must have hired a smart person somewhere who is now making a pretty good attack on steam.
Scott: This isn't gonna get me to use origin because it's still crappy compared to steam and I trust valve a lot more than EA but Hopefully this pressures steam into getting a fucking refund policy, right?
Scott: So when I go and download a game on steam that doesn't work I can return it or you know such-and-such.
Scott: Well, we'll see the thing.
Scott: the thing I've noticed about this though, right?
Scott: Is that I think EA is only doing it for EA games on origin, right?
Scott: So as opposed to say valve which most of the games you would run a return would not be the valve games.
Scott: Yeah, it would be the other people's games.
Scott: and as much harder, you know Valve pays someone some company right because you bought their game and then you return it and then right.
Scott: It's kind of you get into weird areas with that kind of situation.
Rym: Yeah, but steam could even easily cover that just by having a fairly draconian policy for the developers.
Scott: Yeah, we don't pay you and we don't give you the money from all the people who bought your game for seven days.
Rym: There would be ways to do that.
Rym: The thing is steam.
Rym: Actually, I hate to say this.
Rym: they have enough goodwill Valve does from the gaming community to where they don't need to make overtures like that.
Rym: It's also true, which is Good for them not great for gaming.
Rym: I wish there was a viable competitor for steam just to force them to do cool things that they don't have to do.
Scott: But you know what if I was making a game today?
Scott: Right, if it didn't cost me anything to put it on origin and steam why not put it on origin?
Rym: Unless if I were origin, I actually would not want you to put it on both.
Scott: Well, you'd have to pay me to be an exclusive and even then I probably would say no But you wouldn't want me to not have my game on origin at all if I was willing to put it there.
Scott: Yeah, right and it's like.
Scott: sure I'll put it there, right?
Scott: It's like, you know mate that will just help it compete with steam, right?
Scott: I would be basically not doing it to sell more copies of my game.
Scott: Although that might happen I would be doing it simply to make origin more viable to pressure steam so I could get a better deal on the steam that I cared about.
Rym: So in other PC gaming news games for Windows Live is shutting down in 2014.
Scott: Okay, so here's the deal.
Scott: So a few games Decided that they were gonna dump games for Windows Live and switch to Steamworks, which is awesome because it was.
Scott: Windows Live sucks.
Scott: Yeah, it's a pain in the ass and Steamworks is great.
Scott: Yeah, mostly good, right?
Scott: So then somebody noticed like on the Age of Empires 3e support page or something like that quote.
Rym: I'm looking at a screenshot of it because they took it down Almost immediately.
Scott: The Age of Empires Online.
Rym: Yes, Age of Empires Online Posted an update that said and I quote games for Windows Live will be discontinued on July 1st, 2014.
Scott: Okay, so They took this down.
Rym: Although it is available through Steam Age of Empires Online requires the features of games for Windows Live service Mm-hmm to work.
Rym: Yep, and That update I only have a screenshot of it because they took it right the fuck down after everyone noticed it.
Scott: Yeah, so basically a game that uses games for Windows Live for example Borderlands, right?
Scott: You can buy a lot of these games on Steam or on DVD or on CD or download from various places And when you open the game up, basically you have to it this Windows overlay comes in.
Scott: That's sort of like the Steam overlay But it's the game Windows overlay and you log into it and you use the same account that you use for Xbox and for you Know Xbox Live right same account that you use and then you have to type in your CD key And it basically adds that game to your account and it makes sure you're not Pirating it while you run it and you have to be logged in in order to make the game run.
Scott: and that's how games for Windows Live works.
Scott: It's basically like an Xbox game that runs in the PC Yep Probably because of the Xbox one the X bone and all the stuff that's going on there upgrading Xbox Live.
Scott: The fact that games for Windows Live is really kind of a failure.
Scott: They are rightfully dumping it but some of the games are patching to switch to Steamworks or to switch to some other system.
Scott: But I'm sure there are games that aren't going to make that patch And games that don't make that patch won't work at all After July 1st, 2014 Without some sort of hack or DRM removal.
Scott: That's DRM guys.
Rym: Now what's interesting is that Microsoft did not want this to be public and Basically Age of Empires leaked it and the press found it.
Rym: Age of Empires is a Microsoft game Yes, and it appears to be a mistake and I had a little page here.
Rym: Actually, I realize now that I'm looking at this, Michy D wrote this.
Rym: Okay Our friend Michy D Microsoft provided a statement and Microsoft said Yesterday an Age of Empires support webpage communicated that the free-to-play Age of Empires Online will be discontinued on July 1st, 2014.
Rym: We believe in Windows/PC gaming and have long-term plans to grow our support.
Rym: We expect there to be transitions as we build out new investments But we remain committed to bringing first blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: Basically Why do you word it in corporate speech?
Rym: I'm going to tell you why.
Scott: They just said you're turning it off.
Scott: Why didn't you just say, "Yeah, we're turning it off"?
Rym: Yes, they just said, "We're shutting it down and we're mad that you found out about it".
Scott: Because if they weren't shutting it down, they would have said Just put it in plain English.
Rym: They would have said, "Nope, we're not shutting it down".
Rym: So, yeah, we'll watch this.
Rym: But another reason why I don't trust anything but Steamworks or nothing.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, Steam has the same issue.
Scott: If Steam disappeared, say goodbye to all your games Right?
Rym: Yep, the only reason I trust Steam and Valve a little bit more.
Scott: Just trust the company.
Scott: It's still the same horrible DRMs.
Scott: Don't fool yourself.
Rym: I think I have a 10% chance if Valve went under of still being able to play my games.
Scott: I think I have a Steam in perpetual offline mode.
Rym: I think I have a 1% chance of Windows Live stuff working.
Rym: No And a negative percent chance of EA stuff.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, you might remember there's a best friends play games thing And there's a two best sisters play games thing Which is the audio from the best friends play thing.
Scott: I thought we were outlawing pony things of the day.
Rym: You've said that several times, I never agreed to this.
Rym: Also, we haven't talked about ponies in a while because it's dead to us.
Rym: Anyway It is So, two best sisters play.
Rym: Persona 4 Kind of went off the hook in terms of production values And in terms of taking the piss out of Persona style games.
Rym: So, I highly recommend if you've never played a Persona game And you want to know what the deal is To watch this video And you will know exactly why people make fun of Persona games.
Scott: Okay, so you know Imagi Animation?
Scott: They made a lot of those sort of throw away-ish CG movies Like the English, the American Astro Boy one Which was sort of generic, right?
Scott: And that TMNT that some people like And, you know, some other stuff, right?
Scott: Yeah Not really, they're not really on the same level as the Pixar's and the Dreamworks, right?
Scott: They wanted to make a Legend of Zelda movie But they didn't.
Scott: But, basically the preview sort of sample that they made in 2007 Is on YouTube.
Scott: Oh shit So you can check that shit out.
Scott: This could have been a theatrical CG Legend of Zelda movie But it wasn't, thankfully I was about to ask.
Rym: So, Scott, should the movie have come out?
Rym: And I think you've answered our question.
Scott: You should still watch this because it's only a minute and 25 seconds of your time.
Rym: I think it's kind of like.
Scott: I mean, if you're a nerd, how could you not watch this?
Rym: You know, it's kind of like how when I was a kid I remembered I had this memory of seeing a Zelda cartoon That I couldn't explain.
Rym: Excuse me, that cartoon is awful.
Rym: No, I watched that cartoon.
Rym: I'm talking about the Philips CDI games.
Rym: Oh I saw them in a store, I didn't realize they were a game.
Rym: And then I had these memories That no one could corroborate.
Rym: I could not tell if I made it up or if it was real.
Rym: And it wasn't until many years later that I learned about the Philips CDI game.
Rym: In the meta moment, the book club book is Stazzyland Increasingly relevant as the NSA stuff continues to explode In a way that no one cares about.
Rym: You should probably care a little bit If GeekNights sounds a little bit weird.
Rym: Our mixer of many years has finally started to give up the ghost.
Rym: I haven't quite fixed it yet.
Scott: Ooh, it's floating around right now Spooky ghost.
Rym: I'm looking into replacing it.
Scott: Is that audition still working?
Rym: It's working fine But we're bypassing the compressor and all my business And the Marantz Recording raw and live.
Rym: Uh oh.
Rym: So yeah, a couple of clips and bits.
Rym: as I get that sorted out Because I haven't had time to go through all the knobbly bits We're gonna be at PAX The real PAX The PAX Weekend after this coming weekend Labor Day weekend Four days Oh shit, it is on.
Scott: We're doing just one panel.
Rym: on the Monday Monday in the Wolfman Theater We're doing a panel entitled Bad Games.
Scott: You know, since this is a four-day PAX There's gonna be a lot going on there besides our panel Which is a Monday panel.
Scott: Kind of weird, right?
Rym: Well, this is the first Monday PAX.
Scott: I just want to open up my guidebook here And go to the My Schedule section And read to you my schedule, right?
Scott: For PAX.
Scott: Okay, 10.30 on Friday Story time with Peter Molyneux.
Rym: I'm excited about that.
Scott: Yeah, another top name game making guy.
Rym: Wait, wait, I'm gonna make a prediction.
Scott: That's the fable guy, right?
Rym: I'm going to make a prediction.
Scott: I don't hate it, but I don't like it.
Rym: He is going to talk about how Star Wars inspired him.
Scott: Hopefully he'll talk about black and white To go on and make games.
Scott: Not you too, tribes two Alright, followed by the hustle Saturday I actually want to go to a panel on Saturday.
Rym: Whoa, whoa, whoa, what the fuck?
Scott: I might have to wait in line for this fucker, right?
Scott: 4.30 PM, Keiji Inafune From 8-bit to next-gen and beyond.
Scott: This is basically the dude who made Mega Man And then quit Capcom because they were fools.
Scott: And he's going to do a panel from 4.30 to 5.30 Basically spilling all the beans on all that shit.
Scott: And it's also the guy who made Mega Man.
Scott: So how can I not go to that?
Rym: Nah, not bad.
Scott: Sunday, 11 AM, Android Netrunner Tournament Winner gets a PAX medal.
Rym: Oh, alright.
Scott: Sunday, 12 PM, Mario Tennis Open Tournament Until 2 PM.
Rym: Oh, that's the one on the 3DS, right?
Rym: I think it might be Wanna practice and both enter it?
Scott: I don't know if it has do whatever.
Rym: No, we'll just play against each other.
Scott: It's going to overlap the Netrunner Tournament.
Rym: Oh.
Scott: Sunday, 3.30 PM, Strip Search Reunion Superpanel If you like Strip Search, right?
Scott: Monday, us.
Scott: Monday, 1 PM until 3 PM, Tournament Saturn Bomberman.
Rym: When was the last time you played Saturn Bomberman?
Scott: I've naturally, I've only played Saturn Bomberman once.
Rym: They had it set up at that UberCon.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: In fact, they had it set up at the other UberCons I went to before you went to UberCon.
Scott: Woah, anyway Monday, 5.30 PM, Omegathon Final Round.
Scott: We're 4 day.
Scott: Omegathon 4 day.
Scott: Omegathon.
Rym: Monday, noon, our panel, bad games.
Rym: You have to show up to that.
Scott: Oh, what?
Scott: I can't go play Saturn Bomberman?
Scott: Listen guys, if you know who we are, you should go play Saturn Bomberman.
Scott: Let the people who don't know who we are come to the panel.
Rym: Yeah, we'll video it and as many of you complained about not put the whole thing on YouTube and just put a bunch of clips up.
Scott: That's all Rym doing that.
Rym: That is all me doing that.
Scott: I got nothing to do with that.
Scott: I would just put the whole panel up.
Rym: It's a pain in the ass to put the whole panel up.
Scott: I didn't say it wasn't.
Rym: Yeah, but we're doing one other thing.
Rym: We're actually doing something.
Rym: on Thursday There is an event, myself, Scott, and Emily.
Rym: You may know her from previous episodes of GeekNights and Muse Games Are going to an event that is not run by PAX or Penny Arcade.
Rym: It's just ahead of time.
Scott: It is basically the pre-PAX Sky High Table Tap benefits Right, so we have thought in many years Look, everyone loves to play Table Tap games before and after PAX in hotel lobbies Except for PAXOS for some reason, right?
Scott: So, but their tables there A) suck and B) are always completely jam-packed with people.
Scott: You can't get a table.
Scott: If you could get a table, it'd be a shitty table.
Scott: Why don't we rent a hotel ballroom Thursday night or Monday?
Scott: Well, now Monday night, right?
Scott: Instead of Sunday morning, Monday morning And that way before and after PAX, when PAX is closed Everyone can go to those places and play games, right?
Scott: With comfortable tables and plenty of space.
Scott: And that was an idea we had going around.
Scott: Let's get sponsors, let's do this.
Scott: Someone who's one step smarter than us is like "Hey, if we make it a charity event, it's actually feasible to make it happen".
Scott: And it's like, "Oh, duh, I wish I would have thought of that".
Scott: So these guys, what is it called?
Scott: What's the name of the thing?
Rym: Pre-PAX Sky High Table Tap Play benefiting Food Lifeline.
Scott: So, yeah, someone else did this thing And I think it's Dog Sled Events is the people who did it.
Rym: It's in the tallest building in Seattle Which I haven't been in And a very high floor.
Rym: It's kind of like the Rainbow Room.
Rym: It's like a private club, lounge, gaming area.
Scott: Right, but they rented it out.
Scott: So we bought tickets to this And we're gonna freaking run games there and shit Whether it be tabletop RPG or board or netrunner.
Rym: We might have some announcements We might be doing some special things at it But we're gonna be there as VIPs.
Rym: The money pretty much all goes to charity And it's basically an extra day of PAX gaming in a swanky place.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's from 7 to midnight 7 to 2 AM.
Scott: Yeah, so it's basically... PAX this year is only going to midnight, not 2 AM.
Scott: So I think, really, it's like kickoff PAX with a PAX's worth of tabletop gaming.
Rym: Yup Sign me the fuck up In a private lounge with a cash bar and only cool people And dinner.
Scott: It covers... I was gonna spend how much money on dinner, you know, that night anyway, right?
Scott: I was gonna be in Seattle buying dinner anyway.
Scott: So now I'm buying the dinner and getting a table And giving all that dinner money to charity.
Scott: anyway It's a great deal.
Rym: Now, if you want to go to it, buy tickets right the fuck now Because general admission, the early bird cheapie and the sort of tier 1 are sold out.
Scott: Oh, when I last looked the tier 1 was not sold out.
Scott: So already this thing is filling up.
Rym: Yes, so there are $45 tickets left for tier 2 Which is the same as tier 1, just more expensive.
Rym: The money all goes to charity, so whatever It's a good charity too.
Scott: It's like a highly rated charity that gives money to like homeless people Or food to homeless people and starving people in the Seattle area.
Rym: But seriously, if you want to go to this One, me, Scott and Emily will be there.
Scott: If no one else is there, you'll play games with us Except tier 1 and tier 2 sold out, so yeah, there'll be people there.
Rym: We will hang out with you and play some games.
Rym: This is probably the only chance.
Rym: you'll have to see us for any length of time.
Scott: Well, it is a four-day pecs, you might have better chances than any other pecs.
Rym: Maybe, maybe, but at the same time we'll see how much we're doing, we pop around a lot.
Rym: This will be in one place for a long period of time with guaranteed tables.
Rym: True And if you're a VIP, you get a plated dinner instead of the buffet.
Scott: Whoa, snap Okay, so we've been going to packs for many years And there's always those certain games you see about And you see them constantly, but you don't play them for whatever reason.
Rym: Yep, like Shaggy not gonna play, Munchkin not gonna play.
Scott: Well, I've played Munchkin, but I haven't, you know Not gonna play it again.
Rym: I only played Shaggy once, right Not gonna play it out of packs.
Scott: Innovation is a game I saw constantly, I saw it everywhere.
Scott: I've seen it not just at packs, but at board game nights.
Scott: I just kept seeing the same box over and over and over again.
Scott: So Asmadi Games, who publishes that as well as We Didn't Playtest This series, right Had a super sale, buy direct from them, huge discount.
Scott: So I went to their website, just check out the sale And I bought the full.
Scott: We Didn't Playtest This series just because it was so cheap And it included.
Scott: We Didn't Playtest This Legacies Which is right on the cards like Risk Legacy.
Scott: We're gonna bust that at packs so hard.
Rym: Oh yeah, we are.
Scott: I think we should make it packs only.
Rym: Yes, we play it at packses, maybe packses and magfests.
Scott: Anyway, and I bought the full set of innovation All the original and both expansions because again, so cheap And I was like, well, I've seen that game everywhere, I should play it.
Scott: So we started off with just, without even opening expansions Just playing that first box and we still haven't opened the expansions.
Rym: So we're gonna review this game, but it's more like an, I don't know, an overview.
Scott: Yeah, we haven't even completed one full game of innovation.
Rym: We played like a third of one game of it And, you know, we play a lot of games And it used to be a time when we would force ourselves to play every game.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like, yeah, if you want to say you guys are discussing this game And judging it having only played it a third of a session And not even finishing it once, not even seeing all the cards Perfectly accurate statement by you.
Scott: Yes Just pin that on us.
Rym: However, I played a lot of games in my time.
Scott: I have And I can judge a game pretty quickly Just like I can judge a book in the first chapter.
Rym: It is rare that I have played a game where my initial impression was not the correct one.
Rym: I have played many games where I doubted my initial impression.
Rym: Like Twilight Struggle, I kept trying to play it Like there's got to be something to this.
Rym: Everyone says this game is so great.
Scott: Maybe we should play it again.
Rym: Yeah, every time we've said that it's ended in misery Well, maybe we should play it again.
Scott: It's still BoardGameGeek number one.
Rym: Yeah, because BoardGameGeek's ranking system is kind of broken Is tilted toward the grognards.
Rym: Okay, so continue Innovation, I've no desire to ever play this game again.
Rym: I think it's kind of a bad game.
Scott: So the way it works, I don't even, you know, is There's all these cards, right?
Scott: And the cards go basically get laid out into this circle, right?
Scott: Of like ages, right?
Scott: So you're basically going through time developing more and more technologies.
Rym: Don't even try to link it to the theme Point number one.
Rym: The theme of this game means jack.
Rym: all compared to the mechanics It might as well just be clubs and diamonds and spades Right.
Scott: So basically you can get cards in the different colors.
Scott: And when you play a card, right?
Scott: It goes onto the top of the stack of that color, right?
Scott: And each card has these symbols visible.
Scott: And when certain people activate abilities on cards If you have more or less symbols of the appropriate type Of the matching the ability that was activated.
Scott: Then you can maybe team up and also do that ability Or maybe even be forced to do an ability or be the victim of an ability.
Rym: Ah, now already the game has trouble because the way that was all worded Took a couple of readings to get right.
Scott: The wording of everything is very poor And confused.
Scott: everyone at the table Seasoned gamers were confused by the wording of the rules in this game.
Rym: Now we were able to figure it out, but already it's a strike against your game If I have any question about the rules while I'm reading them Other than things that I haven't read yet Right?
Scott: The other thing about the game is you have these splays So you're piling up, say the red cards.
Scott: Every time I get a red card played it goes on top of all the other red cards.
Scott: But I could perhaps splay the red cards upwards, leftwards, rightwards, or downwards Only one direction at a time To make additional symbols appear.
Scott: Yeah, that would reveal the symbols on the red cards beneath the currently active red card Right?
Scott: So the red card on top is gonna be the highest level, most modern one In terms of technology, right, the best But below it are many other ones And making those symbols appear on the red cards below that top one Will greatly increase the likelihood of me not being the victim of abilities Activated by other people And also being able to make other people the victim of abilities I activate And also being able to team up and take advantage of abilities other people intentionally activate Like, "Oh, you're doing something?
Scott: I'll get in on that.
Scott: Look how many symbols I have that match that.
Scott: Yeah, I'm doing that too".
Rym: So, the problem with all of this is that these mechanics are not intuitive.
Rym: Don't analogize to anything at all in the real world or anything even close to the theme.
Rym: And they're all so varied And there's so much text of all this crazy bullshit and so many cards And so many bonuses.
Scott: And there's these bonuses that get triggered And this is the not expanded version.
Rym: There are these bonuses that get triggered.
Scott: We didn't open either of the two expansions.
Rym: Like, if all these conditions are true then don't forget to take the bonus card that you earned.
Scott: How can you remember all those fucking possible conditions?
Scott: Like, every time someone takes a turn you have to fucking check all these things To see if you got one of the bonuses.
Rym: It is literally not worth playing the game unless you have read every single card in the deck And remember them all.
Scott: Yep And, you know, it's like in most card games.
Scott: You sort of have things that go together In board games even Things that go together Like, we played Sulken at PAXOS And it's like, "Oh, you can go the crystal skull route All these things sort of go together.
Scott: Oh, the food, all these things go together.
Scott: In innovation, it didn't seem like anything went together.
Scott: Like, every card had basically these random abilities Some of which would seem beneficial But you couldn't find any way to combo anything.
Scott: Because, like, what came up was so random.
Scott: And it's like, you know, Rym played this card that was like "Oh, draw until there's no castles".
Rym: And Scott got to do it before me.
Scott: I had more castles or I had more symbols basically already out.
Scott: I think it was the castle symbol.
Scott: So I also got to do the ability And I got to do it first.
Scott: So basically, I drew, Rym activated this thing But I basically got lucky And it was just tons of castles And I had all these free cards And I was able to score all of them.
Scott: And Rym drew the first card And it was like, "No castle".
Scott: And it's like, "Well, what the
Scott: fuck?"?
Scott: Yeah, that was random bullshit.
Rym: And also different symbols don't appear In, or different abilities.
Scott: Castles only appear in levels one through three And certain other ones only appear at the end.
Rym: The game, basically, for an early player Or a noobish player Has minimal and often counter-intuitive directional heuristics And zero positional heuristics.
Scott: No positional heuristic, whatever.
Rym: You could not tell who was winning, who was losing, or whatever You couldn't, but directionally You couldn't tell if doing something was a good or a bad idea Unless you'd read all the cards.
Rym: And even if you've read all the cards You would have, the game would take forever to play If you were actually trying to win.
Rym: So I think the people who play this game and like it Are not trying to win with all of their abilities.
Scott: They're just like, "Oh my god, look at all this random stuff Because if
Rym: you're trying to win this game You have to check on conditions And read everything on the board regularly And the game is not-
Scott: You have to count everyone's number of exposed symbols Every time you're about to make an action And there's
Rym: a lot of symbols.
Scott: Yeah, there's no way you could decide what to do During other people's turns either Because during their turns they get symbols.
Scott: So it gets to your turn.
Scott: The guy to your right just played some cards Giving him more symbols.
Scott: And so did other people too Because they maybe joined in on the action.
Scott: And now you have to count again Like, "Hey, if I do this action Rym will be able to join in on it.
Scott: If I do this action Jess will be the victim of it,
Scott: right?".
Rym: It's like there's no- You have to- So it takes forever Forever And different cards have different sets of actions That go in order And the order that you do things is really important.
Rym: But it's also confusing.
Rym: Like I'll read a card right now Invention.
Rym: It has a four on it.
Rym: Action You may splay right any one color of your cards Currently splayed left.
Rym: If you do, draw and score a four.
Rym: And then there's the second action.
Rym: If you have five colors splayed Each in any direction Claim the wonder achievement.
Scott: Fuck that.
Scott: So that's an additional way to claim the wonder achievement In addition to- May also be claimed by invention from age four Renaissance.
Rym: So it says that on the wonder And wonder can also be claimed.
Rym: Claim the special achievement immediately.
Rym: If you have five colors on the board Each is splayed either up or right.
Scott: How could anyone possibly have like play tested or like Chest and balanced every freaking thing in this game?
Rym: If this is your game If you play this game the way we played Puerto Rico?
Scott: Hey that guy on the left I think is a guy I play netrunner with.
Scott: It might be.
Rym: These are all board game geek pictures.
Rym: Yeah I can't get back to that picture.
Rym: Okay Anyway Oh and uh Scott we were playing the game wrong Were we?
Rym: So here's a screenshot from the rules.
Rym: Fun a mandatory rule.
Rym: You must have it.
Rym: Oh So yeah we were cheating.
Scott: We're cheating.
Rym: Maybe that's why we didn't like it.
Scott: Maybe I don't know.
Scott: It's a game you see everywhere.
Scott: If everyone wants a full set including expansions Let me know because I got them The game.
Rym: I want to make one more point.
Rym: It introduces a ton of its own terminology Which further makes the game difficult for a noob to play Because noobs can play games like seven wonders.
Rym: They usually understand what a draft is.
Rym: They understand what draw a card is.
Rym: But this game doesn't use words like draw.
Scott: It uses words like splay.
Scott: Yeah What the fuck is a splay?
Rym: And the terminology doesn't really fit.
Scott: The instruction manual has a glossary in it.
Rym: Yes It has a glossary for things that really could have been described more simply.
Rym: And this is all a consequence of the fact that the game tries to do the glory to Rome thing Where the cards are the economy and are all the actions.
Rym: But they tried to do too much with it.
Scott: Glory to Rome is much better than this game by a lot.
Rym: I played glory to Rome again after trying to play this just to see.
Rym: And no glory to Rome is the.
Rym: it does a lot of the same kind of things But so much more.
Scott: And here's the thing you know.
Scott: even though the games may not be similar mechanically Right even though they're dissimilar physically They fill the same niche as what you need in your board gaming library A. you know moderately complex mid-length you know small package.
Rym: There's no way this game is mid-length if you're trying to win.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: but I'm just saying is you know Can you imagine playing this?
Scott: It fills the same niche in a board gamer's library of owned games.
Scott: So if you have glory to Rome or I guess Euchronia is right you don't need this.
Rym: Can you imagine playing this game with someone who doesn't take the turn?
Scott: Yeah I imagine stabbing.
Rym: So I'm gonna say don't bother with innovation If you like it.
Rym: I'd really like to hear why.
Scott: Yeah uh maybe we just misunderstand this game.
Rym: Yeah tell us tell us I implore you tell us why we're wrong Tell us why we should play this game again rather than just immediately getting rid of it Having not even finished one game.
Scott: Okay let's talk about a different game now.
Scott: This village is much better than innovation.
Scott: Village is the game Not perfect.
Rym: Village is the game you might have seen it where there's a bunch of graveyards And you basically put peasants out to work in the fields and then they die Thematically.
Scott: this game is incredible.
Scott: This game had the best like mechanic theme uh synergy that I've seen in a long ass time.
Rym: Yep send peasants into the field to do work And then the plague comes and kills some of them and they go into graves.
Scott: Right.
Scott: so basically there's a village.
Scott: You are a family of people who work and live in the village Sort of like Agricola but you're you know right You're.
Scott: it's a more of a shared space than Agricola right?
Scott: Then you know right and on your turn you sort of you know you put your guys out there to work The different places in the village.
Scott: It's like oh you go visit church You go work in the craftsman's workshop.
Scott: You go traveling around to other villages and see what's there.
Scott: You go try to you know grow in politics maybe become the mayor or some shit right.
Scott: You tell your go farm we need food go to the marketplace and sell some shit.
Scott: We got shit.
Scott: we got to sell.
Scott: right We just made some shit.
Scott: let's sell it.
Scott: and you tell your people what to do.
Scott: But over time your family gets fucking old Because they're old ass you know.
Scott: and you make babies of course And plague.
Scott: Yeah but this plague and people get old and die.
Scott: So when they die they sort of if they're awesome enough They go into the history book of the village to be remembered by the villagers for you know And there's actually a little book and you put the dead people into the book.
Rym: And if they if the book is full then they go to unmarked graves Unmarked graves.
Scott: or if they're not worthy of being in the book They go in unmarked graves.
Rym: Now the game has a sort of economy kind of like Agricola and all these other games Where you're placing workers.
Rym: they're getting cubes.
Rym: You're spending those cubes in other places to do stuff.
Rym: You've got a bunch of places you can level people up Each of the areas of the game is really well self-contained Really well explained makes sense.
Rym: The game's just kind of simple after you actually play it.
Scott: Yeah basically when you put your workers out Each space you can put a worker has cubes allotted there And when you put a worker you get a cube.
Scott: So what'll happen is a place will have like an orange cube and a black cube.
Scott: So it's like oh I put my guy here I do the action for that space.
Scott: I take the orange cube.
Scott: Now only one more person can go there this round.
Scott: If they go there they must take the black cubes.
Rym: Black cubes bad Which is a bad.
Scott: it's a plague cube.
Scott: it's not a useful cube like the orange one.
Scott: So it's like you sort of have to decide well I want a pink cube But I don't want to do the action that the where the pink cubes are right.
Scott: now I want to do the action where the orange cubes are.
Scott: So it forces you to make some you know slightly tricky normal board game decisions.
Rym: Now interestingly you have to keep going until all the cubes get picked up.
Scott: So eventually it's all black cubes and people are like ah Well you also sort of want to take the black cubes right.
Scott: It's not necessarily bad to have your people die off Because then you can get into the book first.
Scott: That is a way of scoring points and legitimate strategy.
Scott: Also I think the game ends when the book fills right Now.
Rym: that is actually a problem I had with the game's theme The game the way it's mechanically set up.
Rym: You feel like you want to delay and avoid death.
Scott: That yeah you want.
Scott: the less you die the more people you have on the board doing things The more time you have to spend actions collecting victory points from the board.
Scott: But if people die sooner you get more victory points by being more prominent Well-known ancestors in the history of the village.
Scott: So how do you balance that?
Scott: this person if they keep working can get five more points But if they die now I can get four points Now.
Rym: that's my problem with the game Blocking someone.
Scott: if I do that The game on your turn.
Rym: like you can spend actions you move this clock around And someone dies every time it goes around.
Rym: The problem is that all the mechanics of the game feel like you're avoiding death But intentionally spending actions to kill your guys is a huge part of the strategy A huge part.
Rym: I was regularly intentionally trying to die as fast as possible to beat Scott into the graveyard.
Scott: Early in the game.
Scott: I was trying not to die because I basically wanted to get a setup.
Rym: Yeah and I said fuck that die die die.
Scott: And I basically picked.
Scott: you know I was like which part of the game Should I?
Scott: I was like I'm gonna focus on getting points from like a single source Because they.
Scott: it's one of those games where if you keep focusing on one area You get more and more stuff from that area.
Scott: It doesn't encourage diversification like Agricola.
Scott: it encourages specification.
Rym: There's very little reason to diversify and you're pretty much punished for doing it Right.
Scott: so it's like I basically did the bare minimum in every place And I maximized traveling.
Scott: why did I choose traveling?
Scott: I didn't calculate how much points things are worth And you know which area would be the best to specialize in.
Scott: I philosophically like the theme of traveling like yeah get out of this peasant ass village And make something of yourself.
Rym: Yeah I saw you go in there and I ignored that entire part of the game Which made it easy.
Rym: I almost maxed it out Yeah and I counted and I realized if you had maxed it out It wouldn't account for even half the points I would get just doing the trading.
Scott: Yeah you were doing the marketplace which I could have specialized in as well And the marketplace way more points way better than freaking traveling.
Rym: Also I maxed out the church.
Scott: I did some church too.
Scott: You tried the church.
Scott: I also.
Scott: I did more town hall.
Rym: also I ignored the town hall mostly.
Scott: Town hall was pretty good actually.
Scott: but yeah if I played it again I would basically Fight for the freaking workshops and the marketplace and fuck and only do the other shit.
Scott: Also keep in mind the workplace and the workshops and the marketplace.
Scott: Sort of grease the wheels of everything else.
Scott: so if you focus on those Doing the other things becomes a little bit easier If you have wagons from doing all that shit.
Scott: it's just way easier to travel because you have wagons.
Rym: The game's fun and I would actually recommend it for most board game people.
Rym: I know I don't want to buy it and I don't really want to play it again because it feels too simple.
Rym: I feel like if I played it.
Scott: It's one of those lower level board games like in the settlers level And it's like we personally have moved beyond that.
Scott: But if you're still down there in settlers land where like settlers is a good game for you.
Scott: I think this might actually be a better intro to euro game.
Rym: This is a better intro to games like Calus.
Scott: This goes in between I think Carcassonne and Calus.
Scott: Like you play Carcassonne you play settlers.
Scott: you're not ready to jump to Calus.
Scott: Puerto Rico Village goes right in the middle.
Scott: perfect game for the people at that level of euro gaming.
Scott: You know it's clean it's fun.
Scott: the theme is amazing with the dead people
Rym: And also like here's an example the game limits you like you can go get grain but you can only Get so much but you can buy a thing that'll let you get more grain and the game does not punish You heavily for not being crazily optimized like in Agricola.
Rym: if you fuck up with your food You're fucked it's true and this game fucking up is not nearly as directly bad.
Scott: Yeah it's like what's the worst you can do?
Scott: some of your people die sooner like a guy who would Have been useful.
Scott: who was maybe you're maybe a guy who's hanging out in a workshop.
Scott: he was Living there and he was gonna help you produce wagons really fast but he died because he was The oldest person and you accidentally had to take plague cubes because you miscalculated.
Scott: Okay now he's in the craftsmanship book and he got a lot of points.
Rym: but it's like send a guy to get Some grain.
Rym: you've got some grain now you can.
Rym: you can get two grain at a time you can only hold five.
Rym: Anyway so it limits the amount of calculation you need to do for moderately successful directional Heuristics.
Scott: yep and a lot of times there just aren't that many choices.
Scott: because as the cubes Disappear it's like okay you have to put a guy you have one you have a guy you can put him either in The traveling or in the church.
Scott: I guess it's the church.
Scott: okay you know a lot of simple decisions.
Scott: It's not a lot of tough decisions like Agricola has.
Rym: so yeah super fun.
Rym: but I probably won't ever Play it again except maybe in polite company if someone else busted out.
Scott: yeah it's just sort of you Know fun sort of simple.
Scott: uh you know I wouldn't like seek it out I wouldn't pull it out of a library But it's cute not bad not you know?
Scott: it's not like.
Scott: I wouldn't avoid it like I would say innovation.
Rym: Or uh skyline uh no or ground floor ground floor skylines the dice one which is also meh but ground Floor was awful.
Rym: yeah this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to dj pretzel For the opening music cat lee for web design and brand ok for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our Website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights Is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays And indiscriminate thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other Late shows it's actually recorded at night.