Rym: It's Tuesday April 30th 2013.
Rym: I'm rib, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Monaco what's yours is mine.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Aka the game.
Scott: We've been talking about since 2010 a game We already did an episode on when he interviewed the guy who made the game the game.
Rym: I have a bag of cut Sort of Jimmy cubic zirconias from Andy Schatz because we used our packs guest speaker privileges that we no longer get because they don't give that to people like they used to to get into the expo hall early And play Monaco and we won.
Rym: We interviewed Andy Schatz on GeekNights.
Rym: We got the game early.
Scott: I wonder if we think this game is any good.
Rym: Yeah, Monaco sucks.
Rym: Don't play it.
Rym: So, uh on the way to work today I was biking, you know biking to work like I do And I'm riding in the car lane because there's only one car lane and there's nowhere else to go.
Rym: cuz I'm there's no bike.
Scott: Let's treat me this Manhattan Avenue.
Scott: Okay in Brooklyn in BK There's a.
Rym: it's basically a two-way street and then there's four lanes But two of them are parking lanes the van parked in the parking lane.
Rym: So I take the main lane and it's not much traffic.
Rym: This old man and a big old old man car pulls up behind me and starts honking.
Rym: Mmm, I flip them off immediately because that's just what you do.
Rym: I mean, I'm not getting I'm not gonna stop and let you pass me Already going like 28 miles an hour so you can you can cool it.
Rym: so then he honks and starts yelling something and pulls into oncoming traffic and Pulls up next to me and starts trying to yell at me.
Rym: so I look at him and I just flip him off and just keep going.
Rym: and He like starts to get really mad.
Rym: and before anything can happen a cop Pulls him over.
Rym: nice and I just kept going and I'm pretty sure he got a ticket the best.
Rym: I was very happy with that.
Scott: So that was my morning.
Scott: it would have been more exciting though if someone hit him head-on.
Rym: Perhaps another angry old that would have been exciting would have been less satisfying to me.
Scott: I'm just saying it was another angry old man.
Scott: Like both of them were trying to honk at you.
Rym: But I always want sort of real objective justice in the sense of society as opposed to sort of Karmic.
Rym: a dumb person was hurt because serendipitously another dumb person.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Everyone wants justice.
Scott: It is the hardest thing to get.
Scott: That's why I always play as justice a magical drop And other games are just as cheap the cheapest one.
Rym: Anyway, anyway So you got any news.
Rym: gaming day?
Scott: I don't have any news necessarily, but I played this game that I saw Someone do a. I guess he does.
Scott: It's total halibut this guy on YouTube.
Scott: He made a video.
Scott: WTF is papers, please beta.
Scott: so papers, please.
Scott: beta is a game Made by Lucas Pope who's I guess an indie game dev guy who's made a bunch of really interesting games And this is the latest one that's in beta right now.
Scott: You can just download it and play it for free.
Scott: So I've downloaded and played it for free and it is Crazy awesome this game.
Rym: So I haven't actually played it yet.
Rym: So I have one question for you in terms of that kind of game.
Rym: Is it above or below old gravity bone?
Scott: It's not really anything like gravity bone at all in terms of quality, I guess of subjective experience I'd rather play this than gravity bone.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So the way it works is you live in some sort of police state in generic Europe The Stan I guess.
Scott: the country you live in is I forget how to pronounce it Aristic or whatever?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: All right, and it's a stand basically and it's bordering all these other stands.
Scott: and What happens is you get conscripted to be the Border Patrol guy?
Scott: So your job is to sit there and approve passports.
Scott: so it looks and feels graphically a lot like a Carmen Sandiego 90s kind of PC game and Basically people walk into your little booth You push a button to to use the loudspeaker to say next someone comes in.
Scott: you see their face.
Scott: Right behind them is a height chart.
Scott: Alright, they put a bunch of papers in the slot that you pick up You know with your mouse and move them over to your area so you can see them and flip through them.
Scott: You see their picture on their passport.
Scott: you see, you know all their information the passport numbers the official stamps.
Scott: There's all these details and you've got to sort out whether to approve or to let them in or not.
Scott: Let them in and there's all these tools at your disposal.
Scott: like you can look through the rule book You can look every day you get like a notice that says like, you know things that are happening today new rules things like that this news.
Scott: there's a newspaper and the newspaper is like so-and-so is Criminal whatever.
Scott: and then I see that guy come in and there's his name.
Scott: I remember him from the newspaper, but all his stuff checks out.
Scott: so I call the guards over to arrest him even though his stuff checked out.
Scott: and The thing is the more people you let through the more money you get which helps feed your starving and dying family.
Scott: Uh-huh, but but if you let through say a terrorist Then the day ends immediately.
Scott: or you know, there's plots like a girl comes in and gives like a card for like a strip club She's like, yeah, we're we are being you know, human trafficked.
Scott: This is the name of our human trafficker.
Scott: if he comes in don't let him through.
Scott: but that guy came in and he had a valid Shit, so I let him through in the newspaper the next day.
Scott: It said, you know human trafficking girls killed.
Rym: Good job asshole.
Scott: Hey, I will my family.
Rym: I Thought you wanted justice.
Scott: and then they'll be like, you know a terrorist came from a particular country.
Scott: So the next day anyone who comes from that particular country you have to use the you know X-ray scanner on them to see if they have you know goods.
Scott: so everyone who had goods I'm like up you're going.
Scott: you're going to jail.
Scott: good smuggler weapon bringer, but I got one guy came in.
Scott: He's like it was just medicine.
Scott: you asshole You won't let me smuggle in medicine and I'm like, nope He's just trying to get medicine to his starving dying family.
Scott: You know.
Scott: and the thing is the book the game really will catch you with.
Scott: like these details and like.
Scott: do you have time to check to see?
Scott: You know every passport.
Scott: well They can issuing city and if that's and there's a book of which cities are issuing cities for which countries?
Scott: so it's like you either memorize that shit, which is a pain in the ass because you're not gonna memorize that shit or You basically ignore it and I ignore it and once every day There's one person like a wrong issuing city and I'm just like fuck it.
Scott: I don't care Is it?
Scott: you got to play this game?
Scott: I can't wait for the you know Final version to be out.
Scott: that if this is the beta holy shit.
Scott: What's the final gonna be basically?
Rym: I'm also on lately because I've had access to a lot of betas of games and if a game is good I almost don't want to play the beta and I'd rather play it once it's polished.
Rym: I don't kind of reach red ground.
Rym: Sure, but that's More than a trivial amount of don't starve.
Scott: this beta ends really quickly.
Scott: It's really short So you're not retreading ground, right?
Scott: It's gonna be like Monica where they add ground.
Scott: But the thing with this game is I really wish that would do a remix of it Where you would approve and disapprove people like in a modern setting and not in a fictional, you know Setting a police state setting and what you would it would do is at the end It would basically be like up.
Scott: This is your racial bias your racial profile But no one's met.
Scott: He's not making that game.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: A similar game but instead it's TSA and it's do you let stuff slide or not?
Rym: but the moral is there aren't any.
Rym: the only feel like one terrorist comes through out of a million people and The guys just got like a fucking bomb.
Rym: That's just obvious.
Rym: And that's it.
Scott: Anyway, you gotta check this thing out for free.
Scott: You got to check it out.
Scott: It's crazy good.
Rym: The only reason I didn't play it actually today was that I was at work when I learned about it and I was kind of Busy at work.
Rym: Yeah, I couldn't just take a game break.
Scott: Well, you can do this as soon as I leave.
Rym: So as you guys know, I play a lot of counter-strike Scott's kind of falling off the counter-strike wagon.
Rym: I worry you won't be able to click on my head as quickly as I can click on his head.
Scott: If I I already have never been that fast at clicking on that I know.
Scott: but I uh, I'm even worse now clicking on that because I've actually played even less NS lately in favor of net run.
Rym: So I was really good at counter-strike back in the day as in I don't know.
Rym: Yes one six Mm-hmm early 2000s is when I was kind of at my peak game and I was super fucking good at counter-strike.
Rym: and You know, I've had my ups and downs and I've been playing pretty much continuously since then but not seriously.
Rym: and recently was counter-strike go.
Rym: I kind of doubled down on replaying counter-strike.
Rym: being older and slower I am better than pretty much anyone on the pubs but at the same time I am easily in the bottom third or bottom fourth of players in the Competitive circuit which is what you would expect.
Rym: I only play a few hours a day.
Scott: anyone who can actually click on heads kills you instantly.
Rym: But I click on heads pretty well and counter-strike go hasn't been super popular.
Rym: like it's still a very popular game, but it hasn't been stupidly popular.
Rym: and It's interesting that valve is really sort of pushing and adding updates to it and Really trying to make counter-strike come back in a big way.
Rym: So they're supporting the competitive people and all that.
Rym: but there was just a huge update to counter-strike.
Rym: good did a number of things all right.
Rym: one Hostage mode has received an update.
Rym: It's not the same as it used to be now.
Rym: It is slightly less real.
Scott: You still play the old hostage mode.
Rym: Uh Maybe it depends on the map.
Scott: Hmm,
Rym: but basically on these new hostage maps and the way this mode works now instead of there being four kind of dopey hostages standing somewhere and You have to see T's have to get all of the ones who are still alive all the way back with their dope-ass getting stuck on crates mechanic.
Rym: Also the well, it's Italy just all sit in the house with sniper rifles.
Rym: Okay, let's go.
Rym: So they've changed it and now there's two Maybe three in some cases individual hostages sitting down In different places.
Rym: and what you do is you just guard him and if a counter terrorist finds one You can pick him up and carry.
Rym: him can still shoot but he's way slower carrying the hostage.
Scott: in other words Everyone's gonna get a hedge.
Scott: even I'm gonna get a headshot on the guy.
Rym: Pick up a hostage the terrorists get a ping that basically says oh shit guys.
Rym: Someone's gotta tell hostage They're walking out with.
Scott: so it's like catching the flag with a heavy fucking flag If you get and a bunch of flags.
Rym: if you get even one hostage out as CT's you immediately win.
Rym: Okay, it is made hostage maps way more fun and way less one-sided because.
Scott: but it really makes no sense.
Scott: It's like yeah, you guys let two hostages die, but you rescued one.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: Well, no It does make sense in one sense that it has that immediate situation of.
Rym: we've stormed the compound had a victory.
Rym: of the two hostages We got one out.
Rym: So I think the way I look at it These are two dignitaries the president and the vice president.
Scott: if I save one of them, it's probably good enough But much more important sure the one who died feels great about it.
Rym: the there there's a community Around making making maps that is very well supported for counter-strike go.
Rym: And what they've done is this all came out as part of operation payback.
Rym: Nobody seems to understand what operation payback is and everyone I saw in the internet was basically just complaining That they had to pay for some micro transaction.
Rym: bullshit.
Scott: Nope
Rym: If you pay
Scott: the
Rym: three dollars that it costs you get a little thing that says you paid next to your name anywhere you play and until July 31st, you get access to low-paying Officially sanctioned run by steam servers that run just all these new maps in a tight rotation.
Scott: Nice, I should pay because those are probably no shit cock servers.
Rym: So basically you pay a tiny amount of money and as far as I can tell all or a significant portion of that money goes To the non employees who made these maps for the community.
Scott: That's something valve is doing a lot.
Scott: That's their big thing.
Scott: now right is basically save on the money that you know.
Scott: instead of hiring employees They set up the whole steam inventory system, which is like hey Regular old people out there make hats and you'll get money if people pay real money for those hats.
Scott: And it's not game affecting items.
Scott: It's all just cosmetic stuff like maps.
Rym: Yep It's not like pay three dollars to get the p92 twice as fast.
Scott: Yeah, no twice as many bullets don't have to reload right.
Scott: it's just pay money for maps and all this game content stuff that doesn't imbalance any games and Most or all of that money ends up going to the community.
Scott: people making that.
Rym: so listen assholes.
Rym: You can play these maps anyway.
Rym: many of them were already out.
Rym: They're just from the steam workshop.
Rym: You can just download them and run them on your goddamn workshop.
Scott: so good.
Rym: But if you pay the three dollars you get access to awesome servers That only people who paid three dollars and people they invite are allowed to play on For the entire for most of the summer.
Rym: and let me tell you it's actually a really high quality community of people on those servers because of the Trivial barrier to entry.
Scott: if you want to make a game these days is you know and put it on steam Really?
Scott: You should make your game moddable via the steam workshop because that is gonna carry your game For the longest time.
Scott: if a community builds now the community can basically maintain your game.
Scott: you can stop maintaining your game and go do something else and You can focus and your community will pay your community to keep updating your game forever.
Rym: Or if you're one of those companies that really is focused on the game itself do this to offload The maps and kind of all that stuff to keep the community going.
Rym: it'll maintain itself.
Rym: But you can then take the resources you do want to spend on the game on doing things like fixing bugs or adding new Hostage.
Scott: look at NS2 right.
Scott: all most of their shit is from the steam workshop And they keep incorporating the community stuff into the game.
Scott: a lot of the maps that they have our community Community maps right I mean in the NS2 though right a lot of the maps started out as community maps.
Scott: a lot of the you Game modes we call the spectator thing was community made.
Scott: almost all this stuff was was made You know by in with the community people and also the actual developers, so It's pretty awesome.
Rym: none of that is my news other than my news is one.
Rym: I'm gonna double down as soon as I have time.
Rym: I'm gonna get these maps running on the GeekNights Counter-Strike server, and I'm gonna start still up.
Scott: yes, okay,
Rym: and I'm gonna start organizing play dates and Standing games so that we can start playing this shit together because as much as I like playing with the clan people I play with I kind of want to be neo and walk around a god Looking on to you peasants destroying them as I see fit.
Rym: Okay, - the only news that actually matters that the seven maps are downtown.
Rym: I never.
Rym: really a lot of these are new you know vertigo.
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty sure this is just the bottom floor vertigo oh Clever.
Rym: and - I want to point out - all these maps are like militia and that they have crazy Details nice lots of weird little fucking room loading poops and toilets nothing like that.
Rym: Library which is this crazy maze of library with all kinds of awesome bookshelf.
Scott: It's gonna be good.
Rym: Ella is this really sort of weird vertical favela with stuff all over the place, okay?
Rym: Seaside has boats, okay Museum is just gorgeous to behold.
Scott: how about Vegas?
Rym: motel?
Rym: Vegas isn't there damn it?
Rym: Motel is pretty good, but uh CS Thunder CS Thunder.
Rym: this map was in Counter-Strike.
Scott: I think it was 1.1.
Scott: Yeah Counter-Strike something like that.
Scott: I think so.
Rym: I'm guess this is before that.
Rym: This is the ancient days Counter-Strike you know.
Scott: basically way back in the day There was one update to Counter-Strike that added a few maps one of those maps of CS Thunder Which was the best fucking map and then a later update?
Scott: Removed the map and the map was forgotten by.
Rym: there was a story like the.
Rym: the source to the map was lost So no one could recreate it.
Rym: I know is our favorite map ever and it was super popular at its time.
Rym: sadly nowadays I'm the majority people I played with have no idea.
Rym: They've never played Thunder before.
Rym: they're getting lost on it.
Rym: I had it memorized.
Rym: it is pretty much identical to the You.
Scott: just if you have a sniper rifle you go to the outside of the the hydroelectric dam.
Scott: if you don't you stay to the Inside and you go to the power control room.
Rym: you stand in that top area looking down.
Scott: You stay in the top area in the vent or in the catwalk And you hose everyone down.
Rym: if you get enough players like 15 on 15 this map will recreate over and over again That scene in the rock where the Navy Seals come into that room and all the terrorists are up above them.
Rym: right that scene will Just play out every time meanwhile.
Rym: There's a sniper battle going on outside.
Rym: this map is so fun.
Scott: This map is the best map.
Rym: so kids stay tuned.
Scott: Please counter-strike the lost maps and sort of bring back every map.
Scott: Vegas Rig oil rig.
Rym: I really want some assassination maps coming back.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what other what other maps were lost.
Scott: I forgot an Arab.
Rym: that map was a.
Scott: I'm just saying it's a lost map.
Rym: I don't care about bad lost maps.
Rym: I don't play jail.
Scott: What was the one with a back alley back alley?
Rym: I hated that map so much.
Scott: I'm not saying it's a good map and just saying the lost maps good or bad.
Rym: I want Jeep Athan Vegas oil rig Man.
Rym: Remember that goes to Gordon Freeman in the estate basement.
Rym: Yeah, I never knew how to make that occur.
Rym: So yeah stay tuned.
Rym: counter-strike shit be happening with GeekNights soon as we deal with anime.
Rym: Boston, Connecticut packs, Australia.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: I tumbled this earlier.
Rym: I have a tumbler so you can follow me there.
Rym: But I promise the tumbler won't just be previews of things of the day going forward.
Rym: But this is just too good to not be a thing of the day.
Rym: It is my thing of the day.
Scott: This is a collection of Soviet anti-drinking posters anti drinking So basically the most ineffective posters in the universe.
Rym: basically these posters are like stop drinking you assholes.
Rym: It's ruining everything.
Rym: Here's a guy a plumbers like drinking with this bottle of Boca You know back And he's dancing with this broken ass pipe that I guess he was supposed to.
Scott: that means we want to drink.
Rym: These all make me run a drink but there maybe that's the exact reason.
Rym: There's one where guys just drinking about to walk off a cliff and the government's like stop.
Scott: I just imagined a bunch of guys.
Scott: they're sitting in the propaganda office and it's like alright guys you to make anti drinking posters.
Scott: What drinking posters?
Scott: as in telling people do not drink?
Scott: They're sitting there drinking and he's like, why'd you say come rad?
Rym: I'll just say one thing The Soviet Union overall not the greatest thing to have happened in the history of humanity,
Scott: but
Rym: the art especially the propaganda art that came out of the Soviet era is one of my favorite kinds of art and There are so many different styles Represented here, but they're so recognizably Soviet.
Rym: Enjoy these.
Rym: the soda pop in skiing vodka drinking ski.
Scott: That's right Okay, so my thing of the day is this trailer for a game that came out today.
Scott: I haven't played it yet And the reason I haven't bought this game yet today is because it may.
Scott: I'm not sure I'm you know But it may have microtransactions pay-to-win.
Scott: if it does not have those things I will buy this game today.
Rym: all I know cuz Scott watched the trailer.
Rym: I didn't.
Rym: I was at work You know working the trailer just now just now but earlier I hadn't.
Rym: so I see internet all the people I know on the internet like oh my god this game.
Rym: Ah, and I clicked.
Rym: I looked I'm like what?
Rym: All right It looks like some kind of RTS like what's going on here and I kind of ignored it.
Rym: then I watched the trailer.
Scott: Yeah, so it's called Leviathan warships.
Scott: It's a turn-based boat strategy game.
Scott: It has four game modes.
Scott: It has all kinds of good shit that the coolest thing it has is.
Scott: that has co-op and multiplayer And of course is turn-based.
Scott: so you can take a turn on your PC then take a turn on your iPad and your opponent could take a turn on their iPad and then on their Android tablet and then On their Mac and then in there to be the best part.
Rym: what this trailer is the best trailer.
Scott: That's why it's a thing of the day.
Scott: It's like it was.
Scott: the game announcement Is the best video game trailer I have ever seen in my entire life And I've seen a lot of video game trailers.
Rym: the moment where he got me is it just cuts to the ship customization.
Rym: He's like you want to customize your boats.
Rym: we can head start.
Rym: I was like, oh my god I want to click on that right now.
Rym: I just want to drag boat lasers out of my boat.
Rym: Look at all those holes.
Rym: I'm gonna fill it with boat lasers Boat lasers.
Scott: this game has.
Rym: that's the one thing missing from the new xcom that I kind of miss The actual inventory Tetris.
Scott: We'll have to start calling it Leviathan warship inventory.
Rym: It's fine because clips inventory Tetris.
Scott: I believe by noon tomorrow the torchbearer Kickstarter will be I think exactly at noon tomorrow the torchbearer Kickstarter will have be happening Clenching because there is no torch in it.
Rym: I'm holding this pistol grip for the HD camera.
Rym: Yeah, I Need a sword met a moment.
Rym: go over this quickly.
Rym: Our book club book is player of games.
Rym: enm banks the.
Rym: We're gonna be a ConnectiCon.
Rym: we're gonna be at PAX Australia.
Rym: We're gonna be an anime Boston.
Rym: We're doing a shit ton.
Scott: I can't you ever do in chronological order.
Rym: That's on purpose.
Scott: It's anime Boston.
Scott: then ConnectiCon.
Scott: then packs awesome.
Rym: PAX Prime Well, then PAX dev probably.
Rym: then PAX Prime all right, and then we had a little bit of a break because we're probably like hot Scott or anything.
Rym: and Then magfest Mark MAGFest.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I keep forgetting that magfest is gonna have machine supremacy.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I haven't been looking forward to a concert as much as I'm looking only Seven months away.
Scott: Ah, I guess we should get our panels in.
Rym: And yeah, we got shit on the internet.
Rym: We just uploaded video of the second of our packs lectures from this most recent PAX East our 23rd goddamn packs panel 23 in all those years.
Rym: We did 16 Otakon panels.
Rym: We have 23 packs.
Scott: It's something just fly by the window.
Scott: I think it was a clock.
Rym: So Monaco.
Rym: I'll link to the other shows we've done on this but in a word Brilliant.
Rym: It's everything I expected it to be having watched it since 2010 right?
Scott: so think about the early prototype of this game won mad awards at GDC or IGDA or whatever it is.
Scott: It won a ton of fucking awards the earliest of prototypes Right.
Scott: and the guy basically takes this game and for years just keeps working on it and keeps working on it and keeps working on It and every time he brings it out of packs in its car.
Rym: I'll give you $100 right now.
Scott: don't die the game was already fucking incredible when it was brand new prototype.
Scott: and He brings out of packs like every packs with a slightly updated version and it keeps getting updated and updated and he just kept working On it and actually didn't stop working on it for many years just kept upgrading the game and improving on it and iterating and adding stuff to it and It would be just so much better every single time.
Scott: and it's like well, why even fucking release this game?
Scott: Just keep you know updating it or be like minecraft give it to us now and just keep giving us updates all the time.
Scott: But no, they didn't do that.
Scott: They just get working on it until like a week ago.
Rym: Maybe a few days ago We got it a little earlier because we got a review copy.
Scott: They just friggin finally put it out saying here it is all these years of work.
Scott: We weren't you know Duke Nukem forevering.
Scott: We weren't half-life 3-ing.
Scott: We really were just improving on it and not releasing it till it was done.
Scott: Just like half-life 1. and here it is.
Scott: and Yeah, it's still terrific pocketwatch games.
Rym: I salute you.
Rym: The game is great But the thing is it's guy.
Rym: there were things I expected to be great because I already played it in its early iterations.
Rym: Those things were still there and I was already excited about those.
Rym: But there were things that were great that I didn't anticipate.
Rym: I did not expect The characters and story to actually be what they were.
Scott: Yeah I mean, I thought the game would just be sort of like, you know The characters are just sort of classes and they don't really matter But they put in like this whole story to this thing.
Rym: It's a pretty good story and I think my favorite that the level of detail and we'll talk about what the game is in a. In case you've lived under a rock since 2009 ish.
Rym: But basically I noticed at one point when I just started playing I just got that review copy and I keep.
Rym: I say we have a review copy because in full disclosure we do.
Rym: I hate it When people don't disclose.
Rym: they got something for free cuz you know by us or I paid for it actually bought a four-pack.
Scott: I gave away two keys already.
Scott: I just gave one away I think in the newsletter and I gave one away on Google our Google Plus.
Rym: Maybe I'll give the other one away sometime But it was the fact that I was playing as Someone and I ran into a bathroom and I was like, oh I can pee cool.
Rym: That's funny Yeah, and I always kind of want to hide in the bathroom.
Rym: Just kind of pee.
Rym: This is what I do.
Rym: And then one time I was playing as one of the characters trying to avoid spoilers there because you guys should just play this game And I couldn't pee and I was like what?
Rym: Oh, it's a girl duh, duh.
Scott: Yeah, the the attention to detail in this game the time, you know Even though it's basically you look at it from far away and it's a bunch of pixelated mess just moving around.
Rym: It's like what the hell is going on but if you're focused on it like you're playing it it starts to become a sort of Blue like you start to just sort of jive and see through the matrix and see exactly what.
Rym: like you look at your little iconic Dude, your little red splotch, you know exactly what's up.
Scott: Yep Anyway, so what is this game Monaco?
Scott: It is a game about some thieves and these thieves bust out of jail And then they are trying to thieve their way to the riches and it's all oceans.
Scott: 11 shit.
Scott: You've got a person for every possible role that you would need.
Scott: you've got a gentleman the recon the mole Yep, the lock-picking the cleaner the hack.
Rym: I like the cleaner a lot.
Scott: Yeah, that's your guy.
Rym: I pretty much play the cleaner or the mole.
Scott: I like to play the hacker.
Scott: actually once I got the hacker I was like, oh shit.
Rym: Yeah, I can hit those power outlets exactly for it.
Scott: So here's the thing right, you know how in a lot of games you'll have a situation where we're like You know a class does something in particular, but maybe that class isn't really needed in a particular map or level.
Scott: So it's like if you choose that class for that level, you're like, ah shit, right?
Scott: So for example, maybe you picked the Locksmith right, but this level doesn't really have that many locked doors.
Scott: It's like oh It's so disappointing right.
Scott: or maybe you pick the hacker and this level doesn't have really any computers.
Rym: Every level has every.
Scott: every level has everything you can't pick wrong.
Scott: And this is why I like the hacker the most.
Scott: not because it's thematically You know hacker or because it's bright neon green like hacker, even though those actually are good reasons as green is the best.
Scott: The reason that I like to pick the hacker is because the security systems are the most annoying.
Scott: It's like yeah I could you know dodge one laser at a time and hack one laser at a time and one alarm Break the motherfucking wall down and walk around it.
Scott: sure you can do that too But it's tedious right either?
Scott: one of those things is tedious with the hacker.
Scott: All you have to do is get to the power outlet hit it for a few seconds and like Multiple rooms just open up to you.
Scott: No problem.
Scott: You will just walk right through it's it's so You know of all the classes that one the most Reduces tedium and allows you to breeze through quickly.
Scott: I think if you're going for speed runs, which it seems some people are doing Guessing probably incorrectly that depending on the level hacker or mole are your guys.
Rym: I like mole.
Rym: I don't use mole so much to get in is to get out.
Rym: I'll go around with the mole and basically make Escape routes for after shit gets fucked.
Rym: Oh You're thinking hard because this game people have called it off and on a stealth game or an action game.
Scott: There are stealth aspects.
Rym: there are but I think this is a genre.
Rym: We have rarely if ever seen I'm going to say right now.
Rym: This is a heist game.
Rym: Heist is different from stealth in that in a stealth game.
Rym: Look at mark of the ninja, which I've been playing a lot of.
Rym: I love that game.
Scott: That's a stealth game for sure.
Rym: That is a stealth game.
Scott: It's a stealth puzzle platformer.
Rym: Yeah independent of Other aspects even if there is a way to fight or survive or get away if you fuck up The majority of people who are into games.
Rym: if you're playing a stealth game you get seen.
Rym: You just kill yourself and start over because you're going for that perfect run.
Scott: It's also in stealth games Fighting is usually super hard and dangerous like in Metal Gear Solid.
Scott: Basically, I would get seen and killed.
Rym: I could get away but fuck that I fucked up.
Rym: I'd being seen was tantamount to losing.
Rym: as far as I was concerned in my own meta In Monaco, the game is not up.
Rym: you were seen now.
Rym: Everything sucks.
Rym: The game is sneak sneak sneak and then eventually you make a mistake.
Rym: Someone's seen the alarm blows and then shit goes crazy.
Rym: It's just now.
Rym: it's everyone's like running around.
Rym: the plan breaks down like every heist movie where you've got the perfect plan And then you know Scott Stepp breaks the you know breaks the laser beam and the alarm goes off.
Rym: And then it's every man for himself and it's just chaos.
Rym: Yep, and the fact that that chaos Is guaranteed to happen at least once every other mission.
Rym: It's guaranteed to happen constant.
Rym: I've had a few missions that go off smoothly.
Rym: You'll have the plan and the plan works But the plan not working is just as fun as the plan working and that is why I love Monaco.
Scott: It's also, you know, not that hard to escape right?
Scott: if you run No one sees.
Scott: you can like you hide in a bush or something.
Scott: You can wait a while and the chaos will calm down.
Scott: you can sort of try to pick up the piece exactly.
Rym: But it's a situation of you've got one guy who's like off in the corner somewhere and there's guards everywhere over there And he can't get away.
Scott: He's the mole he can.
Rym: Sometimes the mole if he gets surrounded by a bunch of guards doesn't have a weapon.
Rym: He can't break through walls fast enough.
Scott: No, not at all.
Rym: Ah But I I love this game.
Rym: the online co-op works pretty well But it's really shines if you're playing together with people in the same room in my a lot of the levels, right?
Scott: I guess it's theoretically possible to beat everything alone, but it's super hard.
Scott: It's crazy hard to do it alone.
Scott: If you have friends it becomes way easier, but Because then you'll actually have a person who can actually do everything right?
Scott: It's like if I'm the hacker I'll go in and disable a bunch of computers, but then right after that it'll be like man.
Scott: I wish I had the mole right now to go through that wall But you don't you're the hacker.
Scott: if you had a hacker and a mole Well now you're talking business or maybe there'll be a guard.
Scott: You just can't get around.
Scott: It's like man.
Scott: I wish we had fucking either the gentleman with his costume and a weapon or the cleaner.
Scott: So if you have a cleaner and a hacker and a mole now, you're really set Really most fun with three or four players.
Rym: I got a good chunk of the way through the game completely by myself But it's really tedious and not nearly as fun, right?
Scott: If you have more people you can breeze through much faster much more efficiently.
Scott: But here are the problems with having more people.
Scott: you need to a coordinate.
Scott: Yeah, you can do.
Scott: you can do that unless your Rym - Scott is the worst cop.
Scott: People means more people fucking up.
Scott: need I remind you of the level in four swords with the searchlights?
Rym: That was one of my most memorable gaming moments.
Scott: with four people, right?
Scott: You're gonna have four times as many fuck-ups, right?
Scott: Cuz everyone's gonna fuck up pretty much equally.
Rym: I Think I think it was the ninth or tenth time We've been hit by a searchlight and I don't remember who said it but someone said guys the fuck is wrong with you.
Rym: How hard is it to not get?
Rym: and it must have been karma, but that was when the searchlight got him.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So, did you beat the game?
Scott: no, I'd be.
Scott: I didn't even beat all the blue love.
Rym: Oh, oh, okay.
Rym: So not gonna spoil stuff, but I'll say this some things happen in the game that are unexpected obviously and Game mode may change in a certain instance.
Rym: Trying to be really vague about this because it's the game is too good for me to waste my breath.
Rym: Spoiling crap for you.
Rym: There is no reason anyone listening to GeekNights should not buy this game.
Scott: Yeah, and if you have to buy a four-pack, it's cheap and give the rest of you don't even need xbla.
Rym: I don't think even works on xbla.
Scott: Yeah, I think the Xbox version they're having trouble releasing it.
Scott: There's a statement on their site or something.
Scott: Just buy the steam one.
Scott: What the hell is wrong with you.
Rym: and this game will run on pretty pathetic hardware and it works perfectly.
Scott: with steam big picture mode On your TV with Xbox wireless or wired controllers it works.
Scott: It's designed that way.
Scott: it's designed for that shit.
Rym: But yeah, seriously stuff happens at the end of the game.
Scott: That is crazy and unexpected I mean if they're working on for so many years, all right I would hope that you know, this would be the most polished and yeah, it is.
Scott: It is the most polished and amazing.
Rym: So the visual style, you know pixelation everything aside.
Rym: what I like about it is The Specifically the fact that it does that Ultima sort of style line of sight where if you can't see it You just can't see it
Scott: unless you're the lookout
Rym: true But even then the lookout just sees like the floating gun or the fist or the little doggy.
Scott: see that reminds me, right?
Scott: Another thing this game does, you know, I already mentioned four swords.
Scott: It gives you the Crystal Chronicles kind of action right where?
Scott: remember in Crystal Chronicles on your GBA screen Everyone had something different one person at the map and one person had like the mission, right?
Rym: Whatever Sort of thing it forces you to share information among yourselves.
Scott: It's not classes in the same way as Team Fortress 2, right?
Scott: It's Really strictly defined roles more than just classes, but everyone sort of has the same role, right?
Rym: Recon fucking hide there and recon for me or a scout so I can see where I'm going.
Rym: don't get up to start running around For no reason.
Rym: Yep And I think what I hate the most is guard dogs though.
Scott: Yeah, guard dogs are pretty rough.
Scott: A lot of the weapons are silenced like you can just get.
Scott: if you get a gun You can get away with shooting a lot of people.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, you know many times I've cut the power just to murder the guard who comes to turn the power back on.
Rym: Mm-hmm That is like my go-to strategy.
Scott: And the thing is the items are really fucking useful.
Scott: you get the EMP.
Scott: It's like yeah, it fucking cuts the power.
Scott: if you actually, you know use the computer virus thing It's like yeah It freaking.
Scott: you know All the computer things in the sequence of where you walk so that you can get through very easily.
Scott: It's like, you know when you.
Scott: these special abilities that you have are crazy powerful.
Scott: The mole can dig through any wall on any map anywhere ever.
Rym: Well, there are a few things he can't dig through.
Scott: can't dig through to go jump out of a building.
Rym: Yeah, he also there's.
Rym: there's a courtyard.
Rym: There's one kind of like ultra security wall.
Rym: He can't seem to dig through either.
Scott: Oh, I have an encounter.
Rym: It's not common.
Rym: Hmm, at least as far as I've seen.
Rym: I've never not been able to dig somewhere.
Rym: I really wanted to dig.
Scott: Yeah, but it but it's like yeah, right and everybody has a crazy powerful superpower like dune.
Scott: That is way off.
Rym: What I was getting at is that the visual style.
Rym: There's the line-of-sight thing but augmenting that is that the places you can't see show either nothing or a blueprint of what should be there which is fantastic Immersion for a number of reasons.
Rym: one if you blow shit up and change stuff around The blueprint does not update to reflect that.
Rym: that's the plan from before.
Rym: you guys went
Scott: in Yep
Rym: Which is just really cool like you come around the corner because you forgot that you blew up a whole room and then you see Oh the room is still blown up and there's a bunch of cops here great And to some of the missions and sometimes you don't know what the place is like or the plan went wrong.
Rym: You don't see shit.
Scott: Yeah It's pretty much the information that you have on the screen is the information that your criminal guy would have in that high Situation and it's just communicated so elegantly.
Scott: Right, but at the same time you have to sort of see through the matrix.
Scott: if you're just watching some people play.
Scott: It's gonna be like what but the people are playing.
Scott: you're like whoo.
Scott: go like no, they know exactly what's going on Now.
Scott: and if you pick up the controller and move around a little bit, you'll know exactly what's going on.
Rym: So let's talk about that game.
Rym: design wise the game is ridiculously intuitive and doesn't really need to rely at all on.
Scott: No, no, Mega Man Mega Man Like at one point a little bit where it says like yeah get ten coins to get more ammo for your item.
Rym: Yeah, but notice how it only does that for things that are actually not directly intuitive.
Rym: Yep But as a result, there are so few core mechanics and they visualize so well that the game teaches you Automatically.
Scott: the only buttons you have right and it Megaman's these at the beginning right is walk around.
Scott: Yep use an item.
Scott: Yep sneak sneak and Look at your objectives and how much money you have.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's all you do.
Scott: It's most things in the game you interact with just by bumping into them.
Scott: It's like oh, there's a lock.
Scott: How do I pick the lock?
Scott: walk into it?
Scott: Now?
Scott: How do I hack that computer?
Scott: walk in.
Rym: all these things are different.
Rym: I steal things walking stairs start the helicopter start the getaway car crack the safe.
Rym: They all just show a little clock that ticks down at the time until you're gonna finish that task.
Scott: So all you do is walk up to something keep walking into it until the clock finishes.
Rym: Conundrums of.
Rym: so there's a treasure that isn't what I'm after.
Rym: that's in that room surrounded by a bunch of guard dogs and shit.
Rym: I wonder if I can pick that lock in time before the guard dog comes back.
Scott: Yeah and the game will reward you.
Scott: basically every level you get sort of scored based on a. how much of the treasures did you get?
Scott: and Be?
Scott: how fast did you do it, right?
Scott: So it's how fast did you complete the objective and how much treasure you got?
Scott: and it's you.
Scott: basically you can go for complete treasure.
Scott: you can go for fastest time.
Scott: you can go for both you, you know, it's sort of like portal does that?
Scott: and What's a space cam?
Scott: does that?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Cam is like less symbols or less, you know You know, whatever is faster finishing and whatever.
Scott: It's the same thing.
Scott: We have multiple scoring metrics for challenging yourself.
Rym: So at one point you see an icon on a thing that looks like a dress like a tee a shirt like a work shirt.
Rym: Do you use that?
Rym: suddenly you're in a costume and guys just think you're a normal, dude.
Scott: Yeah, unless they get too close to you Then they sort of sniff away your costume or your disguise still gets you or in the hospital if you open those fucking boarded doors.
Scott: Yep, you know, but it's like yeah Disguises are fucking amazing.
Rym: Yeah, that's why the gentleman is pretty cool.
Scott: Yeah, I like it.
Scott: when you get another character.
Scott: See the gentleman can get a costume disguise any time, which is great.
Scott: But like if another character gets a disguise super powerful hacker with a disguise you just fucking walk up and hack everything.
Rym: When you hack something a little green squirrel I guess yeah green square pops out of you And if it's some other someone else hacks a normal computer Then it's the color square of them just moves around the map along these wires Kind of disabling everything it bumps into until guards or time or whatever on hack it.
Rym: Yeah, so you can just hack a bunch of stuff.
Rym: You kind of see your virus program going around cleaning stuff up for you, which is awesome.
Scott: The game's just intuitive means all because every most of the level designs, you know Every character is useful in every level no matter what level it is.
Scott: There's gonna be a thing to hack All right, there's gonna be a wall to break through When you get the hacking going on all the security systems just off and it's just like oh so relaxing.
Scott: I can't stress that enough.
Rym: The other thing I like is that if you kill a dude, there's a little Skellington laying there.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and if someone sees it they freak out and you can push it by.
Scott: you can push walking into it.
Rym: But yeah, I didn't.
Rym: I kind of didn't think about that because in mark of the ninja that's a big deal.
Rym: Like when I kill someone I drag their body somewhere and hide it.
Rym: So I kill a dude I'm doing about my business and then suddenly I see this person come around the corner and bump into the Skeleton and then freak out And run and call someone on the phone and then guards are up my ass.
Scott: You can also hack the phones and then they can't call.
Scott: you can go and pick up the phone yourself.
Scott: You can go make a phone call to get someone to pick up at the other end.
Rym: This game just does so much so elegantly with such economy That it is easily one of the best games to come out this year.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we saw it coming and we saw correctly.
Rym: It's everything I expected.
Rym: It's in many ways It's better than I expected in other ways.
Rym: I have almost nothing negative to say about it.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: This really replaces at least until everybody's beaten every level and gotten tired of it is the bomber man Does because it's like it's that kind of party game, you know, you know slot in your gaming library.
Scott: But it the thing it doesn't have that bomber man does is sort of an infinite replayability, right?
Rym: It does have the ability does.
Scott: don't get me wrong though.
Scott: This game has a zillion fucking levels.
Scott: holy shit does.
Scott: the game have a lot of levels.
Scott: you will not get old quickly, but Once you and all your friends have played all the levels eventually, it's like, okay.
Rym: But then what becomes fun is if you play like you've got two veterans and two people who have never played the game before.
Rym: It's just like in the heist movie with two veterans telling Robert Redford how to do it Like you.
Rym: listen kid.
Rym: Don't touch that.
Rym: That's an alarm.
Rym: I want you to go over there.
Rym: I want you to hack that computer.
Rym: Yeah, and then when he doesn't hack the computer and dicks around on his own and shit goes down.
Rym: you can yell I told you as you run past his skeleton with the loot.
Scott: There's also a little bit super meat boy action where you sort of play the level and die and then play it again And now you know where shit is and you know where to go.
Scott: Yeah, and there's also the thing is when you die Basically, you don't lose until all the characters are dead.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So and every time moles dead.
Scott: Well, yeah You can't use the mole again in this level and it's like shit.
Scott: cuz like you'll pick the character who's most useful for beating that Level.
Scott: they'll die and it's like well you have to beat the carrot.
Scott: If you're playing one player now, you have to beat the level with a different character.
Scott: Not that one.
Scott: It's like well That's gonna be a huge pain in my ass To do it the other way and then you eventually just die all the way and then you start over with the same guy again.
Rym: so This is one of the very rare Completely unqualified buys I can think of no one who hears these words right now.
Rym: who should not buy this game?
Scott: someone who does not have a PC or an Xbox cannot buy this game.
Rym: someone who actually does not have the $15 or whatever.
Scott: You're that poor.
Scott: Seriously, any computer can play this freaking game.
Scott: Yeah Any as long as you have a GPU Like an old-ass GPU like the oldest in dude.
Rym: I'm playing it on a GTX 260.
Scott: it works beautifully on my HTPC which has like some AMD an ATI like hat low-profile piece of crap Radeon something old GTX 440 Something low-profile and with an i3 it runs flawlessly at 1080p.
Scott: So Yeah, get this game.
Scott: we told you a long time ago This game is good enough to do two full GeekNights episode and an interview with Andy Schatz.
Scott: That was one of the episodes Like I think we did.
Rym: I did a preview I forget.
Scott: I think I don't know how we can possibly recommend a thing more.
Scott: We did more talk about this game on GeekNights than about like prince of nothing or maybe not counter-strike.
Rym: Yeah, counter-strike burning wheel.
Rym: We've talked about a lot too, right?
Rym: But I mean, come on seriously speaking of which we will soon as soon as we can arrange it We're gonna have tour on GeekNights to talk about torch bear.
Scott: torch bear I won't make that joke when he's here cuz that would be.
Rym: you will make that joke And I'll go and I don't know if he'll laugh or not.
Rym: I think he'll chuckle a little maybe like hey He's such a normal and nice person.
Scott: I know not a wacky or crazy or silly person at all.
Scott: He's so level-headed.
Rym: I'm just really interesting to have my GeekNights.
Rym: I'm gonna ask him mostly about stuff that I just don't know about him because I don't hang out with him much except at burning Cons, yeah But yeah, Monica's great.
Rym: We're gonna play some more.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night La mr.
Scott: Fionn.
Rym: but you gotta see get all those Bum-bum-bum-bum-bum.