Rym: It's Thursday, May 2nd, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: Camping.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So today at work I was killing some downtime on the old tweeters.
Rym: And basically Conrad and I came up with a brilliant business proposition.
Rym: And I feel like you could turn this into a real, not so much a business, but at least a funny or cool app.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Homeopathic iTunes.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: So think about this.
Rym: I was making a joke.
Scott: They give you money and you give them some bits but it's not an app?
Rym: A dude who was selling basically dowsing rods as bomb detectors was arrested and is going to jail for a long time.
Scott: Hooray!
Rym: So I was musing on why we don't arrest all the other people selling homeoepithes.
Scott: There's a lot of people selling that kind of shit.
Rym: I know and they should probably all be in jail.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: But I made some jokes about homeopathy and then kind of realized something.
Rym: Say we started selling homeopathic music and the way you do it is...
Scott: It's like a second of music?
Rym: It's just iTunes but it gives you just a tiny snippet of music and just a little, maybe even just the cover art.
Rym: And it assumes that if you've seen that music before, you'll remember it and play the song back in your head.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: And thus getting a percentage of the effect of listening to the real song.
Rym: Like if I see a picture of Michael Jackson and the word Billie Jean, even just the words Billie Jean, I hear a few pieces of Billie Jean repeating over and over again in my head for like the next 20 minutes.
Rym: So basically homeopathic music kind of works.
Rym: Or in the very least it works way better than actual homeopathy.
Rym: Also Billie Jean is my example because two days now I've gone to the Taco Shed by Brooklyn Bridge.
Rym: And both times there's been these dudes who hang out and do mediocre breakdancing and they always do the same set.
Rym: Every day at noon they do Gangnam Style and then Billie Jean.
Scott: I was on the train just now and the dancing guys were in the next subway car over.
Scott: I peeped them through the window.
Rym: Gangnam Style?
Scott: Billie Jean?
Scott: I couldn't hear their music at all because they were in the next subway car.
Scott: It was a loud subway and I had my headphones in.
Scott: They looked real derpy just sort of dancing with no music doing their grab onto the subway bar flipping around stuff.
Scott: It looked very uncoordinated with no rhythm whatsoever.
Rym: Well living in New York, much like how you learn pretty quickly, the majority of people with instruments anywhere in public don't actually know how to play shit.
Rym: And they just kind of doodle enough to where if you walk by and you're not really paying attention, it sounds like they're playing music.
Rym: I think the majority of breakdancers on the streets of New York City are the same way.
Rym: So yeah, it's Thursday.
Rym: It's the lounge.
Scott: It's your mom.
Rym: Care to talk about anything on the loan?
Rym: No.
Rym: The geek nudge lounge?
Scott: I'm boycotting the lounge.
Rym: It's the lounge.
Scott: We just kind of hang out and talk.
Scott: Just stop calling it the lounge.
Rym: What are you going to talk about then?
Rym: I got nothing.
Scott: No, I got nothing actually.
Scott: You really have nothing?
Scott: There's nothing.
Scott: I have a cough.
Scott: I was coughing in the morning.
Scott: I woke up and I was like BK.
Scott: Shit.
Rym: I wonder how many Monday listeners know why we say BK instead of bike.
Rym: I mean, I remember we got an email from a dude in like 2006 who was like, "Guys, it's pronounced Chipotle, not
Rym: Chipotle.".
Rym: And we had to be like, "Yeah, we
Rym: know.".
Scott: Yeah, it's also Clash of the Titans.
Rym: So you admit that it's actually Titans and that you just do that because it's funny.
Scott: What did I just say?
Rym: All right, Scott.
Rym: So what's the name of the song?
Rym: I believe it's "Have You Never Been
Rym: Mellow?".
Scott: What song are you talking about?
Rym: The song in DDR, "Have You Never Been
Rym: Mellow?".
Scott: I've never heard of that song.
Rym: I see what's going on here.
Rym: So I got something I want to talk about.
Scott: I actually just listened to that song today.
Rym: I just danced to that song a few days ago.
Rym: DDR is my thing.
Scott: I'm in a DDR mood, do not deny.
Rym: For those of you who weren't alive and conscious enough in the '90s, the '80s to remember this, let alone people are old enough to remember actual anarchists.
Rym: May Day is a day every year where basically morons in Western countries will, and particularly in places like Seattle, Toronto- California, all of it.
Rym: Will basically protest nothing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The man.
Scott: It's people- They're protesting the man.
Rym: Who are ostensibly anarchists of some stripe, or maybe they're anti-corporatists or whatever.
Rym: They're all the same kinds of people with the same weirdo talking points.
Rym: Like, take the people who did Occupy Wall Street and go one step crazier.
Rym: Exactly one step.
Scott: It doesn't really get crazier than contrail guy.
Rym: Yeah, well, chemtrail guy is way beyond all of that.
Rym: It's like a separate spectrum.
Rym: But there's a particular class of people who will do the Occupy thing in that kind of derpy way that they do their thing.
Rym: One step beyond that is the self-described anarchist.
Rym: Basically, it's the equivalent of hipsters who pretend to be into politics and live on the West Coast.
Scott: They're really about equivalent to Ron Paul guy in my book.
Rym: Yeah, I've never understood what they actually want, what they're actually after.
Rym: Don't think they know about anarchy.
Rym: At best, they're like the anarchists in Chesterton's book, The Man Who Was Thursday.
Scott: Right, they're basically anti-current society and they just want to fight against it.
Scott: So the first thing that comes along that is a replacement, they latch onto it and that's their thing.
Rym: But what's even funnier is that one step beyond them are the guys who are "anarchists" in quotes.
Rym: But they pretend to be old-timey anarchists and they actually wear bandanas and are ready to fight the cops and basically provoke fights with riot police without fail every year on May 1st.
Rym: And every time there's a G7 or a WTO conference, they show up, they break a bunch of windows of Starbuckses, they try to flip over cars, as soon as the police come anywhere near them, they start screaming, "The man, the man, they're getting me!
Rym: I'm going to sue you for arresting
Rym: me!".
Rym: Blah, blah, blah.
Rym: And in the 90s, this was always in the news.
Rym: It's basically not in the news anymore.
Rym: My news is just to show people who don't pay attention that this still happens.
Rym: And it's kind of hilarious because at least in the 80s and in the early to mid-90s, because there wasn't an internet like we know today, this stuff would make the mainstream news and you could kind of understand at least.
Rym: these are people who have a thing and this is the only way they can get attention.
Rym: But there's really no excuse for this bullshit anymore and no one sides with them at all anymore.
Scott: Well, they side with themselves.
Scott: There's more than one of them.
Scott: There's not just one guy.
Scott: There's still these two guys and they side with each other, so that's who sides with them.
Rym: To quote one of them, "They're just doing what they need to do to stand up for ourselves.
Rym: These are our streets and we have the right to take
Rym: them."
Rym: Says the guy who basically breaks some Starbucks windows and then screams that he's getting arrested.
Scott: I don't think you have a right to break the Starbucks windows.
Scott: The Starbucks window is not part of the streets.
Rym: So, if you're not aware of this subculture, take a gander at this article because the headlining picture says everything.
Rym: Two totally normal police, but because it's Seattle, they're bicycle police and they're just dragging away.
Rym: this guy who looks like he deserves to be dragged away and/or tased and has the exact face that people like this tend to have when they're being arrested for doing their absolutely nothing wrong that they were doing.
Rym: So, that's all I got to say.
Rym: If you're not aware of these morons, this is all kind of funny.
Rym: And this is coming from someone who thinks we should be doing protests for things like this, but actually about real things.
Scott: What are they protesting even?
Scott: They're just protesting the man.
Scott: They don't have a specific thing.
Rym: Protesters began throwing metal rods and water bottles at officers and business windows.
Rym: And then the officers walked in and just started arresting them.
Scott: In protest, you gotta be Gandhi style.
Scott: If you're throwing shit, it's like, well, fuck you.
Rym: You can throw shit in certain situations, but I can even rationalize certain kinds of violent protests.
Rym: However, that's neither here nor there because nothing related to the May 1st WTO anti-globalization protest for the last 20+ years has been even close to reasonable.
Scott: No.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: I used to be a big fan of these sort of things.
Rym: Especially in the early anime-con days, like the fake trailer to a movie, like the fake trailer to Evangelion, or take a movie trailer and mash it up with an anime or something like that.
Rym: This is a gritty movie trailer, and these people seem to have done several, but this one's probably the best one.
Rym: Basically, they make fake movie trailers that are the gritty reboot of X. Because that seems to be what Hollywood does lately.
Scott: And you do a gritty reboot of something that's already gritty?
Rym: That'd be pretty cool.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: I would do a gritty reboot of Batman.
Rym: It's just Batman going, "I'm not the hero that Gotham
Rym: wants!".
Rym: And then it's just him, Hannibal Lecter.
Rym: Anyway, this is a gritty reboot of Calvin and Hobbes.
Rym: And the reason I make this my thing of the day is that it's not only well done and apt in many ways, but if this were a real movie, I would actually consider watching it once it came to Netflix.
Scott: Calvin and Hobbes mixes seem to be very popular lately.
Scott: I mean, they've been popular always, but lately, I think the frequency in which new ones appear has been increasing steadily.
Rym: I think it's partly because the people who grew up reading Calvin and Hobbes all have money and professional lives now.
Rym: And media production got easier.
Rym: And you can't make anything legit related to Calvin and Hobbes, but you can totally make parodies!
Scott: Alright.
Scott: So check this out, right?
Scott: Normally, if you're the kind of person who makes models or miniatures or anything like that, it requires a lot of careful skills to do good stuff, right?
Scott: So it's like, if you got a Gundam or something, you gotta airbrush each piece, and carefully mask off different parts and draw the panel lines.
Scott: Or if you're like a Warhammer, you gotta get a really pointy brush and paint some eyeballs on your orc or whatever, right?
Scott: It's all about this careful, high skill, lots of practice kind of work.
Scott: So this guy here has the greatest method of putting damage.
Scott: Damage is a thing that you want to do pretty often, right?
Scott: You want to make a guy look like he got hurt.
Scott: Especially if it's something involved in a battle, right?
Scott: Or maybe you even want to do a car model and make it look like it crashed.
Scott: See, he has a Gundam, and he wants to make it look like it's been in a battle.
Scott: He does this in the least skilled way I've ever seen.
Scott: I could even do it.
Scott: And it comes out better looking than almost anything I've seen.
Scott: All you have to do after you do his method is basically spray a topcoat on it to seal in the damage so that it doesn't rub off.
Scott: But he has this amazing method of making the kit look damaged.
Scott: that is trivially simple.
Scott: If you've never built a Gundam model before, you can do this.
Scott: And it looks like a pro did it all carefully by hand.
Scott: So really, anyone who's doing this sort of damage look by hand, you're fucking stupid.
Scott: You can just do it this way, and it comes out looking better and more natural.
Rym: Not too shabby.
Rym: In the meantime, the GeekNights Book Club book is Player of Games by Ian M.
Scott: Banks.
Rym: I will start reading it today.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: There's a guy in the book.
Rym: Let me guess.
Scott: He plays a lot of motherfucking games.
Rym: Scott, spoilers.
Rym: Jesus fuck.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: Even though he plays many different games, mostly there's just one game.
Scott: he plays a whole lot.
Scott: But that game has a lot of sub-games.
Rym: You know, it'd be funny if that game was just Counter-Strike.
Scott: No, it's a fictional made-up game.
Scott: It might as well be Benjuka.
Scott: It's basically Benjuka.
Scott: Only they describe it a little bit more, but not totally.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: So we uploaded numerous recent lectures from Penny Arcade Expos and the likes.
Rym: You should check out our YouTube channels.
Rym: I'll link to them in the thing.
Rym: We're going to be at, coming up very soon, Anime Boston doing not one, not two, not three, not four, but five lectures.
Rym: And Emily will also be doing a lecture.
Rym: We're doing a ton of crap there.
Rym: Anime Boston's going to be awesome.
Rym: In the time we're not doing them, we'll either be in the tabletop area or out on Newbury Street eating expensive food.
Scott: Or coughing and sneezing or barfing if it's Anime Boston.
Rym: Not too long after that, we will be at ConnectiCon helping run and running the panels and workshops department and doing panels and lectures.
Rym: And then immediately after that, Scott and I are flying to Land Out Under to present Beyond Dungeons and Dragons 2.0 version beta, all new content at PAX Australia.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I'm pretty excited about this.
Rym: And then of course, we're going to be at PAX Dev and PAX Prime and then MAGFest.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And we did not submit any panels to Otakon after three years of being blacklisted officially.
Rym: We're not going to bother even trying to submit any words.
Rym: Clearly they don't want us there.
Rym: So if you want us at Otakon, tell them, because it's obvious that us submitting panels.
Scott: Take over Otakon.
Rym: Yeah, guys.
Rym: Join the staff.
Rym: Take over.
Rym: That's how we took over ConnectiCon.
Rym: It's working out pretty well.
Scott: Not going too badly.
Scott: Uh, any other meta things?
Rym: No more meta?
Scott: I know the backgammon round of the Grand Prix is almost over.
Scott: Another round will begin soon.
Scott: Not too many people participated in the backgammon round, even though it went pretty well.
Scott: Relatively speaking, the next round is going to be much easier and more straightforward.
Rym: You know, I would have participated in the whole Grand Prix.
Rym: The only reason I didn't is that you had a wall of text that I didn't fully read.
Rym: So I missed the registration.
Scott: Well, that's important.
Scott: That's part of the thing is if you want to, you have to read the fucking rules.
Rym: And I wasn't willing to do that.
Rym: So I'm completely out.
Rym: I'm not going to participate.
Scott: Just at all?
Scott: No.
Scott: You missed one round.
Rym: I pretty much said that as soon as I was like, Hey, is it too late?
Rym: You were like, yep.
Rym: And I'm like, well, I'm out of the Grand Prix.
Rym: I have the chat log to show it, to prove it.
Rym: What?
Scott: You think you can't come back?
Rym: I just don't really care.
Rym: It's not, I wouldn't have even had time or effort to do the backgammon round.
Scott: Apparently you didn't even have time or effort to read something, which takes about a minute to read.
Scott: So you didn't care that much to begin with.
Rym: No, by the time I read it, it was already too late.
Scott: Why didn't you read it as soon as I put it there?
Rym: Partly because I was busy.
Scott: You know, it doesn't take long to read things.
Rym: Sometimes it does.
Scott: It seems like I'm the only person in the world who like reads things as soon as they're posted and reads them really, really quickly and reads all the words.
Rym: I only actually read our forum once or twice a day at most.
Rym: I don't read every thread.
Scott: I don't read every thread, but if there's something I want to read, I'm constantly checking it.
Scott: And I read it completely and really, really quickly, like whoosh.
Scott: And I read like tons and tons of things really fast all the time.
Scott: I don't know why.
Scott: And it's weird that no one else does this because basically it's like, why I know all these things.
Scott: No one knows these things.
Rym: I mean, I think it's good for you because I know about things that matter and I don't know about things that don't matter.
Rym: This is why I don't use things like Google Reader because that's more data than I need.
Scott: I don't use Google Reader either, but it's useless.
Scott: I'll read boing boing and I'll just whoosh.
Scott: And I can just scroll down the page in like 30 seconds and basically get all the headlines.
Rym: I do the same thing, but you know what I do that with Google News.
Scott: I do with Google News also.
Scott: Yeah, I can basically read like many, many websites just like tab whoosh, tab whoosh, tab whoosh, tab whoosh in like a minute.
Scott: And then if there's articles I wanted, I already clicked on them to open a tab and it takes me about a minute per article to read all the words.
Rym: Good for you.
Rym: What I'm saying is, yes, that's a common skill.
Rym: I simply don't consume the same things you consume.
Scott: But then it's like, but that is you.
Scott: You know, you miss the thing.
Rym: I miss the thing.
Rym: You miss a lot of things.
Rym: I think you're missing my unstated point.
Rym: Wasn't super into the thing to begin with, so I didn't read it right away.
Rym: I only read things I'm super into right away.
Scott: I'm super into everything all the time.
Rym: Are you?
Rym: You're into everything all the time.
Scott: What don't I know?
Rym: Why didn't you bike today?
Scott: Because I'm coughing.
Rym: So you're not super into biking right now.
Scott: If you cared about it, you would have biked.
Scott: I tried to bike and then I went outside and I was like, I went back inside.
Rym: Uh huh.
Rym: Anyway, so camping.
Rym: I had a bunch of, I want to talk about transhumanism.
Rym: I got these great show ideas.
Rym: What do you say about transhumanism?
Scott: You got nothing to say.
Rym: I got about an hour's worth of discussion.
Scott: I don't have anything to say.
Rym: You seem to forget that, especially on Thursday episodes, listeners don't really care about our specific direct opinions.
Scott: Listeners aren't even listening to this stupid show.
Rym: Or are open, you know, like, oh, let's expound for an hour.
Scott: Nobody listens to this podcast.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, whatever.
Rym: Your self-deprecating act is kind of old.
Rym: You just say the same things over and over again.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: As opposed to yourself aggrandizing act.
Rym: What did I say right now?
Rym: We have at least one listener.
Rym: So I think I could least extrapolate from that, that there are two.
Rym: So it is okay for me to estimate that I can say listeners.
Scott: If you say that because there's one listener, there must be two listeners, then you might as well be, you might get extrapolated as infinity listeners.
Rym: No, because one, the difference between one and two, I mean, look, one, two, three, many.
Rym: So I think there's one of those four.
Scott: I think there's one listener.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So as a result, the thing is, you see what I'm doing there, right?
Rym: Right.
Scott: The thing is, right.
Scott: Suffice to say the thing is right, you know.
Rym: But no, I think the person who does listen to this show is more interested in the banter than in the expounding opinion, especially on Thursday topics.
Scott: That's why we just spent like a good minute, not even completely dodging our topic and killing time saying right, you know.
Rym: That if we may, if we pick a topic, that's just some bullshit.
Rym: We'll just bullshit for an hour.
Rym: We're just bullshitting right now.
Scott: We're not saying anything.
Rym: The way we talk.
Scott: Everyone who's the one listener already stopped listening at this point.
Rym: This is their favorite shit.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: Listeners, tell us.
Rym: This is the worst shit.
Rym: Every time I have ever turned to the listener and asked him or her what he likes.
Rym: We always get like one email that's like, actually, I really liked the episode you did about blah.
Rym: I don't know why Scott was so down on it.
Rym: That's what the listener sounds like.
Scott: That listener is pretty sad.
Scott: You should be listening to some better podcast or doing something else with your time.
Scott: If you're listening to this right now, that is sad.
Rym: Anyway, guy, would you like us to talk about transhumanism?
Scott: What do we have to say about it?
Rym: Or the surveillance society?
Rym: or urination?
Scott: We've already discussed that.
Rym: Because we already did a show on pooping.
Rym: So urination was also a topic.
Scott: There's a lot less to say about urination than that.
Rym: I got a lot to say about urination, but Scott wants nothing to do with these topics.
Scott: I got nothing to say.
Rym: So I've realized that a lot of people I know in the real world have never, ever in their lives been camping in any capacity.
Scott: A lot of these people might be urban peoples.
Rym: But not all of them by any stretch.
Scott: A lot of them are suburban peoples who just don't leave society and go to the woods or anything.
Rym: Well, I've realized something because I was kind of thinking about this in light of, for example, the fact that I would say the majority of people I know, until recently, if not currently still don't, don't actually know how to use gears on bikes.
Scott: It's just a common thing.
Scott: Yesterday, when I was biking up the bridge, there was some girl and she was going in the highest possible gear.
Scott: And I was actually like, "Hey, you should use some
Scott: gears.".
Scott: And she actually wasn't like, "Damn, don't tell me what to do,
Scott: whatever.".
Scott: She was actually like, "Oh,
Scott: okay.".
Rym: Did she?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: She did.
Rym: She asked her out.
Scott: No, she wasn't.
Scott: I could tell that she was sort of like, "Oh my gosh.
Scott: Let me see
Scott: something.".
Rym: So just like Rainbow Dash?
Scott: No.
Rym: Different kind of, "Oh my
Rym: gosh."
Rym: Like, "Let me see
Rym: something.".
Rym: But I realized that the reason I knew how to shift gears, and I can't say... It's not to fault people who don't because it seems like it's the vast majority of people.
Rym: I mean, I just found this article talking about how with all these new bike paths in New York City and the Citi Bike Program, there's classes for adults who never learned how to ride a bike to learn how to ride a bike without being embarrassed.
Rym: There's semi-private classes and they're stupidly popular and there's a whole industry now in teaching adults how to ride bikes.
Rym: Then they're teaching like, "Don't fall over.
Rym: Don't fall over.
Rym: Let's take the training wheels off
Rym: now.".
Rym: They're not teaching advanced shifting techniques.
Scott: Not everyone grew up riding a bike.
Rym: But even the people who grew up riding a bike often don't know how to shift.
Rym: I think the only reason I knew how to shift was that I grew up in a family that had a culture of bicycle riding together in groups and going to the woods and biking through the woods.
Scott: You know how I knew how to shift?
Scott: I had it when I was a kid.
Scott: I had a tricycle.
Scott: Then I had a two-wheel bike with training wheels.
Rym: BMX bike?
Scott: No.
Scott: It was just sort of a little bike.
Scott: Regular bike.
Rym: No gear shifting.
Rym: Coaster brake?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But it was, you know, two wheels, whatever.
Rym: Most kids get what is effectively a BMX bike, even if they don't use it for the things that BMX bikes are often used for.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't BMX bike.
Scott: But then, you know, I was biking it.
Scott: Then, you know, I got too big for that shit, so I got a 10-speed bike.
Scott: I was like, "Oh, what do these buttons do and switches and
Scott: things?".
Scott: I looked at the gears and then I've moved them all around and figured out how they worked on my own.
Scott: I'm just like, "This thing's here.
Scott: Clearly, there is a reason for these things to be here.
Scott: I will push them all around to figure it
Scott: out.".
Scott: Then I was like, "Oh, if I use these ones, it's harder to pedal, but I go faster if I can pedal.
Scott: If I go this way, it's easy to pedal, so I can go up a hill real
Scott: easy.".
Scott: It was just my natural curiosity and exploration of doing things.
Scott: I noticed there's a different kind of mentality that some people have where they just don't want to touch things.
Scott: They say, "Leave it
Scott: there.".
Rym: I think there's one other factor with biking in particular.
Rym: I think it's an anti-intellectual attitude that I do not like.
Rym: No, because with biking specifically, it's the fact that most people don't bike in ways that even really need the gears.
Rym: unless you live in the city.
Scott: If there is a hill at all, unless you live somewhere that's 100% flat or on a beach.
Rym: There aren't hills in Michigan at all.
Scott: Not even one hill?
Rym: It is literally, if you bike in Southeast Michigan, completely flat.
Scott: 100% flat?
Rym: Yes, effectively 100% flat.
Scott: Even right next to my house.
Scott: You know what's right next to my house?
Scott: That road.
Scott: You know that road to hell.
Scott: Nothing but hills.
Rym: As a kid, I learned how to use gears and everyone in my family knew how to use gears, but most people I knew didn't.
Rym: The difference was we went biking out in the woods on trails where there were- Hills?
Rym: There were basically hills.
Rym: Because you're out in the woods, there's hills there.
Scott: See, even if I had been somewhere totally flat, I still would have messed around with the gears and figured out what they did.
Rym: Oh no, a lot of people messed around with the gears, but they never fully grokked how to use them.
Rym: Or even if they grok how to use them, not grok, but they get how to use them in a basic sense, what they don't get is the kind of subtle things that require a little bit of mastery, like exactly how to let up on pressure to shift and then start going again on and uphill.
Scott: Well, if you have a certain kind of gears, you don't need to let off the pressure to shift.
Rym: You don't have those gears.
Scott: Yeah, actually I do.
Rym: No, you don't.
Rym: You cannot maintain full pressure going up a hill and downshifts.
Scott: It depends.
Rym: If you do that, you're basically going to cause a little wear on your gears in the log run and/or fuck your chain up.
Scott: There's one kind of gear that the teeth are different shapes, so you can shift while you're pedaling versus stop pedaling and then shift.
Rym: Yeah, I can shift while I'm pedaling, but you still let up on the pressure.
Scott: If you're full force pressure, it's all about the tensioning thing at the bottom.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even then, if that is the limit, then you're in trouble.
Scott: But not even then.
Rym: You let up on the pressure slightly whenever you shift.
Scott: I've never had any problem.
Rym: You're probably not pushing too hard anyway, but it's because I also usually downshift before I get to a hill.
Scott: Not on the hill.
Rym: Yes, but if you're going to shift on the hill, you often will.
Rym: For example, I'm in a certain gear, going up the Williamsburg Bridge, jackasses on fixies are blocking the entire way and I have to slow down.
Rym: Now I need to downshift on the hill.
Rym: And that happens every morning.
Scott: Don't have that problem.
Rym: Yeah, bike over the Williamsburg Bridge in the morning.
Rym: There's like a hundred assholes walking fixies up the bridge in both directions.
Scott: Come on, cops.
Scott: Do something about it.
Rym: It's not illegal.
Scott: It should be illegal to have a fixie on the streets.
Rym: It should be illegal to have a fixie on the streets.
Rym: It should not be illegal to have a single gear bike.
Rym: That's just dumb.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If you see a single gear bike, you smile and nod like, oh, yeah.
Rym: But if you see a fixie, it's like seeing a drunk driver.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: Anyway, not the bike show.
Rym: My point is with camping.
Rym: Everyone I know who knows how to camp and has camped grew up in a family culture of family camping trips.
Rym: Everyone I know who has never camped and does not know how to camp did never, never went on a family camping trip because their family was not into camp.
Scott: Our family did not have a culture of camping, but we had a culture of send kids to summer camp, which I mean,
Rym: like
Scott: when I was a kid, I sort of assumed everyone went to summer camp and only later in life did I realize, oh, only some people send their kids to summer camp and most people fucking don't because they're stupid as shit.
Scott: Now, the thing is, there's a different can't afford it.
Rym: There's a different world in the Midwest.
Rym: The stuff of summer camp is just in the neighborhood.
Scott: There are neighborhood summer camps you can go to, but you don't need to go away to camp.
Rym: You just there's just shooting ranges.
Rym: You just go to as kids in the summer and just shoot and there's just archery ranges.
Rym: You just go to just fuck around in the woods and whatever.
Rym: So you didn't need to go to camp to get those experiences.
Scott: Summer camp is his own thing.
Rym: Yeah, I know you just got you're saying that.
Rym: What I'm going to say is that the most people I know for whom summer camp was a thing, like a thing as opposed to just, yeah, I went to summer camp once or twice.
Rym: Our kids grew up in Connecticut and New York and New Jersey and almost nowhere else.
Scott: It's a Northeast thing.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It is.
Rym: I go to the Midwest.
Rym: It's not a big thing.
Rym: Kids generally don't go to summer camp.
Scott: They will.
Scott: Summer camp is the best.
Rym: They'll go to like week long camps like space camp or science camp or Starbase or programmer camp, but they won't go to.
Rym: I am away from home for more than a couple of weeks.
Scott: Eight weeks sleep away camp is should.
Scott: every kid should have that.
Scott: In fact, it should be sort of like public school.
Scott: We should have public sleep away camp for eight weeks every summer.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think you're too close to it because you grew up in a culture of that.
Scott: Summer camp is the best.
Rym: Did not exist where I grew up and I frankly don't think I miss much.
Scott: It's the best.
Scott: You missed a lot more than you realize.
Rym: Like what?
Scott: It's pretty much the greatest.
Scott: That's, you know, there's not this night.
Scott: So like you watch freakin, um, salute your shorts.
Rym: That looks like a horrible existence that I would have avoided at all costs.
Rym: My summers were fuck around in the woods with my own friends, uh, fuck around in my computer, in my house, play video games.
Scott: Hey, you know, uh, my summer at the summer camp was, you know, capture the flag with the entire summer camp with all, all hundred plus kids.
Rym: We do that with like the like dozens of kids in the woods on our own.
Rym: We play softball every Sunday just with a whole bunch of people, two full teams.
Scott: Yeah, but that's, see, this is the thing, right?
Scott: You played softball every Sunday, two full teams.
Scott: This is, you're there for eight weeks.
Scott: This goes on for 24 hours a day, every day for eight weeks, nonstop awesomeness.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like you play capture the flag in the woods with 200 kids and then immediately after you're playing D and D and then immediately after it's like nonstop.
Rym: So I would play it.
Rym: My summers are mostly like that.
Scott: There's only sleeping stops.
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Rym: Plus it was that and I had access to my computer.
Scott: Go put it in the lake.
Rym: I think we, didn't we do a show on summer camp?
Rym: I'm talking more about camping, actual camping.
Scott: Well, that's part of summer camp.
Scott: also is when you're at summer camp, you know, you stay in a cabin most of the time, but you're guaranteed to have at least one camping where you grab all the tents and you go out into the woods.
Rym: How far, I'm so curious.
Rym: So there's degrees of camping.
Scott: It depends.
Scott: It depends on the summer camp.
Rym: So you personally, so the one degree is you go, you're basically take a camper or something or stay in a lodge or log cabin somewhere.
Scott: Well, that's summer camp default, right?
Rym: So I've done that.
Scott: Yeah, that doesn't even really count.
Scott: That's like you're in a house just in the woods.
Rym: There's you go a trivial distance from a place like that and set up tents.
Scott: I did that when I was a counselor, you know, and I had little kids.
Scott: So basically that was the camping that we did with that.
Rym: There's you hike a significant distance into the woods camp and then possibly continue on from that and set up a second camp.
Scott: I've done that as well.
Scott: When I was in the camp, when I was in the summer camp, we hiked and we passed the Hicks house and the Hicks had a natural spring and we drank their water.
Scott: And it was like an adventure.
Scott: And we went over the out of the valley.
Scott: The camp was into the next valley.
Scott: And then we went to the second valley and then we came to valleys back.
Rym: Yeah, there's doing that in the winter.
Scott: I didn't do it in the winter, but I did it in the desert.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So what was the desert camp like the desert of Israel?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You walk all day next to a camel.
Scott: You drink a lot of water.
Scott: You keep walking, lots of walking, looking at desert shit.
Scott: And then eventually you get when the sun goes down, you sort of sleep in the desert.
Scott: And but the thing is, you sleep.
Scott: It's like a company did it, I guess.
Scott: So basically they had these pre-prepared sleeping places.
Scott: And it wasn't like it was some sort of shelter that you were sleeping in.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was pretty much the middle of the desert.
Scott: They had a spot that they had lights installed so that those scorpions would bite you at night.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And actually even like hiking on the Adirondack Trail or whatever, it's kind of the same thing.
Rym: But they'll be like, you'll hike and hike and hike.
Rym: And occasionally there'll be these shelters, but I say in quotes because they're basically just a slightly raised platform of semi rotten logs.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I was sleeping in a sleeping bag on the sand.
Scott: And that was it.
Scott: Except for lights that would keep bugs away.
Rym: I'm really I'm actually a fan.
Rym: Like I like doing sort of death march hiking's that don't necessarily involve camping.
Rym: Like let's go to a trailhead hike for like 30 miles and then end up back at a place where Carl take us back to the hotel.
Rym: But I also like the thing where you like hike, you get to a trailhead with all your shit.
Rym: You hike like a whole day out somewhere.
Rym: You set up a base camp and then every day you do hikes out from the base camp to other places.
Rym: Maybe you like bring a pup tent and you sleep like out one night at a secondary camp away from the base camp.
Rym: And then the next day or two, you return back to the base camp.
Scott: See, the thing is, I'm not really too much into the walking around in the woods.
Rym: I like the making a campfire and fire is other than campfire chili and campfire curry.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Campfire is the best part of camping.
Scott: I like campfire, you know, doing campfire activities, eating campfire food, cooking campfire food.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's the number one best part.
Scott: The simple stuff like hobo meal, hot dog on a stick you took from the woods, just grab a hot cold hot dog.
Rym: We took from the woods like you found the hot dog.
Scott: You grab a stick from the woods, you take a defrosted frozen hot dog, you shove it on the end.
Scott: after you sanitize the stick in the fire, you stick the hot dog in the fire and then you eat it off the stick and then you put a marshmallow on the stick.
Rym: So you've clearly.
Rym: have you ever gone camping where you had to bring primarily non perishable goods that don't require any free refrigeration of any kind?
Rym: I mean, it was all like you can't like for the kind of camping I used to do.
Scott: The longest camp was in the desert for like, you know, I guess three, four days.
Scott: The camel carried all the food.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I'm saying you can't bring things that require cooling or refrigeration most of the time.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Well, the hot dog situation was mostly like.
Scott: that was mostly in summer camp.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Basically once a week we would just they had basically these campfires like in the woods on the edge of the camp.
Scott: So once a week you would just do campfire without camping.
Scott: So it's like you'd go do a campfire and then go to bed in the cabin.
Rym: Kevin, I think, but it's just the campfire you were able to.
Scott: you were able to get campfires without camping.
Scott: You only camp like once every four weeks.
Rym: Look at how much we like, like in one of the parties or like at our friend's wedding before.
Rym: There's something about you start a big fire and you and all your good first invention before they had TV, before they had books, fire.
Rym: If it's like acquaintances or strangers.
Rym: But if it's like your close friends and a relatively small group, you got a fire in the middle.
Rym: You sit around the fire, mostly not talking, staring at the fire, drinking things, maybe cooking marshmallows.
Rym: Your feet get too hot and your shoes melt a little bit.
Scott: Don't sit down when there's always that came in.
Rym: There's always that one group of people who sits there and they talk about, oh, we should do something to the fire.
Rym: Hey, I think I'm gonna put another log on the fire.
Rym: Man, you made a really good fire.
Scott: Yeah, fire managers.
Rym: But then there's the other people who ignore that and sit there saying nothing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And then there's the people who play Benjungka.
Rym: There's something about that.
Scott: That's what I'm saying is like we think about all the different mediums of entertainment, you know, TV, movies, books, music, fire, video games, board games, fire.
Scott: It was the first one like sitting and it's the one that's least enjoyed by people.
Scott: The reason.
Rym: But here's why I like having so much.
Rym: We combine all these things that as adults we don't get and as adults who are no longer in college, we don't get them often anymore.
Rym: These are things you really only get in college or you get snippets of them camping as a kid at summer camps, places like that.
Rym: You get one sit around the fire, which we just talked about why that's great.
Rym: Two, you get the sleepover situation of you and a bunch of friends are in a tent or sleeping isolated and nobody will shut the fuck up, which is a very important aspect of enjoyment.
Rym: Three, you don't have access to your technology and you're basically just hanging out with each other.
Rym: And four, there is no way you can do any work or be productive in any way.
Rym: So as a result, you're going to do nothing but fuck around.
Rym: Those are the four key elements that make camping great.
Scott: And there's another element that you're forgetting.
Scott: See, I don't really like walking long distance in the woods, but explore the woods, right?
Scott: Because a lot of times a woods will have all sorts of, you know, hidey holes and type of things, the kind of things that inspired like, you know, Zelda one and Miyazaki movies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like near your camp.
Scott: There's going to be like, oh, that weird tree that looks like maybe someone was lynched on it.
Scott: Oh, and there's that weird kind of cave.
Scott: Oh, and there's that little rock thing that hides some salamanders under it and all that kind of action that's right near, you know, and you can explore all those bits.
Scott: Down by the stream.
Scott: Oh, look, there's a little there's a little nook in the stream.
Scott: There's something going on over here.
Scott: Check out all that stuff.
Scott: That's really good.
Scott: That's the other aspect you did not mention.
Scott: The good aspects.
Scott: I like that aspect a lot.
Rym: Now, there are problems with camping.
Rym: One, most people I've known who have camped in quotes have never actually camped.
Rym: And they usually bring these gigantic tents and these gigantic pavilions.
Scott: The more money you spend on your camp equipment, the less you are actually camping and the more you are.
Scott: It's like a hotel.
Rym: You'll spend more on better equipment.
Scott: The problem is just bringing bulky and or useless equipment or equipment that makes it more like the people like people like drive their SUV, back it up into the camp and use the power of the SUV to turn a TV on and shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, come on.
Rym: That's not camping.
Rym: That's just portable motel.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It's like I think a lot of those super giant tents.
Scott: That's basically a portable hotel.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you have to be abandoning a certain amount of stuff.
Scott: And only do the camp stuff for it to be camping.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, and it's obviously.
Scott: it's like, OK, obviously you don't have to just go naked into the woods and hunt and gather all your food.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And make fire with only sticks and not bring any matches as a line.
Scott: And it's, you know, it's a little gray area of how much stuff can you bring?
Scott: It's like, can you bring, you know, a little gas lighter?
Scott: It's like, yeah, you can bring that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Can you bring some log that automatically sets on fire?
Scott: That's sort of cheating.
Scott: You should probably collect some firewood.
Rym: I guess there's a difference between people who know basic survival skills and bring the right things versus people who bring things that seem comfortable, but don't really understand the ramifications of those things.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, can you bring a tent to protect yourself from the elements?
Scott: It's like, yeah, you probably need one of those motherfuckers.
Scott: It's like, can I bring basically a pavilion?
Scott: It's like you could, but that's basically you're not in the woods.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: For example, you bring the pavilion to your base camp and then you set out with a lesser amount of material from the base camp.
Scott: I had to see the pavilion to judge it.
Scott: It might be too fancy a pavilion.
Scott: I guess if it has some sort of climate control, that's not just flaps.
Scott: That is too much.
Rym: But there are, you know, the things that it has lights too much.
Rym: The things I do dislike about camping that mosquitoes depends on where you are.
Rym: You got to choose a good spot to avoid that shit.
Rym: But also things like not really being able to bathe.
Scott: Well, you don't go for that long.
Rym: Yeah, you do.
Rym: I've been camping for weeks.
Scott: You also haven't been camping for weeks.
Scott: And then you always find, you know, like a stream or something to roll around in.
Scott: That's often not a camp near some water.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: All right.
Rym: In particular, you've ever been winter camping.
Rym: You basically cannot bathe.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: Well, desert, we couldn't bathe.
Scott: We were only in the desert for, I think, four days, something like that.
Scott: So we bathe before we left and bathe and got back covered in sand otherwise.
Scott: But it's dry sand.
Scott: So no one is really sticky.
Rym: It's a dry heat.
Scott: Yeah, it's a desert.
Scott: Come on.
Rym: But that's pretty much it.
Rym: That and people sometimes if you run out of food, you can't for too long.
Rym: The food basically gets increasingly worse.
Rym: the longer you have camps because you're eating the more preserved food.
Rym: You've got less fresh eggs and bacon and more jerky and trail unless you actually hunt and gather.
Rym: Yeah, which I have never I've gathered, but I've never hunted.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't.
Scott: I haven't gathered much.
Rym: I've done so far as gathering things like.
Rym: I have gathered nuts in some places.
Scott: I've never seen a nut tree.
Rym: And I have gathered like cattails because you can take the roots and they're super good.
Rym: They're like scallions.
Rym: And I've gathered dandelion.
Scott: And I don't like to eat dandelion.
Rym: Dandelion is delicious.
Scott: It's a weed.
Scott: It's delicious shit.
Scott: It's not a food.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: A lot of things that you consider food are also considered weeds.
Scott: No.
Rym: And dandelions are food.
Rym: In fact, that L.I.C.
Rym: place you get brunch at has a really good dandelion frittata.
Scott: Is it run by hippies?
Rym: Actually, no.
Rym: It's got a lot of fancy restaurants sell and serve dandelions.
Rym: Fresh Direct sells dandelions.
Scott: A lot of fancy restaurants these days are hippie restaurants.
Rym: Non hippie restaurants, Scott.
Scott: How come they're not coming to harvest my lawn?
Rym: Because your lawn has pesticides and bullshit on it.
Rym: And that's not efficient in any way.
Rym: Hey.
Rym: Anyway, but there's always amateur hour, too.
Rym: I've many times I've been camping with people who don't quite know what's up.
Rym: Number one, the person who does not understand how tents work.
Scott: No, I can't set up the tent.
Scott: These are the that's that's so common.
Scott: It's made fun of in like every TV show or movie about camping.
Scott: Dude can't set up the tent.
Scott: It's like the first joke.
Rym: But it's the specific thing that I always see happen are the people who, because they haven't really been outdoorsy people, they seem to make this differentiation in their mind between indoors and outdoors.
Rym: Like you don't think about the fact that we're sitting indoors doing GeekNights and 10 feet to my left is outdoors.
Rym: Yeah, it's right there all the time.
Rym: There's not any real difference.
Scott: No, but that's true.
Scott: But doors have a psychological effect on people like, you know, I notice I've read about this a lot in terms like video game level design.
Scott: It's like they'll put a door when they want you to sort of psychologically change your frame of reference.
Scott: Like if you put a door like in between two rooms and the two rooms, the puzzle spans the two rooms, you're going to fuck everyone up because when they go into room two, room one gets washed away from their brains by the door.
Scott: So you guys.
Scott: that's why in Zelda, it's always you're not going to see a door splitting up a puzzle into separate pieces too often.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's always, you know, each room has a puzzle to it.
Scott: And it's the same thing with the real world.
Scott: And you go in a door.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I come into your apartment, I forget the hallway, but the hallways right there.
Scott: It's so close, but it's not in my mind.
Scott: It's compartmentalized by the physical doors.
Scott: And so is the, you know, the wilderness.
Scott: When you leave your car, suddenly you're outside.
Scott: It's totally different from being in the car, even though physically you're like an inch away, just glass in between.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if you park your car on the side of the highway and get out to pee.
Scott: It's like, whoa, totally different world suddenly.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I used to do that very often when I drive back from Rochester to Michigan, just for like weekends to see my family or whatever.
Rym: I'd always do it in the middle of the night.
Rym: Like I'd leave at like midnight and drive through the night.
Rym: And these were these very pleasant.
Rym: Like I have these many fond memories of just blasting music and driving through the night on an empty highway with blackness in all directions.
Rym: And occasionally I just stop on the side of the freeway, turn off my engine, get out of the car and just walk like off into a field for a few minutes.
Rym: It was just a very interesting and kind of eerie experience when we talk about.
Rym: But what I'm getting at is that these people think of the inside of their tent as indoors and they do not understand how capillary action works.
Rym: And they don't understand that tents are often not actually waterproof.
Rym: And their bedroll is right up next to the fucking edge of their tent.
Rym: And or they didn't put a tarp over the top of their tent.
Rym: It rains or a dews.
Rym: The entire inside of their tent is soaking wet the next day.
Scott: Yeah, it's bad.
Scott: I'm guessing this has happened to you.
Rym: Never happened to me because I know it happened to someone you were with.
Rym: I was a Cub Scout.
Rym: I learned I had actual lessons on this bullshit.
Rym: I've seen it happen to so many people.
Rym: Amateur hour number two are the people who don't stake their tent down and it just blows away.
Scott: Or that's the most common joke you see.
Rym: Or they put their tents in what appears like a good spot that is actually a place where rainwater will collect and or wash.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Why don't we talk about going to the bathroom when camping?
Rym: Fucking pee in the woods.
Rym: It's awesome.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But what if you got to poop?
Rym: So sometimes I've been to places where we're camping, like our base camp is near a place where the park service or someone has dug latrines or set up designated places that it'll be taken care of porta potties.
Rym: I have only once or twice in my life gone camping in such a place where I either had to poop in a bag and take it out with me, which in some preserves you have to do that or you have to dig a cat hole.
Rym: And let me tell you, if you are going somewhere where you're going to have to dig cat holes, for the love of God, learn how to do that.
Rym: So don't fuck it up or bears will come and murder you.
Scott: That's also true.
Scott: That's why you need the anti bear weapon.
Rym: They need the bear ball.
Rym: You need the bear blasters.
Scott: Yeah, we had those.
Scott: But yeah, in the desert, though, right?
Scott: It's totally different in the woods.
Scott: In the woods, your biggest worry is like, did I bring toilet paper?
Scott: Should I use a leaf or something?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you sort of throw it away into the woods or put it in a trash bag or something.
Scott: And the desert.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, OK, if you just pee, just pee in the desert.
Scott: Whatever desert's happy to have some fucking water.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What do you poop in the desert?
Scott: OK, just leave some poop in the middle of desert.
Scott: Who gives a shit besides the shit.
Scott: But how do you wipe yourself in the desert?
Scott: There ain't no leaf.
Scott: There ain't no nothing.
Scott: Just sand.
Scott: You can wipe your ass with sand.
Rym: No, I would waste some of my water.
Scott: No, it's not going to do it right.
Scott: You have to physically wipe.
Scott: See, what you do is you bring toilet paper with you into the desert and you bring it out with you.
Scott: No.
Scott: And then how do you get rid of the toilet paper?
Scott: All right.
Scott: You set it on fucking fire.
Scott: That's what you do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you don't set it on fire in the campfire.
Scott: You just leave.
Scott: you basically have the designated area.
Scott: It's like walk at least this many paces away from the fire, the campfire.
Scott: You know, if you even have one in the desert, you might not need one except for cooking.
Scott: You don't need it for warmth.
Scott: And then poop, wipe yourself and then set the toilet paper on fire at the spot you pooped and then come back.
Scott: And a lot of people like had trouble setting their toilet paper on fire.
Scott: Pretty sad.
Scott: Like, come on, guys.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.