Rym: It's Thursday April 22nd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott talking kind of slow for some reason and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're going to talk about living in the city.
Rym: Definite article.
Rym: let's do this.
Scott: So Rym you say you got some sort of meta Open e bit that pertains to your life in some way jackass.
Rym: We sat here for like five minutes with no open e bit, and then I'm like all right I'll do this thing for my life.
Rym: That's boring, but we'll just fill it out.
Rym: You're like no no no I got something.
Scott: what the fuck?
Scott: yeah, that's all I had and you know what.
Scott: in fact we even discussed how.
Scott: I you know cuz We basically had a cascade of meta meta meta where I was like oh well actually let's talk about how I came up with this Open e bit.
Scott: that was actually just an intro to your open e bit.
Scott: Decided to do that meta.
Scott: We then that meta thought.
Scott: we decided to bring that meta thought onto the show which was the double meta But then it was a cascade of metaness by pre meditating them.
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: I don't know what happened here.
Scott: pre meditated double meta Open e bit.
Scott: the funny thing is that hopefully better than you know the open e bit itself And maybe it will make up for the complete lack of a good open e bit.
Rym: There's even.
Rym: well, I can't get into the reasons for this, but there's a fourth meta that we didn't bring up yet As to why we just did what we just did.
Rym: Anyway, I do have an open e bit, but it is totally lame.
Rym: so Actually forgot it, so let's just get right into this.
Scott: It was a meta.
Scott: cascade overflowed your brain and then see cuz you were storing it in the stack.
Scott: But I totally overflowed the heap and you didn't deallocate.
Scott: so I over wrote the stack and then there was override.
Rym: Yeah, it didn't.
Rym: the thing is at least you didn't execute any code elsewhere.
Scott: It's not like I just suddenly pooped myself and actually if anyone wants to come in like you know write me an email about like.
Scott: No, you actually would overwrite the stack to get into the heat shut up right.
Rym: So this I wouldn't normally talk about this sort of thing because it's happened before quite good God and I have to talk about it though because I was.
Rym: I can't believe this is still an issue And I can't believe that basically the exact same course of events has happened again South Park as you all know episode 200. you know they were building up to it there.
Scott: 200 amazing genius work.
Scott: You know work of genius brilliant.
Rym: I love South Park Scott love South Park.
Rym: It's it's the thing.
Rym: We don't talk about it on the show.
Rym: I'm in order gonna say hey.
Rym: I like that show hey.
Rym: I like it, too.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I guess we could review it the same way we review.
Scott: Well, maybe you know I think I don't know.
Scott: we should definitely shouldn't review or talk about any of these kinds of things at length But I think at the very least we need to you know.
Scott: mention them quickly in passing more often because people seem to think that Like people seem to either think a we watch all that stupid geeky shit that everyone else watches.
Scott: That's completely retarded and Vapid or people think we don't watch anything at all.
Rym: I will admit the only vapid thing that I watch it all right now is Glee, and I don't even like it that much.
Scott: I don't watch any of that shit.
Rym: I want South Park and You don't even watch Archer, which I think you should some animes.
Rym: I watch one Archer and South Park, and I actually still watch the Simpsons.
Scott: I don't watch it regularly, but like if you turned it on I wouldn't be like so you really?
Rym: There's a recent one where they go to Israel.
Rym: No shit.
Rym: It's it's not that great.
Rym: The jokes are kind of the obvious ones.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: So South Park you know once showed Muhammad and then showed Muhammad again and no one had any problem.
Rym: and then they wanted to show Muhammad another time, and they weren't allowed to.
Rym: and Now for the 200th episode they basically did this whole meta thing of bringing everything back about South Park except Muhammad and Straight up pointing out how stupid it is that Comedy Central won't let them show Muhammad on the show
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and they did not actually show Muhammad, but they did this great thing.
Scott: actually have a feeling right.
Scott: This is one of those situations.
Scott: It's not Comedy Central like if you.
Scott: just if Comedy Central was like you know broken off into its own deal It would be probably be cool.
Scott: I think it's probably Viacom Executive.
Scott: probably you know cuz I don't know what the hierarchy is like over there.
Scott: It might be one in the same I'm not sure, but that's that's the feeling you get right.
Scott: like a Comedy Central person wouldn't be a dick.
Scott: a Viacom person Would be it.
Rym: then again look at the majority of the programming on Comedy Central.
Rym: It's not all South Park.
Scott: Well look at the majority of programming on Anything cable television yeah, and then the people were anyway.
Rym: So the episode.
Rym: they get to the point where they're basically like well Is it okay if we just kind of put him like in a box?
Rym: You don't see him you just see the box.
Rym: What if we put a mask on him?
Rym: What if we just say you know all that kind of stuff?
Rym: it was good, and it made its point very very well.
Scott: They also you know.
Scott: the key point They made was like look we're not doing something because someone is threatening violence against us if we do it.
Scott: So then they're like.
Scott: they bring up the question what if someone also threatened us with violence?
Scott: You know to make us do it.
Scott: We know who would.
Scott: what do you do then?
Scott: well?
Rym: If you're if you're violence either way if you're reading Japanese political manga the answer is you threaten someone with violence If they do the thing they were gonna do other anyway.
Rym: because then if they do it It looks like you won, and if they don't do it you stop them.
Rym: yep I learned that from Eagle and sanctuary.
Rym: that is a key key strategy especially in a board game, but the episode was great and Comedy Central you know they did do the second half of this episode, and they bleeped everything out at the last minute.
Rym: And now they took the episode down from the online streaming.
Scott: well Usually take things down for the online streaming.
Rym: no no, but they took it down down.
Rym: It doesn't say you know pre-contractual or whatever.
Rym: it says this long little rant about.
Rym: you know We didn't want to take it down, and I quote we apologize that South Park Studios cannot stream episode 201 at this time.
Rym: After we delivered the show and I'm gonna go broadcast Comedy Central plays numerous additional audio bleeps throughout the episode.
Rym: We do not have network approval to stream our original version of the show mm-hmm.
Rym: That's the end of that.
Scott: Well let me go on the bit Torrance here, huh, let's see 201. ooh HDTV.
Scott: how many seeds are there?
Scott: wow this must be the right one because it has right.
Scott: guess the number of seeds 20,402 and there's that's.
Scott: wait there are six Torrance.
Scott: That's only one of them right?
Scott: so it's season 14 episode 6 right That's the one I want.
Rym: yes click.
Scott: I'll download it here with your files.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: I will start downloading.
Rym:  that's two more seeds.
Rym: yep.
Rym: So I don't think they even sir show Muhammad in the second episode and The scariest part is that the whole point of the episode was all right.
Rym: look We're gonna put him in a bear costume and have him barely talk.
Rym: There is no actual visual representation of Muhammad at any point in this episode.
Rym: is that okay?
Rym: and in the show They're like yes, that is okay, and they got threatened anyway in the real world it wasn't threatened.
Scott: It was a warning right at least for the one that I read.
Scott: right was basically there was some group of non You know crazy Islamists or Muslims or whatever and they said look right?
Scott: We're not threatening you We're not gonna come and blow you up, but we're warning you that someone else is but that's that's Manna That it's almost as you know.
Rym: that's the nice army you have here.
Rym: It's a shame if anything were to say happen to it.
Scott: so this torrent isn't working.
Rym: Maybe there's trouble.
Rym: you know what.
Rym: I'm so sad.
Scott: Maybe it's cuz I'm using this weird Ubuntu torrent.
Rym: I wanted to watch my South Park and that the opening theme even played.
Rym: you get you know five minutes into that shit Then out of nowhere Rick roll If only.
Rym: So I don't know.
Rym: I don't really.
Rym: I mean everything that could be said about this can be said.
Rym: I just think this whole idea that We're going to give up our free speech on one thing because a bunch of people have threatened violence about it And I mean the episode shows Buddha smoking crack and yet.
Rym: They're not allowed to show Muhammad standing there saying hi Yeah, well there's not really much to discuss.
Scott: It's all incredibly obvious stuff, and it's just You know network people Is that one remember way back in the day?
Rym: How there was that you know save internet free speech banner campaign the blue ribbon, maybe we need a Muhammad's head campaign The exact same thing just a little banner with a happy Muhammad being like hey, I don't know.
Rym: hey everybody Sure, I don't know.
Rym: that's the best I could come up with on this Thursday.
Rym: So what do you have on this Thursday?
Scott: Well, you know usually it's like we try to save.
Scott: you know like tech anime and gaming things their respective days But you know what today.
Scott: I want to bring in like a little bit of everything, so I'm bringing in a tech news Because there'll probably be a better tech news on Monday right?
Scott: so this tech news is that Ubuntu Ubuntu version 1004 which is number 1004 because it's you know 2010 in April right.
Scott: so it's 10 for 10 2010 and 4 for April.
Scott: In seven days will be released now.
Scott: This is important for two reasons.
Scott: number one reason It is an LTS release.
Scott: that means that this release will be supported for like five years.
Scott: So you can install this and just not upgrade it for like fuck ever You know.
Scott: so if you want to like put Ubuntu on your parents computer or on your server or anything like.
Rym: you're working a company.
Rym: That's pretty much the best reason.
Rym: you're using these in an office.
Scott: you want the LTS Yeah, so use this one and it's gonna have all updated stuff And it's gonna.
Scott: you won't have to upgrade it for a long time.
Scott: You can just update and not upgrade which is a big difference right.
Scott: and the other thing is they've changed a lot of the UI Stuff if you are using the GUI parts at least the default GUI parts.
Scott: There's a lot more purple going on.
Scott: There's a lot more.
Scott: You know all the UI elements are like much brown.
Scott: The icons are still seem to be the same orange icons, which I think is weird.
Scott: It's like why didn't they change the eye?
Rym: I do not like the orange and brown of Ubuntu.
Rym: I get that.
Rym: That's what they like.
Rym: That's what now.
Scott: It's all like.
Scott: it's weird.
Scott: It's like this whole purple and gray and orange.
Rym: That brown shit is still coming in.
Scott: it's all whatever.
Rym: just it looks so bad.
Rym: I The blues and the purples and the blacks tend to I think make cleaner looking interfaces.
Rym: Yeah, well, you know like light brown or pastel colors anything like that I want cold hard like light on dark representations of everything.
Rym: anyway.
Scott: Yeah, that's just how they do what.
Scott: nothing you can really do about it, but anyway.
Scott: Yeah, there's a new Ubuntu.
Scott: It's gonna be pretty high.
Scott: It's gonna be high quality and even if you don't like how the GUI looks you know you can change it because it's not OS X. you can change things and So you should pay attention to that shit.
Rym: so things of the day This is a cross between the Batmobile and Roger Smith's car.
Rym: What and if this car were available in the real world now with modern engine and modern stuff inside of it?
Rym: I?
Rym: Have to give up on the.
Rym: I want a tiny little car plan and get the Phantom Corsair somehow, I don't think a 1938 car is gonna work very well.
Rym: the thing is it was actually very aerodynamic.
Rym: it performed really well.
Rym: It was.
Rym: it was a prototype car made by rust Heinz Probably not the best name of a manufacturer of cars But it is the baddest ass looking car of that style I've ever seen because it's a real car, and it's freaking awesome.
Rym: It cost apparently about $300,000 equivalent to today's money back then to produce one of them Mm-hmm and they were gonna sell it for about half that.
Rym: but what I've got for you Is this this car actually has a weird history.
Rym: it was in fact called the Flying Wombat in a movie Back then called the young in heart in 1938. so they used the prototype car in this movie But rather than using the movie as marketing for the car.
Rym: They just called it something different in the movie.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: It's kind of a that wouldn't happen that way in the modern world.
Rym: also this old movie gets points for having the most ridiculous Like projection screen driving scenes I've ever seen.
Rym: we really take the way movies look today for granted when you look at this whole shit.
Rym: Yeah, I kind of watch this movie though Has some weird carded.
Rym: I also have the movie looks good on Herbie.
Rym: also Herbie not so good But this good.
Rym: Okay, seriously watch this clip, and I think you will agree this looks like a pretty good movie.
Rym: It's not a bunch of con men and they con an old lady and the cars involved and it's good stuff.
Rym: I also have a video of the actual 1938 Phantom Corsair driving around Mm-hmm at a show and it sounds pretty damn impressive.
Rym: Okay, I don't know.
Rym: It's a cool story.
Rym: I found all this stuff.
Rym: I found this whole like weird story about the movie.
Rym: actually I don't want to get into it But if you look at the movie There was a famous actress who was on the stage not in cinema And there is no video of her ever performing to fight despite her being crazily popular and famous back in the day Except she auditioned and did a screen test for the movie that has the flying wombat Aka the Phantom Corsair in it and because they found that screen test we actually have a video of this famous actress.
Scott: Uh-huh, so there's.
Rym: it is proof that if you pick almost any thread in the world no matter what it is And you follow it you can find interesting stuff in almost every direction a long way out.
Scott: I don't think you'll find any interesting stuff.
Rym: If you read if you read what about about Oh By the way that South Park was done before the thing of the day.
Rym: music stops.
Scott: Yeah, all right anyway.
Rym: So I saved you there.
Rym: you didn't have anything and then I cut you off by saying something related.
Scott: like it was prompted like I My thing of the day here right I used a Technology news on Thursday, so I'll use a gaming thing of the day Talking about some dwarf fortress here.
Rym: door door door you may recall new listeners We did a panel that was basically the dwarf fortress panel And we also did an interview with the creator of dwarf fortress on this very show.
Scott: But anyway dwarf fortress you know the thing that's great about.
Rym: I believe it's pronounced dwarf right.
Scott: the thing That's great about this game is mostly.
Scott: You know the stories that emerge From.
Scott: you know the the game itself.
Scott: You know afterwards you know someone will play a bunch of dwarf fortress, and then when they're all done They will you know tell an epic tale of what happened.
Scott: And you know to watch it unfold in the game is not nearly as epic as you know when the imagination is applied To the to the raw structure.
Rym: the dwarves dug too deep into a den of magma as demons.
Scott: So this guy was brutal this guy in this forum here the NZ fortress Forum which looks like a team fortress 2 forum.
Rym: Oh, that's what you're doing What I know what I know what you think.
Rym: the day is now.
Rym: Oh, it has been revealed to me by meta information.
Scott: Uh-huh so Basically what he did is he played some dwarf fortress right and he wrote you know an epic tale of what happened.
Scott: He made a little report as you're supposed to do you know so that the people out well you know elsewhere in the world can sort of you know hear your epic tale of dwarfness.
Scott: and Because you know screenshots from the game aren't really you know easy to understand for normal people Especially in a team fortress forum as opposed to a dwarf fortress forum.
Scott: He illustrated it in a children's book style, and he has some pretty good art skills And he has some good Photoshop skills.
Scott: I guess to go with his art skills I guess they're one in the same.
Scott: and He tells a very good story of what happened to in his dwarf fortress game.
Scott: And let me say his story is quite the epicness.
Scott: It is one of the highest quality dwarf fortress stories I have read.
Rym: so Now be warned if you think this is awesome you might think maybe I should play door fortress to have my dwarfs.
Rym: do Dorothy things And then tell my own story.
Scott: go for it go for it.
Scott: You go.
Scott: Good luck Everyone.
Rym: you should try it once.
Rym: It's one of those things you've got to see like.
Rym: you have to see it with your own eyes to realize What it really is.
Scott: yes, but I behold I present to you the story of Bronze murder the fortress of bronze murder versus the monster.
Scott: a guess Russia's.
Rym: So right before we get into the main bit we have to do the meta Moment which normally Scott reminds me just before we skip to the second half of the show says hey Don't forget the meta moment, and I say don't remind me I always remember that I do it.
Rym: and then last show he didn't remind me, and I totally didn't fucking do it.
Rym: So here we are not a moment.
Scott: Do we have any metaness at all?
Scott: Yeah, this cosmos is still the book club book.
Scott: I still don't have a copy.
Scott: Rym still hasn't finished reading his copy.
Scott: I Can't even find a soft cover on Amazon.
Scott: They're all hardcovers.
Rym: dude the strand.
Scott: I'm probably gonna head yeah, but I have to go down there.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah go this weekend We got people coming out anyway.
Rym: Yeah, maybe we'll take the whole crew to the Strand.
Rym: It's a lot of going and then we'll ditch him there and go back to our place and see if they can find their way back.
Scott: Yeah, but what other men in this do?
Scott: we have convention season.
Scott: It's a lull.
Scott: There's no conventions until July.
Scott: It's still April so you got you know a couple months off here with nothing doing and I guess you should you know go to our website.
Scott: You know cuz a lot of people who listen to us don't do that front row.
Scott: calm.
Rym: I'll say straight up though where I'm not going to announce what yet But we are definitely doing panels and other things at PAX prawn, so we will be there But we don't have a schedule or anything yet.
Rym: Obviously.
Scott: It's a little it's a little early temper.
Scott: That's a little ways out.
Scott: Let's worry about the July.
Rym: This is what I gotta get into fucking Otakon.
Rym: Which is in August.
Scott: I thought it's in July dad late July whatever.
Rym: No schedule yet.
Rym: No no plans.
Rym: We didn't.
Rym: we started like going over panels with Otakon.
Rym: yet Meanwhile ConnectiCon which we're doing panels for we're gonna have a penciled in schedule done you know within a matter of days and Pax prime which is in September.
Rym: We're already talking schedule.
Rym: Yep, I Don't know if I can deal with these unprofessional cons anymore.
Scott: I don't know either, but you know We've gone to Otakon like how many years in a row Not to go, but it's like if they can't step up the game.
Scott: What am I supposed to do?
Scott: And I don't even have a car.
Scott: so it's like going to Baltimore is a bigger pain in the ass than it ever was before.
Scott: At least I'm gonna go through all that hassle for at least anime Boston is the fan con that is still treating us Professionally yeah, and it's much easier to get to than Baltimore.
Rym: Yeah flying to Boston's cheaper than Amtrak into Boston.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: ah.
Scott: So without further ado Yeah, so I guess we're gonna do an episode.
Rym: this was suggested by two independent listeners.
Rym: I don't know if you colluded or what but yeah people have been asking us What it's like or what's different.
Rym: now that we live in the city They want us to do a show on something about living in the city.
Rym: You know definite article city as in New York City.
Scott: Yeah, personally, you know, I'm like and it's sort of a bleh episode.
Scott: It's gonna really be that good.
Scott: But you know what I figure at least once right people there are certain episodes people keep asking for and we keep saying no No, no, that's a really stupid episode.
Scott: It's not gonna be good.
Scott: We don't have a lot to say.
Scott: We have some reason that that's a bad episode.
Scott: So, you know what, you know, you you know.
Scott: the listener requests usually You know are not the greatest Jackass is always asked for food episodes.
Rym: the food episodes.
Rym: The thing is I don't count zombie requests as actual requests because they know we're never gonna do it.
Rym: Okay, they know Now they know.
Scott: but anyway, you know, so let's Let's for once let us oblige right?
Scott: We'll do the what the listeners want and it's okay because this is not a.
Rym: Here's the trouble.
Rym: here is the problem with what you just stop.
Scott: it's the tea.
Scott: It's a tribes to mistake right the one we always complain about.
Rym: if this is a popular episode We've basically just shot ourselves in the foot.
Rym: now We're gonna have to start doing all the thing is right.
Scott: No, cuz the thing is like look if it's a popular episode among the listeners.
Scott: That doesn't mean shit It's only.
Scott: it only will prove to be a popular episode if it brings in a whole bunch of people we never saw before.
Scott: then Well have to keep doing.
Rym: I would argue that is a false dichotomy because the only Kinds of episodes that would bring in people in large quantities are the ones that have some independent of the quality of the show External appeal for the subject matter in the title alone.
Rym: But yeah, so could link to.
Scott: couldn't this have some?
Scott: you know Some people could be how many people are interested in like learning about what it's like.
Rym: But for example the masturbation episode brought a lot of people in because it was kind of weird and it got the word out there.
Rym: But a topic that might even it.
Rym: the problem is what if it's a good show that just doesn't bring in new people But is popular know what?
Scott: we will need some evaluation.
Rym: I just don't want to set a precedent for people to say well that episode was popular.
Rym: Why did you my episode on burritos?
Scott: Yeah, like you I think.
Rym: actually though the reason we should do this is that and we'll stop the meta minute in a second This is still all meta.
Rym: It's been the meta show Mm-hmm is that?
Rym: very often Scott and I will both say something like yeah, we don't have anything to say about this topic But then it'll be go time in the South Park style the terrain Parker style.
Rym: We won't have any episode better than the crab people crap episode that we came up with.
Rym: So we'll do the crab people and it'll be just fine because we suddenly have emerging conversation.
Scott: Anyway, so living in New York City.
Scott: We've been here.
Scott: What how many months I've been here since December basically.
Scott: So four months and change here earlier than that like November October.
Rym: The thing I really have to say is that I did.
Scott: I paid a month of rent where I was basically going back and forth.
Scott: Yeah, then I was here for reals.
Rym: I mean I can summarize it pretty straight out.
Rym: I now looking back on Rym from six months ago cannot even imagine a time in my life where I even Considered the possibility of not living in the middle of the biggest city in the world Well the greatest city in the world the city Like.
Rym: I can't imagine that I actually wanted to buy a house outside of the city that I even considered it.
Rym: That's the fact that I put down 20 grand to buy that house like it shocks me.
Rym: I I'm so glad that that deal fell through I I would have.
Rym: the thing is I don't know if I would have regretted it because if I'd gotten the house I never would have moved here I wouldn't have known.
Scott: You would have known because you came down to my apartment and that's when you were like, oh shit Scott knows Got smarter than me.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: Because Scott did move to the city first and I was gonna buy the house and the plan was to put like a studio Upstate for doing video and all this all the GeekNights plans we had and make it kind of the center of the front row crew.
Rym: and then Emily and I just stayed at Scott's apartment one night and Suddenly it clicked that wait a minute.
Rym: I Have like a 15-minute commute now.
Rym: Yeah, I can do stuff in the city.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's not that much more expensive.
Rym: Nope that was the kicker.
Rym: it is not that much more expensive to live in the city.
Scott: Yeah, people look at people look at the city rents, right?
Scott: Okay, so check this out, right?
Scott: I was living upstate.
Scott: the rent for the.
Scott: you know It was like a big apartment like it had a living room and a kitchen and a hallway two floors two floors Two bedrooms too bad, you know, it's big two decks.
Rym: I mean by the bedroom was enough for two like king-sized beds.
Scott: It was a lot of space in this thing, but the rent was 1200 and there were two people.
Scott: so it was 600.
Scott: That's a low rent.
Rym: Yep, 600 bucks a month.
Scott: That's that's a low rent.
Scott: So now right my city rent in Astoria.
Scott: So I got to take the subway to get into the city or ride my bike, right and it's not like in Manhattan.
Scott: It's you know, it's on the across the river, but it's not like, you know, it's it's still New York City It's.
Scott: it takes me like, you know, 15 minutes to get to work.
Scott: It's not a big deal.
Scott: The rent is I have one bedroom one living room one bathroom.
Scott: The kitchen is sort of part of the living room.
Scott: ish I have a little balcony.
Scott: I got some windows.
Scott: It's nice and modern and everything.
Scott: It is an elevator and I'm on the third floor and it's pretty nice, but the rent is 1500 And that's just one person rent.
Scott: So alright, so it is more than double rent, but that's only on the surface.
Rym: You think alright more than double rent, but for a lot less space, but living upstate We had almost $400 a month in the train.
Scott: Yep, the train ticket, right?
Scott: It was like 400 something $400 a person.
Scott: and then if you didn't live near, you know If you didn't work near Grand Central, you had to also pay 80 for the unlimited Metro card.
Rym: So you're pushing almost 500 bucks extra on just for commuting on top of the New York All right.
Scott: So now the upstate cost of living is like 1100 versus the 1500 rent in the city.
Rym: So I thought to myself would I pay $400 a month to be able to teleport to working back rather than taking this train?
Rym: And then I realized that well I might as well move into the city.
Rym: it's the ATM conundrum.
Scott: But I mean there's more.
Scott: there's even more financial things to consider like well, I won't have any car at all period I'll just get rid of it.
Scott: So that saves even more money.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, well that's saving me $11 a month in insurance.
Scott: It saved me a lot more than that.
Rym: Well, you're a nicer car.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, there's also other things like okay the food in the city is more expensive But not that much more it's still.
Scott: it's a lot more expensive.
Scott: a yogurt and in a normal grocery store outside of New York City is like 20 cents.
Scott: a Yogurt anywhere in New York City is a dollar.
Scott: So it's like, you know, you're spending all the prices are much higher.
Scott: But the thing is when we were upstate, you know the drive to the grocery stores.
Scott: you'd pay for gas and then you would buy all this food of the grocery store because you couldn't really go there that often and then Most of that food like wouldn't get eaten because you bought too much.
Scott: I can stop I can walk to the grocery store and get exactly the amount of food that I need at any moment in time.
Scott: So I'm not buying any excess food.
Scott: So it actually the money I've been calculating because I keep track of this sort of thing I'm actually making out because I'm buying a lot less food, but I'm eating pretty much 99% of it.
Scott: I hardly throw out any foods that isn't?
Scott: you know, that's actually went bad or anything like that.
Rym: Yeah, and even better I mean where I am.
Rym: I actually use fresh direct so I don't have to go outside for anything I purchase in the entire world except some clothes.
Scott: Yeah, and the savings in time is just off the charts in terms of things that I can do.
Rym: course It's amazing how quickly things go from amazing to taken for granted to still not perfect.
Rym: Emily and I do could not find the time last week to order our fucking groceries Online.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have this problem.
Rym: I couldn't be asked to just log out of the website and click on Order the same thing.
Rym: I ordered two weeks ago and have it brought into my apartment and put in my fridge for me by people?
Scott: Yeah, this is this is a problem.
Scott: I do not have.
Rym: well, I live a much more Life lately right.
Rym: but the crazy thing is, you know Scott by himself Emily and I moved You know got the place together and our rent is double Scott.
Rym: So it's about three thousand dollars a month.
Rym: but if the two of us moving into the city means we're saving about a $1,000 a month in train and metro card.
Scott: Well, it gives us two people times, you know, so it's $800 in train tickets.
Rym: Yeah, plus all the associated fees.
Rym: We both had cars upstate that we got rid of and Basically dividing it all up.
Rym: It is way cheaper than that mortgage was gonna be.
Scott: Well, there's all those, you know added fees on the mortgage and things like that.
Rym: You don't even realize I took all those into account the property taxes and all that.
Scott: but there's also the New York City tax.
Rym: Yeah, I did.
Rym: I did not worry about the New York City tax yet because my taxes are going up rapidly anyway.
Rym: Yeah, fucking capital gains taxes.
Rym: I still can't figure out how they work.
Scott: I know it's weird Like I thought you know, I calculated, you know before I came to the city and it's like, you know the calculations.
Scott: It was like, you know, I was trying to be all you know, I wasn't you know, a hundred percent like.
Scott: okay I was trying to be conservative and then you know, I'm conservative and I was like, oh man, there's plenty of money.
Scott: Oh, man, there's not enough money.
Scott: Uh, be realistic.
Scott: There's not enough money.
Scott: Oh, you're gonna have less extra, you know profits.
Rym: There's plenty of you.
Scott: profits are fine.
Scott: It's all good.
Scott: Money's not an issue.
Scott: It's it's fine.
Rym: Yeah, but I think what we should do is I we should not skip a little bit of the personal experience like this.
Rym: And I just want to get into kind of the things about this living in the city that are great or that are just different That I guess someone who hasn't lived in the city or just someone who's thinking like living in the city or a city Wouldn't realize or like things you just wouldn't think about.
Scott: it's pretty much only two things right.
Scott: number one Tourists need to all die.
Scott: Jesus Christ people Walk, don't just stop.
Scott: Whoa, Disney World right is a place where there are tourists But those tourists pretty much just stay in Disney World and there aren't any non tourists in Disney World except for Disney World employees.
Scott: Right, so it's not like you have this sort of clash of situations.
Scott: But in New York City, right?
Scott: I work near ish to Times Square.
Scott: You've got people who are living in apartments You got people who are going to fucking work and you have tourists and it's like listen You tourists get the fuck out of the way.
Scott: I live here get the fuck out of my house Right.
Rym: The thing is though, isn't it?
Scott: You got to admit it's a name you've got and you got people like preying on the tourists also getting in your way every Time we walk out of the office building.
Scott: It's like hey you guys want to see a comedy show and free beer?
Scott: It's like shut the fuck up.
Rym: I Know the deal.
Rym: It's shitty comedy and it's shitty beer.
Rym: I've been down that road.
Scott: Yeah, you're the comedian You already drank the beer.
Scott: Now I keep trying to like.
Scott: I have this plan that basically I'm gonna sneak up on him and be like Hey, you like comedy and beer, you know and give them their own shit but they always get me.
Scott: I saw a guy and I Made eye contact with him and I was ready to go and he got me from like 10 feet away.
Scott: I'm like, dude, he saw you come I was gonna get you when I was at 7 feet away.
Rym: He knew you're not the first New Yorker to think of that.
Scott: I'm gonna get him next time.
Rym: You should do When the hobo is about to ask you for money, you should ask him for money.
Scott: I hope I was never asked him.
Scott: I started to go.
Rym: It depends.
Rym: I've run into a couple.
Scott: of the only ones I don't like are the ones that are the the subway hobos.
Scott: So they get on and give you the speech.
Scott: It's like shut up.
Scott: We know it's all lies.
Scott: Shut up.
Rym: The thing is it's also all lies outside of the city.
Rym: I remember one day I came home from you know to beacon late at night.
Rym: I'm walking back from the train and This guy gives me the sob the sob story which reeked of bullshit of you know.
Rym: I just need money to like blah blah blah.
Scott: I need some change to get on the bus.
Rym: I need you know, but he gives me the story about like how his truck broke down.
Rym: He's got to get money to do something for gets towed whatever whatever whatever.
Rym: and I was like, yeah, right, whatever dude.
Rym: and he yelled at me and The next day I came home and the same dude tells me the same story.
Rym: and I was like Don't you recognize me from yesterday?
Rym: And he was like, oh And he kind of just like backed away.
Scott: You know you should do.
Scott: is anyone who comes and tells you any story, right?
Scott: You should just be like Yeah, you told me the same story yesterday, even if they didn't That would be a good idea.
Rym: I've realized that anyone who starts talking engages you on the street unless they want directions.
Rym: Yes, but it's fine.
Rym: So think of this anyone who engages you on the street and does not begin The first thing they say to you is not either a direct greeting or the beginning of a question.
Rym: They're scamming you because the people who are scamming you and asking for money never immediately ask for money.
Rym: They start telling you the story exactly, but someone who's actually lost or actually has a problem says hey, can you help me out?
Rym: But the scammers never do that.
Rym: The scammers always are like yeah, my son right over there fought in the war Civil War whatever war you can remember Yeah, the Civil War.
Scott: really Well, I can definitely get you a lot of money if that is true.
Rym: that's always the joke in my building cuz it's the Lincoln building and it's the building is always like pre-war pre-war pre-war and The joke is always yeah, what the Civil War is the building's piece of shit.
Rym: There's some problems in there anyway.
Scott: so the pretty much the only other thing there is to say about New York City is that once you live here you can't live anywhere else because pretty much Anything you want is here immediately.
Scott: this except fucking donuts this donuts here not good donuts when I wear Tell me where to get a good donut.
Scott: Let's go type into the Google.
Rym: It's gonna be like one place way downtown.
Rym: You have to go like 40 minutes out of my way to find it Donut plant New York City.
Scott: How about that?
Rym: Is that a shop or is that a factory?
Scott: I'm gonna find out real soon.
Rym: that is a shop or a factory.
Scott: So really it's a. it's a flash website.
Scott: So it's all Yeast donut strawberry trace leches peanut butter glaze blackberry jelly vanilla bean glaze blackberry.
Rym: These sound like fake Dunkin Donuts style donuts and not a real old-school fried donuts.
Scott: Whatever you and your just donut.
Rym: ism real donuts like what bakers make not Dunkin Donuts.
Rym: Those are not donuts.
Rym: They look like donuts.
Rym: They taste a little like donuts.
Scott: They're not donuts their bakery of the year for 2008.
Scott: So, how about that?
Rym: also, you know, what is not terribly common in New York City?
Rym: good submarine sandwiches.
Rym: there's good paninis and good other kinds of sandwiches and good like kosher deli sandwiches, but a traditional like Submarine sub kind of sandwich.
Rym: They're not that common.
Rym: They're not that easy to find.
Rym: No, they're.
Rym: you know, I feel like you get better subs in Philly and in the Midwest.
Scott: That's just a you know a Geographical situation.
Rym: Yeah I mean New York.
Rym: not everything in New York is perfect.
Scott: Also, I'm sure there's probably at least one place you can get them somewhere.
Rym: Also, one of the drawbacks of living in the city is that much of Manhattan does in fact smell like urine through most of The summer.
Rym: so there's really no way around that don't go.
Rym: However, right now it smells more like flowers than urine in most of the city.
Scott: Well, if you're near a park, I mean, uh, and there isn't a hobo in the park.
Rym: God last night that hobo on the train.
Scott: Yeah, if you see if you see a bunch of subway cars and one of them is empty and it looks like there's a hobo In there getting a different car that's crowded because the hobo price smells real bad smell doesn't get out.
Rym: So See I was gonna say something before I get sidetracked.
Rym: it is cool as much as the tourists piss me off and get in my Way, I don't mind them that much just because it's kind of a weird cool thing To have something that I just live in and just take for granted and use all the time like the stairway in Grand Central.
Rym: Just it's a stairway.
Rym: I use it and yet people will fly from all over the world to go into this place Stand on the thing that I just use and take a picture to prove that they were there.
Scott: Yeah, this is why you know, I need I need to be able to think tourist to death.
Scott: just with my mind It's like get off the fucking stairs.
Scott: It says no step stopping on the stairs walk.
Rym: I'm using these but one thing I will say.
Scott: well one I keep saying that like imagine if you're at work Right, and you're trying to type, you know do some work and someone comes Oh my god, that's Scott's computer and they make you stop working so they can take a picture with your computer.
Scott: It's like no you will die.
Rym: now New York does cause you to say the word fuck a lot more often.
Rym: Yeah, I just Something you've got to notice.
Rym: I mean I say it a lot a Surprising amount and everyone I know says it a lot.
Rym: It really isn't a bad word here.
Scott: Why is why?
Scott: where is a bad word?
Rym: in the red and other places?
Rym: if I'm like blah blah blah blah, fuck Blah the fucking blah.
Rym: some people go.
Rym: Whoo.
Scott: Well my word.
Scott: Well, those people are bad people You know, it's a bad word here.
Scott: Hello.
Scott: Hello is a bad word.
Rym: No, it's fine Hello is not that bad?
Scott: don't talk to me.
Rym: that word is sir, I would.
Rym: I would like to talk to you.
Scott: That's a lot more than one word Right.
Rym: a complaint people have about New York is that it makes you hard.
Rym: People always say yeah, it makes you hard and I can see someone having the impression that we are you hard that we are harder.
Rym: I mean look it has.
Rym: this conversation is fuck those tourists get those hobos out of my way.
Rym: This sucks urine Fuck okay.
Scott: But
Rym: I think the misconception a lot of people have about New York is that they they see what is in fact Straight up honesty and somehow misconstrue it as anger frustration unpoliteness or meanness when really I think people in New York City are just desperately incredibly Straightforwardly honest about everything with each other except for the people trying to scam money off of tourists.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know a lot of people talk about things like oh, you know, this southern hospitality or oh You know people are so, you know nice and friendly in country X, right?
Scott: And what it is is those people they have, you know, they put on a show not everywhere in Costa Rica.
Rym: I get the impression that everyone I met legitimately was that friendly and happy.
Scott: Yeah, it's pot, you know, they're those places too.
Scott: But the thing is that you know acting friendly, you know, and you know Is is Completely different from actually I would rather have people just be honest then act friendly.
Scott: whether the friendliness was true or false You know because it's like listen, I don't even know you.
Scott: so why am I gonna waste all these extra words?
Scott: Saying all things like, you know, hello and good evening, and please and thank you right wasting a whole bunch of time You got shit to do.
Rym: there's no defending grammar with you.
Rym: I think.
Rym: at one point.
Rym: I remember you arguing with me trying to say that using politeness in any context was basically manipulation and mind an attempted mind control.
Rym: But but at the same time notice how Rapidly New Yorkers want to show themselves the fuck off.
Rym: if a tourist is standing there looking at a map Like 20 people be like hey you want some help.
Rym: Where are you trying to go?
Rym: What are you trying to get to?
Rym: looking for the end train?
Rym: It's down there.
Rym: So Yeah, slight microphone cable issue, so we're just picking right up here rather than me trying to cleverly edit this whole thing out Again, yeah, I'm lazy.
Rym: What of it?
Rym: What's it to you?
Scott: lazy ass New York person I Think the.
Scott: the main thing that has changed in my life though Is that you know in addition to the additional free time right of not having to commute in such-and-such is that?
Scott: Pretty much everything I could possibly imagine I guess with the exception of donuts and subs according to RAM right is available to me.
Rym: anything I want, you know and One other is not available to me.
Scott: I don't have to what.
Scott: stop listing things that aren't available to you.
Scott: Everything is available here, right?
Scott: You just haven't.
Scott: Every time you think of something that's not in New York City.
Scott: We always find it.
Scott: so you didn't just shut up with any of that.
Rym: Let's find some good donuts and actually confirm that they're good donuts, right?
Scott: Is that I don't have to worry about like taking the train home or spending money in a hotel or anything like that?
Scott: So I can do whatever I want in the city 24/7 and all these things are there.
Scott: So just the.
Scott: the number of options I have of things I can do in my life are expanded like like Exponentially many many times over.
Rym: I mean if I want to play board games, there's just people playing board games I just go play with them.
Rym: It just it's like.
Scott: no matter what you're into no matter what you want to do You can do it if you're in.
Scott: you know bumblefuck, right?
Scott: Even if you're smarter than me and have more money than me and better than me in every possible way and you're cooler and everything You just can't do as many things You know that you could be doing if you lived in New York City.
Scott: if you wanted to learn, you know Say, I don't know.
Rym: a good example from from last night.
Rym: We went to an event at a place where they do like the center Center for book arts, right and they have typesetting classes.
Scott: you want to learn typesetting out in bumblefuck?
Scott: Well, it better be a specific bumblefuck.
Scott: that happens to have like, you know a place with a bunch of printing presses.
Scott: Otherwise, you ain't gonna learn shit out there, right?
Scott: But if you want to learn bookbinding or freaking potteries or fucking potter is pretty widespread computers or You know anything that you can imagine any activity any?
Scott: Education any book any Item, you know, it's not just learning to either.
Scott: It's like oh, you know this new movie came out You know in some foreign country, it's in a theater in New York somewhere, you know.
Scott: Oh this you know, this movie is coming out, but it's also gonna be an ultra IMAX 3d.
Scott: Oh, yeah, ultra IMAX 3d.
Scott: We got like five of those, you know.
Rym: So Scott saw right there aside small observations, New York Despite the fact that it's one of the denser, you know, like happening 24/7 places in the world It's still not as dense or 24/7 as you might be led to believe.
Rym: I mean late at night like after about 2 a.m Midtown and a lot of the city is just ghost town.
Rym: There's no one around everything's closed.
Scott: Yeah It really depends on where you are.
Rym: very small number of neighborhoods keep going all night long Like the st.
Rym: Mark area is pretty much rocking until the Sun comes up.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's it's.
Scott: it depends if there's a lot of bars somewhere right?
Scott: those places usually have later night activity, right?
Scott: But places that are say all office buildings like Midtown you or touristy things tourists don't really hang out that late.
Scott: They'll hang out, you know it's a midnight ish maybe.
Scott: or it's all like the Broadway shows.
Scott: get out and then they'll eat a late dinner or something and then they're gone and Office buildings people are gone after like six seven eight.
Scott: So any of those areas are gonna be empty at night and there's not gonna be much going on.
Rym: And - it's not as like.
Rym: it's as dense as it is.
Rym: it still feels Less dense than I kind of want it to be.
Rym: it's weird like I have this idealized just Density of ideas and people and everything all together.
Rym: and yet even New York feels very wide and open.
Rym: I'm gonna take the subway past large parks and big swatches of trees.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: you know a like an uber dense city like, you know some places in India or Japan or any of those right or China where people are stacked like cordwood, you know, you have some room in New York City.
Rym: Well, that's the biggest thing.
Rym: the main reason I didn't want to move into the city originally was that I did not believe I had enough money to live in a Large enough place to suit my needs.
Rym: I mean me personally.
Rym: I wanted to have a recording studio like I needed a separate place for that and I wanted to be able to entertain large numbers of guests on a regular basis the kinds of things I wanted a house for and At First I my idea of how much space I needed was about double what I actually ended up getting now.
Rym: Because the thing about New York is that you have all these kind of shared spaces that you can just use when you need them and it kind of Adds these extra rooms to your apartment that just aren't directly connected to it, but are still yours to use.
Scott: Yeah, that is.
Scott: one thing though Is that everyone is always looking for in New York is like let's say you've got I don't know a club.
Scott: You just want to start a club and you need to have meeting somewhere, right?
Scott: Where are you gonna have this meeting?
Scott: a coffee shop?
Scott: Okay, so the coffee shop is already crowded with patrons.
Scott: You're gonna scrounge up some tiny ass tables and get together.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Good luck with that.
Scott: Right, you get a bar and you can get the bar to like.
Scott: lend you a table, you know.
Scott: But what if you start getting a big club?
Scott: What if?
Scott: what if I'm awesome and I get like a 200 person anime club going in the city?
Scott: Where the fuck am I gonna have this thing?
Rym: Well, there is.
Scott: you can't because there is no place to have it unless you have money.
Rym: if mad money Depends on what you're looking for.
Rym: It's not actually that expensive.
Rym: The problem is that a lot of the people who join groups like that No one is willing to put forth the accounting and the effort to sort it all out and maintain Everything to continue to get a space right.
Scott: and even if you do get the money like what space are you gonna get?
Rym: actually, the the best place to look is most nicer.
Rym: restaurants have a room you can rent out and Off hours you like.
Rym: on certain time like earlier in the day on weekends You can get those places pretty mad cheap Usually just for the cost of the food and a nominal fee on top of it.
Scott: It depends and often those rooms are not suited to particular activities.
Rym: The other thing is if you go you want like if you go just out of Manhattan There's actually plenty of spaces.
Rym: people just don't look that hard.
Scott: Yeah, but you got to go out, you know It's not.
Scott: you know a lot of it.
Scott: So you're gonna get a lot less people if you try to do something like, you know out a little bit in Long Island Or out in Jersey and if you do it in Manhattan Straight
Rym: I think a lot of the people who are looking for spaces to do these regular things Don't look as hard as they could and don't consider a lot of surprisingly reasonable options.
Scott: Well, I mean you have to you sort of have to know someone or you have to find someone who's got a space that's usually used for something else but isn't being used at that moment and you repurpose it like
Rym: like how the mocha is in the Parade room at the batter not the battery the armory.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: okay.
Scott: This is an armory.
Scott: It's in use but you know what?
Scott: We will repurpose this armory room that no one is using at this moment to have our comic festival You know, but it just back to my point.
Rym: It was that my apartment is big enough to do everything I want to do.
Rym: But part of that is that outside of my apartment, you know The building has an exercise room and a lounge and a roof and a pool room and I can use all these rooms Like billiards room not assuming pool room.
Rym: Yes Not a pool.
Scott: other other apartment buildings do have a pool.
Rym: the run the one next door has a pool But it's you know what?
Scott: The thing is a lot of those are actually tiny pools.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, but I mean that's the thing is out in.
Scott: you know If you get in the suburbs, right you have your own Exercise room you have your own basement.
Scott: You have your own swimming pool here.
Scott: You pay to join the New York Sports Club and you can just anywhere in the city.
Scott: You have that you that you can find one of these clubs which is a lot of them.
Scott: you have a locker and a shower and a swimming pool and A whole bunch of exercise machines just all over the city.
Scott: You have a whole bunch, you know for this fee that you just pay recurringly and that's it.
Scott: And that's how things work here is mostly just that.
Scott: I like the idea that it's more efficient because I remember I don't I don't Have a coffee machine, you know, cuz my kitchen is tiny.
Scott: I have Starbucks is everywhere so matter where I am.
Rym: I can just get coffee instantly, but the lifestyle of the suburbs I mean because I grew up in that environment of every family has a house that provides Almost everything you'd want all the time.
Rym: I mean in your house.
Rym: You have the exercise room You have the pool outside you have you know if maybe the hot tub or all the billiards room or all these things and As a result you tend to stay in your house all the time or you'll always invite people over to your house.
Rym: New York There's much more of the.
Rym: everyone gets together somewhere.
Rym: That isn't a place for any one of them lives.
Scott: You don't want to go to someone's house because they live in a tiny apartment somewhere and like if it's just you visiting or just A couple people it's all good, but you don't spend a lot of time there.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: We're all sitting on this couch and this tiny apartment and outside There is everything you can possibly imagine to do.
Scott: and inside is what do you have here?
Scott: a fridge with a bear and just enough Food for one person to eat some computers some books and TV.
Scott: Yeah, let's get out of here.
Rym: of course one observation along those lines is that Money in New York just makes everything better and everything easier because it is a city where if you have money You can waive it and get just about anything you want.
Scott: Yeah, but at the same time people who don't you know people have significantly less monies than us.
Scott: They just get they get by they no problem.
Rym: I mean the often surprised how they get by but they do because one the ultra-rich lawyer rides the same subway that the smelly hobo Does.
Rym: that's true like the.
Rym: the democratization of the municipal and shared services like the parks and everything like that is Really cool like everyone uses the same infrastructure to get around and everyone kind of is in this together.
Rym: We're in this together Mm-hmm, but at the same time I'll admit my experience is skewed by the fact that I actually do have a very large apartment and Relatively speaking.
Rym: I mean, you know for New York It actually sleeps more people easily than the house and beacon did just because the configuration.
Rym: Yeah It's actually I think a better space than the house and beacon was for entertaining people Because the I remember that was in beacon like that hallway upstairs Which is wasted space and my big-ass bedroom just wasted space.
Rym: You could really use that having people over everyone crammed into that not that big living room.
Rym: The floor kind of bow down.
Rym: Yep That was not optimal.
Rym: Nope, but the other observation I have I forget so we'll just move on.
Rym: Okay No, I remember.
Rym: so the last night we ate dinner at like the Shake Shack in the park just like late at night after the thing and it was cool, but I Have such a different perspective living in the city now of places like Central Park or you know Brian Park just the parks and the hangout places and the Starbucks's and all these things.
Rym: before were kind of went to them to do an activity specifically like I'd come into the city do a thing there and then leave and there were always these kind of end points for doing things specifically.
Rym: and Now that I live here and I don't have to go anywhere after I'm done doing things suddenly these parks take out a very different character like going to Central Park and just kind of milling around is a very different experience from Coming into the city and going to Central Park as an activity.
Rym: Hmm cuz you know if you come in and go like like a tourist like I want to go look at Central Park or I'm Gonna go walk around Central Park.
Rym: It kind of puts this impetus on.
Rym: your kind of rushes you a little bit.
Rym: you have this this almost duty to Walk around and see it all but you can't experience it from the.
Rym: I'm just gonna go lay in the park for a while because I Got nothing else to do whatever.
Rym: Yeah, so the whole and a lot of the things in the city just have this very different perspective when you don't have to leave It.
Scott: yeah, I mean, you know if you live You know in a particular thing right if you see something every day Right as opposed to it being like a one-day activity I have one day to see this thing or to experience this thing.
Scott: In that one day, you're gonna try to experience the whole thing deliberately.
Scott: But if you can just experience something whenever you want any part of it at any time, right then It's it's like there was you in a concert and having an mp3, right?
Scott: If you go to a concert you got a. you got experience all the live music while it's there.
Scott: But if you got an mp3, it's like well I can listen to this anytime.
Scott: So it's completely different even if it's like the same exact audios and even if you have a concert sound system it's you know, not the exact same.
Scott: so but yeah, the other thing about New York City is that Transportation, right?
Scott: We already talked about I guess in-city transportation kind of right.
Scott: you get rid of your car to save money It's awesome.
Rym: You can get everywhere.
Scott: There's no reason to have a car because it's just a hassle.
Scott: dude Rollerblade to work every bicycle to work, but I subway up.
Scott: the weather's bad, but you know, it's.
Scott: uh You know, you can just get anywhere in the city.
Scott: You don't want a car cuz the car only gives you trouble just to keep moving it around and you're not.
Scott: well I guess you have so much money that you can get park it somewhere Unless you have money for like a hundred bucks a month.
Rym: I could just park a car in my building and then doorman go and get it for me when I want it.
Scott: Yeah, if you have that much money, you're all set.
Scott: But if you don't have that much money, just get rid of your car It's only a hassle.
Scott: and then you can take a taxi you can take a subway You can basically you can take a bus you can get anywhere in the city that you want really easily.
Scott: You can even get to places like Jersey on the path or Long Island and long on railroad or you can take the Metro North railroad to New York State or Connecticut or All long distance travel is a whole different game.
Rym: now living in the city And I remember before you know with the car centric cars are still for most of the kind of travel we do Faster and cheaper and easier But only if you live outside of the city you need the car anyway.
Rym: So it's the kind of like.
Rym: it's not like it's an extra cost to maintain the car.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you already own a car and you need it So you're already paying for insurance and all that stuff already.
Scott: So that's already is sunk cost and you need to go to Boston right.
Scott: then Driving to Boston is the best idea because you can bring a bunch of stuff with you.
Scott: It's real easy.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna have to pay for parking which sucks but that's still less than the cost of.
Scott: you know some as an airplane and such and you know it makes up for it cuz you can bring stuff with you.
Scott: and Yeah, you have to pay for gas But even that is still less, you know, and there's no hassle of like waiting for a flight to take off or anything like that.
Scott: But if you don't own a car, you know, and you know, then suddenly it's like well to drive There is really stupid and expensive because I had to pay to rent a car or buy a car and such and such and such.
Scott: You're much better off paying 20 bucks to get on like the Chinatown bus Even though it might break down and does so often.
Rym: but that's what's awesome.
Rym: I didn't I guess way back.
Rym: I didn't account for the fact that while the delays of taking like a bus or a plane are annoying compared to a car From anywhere else like from Beacon from the city flying is crazy convenient.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the airport is just right there.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: you know, I can get to the airport as quickly as I can get to work.
Scott: So it's not like a big deal to go fly somewhere.
Scott: it's just like oh I walk out the door I get on a plane whoosh, you know.
Scott: and in the planes, it's not like, you know, I'm in Rochester We're okay.
Scott: if I want to fly to somewhere I have to fly first to New York and then somewhere It's.
Scott: I can just go anywhere in the world on a direct flight pretty much for a pretty reasonable price.
Scott: So there is a complete access to the entire world from where we are.
Rym: That's just with the planes but the bulk buses and the things like that are fucking awesome.
Scott: I gotta say And it's not internet it's not just physical travel access to the entire world It's not just internet access to the entire world, which everyone I would hope has right?
Scott: It's access to things from around the world.
Scott: if our French things Indian things Chinese things I can get things from anywhere in the world.
Scott: just in stores in New York City people from anywhere They're opening a second Uniqlo.
Scott: Yeah, it's like oh, I'd really like to talk to.
Scott: you know, oh shit I'm gonna go to.
Scott: I don't know Slovakia.
Scott: I should really talk to a Slovakian dude.
Scott: Hey, I found a Slovakian dude who lives in New York.
Scott: What's up, dude?
Scott: Oh here.
Scott: Look, it's a Slovakian restaurant.
Scott: I can try out some Slovakian food.
Scott: There's some books about Slovakian library.
Scott: Well, I hope everyone has that also, but you know, you have access to friggin everything.
Scott: It's there somewhere You can find it, you know, oh man.
Scott: I really wish I had this comic book.
Scott: Yeah, I had to drive like, you know an hour to get to the nearest comic book store.
Scott: Yeah, I've got like 20 comic stores like a walk to but that's one of the.
Scott: that's a niche thing.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of them.
Rym: That's really the biggest change in my life of living in the city.
Rym: Is that Before when I lived out of the city, I had this kind of weekend centric life.
Rym: I would do things on weekends and on weekdays after work We do the show and I'd kind of stay home and do very, you know home kind of things.
Rym: I'd watch anime I'd read but I wouldn't do things.
Rym: because doing things outside of the city meant Traveling somewhere at least somewhere somewhat far away maybe even like to Poughkeepsie or something.
Scott: Or it meant staying in the city after work and then Getting on a train and getting home extra late at like 1 a.m.
Rym: But even events just doing something that doesn't involve the city at all out out of the city Requires a lot more kind of doing to do.
Rym: you got to get your car drive somewhere park go to an event Find dinner later elsewhere pick a rest or all that stuff.
Rym: Now my life is much more just constant like it used to be weekday weekday weekday weekday weekend.
Rym: now It's just day day day day and every day I do stuff and every day is different.
Rym: It's a lot more like college Except I still have that nine-to-five work in the way, but well, you know, you got to pay for it somehow, right?
Rym: Yeah So whatever I just I I love living here.
Rym: I. the only two places I ever want to live in my life again are either in the center of this city as close to the middle of it as I can possibly get or In like a Costa Rican paradise with a poly car.
Scott: Yeah poly chronic lifestyle Yeah, but the thing is even if I live there, you know the poly chronic lifestyle of relaxing in the Sun would be totally awesome.
Scott: But every time I wanted to do something well, I'd be like fuck.
Scott: I don't have anything here.
Scott: I have fucking trees.
Scott: Well, I supposed to do the way around.
Rym: that is to be rich enough to have the apartment penthouse apartment in the city and the Costa Rican paradise house and just go back and forth between them whenever you want.
Scott: Yeah, but I spent all the time going back and forth.
Scott: They need a teleporter Or I need a city in a tropical paradise and then I have the penthouse like decks I know I with some palm trees growing on the roof.
Scott: Now that's where it's at.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and a comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.