Rym: Hey, it's Monday January 11th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight our CES commentary roundup.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So Rym I see you Haven't put your pants on since what yesterday.
Rym: Yeah, they're pretty much off.
Rym: I had to put them on for work.
Scott: Did you like not do any laundry?
Scott: Oh you did put pants on for work.
Rym: I figured for work.
Rym: I should put pants on because No one at my office would have had any idea about this except for the fact that one guy was like Yeah, there are all these people on the subway yesterday, and they just didn't have any pants on.
Rym: And I was like I was one of those people.
Rym: What was going on?
Rym: and I was like well, I just forgot my pants.
Rym: I don't know what was up with all those assholes.
Scott: Yeah, actually on the stop right before Union Square yesterday.
Scott: You know I also happen to forget my pants just randomly, but like The the co-worker that I work with the most just happened to get on the same exact subway car that I was on.
Rym: So my thing of the day from our triumphant return was of course the improv everywhere International no pants day on Sunday, which as we said we participated in myself Scott Emily Judith and Natalie.
Scott: I think though it's gonna be a problem because like too many people know what's up.
Scott: You know this.
Scott: it's hard to freak squares when like they saw it on the news this morning or something You know and people just come up and ask you like so you guys You stand on this train into Union Square.
Scott: You're gonna transfer.
Scott: It's like you know.
Scott: There's no more.
Scott: I forgot my pants.
Rym: the trouble with that is that you still get people because remember for all the people that are hip in the City there are twice as many people who don't say anything, and there's looking at you like what the
Scott: fuck It's true, but but it's
Rym: generally a hip and techie city So it's difficult to get away with any sort of large public flash mob.
Rym: That's why the true great flash mobs of improv everywhere are the private ones like let's go to Best Buy.
Scott: Yeah, it's a good one.
Rym: That's still my favorite one.
Scott: Well, just keep an eye on their website because I'm sure they do lots of New York action that we can be involved in.
Rym: Yeah, but no pants was very near and dear to me.
Rym: I mean we have our own custom no pants card and nanofictionary Mmm.
Rym: I should have brought that.
Scott: oh yeah, right the no pants guy.
Rym: I didn't even think to.
Rym: we should have played some nanofictionary, but it's funny.
Rym: How you know.
Rym: they separate us into groups and It's always great.
Rym: It's very rare for Scott and I to be members of the following crowd as opposed to the people organizing it like a con or An event like this mm-hmm, and it was cool to be in the audience of a group of people organized by someone Who is very competent at crowd control?
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: I mean he got everyone together.
Rym: He did all the right things.
Scott: It was so cool out.
Scott: It's like all they had to organize this thing.
Scott: it was basically one website and like ten generals with with Megaphones that was all they did to organize.
Scott: like Thousands of people
Rym: he walked around and he saw people who obviously had done this before and knew what was up And he made them like team captains gave them all a number and in a stroke of brilliance that I never thought of and I Plan to use this at every freaking anytime.
Rym: I need to divide a crowd up, and it's large.
Rym: He asked everyone to go to the number of the group that matches the last digit of their cell phone number.
Rym: Yep, it was brilliant, so we all split up and in my group only works if you're dividing people up into ten groups Yeah, or you know if your number is even or odd.
Rym: there's all sorts of ways.
Scott: yeah I'm just saying it's you know.
Rym: But I go to my group and the team lead there is like.
Rym: so I need a volunteer to Basically go first and be the odd man out.
Scott: I'm like yo Yep, and then I go actually originally scheduled to go second.
Scott: But the guy who was gonna go first was he wanted to stay with his girlfriend or whatever.
Scott: so that I was.
Scott: I was promoted To going first.
Rym: I basically got on the train and looked around and there were.
Rym: there were a bunch of normies on my car When our group got on yeah surprisingly crowded for a weekend train.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: I sit down I look around and I just say oh shit.
Rym: And then I just take my pants off and put him in my bag and sit back down.
Rym: like there we go And people just kind of look at me.
Rym: I had a line so set but no one asked me when I was taking my pants off Why I was taking my pants off because I had this surreal stroke of genius.
Rym: I wanted to say if anyone asked me.
Rym: Oh, well.
Rym: I just forgot I was wearing him Like Stephen Wright must have come to me from the grave.
Scott: So I just got on the train and it was so quick into the next stop that I had to hurry up to take Them off quickly enough.
Scott: you know I get was mostly getting the shoes off Getting the pants off getting the shoes back on getting the pants in the bag.
Scott: It was it was difficult operation.
Rym: It was great standing at that next stop because that we were the ones who got to stand.
Scott: Yeah, so me and ram are standing like 20 feet away from each other on this subway platform.
Rym: That's real nonchalant like he's standing there like just a commuter guy.
Rym: I'm standing there playing my DS kind of spread eagle.
Scott: It was cold.
Rym: It was fucking cold.
Rym: Good guy really cold, but it was great.
Rym: I one by one like normal people would walk up and their little conversation would be going along and they kind of just Like stop talking for a minute and look around Giggle or something and then just try to avoid all of us.
Rym: But they couldn't because there was one of us like every 20 feet Mmm.
Scott: Yeah, the thing was is like at the next stop.
Scott: No one got on my car even though it was the same exact car that I got off of.
Scott: so I was like uh-oh Did we mess up this or something?
Scott: and then?
Scott: You know eventually people did get out of my car.
Scott: I was not like left alone.
Rym: my car had a few extra pencils people yeah.
Scott: And then was awesome is like Times Square because we only had people going down to Queensborough Boulevard And that was our entire group.
Scott: right, but we got to Times Square.
Scott: It's like perfectly timed.
Scott: all these other people who I assume must have been on like the seven train Transferred onto our train from the seven.
Scott: so it was like ah look at all these people just joined us.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: But one of my favorite moments was I got to the place you know Union Square And I went over to the Starbucks And there was like one guy in there other than me with no pants on and no one really noticed him except for a few People are kind of staring at him like that guy's no pants.
Rym: What's he fine?
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: Yeah, that guy doesn't have pants either.
Rym: That's weird, and I go up.
Rym: I'm in line everyone's kind of looking at me, and I'm like I Need some coffee.
Rym: It's real cold out there, and the brisk is like yeah, you look like you could use some coffee And I'm like oh iced.
Scott: You paid for iced coffee.
Scott: They didn't drink just for that joke.
Rym: I drank half of it.
Scott: You should have just said I'm just kidding.
Scott: I don't want it.
Scott: I did want it.
Rym: It's just.
Scott: I just wanted the joke.
Rym: it was just so cold.
Rym: when I got outside I was like all right.
Rym: I cannot continue to drink this or I may die.
Scott: Why didn't you just get an actual warm coffee?
Scott: I just make the ice joke.
Scott: don't actually buy it.
Scott: I really like cold coffee But it was cold out.
Rym: she got a revenge though.
Rym: She put my muffin and upside down.
Scott: I was very all the cupcake.
Scott: Yeah, you know I want to on our subway at one point.
Scott: There was a crazy old lady who was like oh taking pictures.
Scott: Who's crazy old lady?
Scott: She was acting crazy And then she got off.
Rym: one guy in my car towards the end was like well shit if everyone else is taking their pants off He's took his pants off.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It was just some guy.
Scott: Are you sure or was he actually in on it?
Rym: He didn't.
Rym: he was not in on it as far as I could tell.
Rym: uh-huh You know I think everyone had the encounter where someone was like so uh what's the deal yeah?
Rym: And I just looked at him like must be like what deal I was like what he's like.
Rym: You're not wearing pants.
Rym: clear something wrong, and I this is still in the Starbucks.
Rym: I just got my coffee.
Rym: I looked down.
Rym: I was like oh shit, and then I just walked out like in a hurry No pants was crazy awesome and everyone who missed it sucks.
Scott: Yeah, I just I worry about the future.
Rym: if too many people You know no pants will no longer be a freak the squares.
Rym: It'll just be like a national holiday.
Scott: Yeah, I think we need to mix it up a little bit.
Scott: It needs to be no shirt Just underwear only.
Rym: I'd rather wait until at least March.
Scott: We should also move it to a non cold time of year.
Scott: You know it's the point.
Scott: No, you know it's not fair right to Sydney right?
Scott: Sydney Did it at the same day which means it was really nice and warm there?
Scott: They should have to move there six months over.
Rym: Yeah They should.
Scott: or maybe what we could do is in compromise make it twice a year six months I think so everyone gets both sticks.
Rym: It's not so bad You know what the people in like.
Scott: you know Florida.
Scott: They never have a problem.
Scott: They're like yeah, it's Jamaica No pants day.
Scott: what they have pants in Jamaica.
Rym: It's not so fans.
Scott: ever.
Rym: if I was in Jamaica bad except for the fact that we were on the end.
Rym: So we had to stand on the platform.
Rym: That's above ground.
Scott: Started with like the Williamsburg people we could have taken the L And it would have basically been like yeah, we're underground the whole time.
Scott: big deal.
Rym: I gotta say though it was funny that the crowd of people who showed up to do this Was very reminiscent of the crowd that showed up at PAX West.
Scott: all people our age who are cool and hip.
Rym: I mean We are no old people no kids our group.
Rym: We were all arguing about homeopathy and all that stuff and then these two cute cool girls come over.
Rym: They're like hey, yeah, yeah, we heard conversation, and that's something that's kind of up our alley My name is blah, and we hung out and then this guy and this girl with two ferrets came over.
Scott: Yeah ferrets did the ferrets take the pants off?
Rym: uh?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I've never seen a ferret wear pants But maybe the fur counts in which case I don't want to see them.
Rym: take that off mmm Cuz.
Rym: there's kind of scraggly and wrinkly.
Scott: go look on you.
Scott: go on the internet We got to search for like hairless ferret always got to search for ferret and pants or hairless mongoose or something.
Rym: At least we didn't miss the fancy pants parade.
Rym: That song was stuck in my head for most of the event as was that Seinfeld episode with naked guy on the subway anyway.
Scott: so This show that we're gonna do today is mostly about CES the consumer electronic show.
Scott: But I want to talk about.
Scott: is that Leo Laporte you know from the twit network?
Scott: They did a big thing at CES.
Scott: you know.
Scott: he would always talk about how you shouldn't go because you can just read it All in a gadget, and there's no reason to go.
Scott: yep, but he got sponsors that sent him there, so he went.
Scott: and You know I was one day I was watching him live just to you know.
Scott: see what he was doing at the CES and apparently he had the biggest number of Like live viewers he ever had ever during that time that I was watching.
Scott: so something about it was.
Scott: I think it was cuz it was Friday he was at.
Scott: it was CES.
Scott: There's a big event.
Scott: He was live there I you know and I was watching him operate and I realized The only difference between us and him at this point right is a. he has a professional radio voice because he's a professional radio guy Right - he has sponsors and money to buy better equipment.
Scott: now He doesn't buy super professional equipment like TV networks, but he has more equipment than we do.
Rym: you know He's basically one step up from us.
Scott: if I can buy multiple HD cameras.
Scott: He can buy better microphones He can buy a caster.
Scott: He could buy any number of computers He needs.
Scott: right.
Scott: he can buy wireless cards to get on evdo networks or whatever.
Scott: you know.
Scott: he could buy one cell phone from every Network.
Scott: he's right yeah, and He has enough money to hire people to help him.
Scott: other than that like watching him operate I was like oh my god It's just like when I had to run the panel all day at Connecticut.
Scott: only he's running a podcast all day at CES.
Scott: Oh God, I just I felt like I was at Connecticut again like he was talking about how the Convention Center is so dry.
Scott: Hey, my throat is dried out, and you know I was like ah It was like I was.
Scott: I was taken back right into Connecticut.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: So just knowing that he was doing going through that and he was doing basically the same thing I was like yeah, I can do everything he can do except have professional radio voice and have more monies.
Scott: so If anyone wants to give us more monies and maybe give us some radio voice training We can put on a Leo Laporte show for you, please sponsor us.
Scott: We can put on a show just as good as he can.
Scott: we've done it before.
Scott: we can do it again.
Scott: Call me.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: at the same time Think back to all those cons.
Rym: It's real fun, and we like doing this, but it sucks.
Scott: But if you get paid big money yeah, imagine if someone are you understand like what his sponsor is paid for.
Scott: they bought him a a Broadcasting platform right because there's all these broadcast platforms you can buy.
Scott: you know like when you're at New York comic-con There's like up on the site right.
Scott: so they paid for him to get a broadcast platform.
Scott: They had a t1 sent to the broadcast platform right.
Scott: so already that's so worth what right they paid for it.
Scott: I have like these banners hung up.
Scott: that was like to it at CES.
Scott: They paid for you know advertising and all the programs it paid.
Scott: Oh, they paid for it.
Scott: They gave him a car to drive their plane tickets in first class.
Scott: Well what I was thinking is to get the equipment there.
Rym: We wreck ourselves at conventions anyway.
Scott: So if someone paid me to wreck myself at a convention That's great, and they paid for the staff and the food and the went to parties and yeah, and hey We're going to PAX.
Scott: if anyone would like to sponsor GeekNights at PAX East slash West give us a broadcasting platform inside the email.
Rym: Remind all of you will be doing a ton of panels at PAX East and if you have not pre-registered for PAX East yet Do it today.
Rym: They're going to sell out I guarantee you.
Rym: and for the talk about this tomorrow Yeah But I you know tech people is that you should go to PAX East to.
Rym: the hotels are almost all sold out.
Rym: get your hotel Right now or you're not gonna go to PAX East.
Scott: yes There is a good chance that more than ten percent of the PAX East panels will be by us or associates.
Rym: Oh, yeah, well the good chance is pretty much a hundred percent But it might be as high as sixteen percent depending on what we find what the final contract is yeah It also depends on a lot of other factors that may or may not change.
Scott: so yep We'll see.
Rym: oh my god, but I do want to talk a little bit.
Rym: There is a story about CES vendors being kicked out of their hotel rooms around Vegas during CES and supposedly what they were doing in the hotel rooms was Demoing products and and basically doing what they would have done on the floor of CES.
Scott: They've always done this in their hotel room.
Scott: this
Rym: all happens a lot I know, but the point is a whole bunch of hotels according to this report Kicked them out of their hotel rooms even the large like business suites and everything For on the grounds that they were using the rooms for this and no one can really figure out What the deal was.
Rym: and people are speculating that maybe CES was going after the people who were doing this But not actually paying for space at CES.
Scott: Well first of all I think the space at CES was sold out.
Scott: I can't confirm that but um you know when you look at it They have multiple halls, and they're all full right.
Scott: Secondly it is a common occurrence.
Scott: This has been going on for a very long time.
Rym: This is a normal tech conference thing like yes, even like tech conferences I've been to there's like hotel room suite parties and hotel room demonstrations.
Scott: Also, it's completely normal and not out of the ordinary whatsoever for what usually happens is if you have a really niche Sort of area of consumer electronics or whatever what happens is like oh yes consumer electronics shows in the convention center But actually some guy rented out the ballroom at the Sheraton and all like the audio file Companies are in there like this audio at CES, but all the audio file stuff is at the Sheraton.
Scott: There's nothing to do with CES It's just they cuz CES.
Scott: at the same time this niche Sets up in a hotel ballroom and pretty much every hotel ballroom is set up with some niche of CES.
Scott: You know something that really wouldn't justify Getting tables at the big show But people who are into that will know to go to the hotel ballroom.
Rym: people are reporting to that.
Rym: Apparently all the vendors who were doing this who had rented floor space at CES had no problem.
Rym: Oh Really yeah, I've seen multiple reports of that and this I mean I can't say I don't know, but it does reek of some sort of agreement between the hotels and CES.
Scott: I think that somebody could investigate get a lawyer and maybe you know find some Bad competition something something.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know that.
Rym: I know I was reading not a lawyer.
Rym: I was reading about all the weird laws about hotels and There are a lot of crazy weird laws about hotels and what they can and cannot do and when they're forced to give you a room And how they can't turn you away unless they think you're gonna.
Scott: Then that's something I should learn because it's like I know all the rules of like what they can do if you're renting and what?
Scott: They can do if you.
Scott: you know.
Scott: It's always good to learn about the rules of what someone can and can't do to you like what kind of cop do to you And if he stops you on the street knowing what a hotel can do to you.
Scott: I think it's a very important thing that I must learn.
Rym: Well, we haven't.
Scott: what are your rights as a hotel guest?
Rym: We only really need to know that if we decide to try to ever run big room parties I said the hotel on fire.
Rym: Uh, I don't know.
Rym: on one hand I'm kind of sick of room parties at conventions try to steal some towels But on the other hand It would be fun to put on a room party like in the old days at a convention like packs not like an anime con Cuz.
Rym: no one's old enough to drink at an anime.
Scott: I think our plan of getting a hotel ballroom for the night party and doing overnight gaming is all right.
Rym: Here's the one problem with that.
Scott: If anyone would like to sponsor overnight gaming in a hotel ballroom at PAX East or West or West GeekNights at front road crew All we need is enough money to rent out the ballroom and rent a bunch of tables.
Scott: We can take care of the rest.
Rym: All I have to say to that is John Dvorak dot org slash blog.
Scott: Yeah, if if Best Buy or some other company would like to you know Lend us a bunch of TVs and video game consoles for our overnight sponsor the GeekNights at packs.
Scott: Yes Geek that's appropriate.
Scott: I go.
Rym: No, so things of the day.
Rym: the illustrious Daryl Surratt sent this to me and he basically said that Someone who had some shitty reporter job.
Rym: This was his ultimate moment.
Rym: He'd been waiting his entire life to write the headline and I quote Skywalkers in Korea cross Han Solo.
Rym: Apparently there is a high-wire championship in Seoul right now where they got I think 18 people who are professional like walk on the high high tightrope whatever guys and They're going across this river on this one and one point two inch thick wire, it's the Han River.
Rym: Yes Yeah, and they do it solo.
Rym: It's our race.
Rym: Whoever does it the fastest wins.
Scott: Whoa What if you fall you fall in the river?
Rym: Oh, yeah, do you die?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I mean if you're in the middle of the river, maybe you'll be alright because it's kind of shallow depending on how high you are.
Scott: But I mean towards if you're near the edge.
Rym: Oh To quote the article the iron cable was supported by 72 foot high towers on either bank of the river.
Rym: a Safety net was deployed under the sections of the wire over the riverbanks.
Rym: Otherwise, the Walker's faced a plunge into the swirling gray water.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: Well, it depends.
Rym: how high was it?
Rym: 164 feet?
Rym: no, no, no higher than that.
Rym: But uh, I'm not getting read the whole article.
Rym: You can read the article.
Scott: However, I'm just questioning whether a fall into the water meant death or two people fell into the water and they did not die.
Scott: All right, that's good.
Rym: But it was a competition and I thought this is really cool
Scott: reminds me I watched this video of that guy was bungee jumping and his friends were like, oh right when he was about to jump They're like, oh no wait, and they threw a rope over the edge to make it look like his rope and messed up.
Rym: That's messed up.
Scott: They're like.
Scott: you thought you were gonna die.
Rym: Wow, it was a kilometer long cable.
Scott: Well, that's a big cable.
Scott: Yeah Of course this cables a lot longer than that.
Scott: They go across the whole ocean with internets.
Rym: There are much more important cables.
Scott: Yes much more.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I like the idea of Competitions like this just direct competition on something very specific and weird.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: What was the winning time?
Rym: I Don't know.
Rym: I didn't read the article and there's two pages of it.
Rym: I don't want to click on next.
Scott: I would have just ran because if I already have tightrope skills, you know It's all about the confidence and building up the the rhythm and the.
Scott: you know, I don't know.
Rym: It's a kilometer.
Rym: Can you even run a whole kilometer?
Scott: Oh shit Good god Cuz you're thinking of.
Rym: like when you're trying to walk out of railroad tracks you start to fall You run to get as far as you can before you fall.
Scott: exactly.
Rym: gotta run a whole kilometer.
Scott: Oh god.
Scott: Yeah Surprised anyone made it 18 contestants from nine countries.
Scott: No.
Scott: Well, so There's a programming language called APL and if you'd have asked me like a week ago, like what's APL I'd be like It's a programming language.
Scott: I don't know anything else about it other than there's a programming language called APL.
Scott: But apparently APL is really good at doing like, you know grids and two-dimensional array type operations, right?
Rym: Ah, like making 2d game.
Scott: Well, basically like making the game of life and This is a YouTube video.
Scott: a guy shows you how to make the game of life and basically one line of APL.
Scott: And it's like you watch this and you know Like I don't understand that the specifics, you know of how APL works and all these things.
Scott: But I you know, I can understand sort of I can follow him see what he's doing and it's pretty epic.
Scott: and it you know.
Scott: It makes you want to learn APL, but then you go wait, I'll never use that for anything useful But it's still pretty awesome.
Rym: That's the kind of thing if you're a punk kid and you're in some sort of tech school like CS or software engineering.
Rym: Do stuff like that.
Scott: Yeah, it's it.
Scott: this is an epic epic Programming video.
Rym: So I think we just jump right into all the CES news.
Rym: Obviously if you want to know all of the CES news or you want the details just go to like Engadget and read The text is there.
Rym: We're not gonna talk about how many pixels wide X was and how many jiggawatt?
Scott: We are going to comment on how useless half of this shit is ha ha ha ha or how useful a very small portion of it.
Rym: I gotta start by talking to how freaking awesome that micro vision laser projector gun was.
Scott: All right Tell me about the micro vision laser.
Scott: Basically good.
Rym: It's the.
Rym: it's this projector that uses lasers.
Rym: So it's super focused like no matter where you point it.
Rym: Every pixel is like a dot of laser light.
Rym: It's like 800 by 400 something pixels.
Rym: It's super bright.
Rym: It's awesome.
Rym: It's the kind of thing they're gonna stick on the phone soon.
Rym: It's really really tiny.
Rym: So to demo it they stuck it on a gun and they set it up such that the gun had motion sensors.
Rym: And as you moved the gun around the room, it showed you what you would see in the game.
Rym: It was basically like you had a gun and on the wall in front of you was always a screen showing you what was there In real time, but so but if you're looking up It's the gun.
Scott: if you aim the gun at the ceiling you see you can see the sky, right?
Scott: Yes, but if you're aiming at the sky with the gun, you can't really see in front of you.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, it was basically just an awesome demo of how crazy cool this projector is.
Scott: It was pretty cool, but be even cooler is if it projected everywhere and then to the gun just controlled the gun.
Rym: Well that that's the holodeck.
Rym: that's next.
Scott: see they already have that, you know, they've rooms you can do that in.
Rym: Yeah, they're not so great.
Rym: I think my my bag is still with the augmented reality Mm-hmm, but this was just a cool tech demo and you know We talked about this almost a year and a half ago when the first inklings of this technology was appearing.
Rym: but portable projectors Within the next year or two at anime conventions are going to be the most annoying thing in the world.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much everyone projects of anime onto a wall somewhere.
Scott: I mean they're worried now about like you sharing songs with your friends, right?
Scott: or you know?
Scott: I mean you read that FBI warning the beginning of a movie.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It says you may not show this you may not have a public showing only private home viewing only.
Scott: Dude, what happens when anyone can project any movie onto any wall?
Scott: People are gonna go download a cam of like avatar Projected onto a wall with their cell phone in 3d and hand out glasses to everybody and watch it on like the side of a building And all the homeless guys will walk over.
Scott: That is what they should be worried about and you know, what is nothing they can do.
Scott: So worrying is useless.
Scott: Don't worry about it.
Scott: Just deal with it.
Rym: however it's gonna be pretty badass because the one thing is the anime con culture has the Some guy's gonna bring like his computer and like laptop and screen and everything to play like his stupid game and show people music videos or something and People are gonna like gaming.
Rym: cons primarily aren't willing to deal with all that BS.
Scott: We don't have to everyone cell phone.
Scott: Basically, you'll turn yourself on sideways.
Scott: It'll be a game controller and a projector simultaneously and you just pull.
Scott: so your friend will pull out his cell phone Connect to you.
Scott: He won't even connect to you.
Scott: I guess they might have to connect with bluetooth or Wi-Fi or something.
Scott: And now you each have your own screen projected on the wall and you're playing a fighting game against each other or something.
Rym: That is gonna be awesome.
Scott: So you just walk up to you see bump into someone on the subway like hey, what's up?
Scott: Hey, let's play a game.
Scott: All right, you aim your phones at the wall and just play a game.
Rym: However, once they're ubiquitous enough to where they're everywhere, you know Like you can assume that most cell phones have them like how most cell phones have cameras today.
Rym: Go see it's gonna happen.
Scott: Oh, yeah go see on the wall.
Rym: It's gonna happen a lot But we have to wait until there's that peak where they're not Common enough to where everyone's used to them like laser pointers.
Rym: Remember when laser pointers first got popular and for like a year, they're just red dots everywhere.
Rym: As soon as they got cheap enough when they're ubiquitous and novel go see everywhere.
Rym: once they're ubiquitous and non-novel that problem will disappear.
Scott: Yeah, but people still use them for like a game on the wall or that sort of stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I don't want to talk about all the different projection things beyond that.
Rym: Portable projectors are going to be huge within the next year at the convention circuit.
Rym: Mm-hmm Okay, I guess I have to bring everything up.
Rym: captain forgot his laptop.
Scott: No, I got one.
Scott: So there was this, you know guitar called the you rock guitar.
Rym: Oh, that thing's pretty cool.
Scott: So what it is, it's a guitar But it doesn't.
Scott: you don't have to tune the strings and I don't think they break either because it's a MIDI controller It's right.
Scott: See you play it like a guitar.
Scott: you hold down strings and strum them and pluck them and whatnot, right?
Scott: However, it's a MIDI controller so You can use it to control any MIDI anything and it just has USB cable that comes into it and plugs right into the front Of your computer and you're good.
Scott: and it works pretty well with I guess the default Apple MIDI thing like.
Scott: that's what they tested it with, you know.
Scott: Secondly I'm pretty sure that you can play rock band slash guitar hero with it Somehow even though I didn't read how that works.
Scott: It works apparently, right?
Scott: So that's already two things.
Scott: It does three things.
Scott: it does Right, you can sort of like there's a there's a dial and you can dial up all these different instruments.
Scott: You can play like, you know, even sounds that normal guitars usually can't make but you can like put it in like You know metal mode and go dah dah dah dah and you can put an acoustic mode and all sorts of you know modes.
Rym: Does it have both squiggly and mealy?
Scott: It has like ten squealies and ten mealy's and apparently you can download more squealies and more mealy's right because it's like it's you know Internet's.
Scott: Then on top of that, it's got background music.
Scott: So like you could put down like, you know, the blues, you know Or whatever or like some jazz and it'll go it'll just start making like a background music like doo doo doo doo And then it's up to you to play in front of that, right?
Scott: So, you know you gets all sorts of backing tracks, you know, you could put like some, you know metal backing track.
Scott: It'll like play a drum like digga digga digga digga digga and then you go.
Rym: Now this is interesting in a lot of ways.
Rym: I mean think about what happened with auto-tune and how we like more and more.
Rym: celebrity singers aren't actually necessarily that good but you can make them sound good and eventually the technology is gonna get to the point to where you can have a fake guitar and if it like a microphone and Everything and you won't be able to tell that it's augmented and basically everyone will be able to sing Whatever is in their head
Scott: everyone be able to be a rock star and sound like exactly what you know They imagine.
Rym: almost I wonder what that's going to do for a lot of culture and media.
Rym: I mean, there's no way around it's gonna get to the point to where there will be people who everyone's a rock star Or no in the very least where anyone who has any idea in their head that is musical We'll be able to get it out.
Rym: If Lee at least if it's single person music or maybe single person and backing tracks We'll be able to kind of get it out there in a listenable form.
Rym: that is going to kill the majority of like generic Pop music.
Scott: Well, I mean think about it.
Scott: What if anyone in the world was good at programming?
Scott: Well, there'd be no job for a programmer, right?
Scott: What if you know?
Scott: What if everyone in the world could make music them?
Rym: You know job for musicians if everyone in the world was good at music if everyone in the world could play the every instrument?
Rym: Very well, not, you know perfectly not virtuoso, but very well effectively even if they had no training You will drive up the demand for and value of the virtuosos the crazily talented and skilled people.
Scott: Yeah, but you will destroy the market for anyone who is just really really exactly what I was gonna say Which you know what those virtuosos will be hired to do.
Scott: They'll be hired to make the music and all that stuff that goes into the instruments that everyone else is playing.
Scott: Right Dave.
Rym: This is probably Dave Riley's paradise.
Rym: He will just be singing non-stop for the rest of his life wandering around the city Maybe but he is.
Scott: let me I didn't finish telling you about the things this guitar does.
Scott: This guitar you can put it into you rock mode and what it does.
Scott: and you rock mode is Let's say you put on a backing track that's in the key of f-sharp, right and you rock mode it will disable all notes that are not in the key of f-sharp and If you try to play a note that's in the key of f-sharp It'll sort of make the guitar hero like you suck noise like growl, you know that that sort of oops noise.
Scott: So you put it in this mode and you just sort of a met you to learn which notes are available and which ones aren't And you will always be in key Right, and it's all digital.
Scott: so like your technique doesn't matter that much as long as you hit the right note and it just gotta Have rhythm.
Scott: I think yeah, I mean, yeah, it'll be all your rhythm timing and hit the right note.
Scott: It won't matter like, you know other things because it's a MIDI controller It's not you know.
Scott: This
Rym: is a good way to learn
Scott: as a whammy bar to for like which pitch shifts if you if you whammy it
Rym: you'll learn How to be a mediocre to average improvisationalist,
Scott: but I mean and this thing is, you know expandable though, you know People are gonna firmwares this thing and but they really it's.
Scott: it's good to see someone actually take this technology That is incredibly old and actually push it to its limit or close to its limit or further.
Rym: Not.
Rym: so they're not pushing it to its limit because you could do this a lot better in a studio you could.
Rym: they're taking What is just good enough for consumers and making it mass-market and they're also make you know.
Scott: But I think the things that they're doing are things that could have been done a while ago, you know They just weren't, you know, they could have.
Scott: someone could have made a device like this, you know ages ago.
Scott: What are they gonna do?
Rym: I don't want to talk about this in depth So eventually it'll get to the point to where you can augment your own performances in real time to sound like whatever you want.
Rym: What are they gonna do when I can perform stairway perfectly like Led Zeppelin entirely by myself?
Rym: I'm not playing a recording.
Rym: I'm performing.
Rym: Yeah, what's that gonna do?
Scott: I'll just record Myself playing stairway.
Scott: I'll push I'll make an mp3 of me singing it and I'll listen to that.
Scott: Listen to it.
Scott: It's exactly the same as the original studio recording if not better.
Rym: Here's the thing I would have to pay statutory royalties as a cover if I performed it.
Scott: It's a lot like five bucks.
Rym: However, if everyone just records their own version of everything that ruins Everything.
Rym: when it comes to IP rights, it sure does but that's all pie in the sky.
Rym: It's gonna be at least a couple decades before we get anywhere near that.
Scott: We're still gonna get much closer in the short term.
Scott: It's gonna be a lot easier for people to play much better music with a lot less musical talent.
Rym: I foresee a lot more cosplay skits and an Improvisational fun like public things happening that are good as opposed to horrifying or no.
Scott: It'll just improve the quality of no talent.
Scott: You know the same way that like, you know Like GTR turns the no talent driver into a doesn't crash or like a better camera can turn a YouTube video better.
Scott: You know, it's that same kind of thing.
Scott: It's like let's increase the quality of the tools make them easier such that the quality of amateur production will increase without Necessitating amateurs learning anything.
Rym: what it really reeks of it's the idea of intelligent defaults.
Rym: taken to the extreme.
Rym: It's playing default songs that are pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, it's got it by that logic.
Rym: and acoustic guitar is Linux.
Rym: You got to figure out all this bullshit about it.
Scott: You gotta tune it.
Rym: There's tablatures and that's even like the like my break someone using tabs.
Rym: that's like downloading the rpm.
Rym: You gotta compile that yourself.
Rym: Mmm, so let's move on.
Rym: Nintendo hinted that maybe they might possibly have Netflix.
Scott: Like hitting that Nintendo would have net.
Rym: and Nintendo was like, yeah The no one.
Rym: there was nothing clear here.
Rym: All I have to say is it doesn't matter.
Rym: It's too little too late.
Rym: There's no.
Rym: no one who wants Netflix on a device doesn't already have another device to do it.
Scott: at this point You know and it points out now people don't seem to realize is they don't look often at the US.
Scott: Japan Divide on these things right?
Scott: the Xbox had the Netflix.
Scott: That's a US device.
Scott: the ps3 had the Netflix.
Scott: Does it even have it now?
Scott: I'm pretty sure it does.
Rym: Yes, three does I believe it got it late.
Scott: if it did it got it after the Xbox did which is because they're Japanese.
Scott: They don't have Netflix really and you know, they might have something else, but they don't have Netflix.
Scott: Yeah, it's not on their radar.
Scott: well, I think this is why Nintendo is is missing out on a lot of things because Nintendo of America, you know, we think about like Reggie and stuff.
Scott: Reggie can't really do that much.
Scott: He doesn't make any games.
Scott: They know what's hardware.
Rym: Nintendo of America has always known what's up and Nintendo of Japan often will.
Scott: Nintendo Japan is where everything happens.
Scott: Nintendo of America is basically just salespeople that just take stuff from Nintendo of Japan and market it in the US.
Scott: They don't really have too much say in what gets made or how it's made.
Rym: I mean look in the old days you had Nintendo Japan saying Americans are too stupid to play our games.
Rym: We'll give them the easy modes.
Rym: Now.
Rym: You have Nintendo Japan saying why would anyone want to rent videos on a console?
Rym: No one does that here.
Rym: Why would anyone do it in America?
Scott: Yeah, I mean Nintendo of Europe is the same way.
Scott: It's basically just a selling company.
Scott: It's all salespeople and Nintendo of Japan makes everything and it's just up to them to sell it to Europeans.
Scott: You know and I think in the longer run this is gonna start to hurt Nintendo because Even all these normal people who bought all sorts of Wiis and made them so much money are not buying that many Wii games.
Scott: they're only buying like three.
Scott: Wii Sports is Wii fits and Mario and Their Wiis are collecting dust and they know it.
Rym: Thing is they made a profit on all the Wii.
Scott: Yes, but in the long run when they have to come out with Wii 2 People are gonna see there We won with this pile of dust and they're not gonna buy Wii 2.
Rym: the thing is the normal people might the muggles my I don't.
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: Nintendo's real problem.
Scott: They'll buy DS 2, but I don't know if they'll buy we.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: We shouldn't talk about Nintendo's problems because that is a Tuesday show.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: There's been a lot of augmented reality stuff at CES.
Rym: I don't get into all of it but there are a couple of different like glasses and they all look stupid and they're pretty poor but I Really want augmented reality to be awesome, but it's at least five to ten years out sadly.
Scott: Yeah, I mean MIT has that thing.
Scott: I forget what it's called But basically it to wear this big Electronic thing around your neck and it's smaller than this kind of thing has ever been but it's still too big.
Rym: I really just want my glasses now to have a wireframe overlay so I can tag people as stupid or not stupid.
Scott: Yeah, you only have two tags.
Rym: Well, you know that would suffice for the majority of what I do Mmm, I mean second would be having the the Grand Theft Auto arrow pointing where to go when I'm driving or walking.
Scott: Yeah, we need that.
Rym: and then the stupid not stupid tag.
Scott: Mmm All Right.
Scott: So let's talk about this boxy box, right?
Scott: It's really pretty.
Scott: It's a really nice looking box, right?
Scott: It stands.
Scott: they made it that way so that it stands out in your home media center.
Scott: You know apart from all the normal boxes that way it'll get attention to people come over to your house.
Scott: I think that was a good decision for marketing and such.
Scott: It's also pretty powerful box.
Scott: It's gonna run boxy pretty damn Well, you know.
Scott: considering that's all it's designed to do and if you just want to have boxy, this is not a bad idea.
Scott: However, there is a problem with the boxy box.
Scott: The problem is that all it does is run boxy.
Scott: I could go and buy.
Scott: it's gonna blow up.
Scott: I mean all it does is run boxy, but it is cheap.
Scott: It's only like they said it's gonna be like $200, right but for $4.99.
Scott: ish I can go get an aces triple-e 1501 which runs boxy just as well If not better.
Scott: and also is a computer with Windows 7 which means it can do any anything like, you know run an emulator.
Scott: You know run Windows Media Center extender, so it could be a DVR.
Scott: it can do all sorts of stuff because it's a computer.
Scott: It's basically a netbook without a with.
Scott: that's not a laptop and you could plug it into your TV with H You know an HDMI cable.
Rym: Well, there's a lot of competition in this space now, too.
Rym: I mean, there's that pop box that a lot of people are talking about.
Scott: Yeah, and I mean there's a company they made this thing called the new box.
Scott: Basically, all it is is a netbook just like I you know a net top just like I said.
Scott: only They just pre-installed pretty much every media program in the world on it and also there it is slowly.
Rym: Actual televisions are having more and more of this functionality just built in even though they implemented shiddily and drme.
Rym: It's there Mmm, and there's the problem that you know, well not really the problem.
Rym: I was looking at the Mac minis because I was thinking you know Maybe buy the new Mac mini at some point get rid of the old one.
Rym: I don't know what to do yet But they very clearly and prominently suggest on the Mac mini site and Apple now hook it up to your TV.
Rym: It's an amazing media PC Mmm, and it is.
Rym: I mean it really is.
Rym: it's.
Rym: it's more expensive than everything else But it has some of the most beautiful form factor there is for that sort of thing.
Scott: The thing is I think the aces is a better choice than the Mac mini right now because it has windows 7 emulato.
Scott: It can do more than the Mac mini can do right and it's cheaper by like over $100.
Rym: The only thing the Mac minis got going right now is the.
Scott: the aces has an HDMI output.
Scott: with the Mac mini you need to get like a mini display port to HDMI converter and a special optical audio cable and a.
Rym: All the Mac minis got going for it.
Rym: Is that OS X is really pretty though?
Rym: That's not really a deal maker right there.
Rym: And the form factor is perfect because it's completely a hundred percent silent and tiny.
Scott: the other the other one smile.
Scott: It's silent tiny.
Rym: Also, is it actually silent?
Rym: A lot of people said it's not.
Rym: it makes a little word.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I had to go listen to.
Scott: I don't know either but it looks silent and tiny to me.
Rym: It looks silent.
Rym: So I want to talk about this really quick.
Rym: the Zomteather.
Scott: Oh wait I forgot one thing though about the boxy box the boxy box remote control.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Ah, if they don't sell that fucker separately, I swear to God.
Scott: basically what it is on one side It's you know four arrows with a button in the middle You know just like the Mac mini the the Apple remote sort of only a little bit bigger.
Scott: on the other side is a keyboard Genius.
Scott: why do we have that stupid full-sized, you know wireless keyboard in the living room all this time?
Scott: We could have had a remote control like that because that remote didn't exist yet Even though it should have.
Scott: Oh God if they sell that remote control separately I might just buy two and if they don't sell it separately.
Rym: I might just buy a boxy box because you get the fucking remote control.
Rym: I'll sell the boxy box on eBay With boxy box no remote control.
Scott: one hundred and fifty dollars.
Rym: You don't need the remote.
Rym: So the Zom wireless tether all it is Bluetooth device.
Rym: you you link it to your phone or something.
Rym: if you get too far away from your phone and starts beeping to remind you that you left your fucking phone behind.
Rym: Oh, I think that's a pretty cool.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: So what if you forget the tether?
Rym: Well, I don't know.
Rym: I didn't look into it more than that.
Rym: You put the tether on your keychain.
Scott: Ah What if you get your keys?
Rym: Well, maybe get two tethers and tether them together.
Scott: I guess one thing that's good about it though is like if you know it also acts as a speakerphone.
Scott: Okay, one thing that is good about it is like, okay Let's see you have the phone but you forgot your keys, right?
Scott: Yeah, I'll be.
Scott: if you have the keys and forgot the phone It'll beep.
Scott: so you can't go wrong in both directions.
Rym: Of course if you forget all of your do everything at the same time You're in the I'm one step away from being a hobo situation.
Rym: There's really nothing you can do.
Scott: Anyway, yeah I'm gonna get stuck outside and not be able to call anybody.
Rym: You know what I realized if it weren't for the fact that I Almost know Emily's number by heart like I could probably dial.
Scott: I don't know anyone's phone number.
Rym: if I was like out somewhere like in the street and I lost my wallet and my cell phone There is almost no way for me to get help.
Rym: No, not really.
Rym: I would usually have to go to a Starbucks beg them beg someone to let me use their computer to get on my email and Message someone.
Rym: Oh, no public library.
Scott: That's not a bad idea.
Scott: Just go find a computer with a web browser and you're okay.
Rym: magic Jack has that femtocell which is I Don't know that whole thing wallet shady.
Rym: I Foresee many many more things like that that are not magic Jack but are just nerds doing it on their own.
Rym: Well my you know magic Jack made a femtocell.
Rym: So basically your cell phone will sync to it with GSM instead of anything else.
Rym: Yep, and then it's basically you can make calls like a real cell phone without any like no one knows but his voice.
Scott: Yes, it is Some people don't realize.
Scott: is that you know Verizon and Sprint with their CDMA of do whatever is right?
Scott: That's all proprietary technology.
Scott: If you want to connect to that kind of network, you need to buy chips from Qualcomm.
Scott: You know the company Qualcomm, that's what they do.
Scott: If you use GSM GPRS edge HSD PA that's all open source stuff, right?
Scott: There Pete that there were like tech conferences in Europe where nerds just set up their own GSM networks Just you know and handed out SIM cards.
Rym: now, you know, what's gonna happen?
Rym: Especially if there's more white space in the spectrum and all that sort of stuff?
Rym: we're gonna get to the point where either nerds just put open femto cells all over the place connected to the internet or I don't know.
Rym: the possibilities are endless and I don't want to sidetrack the whole show with them.
Rym: But that is cool and magic.
Rym: Jack.
Rym: while they reek of shady They seem to do what they say they do and that sort of thing is gonna completely screw Verizon and Sprint in the long run.
Rym: Yeah, especially because now Verizon saying yeah, no more unlimited plans possibly.
Scott: Well, another thing is that The femto cells.
Scott: the original idea was that like, you know, okay, I'm an AT&T customer But they don't really have service so much in my apartment.
Scott: Maybe it's blocked by the walls or something.
Scott: Yeah, so I go and get a femto cell.
Scott: put it in my apartment.
Scott: now I have good coverage of my apartment - the problem is they wanted the customer to buy the femto cell Right and then keep it in their apartment.
Scott: It's like, excuse me.
Scott: You've got it wrong.
Scott: You you should give me half off my plan for installing a femto cell and donating my electricity To your freaking network or not?
Rym: Just that the idea that just give them away for free to anyone who wants them and then you basically Increased your network a lot.
Scott: You're not without having to wait for a lot less than the expense of building towers - yep In fact have multiple levels have like a tiny one.
Rym: That's just in a house.
Rym: It's kind of low-powered.
Rym: have a more powerful one for nerds that just goes on the roof.
Scott: Well, yeah, you find out where someone's living before you figure out which one you're gonna give them.
Rym: Yeah, I mean think you say you live in a neighborhood with nimby So you get bad cell service because no one will let him build a cell tower.
Rym: if you live there Just have a roof tile.
Rym: That's actually a femto cell and now you've got great cell coverage.
Rym: Yep All that stuff is cool.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: There's the Ford sinking Google stuff.
Rym: They talked more about that.
Rym: There were some demos.
Scott: Yeah, the Ford sink is looking like you're finally gonna have basically a computer in your car that you know.
Scott: Does everything that your computer does.
Scott: you can check your emails and your sports and two items of note?
Rym: The long run of this is cars that talk to each other and you'll basically have real-time traffic data That is accurate and rerouting and all that stuff and you'll have an ad hoc network effectively of all the cars which alleviates a lot of problems with coverage.
Rym: internet in the car all the time.
Rym: and As far as I can tell there's a podcast button or channel to start.
Rym: I think we're finally getting to the point to where in cars which is where most People who aren't in major cities with mass transit listen to the radio.
Rym: now We'll be able to just listen to a podcast like it's radio and not know that it's not radio.
Scott: Yeah That's you know, that was the thing I wanted for podcasting all along was you know, it needs to just be on-demand audio.
Scott: You know someone browses through a directory of audio content pushes a button It just plays immediately and all the content is in the library all the time that not even just that with these cars.
Rym: It's also got to have these serious equivalent where someone makes podcast quote-unquote stations that aren't live or anything.
Rym: It's just playing something all the time and people smell a lot of satellite radio.
Scott: There are channels that just play podcasts in order.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: We looked into doing serious long time ago, which is only pain.
Rym: It was too much of a hassle to conform to the standard to fit like in the time slots and stuff.
Scott: They also support things like stitcher.
Scott: with stitcher What you can do is like let's say you know that you drive an hour in the morning and an hour on the way home.
Scott: Right with stitcher you can be like, yeah I want to listen to the traffic for this area then the weather then this news guy then this news guy then You know this, you know band and then and then it basically puts together every day.
Scott: You know the thing for you to listen to.
Rym: stitcher is pretty cool.
Rym: I actually I've been using down my pre through the beta and everything and we should interview them.
Rym: Actually, I've emailed him a bunch of time.
Rym: No, did you cuz way back when their podcast like directory had almost nothing I wanted in it.
Rym: I was like your thing sucks and I listed like everything I wanted to listen to.
Rym: they didn't have that day.
Rym: They emailed me.
Rym: They're like, those are all added anything else we should add.
Rym: Yeah No, and they're like any suggestions anything anything.
Rym: and they're like, yeah, it looks like you do a radio show blah blah blah.
Rym: So they're cool people.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All righty.
Rym: Yeah, there's that mobile credit card swiper for the iPhone Brilliant.
Scott: Yeah, can I say really been around for a while?
Rym: I know But there was something about it here.
Rym: They'd announce something about it at CES.
Rym: I don't know what.
Rym: mm-hmm.
Rym: Oh, I think this is a different one.
Rym: No Regardless.
Rym: I look forward to the day to where everyone has a card scanner or the equivalent.
Rym: And if I want to give money to Scott, I just swipe my card on.
Scott: Why do we look at I'm swiping a card into someone's phone, right?
Scott: Why don't we just bump our phones together?
Rym: Seriously well because Bluetooth and every every information sharing thing like that has always been crippled by bullshit.
Rym: yep, and This swiping a credit card is the only thing that's not crippled by bullshit because the credit card companies want you to swipe it as much as possible.
Rym: Nvidia ion Demonstrated it's everything it lived up to be.
Scott: Well, that's what's in that aces.
Scott: I was talking about.
Scott: Yeah, basically if people still don't know I've talked about it before I think the Nvidia ion is a GPU.
Scott: That's really cheap, right?
Scott: It's not gonna run the latest and greatest games, but I probably play half-life.
Scott: It'll play old games.
Scott: Yeah relative, you know, it might even play half-life - who knows.
Scott: but what it is is a very low power very inexpensive GPU.
Scott: So what you can do is you can get a cheapo computer like a netbook with the Intel atom CPU.
Rym: We're talking on netbook.
Rym: That's like you can make a computer.
Rym: That is the size of like my three harmonic is sitting next to each other.
Scott: Well, maybe not that small.
Rym: I'm looking at a picture of one right now.
Rym: That's that's this big.
Rym: Okay It's the entire computer.
Scott: So and then you put the Nvidia ion GPU next to it.
Scott: It doesn't use that much more electricity.
Scott: So your battery life isn't gonna get killed.
Scott: Yeah, right, but you now have a GPU which means that if you're gonna use your netbook for things like watching Flash videos right watching any sort of video that can be accelerated by the GPU doing anything HD Doing anything with only a little bit of 3d in it.
Scott: now you can do it.
Scott: You can have a really low power Cheap inexpensive tiny computer that could actually like play HD videos that you downloaded from iTunes or whatever.
Scott: That is crazy.
Scott: It's like You know, it's not like a Ferrari.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's almost like a Taurus SHO, you know It looks like a normal slow black car, but secretly it's pretty fast.
Scott: Not Ferrari fast not Porsche fast, but like, you know Mustang fast, but doesn't look like a Mustang at all.
Scott: It looks like a Pete looks like a piece of crap.
Scott: There's the and cotton, you know only cost what a piece of crap costs.
Rym: also Open peak made an atom-powered.
Rym: They call it the pro frame VoIP phone.
Rym: It's like it's a business e VoIP phone like all those VoIP phones.
Scott: I mean, have you seen true phone?
Rym: I believe yes true phone.
Scott: It's like TRU phone and a lot of people in Europe use it Apparently.
Scott: what it is is I think it's an app you can get for most.
Scott: I think it's on iPhone and it's iPhone Android web, I forget which ones it's on and which ones is not on but they want it to be on all of them.
Scott: and Basically, what it does is you know, you can you know have Skype and then you can call Skype people for free But then you got to pay for anyone else.
Rym: No this is like a VoIP phone to replace my VoIP phone.
Rym: the one up there and every business e VoIP phone is Has the old-school interface that old-school business people are used to.
Rym: this one has a big color touchscreen Multi-touch icons like all the user interface that I want my phone.
Rym: if I want to dial someone's number and I don't know their number I have to type their name in like I'm texting it just awful.
Scott: Now what the true phone does?
Scott: it lets you call Skype for free unless you call a gizmo for free.
Scott: It lets you call without anything anyone that it can call for free over some sort of VoIP.
Scott: It will call for free and if it has to use the actual phone lines, then they'll charge you money.
Scott: But what they charge to call anyone in the US on any phone, you know calls to any phone in the?
Scott: u.s Like three cents a minute.
Scott: So people in the in Europe are like true phone Using that for my international calls or even you know non international calls because it's just incredibly cheap for the.
Scott: you know Even when it does charge you money and if it can make a free call for free it will every single time Which is pretty awesome.
Rym: So if you're looking to save money on lots of international calls true phone I think we should wrap this up with perhaps the most important part of CES.
Rym: Mm-hmm the in gadget crap gadget No and catchy.
Scott: So yeah and gadget goes around and they love to find, you know Well, they have the curves right which is the keeping it real fake Which is all like the the boot, you know the thing that looks like an iPhone, but it's not an iPhone.
Scott: But that CES they do the crap gadget.
Scott: They basically find gadgets that are crap.
Rym: Those shoes that are ugly high-heeled plastic pink shoes that are also speakers.
Scott: I think that they're only speakers.
Scott: I don't think they're you supposed to wear them?
Rym: Yeah, apparently everyone kept asking them.
Rym: So do I wear them or what?
Scott: Yeah They're.
Rym: they're horrifyingly ugly.
Scott: I don't understand why you would want speakers that look like high-heeled shiny shoes.
Rym: There's that finger ist which is basically a giant ugly keyboard to stick on your iPhone and then try to play it like a guitar.
Scott: Alright, no.
Rym: Yeah, I see the picture of the iPhone screen and they draw like a bunch of strings on it.
Scott: Yeah, I like the polar bear television set is a stuffed polar bear with a television and it's.
Scott: I think that's my favorite one.
Scott: That's definitely.
Scott: that was the first one.
Scott: It was the most obvious.
Scott: but audience is that for I mean I could see like I think you're supposed to use it like a kids room, you know to make like a cute TV.
Scott: But they already have like, you know the Mickey Mouse TV or whatever.
Scott: I guess I could see that being you're gonna get any television just put a cute bezel on it It's not.
Rym: I could see that being in the like den of some sort of ultra modern fancy apartment.
Rym: just cuz it's weird.
Scott: I Being in like the safari lodge as the TV set cuz it fits in.
Scott: there's that wrist.
Rym: cell phone There's.
Rym: it's like this wrist like holster for your cell phone But the pictures of it show someone putting an entire freaking iPhone in there.
Rym: Yeah, it's like gigantic.
Rym: It's like a wrist.
Scott: brace On my iPhone might be wider than my wrist.
Rym: Let me say mine is a lot wider.
Scott: Yeah, mine is definitely wider than my wrist.
Scott: Look you can see it.
Rym: My pre is even wider than my wrist.
Rym: granted I have tiny wrists.
Scott: I also have a very tiny wrist One.
Rym: I don't get.
Rym: that's on here.
Rym: It looks like a good idea.
Rym: It's a tiny DV camera that police officers can wear like on their chest to record everything they're doing.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: Yeah, that's great.
Rym: However, the company that makes it they called it the ghost scam.
Scott: Okay Not a very good name.
Scott: Sure, it's not like the ghost cam.
Rym: It says go scam.
Rym: It just has really really bad Graphic design.
Rym: on the ad.
Rym: it shows like this really old cop standing there with the thing kind of like photoshopped onto his.
Rym: It's bad But the product I feel like.
Rym: by law every police officer on active duty should have a camera recording everything They do while they're on duty except maybe peeing.
Scott: hmm Okay.
Rym: Yeah, I don't have a lot else to talk about CES why a lot of things went down at CES.
Scott: You can go read all about him on the internet.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: 3d was making a big jump.
Scott: Let's talk about some 3d.
Rym: Let's talk about that because Nvidia has been on the 3d boat forever, but no one knows.
Scott: that's one You know, they're looking for any area in which they can sell you something new.
Scott: It's like well if everyone if we can get everyone to start making 3d games and you need an Nvidia card to play those games In 3d at least.
Scott: then we will be able to sell a lot of Nvidia product, you know.
Scott: And then we can also sell glasses.
Scott: Well, you know, that's they're looking for.
Scott: As far as 3d goes I think that the you know Like people are liking it right now because it is pretty awesome.
Scott: You know If you're if you're the kind of person that it doesn't make you sick.
Scott: and even the thing is even people who complain about it Making them sick.
Scott: They go see it.
Scott: Anyway, they say oh man, it was awesome.
Scott: But I got nauseous.
Scott: I would you do it again?
Scott: Yeah, it's like okay.
Scott: and second of all People already have glasses.
Scott: It's sort of problematic for them to wear other glasses.
Rym: Yeah That's why they always make the things really big and you stick them in front.
Scott: and then there's the like.
Scott: I've never been to one That has these but some people go to the ones that have like the battery-powered glasses.
Rym: Oh, yeah, there's the shit.
Rym: Well, there's shutter glass.
Scott: I've never used those ones.
Rym: There's the polarized ones.
Rym: There's the red and blue ones.
Scott: There's a people talked about like the ones of the batteries.
Scott: I was like what the hell are you talking about?
Scott: I've never seen one of the battery in my life But I guess they exist.
Rym: people have said that those Give you the most options.
Rym: like you can make the best 3d with the shutter glasses.
Scott: But how do you like?
Scott: if it's so it it's shuttering open and closed all the time.
Scott: Is that what it's doing?
Rym: Yes, so fast that basically so so you can.
Rym: it synchronizes with the screen.
Scott: Oh, so there's no.
Scott: so you don't see black see something.
Scott: don't see something.
Scott: see something don't see something.
Rym: No, it flickers so fast that it like imagine does it make noise while it's flickering like?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Imagine this.
Rym: imagine.
Rym: you've got a screen to say 120 Hertz Mm-hmm, and the shutter glasses are going in each eye at 120 Hertz offset And then the screen is flipping between the two images that together create the 3d in your eyes.
Scott: Synchronize the glasses with the projector.
Rym: I think there's a way to do that.
Rym: I mean, I don't know a lot about the technology.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: and then you know, I like the ones without the battery.
Rym: There are also a lot of multiple demos of different technologies of glasses free 3d.
Rym: Of course the consensus so far has been that it's not that 3d.
Rym: Yeah, and it's kind of blurry.
Scott: basically what seems to have happened here right is that Panasonic had a 3d TV Right with an actual release date.
Scott: Everyone else is sort of like yeah, we're gonna do 3d.
Rym: Well, because all the technology manufacturers realize that look at Avatar.
Rym: Look how crazy it is in the theaters.
Rym: Even if people pirate the movie.
Rym: They want to go into the theater to see the awesome 3d Mmm, once people have 3d TVs that gimmick disappears.
Scott: something else really interesting is that?
Scott: Apparently like it doesn't cost that much to add 3d to the TV.
Scott: It's they can just sort of tack it on.
Scott: Yeah So if they can do something like that to sell everyone a new TV that they just sold them HD TVs Big money for them.
Rym: I wish this was gonna happen a little bit sooner.
Rym: I would wait until the 3d wave starts.
Rym: my I'd buy the best 2d TV money could buy.
Scott: a guy at work was looking actually a Projectors and he said that there was a 1080p Projector with 3d abilities that was actually cheaper than a 1080p projector that didn't have 3d.
Rym: The only reason I didn't I'm not getting a projector just yet Is that a 52 inch TV is as big as I need in the room.
Rym: Anyway a projector would just be overkill.
Scott: also a projector is very annoying You see to put all the equipment in the back and then get the wiring and the pain.
Rym: That would be fine because I wouldn't put anything in the front.
Rym: I don't have a we.
Scott: I guess there'd be nothing in the front.
Rym: The problems are one the blacks aren't that black and I'm not gonna get that expensive Sony thing with the black screen.
Scott: I don't even know if that's still around anymore.
Rym: There's got to be somewhere or that technology and to the bulbs do burn out.
Rym: So you basically you need to have a projector and a TV and you only use the projector for like movies and the TV for Like playing my video games.
Scott: Maybe personally like I'm not you know, I'm only partially excited about 3d.
Scott: It's like yeah It would be pretty cool if I could watch like a hockey in 3d But I'm not gonna pay money for that for a very long time.
Scott: However, however glasses Imagine it's like I gotta buy all these glasses.
Rym: I'm playing an FPS that just has natural 3d while you're playing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah be pretty good Wouldn't?
Rym: I wouldn't spend $1,000 on it, but I'm not gonna buy all new monitors Yeah, but what I would do is I would just upgrade when it was time to upgrade and I'd get 3d.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I foresee, you know, it's like they're being a big 3d push now, but remember the initial HD push right was Like in the late 90s, right and it wasn't until like the late 2000s that eight, you know Everyone's got HD or at least a lot of people have HD and not even the majority have it yet.
Scott: So and no one cares about blu-ray or anything and a lot of people are putting standard def content into their HD TVs.
Scott: So I think it'll be probably 10 years before before a lot of people actually have 3d.
Scott: you know as many as have HD now and Before.
Scott: there's like a standard and there's a lot of actual, you know 3d content.
Rym: The real drive right now like all the trends are toward digital distribution distribution That is going to take precedence over even high def and I think a lot of people are more interested in getting media easier Than getting high quality media.
Rym: Mmm, I mean look how you know people watch entire movies and TV shows on YouTube.
Rym: Yeah, people are willing to put up with really bad quality.
Rym: They just want the content and they're not even willing to pay for the content.
Scott: Yeah, they're much more excited about a boxy box than they are about day TV a goat seat projector.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.