Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, December 21st, 2010.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: Bomberman Let's do this.
Rym: So it turns out that I had in fact come like a thief in the night and one by one dropped the revelers and the Blood Badoon.
Rym: What?
Rym: So I I got sick.
Scott: Is there a plague situation?
Rym: I got sick and I stayed home from work for like two days and then I went to work and I got everyone at work sick and Emily got sick and Scott got sick.
Rym: and Awesome Pax Enforcer Aaron Clark who was out visiting in New York for the week got sick.
Scott: I'm not really that sick.
Scott: I mean my throat was just kind of bleh, but I wasn't feverish or you know, I can operate.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait.
Rym: So your throat was bleh today.
Scott: It was all it's been bleh But today it was especially bleh and then it unbleed mostly.
Rym: You'll find out tomorrow's D-Day You might wake up.
Scott: That's the thing I hate about throatiness, right?
Scott: Is it?
Scott: you go to sleep You're laying down.
Scott: the gravity stops working for you, right?
Scott: And then when you wake up in the morning It's the worst but then when you stand up for a few hours It fixes.
Rym: As a veteran of sinus infections as in fact Perhaps an expert in the field at least in the field of accepting and dealing with sinus infections I can say this you take yourself some mucinex at night.
Rym: No problems in the morning.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, this is a throat situation.
Rym: Yeah Mucinex fixes the throat.
Rym: Because you realize why the throat gets irritated is that you got mucus just constantly going down the throat irritating it Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the way around is the mucinex thins the mucus and at the same time prevents the mucus from coming out Uh-huh.
Rym: So as a result the throat doesn't get irritated.
Rym: you're good to go.
Scott: But I gotta get the real mucinex.
Rym: I got enough to where I was barred from buying more pseudoephedrine a month ago.
Rym: Until January 1st I have bought the federal limit.
Scott: Do they look it up like in the computer every time?
Rym: Yes I gotta swipe my driver's license at the Duane Reade and they're like, "Sir, you can't buy any more
Rym: pseudoephed.".
Rym: Yeah, I argued with him and then I had to go.
Scott: I'll go buy some.
Rym: It's a felony for me to ask you to buy It for me.
Scott: No, I'll go buy some.
Scott: For me?
Scott: You didn't ask me for it.
Rym: Okay You just buy some.
Scott: I'm not buying it for me.
Rym: You buy some independently and if I need it.
Rym: I might just steal it from you.
Scott: Well that's illegal stealing it from me Because we got a big meth lab going on here.
Scott: That's why we go to work every day because we got a meth lab.
Rym: Let's go to work.
Rym: Yeah So we're we're doing okay.
Rym: A little low energy here.
Scott: Speaking of medicine, get this, right?
Scott: So there was like a letter in the mail, right?
Scott: And it had like this NYU logo on it.
Scott: So I mostly ignored it and then I opened it and it was actually.
Scott: it wasn't from NYU You know, it was actually from the doctor I went to who happened to be like associated with NYU You know, the practice.
Scott: And you know what it said?
Rym: What did it say?
Scott: Well, I'm a doctor and I'm gonna go become a director of doctors down in Florida and I'm like no I should send you some blackjack.
Scott: I was like cuz like it took me forever to find a doctor who wasn't a schmuck and then he goes to become You know some you know, the doctor, the director of some hospital or something.
Rym: You realize what he's really doing.
Rym: He's going on to have an okie or a sawa plot.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: It's totally he's chasing the monster.
Scott: It's totally gonna be an evil Hospital Tezuka or a sawa manga plot.
Rym: Well, then the master Keaton looking good guy is gonna come up here and talk to you one day like remember doctor so-and-so.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: I went to this doctor once and I was like, oh finally a doctor who's not a quack.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna go I gotta go find a different doctor.
Rym: You're gonna get to be the one-off side character.
Scott: I'm not even he's got his thousands of patients.
Rym: Yeah, you'll be the one.
Scott: Okay the way that works He's you know, he helped me with my barely any illnesses once And because I survived But I do.
Rym: before we get onto the news and everything I want to give a shout out because we did have Aaron Clark.
Rym: It's funny because we know.
Rym: to Aaron Clark's There's the awesome one who is like the super enforcer packs that and his evil non-twin.
Rym: Yeah, the other Aaron Clark works for Otakon and said that it shouldn't be fun to volunteer for cons.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: They're like polar opposite Aaron Clark and the other one is the awesomest con volunteer who has more fun.
Rym: You may know him if you're at PAX.
Rym: There's one enforcer above all the others.
Rym: The main theater a real kilts in the main theater as opposed to a utility kilt.
Scott: Is his actual position like head of main theater legit something like that head of kilts?
Scott: Yeah, basically real kills not you.
Rym: So we were gonna do a show with him on like helicoptering because that's one of the things he does.
Rym: Well, the thing he does yeah sickness got in the way.
Rym: So we'll Skype him in at some point in the future.
Scott: talk about helicopters Yeah, but basically he could talk about helicopters for like forever.
Scott: I learned as long as we could talk about computers.
Rym: I learned a lot about helicopters.
Scott: I am now sated in my Helicopter knowledge.
Rym: I'm mostly sated.
Rym: I want to learn more about these double rotor ones.
Scott: now suddenly Well, you told me that the blades actually spin in the opposite direction, right?
Rym: Which sounds far scarier, right.
Scott: and the Because the blades are like at an angle they'll never hit each other regardless of like the timing.
Scott: It's not a timing thing It's just that you know because they bend when you go up and down So they'll always be bending in the same way.
Scott: So they in their angles that gonna it'll be cool.
Rym: So one game one kind of game that I like is the sports game, but of all the sports games to this day Not counting Super Techno ball ice hockey and ice hockey.
Rym: The best games are actually the Mario sports games because they're not that realistic But they I feel like they capture Mario.
Scott: Mario Tennis and Mario soccer strikers are you know are good?
Scott: I don't know about that baseball one.
Scott: I never really played that enough.
Rym: I played it a little bit.
Rym: It was fun.
Rym: Yeah, the trouble with the Mario baseball was that I Think Super Baseball Simulator 1000 is a better game.
Scott: Well, I mean, yeah, if you're talking about your unrealistic baseballs, you know More realistic baseballs you got to head to bases loaded or maybe Ken Griffey baseball on the Super Nintendo.
Rym: Of course, I mean Mario Tennis is perfectly realistic.
Scott: That's Mario Tennis is perfect.
Rym: That's exactly what tennis is.
Rym: I actually don't.
Scott: you know people love Virtua Tennis.
Scott: I actually don't like Virtua Tennis even though I like Virtua Racing Virtua Tennis, I think the controls just have problems.
Rym: But the trouble is to this day if I want to play a good Mario sports game I tend to go back to the Mario Tennis on the game of cube Mario Tennis Because the newer one, but anyway, there is a new Mario sports game coming.
Rym: It was finally announced and there's some shadiness some trickiness.
Rym: I'm not looking forward to this.
Rym: I'm worried.
Scott: What are you worried about?
Rym: one?
Rym: It's not made by a Camelot.
Rym: Uh-oh And Camelot's done a good job of making the Mario games.
Rym: They added this kind of.
Rym: I don't want to say edginess But if you look at like the the animations the way the characters were in the games that Camelot made they were a little.
Scott: Who's making it?
Rym: You're never gonna guess.
Scott: All right, you're never gonna give me one guess square You know, it's Eidos slash.
Scott: No, it's it's Square Enix, right?
Scott: So they that's that makes sense because they made the.
Scott: there was the basketball one for the DS that had both Final Fantasy characters and Mario characters, so they're doing that and it's a Mario sports game called Mario sports Mix that has hockey basketball volleyball and dodgeball.
Scott: That could be good.
Scott: Volleyball games are usually great Dodge balls.
Rym: pretty great thing is when you and whenever you put multiple sports in the same game.
Rym: I'm leery that this is head.
Scott: Yeah, that is one thing right is that when you get a game like Mario tennis They put the full-on tennis right.
Scott: multiple courts multiple moves, right?
Scott: They make eat they make that game They put as much into it as they can.
Scott: when you get a multi pack, right?
Scott: They're not really gonna put in and make each individual sport as deep as it would be they could.
Rym: there's no reason they couldn't.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: They won't.
Rym: there is no way.
Rym: you'll tell me that they will.
Rym: there's no way.
Scott: if they did It would be amazing but odds of them doing it are very low.
Rym: and you know for player online play all that stuff.
Rym: There's a gameplay video.
Rym: I I don't know.
Rym: Nintendo has been kind of turning its back on me more and more as time goes on.
Scott: I'm playing Mario Galaxy 2 right now and Kirby yarns pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, they're okay, but they're not.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: They're not my go-to games anymore.
Rym: There was a long time when the Wii and the DS what I'm going to.
Scott: it's what I'm going to right now.
Scott: It's very moment But as soon as I beat those are single players as soon as I beat those bad boys the Wii is gonna take another nap.
Rym: Yeah, because these games are only great when you've got people physically in the room playing with you.
Rym: You gotta have four people and they all have to be good.
Rym: Yep Though we'll see what happens with Mario Sports Mix, but I I don't think I'm gonna buy it.
Rym: site on zine.
Scott: No, especially Nintendo still has this problem right where they put out a game.
Scott: It's 50 bucks.
Scott: All right, a lot of people play out of the game 50 bucks and then you know, for example Fallout New Vegas Which I was moderately considering but now I'm sort of not considering it anymore.
Scott: No matter how far.
Rym: Oh, I'm gonna buy it.
Rym: I'm 100% gonna buy it when it's a dollar.
Scott: Yeah, right the thing is Nintendo.
Scott: you wait like a year or two after the game comes out.
Scott: still 50 40 bucks.
Scott: Right, maybe you'll be lucky and I got like a slight discount on galaxy tube from some Amazon.
Rym: This way if the GameCube Mario Tennis came out had never existed and it came out today On the Wii and it was the exact same game and you would you pay 40 bucks for it?
Scott: Uh If I tried it out and it was you know I guess the thing that made Mario Tennis so great though is because we had played.
Scott: we had recently played the Mario 64 Mario Tennis which was also like a paragon of game.
Scott: Of course We played the Mario 64 Mario Tennis and we had recently had amazing Experiences with it.
Scott: and shortly thereafter Right the Mario GameCube tennis appeared and that is why we jumped on it Because we had so recently played the high-quality Mario Tennis on the GameCube.
Scott: the thing is if the GameCube one had never come out that the N64 one would be like a distant memory.
Scott: and because I'm not in a college Situation if the GameCube one came out now on the Wii I might not be so, you know all about it.
Scott: If I was still in college, you know, and I knew that there was gonna be tournaments and all sorts of activity.
Rym: Maybe well part of what did it was the Mario Tennis trash talk tournaments That's right, which which began on the n64 and migrated to the GameCube Which packs take heed a Mario Tennis trash talk tournament where you have to both win the trash talking and the tennis.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: You don't have a panel of expert judges.
Rym: get the pollen storm in the wheat and up there.
Rym: It's a pretty good action.
Scott: Oh tricky boot up at the ball right behind Luigi asshole to keep the Koopa covering boos and bots.
Scott: Okay, cuz boo can't get to the law.
Scott: I get all the love Deliver all the love.
Rym: I know that Scott boo not so great on his own Scott boo with Any boo on its own right.
Scott: if I'm on my own?
Scott: I'm not gonna pick the boo even though I probably will anyway.
Scott: But the read the problem with boo in Mario Tennis is that he is wicked tricky.
Scott: He has the hits that are like unbelievable.
Scott: You can hit it hard You know, he can't hit it the hardest but you can hit it real hard.
Scott: He can hit the the lob over your head the lob just over the net and all sorts of tricky hooks.
Scott: Put a ball out of your reach, but he's slow and his teleport isn't very slow.
Scott: So if you it's real easy to score on boo if he messes up at all Right, if he doesn't recenter after every hit.
Scott: you could totally get him so easily and he's no way He can make it all the way across the court where the kid the Koopa comes if he doesn't have the super shot Right.
Scott: So if you're playing on your own you're much better off picking a character like say the paratrooper who is you know?
Scott: Almost as tricky as the boo, but he has the speed.
Scott: this paratrooper can just go straight across the court.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: straight up dude listeners the first two listeners who challenge us to a game.
Rym: if you're gonna be at PAX Boston Aka bitch pack or mag fest or mag fest.
Scott: We'll uh, we'll play you and no one's gonna beat us at Mario.
Rym: No one's gonna beat us at Mario I mean, who was the last group of people we played?
Rym: it was like Pete and Wyatt and they're pretty good But they're terrible.
Rym: They were pretty good.
Scott: Of course team Scott is the best.
Rym: Yeah, because the problem is I don't have me and a Scott to play against team Scott.
Rym: It could be either Scott Scott Johnson's equally good.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Anyway, it doesn't play the boo though.
Scott: No, he plays.
Scott: I think he plays the the Yoshi, right?
Scott: I don't remember what.
Scott: he really don't remember.
Scott: No Wow I'm gonna kid Koopa Anyway, or I think he's the shy guy sometimes too.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: No, I think he was the shy guy shy guy.
Scott: I'm pretty sure Pete is the shy guy shy guy.
Scott: That guy sucks All right, so In the news here, right?
Scott: So, you know, uh, Mame right the multiple arcade machine emulator That is like the the most number one emulator in the world.
Rym: that is important for as an aside the most stupid and horribly configured Program ever written.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's just it's.
Scott: it's a little tricky to use right because basically what they did is, you know For example any NES emulator only emulates the NES so it only has to worry about NES things.
Scott: Mame right emulates all these hundreds of different arcade machines.
Rym: for example There's a mahjong game that has like 20 buttons on the front So you've got to make sure that it'll handle these individual buttons for this one game, right?
Scott: Exactly So what are you trying to emulate?
Rym: the soccer game?
Scott: You got the kicker instead of making multiple emulators?
Scott: They have this one program that selects the emulator based on the game you're playing right and then you know has this common Configuration as much as possible for.
Scott: but even if you make the configuration as you know condensed as possible There's still all these ancillary things all over the place, you know.
Scott: Like for example, you got to worry about six player x-men which means you need six coin slots, you know.
Scott: So it's like oh my god.
Rym: and and as a note the game was upside down because in the arcade it's displayed upside down So we had to turn it.
Scott: Yeah, it's all kinds of weird stuff anyway.
Scott: So Mame exists, right and there's actually a problem with Mame and I realized you know In the past day or two this problems actually bigger than I thought right.
Scott: and basically what's going on with Mame Is it's an open-source project and there's people working on it But a lot of these people are not working on the parts that need to be worked on Like the interface of binding keys.
Scott: Well, no, no, no, they're working on things like, you know Re-architecting the code or you know filing bug reports, right?
Scott: But there aren't people who are doing things that really need to be done like on the emulation level like hey Let's get more games to work better, right?
Scott: People are working on the low levels.
Scott: There's almost none of them left like a very very small handful and that's a common problem with open-source projects.
Scott: And what tends to happen is there are people come in and they'll fix like one thing that they really care about and then leave You know, so they're having this trouble where they're basically Mame.
Scott: You know the important part to like add an almost standstill and this Mame developer.
Scott: He writes a whole big blog post here about it and there's all these comments, right?
Scott: And I was like all.
Scott: that's sad, but I can't help.
Scott: I mean emulator writing is not exactly my department You know, it's not.
Scott: that's not where I do.
Rym: also the long queue of already shat talked things.
Rym: We have to poop out.
Scott: I already did so.
Rym: I've been not talking in a very long time working on stuff But as a result, we don't have time to commit to more things.
Scott: Yeah, I can't.
Scott: I can't start working on someone else's project.
Scott: One of my my projects not done yet Right.
Scott: So anyway, also one of our listeners right is has made a version of Mame.
Scott: I think it's a fork or a mod or I'm not sure exactly but it's basically.
Scott: it's a client server Mame and it allows you To play Mame over the internets.
Scott: so you can play six player x-men with six people in six different places.
Scott: That's pretty cool.
Scott: Anyway, so the other day for this show I need to emulate some Saturn games.
Scott: So yesterday last night, I was trying to emulate the Saturn and oh boy all the Saturn emulators are shit.
Scott: Yep, and I think basically what has happened here is I tried to do some examination right and it seems like what's happened was NES is emulated thoroughly right and there's a zillion NES emulators.
Scott: basically because people Copy, you know the one NES emulator that was out there.
Scott: It's like there's a lot of people.
Scott: they don't actually know how to write an emulator But they just copy the existing ones that are able to make all these emulators Really?
Scott: There's only a handful and it's the same one over and over again crooks lightly.
Rym: So yeah different levels of malware, right?
Scott: Yeah, but you know nestopia seems to be the winner and that's apart not nesticle.
Scott: You know the SNES has two emulators, of course the Super Famicom being the most, you know Number one console that anyone would want to emulate right?
Scott: So that's you know, the SNES 9x and ZSNES are pretty much the winners right and so on and so forth.
Scott: But as you go forward in the console, you know history, right the more obscure consoles turbo graphics, you know There are emulators, but they're not that great.
Scott: and 64 there are emulators, but they got problems.
Scott: You know, the PlayStation has EPS XE, which is a very good but PlayStation 2 very shitty.
Scott: We should be able to emulate the ps2 on the hardware We have now right and almost able to emulate the Xbox one.
Scott: But the emulators are just so bad and it seems like anyone who is capable of writing emulators Has no interest in doing so and is not putting any effort forth in doing so.
Scott: and as a result there is like this dearth Basically old systems that are already emulated are gonna are safe and new systems are not.
Scott: and you know You think oh you just want a pirate ps2 game.
Rym: No, I want to play like the utenna game on the Saturn?
Scott: Well, no, but here's the real issue at stake here, right?
Scott: Is that okay?
Scott: I'm gonna go and buy legitimately buy a Sega Saturn ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: There aren't enough of them to go around, you know for historical and preservation reasons, right?
Scott: We need good emulators of every system ever now, right?
Scott: It's absolute must and I if I was like, you know, there needs to be like a government grant.
Scott: Well, you realize what like library of Congress needs to give money to somebody at an edit college.
Scott: We're real computer scientists can make these emulators.
Rym: humans have been down this road before for a long time.
Rym: film movies TV shows.
Rym: we didn't keep them.
Rym: We're like who would want to see this TV show again.
Rym: We already showed it on TV Wasn't that what?
Scott: that's a no bro.
Scott: Is she girl talked about when we're at Otakon, right?
Rym: How many anime?
Scott: There's like look Disney has snow white right because keeping film right movie film in a real, you know All rolled up actually damn, you know damages it.
Scott: Disney has these underground pipes that are incredibly long and they have snow white on film Stretched out full length right in this pipe and many other films as well, you know to preserve them because it's important Right, but meanwhile you've got these animes like old animes just lost throwing away Degrading and he doesn't even want to stretch him out, you know in a tunnel.
Scott: He just wants to digitize them which is all you need to do and he's like it only caused this much to digitize a half Hour of anime, you know.
Scott: instead of giving money to this crap over here.
Scott: Maybe we should preserve this.
Rym: Well, it's the problem of any new art form I mean any new media.
Rym: but so many movies were lost just because people didn't care or by the time they cared It was too late or the medium was bad and they had no way to make a good copy.
Scott: Well, it's not too late, right?
Scott: Let's get some movement and preserve these old consoles and you know old.
Rym: Is there a movement already you can link to or are we trying to start the movement?
Scott: No Well, I mean there is sort of right there.
Scott: actually I forget what University is in California I think because gaming is actually new media like gaming.
Rym: There's.
Rym: It's like we invented movie.
Scott: There is a department at this university that is actually trying to preserve MMOs Which is why it's a research kind of thing.
Scott: They're like, how do we preserve this MMO?
Scott: It's like even if we save the copies of the server and client software and we emulate the machines It could run on so that we can run this software.
Scott: you go to the world and it's empty so it won't be anything like it was when the world was there.
Scott: and even if we have like a Recording of the world as it was of all the players and everything They played then, you know, you still wouldn't interact.
Scott: so you wouldn't be able to preserve the play experience.
Scott: It's lost forever like tribes - right we have the software but the play experience is lost forever, right?
Rym: Well, the people who cared about the game bought it, but they still haven't preserved the original play experience.
Scott: It is almost no one in there.
Scott: You know, it's not.
Scott: you can't go and experience the way it was.
Scott: You know play the game as it was meant to be played as it was in the 90s.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: that's gone It's lost probably forever and these people are researching how to preserve MMOs Right for all time, you know.
Scott: Because I guess you know, that's a my actually that's honestly a much more difficult problem than just preserving Saturn games.
Rym: in the very least however, PCS as long as the Documentation on how these old consoles are made is there and people have at least digitized the ROMs of the games.
Rym: Then they're not lost forever.
Rym: So long as someone can get access to that original spec.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is it's like we've got them Right.
Scott: I mean the ROMs are sort of out there and the emulators sort of exist.
Scott: But it's not it's still.
Scott: it needs to go all the way right?
Scott: Because you know, it could become.
Scott: you know It's.
Scott: it's a little bit shaky right now.
Scott: Well, this could be just like Situation.
Scott: we forgot how to make that.
Rym: look at the angry video game nerdy.
Rym: Well when he does the cinema ask her stuff and he talks about you know This old horror movie by whatever name is lost, but here's what we know about it.
Rym: Imagine it 40 years from now He's like.
Rym: there is this game called Zelda 2 and we've got it.
Rym: There was a game called Zelda 1 that came before but no one has a working copy of it to this day.
Rym: Yeah, imagine if that was the world.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: I love it when the fat guy gets the ball and tries to run with it in football.
Scott: I think this is my theory of football popularity already I you know, there are many reasons that football is you know, and shut up soccer people, right?
Scott: Save that for another time that football is the most popular sport in the United States, right?
Scott: And I think there are many factors such as there are so few games that the importance of any one given game is incredibly high.
Rym: Efficiating is very good in the game is actually, you know, it's mostly.
Scott: it's mostly good.
Scott: It has issues though It's on network television as opposed to cable television.
Scott: so you can actually see every game.
Scott: Right, even if you don't pay for cable or you know have to you don't have to watch it like so frequently You know, there's discrete units of play and very recognizable strategy and tactics.
Scott: But I think the number one reason that football is the most popular sport in the United States is the fat guy gets the ball is because Right, unlike other sports on any given play and you know as the old saying goes any given Sunday Almost anything can happen.
Scott: right, you know, most plays are boring hand the ball off guy runs gets tackled.
Scott: Okay, but anything could have happened right?
Scott: Oh, there's so many ludicrous things that could happen.
Scott: Whereas in baseball, you know, what could happen?
Scott: He could hit a home run.
Scott: He could steal home.
Scott: There aren't that many possibilities.
Scott: But in football just any game even the most boring game between two lame teams almost, you know There are very few games where nothing exciting happens ever.
Scott: go to NFL comm videos Click on highlights of any game and there are highlights for every game.
Scott: So basically them is gonna be really good for non football people.
Rym: But I will say this because we say this a lot if you don't think you're a sports person It's a very kind of stereotypical thing for nerds and gamers to be like.
Rym: I don't care about sports and anyone who hate you like sports is stupid and sports are bad for stupid people Aside from the fact that sports nerds are just as nerdy as you.
Rym: but about sports football is basically a game.
Scott: Yeah, I mean football, you know, if you really examined it from the right angle is perhaps the nerdiest of all sports.
Scott: You know, I guess not all sports cuz I mean banana grams is technically a sport.
Scott: also chess boxing yes, but but but is the nerdiest popular profession?
Scott: to explain what happened?
Rym: a Gigantic fat guy like one of the big fat not people that people down keep people from going past me guy a guy who was Never gonna touch the football in his career.
Rym: It's an accident.
Rym: Maybe bounces off of him.
Scott: I know most circumstances.
Scott: when this guy is playing because he's an offensive lineman He's not allowed to get the ball except under crazy circumstances like someone fumbles it and he picks it up So he gets the ball.
Rym: He's your.
Rym: he normally doesn't get it and You'll.
Rym: even if you've never seen a football game in your life It is obvious that he is not the kind of guy who's supposed to have the ball.
Rym: He runs in a way that guys like that.
Rym: it it's pretty great.
Scott: He just keeps going and all the other little guys can't knock him down Even if you don't care about the game situation or what it means, right?
Scott: Just the physicality of it.
Scott: watching this guy run with the ball is an audience.
Rym: They can't even tackle him properly because he's got too much momentum.
Rym: Two guys have to jump and just push him forward simultaneously and hope he falls over.
Scott: I wish he would have made it to the end zone though.
Scott: That would have been.
Rym: He might not have been able to stop.
Scott: Yeah, so anyway interrelated to make it double football things of the day, right because football season is almost over here, right?
Scott: You know, even if you don't care about football.
Scott: This is a video of the top 10 memorable NFL coaching rants because you see in football after every game There's countless press conferences for both teams and the coaches come out and you know, they get questioned and they say stuff, right?
Scott: So, of course in many years of football some coaches have said many things that are funny or interesting or they got really mad.
Rym: All right I was familiar with made a little under half of these just because I don't watch a lot of sports.
Rym: compared to Scott Especially I never watched the pre or post anything ever.
Scott: Yeah, the pre or post things are usually just really bad.
Rym: but what to Scott's thing if you're even if you're not a sports person?
Rym: These are the kinds of like shared meme lines like when you're a gamer and you make some Starcraft joke about a zerg rush in an Unrelated situation.
Rym: sports people do the same thing with these, right?
Scott: So there's three.
Scott: there's three of these that you really have to pay attention to right?
Scott: The first one is playoffs.
Scott: playoffs He's like, we're like if we win another game.
Scott: playoffs, right, so the other ones that are the most important right are You've got You play to win the game.
Scott: You don't play to just play it right.
Scott: you play to win the game.
Scott: So, you know, that's something that you can use right in your gaming.
Scott: nerdery Right is if some if you're like cheesing it up with your camping counter-strike and someone's like stop camping Just be like you play to win the game.
Scott: All right, and I we did it, you know, I fully agree with that 100%.
Rym: Yeah game mechanics and mechanism design We've I mean we basically make the straight-up argument that if you're not playing to win a game You are griefing.
Scott: It's like if you're not playing a widget just get out Right, and then the third one, you know, it's it's the number one here, right?
Scott: You'll hear this.
Scott: there's people saying this a lot is they are who we thought they were And if that's not a catchphrase that you can apply to all parts of your life, I don't know what is.
Rym: So very briefly the meta moment the GeekNights book club book is Michio Kaku's hyperspace.
Rym: the next live event We will be doing is MAGFest Four days of non-stop games and concerts at the Hilton Alexandria in Virginia and if you're in New York City when we're at mag fest you can go to recess.
Rym: nerd two days of RPGs and tabletop games but January 13th through 16th That is the weekend at mag fest.
Rym: We will be doing three panels.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: One is our panel.
Rym: It's an old one.
Rym: I'm revamped a little bit.
Rym: losing should be fun.
Rym: Alrighty, and we're also part of the mag nine.
Rym: nine gaming intellectuals We're gonna sit out with.
Scott: I'm an intellectual now with other experts.
Scott: I'm playing computer science degree.
Rym: two of the panels that this group is putting on will just be panelists.
Rym: So it's not like us doing a lecture.
Rym: It's all sitting there with other people with whom we may disagree publicly and possibly angrily because there John St.
Scott: John's also gonna be there and so is James Rolfe.
Scott: James Rolfe It's gonna be a nerd fest.
Rym: But we're gonna be on technical changes in game design and we're gonna be on achievements and metagaming.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: We got to say about that.
Rym: I hope somebody's like man.
Rym: team fortress 2 is so much more fun after they added hats.
Rym: Yeah, gonna bring up dad's waiting for that race at the roof on fire at clown pistols all a whole bandolier of clown pistols.
Scott: Oh shit, we need some of those.
Scott: Can we get those in Virginia?
Rym: I have no idea.
Rym: Anyway, we're also gonna be a paxies and all that stuff.
Rym: But it's down the road.
Rym: mag fest is what you got to care about right now And we're almost out of gig night's t-shirts.
Rym: So once they sell out we're gonna order more.
Rym: and So in 1983 the game was made we're one year old about a guy who drops bombs.
Rym: dude That was pretty much it.
Rym: Bomberman was a single-player game where you drop bombs.
Scott: Well, I mean it wasn't just that you drop bombs right cuz in kaboom you catch bombs.
Rym: Yeah But spiritual successor one might say.
Scott: well in terms of games with the theme of bowling ball candle Right, but I mean the first.
Scott: the thing about barman is you drop a bomb and it blows up into four directions because the square Grid, right?
Scott: But what you have to do is you have to drop the bomb and then you have to hide because your own bomb Hurts you.
Scott: and actually I think that's the one that is the of all the different things in Bomberman.
Scott: cuz everything is like 70 plus Bomberman games and they all have incredible amounts of differences and modes and power-ups and items and all.
Scott: there's so so much variation.
Scott: but the Fundamental thing that makes Bomberman Bomberman is that your weapon of attack is is the dangerous bomb That can also hurt you.
Rym: It is not always the dangerous bomb It is a dangerous bomb.
Rym: that could in fact be a dangerous bomb.
Scott: Yeah, right, but I mean, you know what other in what other video game right like it?
Scott: You know until they came out with games like say quake where you could hurt yourself with your own grenades, right?
Scott: But even then while you can hurt yourself with your own grenades or rockets that isn't like the fundamental gameplay mechanic Right.
Scott: That's just an aspect of the game.
Scott: most of the time You're probably using some other gun anyway, and or you're shooting a rocket far away from you.
Rym: Well, that does get to the point with the simple mechanic.
Rym: I think the reason Bomberman is so Loved so ported so remade forever and continuously is because they're milking it for money in Japan big time.
Rym: one One was released on the Xbox like just a little while ago.
Scott: It was actually the second one that was released on the Xbox.
Rym: is that it's one of those rare Simple kind of discreet easily understood easy to learn difficult to master direct fucking versus multiplayer games?
Scott: Yeah, I think that's the one thing.
Scott: is it started out as a single-player game But I think was it in Bomberman 2 or was it in Super Bomberman where they first added the multiplayer aspect?
Scott: I'm not sure where the first place that I experienced the multiplayer was in the Super Bomberman Right with a two-player versus on the Super Nintendo.
Rym: For me was I remember the turbo graphics is where I was playing it.
Scott: The turbo graphics is a very popular version of our man.
Rym: That's oddly enough.
Rym: when I was working that might have
Scott: been Bomberman 93
Rym: when I was working at IBM one of my co-workers I went out to dinner with like him and his wife and everything and the wife went away and then he was like I got Something and he whips out his old turbo graphics and we played some Bomberman.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: But yeah, the thing with Bomberman is that they mean the very first video games.
Scott: I mean, I guess space war wasn't but pong was a direct versus game.
Scott: You know my paddle versus your pad warlords right warlords is the direct versus game.
Scott: So the Bomberman is by no means the first direct versus game.
Scott: nor did it rep You know, but what it is is it's sort of when it comes to many players, right?
Scott: I mean warlords had four but Bomberman can be a zillion right.
Scott: and when it comes to like direct Fighting you like ultra direct, you know, I mean there were games, you know If you think about it back in those days.
Scott: in terms of ultra direct versus video games I mean you had your sports games and you're fighting games, you know.
Scott: And sometimes you had a turn-based strategy game or maybe the real-time one later on.
Scott: But in terms of direct gaming Mike every other game and every other genre was not direct versus.
Scott: you know If you know pong is a sports game, right?
Scott: Racing games or sports games most games were.
Rym: you know You play them someone else plays you compare the score as in Mario, right?
Scott: or there were co-op games, right?
Scott: Which is contra which disappeared and came back River City Ransom, right?
Scott: So in those days if it wasn't a sports game and it wasn't a fighting game It wasn't a direct versus game unless it was Bomberman, you know and even Tetris is sort of an indirect versus.
Rym: in a way Bomberman is proof of something else because these These sorts of direct games definitely resonate with people who are gamers because they're.
Rym: they're very much more like what we call sports.
Rym: Four people playing Bomberman has the same feeling as four people playing dodgeball or four people playing, you know any sport?
Scott: Yeah, I mean there was super dodgeball, but that's a sports game.
Rym: That's a great game But only two player true and you know their remakes recently.
Rym: that kind of crappy.
Rym: I think that dodgeball franchise is dead.
Rym: But part of is the Bomberman is so simple and yet as simple as it is The like.
Rym: the skill cap is surprisingly high.
Rym: You can be very very good at Bomberman.
Scott: Well, I think part of the help the reason that the skill cap is so high is because there's just so much variation Right.
Scott: It's like Tetris.
Scott: they keep bringing up variants of it Bomberman They can you know, there are many variants of our men all over the place But they can really milk that fundamental game with only slight changes very very far, right?
Scott: They come up with new power-ups new maps.
Scott: maps have gimmicks, right?
Scott: You know, they can bring power-ups that do their down power-ups.
Scott: They can get viruses and then they can think of all these different viruses for you to get right?
Scott: They can just keep going and keep going without changing the fundamental rules of the game much like Pac Man.
Scott: CE DX doesn't really change the fundamental rules of Pac Man other than adding bombs, right?
Scott: Bomberman you can mix it up so much without changing the fundamental rule set so that anyone who's played any Bomberman Ever can pick up one and play and what surprises me the most is when we go to play a Bomberman because it's the ultimate party game.
Scott: almost Every time there will be every time there's like what's Bomberman?
Scott: I don't know how to play and I'm like what the hell.
Rym: now they watch you play and they're really confused.
Rym: But if you just put a controller in anyone's hands and you're like, press a to drop a bomb Yeah and use the stick to move they'll figure it out and reveal fast and then they'll have a lot of fun.
Scott: Yeah, they'll have a lot of fun after 20 minutes of blowing themselves up.
Rym: It's also.
Rym: it's a game that is it does the right balance of you know Because the bombs hurt you you can't just try to kill the other players.
Rym: The best strategy is to let them kill themselves.
Scott: Yeah, it's like unless they're good in other direct versus games, right?
Scott: You know, it's always like a fighting game.
Scott: It's always about the attack and the defense and some people might go all out attack Some people might do defense and attack at the opportunity.
Rym: There's really no defense Bomberman.
Scott: There's really no defense except for the shield mode, right?
Rym: So in the DS version, yeah, or like the barrier Yeah, maybe you play the like the bomb to prevent someone from running around there.
Scott: There isn't much defense and you can't just sit still because you need to get the power-ups.
Scott: You have to bomb right.
Scott: if you just sit still and wait for someone to come to you It's not gonna work out too well, right?
Scott: It's as you're either gonna get killed at best double suicide.
Scott: Do you have to go yet right away?
Scott: You have to get power-ups and then before you know it you're in with someone else and someone's good.
Scott: You got someone's gonna die from bombs.
Rym: I love watching all the different play styles.
Rym: Like I tend to either Be very particular like I'll drop bombs at intervals and I'll try to box people in or I'll leave bombs at a bunch of different Places as I'm running and kind of random intervals so that they don't set each other off.
Rym: So they're blowing up like boom boom boom boom boom all over the place.
Rym: I'm trying to confuse my opponents But a lot of other people unnamed front row crew people will basically just run next to you hitting a as fast as they can.
Scott: That is not a good idea in a game where your weapon is a bomb.
Scott: If your weapon was say a kicking foot or a punching fist That is a great idea.
Scott: Kendra Rose got that down when your weapon is a bomb Running right up next to the enemy and dropping the bomb.
Scott: I mean think about when you want to play a bar man.
Scott: If you want to get skilled at it think of the bomb as a grenade that you can't throw.
Scott: So you basically pull the pin unless you get the power glove a true.
Scott: But basically you pull the pin and drop it on the ground, right?
Scott: If you're gonna fight someone with grenades, would you run up to them pull the pin and drop it on the ground?
Scott: Hell no, that's the last thing you would want to do.
Rym: sometimes it works.
Rym: What in your opinion?
Rym: we're debating this a lot.
Rym: we're trying out different versions because there's so many bomber meds.
Rym: What is the best bomber man?
Rym: because the newest one which I just bought so we can Scott plays?
Scott: Yeah battle fest for the 360.
Scott: Yeah bomber man live battle fest is not the greatest.
Rym: It's at best a mediocre offering.
Rym: I'm actually extremely disappointed in this game.
Rym: I only bought it because I don't have any other bomber man.
Rym: It's just the style is kind of tacked on the game is kind of slow.
Rym: It's got a couple of problems.
Rym: It's not that configurable.
Rym: It's just yeah, they're putting in the minimum effort.
Rym: They're like, yeah, we made another bomber man.
Rym: People are gonna buy it.
Rym: They're not trying anymore.
Scott: Yeah The biggest problem here is that there's like 70 plus bomber man games and a lot of them weren't released in the u.s.
Scott: Did you know there were super bomber man?
Scott: One, two, three, four five three was only released in Japan.
Scott: in Europe Four and five were Japan only.
Rym: Yeah, you think people get the hell jerks with the Final Fantasy situation.
Rym: That's got nothing on this.
Scott: Yeah, we didn't.
Scott: even it's Final Fantasy.
Scott: We got the games with different numbers here, right?
Scott: We don't even get the damn games, you know.
Scott: They were like online bomber men that were only available in Japan and Korea apparently in Europe.
Scott: How come I didn't get to play the online bomber man?
Scott: What the fuck in Europe?
Rym: The ZX spectrum version was not called bomber man.
Rym: It was called Eric and the floaters.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: I mean, we're learning all this from Wikipedia, by the way, or don't?
Rym: Pepe in Los Globos There was also.
Scott: there's also a thing I only recently found out about while I was researching for the show called bomber man be demand and Bomberman be demand isn't?
Scott: is more like that Bakugan with the spinning tops only you shoot marbles.
Scott: It's like marble shooting toys.
Scott: I don't know how they're related to bomber man, but they are somehow I don't get it.
Rym: One of the early bomber man games was first-person.
Scott: what?
Scott: yeah I mean there were some 3d ones for The n64 and such and the GameCube that were 3d bomber man in 1984.
Rym: Whoa was first person?
Rym: what the crap?
Scott: Yeah, how would you even know where the bomb?
Scott: I mean you turn around a corner you turn right to look for it to scan to see.
Scott: is there a bomb there?
Rym: Well, that was on the MSX.
Rym: I mean, okay.
Scott: It's like you're gonna get bombed.
Rym: I would like to see.
Rym: you know, if you remade bomber man in unity, you basically could be like, alright, it's topped out Alright, it's FPS instead.
Scott: Yeah anyway But yeah, so I mean if I had to pick the best bomber man I mean the best bar man that I personally have played and have had the most fun with I think Honestly is the GameCube one which I believe is bomber man evolutions
Rym: the one
Scott: Because we played that GameCube one down at the shore and we fresh the one that has gold bomber.
Scott: Yeah, right Yeah, that's that one.
Scott: So that is actually.
Rym: that is a pretty good one I would put at the top of the ones I've played regularly the DS one because it's so quick to get an awesome game.
Scott: Yes, one it has advantage over it because a it's portable, right?
Scott: Be you can get eight people at once instead of just for my god, right?
Scott: But the DS one I mean it has some good modes that you won't find anywhere else, but it also has some modes I really don't care.
Rym: Here's the trouble.
Rym: It has better modes than the current one on the Xbox.
Scott: That's true because the like the Xbox has a mode that sounds at first to be the greatest mode just team crown.
Scott: But DS one has get the crown which is much better which isn't far superior mode, right?
Scott: So But yeah, the GameCube one still has you know, really good modes and stuff and it's you know It's a pretty much all-around bar, man.
Rym: But the thing is if you see people at conventions like out in the wild like when we used to go to uber-con every year They'd be playing this in the lobby.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: It's always the Sega Saturn Is it?
Scott: yeah, I don't know but I mean basically my Reese.
Scott: I haven't played the Sega Saturn one until yesterday.
Scott: Let's I was talking about emulating it.
Scott: But yeah, apparently one of the most heralded Bomberman games is the Sega Saturn version which can support 10 player verse Right and just watch a video of the multi the 10 player verse multiplayer in Sega Saturn Bomberman and you will know immediately if you know anything about Bomberman that that is a damn good power.
Rym: Now this is my trouble with Bomberman live battle fest.
Rym: one The maps are all way too small.
Rym: and two, they're all tilted 3d like way tilted.
Rym: I want to.
Rym: just I want a top-down view.
Rym: not every game needs to be like super.
Rym: check it out.
Rym: We're two and a half D. It only hurts the game It does not.
Scott: I mean the thing is even if you make your game two and a half D Right, you can still put your camera directly on the side or just give me the I changing it.
Rym: But they don't because they don't care because people buy it anyway.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's like they don't need to put that much effort into making a party game You know to cover all these bases as they do have to put into effort to make say You know an FPS that is meant for a competition.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is RTS.
Rym: who's competing with Bomberman Bomberman?
Scott: Yeah, all the 70 other Bomberman games are competing with every new Bomberman game And I think that's like.
Scott: should you buy the new Bomberman battle fest?
Scott: You can still buy the previous Xbox Bomberman.
Scott: It's still up there.
Scott: You could buy you know Bomberman for your Wii instead.
Scott: I think that's a better one.
Rym: That we don't have is the pac-man championship edition DX equivalent for Bomberman, that's absolutely.
Scott: I think whoever worked on pac-man ced-x needs to go and I know it's.
Scott: I think it's a different company, right?
Scott: That's Hudson.
Scott: But yeah, but they need to go over and wearing pie studio.
Scott: Maybe Namco's one.
Scott: Namco should buy Hudson and make Bomberman awesome.
Scott: the way they've made pac-man awesome.
Scott: Oh shit what I get all over that.
Rym: It was pie they're making.
Rym: they made the new Bomberman battle fest.
Rym: they never made any other Bomberman Mmm, so they're probably probably.
Rym: I don't know why but they basically just made a kind of crummy port of the previous game by whoever.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, there's actually there's a Wii Bomberman.
Scott: That's not.
Scott: I think battle fest is actually also on the Wii But there's actually a previous WiiWare Bomberman.
Scott: that's on the Wii.
Scott: That's not a bad one You know, it's not as good as the game.
Rym: I think you can get the turbo graphics one on the virtual.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you can do that too.
Rym: You can get the turbo graphics, but I was not that good though I mean it was five player which is a big deal, but there's not that much going on for it.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, this you know Bomberman multiplayer is really where the action is.
Scott: The thing is there is single-player Bomberman, you know pretty much almost most of the Bomberman releases have single-player.
Scott: In fact the original one there was single-player only and basically it was these bad guys going around the map.
Scott: You had to bomb them without bombing yourself and you had to find the exit.
Scott: But if you bomb the exit bad guy got angry and bad guys came out.
Scott: Then you had to kill them and then get me exit bad guys.
Rym: I was like those little balloons or the.
Scott: yeah, actually pretty challenging to play single-player Bomberman It's.
Scott: it's not an easy game and it is a good game.
Scott: But you know, it's not multiplayer.
Scott: around me there's also What's it called the huh?
Scott: Trouble.
Scott: yeah, I forget you forget you got nothing Had it.
Rym: what a game a Bomberman game.
Scott: Oh, yeah Yeah, there's the Bomberman games that are that are sort of like, you know, they're.
Scott: they're not like the other Bomberman games, right?
Scott: It's like there's the 3d one on the 64 and there's also a 3d one of the GameCube where it's like Third-person shooter almost where Bomberman.
Rym: Yeah, you don't have to say remember mega the Mega Man game where you fight a fire in 3d Mega Man Legends.
Scott: Yeah That's basically it's the.
Scott: it's the Mega Man Legends of Bomberman.
Rym: I played Mega Man Legends by accident.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I modded.
Rym: my thing is one to play here and I had to.
Rym: I needed a game to test.
Scott: so weird.
Scott: I always had the idea that Mega Man's Legends was hated.
Scott: good and I hated it too.
Scott: And then Mega Man Legends 3 was announced more recently and suddenly all those people came out of the woodwork.
Scott: They're like, yeah Mega Man Legends.
Scott: I'm like what terrible like who liked it.
Scott: It's like you like it.
Scott: now suddenly what?
Rym: Maybe they always liked it.
Scott: I I don't get it.
Scott: I don't get it.
Scott: Yeah, there's you know, this puzzle the bar read be demand and all these.
Scott: there's all these Bomberman games that are not Straight-up Bomberman.
Scott: I cannot accept, you know, just you know get about because what I want is the.
Rym: It's like.
Scott: it's like the x-com third-person shooter, right?
Scott: It's like who wants that?
Rym: because I mean, you know, we just had it's like a sport and everything.
Rym: But this is proof if why couldn't rampart have had the same fruit.
Rym: Why aren't there like 30 rampart games over the last decades?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I mean it could have been the exact same thing just incremental improvement art.
Rym: another rampart.
Scott: We got eight cats like I don't you know, I mean there's a point where too much is too much, right?
Scott: I mean you can remake something too many times and then it's like okay stop remaking it.
Scott: But I do think a game that is a perennial, you know thing like that needs to be remade.
Scott: There should be a Tetris on every platform, right?
Scott: There should be a Bomberman on every platform and when you bring it to a new platform You have to make it better than it was previous, but you don't have.
Scott: I'm not asking for a pac-man CEX revolution Although I am.
Scott: I would mind that it just needs to be the best Bomberman.
Scott: yet It doesn't need to be.
Rym: they're almost like seasons of Bomberman Like.
Rym: this is the season of Bomberman and everyone gets good at it.
Rym: Then the next season they change the rules.
Rym: It's different Bomberman.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So like how the mahjong card is different every year for the Jewish ladies You know, there's some.
Rym: there's a model with the direct versus games like Bomberman or if you remade rampart?
Rym: What if instead of buying the game?
Rym: it was a pac-man DX situation where you bought a subscription and Every three years the official new version for all the tournaments for that three years span came out.
Scott: I don't think the thing is there's not exactly a hot tournament circuit for Bomberman.
Rym: You could make it I. There is a hot like mid-level convention circuit of Bomberman.
Rym: You go to any gaming con.
Rym: There's a Bomberman tournament.
Rym: You're gonna win like a hundred dollar gift certificate.
Scott: Yeah, Bomberman would make a great omega-thon final round.
Rym: Oh Man, oh, yeah or rampart.
Rym: I have a three-way.
Scott: Anyway, there's also You know the Bomberman the single-player games.
Scott: there are plots in them.
Scott: In fact, some of the games including the Saturn one have like an anime intro and lots of animated videos in them.
Rym: Oh, look a bowling ball candle.
Rym: Yeah, but this is my power.
Scott: The plot really is like it's.
Scott: so it just completely mixes up between games.
Scott: It really there's no continuity to it.
Scott: It's not like Sonic Sonic the Hedgehog or Mario where you can actually sort of like be like, okay This is the store Zelda where you can be like, okay, this is the story, right?
Scott: Even though even those stories are kind of choppy.
Scott: This story is basically non-existent, you know, Mega Man has the story Bomberman has It's just you know Colors on each different game that are slightly different.
Scott: There's also I don't know people remember this right?
Scott: There's two Bomberman games that actually I played mostly before my college days.
Scott: There's Bomberman GB, which is a Game Boy Bomberman for the original Game Boy But it actually came out late in the Game Boy's life like right before the Game Boy Color appeared and it actually has this Indiana Jones theme to it.
Scott: I don't know if it has any multiplayer.
Scott: If it did I never played it.
Scott: But as Indiana Jones theme and it's actually a pretty good Bomberman that I think is sort of lost and forgotten.
Scott: the way Wario 2 Is lost and forgotten.
Scott: it actually came around out around the same time as Wario 2 if I remember.
Rym: That was a good game.
Scott: It was also this PC version of Bomberman that I bought Called Atomic Bomberman.
Rym: and the thing with Atomic Bomberman is I remember we all bought it and tried to make the multiplayer.
Rym: Yeah, I found it in the discount bin.
Rym: So I bought a couple more CDs Yeah, and then we never got it to work.
Scott: you use IPX networking only.
Scott: Yeah But what it is?
Rym: no, no, no, remember that was when we were accused by the neighbors of hacking.
Scott: No, that was because I was using.
Rym: it was also cuz I have likes on half-life.
Rym: We'd set up IPX for a bunch of stuff.
Scott: Yeah, man IPX and their firewall went.
Rym: oh my god, that's a blast from the flask.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway zone alarm.
Scott: Anyway the Was I saying right.
Scott: so Atomic Bomberman is a weird Bomberman that I think no one remembers really.
Scott: But the thing about it was it was a PC game.
Scott: The the guys were shaped like Bomberman, you know with space helmets and whatever, but they were not styled like cute Happy Bomberman, right, you know Bomberman is like white bomber.
Scott: I think in Japan.
Scott: I found out his name is Shiro ban right and Basically, he's like the cheerful hero right and that describes Bomberman exactly, right?
Scott: He's like yay bombs.
Scott: All right, that's Bomberman, but this it was like dark.
Scott: It was like yeah bombs atomic bombs.
Scott: Yeah, it was you know, it was dark Bomberman, but it wasn't completely dark.
Scott: It was just dark.
Scott: And but the thing about a Tom Barman despite its darkness and despite its sort of pixel ish DOS early Windows game kind of graphics It actually had an insane number of game modes and maps and Customizability because it was a PC game.
Scott: You can get your hands on it.
Scott: Unlike, you know other Bomberman games.
Scott: They're just console You can't do anything to them.
Scott: and the result of that was that it had ridiculous modes and the one mode I remember that was the most popular I've never seen in any other Bomberman ever is Wally bomb mode.
Scott: and Wally bomb mode is basically there's an impenetrable wall down the middle of the map and there's two teams one on the left and one on the right and Everyone has the gloves so everyone can throw bombs to the other side And that's Wally bomb mode.
Rym: That's pretty good.
Scott: I've never seen that mode in any other game except the Tom apartment.
Scott: so really what I would really like more than anything is I think the perfect Bomberman would be a PC Bomberman released on Steam That was as customizable and had as many modes as atomic Bomberman right with the mod ability of a PC game, you know in terms of maps and characters and power-ups and all these sorts of things and game mode rules and Bring it back to the real original cute Bomberman graphics and not the scary dark evil Bomberman.
Rym: Well, there is another low-hanging fruit.
Rym: I mean, you know our egregiously unrealized potential panel from fax.
Rym: Well, what are you complain about the most?
Rym: the fact that we don't have just good DS games with the shared screen on the TV And everyone's got their own screen.
Scott: That would be a good game as if you had a Bomberman much like Pac Man verse on the GameCube.
Rym: If four friends sit down with four DS's and there's a big man aiming too low.
Scott: eight DS's 16 DS's you can.
Scott: only it can only handle eight technologically.
Rym: Yeah, we could write something.
Rym: No, you can't.
Rym: they could do something.
Scott: It only supports eight.
Scott: It's the limit in the wireless bandwidth besides the Wii's that we have a new Wii eventually Maybe but right now with the technology that exists today Somebody could make an eight player Bomberman where you have eight DS's.
Scott: everyone has a DS right and you don't need a cable.
Scott: So it's not a Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles situation.
Scott: You can't complain because if you complain you don't have to buy a cable and what you don't have a DS.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: Right and you'll need one Wii and one disc to load up the game on the Wii.
Scott: Right and then you can have eight people playing Bomberman where they can see their stuff on their DS screen.
Scott: But also there's the main screen on the television and you could play ridiculous Ridiculous Bomberman with that kind of setup, right?
Scott: It would be off the hook, but no one's made it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's a no-brainer.
Rym: but then again, it's not a no-brainer for making money Because games like that I mean Crystal Chronicles was an important game Zelda Four Swords those were really pushing the boundaries and what console gaming could be and Every game company in the world has said yeah, that's not worth as much money as things like Wii Sports.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I could Just make my own right because Bomberman is one of the easiest games to make in the world.
Scott: I mean, it's it's pretty straightforward, right?
Scott: I mean they made it for the NES I mean demons to diamonds.
Scott: Yeah, that's also really straightforward.
Scott: But it's like I don't want to get sued here and it's pretty much.
Scott: You know, there were have been Bomberman clones in the past.
Scott: I mean, I remember there was some.
Scott: I can't remember the name of that game.
Scott: I think I think it might have been like atomic bomb man or Call it bowling ball candle.
Scott: Yeah, it was something.
Scott: it wasn't called Bomberman But it was a single-player game that had the same mechanic.
Scott: It was obviously stolen from Bomberman where you drop the bomb and you run away and it blows up and the whole thing, right?
Scott: And there have been quite a few clones, but none of them are really gotten anywhere.
Scott: and it really even if I cloned it It wouldn't feel right playing Bomberman if it didn't have.
Scott: you know, white bomber.
Rym: Well, there's that air of Legitimacy like when I when you beat someone at a real Bomberman game you at least know Alright that this was technically a legit Bomberman like the Emperor Nintendo or the Emperor Hudson.
Scott: Yeah That is because the theme because the styling of atomic Bomberman is so dossish and dark when you win at it Doesn't feel like a legit Bomberman game.
Scott: I think that's its problem right?
Scott: is?
Scott: it's almost like, you know It's like you can play baseball with a referee or you can just go down to the field with a stick and a ball And it's like.
Scott: does that really count if you win?
Scott: Not really.
Rym: I do encourage all of you though listeners a lot a lot of people and there's even article on slashdot about the death of Like shared screen co-op and it's true to a big degree.
Rym: One of the greatest gaming experiences you can have is to physically have two or three other people in the room with you Playing a single screen direct versus video game.
Rym: Mm-hmm And I think a lot of people are missing that experience today and you're really as a gamer doing yourself a disservice.
Scott: Yeah, I mean in terms of games where there's multiple players like more than two in direct versus, right?
Scott: So the fighting games are out and the sports games are out because those are all two players, right?
Scott: This is for player on modern systems, right?
Scott: You got Mario Tennis, but that's two on two co-op, right?
Scott: You got Power Stone, but that died right.
Scott: Power Stone was the shit.
Rym: Oh my god, we should do a show on Power Stone?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I haven't really played power.
Rym: I played the ever-living crap out of that when I used to go to like anime central.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Power Stone is the shit that needs to come back in a major way.
Scott: It's good for the same reasons as Bomberman right?
Scott: You got like Smash Brothers.
Scott: That's a fighting game kind of right, you know There's really not a whole lot in the department of one screen.
Scott: Not a split screen like they do with the halo or whatever.
Scott: right one screen more than two players Every man for himself everyone versus everyone else.
Scott: direct, you know.
Scott: You know competition video game.
Rym: Well, there's something about many more than Bomberman something about being in the same room where the trash talk is right there.
Rym: It is intimate.
Rym: There's no way around it.
Rym: You can hear every groan every elbowing every blocking the screen as you're every hitting the other guy's controller.
Rym: I Don't know.
Rym: I grew up on that and I you know A lot of times.
Rym: there are aspects of so-called old-school gaming that I believe they made me the game I am today.
Rym: but at the same time I recognize that we cannot and should not want to go back to those days Because they did suck.
Scott: really, you know, but I think you know.
Scott: the point is what other game Can you find that has all those aspects that Bomberman has?
Scott: what I said that is current.
Rym: this one thing the the shared room Shared space experience we don't get now.
Rym: you can emulate it pretty well with if the Xbox had a mode.
Rym: Well, you can play Bomberman and it has the screens in along the top of the faces of everyone else.
Scott: You're playing with with the web with the webcam.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't think they have anything like that.
Scott: No, yeah, I mean Uno has it but I don't think Bomberman has that feature also.
Rym: This bothers me how annoying it is.
Rym: Like.
Rym: if you want to play this game online You're just like BAM and you just go.
Rym: you want to play the new Bomberman with like four or five people locally.
Rym: It's actually a giant pain in the ass to get everyone signed into a profile and it just it's good.
Rym: That is who it is actually.
Scott: one thing I think is advantageous for the Wii.
Scott: everyone's god we internet sucks and it does sucks bad.
Scott: But Xbox if you want to play locally, right?
Scott: It forces you because it's like uses your avatars or whatever to actually choose a profile for every player.
Scott: You have to create all these offline profiles for everyone.
Scott: you have to select them every time.
Rym: also a lot of games don't allow You to have like two people local playing against other people somewhere else.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of them are either all online or nothing online.
Scott: That's such a pain.
Scott: It's not cool.
Rym: Yeah It's just.
Rym: it's an example of how far we've come in gaming.
Rym: Like we make leaps and bounds and gaming is a million times better now than it was in some aspects.
Scott: I mean, this is this is a professionally made game But it's making the same kind of mistakes that we always yell at indie game companies for making but it shows you that it's not You know a problem to any to either or it's a problem in general
Rym: for
Scott: all of gaming.
Scott: people are missing very important details.
Rym: They are only mistakes from the perspective of good game design.
Rym: They are not mistakes from the perspective of making money.
Rym: That's right, because I'm sure there is no one who would have bought that.
Rym: Bomberman who said oh the multiplayer local doesn't work Exactly the way it should.
Rym: I'm not gonna buy that for a dollar.
Scott: I mean we tried the trial out which is one.
Scott: the one greatest thing about Xbox that beats everything else is every single game Has a free trial, but what we played it.
Rym: We're like, yeah Bomberman Let's just play the trial right now so we can just play it.
Scott: and then we were met after the trial.
Rym: after the trial I wasn't gonna buy it.
Scott: The only reason I didn't buy it because I bought this game.
Rym: I went from 100% buy to 90% not buy just from playing the trial once.
Rym: But then Aaron C was over and we needed a multiplayer game to play and we're sitting down.
Rym: I was like, let's play some goddamn Bomberman I just bought it right.
Scott: the thing is I already I have the Wii Bomberman the the first WiiWare one.
Scott: It's not it's not battle fest, which I think is coming to WiiWare.
Scott: It's the original WiiWare Bomberman and that will suffice for being the Bomberman at my house, you know.
Scott: So I don't need to buy the Xbox Bomberman.
Scott: I got the Wii Bom All right.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.