Rym: It's Thursday, July 22nd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight, our review of the book club book, The Lies of Locke Lamora.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we had this discussion just before doing the show.
Rym: Scott didn't want to do the news bit because he basically said, "Yeah, nothing happened.
Rym: I don't have
Rym: anything.".
Rym: So Scott, my question to you is, has nothing in the entire world, any news elicited any opinion whatsoever from you?
Scott: I'm scrolling on the Google News.
Scott: So if there is such a news, which there may be- So nothing.
Rym: You don't care about the fact that BP was basically caught.
Rym: You know when they were injecting all that stuff to try to kill the well?
Rym: The stuff they injected was toxic waste that they normally couldn't legally dump.
Rym: And supposedly, according to the news now, they used the kind of special permission they got- Is this on the real news or is this on the hippie news?
Scott: made up stuff?
Rym: This is on the real news.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Because I'm seeing lately a lot of- Did you see that Onion article?
Rym: they got picked up by a bunch of right wing blogs and people are taking it seriously about like- That happens like every day.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I've noticed something weird about that.
Rym: Is it just me or when the onion gets taken seriously, like someone's stupid and thinks it's real, why is it almost always the far right that takes it too seriously as opposed to the far left?
Scott: Because they're- You know what?
Rym: I was reading a- It's like they're both crazy, but I feel like they're crazy in like very pathologically different ways.
Scott: This reminds me of two things I read recently.
Scott: Number one, there were some people discussing that there's a- They always look for like discrimination in colleges, mostly because colleges brag about diversity.
Rym: So therefore- What was that one college where they caught them photoshopping black people into their- Right, exactly.
Scott: But you know, the colleges brag about diversity on campus, so therefore they get heavily scrutinized in terms of the actual diversity.
Scott: And it turns out that yes indeed, statistically speaking, a lot of these colleges, what they're doing is they're not discriminating against white people.
Scott: There's plenty of white people there, right?
Scott: Is they're discriminating against white people from the sticks?
Scott: You know, these right wing type people.
Scott: And like if you look- No, no, no.
Rym: Is it discrimination or is it just those are not the kind of people who tend to get into colleges?
Scott: So there was a study and it showed that Asian and white people, at least in the US, when they apply to colleges, if you want to be accepted, you need much better grades.
Scott: Whereas if you were something else, African-American, Hispanic, anything except white and Asian, you could actually get into the same school with much lower grades and you would be accepted.
Scott: And the thing was, is that actually also what they've noticed, which is the main problem here, these right wing people, right, is if you're a white person from the sticks, it's actually harder to get into the schools, right?
Scott: It's like they want to bring in and be able to say our campus is so diverse.
Scott: So they kick out the white people from the sticks and they bring in anyone else who's not white.
Rym: I think the real trouble is that the standards, at least for university, should be the same.
Rym: If you have the ability, go for it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't like, you know, they can brag about having a diverse campus or whatever, but that's just
Scott: B.S.,
Scott: right?
Scott: They should accept.
Scott: they should not.
Rym: That's marketing to the parents and the high school.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: They shouldn't even like, no.
Scott: When you're employing people in the real world, you're not allowed to even use that as criteria.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The college should be the same way.
Scott: They shouldn't even know what color you are.
Scott: Maybe they shouldn't be like, you know, they send in your application and you need to put down your name.
Scott: And sometimes they give stuff away like if your name is like, you know, like, you know, like my friend Luther Wang.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There is no question.
Rym: No question.
Scott: You know, you know, he's a Jew just from his name, you know, or like Tony Zhao.
Scott: Obviously, that guy is French.
Scott: There is no question.
Rym: So, you know, it is pronounced Thibodeau.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But the thing is, remember, the reason we had these sorts of affirmative policies before was to give people a shot to kind of reduce the built in discrimination from previous areas.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: it's like a Band-Aid and it's not curing the.
Scott: it's like you had a Band-Aid.
Scott: So you don't see that there's like this gaping wound.
Scott: And every time we lift up the Band-Aid, the wound is still there.
Scott: Well, it's like, look, yep.
Scott: If we it's like, oh, if we made a meritocracy, then the black people, there's still not it's.
Scott: And we still it's like.
Scott: basically we're hiding the fact that we can't fix the real problem.
Rym: I know it or didn't it.
Rym: I mean, is it not possible to say that it did a lot of good from the 60s and 70s where racism was so endemic of getting people onto an equal footing to the point where eventually we can pull these things back and say, all right, everyone starts with the same shot.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, you know, the public school situation is completely different from the university situation.
Scott: You know, I mean, basically the problem was then was that there were people who wanted to get into university and deserve to be in university, but couldn't because there really was outright horrible discrimination.
Scott: And we've mostly succeeded in getting rid of that.
Scott: And it's still out there and we still got to get rid of that shit.
Scott: But, you know, like there's still like golf courses that don't want people coming on and shit like that.
Rym: They don't want me to golf.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, they they'll be like, no women on this golf course.
Scott: There's still those still exist and it sucks ass.
Scott: But at the same time, right.
Scott: It's like, well, you're really just didn't do so well in high school.
Scott: And you're obviously, you know, not white.
Scott: So we're going to let you in anyway.
Scott: And then, you know, I want to see, you know, if they show me some, you know, this is, I don't know, is there a study on this?
Scott: I'd be very interested.
Rym: There's tons of studies on this.
Scott: No, no, no studies on whether those people actually do well.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: There's tons of studies.
Rym: by and large people who are given some sort of non merit based scholarship tend to not do well or not graduate compared to people who had merit based scholarships.
Scott: Oh, so they are actually not doing well.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, so again, so sadly, right?
Scott: Like I was going to say, I wish that the study would say that, look, we get them into college even though they didn't do so well in high school and then they do well.
Scott: So it, you know, it's not, it's okay to accept the people with the lower grades because it works out in the end.
Scott: You are actually helping them, but if they're not doing well in the college, well, it's like, ah, fuck.
Rym: But at the same time, no, because that's on average, what you're doing still is you're giving them a shot.
Rym: because think about how many people could get to could have gone to RIT if money weren't a factor and made it through that crazy ass school.
Rym: And at the same time, how many people got in because they had money and were allowed to stay, but sucked and eventually got kicked out anyway after they lost all their money.
Scott: It's also true.
Scott: But the thing is, right?
Rym: Isn't that almost a reverse discrimination?
Rym: You're saying, all right, you have money.
Scott: So we definitely, we definitely need to keep out the people who only have money and don't actually have talents and skills.
Rym: We also need to keep out the stupid people, which a lot of the people at RIT, a lot of our classmates were kind of stupid, not good at what they were in.
Scott: So, I mean, basically what's happening though is there are people in the sticks, right?
Scott: Who aren't getting in because, you know, and they're basically being discriminated against that way, at least statistically speaking, you know, look at this study.
Scott: Yeah, I got to go find these articles, but basically it's like if you're from the state, but could it also be that the people are stupider.
Rym: I'm guilty of this too.
Rym: So I'm going to say this straight up.
Rym: I have to find the article for you is code for, I am not going to follow up on this.
Rym: I'm going to hope you forget.
Scott: And if you raise it again, partially it was cause I read two articles in the same day that said the same thing from different people.
Rym: Oh, I've, I've, I've been in the same situation.
Rym: It's never that like, Oh, I'm losing this argument.
Rym: I'm going to make up an article and hope they forget.
Rym: It's always, I do have a source.
Rym: I don't remember it.
Rym: I don't care enough to go find it.
Scott: I don't really have an opinion on this.
Scott: It's just, I'm pointing out that like there's been recently, there's been a lot of talk about this.
Scott: Like, you know, people from the sticks are getting discriminated against.
Scott: And basically a lot of these, a couple of the articles were like, they were definitely opinion articles that were raging.
Scott: They were like, uh, evil, blah, discriminated.
Rym: What I would guess, what probably is going on independent of all this is that the quote unquote sticks, I mean, I couldn't say that schools are worse or better out there because I mean some of the richer parts of California have some of the worst performing schools in the country.
Rym: So that doesn't work really well, rich kids.
Rym: The saddest part is that in the end, socioeconomic status at birth seems to be the primary factor in later success.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And that's probably the worst.
Scott: That's what says, I already discussed that how that's, what's under the bandaid and that is what is not still not fixed.
Scott: We need some, we need to stop.
Scott: And the thing is, I think, you know, okay, we still haven't really figured out how to fix it.
Scott: It's a very difficult problem, but we're putting a whole idea how to fix it.
Scott: We're putting a whole lot of effort into fixing.
Scott: Is this your idea of give everyone a pile of money when they're at it?
Rym: I like that idea, but no, it's not that idea.
Scott: The problem is that we're putting all this effort into bandaid ideas and we're not actually putting the full effort into the act, curing the actual wound itself.
Scott: And we should just throw, you know, it's like we should just throw away the bandaid no matter how upset people will be that they have to stare at this gaping wound and concentrate our full effort on the true problem.
Rym: Wouldn't that work for the tea party now if we just said, all right, uh, you know, an unnamed state that doesn't want government interference.
Rym: Have fun without government subsidies.
Scott: I definitely think that there are no roads.
Scott: It's definitely my opinion that there is far too much federal subsidizing and I think the first ones that have to go would be say farms.
Rym: I would take the opposite tax.
Rym: government subsidy is fine in my eyes as long as people who use that subsidy understand that it's there and don't argue against government subsidy while simultaneously protecting their own subsidy.
Rym: That is the only part that bothers.
Scott: Well, that's how that seems to be how most people operate.
Scott: is they just, they don't actually have, you know, they watch TV and they get some idealistic political science viewpoint.
Scott: Like, you know, you know, it's better to be, you know, con fiscally conservative.
Scott: We should have low taxes and low spend, right?
Scott: And they get that idealistic viewpoint, but they don't actually hold that idealistic viewpoint.
Scott: The only viewpoint they actually hold is better for me and worse for everyone else.
Scott: Whatever's better for me is what's better.
Scott: So if I'm getting money from Medicare, Medicare is awesome, but high taxes, high taxes are always bad for me.
Scott: So you want low taxes always because that's better for me.
Scott: Those taxes old man, everyday people just want what's better for them.
Scott: That's what they actually want is better for them.
Scott: They don't actually hold the idealistic viewpoint unless they're arguing about something that has nothing to do with them, in which case they'll default to their idealistic, whatever it is.
Scott: I think we should, if it has something to do with them, then they will pick whatever's better for them.
Rym: I think we should make this a Thursday show.
Scott: The show's already done.
Rym: Now we got more.
Rym: We could, we could pick, I'll, I'll put forth my plan.
Scott: It was something else we were discussing too, and I completely forgot what it was.
Rym: That's a lot of news.
Rym: You said, Oh, there's no news.
Rym: There's nothing to talk about.
Rym: Why even do the front half of the show?
Rym: And I got 10 minutes out of you.
Scott: Oh, the other thing that I remember the other day or even more, it's still coming.
Scott: There was a thing on Boeing Boeing, right?
Rym: And it was talking about how I thought there was nothing on the internet.
Scott: I already blog commented on this side.
Scott: It's kind of redundant, but anyway, the, um, uh, they were talking about how like the feds in the States are actually doing more raids on bad farms that are doing raw food and raw milk and shit.
Scott: And I was like, I was like, yeah, but the article on Boeing Boeing specifically was talking about like this 12 year old girl.
Scott: And I think the quote was, don't take my computer.
Scott: I can't do my homework.
Scott: And I'm like, okay, bad.
Scott: Why are they taking some raw milk dude's computer?
Rym: Because they can don't, don't get me started seizures.
Scott: But on the other hand, of course, half the hippies in the fight or most of the hippies in the fucking comments on Boeing Boeing were like, let the people drink raw milk.
Scott: And I'm like, look, dude, I can respect your freedom to drink raw milk if you make your raw milk and you drink it.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: Hey, the law says that the government has the right to regulate commerce.
Rym: law is no law and morals are two separate things.
Scott: So, and then on top of that law argument, but completely separate from that law argument, here's my moral argument, right?
Scott: Someone might be stupid and they might be, have the right to be stupid.
Scott: And that might mean that they have the right to poison themselves with poison milk.
Scott: All right.
Scott: However, number one, they don't have the right to poison their children with poison milk.
Scott: And number two, even if someone is stupid, so stupid that they want to poison themselves with poison, raw milk, right?
Scott: They don't really deserve to die or get listeria or bar freaking E. coli because of that amount of stupidity.
Scott: That amount of fecal coliform, that amount of stupidity does not warrant that amount of consequence.
Rym: Therefore, I would never wish gastroenteritis on another human being again.
Scott: And gastroenteritis could, you know, just be stomach sickness for a few days.
Scott: And I'm still not going to wish it on anyone.
Scott: So, I mean, while you have the right to be stupid, do you deserve death for being that stupid enough to drink raw milk?
Rym: Well, Scott, we have precedent because if you look at the classic Nintendo game, Shadow Gate, death is, in fact, the consequence of all possible actions, save one.
Scott: So if I, right, if I see someone on the side of the street, right, and let's say they're about to drink, you know, I don't know, they're about to smoke a cigarette.
Scott: Now, that's pretty stupid, right?
Rym: You're going to tackle him, rip it out of their mouth, be like, I saved you.
Rym: No, no, no.
Scott: But let's say that, you know, that cigarette actually has like sign at it and they're going to die.
Scott: But they don't know that they're stupid, even though it said right on the package, like it's instant death cigarettes who sell some cigarettes.
Scott: They they're not so sure that it's that it's instant death cigarette.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even though you told them that, they're like, no, it's not.
Scott: It'll only give me cancer when I'm way old.
Scott: They think it's just a little bit unhealthy.
Scott: And in fact, they still say that these cigarettes taste way better than any other ones, just like they say the raw milk tastes way better.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It does taste a little better, I think.
Scott: I'm just saying, right.
Rym: Let's say I wouldn't drink it.
Scott: If someone is doing something that they think is slightly stupid, but you know, is very stupid and you know that the consequences are very severe and they don't know.
Scott: and they don't believe the consequences are as severe as you say.
Scott: And the consequences are basically they're they're killing themselves and they don't think they're killing themselves.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like if someone's about to jump off a bridge with a bungee cord and you know, the bungee cord is way unsafe, but they don't believe you.
Scott: They say, no, this bungee cord is totally safe.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is physically stopping that person is basically saving them from their own stupidity.
Scott: You're saving their life.
Scott: So it would be if someone was about to do that bungee jump with the cord that they thought was safe and I knew was not safe and I stopped them from doing that, would that not be totally cool?
Rym: Probably.
Scott: I'm saving someone's life from their own stupidity.
Scott: So if somebody is drinking poison milk or whatever, other nasty poison bathtub cheese or whatever the hell raw food they got, they got from the dirty farmer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Who didn't want to, you know, follow the government's rules about clean food.
Scott: And I stopped them or the government stops them from eating that food.
Scott: That's the same as saving that bungee jumpers life.
Scott: And it should totally be okay.
Scott: You know, unless you want to argue that the, you know, I mean, if you want to argue that there's a right to suicide and that's an argument, a separate argument because this is someone committing suicide who doesn't know, they think they're only hurting themselves a little bit, but they're going to get really hurt and they don't know it just because they're dumb.
Rym: Scott, I get like three and a half more minutes out of you.
Scott: That's not, it wasn't any newses.
Rym: My only news was Scott is blab about everything, but then if you actually get him to, you said something, you said something else that instigated this reminded me self motivated that I did in fact come before you.
Scott: I'm just not self reminded.
Rym: You're not an actor, but you're simply a receiver.
Scott: Oh, I was reminded of something to talk about.
Rym: So you're, you're catching as opposed to pitching.
Scott: You want to see what's on my pitch in the ideas.
Rym: You're just catching him.
Scott: I got stuff to say.
Scott: I just don't remember what it was and it wasn't news.
Rym: Now I don't even have to talk about the, the city of old people that is in an uproar in Florida about the fact that the school's being built in their community.
Rym: I don't even have to talk about that now.
Scott: Oh my gosh.
Rym: There's funny things to say.
Rym: Probably the FARC headline was like, town wants everybody to get off their collective lawns.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: But uh, I don't have to say anything.
Scott: We had a good, do we really need to say anything about that?
Rym: I don't think we do.
Rym: I'll link to the article anyway.
Rym: It's pretty great.
Scott: It speaks to itself.
Rym: So anyway, things of the day, I don't know how this guy survived.
Rym: Uh, nevermind the guy in front of him hanging out in all the lightning.
Scott: Is this a, is it like an own video?
Rym: No, just a picture.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It's a picture I took at the Olympic stadium in Athens during a severe thunderstorm over a half hour.
Scott: He caught quote, wait, which Olympic stadium?
Scott: The recent one or the ancient one?
Rym: The reason one.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Caught quote 51 one's still there.
Rym: The Olympic stadium.
Scott: No, you know that they used in the original Olympics, the original Olympics wings on their feet.
Rym: When were the original Olympics like?
Scott: over a century ago?
Rym: Uh, anyway, so he captured 51 quote unquote.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: A century ago was 1910.
Scott: It must've been like multiple centuries ago.
Rym: So basically what he did is he had the camera set up and he just took a pictures of a whole bunch of lightning and superimposed all of them together into one picture of this giant lightning display.
Rym: And it's kind of awesome.
Scott: Ancient Olympics, seven hundred and seventy six BC.
Scott: I was right many centuries ago.
Rym: Yes, many.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So what do you got for me?
Scott: Oh, so you know the one geekery that I do not like is Star Trek.
Scott: However, the one geekery, I don't know what other geekeries don't I like?
Rym: But kind of cannot all things be geekeries.
Rym: I mean you're not really into personal general mutilation geekery.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But I mean the one.
Scott: there's two, at least two, I mean the one thing that is like, you know, stereotypical stereotypical geek.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean it's a sci fi thing.
Scott: It's ultra pot anyway.
Scott: But, uh, I do know at least this much that there was an episode of Star Trek about some like some fuzzy creatures, troubles.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they basically get all over the place and then they get rid of them somehow.
Scott: I'd ever saw it.
Scott: I just know that there's an episode about right.
Rym: They breed like mad.
Rym: They breed like Kirk.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Uh, and I also know that I am excellent at recognizing quality graphic design, although I could not make it for the life of me.
Scott: And apparently at the Alamo draft house, some guy made them some new posters to hang up and they are trouble with tribbles posters.
Scott: And the graphic design is like unbelievably.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: That is the same style as that awesome X-Men poster.
Scott: There's two.
Scott: There's another one.
Scott: There's a red one and a blue one.
Rym: I kind of want that blue one on my wall.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They're, they're like the highest, highest quality.
Scott: And I think it's like a limited edition print something, something you might not even be able to get it now.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Uh, but yeah, 18 by 24 inch go on sale Friday on the Mondo website.
Scott: There's going to be 350 blue ones and 190 red ones.
Scott: Huh?
Scott: So I hope you have your monies.
Rym: I have plenty of money.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the graphic design is a excellent day.
Scott: I can tell even though by the pixels, even though I don't care about the subject matter and that's probably the only reason the only thing that's preventing you from buying this is the subject matter.
Scott: I mean, remember that X-Men.
Scott: is it the same?
Rym: That's what I just said.
Rym: Oh, I said that.
Rym: Do you not even listen?
Rym: No, you're right next to him.
Rym: You were four feet away from me.
Scott: I was busy looking at the excellent graphic design.
Rym: So very briefly, the meta moment, the book club was obviously the lives of Locke Lamora.
Scott: What's the next book club?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know either.
Rym: We're working on that.
Rym: Uh, next weekend is Otakon.
Rym: We will not be there.
Rym: They don't have a schedule yet.
Rym: So we even need to say that we're not going to because other people, you know, a lot of people expected us to be there.
Rym: I've gotten some emails.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Oh, but you know, you should go to Otakon if you're a close by or if you have, you know, we'll probably have fun.
Scott: I mean, not the same amount of fun as if you had, if we weren't there, it's not going to be different perspective of a con goer, unless the only reason you like going to Otakon is to see us.
Scott: In which case, what the hell's wrong with you?
Rym: Probably made a lot of fans happy because, you know, we decided not to do the two panels they'd confirm.
Rym: So they got two more Italian panels.
Rym: I'm assuming.
Rym: But all that aside, we got the penny arcade expo coming up at the end of summer.
Rym: We'll be there.
Rym: New York Comic Con anime festival, 10, 10, 10, all that other stuff.
Rym: I don't have any feedback.
Rym: We've gotten the book club a little bit.
Scott: So while we keep changing it, the thing is, right, is I'm basically, I'm going to, I'm going to tell a secret that I have kept, right?
Scott: Is?
Scott: I've sort of had this attitude where I'm like, no one reads the books, blah, blah, blah.
Scott: We got to make the punk kids read blah, blah, blah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The thing is I have absolutely no idea how many people actually read or not.
Scott: I have not counted.
Scott: I have not done a survey.
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: I'll say this.
Scott: Basically assuming that no one reads, because if I make that assumption then and take this attitude, then I hope that that is the attitude, uh, that will force us to keep trying to get more people to read.
Rym: So self deception is a valid means to success.
Scott: I'm not deceiving myself.
Rym: So you're lying to other people.
Rym: Uh, no, you're saying kids don't read it.
Rym: You don't know.
Scott: the kids definitely don't read.
Rym: What are you basing that on?
Scott: I know they don't read.
Rym: What did you just say?
Scott: His kids tell me they don't read.
Rym: I take a very different tack.
Rym: I've been saying no one's going to read the books because I'm hoping that what will happen is people will feel indignant.
Rym: Like he's going to say, I'm not, I'm going to read the book.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That's that's the idea.
Rym: That's my plan.
Rym: But again, deception, valid strategy of success.
Scott: It's not deception.
Scott: That's just insulting.
Scott: It's like, Hey you, you punk kid, you're not going to read this, but I know we will read it because I said he won't.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well let's, we're going to figure out how many people actually read regardless.
Scott: So we are going to make some changes to hopefully the biggest change.
Rym: And I don't know why we didn't even see this and I thought about it a lot.
Scott: I'm going to tell you what the problem with the idea.
Rym: So basically before we, we shouldn't treat the book club reviews the same way as you treat a real review, like anything else.
Rym: we talk about where we do the review, which is, this is why it's awesome with no spoilers.
Rym: So you know, to read it and you know, it's awesome.
Rym: You're like, alright, I'm going to do it.
Rym: And then we do the final thoughts, the spoilers, the, all right, so we know you've read it.
Rym: Wasn't it fucking awesome when the guy killed the guy in the second chapter.
Scott: The problem is that if we still did Thursday episodes every Thursday, that would work, but we'd have to basically give two Thursday episodes per book and we only do two Thursday episodes per month if that.
Scott: So either we would do a book a month and Thursday would become book club night or we did a book every two months in which case every other Thursday episode would be book club.
Scott: or if we did it every four months and then we're doing a book every four months, it's only three books a year and they still can't finish reading them.
Rym: So that's about a good, it's a good amount of time.
Scott: So, you know, we're not going to be, it's like, uh, I don't know why you want to do more often.
Scott: Well, I mean, I, you know, it feels like either Thursday is going to become book night or I don't know, or we don't do them that often.
Scott: Maybe we should make it a completely separate episode and give Thursday back to Thursday and make book club its own episode.
Rym: You're the one always complaining that we don't have any Thursdays to do.
Scott: I know.
Rym: I think this is my strategy for Thursday episodes.
Rym: now is going to be to just force a topic and we'll just do it because all I have to do is get you talking.
Scott: Maybe if we do, maybe we do two book club episodes per month or one, you know, one book club episode per month.
Rym: You think they're going to read these books in a month?
Scott: And no, no, we do one book club episode per month, which would be two, you know, if we do two episodes per book, that would be six books a year.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But then that, that book club episode is not a Thursday episode.
Scott: It's its own episode.
Scott: It has nothing to do with Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday.
Rym: Well, even if it's his own episode, we can put it up in Thursdays, but we can skip all that meta, but we would still do two other non book Thursdays every month that I expected to do that anyway.
Scott: All right, so let's do that.
Rym: So regardless, the lives of Loch Lamer, the way we're going to do this little change up, we're going to review it and talk about it straight up.
Rym: And we're not going to spoil anything and we're going to warn you when spoilers come.
Rym: So if you have not read the book yet, this is our chance to convince you to read the book and you can come back and listen to, you know, everything past those spoiler line where you find out how lock dies is
Scott: just, you know, doing the, tell you something that may or may not be true as that you are, you know, that's the greatest when you can spoil someone, but keep the uncertainty so that they, you know, even though they'll be thinking about that thing, they won't know if it's actually going to happen or not because now they're uncertain.
Rym: Evangelion is the best example of that.
Rym: You just go to someone who's never seen it, doesn't really know what it's about and say, yeah, that Ava show, it's great, but everyone dies in the end.
Rym: Everyone, every single character dies.
Rym: They won't believe you.
Scott: Well, you know, cause it's not directed by Tamino.
Scott: So no, no.
Scott: Anyway, so Loch Lamer straight up, having read this book, I don't know how to pronounce Lamora and we don't have a guide that I'm going to check the internet.
Rym: Maybe I can find between Lamora and Lamora, depending on how I'm feeling.
Scott: I like, you know, I don't know which is correct, but saying Lamora is it, you know, it feels better on the mouth.
Scott: Sing Lamora.
Rym: It is very, because you say the whole title, it's very like.
Rym: the rhythm is nice.
Rym: The lies of lock Lamora.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I think a lot.
Scott: I think the lies of lock Lamora is, is, but it's not as poetic.
Rym: I don't have the rhythm that, you know, like, like the Assyrians came down like the Wolf on the fold.
Rym: Their cohorts were gleaming.
Scott: It feels better in the mouth to say Lamora.
Rym: You're a terrible poet then.
Scott: Well, apparently he's already got titles for the seven books in the series.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: He's planned everything.
Rym: He DC, all the tricks and all the like little references he put near the end of this book that clearly he is going to answer later.
Rym: Like the fact that locks real name has five syllables.
Rym: He clearly like he has this whole thing planned out.
Rym: now that this book has been mildly successful and the book was pretty successful as far as I can tell.
Scott: Well, judging by the front of the book, which I already discussed when he introduced it, that there's a zillion like pull quotes is is not the most well written book.
Scott: The style, it didn't win the Pulitzer prize guys.
Rym: The style of like the, it is notable for the story it tells.
Rym: It is not notable for the way in which the story was told.
Scott: Well, I mean there are, you know, I mean the writing is not bad writing.
Scott: You can tell what's going on.
Scott: when there's an action scene, you can follow the action really well.
Rym: It's not completely on notable, like there's nothing special about the way it's written.
Scott: No, I mean there are the descriptions of the world, you know, are very full and rich.
Scott: It is like he would be able to make a really good campaign setting.
Scott: He's like, ah, yes, there is a, there are five castles here.
Scott: They are made of this material.
Scott: This one is the tallest one and you know, and this one is shorter.
Rym: They're full and rich, but they're asides always.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And whenever they come, they come in this way that it's really hard to explain this, but they reek of a game book.
Rym: So hard.
Scott: 10 times hard.
Rym: Like they have that kind of nod to your people living in the modern world.
Rym: Like he'll describe a sport and he's so obviously like wanting you to compare it to football and compare the things they've got set up to like the real modern world.
Scott: Describes the rule of the sport, but the sport doesn't actually matter really.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: The problem is the way he describes these things has the same wink and a nod that in a D and D campaign you describe like, you know, some traveler comes from some portal.
Rym: He's got this stick and it's metal.
Rym: It's like four feet long.
Rym: And on the end of it, there's these holes and it made some thunder earlier and the DMS look at you the whole time.
Rym: Like, you know, it's a gun.
Rym: I'm not going to call it a gun.
Rym: Characters don't know, but you know, it's a gun.
Rym: Isn't that cool?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, these books do that all the time.
Scott: The thing is right is on the one hand it's doing the cowboy bebop thing, right?
Scott: Where you have a story and you have a world and the world is obviously this crazy world that has a ton of crazy shit going on, right?
Scott: It's like they have these castles and all this stuff.
Scott: What's the crystal?
Scott: It's what's it called?
Rym: Elder glass, elder glass.
Scott: All this shit is made of elder glass because there was some civilization that lived here before the current civilization disclosure.
Rym: Anything that includes precursor civilizations gets my rocket go.
Scott: So there was a, there was a precursor civilization with crazy advanced magic technology that is now gone and there are people now living in the elder glass that they don't know how to make or any, right?
Scott: Which is totally cool.
Scott: It's a cowboy bebop, right?
Scott: There's these gates and there's something going on with the gates and, but really our story of our characters that we're focusing on has nothing to do with that.
Scott: They're just in this world and we're going to flesh out during the show you that this world is totally bigger and awesomer than these characters to make a really good setting, right?
Scott: And that's always cool.
Scott: The difference between Locke Lamora and cowboy bebop is that coming bebop doesn't really dive into the details of the world.
Scott: They just sort of show you the world.
Scott: It's like there's gates, their characters use them, you know, and they hint like there's, there's obviously a big story about these gates.
Scott: We're not going to tell you anything about them.
Rym: And they tell oblique stories to those like early on there's the kid who was immortal in cowboy bebop and that is like oblique to the gates.
Rym: Like that story comes out of the gates, intersects with our plot that we're following, and then kind of falls away.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Locke Lamora, right?
Scott: They basically go in depth and tell you all these crazy details about things that, you know, are like they actually fill out those things in the world.
Scott: They don't just like wink at you like, Hey, there's a sport called something.
Scott: They're actually like, here's the, all the rules of the sport.
Scott: We're going to tell you every single rule of the sport that there is.
Scott: And we're going to tell you the history of the sport and everything just like they would in the forgotten realms.
Scott: But then there are other things they don't tell you, right?
Scott: It's like they don't give you, you know, usually a book, they tend to either have the omniscient view, you know, everything or the one character view, you know what this character knows, right?
Scott: Or something like that.
Scott: This book, it's like, he tells you whatever it's convenient for you to know.
Scott: It's like, if he doesn't want you to know that because you know, it'll be a cool, suspenseful mystery, then he'll hide it from you and then tell it to you at the right time.
Scott: If he wants to save it for a sequel, he'll give you a character's name.
Scott: Like what's that girl?
Scott: Savitha, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: He'll tell you that this girl exists and won't tell you anything about her, you know, just because he wants to drag it for the sequel.
Scott: And there'll be, you know, something else.
Scott: It's like, he'll want you to know part of it, but he'll want, you know, everything because it's a surprise.
Scott: It's like, come on guys, tell me, you know, you got to be consistent here.
Scott: Don't tell me just what it's convenient to tell me, you know, you gotta, you gotta have some pattern to it.
Rym: Well, I guess it's just, this is why this is a fun book, but not a great book because every time he tells you about the world, it's always kind of a shoehorn in his side.
Rym: It's always just kind of like, it's often cool.
Scott: Like it's awesome.
Scott: Like that sport is actually a pretty good sport, but it just has nothing to do with the story.
Rym: So it's a book where the events and the story itself are the most interesting part.
Rym: It's in my eyes, the perfect kind of book to turn into a movie like the prince of nothing, a completely shallow action movie.
Rym: Not necessarily.
Rym: It's not that shallow.
Rym: It's just that the writing, the style of the writing and the style of the literature and the act of reading it does not impart that much value compared to just the interest in the story.
Rym: I wanted to know what happened next.
Rym: I didn't linger on the meaning of a word at the end of a sentence.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The other problem though is that really there are three stories going on, right?
Scott: You've got the story of the past, right?
Scott: You've got the story of the con because obviously the con is just context for the current situation.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And then you've got the story of, you know, the stranger comes to town, right?
Scott: So you've got the three stories.
Scott: And the thing is the story of the con.
Scott: I like that a lot more.
Scott: The stranger that came to town really felt like he came out of nowhere.
Rym: And even though they, they gave you a connection, that connection was the same connection as like every, like, Oh, here's all the stuff about Wraith stone.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: The connection of the bad guy, right?
Scott: To lock Lamora was so such a weak connection.
Scott: It's like, you know, why, why did like Lamora really care about this guy?
Rym: No, I think kind of the point not to say it's not like a connection.
Scott: Like Darth Vader is Luke's father.
Scott: There's a connection.
Rym: We can't spoil, but that's actually, that was a really interesting twist that we'll talk about after the spoiler line as to why that was the case.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Cause I thought that was actually pretty well done.
Rym: It's something that it's one of the few things that a book like the way this book ends and like what happens in it is not expected.
Rym: Like you'll read this book.
Rym: You're like, I know where this is going.
Scott: I didn't expect it'll, it'll lie.
Scott: I will not lie.
Rym: I was looped, but it, because of stuff like that and not because it's shallow, cause it's not that shallow, but just because the events themselves standalone and are interesting, this would make a great fricking movie.
Scott: I would see this in the theater, but it wouldn't be like a, uh, you know, a deep movie.
Scott: It would be, you know, you'd go for the action and the surprise and the story.
Rym: And the story is good.
Scott: The story is, but the doesn't have a message for you.
Rym: Yeah, it does.
Rym: The messages don't fuck with Locke Lamora.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I mean, it doesn't have a message about, you know, like some, you know, I mean, uh, you know, like the, uh, well, I'll put it this way.
Scott: Lord of the flies is something to say about society.
Scott: This doesn't have anything to say about the prince of nothing.
Rym: Those books, the events, this is why, like I hold them to a higher standard or like a Michael Shayvon book where his writing is so lyrical and just beautiful, but with the Prince of nothing, the events are interesting and I really want to know what happened next.
Rym: But the style of the writing and the way the world is introduced to you is also so masterful that that is like this completely separate enjoyment.
Scott: The Prince of nothing has something to say about the nature of free will and knowledge and such.
Rym: That's the third factor.
Rym: And that is three aspects.
Scott: And that is so Locke Lamora only has like one and a half aspects.
Rym: Locke Lamora has one and a half aspects.
Rym: Prince of nothing has three.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Shayvon has four.
Rym: It's that plus a Pulitzer.
Scott: It's short on aspects basically, but the aspects he has, he's got them right.
Scott: I mean, if I wrote a book, I would have like half aspects.
Rym: This is also the book.
Rym: If you want source material, cause not a lot of people will have read this.
Rym: If you're going to run like a fantasy D and D campaign, just steal this setting straight up.
Scott: Oh, the thing is, I don't know how well it worked for D and D specifically because it's not so much of a medieval, it's more of a renaissance kind of setting.
Rym: Yeah, so set it in Waterdeep.
Rym: Waterdeep is a very renaissance kind of city.
Rym: That kind of thing.
Scott: Oh, is it?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, it's, I think it's definitely, you know, push more toward the steampunk and the technology.
Scott: I mean, you can tell with all the boats going on is definitely supposed to be a Venice situation, right?
Scott: It's so obvious, you know, with all they, they basically take a boat anywhere they go almost, you know, and every, like the big festival is like on the water.
Scott: It does seem though that like, you know, Venice is like lots of little waterways, right?
Scott: In between everything.
Scott: This seems like this big waterways.
Scott: Like if you just replaced all the really big roads with water, but it kept all the regular roads as roads.
Scott: That's what it seems like.
Rym: Well, that's, that was one of the things that was weird, despite how accurately, like how, how much you would explain, like, this is this district, this is that district.
Rym: I never had a clear map in my head of where anything was.
Scott: Did you look at the map in the book?
Rym: No.
Scott: There's a map in the book.
Rym: But like from the writing, you don't get that.
Scott: No, you need to look at the map.
Rym: You just don't have the sense of where things are.
Scott: Without that map, you are basically gonna have no idea, but the map basically gives you everything you need to know because it's all labeled.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But along those lines, the book also kind of, it'll, characters take abuse that is infeasible and survive.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, the book is not a realistic book.
Scott: There's fucking crazy magic and shit in it.
Scott: You know, I mean, come on.
Rym: It was kind of elegant how he, how Scott Lynch was able to have magic and yet set it up such that it's not just the panacea for everybody.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's always the panacea for the boss.
Scott: That's always the trouble when you bring magic into a, into any book.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's like, okay, so this is magic.
Scott: You have to make the, if you want to just let everyone have magic, then it's just crazy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And no one has any problems cause they can solve them with magic.
Rym: So magic gimped and then it sucks.
Rym: Prince of nothing did it.
Rym: well.
Rym: Magic is nuclear fucking power, but only a few people have it.
Scott: You can make magic hurt people.
Scott: You can make magic hard to get, but the thing is you have to do it in such a way that doesn't insult the reader.
Scott: It's like, yeah, we're going to make it.
Scott: So the only way you can get magic is this magic powder.
Scott: You need this magic powder to get.
Scott: It's like, okay, come on guys.
Scott: Really?
Scott: That's kind of weak sauce.
Scott: But here, the way they limit the magic is actually a clever and new way that I have not seen in a fantasy setting before.
Scott: So that is good.
Rym: So I think the best way to sell this to you if you're an anime fan and if you're not, you should watch Lupin the third, the castle of Cagliostro.
Scott: It's similar to Lupin, right?
Rym: The way locks character is.
Rym: imagine Lupin if he had a backstory.
Rym: that was legit.
Scott: All right.
Rym: He's beat acts the same way as Lupin.
Rym: He's ruthless and protects his friends above all else.
Rym: He'd steals and he doesn't give a shit about the stuff he stole.
Rym: He steals because stealing is the whole point.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And he likes to mess with people.
Rym: He's also, he has weird love triangle problems and the girl he likes is never there and other girls like him.
Rym: He doesn't like them.
Rym: The only problem though, he has his gang and every one of them is like, he has his Jigen only instead of a gun, he has two fricking axes.
Scott: The only difference between Lupin and Locke Lammer, right?
Scott: Is that Lupin is pretty much bad-ass all around, right?
Scott: I mean, he's got some friends like, you know, Goemon is much better at fighting than Lupin and you know, um, Jigen is much better at shooting, but Lupin ain't bad at shooting.
Scott: You know, Lupin ain't bad at fighting.
Scott: Locke is bad at fighting.
Scott: Basically anything fighting.
Scott: He gets the shit beat out of him.
Scott: He can't fight for shit.
Scott: So look at who he fights.
Rym: The one guy that we really see him fight out of, outside of his backstory, it's basically a Kenshiro situation, but there's no Kenshiro and you're fighting one of the Kenshiro bad guys.
Scott: No, they're, they're, they're fights that he basically Locke is not good at everything.
Scott: He's always basically put all his min max.
Scott: He's got all his points into being a con artist and such.
Scott: Whereas the Lupin has a lot of points in stealing and is across the board, he's got average points.
Scott: Locke Lammer is min max.
Scott: He's got some min's.
Scott: Lupin has no min's.
Rym: But forget all that.
Rym: The story and the way the character is and the way he interacts with everything.
Rym: This is the story of pretty much what Lupin would do in a world like this.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's just, it's just fun.
Scott: You know, it's like, Hey, let's have a fun stealing old time.
Scott: Woo.
Scott: And then you do.
Rym: So I think at this point, let's, let's spoil stuff.
Rym: Spoilers.
Scott: So if you haven't, if you haven't read it, uh, don't listen or listen.
Scott: I mean, you know, I mean, even with the spoilers, I guess the book could still be entertaining.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I guess before we spoil anything else, the one thing I really want to talk about is Wraithstone because one elegant thing he did is he talks about gentle animals early on.
Rym: Like there was a gentle goat and whatever, and I was creepy ass eyes looking at you.
Rym: And I just assumed that gentlemen gelded basically.
Scott: No.
Scott: Then he explains it.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: But that was way later in the beginning.
Rym: He didn't explain it.
Rym: It's like blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Gentled.
Rym: And I just, I read right past that and I thought, yeah, gelded.
Rym: All right, whatever.
Rym: He's, I don't know why he, I think that was intentional.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: That's why I'm saying it was one elegantly like put together part when he actually explains what he means by gentle and the whole thing.
Rym: Basically the elder glass asbestos, the Wraithstones like, yeah, if you burn this shit, bad news.
Scott: Yeah, no, but I think what actually happened, right.
Scott: We already discussed in the first half how he'll go into great detail about aspects of the world.
Scott: We'll talk about a sport or the elder glass towers or you know, the, the festivals or whatever.
Rym: Rose garden.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He'll go into all these all the roses.
Scott: Oh fuck.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: They didn't tell a shit about that.
Scott: That shit was awesome.
Rym: No, no, that wasn't awesome.
Rym: What was awesome was the teacher in that room.
Scott: That's the other thing is all the teaching characters are always the best.
Scott: It's like, I just want to hear about that guy and chains.
Scott: Tell me their story.
Scott: Give me the prequel of chains in the war with the, with the guy who runs the military school.
Rym: favorite fucking character.
Rym: Chains is the equivalent of a, well, you didn't watch avatar, but uncle Iroh like that level of care.
Scott: How come they never write the book about that guy?
Scott: They always got to write a book about the apprentice of the better guy.
Scott: Give me the book about the better guy.
Scott: Tell me the story of chains.
Scott: Give me the chain book.
Rym: Keep reading the Prince of nothing.
Rym: You know what it is now?
Rym: The second part, like the second trilogy you haven't read, you know, basically the great King, the God King is right now.
Rym: And the great crusade of ancient days is right now.
Rym: No, but all this is now.
Scott: No, I want to, I don't want to read that.
Scott: I want to read about Siswatha who never shits.
Rym: That's all I want to read.
Rym: Same story.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: It's basically all right.
Rym: The baddest ass wizard and the God King and everything.
Rym: This, this is basically the story that will be the story in the past of some other book.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Cause I mean, Earthsea, right?
Scott: The story of Ged, Ged is the guy.
Scott: That's it, right?
Scott: He's the wizard.
Scott: He's, you know, in every, you know, there isn't really a Merlin of that world.
Scott: He's got an apprentice, he's got a master who's pretty awesome, but he surpasses that master and he is just, he becomes the Merlin and the Gandalf of that world, you know, and that's the story of him.
Scott: And that's kind of why Earthsea is awesome.
Scott: Uh, but this book is Locke Lamora is not the, uh, you know, the number one guy in this world.
Scott: And you don't even get to see the Duke whole book.
Scott: No Duke shows up.
Scott: They talk, everyone's talking about the Duke.
Scott: The Duke never appears.
Scott: Not once.
Scott: Where is the Duke?
Scott: There is something.
Rym: He was at that party.
Scott: Did he say anything?
Scott: Did they even, was he a part of any scene actually?
Rym: I think they pointed out that he was standing somewhere.
Scott: I didn't see that.
Scott: I didn't re I don't remember that, but it could have, it could have been a sentence or two.
Scott: Like the Duke was standing in the corner, you know, but I did not, I saw no actual appearance of the Duke.
Rym: So I was, I did not expect his con, you know, spoilers, spoilers.
Rym: I did not expect his con in the beginning to be when, when the Midnighters came and talked to the people who was conning.
Rym: I was like, wow, he's fucked.
Rym: All right, whatever.
Scott: No, I knew that.
Scott: I see that the part with the Midnighters I saw through, I was like, oh, he is the Midnighter.
Scott: He's fooling.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I didn't see what their, I thought at that.
Scott: when he did that though, I thought that the Midnighters were a myth.
Scott: And when there actually were Midnighters, that's what, that's when I was like, oh fuck.
Rym: I expected the Midnighters to come and things to get complicated, but not in the way they got.
Rym: What's kind of cool is there's this story, like the story was the con and like Locke and the secret piece and everything that's going along.
Rym: And then Gray King throws a monkey wrench in everything.
Rym: And this is the part I wanted to touch on from before.
Rym: the Gray King was disconnected from Locke completely.
Rym: He just had his own bullshit to deal with and he had his own plan, his own revenge and all that stuff.
Rym: But it was kind of interesting at the end when Locke is screaming at him when they're having their fight, when he's going to go kill the Gray King and he's basically saying, why'd you do this to us?
Rym: You could have just had the fucking money.
Rym: We didn't want it.
Rym: And the fact that all that death and all the problems that Locke faced, he was just in the wrong place at the wrong time, basically.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, but that at the same time, right, it's like, okay, you know, it might make sense that, you know, uh, this Gray King came out of left field like that.
Scott: But story wise, because he came out of left field, even though it might be realistic or neat or original, it made me not really care so much about the Gray King plot because it was out of left field.
Scott: You know, you don't attach it because, you know, that would be, you know, more whatever you attach it so that I would actually care.
Rym: But that's the interesting part because I cared about all this other stuff and the Gray King just comes in and fucks everything up.
Scott: I really just didn't want the Gray King to plot to be there at all.
Scott: I was like, go away.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Look at Locke.
Rym: Locke felt the same way.
Rym: He's got all his stuff going.
Rym: Everything's going awesome.
Rym: Like, yeah, I got this con things.
Rym: And the Gray King throws a monkey wrench in his plans.
Rym: And what does he do?
Rym: He says, you know what?
Rym: I can deal with this.
Rym: Let's just deal with the Gray King thing and keep doing our awesome stuff.
Rym: And the fact that that's like the turning point in the book when all his friends die and everything goes to shit because he had the same attitude that I had reading the book.
Rym: Gray King, whatever.
Rym: I want to get back to this con.
Rym: Oh, shit.
Rym: Gray King.
Rym: Yeah, I like that part.
Rym: I like the way that was handled.
Scott: I just I just, you know, I really I didn't want the Gray King story.
Scott: I wanted the the con story.
Rym: The con story would have been lame without something.
Scott: I was really fucking enjoying that con story.
Rym: It was so simple.
Scott: It was so good.
Scott: They could have just threw in one more twist on that and then ended it.
Scott: They made the book a lot shorter.
Rym: Plus, the Gray King was an excuse to bring in all these all these other aspects.
Scott: And then what you could have done is instead of bringing in the Gray King, right, is you take the back story of Locke that you were building and actually tied in instead of making me read the sequel.
Scott: I have the sequel.
Scott: I haven't read it yet.
Rym: I'm glad they didn't tie it in.
Rym: It was like a parallel thread.
Rym: They were just flashbacks that served the purpose of.
Rym: I need to explain this away or I need to foreshadow this.
Scott: Well, it is kind of good that they didn't tie it in in a way because it becomes more like the Godfather.
Scott: We're now in the second book.
Scott: Hopefully they will continue with the back story, which, you know, I always end up liking the back story.
Scott: You know, it's Spider-Man 2099.
Scott: After a bunch of issues, they actually started putting like this extra section in the back that had the back story from his childhood and actually ended up liking that a whole lot.
Scott: You know, so hopefully I have the sequel.
Scott: I'm going to read it.
Scott: Hopefully it continues the back story.
Rym: Actually, the new Avatar series looks like he's going to do something similar.
Scott: Which Avatar series is this?
Scott: The TV show.
Scott: So there's a new TV series?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Even though there's a bad movie?
Rym: The movie is done.
Rym: No one cares about that.
Rym: That's not.
Rym: Shyamalan proved that he hates movies.
Scott: But the TV series didn't have an ending or did it?
Rym: No, it did.
Rym: It ended.
Rym: The new series is going to happen in the same world.
Rym: It's takes place 70 years later.
Rym: All right.
Rym: And the deal is basically that it's the next Avatar.
Rym: It's her story, but it'll flash back to kind of the denim on of the previous story that did end.
Rym: So like you'll get flashbacks to like the back story of this new character is intertwined with like the X, like the follow up exposition of the previous story.
Scott: I never watched any Avatar, but you know, it's really good.
Scott: You should watch it and going with the things I've already said, they should tell the stories about the previous Avatar, who is like the most badass.
Rym: This one was that one.
Scott: There wasn't there wasn't one before that.
Scott: That was even more ancient and even more awesome.
Rym: You get straight up.
Rym: You get to watch them hanging out with dragons.
Scott: All right.
Rym: You should really, you should watch Avatar stuff going on.
Scott: You know, I've actually scarily almost watched all the Liji Matsumoto that matter.
Rym: So when you're done with all that, you should watch Avatar.
Rym: It's worth watching.
Scott: I got other things going.
Rym: What if it were an anime and it was coming out right now?
Scott: You know, I probably still, you know, I got other things to do.
Rym: Like what?
Scott: Like shit.
Rym: What are you going to do?
Rym: You run out of Yamato.
Scott: I already did.
Rym: So what are you going to watch?
Scott: Not Legend of the Galactic Heroes.
Rym: Anyway, so I made a bunch of predictions that fell through.
Rym: Like I didn't think Nausicaa was actually dead.
Scott: Oh, you didn't?
Rym: I thought she was behind, cause she winked at Locke, right?
Rym: This is me reading into stuff and then, and they're like, yeah, we'll get out of this arranged marriage that we don't care about.
Rym: But then she was winking and like, Hey, I got a plan.
Rym: You'll see.
Rym: And then, you know, she died and all that craziness.
Rym: I kind of expected that that was all her plan.
Scott: Oh, I didn't even make that connection.
Rym: They made the connection later that, you know, they went out in the funeral procession and they made a point of saying her body was not in the casket, but now now she's dead.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I kind of liked the bonds mage.
Scott: You know who you reminded me of?
Scott: You know, he reminded me of mom.
Scott: Well, first of all, I liked him a lot, but I liked him in a bad hating.
Rym: You reminded me of bullet tooth, Tony, a little bit because he just had this like, who the fuck are you?
Rym: Don't even talk to me.
Scott: I liked him a lot in the way that he's a bad guy.
Scott: You love to hate, right?
Scott: But you know, he reminds me of in the Indiana Jones, that bald Nazi guy, it was all slimy and has the, as the, he turns his thing that looks like he's going to hurt someone.
Scott: He turns it into a coat hanger.
Rym: That guy, that scene was one of my favorite scenes.
Scott: That guy is the bonds mage.
Scott: Cause he's just like so bad, but he's also so secretly dangerous, but he's also not, you don't want to fuck with him.
Rym: He's evil dude, but he's evil in this very like contracted way.
Rym: Like he doesn't care.
Rym: He's just like, I don't care so much that I'm going to torture you because the guy paid me to and I can and because no one can touch me.
Scott: You can't touch this.
Scott: If no one could touch you for anything like you were just like the Kings of the world, if you say whatever you say, it'll be like, okay, you might not have a strong motivation to kill, you know, hurt to torture someone, but you can.
Scott: So why the fuck not?
Scott: Cause you're just so bad and evil and a jerk.
Rym: He said towards the end when he's like, all right, uh, gene kill lock.
Rym: And he's about to have this like, oh wait, now stop lock kill Jane.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like I can picture that scene in the movie being like awesome and hilarious at the same time.
Rym: Cause he's like, no, no, no, wait, I've got a better idea.
Scott: It was a better idea, but it was also, it was the wrong idea.
Scott: Stupid idea.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Because like, as soon as, as soon as he said, as soon as he said, no way, I was like, okay, how are they going to get out of this?
Scott: And as soon as he said, no, wait, I have a better idea.
Scott: I'm like, that's how he's getting out of it.
Rym: So that whole bit, basically I love the bit toward the end cause we can't, you know, just skipping around in this where they have nothing and he's got to get a disguise and like start everything up again from nothing.
Rym: So he tries like the bullshit plan number one and the bullshit plan number two.
Rym: And then like the only plan that works in the end is like the ludicrous plan.
Scott: I do like how he tries these multiple plans.
Scott: They don't work.
Scott: But what I, I kind of feel that it was a little bit forced because there had to be some simpler plan where he could have gotten some clothes.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: Those clothes were like a thousand crowns.
Scott: I'm just saying there had to be a way he could have just like freaking stolen some clothes, like tied a guy up in an alley or something and taken his clothes.
Rym: You know, he's not a good fighter and he's alone.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: But I mean, all right, go into someone's house and take the clothes out of their cabinet, you know, but there's security and guards in the fancy person's houses.
Rym: He can't steal from anyone.
Scott: Paul sneak in.
Scott: He's done that before he snuck into the friggin Don's house with as the midnight.
Rym: Plus he needed ultra fancy clothes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The Don's house had ultra fancy clothes.
Rym: How's he going to break into the Don's house?
Scott: He did it before.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: At night with help.
Scott: Well, you know, yeah.
Rym: Also not busted up.
Scott: He could have gone in, sewn some clothes.
Rym: How that whole plan comes together was so.
Rym: Lupin, you know, he sneaks in.
Rym: like he sneaks in, he bribes the one gay bribes.
Rym: The other guy prized the third and also like in, uh, the Leonardo DiCaprio movie, the, when he's the con man.
Scott: Oh, that one where he prints the fake checks.
Rym: Why do I forget the name of that movie?
Scott: I forget it.
Rym: I feel really stupid now.
Scott: I actually see that in a theater.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We all saw in the theater together.
Scott: Oh wow.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: Regardless.
Scott: Remember the scene where he was the one that was based on a real guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So remember when he, uh, the, uh, Tom Hanks comes in to arrest him and he flashes his wallet, like he's got a badge and then he says, yeah, we already got the guy.
Rym: We arrested him and he waves out the window at the cop who's leading the other guy away and the guy just kind of waves back and then that like seals the deal on the con.
Rym: The lock basically did the exact same thing like four times with the one guard and the other guard and he's bribing everybody and then pretending to be the guy who's pretending to bribe people for the guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That was all awesome.
Rym: It was pretty, you know, it's, it's always, when he gets, when he gets the, the merchant guy locked up in his room, he just fucking throws the orchid away and walks away like, all right, I'm done.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's like whenever you're, when you're an engineer nerd type like us, right?
Scott: If you see just an awesome plan happen, it's just so fun.
Scott: Especially if it's a clever plan.
Scott: It's the same thing with like a clever joke.
Scott: Even if it's a really racist joke or something that's offensive, the construction of the joke in and of itself can be so awesome.
Scott: It just makes you feel good as a, as a nerd type of person.
Scott: So it's the plan, even if it's an unrealistic plan or if the, you know, the content of the plan is stupid or evil as long as you just, you just watching the construction of the plan is like looking at a computer program.
Scott: It's like, ah, so glorious.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: The NSMB.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So at the end, and I'm sure you noticed this, but they kept it.
Rym: I like how gene like all the side stores where they go to stay at all the priesthoods when he goes to stay at the death priesthood.
Scott: Yeah, that was actually a cool story.
Scott: But when
Rym: he runs away and like he leaves the name and the note and then he uses that name again later and then lock uses the same name even later just because, but you know, toward the end when like everyone knows who everyone is like, yeah, I'm the, I'm the this, you're the, that you're the spider.
Rym: We're all cool.
Rym: Let's deal with this crazy Wraith stone that we're all afraid of.
Rym: Like I liked that whole scene because he's being totally honest.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They actually approached it, you know, pretty, it was like, no one was stupid in this scene.
Scott: None of the people were like being jerks about it.
Scott: Even the Don who was like, ah, it's like, listen, don't forget the Don.
Rym: I think a character I like to, we don't get too much is the Don's bodyguard because that guy was like, he was portrayed at first as kind of like a thug and like the Don and the Danya or Donna were kind of portrayed
Scott: on
Rym: a as bad or like likes getting them, but they were both kind of cool and bad ass in their own, right?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I think the Midnighter lady was definitely much more bad ass.
Rym: Oh, of course she was, but she was a lot older, more experienced, but those two were cool.
Rym: But their assistant, like when he catches Locke at the end, he's like, you fucker.
Rym: And Locke's like, no, seriously.
Rym: And then like, as the truth is coming out, he's kind of just smirking like, you know, this is kind of awesome.
Rym: I'm just going to hang back.
Rym: I get it now.
Rym: I like that guy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know why I pictured him as looking like the guy who is the bodyguard to the bad guy in Moulin Rouge.
Scott: He reminded me more of like Sagat from street fighter, you know, that kind of guy.
Rym: Similar guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But at the end, Locke's telling the truth to everybody.
Rym: He's like, look, that did it, did it, did it, did it, and great King did it, did it, did it, did it, did it, did it.
Rym: And notice how he seamlessly turns from actual truth to straight up lies.
Rym: Oh, and the ship, you've got to bomb the ship because you've got to get rid of that thing.
Rym: Cause it's bad.
Rym: And my name, my real name's Taver and all that.
Rym: He just shifts into the straight up lies.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Like that was the climax of the book.
Rym: That was like the pinnacle moment of yes.
Rym: Locke lies.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Cause he didn't lie all that much up until that point.
Scott: No, I mean, it's called the lies of Locke Lammers.
Scott: Like, well, which lies were?
Scott: there was the lie about that, right?
Scott: Uh, there was the lies that he told that he was trying to get close.
Scott: when he's conning, he's lying, but I, and it's also sort of weird that the books from the perspective, you know, it's like, it's you, the book is about the con, right?
Scott: Or the conning and they show you enough of the con because if they don't show you any of it, then it's like, well, you don't get the, Oh man, that's so awesome.
Scott: But they show you some, but then they don't show you like that final bit of each one, you know, until the time is right.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So that way they can at least pull something on you that get, that gives them excitement and twisting.
Rym: But I guess it's just that all the characters that matter in the story aren't stupid.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I don't think, is there anyone at all who's stupid?
Scott: I mean, some people get conned, but it's like anyone would be conned, even a smart person.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They're not stupid.
Scott: They're just, they got, they got fooled, you know, of course.
Rym: I mean, the title could allude to, cause you know, in his backstory, how he basically got all those kids killed because until he understood like what it means to lie and con and like the consequences of things, he got a whole bunch of kids murdered.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And you know, he dealt with that.
Rym: and then I kind of liked the way they dealt with that throughout the story and how he learned his lessons.
Scott: and yeah, the thing is, is right is the part of his childhood that is, you know, you don't, you only get up to a certain point, you know, you don't get the, like you don't learn anything about Savathur or how he, of course not more books.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, that's definitely the cooler part.
Scott: It's sort of the same situation where you don't get the story of the cool old Kings.
Scott: The cool part would be when, you know, lock in the other guys, you know, they said they had ripped off like how many dons already.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And that's, that's the cool part.
Scott: Just give me a book where they rip off those other dons and that's the whole book.
Rym: I kind of like the, the, the fact that they keep using the currency until you start to get a sense of what they're worth.
Rym: And then you think back, you're like, he had 40,000 crowns just in a pit.
Scott: Well, yeah, they tell you like what a crown is worth, like, Holy shit.
Scott: And then they talk about how many, you know, how many crowns it's like, Oh, fuck me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: A crown is like a thousand dollars more than that.
Scott: A lot.
Scott: It's a crown.
Scott: It's only shit.
Scott: Like you could shave a little bit off a crown and you'll be fricking loaded.
Rym: So notice how the style of the speech in the book was straight up vernacular.
Rym: You fuckers, asshole, jerk.
Scott: I'll get you.
Scott: It's a fantasy world.
Scott: You can make it whatever you want.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I liked it too often.
Rym: You don't see this in like, if you do, if you do the these and the thows, but it's more.
Rym: look at other fantasy books on this level, the ones that are well written, but not like masterfully written.
Rym: Like the writing is not special, but have a good story.
Rym: They're a little pulpy and fun.
Rym: They tend to either make up a bunch of proper nouns that characters use for like swearing.
Rym: Like they have their fake swear words, fake swear words, stick out like a sore thumb.
Scott: I don't like, I'm not a fan or they'll use like, they'll like.
Rym: the language will be very God that con matter back.
Scott: Well, they do have plenty of proper nouns in this book that are guarded.
Rym: They don't use it in the way that the more decks are used in those lesser, like not as well or in the fantasy.
Rym: This is true that here it kind of pointedly is in the vernacular to remind you like these are normal people, you know, who talk to each other in a vernacular language in a fantastical world.
Rym: Like it did.
Rym: And once I think it works, it didn't stick out.
Scott: You know, I didn't also.
Rym: they're in a city.
Rym: It's kind of like New Yorkers.
Rym: They just say, fuck a lot.
Rym: Cause that's what you do.
Scott: I didn't notice it.
Scott: It didn't bother me, which means that's the right way to do it.
Scott: You know, it's, it's bad when it stands out and you notice something.
Rym: I also like how they use a lot of Italian ish or even just straight up Italian words, the Venetian references references.
Rym: Most of them are references to mafia stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Because there's the whole mafia thing.
Scott: That's the whole, that's what's going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He's got, he's brought in, you know, the magic plus the mafia.
Scott: How often is that?
Scott: You know, I mean, I guess it's halflings and D and D right.
Scott: Same kind of situation.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I guess, I dunno, I, we should probably end this, but I could just keep talking about, Oh, it was awesome when blah happened.
Scott: But I mean, that's pretty much the whole book.
Scott: A bunch of things happen.
Scott: It's awesome when they happen.
Scott: That's all there is to it.
Rym: Reading these until they Peter out.
Scott: I thought you want her.
Scott: I got the second one.
Scott: I'll read it and then I'll give it to you.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'll probably just keep reading them until I get sick of them.
Rym: Like the, those are the Temeraire books.
Scott: They've already said there's going to be a whole bunch of them.
Scott: So boy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But they're fun enough.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, it's just, I got to read until I find out a couple of things.
Rym: I want to know more about Wraith stone.
Scott: I mean, what's more to know about it.
Rym: I want to know, like I'm sure we're going to see it used for bad and gotten away with.
Scott: Well, I think what actually, you know, the thing is with the Wraith stone, right?
Scott: It's like they tell you about it, but you don't.
Scott: And the thing is, I was, I, she was like, shame on me, right?
Scott: Cause it's such a Chekhov's gun, the Wraith stone, big time Chekhov's gun.
Scott: Like it was Chekhov's elephant in the room, right?
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the problem with that is that there were so many Chekhov's guns, right?
Scott: Because he told you about the sport.
Scott: He told you, he went into great detail about so many things in the world that the Wraith stone Chekhov's gun blended with all these false Chekhov's.
Rym: It was easy to spot it.
Rym: It's Scooby dude.
Rym: Every other aside was a contained aside and maybe it was referenced later, but it didn't come up again later.
Rym: However, the gentle stuff kept coming up.
Rym: He was like, Jen, this was gentle.
Rym: This wasn't gentle.
Scott: He preferred gentle, but he's still his, his use of, you know, it was basically, it was hiding in the crowd, right?
Scott: The Wraith stone aside that told you all about Wraith stone hit amongst all the other ones.
Scott: And even when I read the aside about Wraith stone, I thought, Oh man, this is going to come up later.
Scott: But when it came up later, I was like, fuck me.
Scott: Why didn't I remember earlier?
Rym: He got me.
Rym: There was just the aside.
Rym: All right.
Rym: There was a lot of things that just had an aside Wraith stone had the aside and it also had constant mentions throughout the entire book.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I should have remembered it though, but I didn't until he actually brought it up at the end and I was like, Oh damn it.
Scott: Why didn't I remember it?
Scott: I should have remembered it.
Scott: I even knew that it was a Chekhov's gun and then I forgot that it was Chekhov's gun.
Scott: It's like, it's like a Chekhov standing there holding this gun and he holds it there for an hour and then like, right.
Scott: He puts it away into a drawer and you see him put it away in the drawer and then 10 minutes later he takes it out and shoots you with it and you're like, Oh, I forgot you put it in the drawer.
Rym: So the other thing I want to know is I really at some point want to know what blew that hole in that one elder, elder glass tower and how, Oh yeah.
Scott: Also you got to know about Sabbatha, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And the Rose garden.
Rym: I want to, I want to know like more about that.
Scott: And also I want to see the bonds mages come come, you know, let's see if they really, they're probably going to come and fucking, you know, locks.
Rym: whole thing was, Oh, I didn't kill him.
Rym: I didn't kill him.
Rym: It's okay.
Rym: But look at the way they handled every other technicality in this book.
Rym: It is not okay.
Scott: No, I want to see the bonds majors and come back big time and that's going to be hopefully Epic.
Scott: Hopefully that's just the end of the book.
Scott: The like the end of the last book, the bonds may just come and it's just like, well, boom, every year fucking toast and that's it.
Scott: Just leave them out of it until the very last book and then bring them back and there's no stopping them.
Scott: And that's cause there is no stopping them.
Rym: Maybe there is some sort of elder glass technology elder guns.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Scott: If they bring the world into it though, then you lose the good parts of the cowboy VVOP thing of having a world that isn't the store where the world is not the story.
Scott: I don't want the world to become the story.
Rym: It doesn't have to.
Rym: He can keep revealing stuff as asides and just in the course of telling his other stories because we learned a lot about elder glass and they just didn't learn everything.
Scott: What'd you learn about elder glass besides?
Scott: that is old.
Rym: We learned this indestructible and they keep talking about like the alchemical stuff and how, how it plays with lied and like, well, this one has a hole in it, so something can destroy it, but we don't know what.
Rym: And then like the rose garden, like, well, there's this kind of, maybe they made it with a hole in it.
Rym: so they keep, he can tell us more about the world without making the world.
Scott: The plot could be diamonds.
Scott: Does the world have diamonds?
Rym: And he's got to keep telling us stuff about the world, you know?
Scott: Well, I mean, that was half.
Scott: the book was just descriptions of the world.
Scott: So the next book is just as large.
Scott: It's gotta be descriptions of the world, but they're also traveling.
Scott: So it's going to be descriptions about a different geographic area.
Rym: Here's what I expect.
Rym: I expect at some point in this book series, a character is going to stumble upon either like the mummy of the elders who made the glass or a tomb or something related to them.
Scott: that is an old Herman who knows all the secrets.
Rym: Something like that.
Scott: It's a secret to everybody.
Rym: They're not going to tell us all the secrets, but they're definitely going to.
Scott: I'm telling you the secret.
Scott: Why you old man attack.
Rym: I'm giving you the security system.
Scott: Northwest, Southwest is the way.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: Lies of Locke Lammer, Scott Lynch, worth reading.
Rym: If anyone out there has money and it hasn't already been done, option the rights to make this movie.
Rym: This movie would do really, really, really well.
Scott: And Dodongo dislikes smoke.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.