Rym: Hey, it's Monday, April 12th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight a bunch of cell phone stuff.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So last night, you know Sunday night, usually I don't go out Sunday night, but we went to a cabaret.
Scott: Really it was the ones around the corner actually no way down.
Rym: It's called the duplex which I I'm not sure is twice as much.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: There's a bar downstairs and a slightly differently crook bar Upstairs and then around the corner from the upstairs bar.
Rym: There's this little cabaret Uh-huh.
Scott: Oh, so it's so.
Rym: it's little it's not it's little ish, but it was pretty cool.
Rym: It was just.
Rym: it was weird to go to that thing at like 10 o'clock on a Sunday night.
Scott: It was a good place to deposit all your ones not Scott cabaret does not mean strip club.
Rym: I Had to say something But you know, it was awesome.
Rym: So we get home super late and I think all right six hours of sleep.
Rym: I'm good.
Rym: I go to check my email gonna go to bed.
Rym: You're called by work cuz something blew up Huh?
Rym: So I Took care of it, but I didn't get woken up so I wasn't too mad to be honest.
Scott: Yeah, I would if work called me.
Scott: It's just like at any hour just like Yeah, it was really weird though.
Rym: I was on support.
Rym: Like this is the one week where they're allowed to call Yeah starting at 7 a.m.
Rym: Today.
Rym: I can't be called again for like a month.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: Yeah, it works out.
Rym: Complain.
Scott: no, it's really weird.
Scott: I've been waking up early Naturally, like I woke up at like 6 something before the alarm went off and I wasn't tired at all And then I biked to work and I was there by 9.
Rym: It's just like I think you're getting extra energy from the fact that you're actually moving around Exercise.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: I think so.
Scott: I think it.
Scott: you know, I think it is.
Scott: I think it is the Sun.
Rym: The Sun is far more time when the weather is fine.
Rym: God.
Rym: I love summer so much.
Rym: I'm actually rollerblading home from work every day.
Rym: That is much more harrowing than biking.
Scott: We're going over the same bridge, right?
Rym: Yeah, that bridge is.
Scott: so which which side do you think is worse?
Rym: Cuz I had coming up from Manhattan is much worse because it's steeper and shorter.
Scott: I think it's steeper and shorter, but then there's a long less steep part Whereas on the other side, there's a longer part that is sort of in between.
Scott: steepness You know.
Scott: and the thing is though like one part I do early in the morning and one part I do later.
Scott: So it's like a tough, you know It's.
Scott: I can't compare them with equal Factors on all sides.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the real factor is gonna be when I rollerblade to work which I'm not doing yet.
Rym: I mean, there's no shower at work or anything and rollerblading is a lot harder than biking.
Scott: Here's the thing.
Scott: I don't get right.
Scott: so you got this bridge.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, it's a big curvy suspension bridge right for cars All right.
Scott: So it it's like a hill.
Rym: it goes up and then down and the center is rarely in the middle of a river.
Scott: Of course, the thing is right.
Scott: the bikes and the people Why don't they make a second bridge down at the sea level that is flat?
Rym: What do you mean at the sea level like just above the water?
Rym: Thus blocking the river to boats Bridges that boats can get under.
Scott: it fuck the Very least.
Rym: I mean I do played some about Sim City.
Rym: you put that causeway there.
Rym: Those boats are fucked.
Rym: Fuck the boat, I would usually I'd build roads around the boats to trap them and then kind of keep them there.
Scott: Yeah At least you didn't have a really another, you know a reason that didn't make sense.
Rym: I had a real reason.
Scott: Okay Cuz it's like, you know if there were no boats, right?
Scott: Wouldn't that be a good idea cuz then you know the people in there whatever.
Rym: also Scott It's a lot harder to build a bridge like that What it only had to be a tiny bridge.
Rym: the other point of the suspension bridge is that you don't need pillars in the middle Of the river.
Scott: so much Yeah, but this you wouldn't really need pillars.
Scott: You could just put it on what it's not gonna float You can just hang it for even like a rope monkey bridge, you know what hanging down from the real bridge Yeah, why not?
Scott: It's just people and bikes.
Scott: It's not like it has to carry a lot of weight.
Rym: Ah Actually, it's cool Apparently the part where we ride the bikes and rollerblades.
Rym: that used to be a tramway and there was a stop in the middle Over Roosevelt Island and then you would get off at that stop and get on an elevator.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's not in service anymore.
Rym: No, that thing was totally dismantled.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so I think we should get right into the news because we got kind of an exciting You know, we're doing the thing that I said we were gonna do on GeekNights.
Rym: What like two years ago?
Scott: What is this thing?
Rym: having a guest host?
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: Oh shit indeed I don't know if they're.
Scott: are they actually a guest host or is it a guest?
Rym: I think guest hosts and whatever for the second half.
Rym: That's that's the whole shtick.
Scott: But anyway, I want to get right into the guest host like replace us and then we would leave.
Scott: that would be a guest host.
Scott: We're still here.
Scott: it's their guests.
Scott: well Maybe are we like they have to be a guest host?
Scott: that means that we act as guests and they run the show.
Rym: or are We like the late shows where the guest hosts are guest hosts because there is no real host and they keep passing it?
Scott: Yeah, like yeah, like SNL has a guest host because there's a. you know, the celebrity person, you know comes out at the beginning.
Scott: It's a different person each time, but then you're on Letterman.
Rym: You're not a guest host Because the guest host is Letterman because he'll eventually pass it on to someone else.
Scott: No, he's just a regular host.
Rym: We'll see what kind of wing it.
Rym: I kind of like the idea of guest hosts like we have a third host.
Rym: who is the guest?
Rym: because we're all equal.
Rym: Cuz I mean who of us is the host.
Rym: I mean me clearly me Your mom.
Rym: so Google is doing something that is the host of hosts something, you know Hosanna's in the highest something like that.
Rym: I look forward to the day when our listeners send me Hosanna's.
Rym: I still don't know what one is but it's.
Scott: I think it's something we don't want.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's as far as I can tell it's nothing more than adulations Uh-huh, or maybe it's I don't know like someone's gonna send us one now And you know what?
Scott: They're probably gonna send us more of those than we got.
Scott: cornucopias, you know Send the cornucopia.
Scott: I go make a cornucopia and just like send an email but date It's that the email gets sent on Thanksgiving, you know when the time is right.
Rym: So I actually had assumed for a long time that Google did the thing that they announced that they're now doing.
Rym: so I'm kind of Shocked but in retrospect it's obvious that they weren't doing it.
Rym: because how often you search for something on Google And like the top link goes to some blog or some you know Knockoff site where someone asked the question and didn't actually answer it and it takes forever to fucking load.
Rym: Google is now incorporating speed of the site as a metric in the searching.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not a major metric You know, it's pretty much like order by rel.
Scott: It's like if two sites are equal and one is faster than any other one Then the faster one will go, you know?
Scott: Actually, no, it's not going like way.
Rym: That's not what they're doing because apparently what they did affects less than 1% of queries as my guess is.
Rym: all they were doing is anytime there's a search result that is Slow beyond a certain threshold like it takes a second or so for it to respond.
Rym: They just rank it way down.
Scott: It's possible they're doing that.
Rym: I think what they're trying to do.
Rym: This is just me speculating is Knock off the blogs.
Rym: They're useless.
Rym: the forums that have questions, but not answers.
Rym: the personal sites that are useless.
Scott: Well, they try to do that.
Rym: Anyway, this isn't you know, yeah, but I think this is they've all bet.
Rym: They figured out that this metric of does the slow take the site take for fucking ever to respond is a pretty good indicator If it's a bad site or not.
Scott: Well, I mean isn't you know?
Scott: it happens sometimes we search for something weird on Google and you try all the links on the front page results and half of Them don't work or take forever to load.
Scott: and you know, it's like the only like the fourth and eighth links You know actually load in a matter of you know quickly.
Scott: So you really only got two results on the whole page the other results.
Scott: So that's the reason they're doing.
Rym: of course It's cool at least that the the links usually all work.
Rym: They're just slow as hell.
Rym: remember back in the Yahoo days.
Rym: We're like everything just didn't work.
Rym: Mm-hmm I just thought this was interesting and I'm really surprised they didn't do it before and again.
Scott: It's good that we are moving our technology around that I think our stuff is fast.
Rym: I think so, but I don't know.
Rym: I feel like there's a cool way to incorporate even more metadata like that.
Rym: I mean the metadata about a site.
Scott: I'm sure Google has this all figured out.
Rym: Google did their original search engine kind of used metadata by not using what the site had so much by using what everyone else had About the site, you know linking to it.
Rym: So maybe there's more steps of abstraction out from that.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: the search results are you know?
Scott: The thing is they could probably makes the search results better, but they're as good as they need to be.
Scott: It's like I don't need to be.
Rym: well I use Google less and less actually because I don't need to search the internet for things.
Rym: I usually need to search Wikipedia And then from there Google I only use for looking for like a very specific thing and I know exactly what I'm looking for.
Rym: I just have to actually find it if I don't know what I'm looking for.
Scott: I don't bother I don't serve.
Scott: I think what it is is that you're using Google, but you don't even realize you're using Google.
Scott: You know, it's one of those things where it's just so Blair.
Scott: You don't even notice.
Rym: Well, I use Google a lot of the times as kind of a poor man's DNS.
Rym: I don't type URLs I just have the name of the site into Google.
Scott: Yeah anyway So that's it's all you got there, that's all I got.
Scott: All right, so check this out Drobo, you know Drobo.
Rym: I know Drobo.
Rym: So I remember the Drobo did not do everything that I wanted.
Scott: so the thing with Drobo Right is what they make is they make a little box That's a raid box and you put a bunch of drives in it.
Scott: You can put any drives in there just any drives.
Scott: just shove them in and it would.
Scott: it would take care of all the raid BS you wouldn't have to deal with like Managing or rebuilding the drives or any bullshit, right?
Scott: Totally brainless person who knows how to put a hard drive in a slot can put a bunch of drives in a Drobo.
Scott: They'll have green lights and if a drive crashes it'll be a red light and you take the drive out and put a blank one in and it'll fix and you won't lose any data Unless there's too many red lights and it just works and you don't need to think about it.
Scott: All right, so I was like, oh man I need one of those because I want to have a raid storage NAS thing.
Scott: But I don't want to have to deal with all that raid bullshit.
Scott: The thing was the Drobo right did not have any Networking whatsoever.
Scott: It only had USB and fire.
Rym: Did it have that fucking box you could buy that?
Scott: did the networking?
Scott: At first it had no networking.
Scott: So you just plug it into a computer and I guess you wanted to share it.
Scott: you had to you know use NFS or whatever On that computer.
Scott: So like fuck that, right?
Scott: So then Drobo came out with the Drobo share Which is a separate thing that you would attach to your Drobo and you would put the USB of the Drobo into this thing.
Scott: And then this thing had a network hole.
Scott: So it's like buying a $200 network card.
Scott: It's like fuck that a network card is ten bucks.
Scott: Fuck you, right?
Scott: There's no way I was doing that.
Scott: But now finally they have the Drobo FS Which is a Drobo with a network hole in it and it has a gigabit Ethernet card and it's a Drobo.
Scott: so the only thing any check it can protect to drive failures at once and You can get to 10 terabytes or whatever.
Rym: So the only thing I didn't check I'm curious about did you look how fast is it?
Rym: Like what can I run as fast as a Drobo?
Rym: Might not be fast enough.
Scott: I mean how fast do you need to be?
Rym: I mean a lot of people want to you.
Rym: like a lot of my co-workers have Drobo like things or they bought all these different Products.
Scott: Yeah, there's like.
Rym: They want to use them as file servers But they also want to host services on them and kind of have it all in one.
Rym: I'm hosting and I have storage in this one box.
Scott: Well, I mean personally if I'm hosting a service like a database server or a web server, right?
Scott: You don't want to do that on one of these NAS boxes because the CPU and the RAM are not enough.
Scott: Get a computer get an Intel chip and some fucking RAM and do it that way.
Scott: No, I am I'm like you could.
Scott: you could connect the Drobo to such a computer right use it as the storage part All right, and go for it.
Scott: The thing is the Drobo does let you write Drobo apps.
Scott: So you could you know write a little.
Scott: you know any you could write is basically it's Linux, right?
Scott: So you could write something for the Drobo to like say activate, you know Maybe it doesn't have the kind of file sharing you want.
Scott: So you write one you put one on there.
Scott: You know, you can do that kind of thing, but it's not gonna be fast.
Scott: So if you're hosting any services, like maybe you could do like a cool photo gallery thing, you know But don't expect it's like host photos to the whole Internet's use flickr for that shit.
Rym: But what does make me optimistic is that I believe people were talking about how it has built in already or at least kind of Preconfigured a torrent client.
Rym: So you just kind of schedule up all your torrents and they're just right on the NAS.
Scott: Yep, that's the kind of thing it can do very nicely.
Rym: I think we're very rapidly give it another.
Rym: you know - and I think the line between NAS and San is not going to be blurred but what they're completely so far away.
Rym: But what's gonna happen?
Rym: I think is that all the capabilities that sands have now are effectively going to be in the consumer.
Rym: NAS is.
Rym: But then what is called a San is going to be some horrifying beast far away and is already a horrifying beasts depends I mean is completely different like it some for some of the less heavy-duty stuff.
Rym: We're actually, you know work we're using iSCSI and those iSCSI sands are not that expensive and they're pretty damn big tens of thousands Of dollars.
Rym: you can get one for four or five thousand dollars.
Rym: It's iSCSI with lots of space.
Scott: Yeah, I think what it really is about right is that you know, we went from computing on your desktop right to the cloud.
Scott: I think that the real place to be is the the personal cloud.
Scott: everyone has a server and the things that are blocking us from this are the people don't have enough upstream bandwidth from their ISPs and People don't have static IP addresses.
Scott: I think that in the next five, I don't know not even gonna name a number of years But it's when we get IPv6 and when if we get this national broadband plan Whatever we get some upstream because it seems like they realize we need some upstream, right?
Scott: Then people are gonna be able to have things like this drobo FS or other, you know things like Windows home server.
Scott: Though I think those are ahead of their time, you know, they're.
Scott: they're not right now.
Scott: They don't work because you know It's so difficult to make all this networking with NAT routers and all this BS to get it going.
Scott: But eventually when we're able to get that going that's how things are gonna be.
Scott: people, you know You're gonna be able to have you know, all the stuff that you want on your own computers.
Scott: It'll work really easily.
Scott: You won't have to deal with weird, you know networky stuff.
Rym: Well, I think the other interesting thing that'll happen once everyone has like the idea that your IP address or your connection is static That you were both that the upload and download is equal You're gonna have all.
Rym: that's the you know The idea of having websites that are completely interactive because every website is running kind of on someone's PC.
Scott: Yeah, imagine with IPv6, right?
Scott: You could have a cell phone.
Scott: That is the same IP address no matter where you go.
Scott: That'd be freaking awesome.
Rym: well imagine the idea of I'm hosting a website that is actually on my phone being served to the world from it live and The information about what I'm doing is there.
Rym: and if I browse to like your phone I can see what you're doing and we can have like this dynamic data and information sharing.
Scott: Mm-hmm All kinds of crazy stuff is gonna happen.
Rym: So that's all kind of Kurzwaldian convergence future.
Scott: No, but I mean, you know Kurt's Waldy And who's Kurt's Wald?
Scott: It's Kurt's while and he's crazy.
Scott: But the yeah, the drobo FS is that kind of thing?
Scott: so that's you know, if I if I start running out of see I think is I have more storage now because I got a one terabyte drive in the Home theater PC and a one terabyte in the desktop and a whole bunch of other drives.
Scott: but if I start running low on the storage or maybe what I'll do is you know, I'll I'll get.
Scott: I can get one of these when I get a bunch of extra money and Buy a couple drives stick them in there and put all my extra drives in there, too.
Scott: You know, yeah, I just have one and then put solid states in the computers.
Rym: See I'm holding off right now, but I plan to buy something like that soon basically to be the permanent media archive for GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah, we definitely need something like that for my personal stuff.
Rym: I don't need it that much.
Rym: I mean my computer can host all the data.
Rym: I can put a separate little secure raid.
Scott: Yeah, that's.
Scott: the other problem Is that when you have a desktop computer right you can just shove a bunch of drives in it and you're like well What the hell do I you know?
Rym: Yep, and I need backups But you know what?
Rym: a one terabyte external eyes like scuzzy like external SATA drive crazy cheap I think.
Scott: what though it's good for right is let's say you have all laptops or iPads and phones But you don't want any desktops Yep.
Scott: Then you get one of these babies.
Scott: shove it in the corner and you are rocking the house.
Scott: Connect your laptop to the TV and you can load up a zillion videos.
Rym: You know where else is great college dorms and places where many geeks live together.
Scott: You just get like one for like, you know half a floor college dorm.
Rym: you all get together Like if you're in one of those computer science house kind of things you all pitch in like with your club.
Rym: Buy one and you just everyone who moves into the floor inherits the ever-growing data set Oh shit, which is primarily porn and mp3s.
Scott: I just said the one kid who's got mad money can copy the whole thing.
Scott: What when he leaves?
Rym: but maybe alumni you you set up a kind of secret deal.
Rym: Alumni have the right to come back with their own drobo and just copy the whole thing.
Rym: Yeah So things of the day.
Rym: this was shown to us by the right honorable Lord Darryl Surratt at anime hell at anime, Boston And I should say this for Wednesday.
Rym: I had not seen it before and I could have saved it for Wednesday as Scott pointed out.
Rym: but in the interest of cross-pollination I think anyone can enjoy this now in case you can't tell us have some technology to it.
Rym: This guy is clearly taking the piss.
Rym: He still cracks himself up toward the end.
Rym: He is definitely doing this for humor and this is not legitimate, but this is some of the funniest shit.
Rym: I've seen in a while.
Rym: Basically, I don't really want to spoil it.
Rym: But basically the premise is a young man a young anime fan.
Rym: He likes his soul eater and his bleach and his Naruto which is you know, that's kind of that's the popular anime fan And a lot of anime fans forget that.
Rym: that's the kind of stuff that gets people in.
Scott: But anyway, the thing is I've seen like, you know for up, you know Actually, I saw like 13 episodes Naruto and four of bleach.
Scott: So I think I had to watch like four or so leaders just just to know what it.
Rym: what it's about It bothers me because I like the style of so leaders so much that I want to like the show.
Scott: I'm so desperately afraid that is just gonna be fighting after like 10 episodes probably but I'm just gonna see the dealers.
Rym: There's this upstanding young gentleman wanted to watch his soul leader and a few minutes in it was not so.
Rym: But it was in fact the Rick roll the Rick roll.
Rym: You just got to watch this to see what I mean.
Rym: This is frickin hilarious.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: That's good It's up there.
Rym: It's not a college humor.
Scott: Oh Yeah, so anyway, I was just discussing this a minute ago, huh coincidence my news and thing of the day are related, right?
Scott: There's a problem lately with you know, the fact that we don't get static IP addresses and dynamic DNS is shaky, right?
Scott: so if you want to do something like I don't know host a game server so that people can connect to it and you get your game on like when Left 4 Dead or your NS or something or maybe you want to send a file from directly from your computer to your friend's computer across the internet or Anything like this, right?
Scott: You've got to like open up ports on your router and then sometimes that doesn't work, right?
Scott: And UPnP is just a disaster.
Scott: and there's all this stuff and it's a huge pain in the butt and people, you know Sometimes the guy on the other end doesn't know how to do it or it doesn't work or his routers weird and you know It used to be the back in the day.
Scott: You know people would just connect directly to each other over the internet with no problem because people didn't use routers people did just plug.
Rym: It's not because most people who were playing these games didn't have static IPS.
Rym: Even then they got a dynamic IP from like their cable modem.
Rym: The only time it was easy is when you're on an IPX fucking LAN.
Rym: Yeah that too or you're using some sort of crazy multiple modem dial.
Scott: the thing is it used to be easier, you know.
Scott: And now I take it Having been easier nowadays, right you got Skype which has to do like some crazy nap busting by connect.
Scott: You know it.
Scott: basically there's the middleman Skype server and you talk to it and the other guy talks to it and then it hooks You up, you know, it's like a matchmaker and that's the way that they get around this stuff and that's why Skype works.
Scott: Otherwise Skype would not work at all.
Scott: So The thing is a huge pain in the ass and you don't want to have this middleman, right?
Scott: This is why the thing that bothers me the most is now we have things like, you know, mega upload.
Scott: You're right pretty much that routers are keeping mega upload in business right, so What can we do?
Scott: and some guys came up with this somewhat ingenious solution.
Scott: they pronounce it po-net.
Rym: I continue.
Scott: I will till the day I die pronounce potent the way I first pronounced it when I discovered the word Yes, I will pronounce it po-net and basically what it is is a proxy server that works behind a net.
Scott: So in other words, they do some crazy magic right that Rym could explain and I only half understand it.
Rym: Basically, they use a clever trick of one side is pinging an IP address that clearly does not exist and from and it associates with a certain port and then the other side Tries to connect to the external IP address of one.
Rym: as long as one party knows the other party's external IP at all then you're all in business and it pulls some shenanigans and basically both parties discover each other's external IPs and Then use this clever trick to establish a connection and then you're good.
Scott: Yeah, and it's a proxy server So it can proxy anything.
Scott: So you basically get the pone at hooked up and then you can send anything over it once it's you know Going and I tested it and it worked.
Scott: I got two virtual machines on two different nets Talk to each other.
Rym: it uses some ICMP shenanigans that could a smart network admin could prevent.
Scott: It's probably not gonna work in your office, but you know where it's gonna work.
Scott: three links is yeah It's gonna work through the links is just fine.
Scott: So if you're at home and your friends at home and you want to send them a file Right or you know, you're at home and your friends at home and you don't want to use hamachi to play a game.
Rym: See now this is it.
Rym: All we have to do is combine put ahead with all the functionality that waste was supposed to give us.
Scott: That's my plan.
Scott: Right, so you just get an SCP.
Rym: Oh, it's your thing of the day is Scottish you're talking.
Scott: Yeah No, but the thing of the day is the pun at itself, but you know This could be used right to just get people connect to each other get the encrypted file transfer going on.
Scott: So this is pretty awesome and I'm gonna see, you know, if it continues to work and they continue to work on it I mean, it's open source.
Scott: I'm gonna see what I can do.
Scott: Yeah, eventually I'm working on the website.
Rym: I'm gonna play with it a little bit and see if you could.
Rym: you know My network my knowledge of networking.
Rym: I'll bet we could make it a little bit better have so, you know It relies on that one IP address.
Rym: I feel like you could set up some sort of seated rotation of the IP address to make it even better.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Now before we do the main bit.
Scott: I haven't met a moment met a moment.
Rym: We almost forgot.
Scott: so Here are some items.
Rym: number one book club is cosmos.
Scott: book club is cosmo Sagan.
Scott: read it We're giving you some extra time mostly because I'm waiting for him to finish reading so I can get that copy.
Rym: I don't want to buy a copy of cosmos.
Scott: I've been by.
Scott: I just keep forgetting to buy it when I order other shit on Amazon.
Scott: the Anyone who like applied to the forums recently if you did not get an email approving you saying like yes You are in the forum.
Scott: Well, guess what you're in and you just didn't get the email.
Scott: so go to the forum and just sign in with whatever your password Was and you'll be all right.
Scott: Yeah, I moved the forum to a new server So it should be faster now and the email should be working.
Scott: so if the email from the forum isn't working when you know from now on let me know because it's a problem.
Scott: and Also Rym, I would like you to go now on your computer to shop.
Scott: front row crew.
Scott: calm and tell me what you see there.
Rym: Is it gonna be a picture of me failing in some way?
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: front row crew.
Rym: Yeah, I can just click on the shop.
Scott: you could you could do that as well.
Rym: You're my fancy a dos keyboard Mm-hmm.
Rym: All right for a crew that comes loading kind of slow, but that's fine.
Scott: Yeah, I got to move that to.
Scott: I'm gonna move that to another new server.
Scott: It'll be faster then.
Scott: not bad How you like that.
Scott: not bad at all?
Rym: Thing is I might we'll see.
Rym: I'm looking at to pay to code to cover my ass.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: I don't know How that rolls.
Rym: But yeah, the worst thing is I have a like 80% functional magento running on my laptop in a VM.
Rym: Good job thing is it wasn't 100% and it was open to fraud as I figured out.
Scott: Yeah, good job.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Anyway Does that cover the meta moment?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We don't have any big cons coming up ConnectiCon.
Rym: if you want to do a panel at ConnectiCon we're in charge and we're looking for tech panels.
Rym: Not just anime.
Scott: Yeah, we're looking for anything that is any geekery even if it's like an offside, you know If you want to do it a panel about like car modifications about Frickin, I don't know model train.
Scott: if you know Lego panel would be cool.
Rym: You can think of someone cool that you think we should invite to ConnectiCon as a guest.
Rym: Let us know.
Scott: Yeah, and don't like, you know aim too high.
Scott: Don't be like.
Scott: hey bring Bill Gates and Steve Jobs.
Scott: It's like dude, don't even bother them.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: what else can we do?
Scott: You know give us like, you know reasonable things, you know, that'll help.
Scott: and it would also help.
Scott: You know, if like if you email these people yourself, you know If there's someone you know or I'd be like ribbon Scott.
Scott: Oh, yeah, cool If there's someone you have a better connection to right don't just tell us hey get this person right try to you know Introduce us to that person through you if you're closer to them.
Scott: That's how this thing work.
Rym: is that makes you awesome, right?
Scott: Alright, so for the first time in like a century we have a guest on the GeekNights host.
Scott: No, we're still.
Scott: we're still discussing whether it's a guest host or not, I think it's a guest host.
Scott: Anyway, our guest host here is our friend and now Emily's co-worker who she seems to be really good at turning friends in the co-workers.
Scott: Conrad what's up?
Scott: Hello everybody.
Guest: How's it going?
Rym: So Conrad is a technological wizard.
Rym: We've known him for a long time.
Rym: He's kind of an expert in his field kind of kind of please.
Scott: I I'm pretty sure he's better at coding than me.
Scott: I mean he went to work at like AMD and stuff and I went to work with like, you know, I did that.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I probably wouldn't be able to do that job.
Guest: It actually they had me doing a PHP web development.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Okay, I thought you were doing like.
Guest: well, actually I got to do a little bit of the SIMD intrinsic program.
Scott: Yes Yeah, that's why I could.
Scott: I could have done the PHP.
Scott: I couldn't have done the whatever else you were talking about.
Guest: Yeah, no, that's actually where I taught myself PHP and HTML and CSS which led me down an awful freelance The.
Guest: the moral of the story here is don't go to work for AMD.
Guest: No, that's not the moral of the story.
Guest: The moral of the story is don't go to work doing freelance web development.
Guest: Yeah, that's the real story.
Rym: It's such a jungle.
Rym: I couldn't deal with it.
Guest: It's awful, man.
Scott: But anyway, you know It has been in great demand for an incredibly long amount of time for us to do some sort of show about you know telome phones and It seems that with the news that is about lately notice.
Scott: We avoided any cell phone news during the news part of the show.
Rym: I had like three.
Scott: we got three tech people on the show.
Scott: We got hot cell phone news.
Scott: I think that's what we should talk about.
Scott: So let us begin right?
Scott: I think a good way to get started is a little question here.
Scott: If you could just if you had no contract and you could buy any phone right today in the United States, right?
Scott: What do you do?
Rym: So am I going to get a contract when I buy the phone?
Scott: Well, I mean no you can give it.
Scott: you have a clean slate.
Scott: You could do anything that is, you know, actually available.
Scott: So you could get a contract.
Scott: I'm saying like you could go get something from boost mobile.
Scott: You could do whatever you want.
Rym: all the stuff I want is on the horizon.
Rym: So I would wait.
Rym: I'd wait about four months.
Guest: Unfortunately, he brings up a good case right now the market.
Guest: I mean, there's some good stuff out there, right?
Guest: The Motorola droids been tearing it up a little bit.
Guest: the palm pre plus is pretty good But there's definitely a lot of stuff coming up.
Guest: That is it would make it worth holding out for two months.
Guest: that said if I had to go and get a new phone today because I I'm rocking the HTC droid Eris, which I really want to get a new phone today So well, we got a good coverage here.
Scott: I got an iPhone 3G.
Scott: All right, he's got the Android rims got the Free so we.
Scott: the only thing we haven't covered is like Windows Mobile Blackberry, but I've had Blackberry in the past.
Rym: I have a Blackberry.
Scott: Yeah, you got a Blackberry for work.
Rym: I turned it off cuz I don't want to screw up the audio.
Rym: So we got.
Scott: we have pretty good coverage here in terms of you know, knowing what's up.
Rym: I think what bothers me I think we can all agree on this that there's no phone that does everything like every one of them has.
Rym: it's not just like.
Rym: They're all kind of mediocre.
Rym: Everyone has a fatal flaw, but they all have fatal flaws.
Rym: Mm-hmm quite I mean the pre is kind of a. the hardware broke immediately.
Rym: This is my second one.
Rym: It's only been a year.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know the iPhone.
Scott: it's like I had this great interface, but it's like all the apps cost frickin money You know and any you know I mean like the meebo app for instant messaging didn't come out until very very recently and until then I was pretty much suffering with No instant messaging whatsoever, right?
Scott: I can't do more than one exchange account at a time and all this other stuff.
Scott: You know iPhone 4 is gonna like fix a lot of these problems But it still has the problem of I can't do anything with it.
Rym: What about the drawer though?
Rym: Isn't the droid?
Rym: Perfect?
Guest: No, not quite the opposite.
Guest: In fact, I just wrote it was a five or six page article on my blog that basically Itemizes the problem with Android.
Guest: most notably.
Guest: you can do everything with it and it lets you do everything Which is actually a bad idea for a cell phone.
Guest: When you try to run six seven applications at once.
Guest: Yeah, you're looking at terrible slowdowns laggy interface bad battery life literally.
Scott: But I mean, but all these apps are written in Java right running in like a VM.
Guest: So it's a cut down version of Java.
Scott: Yeah, so I mean if they were written like straight to the like an ARM assembly, right?
Scott: Maybe wouldn't have the problems.
Guest: you know, I mean I think if even the the VM included like just-in-time compilation and like hot code pass code path caching I think that it we would see substantial improvements.
Scott: I think that's what iPhone does right.
Scott: the iPhone has like the LLVM.
Guest: Yeah, the LLVM dynamically optimizes.
Guest: it dynamically optimizes compiled code Whereas we don't even have a just-in-time compiler in Android yet.
Rym: So I think more of the problem is just the developers making very kind of far-reaching 80% solutions to everything as opposed to making a very focused slick solution.
Guest: Yeah Google in particular is actually like the first party in this case is the most at fault in my opinion and you look at it.
Guest: For example, I want you to go into your gmail app right now and copy and paste something out of an email.
Rym: Actually, that was fine on the pre because it comes with its own Built-in mail app that does Gmail perfectly.
Scott: Well on this iPhone I can go into the actual mail app, which I have hooked up to Copy paste or I can go to Gmail's website in mobile Safari and copy paste.
Guest: Yeah, technically I could go to the website, but I mean, it's it's a Google phone.
Guest: I have a Gmail app and yet you can't copy text out of an email not even in reply mode.
Rym: So, you know the only reason by the Google phone is because I have all Google stuff.
Rym: So I want to go all in with Google, but the Google works better on the pre In some cases.
Guest: Yeah also I might I might add that I actually bought an application to scrape my Google reader feed because Google didn't release any kind of reader application.
Guest: and Meanwhile, you'll all be very pleased to know that they integrated buzz into maps so you can find out who is buzzing in your neighborhood.
Scott: If I could use well, I mean if you look at the iPhone right some of the best apps are actually like Google stuff.
Scott: Right, like the mail is only awesome because it's Google in there.
Scott: You can even hook up to Google through exchange, you know with the active sync in the iPhone mail app.
Scott: Right, you have the actual Google app with the voice search action going on.
Scott: You know the Google Maps and the iPhone is friggin great.
Scott: We know what Apple Maps give me.
Scott: you know, that doesn't exist.
Scott: and if it did give me a break, right?
Scott: The thing is this Google Maps doesn't really get updated ever, you know Like it doesn't have the bicycle directions.
Scott: I have to go to the web to get the bicycle direction because that's a new feature.
Guest: mine doesn't have them either though That's a new.
Scott: it's a new feature on the real Google Maps on the website.
Rym: I gotta see if mine does and this is the problem.
Scott: I mean, it's like.
Scott: all I really need is I used mostly Google stuff.
Scott: Like I live on Google in my web browser.
Scott: So all I really need is a phone that is like just as awesome as the Google web pages.
Scott: But it doesn't.
Scott: it just doesn't.
Scott: it's like a poor facsimile of the Google web pages.
Guest: Yeah, you know as you know coming from Android I hate to say it, but I echo that sentiment, you know It's getting better though, you know particularly in the Android scene, you know in the interest of full disclosure I'm running 2.1 on the Aris using the weak OTA.
Guest: Well, you know 1.5 which this device ships with is literally insufferable.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have a co-worker who switched from the 1.5 on his on his Samsung moment to have sung moment.
Scott: The moment is like.
Scott: this is like a low-end Android device you can get from Sprint.
Scott: they're coming out of digital abortion.
Scott: Yeah, they're coming out with the moment - he liked it though Cuz it had a keyboard.
Scott: where it's like the Aris doesn't have the keyboard.
Scott: He wanted the physical keyboard and you know, honestly, it does have the nicest physical keyboard.
Scott: Yeah, like nicer than the droid one even.
Guest: yeah, I was really unimpressed with the droid keyboard.
Guest: Yeah I mean I own an Aris which should tell you.
Scott: Yeah, right, but the the thing is he up.
Scott: he did at you know, the hack upgrade 2.5 and It like.
Scott: he lost all his contacts.
Scott: But because it was syncing with Google contacts all the contacts on the phone were erased.
Scott: Then it synced and erased all his Google contacts on Google.
Guest: that actually really surprises me because during my flash It was quite the opposite.
Guest: it, you know, everything was pushed up to Google.
Guest: So when I flashed my phone, it just pulled all my contacts back from Google and I was like, oh well That was a pleasant surprise and I use an HTC phone.
Guest: So it hooks up with Facebook.
Guest: So if I'm friends with you on Facebook, I automatically have your phone number added to my my thing which is More than once.
Guest: yeah HTC in my opinion like they provide like a best-in-class interface You you can't do better on Android than HTC.
Guest: sense.
Rym: See.
Rym: the thing is though with my pre it kind of it's weird.
Rym: on the apps the app There's no App Store.
Rym: on the pre I would basically say there's no app worth getting on a web OS except like the Twitter app.
Rym: But so sad came with everything like the Google Maps and all this stuff came with it and is built in and supported by The company.
Rym: that's not going to exist anymore.
Rym: Well, I I think that they will exist, you know, obviously today they were announced that they're up for sale We have which I think was a preemptive move because they they want people to buy them, but they want it to be a war.
Rym: They don't want Google to be like, alright, that's your stock price for buying you.
Scott: See the thing is I think I get the feeling Google's just really stupid like I you know Like.
Scott: in some ways Google is geniuses like the search engine.
Scott: only geniuses could make that thing work, right?
Scott: But on the other hand, they're morons Like why does their UI suck like they have so much money, right?
Scott: They couldn't they just hire someone and make a better UI than Apple code.
Scott: Well, look at what I can.
Scott: they do it.
Rym: Look what happened to web.
Scott: Oh, there's that geniuses.
Scott: How come their UI sucks?
Rym: They just got formal at former Apple people instead do something similar.
Guest: Yeah, and when they did it they did it expertly.
Guest: Palms web OS is beautiful.
Guest: It's incredibly.
Scott: Well, yeah, the hardware is a little flaky.
Scott: Yeah, like the durability of like the iPhone or anything like but like navigating through this thing and just using the phone.
Rym: I think it's far and away the best interface Multitasking implementation far in a way Five apps at the same time and tab between them with no trouble.
Guest: You know, it's and that's the important part is the the ability to control what apps are running.
Guest: This is a glaring omission from Android style.
Guest: Obviously, you can go and download a task management.
Guest: Right, but I consider like you want to talk about an 80% solution.
Guest: Yeah downloading a third-party application that lets you manage Windows solution right there Something Windows doesn't have.
Scott: I know I'll go get something else to clog up my system tray.
Rym: get the power tool.
Rym: I actually like how a lot of people are running that hack on the iPhone that basically gives you the cards that web OS has.
Rym: Yeah, that's really hacked together in shoddy way.
Guest: I just saw it yesterday.
Guest: actually It's nice to have it but and yeah, like cards the best the best implementation of multitasking on a mobile device.
Rym: I'm really excited about who's gonna end up getting palm because someone's gonna get palm, right?
Scott: But I mean it's like so ideally right Google would get palm.
Scott: They would put the palm guys on the task of making a brand new Android UI which doesn't suck ass.
Rym: No, they should drop Android take web OS and just extend it.
Scott: No, cuz they already Android has a lot more apps for it and everything.
Guest: All right Yeah, I'll go 50/50 with you there web OS is HTML CSS based.
Guest: So there's literally no reason why you could Build a layer.
Scott: they could get the the web OS apps to run on the Android.
Scott: I mean, they're both Linux at the bottom, right?
Scott: You can merge them.
Scott: the thing is in merging them would Google actually allow them to take the UI where they needed to go?
Scott: Because I read this blog post where you know is a story about this guy who went to work on Google to like do the UI.
Scott: he was the UI genius.
Scott: You know that supposedly would fix everything and apparently Google was doing all this stupid shit that pissed him off like they had to test like 40 different shades of blue and they actually collected like a B tested all of them against each Other and all this crazy stuff that like drove him insane.
Scott: So he left.
Rym: dude, you got to focus on the gestures working before you worry about what shade of blue I know and I mean look at like it's.
Scott: it's all these little things that people Don't realize you know, like look on the palm pre one thing that it does that actually beats.
Scott: The iPhone is like the camera.
Scott: you could push the button.
Scott: It just takes a picture immediately like Yeah I can double tap like diggity-diggity.
Rym: It's like picture picture picture picture.
Guest: Yeah, my device is also incredibly slow.
Scott: I was in the eyes right a slow iPhone.
Scott: I pushed the take picture button.
Scott: It's like chick-chick Chick-chick and then there's a picture has been taken.
Scott: Yeah, you know about but I mean the.
Scott: you know the.
Scott: the iPhone especially in the iPod Department is what really has a lot of things that no one else can do.
Scott: the media playing at everything else Good for a little while.
Scott: Yeah Well, but I mean think about this right?
Scott: It's the same old thing.
Scott: How many years have I been asking for this feature on any device other than an iPod?
Scott: you start listening to a podcast on?
Scott: iTunes you sync you press play on your iPod.
Scott: it picks up where you left off.
Scott: you sync back to iTunes.
Scott: It picks up where you left off.
Scott: Does the Zune do that?
Scott: Maybe I don't know.
Guest: I haven't used one or tested it out but actually I wonder if I had to pick a candidate device that would be.
Scott: the Zune is probably the only thing and I Don't even know for sure if it does it.
Scott: and then even if it does it only did it recently, right?
Scott: Well, then I pod has been doing it since the iPod mini in 1990 like when I was in college, okay So, you know these kinds of small detailed things pick up on this.
Scott: every device should do all this stuff.
Guest: It's a double-edged sword because that kind of control you're talking about comes at a level of Integration that not many other companies are prepared to offer.
Guest: and part of that integration part of the price you pay for that integration I think is the closed nature of the device.
Rym: necessarily He's got a good point because look at this the iPhone the most closed has kind of the slickest everything going on.
Rym: at least the things That's the most well like you're playing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Meanwhile, look at the Windows 7 phones coming out.
Rym: They're less closed I think than Apple.
Rym: at least they're going to be less closed and they're not as slick.
Rym: but Zune is pretty much like the next Step down from iPod in terms of media playing and you can say it looks less slick.
Guest: But the comps that are coming out of Redmond right now look fantastic.
Guest: The metro UI leaps and bounds above six five and I think that they're catching up quickly.
Guest: I believe that they've surpassed Android for sure.
Guest: I think that Android is incredibly clunky.
Guest: They've gone past Andrew.
Guest: I think they're catching up to palm.
Rym: Well, and see the thing is I can't say until I use it because I look at those videos and you see like the very Text-based kind of light on dark text and these big like.
Rym: I don't know if that actually works.
Scott: when I'm it works pretty well.
Scott: I mean in like the Windows Media Center app, you know, they got on the HT PC But the Zune HD has that style.
Scott: Yeah, the Zune HD also, you know people seem to like that.
Scott: It's not a great screen.
Scott: That's for sure.
Guest: Yeah, I played with it for a little bit in a store.
Guest: I was really curious about it And I mean what.
Guest: obviously it was for like five minutes But I had a very positive experience with it and bringing that design element to win.
Scott: That's a big thing.
Scott: is that the reason I got the iPhone originally despite even being upset with a closed nature at that time?
Scott: Right was?
Scott: you know, it was the iPhone 3G.
Scott: it came out.
Scott: the apps came out at the same time, right?
Scott: It was because I wouldn't need an iPod and a phone at the same time.
Scott: I could just have one thing instead of two things, right?
Scott: That is the.
Scott: still the number one reason for me to get a smartphone is because I can have.
Scott: I won't need a separate iPod If I go to get an Android and I need to go buy an iPod mini from the Apple Store.
Scott: What is the point?
Scott: I might as well just go get like a freaking candy bar phone for five bucks and my iPod.
Rym: But at the same time as much as I want convergence I don't think we're anywhere near having one device that does everything because Apple won't make it happen.
Rym: Apple has the power to make this and they won't.
Guest: they're trying.
Guest: OS 4 obviously brings in a lot of.
Rym: That's what bothers me because you look at this every time like anyone is close to competing with Apple.
Rym: They're like, oh, here's the three features We left out.
Rym: there were obvious that we probably already made and now we're giving them to you.
Guest: I'm not just talking about multitasking in this case.
Guest: Honestly the game market that they they announced kind of caught me off guard.
Guest: I wasn't prepared for that and it actually Rochelle and I had several discussions about it.
Guest: regarding convergence like you were talking about She was you know convinced that the iPhone would never take over a Nintendo space the DS, you know, I love my DS.
Guest: I wouldn't ever use my phone to play games But I mean this is the direction that Apple is headed in now and when they throw their weight behind something They can make it happen, you know,
Rym: actually that raises a good point because the only other company that is wanted to do that Sort of thing is Microsoft.
Rym: They're the all the people who also want commodity hardware and then your games are just apps that you sell All right.
Scott: So in terms of games, right?
Scott: Here's the reason I think that the iPhone really can't replace the DS.
Scott: You know like in terms of you know a game on the iPhone something like this flooded game or a little bejeweled, right?
Scott: Totally awesome, right?
Scott: I'm on I'm all over that right but it think of like the games I'm playing on my DS my clash of heroes, right?
Scott: Maybe some Phoenix Wright something like that, right?
Scott: You're gonna you know pay 30 bucks for this something like that, right if you're buying it You know and then you put it on a phone and you replace your phone every two years You know because your contracts run out Maybe you know you like to sell your phone and get it to.
Scott: you know pay for the new one or something You know, especially if it's expensive smart But that's probably exactly what Apple is going for.
Rym: they want to lock people in if you buy a hundred games on your iPad iPhone but the thing is because it because I know I'm getting rid of it.
Scott: I'm not buying the games.
Rym: Yes, but that's you and you're not.
Guest: it's they transfer over.
Guest: This is you you purchase a license.
Guest: You can install those applications on another device.
Guest: Absolutely.
Rym: You can.
Rym: so my pre.
Guest: so if I so I see.
Rym: What if I want to leave Apple?
Guest: I'm sorry.
Guest: I thought you meant that one device That you're on one device.
Rym: They care that you're on Apple.
Scott: I mean at least even Nintendo Nintendo's totally closed, right?
Scott: No question about it, but you buy a GBA game.
Scott: You could play that shit on a DS light, right?
Scott: You buy you know Not a DSI, but you know, they always keep like two generations.
Guest: Yeah, everything's got an expiration date.
Scott: Nothing's perfect You know, but I mean, you know, your DS is not.
Scott: your DS is not like your phone where it's got a contract.
Scott: You're gonna get rid of it and you're getting.
Scott: you know, it's like, you know, you're always gonna carry, you know something.
Scott: It's it's I don't know.
Scott: It's more like it's a permanent kind of thing.
Guest: I don't know.
Guest: It's still vendor buy-in You know, you're still buying into a Nintendo product.
Guest: You're not gonna be able to bring that DS game over to your Sony PSP Go, no, you're stuck on Nintendo hardware, but your current.
Scott: It's not about being stuck on the hardware with a DS because you're you buy a DS and you just you just have it forever.
Scott: But a cell phone is more of a disposable electronic item as opposed to like a DS or a Wii Permanent people don't think of their phones as disposable.
Rym: only nerds like us do.
Rym: Look at this.
Guest: Yeah, I mean a palm free puzzle cost you 600 bucks at the store new I you know, it wears a DS will cost you too.
Guest: So I don't know.
Guest: I think the you know.
Scott: We've said when the contract the thing is right.
Scott: when the contract runs out on that palm free plus in two years You're gonna get a new phone.
Scott: and if you don't get another web OS phone goodbye to all your web OS.
Scott: two years of investment.
Scott: Right sitting with the iPhone.
Scott: It's like, you know, if I go to the iPhone 4, you know, it's like well Goodbye all my iPhone 3 stuff.
Scott: because if I'm gonna carry two devices The second device is gonna be iPod nano.
Scott: It's not gonna be two smartphones.
Guest: Yeah to say.
Guest: but again I mean you could.
Guest: in that case you certainly can install Your old apps on the new phone.
Scott: if I get an iPhone, right if I switch to Android it's all gone.
Scott: No, so then if I switch to Android and I feel like I might switch to Apple I'm not gonna start investing that heavily in Android either.
Scott: Yeah, because I want to be free to pick the best OS two years from now.
Scott: hmm All right,
Rym: it just amazes me that a long time ago I was so like I was a Nintendo fan Just talking about gaming and I remember thinking, you know, what Microsoft or the Xbox said we want You know just PCs and you run just games on anything and it's commodity.
Rym: and I thought they like that was the worst possible thing That could happen to game.
Scott: I always thought it was great.
Rym: now.
Rym: I think it's the only thing that can save gaming.
Rym: Yeah, at least gaming the way I like it.
Rym: but I don't know.
Rym: I don't think cell phone games are just There enough for it to matter.
Guest: yet to be part of the problem is control.
Guest: the input scheme on them is particularly difficult.
Scott: Well, if it's a real-time game, that's true, right but like Phoenix, right?
Scott: I just brought up right Phoenix, right would totally rock on a phone with a touch screen.
Scott: The problem is the long form of it might not work.
Scott: So well, you're gonna pay $30 for Phoenix, right?
Scott: It works really well on your phone.
Scott: touch the evidence.
Scott: touch what you're investigating it.
Scott: battery runs out battery runs out.
Scott: Who's and who sits there with their phone for that long?
Scott: You know, I mean I could sit there with a DS for a long time But to sit there with my phone for that long, you know and it rings while I'm playing the fucking game.
Scott: Oh, no You know fuck that shit It doesn't work.
Rym: well that could work if people were willing to like if Apple was gonna put the effort in but they're not gonna.
Rym: I don't think the iPhone or the iPad is going to be anything for gamers like us for a long time.
Rym: It's going to be the you know, the so-called casual ghetto games like Farmville.
Scott: Yeah, try to advance wars on the iPhone, right?
Guest: I think you get away with advance wars on an iPhone Why not?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: For one reason nobody I no one uses the actual touch interface.
Rym: This is terrible.
Rym: You sit there and use the plus and the a and the B.
Guest: Okay, that's right I was thinking about the touch interface.
Scott: But yeah in that in that particular Well, the thing is the DS does have a resistive touchscreen is a capacitive touchscreen.
Scott: It's far more precise.
Scott: It is screen is much higher resolution.
Scott: so you could zoom in right on your unit move them to the right with a little swipe Zoom out, you know, you could get a lot more creative than they do on the DS.
Rym: So yeah, you'd have to make a different mode of game though like advanced wars as is wouldn't really work.
Rym: Well, they'd have to change the game significantly.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I get more like a turn-based supreme commander kind of deal.
Scott: I thought I think it would work.
Scott: just fine.
Rym: I I could get into the way I play in the way I think and I'm why I think a lot of other advanced wars Players at least.
Rym: it's very discreet and when I'm strategizing I think up up left left left up up up left left.
Rym: I'm just thinking that as I'm like doing my motions.
Guest: Maybe it's just cuz you're used to it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I don't see.
Scott: I mean like zoom in on the units move up into the right.
Rym: There's no reason never zoom in in advanced wars.
Rym: That's the other problem.
Scott: Well giant maps, right?
Rym: I mean but advanced wars doesn't scale.
Scott: Well, no, it doesn't.
Scott: but you know, there are those big maps.
Scott: They have to pan around all the time.
Rym: very annoying Yeah, but they're not that big the game just I think the game doesn't scale enough and doesn't do enough interesting stuff.
Rym: Yeah, good.
Scott: The other thing is if you did it on something like an iPhone is much more powerful You know, you would do like a two and a half D kind of situation.
Scott: You wouldn't do the pixel, you know 2d art.
Scott: So you would.
Scott: you know the zooming in and out.
Scott: you could maintain like it wouldn't you know?
Rym: pixelate and get all jaggy But then you run out the battery.
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: I mean I got some tower defense games that are sort of like that.
Scott: Well, I deleted them cuz they saw me.
Rym: My pre lasts like, you know a whole day and then some like a day and a half two days if I just use it Normally, but if I surf the web or use run like apps on it, it doesn't even last through the day.
Scott: No, really my iPhone always makes it through the day like, you know, sometimes it gets really low if I'm at a convention But I always make it back to the hotel room and charge it up.
Guest: Yeah, this is why I complain about multitasking.
Guest: I'm gonna be flat with you.
Guest: This is why this is why I bemoan the decision.
Rym: sometimes Thing is I'm willing to trade every Disadvantage to have the multitasking because it it's such a paradigm that whenever I borrow an iPhone And like I'm responding to a text message and I want to check my email.
Scott: I'm fucked But the iPhone 4 is gonna have it.
Rym: I know so well.
Guest: Let me get let me get technical and complain about something for a second here and I'm really sorry to go off on this.
Guest: But Apple, I don't know.
Guest: Have you guys ever experimented with the Apple SDK the iPhone SDK?
Scott: But I mean, I know objective C is really painful.
Guest: No objective C is great.
Guest: I love objective.
Scott: Oh, yeah it brings the flexibility of programming in a high-level language to the speed of bring like working in a well level because what I look like It's it brings to me like, you know, like, you know sort of you know memories of the horrible syntax of C++.
Scott: but crook slightly.
Guest: so I The small talk syntax takes some getting used to.
Guest: I'll be the last person to disagree But ultimately I was I was you know, I felt very very natural in it.
Guest: The thing that really bothered me.
Guest: they released an operating system that didn't support multitasking but didn't support any under-the-hood state serialization and Restoration.
Guest: so essentially they gave you no hooks to save your program state and then restore it.
Guest: they just told you that you had to do it and I always thought that that was a really like.
Scott: there's no file system, right?
Guest: There is a file system.
Guest: you Obviously you can write stuff to the disk and that's the only way that developers were able to write their own state serialization codes.
Guest: But they didn't include it by default and I always thought that was a really.
Guest: I Didn't want to say like Apple was snubbing developers, but it was definitely like oh This is like an 80% like you definitely just push this out.
Scott: Well, they did add like how many new you know API.
Scott: they always brag about how many API's they've added.
Scott: I think they're counting like the individual functions, right?
Scott: Yeah, they're like we added hundreds of new API's like what did you add?
Scott: like you're counting each and every function that you added as one API.
Guest: I mean what is and I mean the stuff they had is always really useful.
Guest: But yeah, they didn't address this most basic problem with a non multitasking phone.
Guest: I as a developer I felt a little bit of spite and so I had to go off on that.
Guest: but it the story.
Guest: it needed to be heard.
Rym: We can pretty much end wrap this up I think unless we have some final thoughts on though Like where the where are we going?
Rym: Let's jump in right?
Guest: I palm up for sale.
Guest: HTC needs to grab them shore up their patent defense against Google or excuse me They didn't show up the patent defense against Apple And then they need to bring those engineers on and really kind of turn them loose on The the Android UI itself and Google really needs to take some cues from HTC because HTC picks up the slack Everywhere that Google
Scott: fails.
Scott: Well, I think Google really needs to just pick up the UI across the board.
Scott: They've just been.
Scott: you know, I mean, you know Gmail still got the good UI.
Scott: Google search still really good.
Scott: But like all their new stuff you look at like Google buzz Google wave Android right there like making these like it looks like might as well just get no more Katie up in right to do that Kind of shit.
Rym: Never mind the fact that they have so much money.
Scott: There is no excuse to be you know, they should be able to.
Scott: why can no one make a good user interface?
Scott: But Apple right we're suffering.
Scott: we have to choose.
Rym: you know who can make it people who made a web OS But those are Apple guys, right?
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: why are the nerds are upset?
Scott: because we're forced to choose between good UI and a phone that actually Features that we want, you know, and it's not you know, not just in phones, but in everything.
Scott: Why are we forced to make this choice?
Scott: Why can't we have both Chris?
Rym: Part of it might be look at the.
Rym: you know The slicker phones the ones with better you eyes are also more closed more controlled.
Scott: But why does it have to be that way?
Guest: I actually read an article on slate the other day that ended in the sentence that the idea of a perfect computer and an open Computer are mutually exclusive concepts that they can never coexist.
Scott: Okay So here's here's what I have to say.
Scott: example number one the greatest computer that has ever existed the Apple to GS.
Scott: right the jobs was Combination.
Scott: right.
Scott: you look at this thing you turn it on.
Scott: It's beautiful.
Scott: It just turns on.
Scott: do nice noise You know amazing sound for the time the graphics just blew your mind and it just works.
Scott: It just works.
Scott: and thing is you open it up and the inside is just as much a thing of beauty.
Scott: eight slots Lined up all identical everything clearly labeled.
Scott: flat laid-out board power supply doesn't cover up anything that you need to access.
Scott: It's a straight line.
Scott: It is like the miracle of computing right?
Scott: so why can't we have a phone?
Scott: That's like the Apple to GS.
Scott: the inside is as beautiful as the outside.
Scott: You know it's open But you know all the decisions about design are still being made by one person.
Scott: if some schmuck wants to submit a patch that is freaking ugly as UI stuff Fucking rejected.
Scott: right.
Scott: that's how the Linux kernel works.
Scott: or if Linus doesn't like that shit It doesn't get in.
Rym: you know you can meet midway.
Rym: What if we just had the closed you know iPhone style phone by default?
Rym: But with the option of sideloading for people who are willing to risk screwing everything up.
Guest: yeah Yeah, I was.
Guest: actually I was gonna bring up the idea of once you give people that control you suddenly You know you lose a lot of the control over the user user interface and you expose yourself to a lot of problems.
Guest: But but why?
Scott: I mean 90% of people aren't gonna ever sideload anything And they're all gonna.
Scott: you know you could have this iPhone 3G.
Scott: just it is right now right and have nerd mode.
Scott: So I'm a nerd and I fuck it up right and then I just reset it reflash the firmware And I'm back to beginning if I ever fuck it up too much.
Scott: but my mom had the same exact phone.
Scott: she would never sideload a thing in her life and You know she would.
Scott: you should have the exact same perfect Steve Jobs Experience that it is right now where it's perfectly closed and all Apple has to do is just be like yeah, okay?
Scott: Here's you know one check box.
Scott: It's open.
Guest: now all Apple needs to do is support two entirely different modes of operation.
Scott: It's not too entirely.
Guest: Now you can't install paid apps because you're sideloading.
Guest: where are they gonna go?
Guest: the reason that half the reason that that phone is so Closed down you can't use target disk mode anymore half the reason is because these paid apps that you can't like they don't want you Just copying them off of there.
Guest: so by sideloading suddenly you lose all your paid apps.
Guest: you introduce this weird I mean.
Guest: obviously it doesn't sound like much like oh put another memory card in there But it does induce a lot of variables especially once it's like.
Guest: well You don't know if the memory card is gonna be inserted.
Guest: Android has a lot of problems with this.
Guest: You know you mount the memory card you copy your files over you unmount it.
Guest: It's got to itemize everything on the disk it.
Guest: You know it takes a long time to index.
Rym: Is this not just a matter of maturity?
Rym: I mean PCs were that way a long time ago.
Rym: I mean your PC.
Rym: You don't know if the.
Rym: you know your USB or 512 K stick is in or not and you unplug it.
Rym: you fuck the whole Thing up and you run some app and it crops the boot sector.
Rym: and PCs now are you know like Windows is a very controlled Experience by default now.
Rym: Let's ignore the the security holes for a second because that's more and more.
Rym: It seems like it's third-party things like Adobe that are causing a lot of that.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if they're worried about I want to get into that.
Scott: They're worried about piracy.
Scott: someone copying their paid apps off of there, right?
Scott: It's like come on people are already jailbreaking and pirating the paid apps.
Scott: The people who are you know the only people who are smart enough to copy the paid apps off and pirate them on.
Scott: you know An iPhone that has this mode where you could sideload.
Scott: are the people who are smart enough to jailbreak now?
Scott: So if they're doing it, they're already doing it.
Scott: You're not.
Scott: the piracy is not going to increase it absolutely would know.
Guest: Jailbreak penetration right now is only at about 10% of devices Which is almost nothing.
Guest: whereas if you offered side loading and an easy way to do this I can assure I can literally assure you that it would right.
Scott: but are those people who would side load?
Scott: would they you know?
Scott: Are they buying apps now and they wouldn't buy them if they could pirate them?
Guest: I I had tested at least some of them to say that there are no lost potential sales here.
Guest: It's it's short-sighted.
Scott: I don't think it's a large enough number.
Rym: I would say I would argue that just that isn't it not inevitable.
Rym: I mean, this is what happened with PCs.
Scott: Okay, DRM doesn't right plus alright, so, okay.
Scott: So let's let's go on to the assumption that most people right like, you know The moms and whatever would just continue as normal paid apps, whatever right.
Scott: there would be some nerds and some punk kids Right who are maybe buying some apps now who wouldn't buy them and would sideload and pirate, right?
Scott: But now take into that calculation all the nerds who would abandon Android palm this the mark.
Scott: everything else in the market would die.
Scott: Apple would have a monopoly on everything because there would be no complaints anymore.
Scott: No one would say all iPhone sucks at closed.
Scott: everyone would be on iPhone 100% across the board except the businessman who has to keep a blackberry.
Scott: and That increased sales of iPhones right would make up for all those lost sales of the piracy whatever Right, I mean if the iPhone was open who would not buy it?
Scott: who would buy something else?
Scott: who?
Scott: anybody anyone You know, is there anyone out there who would still choose Android if you could sideload on the iPhone?
Rym: Well, this is partly why I'd be a question.
Rym: Yeah, you're talking about the UI and I'm still like until I use them If he on the Microsoft phones the seven phones.
Rym: But I feel like that is where the middle ground is gonna be in the end because I think that that is going to have Much more capability for loading your own apps and having your own control.
Rym: I think it's gonna be the same paradigm as Windows.
Rym: You can cock it up to a certain degree But at the same time it gets you 80% of the way to having a nice experience.
Scott: I mean, yeah, no one's asking for Linux openness, you know What?
Guest: n 900?
Scott: Yeah, we're asking for Windows openness on that, you know OS X openness on the iPhone.
Scott: We're not asking for.
Scott: you know, give us the whole source code to the whole show.
Rym: That was what bothered me not the phone.
Rym: I don't want to get on a tangent here.
Rym: But the fact that the iPad was a 100% as closed as the iPhone.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I expected it to be a little more open and the fact that it wasn't.
Rym: now Miss under s miss estimating what Apple was trying to.
Scott: people aren't joking when they say it's a big iPod touch.
Scott: It's a big iPod touch.
Rym: That's it, but there's so much potential board games shared space games.
Scott: That is something that could make them for the App Store.
Scott: get them approved.
Rym: It wouldn't compete with the DS Just fine but people like us would all have iPads and we'd all play like Puerto Rico on them You know.
Guest: Actually, if we could bring this topic around for a second you mentioned that it's just a big iPod touch.
Guest: My question to you guys is is that bad?
Rym: It's bad for someone like me because the stuff that I want is probably never going to exist on that device.
Scott: Yeah, because I mean basically all I want in a tablet right is I want you know The good user interface and the really accurate, you know capacitive touchscreen.
Scott: But what would I do with a tablet?
Scott: There are two things I would do with it.
Scott: Number one is I would read the web in bed, which the iPod the iPad perfect.
Scott: Nothing better, right?
Scott: Well, what else would I do with it?
Scott: I would want to program all sorts of crazy shit like board games, you know to work when all my friends had them.
Scott: Absolutely can't do it.
Scott: So it's it's had you know, and it's so much money.
Scott: It's not worth it.
Scott: It was a hundred bucks to read the web in bed sold, right?
Rym: You know, that's the thing because I you know There's all the rumors about the Google tablet coming and Sam's everyone's making tablets.
Rym: Now the iPad is gonna have some stiff competition and those things are gonna just run windows.
Guest: Yeah I don't think they're gonna have any competition because they just run windows.
Rym: windows For people like me because for a $200 like if it was just good enough Like it was halfway to the goodness of the hardware of the iPad But there was but like reading the web in bed with like Firefox on a Windows tablet.
Scott: Forget it I might as well use my laptop.
Guest: Yeah, and once you pull windows on there You're talking about an Intel chipset an Intel hardware stack.
Guest: You're talking about five six hours of battery life tops.
Guest: You're not talking about what if it runs?
Rym: What if we run some sort of Windows 7 like halfway even further between Windows 7 and Windows?
Guest: Yeah, I would love it if they would put Windows Phone 7 onto a tablet.
Guest: I I mean I would be in line for that absolutely.
Scott: but what I'm saying can make it talk to the Xbox just like they've made the Zune and all the Windows computers talk to the Xbox.
Guest: that's absolutely slated for Windows Mobile 7 And I'm really excited about it.
Guest: But what I'm saying is our problem here is that we're attempting to take these desktop operating systems and use them on tablets.
Guest: And when everybody says it's just a big iPod touch.
Guest: I'm like, yeah That's what makes it great because the desktop operating system is not suited to a device of yeah of that build.
Scott: And so, you know, I it is a great UI, but it just doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't.
Rym: It's like, you know the BoS that died a long time ago where you know user interface like user input mattered more than most other Things in the OS.
Rym: we need a new Paradigm of UI which is basically just Apple quality, but Windows openness.
Rym: free as in beer not free as in speech.
Rym: I'd be fine with beer.
Rym: I don't even I don't care about the new stuff anymore at all at this point in my life.
Guest: It's me.
Guest: Yeah, I hate to say but when you look at what it's up against nowadays, it's it's literally difficult to and I'm positive.
Guest: I'll raise the ire of many with that statement.
Guest: But Linux has failed time and time again to catch up in the desktop space where the other contenders are.
Rym: I'm an IT professional using Linux forever.
Rym: I use Linux and like all the important stuff in my life except this show Except gaming except 90% of what I do with a computer outside of work.
Rym: I need Windows for that.
Rym: I run Linux in a VM for the one thing.
Scott: I mean, I have Linux on my laptop, but I got a Windows desktop a Windows home theater computer, right?
Scott: You know and I have Linux in a virtual machine when I need to do development stuff because that's what it rocks at.
Scott: You know, I have OS X at work at work.
Scott: I would like to have Linux because I'm developing at work, but I didn't get to choose, you know and Yeah, I mean, it's just Windows everywhere for servers and development.
Rym: I use Windows for everything else because it's it's open enough to do what I need to do But it starts I guess more usable and better.
Guest: Yeah I mean I use OS X because I almost couldn't give up the Unix shell.
Guest: I don't know what happened.
Guest: I became addicted at some point.
Scott: Definitely.
Scott: Yeah, I definitely, you know, I mean for if it was work with Windows I would be screwed and where I just be doing all my work and putty as a station to some other machine.
Scott: I'm doing that.
Scott: I might as well just have the other machine on my desk.
Scott: But
Guest: no, you know I use OS X on the desktop and exactly like you guys I keep the the Linux virtual machine around for when I need to Really mess around with Android or when I really need to, you know test something on a web server something like that.
Guest: You know, I couldn't imagine using it on the desktop and I feel like that's a pretty common statement.
Scott: Mmm It's unfortunate, but why don't they just freaking get someone to like, you know, there have to be you know.
Scott: Is it just that there are only like five people in the world who know how to make a good UI or like?
Scott: What is that?
Guest: maybe there's only five people in the world who can get enough people moving in the same direction to create a good UI.
Rym: I mean one thing that might have worked well for Apple is the very monolithic, you know You've got the figure at the top saying do it like this and fuck anyone who thinks otherwise.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, you know Linux has that a lot of projects have a leader who says Listen to what he says and go.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna fork it and then they make a half-ass fork.
Scott: They make a half-ass work that fails But as long as the core project lives on let them fork and leave.
Guest: it was actually the start of your sentence that damned it.
Guest: There are a lot of projects dot dot dot it's.
Guest: it's too distributed when you've got it.
Guest: rhythm box is a perfect example.
Guest: Rhythm box doesn't necessarily behave like you're at you know, like pigeon doesn't necessarily behave like Nautilus, you know You can attempt to wrangle all these developers into shape, but there will always be these slight differences
Rym: and think about evaporate out like developers will kind of just just Appear and get mad and fork off and maybe they'll work on another project.
Rym: But you've lost them.
Rym: and if the guys who did the UI like if there are three good guys doing UI and one of them Quits your project because he disagrees about whether or not they should be green or blue You've lost a third of your UI development.
Scott: See, I think that what we need is we need some sort of open source project where it's like you come into it But it's you know You it's.
Scott: the source is open as in.
Scott: everyone gets to see the code everyone sharing it Anyone can come and work on it, but the specs are dictated.
Scott: but you know There is someone who is making the decisions and you either code what they wanted you to code or we don't accept your patch.
Rym: Are you gonna work on a project like that?
Rym: Would that be fun?
Rym: If it was really freaking on it wasn't exactly a hundred percent the way you wanted it to be.
Scott: the thing is, right?
Scott: I mean if it's good if they've got like the demo up that convinces me like that The UI is really good.
Scott: Then I'm like if you you know, if someone put up an iPhone demo, right and was like Hey, we need people to work on this.
Scott: Here's the specs to make this awesome UI and you were like, holy shit But don't you need a jobs or a Wozniak some like visionary to be like look yeah the guy who made the demo.
Rym: So, where are these people?
Guest: I don't know.
Guest: they don't exist making money at Apple and palm exactly, right?
Guest: No, ultimately, you know, I Scott and I were discussing this on his blog at one point.
Guest: I think he's absolutely right, you know, like Plato said you need.
Guest: what did he say?
Guest: It was philosopher Kings in charge of the nation, but we need a philosopher King developer to stand and you know shine a beacon
Rym: Diocletian situation because if centralized governance of any project means that a smart philosopher King can make leaps and bounds They can make revolutions overnight and one asshole can ruin the whole thing.
Scott: How can you ruin the whole thing?
Scott: What's he gonna do?
Guest: Steve Jobs could make sure that you can't program in unity or flash on the.
Scott: So here's here's another right.
Scott: maybe instead of you know There's non-existent good UI creator who's gonna help us all out and design something for us to code up, right?
Scott: Why don't we just fucking copy the iPhone pixel per pixel?
Scott: Fuck them.
Scott: Just copy the shit right make an open-source identical clone.
Rym: What's the patent encumbers though?
Scott: Because they're what we reverse engineered it in a clean room.
Scott: No, right, right.
Rym: a sheer number of patents that all these companies have is I think the biggest.
Scott: I just given the finger.
Scott: It's the same way you get like, you know, the the DVD breaking codes from some server in Europe or the you know The video codec from some server.
Rym: Yeah, someone has someone has to do it and say I'm going to be the DVD on I'm going to take all the shit that is gonna fly my way.
Guest: So so we were just talking about the fact that if you fork a project and it's not quite as good Nobody's gonna use it.
Guest: Everybody's gonna use the good one.
Guest: How long do you think it would take?
Guest: how much effort do you think it would take to re-implement that UI from the bottom?
Guest: Up?
Guest: and even if you did do you ever think that you could get it as good as what Apple has done given how tightly Coupled they are to their hardware?
Rym: and look how fast Apple moves the moment the final when you finally get to.
Rym: I have done You know the iPhone for perfectly.
Guest: they've got iPhone 8 Yeah, and mono fights this battle every day and that's why they're still at dotnet.
Guest: what to five?
Guest: Yeah, maybe they have three now, but I'm not sure.
Scott: I think that's the what the thing is.
Scott: I think the real problem you just pointed out is at least you know in terms of phones Right?
Scott: is the hardware is gonna get you every time, you know, I mean, oh god We could talk an hour about the hardware you're gonna get.
Scott: you need to get.
Scott: you need to get touch screens that are this quality.
Scott: You need to get someone to assemble them as carefully right.
Scott: you need to get you know The whole package.
Scott: you need to get someone to shrink it down to the right size.
Scott: You got to get the right megapixel camera.
Scott: You got to get it all, you know, how are you gonna do that?
Scott: You know, you can't.
Scott: it's not open source.
Scott: You need some fucking money.
Guest: Well, I mean if HTC could you know sell a blank phone for four or five hundred dollars and you could sideload your own OS Into it.
Scott: I think they could be suckered into doing yeah, but you still won't have the the phone that is designed for the OS Tandem.
Scott: No exactly.
Guest: This is that's part of androids big problem.
Guest: We were going.
Guest: we talked about the Java VM earlier.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, you know look at all the different Android phones, right?
Scott: Okay, so it's like well How's my app gonna run?
Scott: and it's gonna run different.
Scott: on the droid I got.
Scott: you know I made an action game and just got keyboard controls if you don't have a keyboard while it's gonna be not as good I can only imagine.
Guest: it makes developing native code.
Guest: They have the NDK the native development could.
Guest: I can only imagine it makes developing native code very difficult.
Guest: now that they're talking about shipping atom powered Android devices now, how's that gonna work?
Scott: I'm what I'll be in the tablets.
Scott: They're not gonna ship phones with Adam.
Guest: Yeah, I was wondering how they're gonna deal with this NDK tie-in.
Guest: are they gonna emulate?
Scott: you're getting your codes gonna look like All the new code.
Scott: if deaf BSD.
Rym: if deaf, you know Yeah, if they have this right that that's the road to just disaster in the long run.
Guest: No, definitely I wouldn't really like.
Rym: in terms of the Linux world We have not come yet to the like final disaster of the fact that everything is so fractured.
Guest: I don't know.
Guest: Have you looked at a config script recently?
Guest: We might be looking at the end still works.
Scott: that's the problem because it's a miracle of all.
Scott: you know The.
Scott: that's why I keep talking about use Linux for development because the development toolset on Linux.
Scott: It's just so unbelievable in that it makes all this shit actually work, you know.
Guest: Unbelievable and byproduct of tenacity or two very different things.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean we're fucking.
Scott: I mean I don't know how to use autocomph, but it's what it's a Automaker the worst.
Scott: Yeah, but I download it and someone else used autocomph And I just yeah, I just typed dot slash configure and it's a miracle, you know.
Guest: And certainly a miracle it is again.
Scott: I used it once and I don't ever intend to go in the internet is just a miracle bunch of people packets hitchhiking from Here to there, right?
Rym: All right, I think we should wrap this up and I think we'll have to have future conversations.
Rym: I mean Hardware alone.
Rym: I have an hour about the fact that I love this keyboard and no one else does a keyboard as good as this.
Guest: Yeah, I hate those for physical keyboards.
Guest: I could go on for an hour about why I think they're not well suited for these devices.
Rym: So I think it'd be a good show Alright, so thank you gentlemen.
Rym: This was Conrad Kraling.
Rym: I'll just give a little.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Do you want to pimp anything?
Rym: You should pimp your awesome blog because our listeners.
Rym: Conrad is smart.
Guest: Yeah, my blog is k?
Guest: on is te?
Guest: H Excuse me.
Guest: Te?
Guest: h dev dot.
Guest: blog spot calm.
Guest: That's con is tech dev dot.
Guest: blog spot calm And I know I apologize for how corny that is.
Guest: I've got the one big actually.
Rym: There's two articles I submit to varak dot.
Rym: org slash blog.
Guest: You're fine I. There's two articles up right now.
Guest: one about why we shouldn't necessarily be fearing the iPad and why we should be looking forward to why?
Guest: Android is good.
Guest: And then the article that comes directly after it which is here's why Android is awful.
Guest: I Intend to update it more.
Guest: I'm gonna get the HTC incredible when it comes out.
Guest: I'm gonna revisit the.
Guest: I you know The Android interface I really has your your contract is over.
Guest: Well, I I'm just gonna buy one.
Guest: Oh, I'm so sick.
Guest: I'm literally so irritated with this awful device that I'm gonna buy a new phone.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I would have.
Guest: I would have probably gone to like the Verizon Nexus one, you know, something like that You know the contract wasn't being credible is sort of a repackaged Nexus one If you will, the Nexus one actually has like a kind of a bad touchscreen.
Guest: Oh, yeah Yeah It.
Guest: it performs really poorly with what's called near axis input Which is when your fingers get close together Like you put your fingers close together spread them apart and register your fingers in the opposite corners So that that's fixed on the incredible.
Guest: the incredible uses HTC's proprietary sense UI Which I find to be much more tasteful than the built-in androids.
Guest: I don't know if y'all ever looked at a stock Android UI.
Scott: It's really bad.
Guest: I think it's ugly as sin.
Guest: I don't know where they dug.
Rym: these people ever used some of the more raw X window or like the Athena widgets?
Guest: It's not quite that bad.
Guest: But I mean we're talking like AWT.
Guest: No, it's it's not like it's not gross.
Guest: They're just poorly designed.
Guest: Well, we're actually what we're talking about is KDE.
Guest: We're talking about plasma.
Guest: They wanted so hard to look cool But it just looks like stupid.
Guest: Yeah That's that's kind of where I'm coming from with that.
Guest: So I'm gonna revisit the article and you know, I want to get a palm pre.
Guest: I want to really play around with that.
Guest: So yeah, I mean if you want to if you want to come hit up my blog I'm gonna be doing a lot more with it And obviously I'm working at Muse games now, so we're gonna be doing some cool stuff in the future.
Guest: So be sure to check that out, too.
Rym: All right, so thank you gentlemen, and that pizza is probably getting cold.
Rym: Yeah Alright This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night Just fucking wind.
Scott: It's not okay.
Scott: It is cool summer.
Guest: It would be awesome.
Guest: But the second it got cold out.
Guest: you'd be like, oh fuck my.
Scott: but then so cool I could wear the wool hat like all day like inside.
Scott: It would just be like, what's up, I guess I can get like an array of hats Scott's myriad of hats I got you know, I'd have a hat rack like the heavy.
Guest: you got hats on top of hats.
Scott: That's we still didn't do our plan, you know the little gospel elitist.
Scott: They were the tiny.
Scott: talk about like four and you want to get like four and like do a little situation like a minigun.
Guest: I've had some kind of awful crown of hats.