Rym: Hey, it's Monday, February 8th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight three news's and cosmos.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know, we would have started recording the show a little while ago.
Rym: We were full of energy ready to run and uh Scott said he had a news and then he forgot it within a second.
Scott: You also forgot it.
Rym: I don't think you even said it out loud.
Rym: I think I did.
Rym: I don't believe it existed.
Scott: I said I will use X news and then like a tab closed and I tried to do.
Scott: you know Undo closed tab and I it.
Scott: it opened all these tabs but none of them was the news.
Scott: and then I looked in the history and Nothing, the history did not contain the news and then I went to all the news sites and I couldn't find the news anywhere.
Scott: So obviously you created a fake news using some sort of HTTP proxy that you then disabled And that is why I had a news and then it disappeared.
Rym: Well, it must have been some pretty good news if you had so much to say about.
Rym: I did.
Scott: It was a good news, but then I lost it.
Scott: So now I had to pick another news.
Rym: You know, are you sure it was a news?
Scott: Nothing I had a news it just disappeared.
Rym: So we really you know I wanted to talk about the robot car and I wanted to talk about the new DARPA project that is effectively the human instrumentality project.
Rym: but I got to talk about 4chan because it's one of those things that Almost became the big news that we would had to do a whole show on and luckily just now we learned that once again It's not I mean for anyone who wasn't paying attention.
Scott: This isn't that new.
Scott: I mean this happened once before.
Rym: Yeah, well things like this happen on a fairly regular basis.
Rym: every time they do there's a little like immediate puff of internet outrage.
Rym: Just people go it's happening It's time and people are like getting super riled up ready to like start DDO s-ing the companies involved now that usually do usually do In the very well fortune.
Rym: they talk about it as opposed to do now.
Scott: fortune does it not?
Rym: not immediately takes him a long time mmm, but basically a Verizon wireless started blocking fortune at some point and Fortune, you know people were like, hey what's going on?
Rym: And usually when something like this happens people immediately cry foul and then within a few hours It is pointed out that no this was actually a technical problem and it was resolved or no?
Rym: This is blown way out of proportion.
Rym: There was an outage in this part of the internet and we fixed it But fortune stayed down and of course the people who run fortune are the fortune kind of people who would you know?
Rym: So they went to 18th or I keep saying 18th horizon.
Scott: Yeah, it's Verizon wireless only which means if you have FiOS, which is Verizon or Verizon DSL, you're cool.
Scott: It's only if you're trying to like use your droid to visit fortune or you have an evdo card on Verizon And you're trying to go to fortune on your laptop.
Rym: You know, I don't think anyone calls it evdo except us Evdio, yeah, whatever.
Rym: I think we're the only people who call it evdo in the whole world.
Scott: If you're trying to use your Verizon evdo card with your laptop, you cannot go to fortune.
Rym: I know I kind of like evdo you can't.
Scott: you can do it with a proxy because you just you know Like a tour or something.
Scott: You just can't go directly to fortune.
Rym: But anyway, you know they went to Verizon wireless and Verizon wireless basically said, you know what?
Rym: Yes We are straight-up blocking what you were talking about due to something.
Scott: now Why is Verizon wireless doing it but not the other Verizon whose decision was this why etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: No one knows.
Rym: so, you know this kept going on and I ignored it.
Rym: and when I saw the news again I thought wait a minute.
Rym: Maybe it's for real happening.
Rym: Maybe an ISP is straight-up blocking something and thus opening a can of worms that anything is.
Scott: they probably block thousands of things.
Scott: the thing is all of those things they block are things that Nobody ever goes to or notices or cares that they're dead that they're blocked.
Rym: Well, there's also a difference between blocking apart.
Rym: I mean a lot of people block SMTP or anything like that.
Rym: Not it's not cool to block a specific website specific port.
Rym: that's the kind of thing that really shouldn't happen.
Rym: I mean, that's the web.
Rym: people don't block port 80.
Rym: That's port 80 is like the one port They're almost guaranteed to be able to get out on Mmm, so of course people started crying crazy foul as this continued in there for Janice preparing a vicious retaliation.
Rym: Before any of you think up it's time.
Rym: Verizon through their policy blog issued an official statement explaining exactly what's going on.
Scott: What did they say?
Rym: Oh, they talk a little bit first about.
Rym: I'm gonna skip all this boilerplate But what's the most important thing we offer our network.
Rym: when our network is attacked or at risk of attack in any way that can Harm the customers ability to make and receive calls or use wireless multimedia and data services.
Rym: We jump into action.
Rym: recently Verizon Wireless security and external experts detected attacks from an IP address associated with the 4chan family of websites that Disrupted to our customers and our network.
Rym: to protect both we eliminated connectivity to this IP IP address.
Rym: at no time was 4chan itself blocked.
Scott: Now the IP address is basically the 4chan server.
Rym: Well boards dot 4chan org, I believe whatever.
Rym: that is that IP address was blocked but not 4chan org see.
Scott: So basically what happened is the IP address that boards of 4chan org that was resolves to.
Rym: there were attacks Emanating from that IP address or at least which appeared to be emanating from that IP address.
Rym: now I'm not gonna read the rest of this but basically they say that it was some sort of why I'm about to answer the question that you keep asking.
Rym: So basically it was some sort of sweep attack that was targeting every wireless device on the Verizon Network To try to get it to respond.
Rym: It was kind of like a port scan of wireless devices.
Rym: so they basically cut that off from the wireless network to prevent this from happening because it was actually causing drop calls and Some crazy network outage.
Rym: It was only getting worse.
Rym: Mm-hmm and they expect to restore connectivity now that whatever this attack was has ceased.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: So while everyone expected the can of worms of up a major ISP is blocking a major website for no good reason.
Rym: now they at least had a pretty obvious technical reason and they seem to have been pretty straightforward about it open about it.
Rym: and if Supposedly are going to resolve the issue though as the time as of the time of this episode They have not yet unblocked this IP address.
Scott: It does seem like them.
Scott: or the last time when AT&T block fortune is because a DDoS is emanating from fortune fortune.
Scott: guys like When you're doing your hacks and attacks don't do them from your fucking web server.
Scott: See them from somewhere else so that you're wet.
Scott: your awesome website does not get blocked.
Scott: Well, we'll get some other computer somewhere to send your attacks from.
Rym: I'm pretty sure the last time something like this happened It was that people posted links to things on fortune and that individual is the AT&T.
Scott: when they blocked fortune It was because a DDoS was emanating from fortune but short of an exploit on fortune.
Rym: That is not something that I expect the people who run fortune to have actually done.
Scott: Well, something is happening on the fortune servers that it is attacking things.
Scott: So they got to do something with their security or stop doing attacks from their web servers or something.
Scott: Well, I see I clearly that is the problem.
Scott: clearly the content on fortune is not the cause of any of these blockages.
Rym: See, I highly doubt however Scott that these attacks actually Legitimately originated from the fortune server in a capacity that was known to or encouraged by the admins.
Rym: I would possible I would wager there's only two about three possibilities.
Rym: a Verizon wireless is totally lying.
Scott: That's true possible.
Rym: Yeah possible not probable.
Rym: But you know, I gotta throw it out there too that fortune is straight up behind this and it's trying to cover the butts.
Rym: or Three fortune servers were somehow compromised.
Scott: it could be that there's a lot of computers behind that IP address with some sort of net, you know, and One of them was sending out these attacks and fortune also happened to be behind the same net.
Rym: now You see there is in fact a Spanish Inquisition fourth option.
Rym: I Was gonna play the music there and I decided The Fourth option is that someone it did some sort of network Exploit or there are a lot of weird ways you can do this to spoof an attack as having come from fortune In order to get them in trouble or to mask the true origin of the attack.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: If you just send out an attack, right?
Scott: It could have been like some fortune person sending out an attack from their house, right?
Scott: But they don't want to be traced back to their house.
Scott: So they're just like.
Scott: I need an IP address to put in these TCP IP packets as the return address.
Scott: I'll use the fortune IP address law.
Rym: Now the thing is that there's no.
Scott: that's the signature that they know.
Scott: this attack is a fortune attack thing is one.
Rym: There's no kind of simple way a script kitty can do that.
Rym: spoofing TCP traffic over the internet like it's difficult.
Rym: You need to guess complicated numbers with advanced math or you have to use very specific exploits at certain levels of the infrastructure.
Rym: It's not that easy and to the modus operandi of fortune is not typically an attack like this.
Rym: I mean, it really doesn't fit with what any of those anonymous people would do or say they would do or even anyone associated with Them.
Rym: they would attack like Scientology or they would attack like some perceived enemy.
Rym: where they really do this very calculated and business-like exploit of Wireless customers for the very specific purpose likely of attacking people's wireless devices later It doesn't make sense.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that fortune had nothing to do with this.
Rym: I accept possibly having very lax or poor security on their side.
Scott: Yeah, or just you know, the NAT situation.
Scott: You know, they might be on some sort of hosting and someone else is also back there and that someone else is doing stuff.
Rym: yeah, it's really hard to say but it kind of bothers me that Verizon released the statement and 4chan supposedly had been in contact with Verizon and yet the 4chan status page still basically says yeah Verizon confirm They're blocking us screw them.
Scott: What I don't understand is why people just block an IP address, right?
Scott: Why don't you actually Specifically block the attacking packets and not any other packets?
Rym: Well, what are you gonna do?
Rym: a deep packet inspection.
Rym: that sort of stuff is not Necessarily easy to do and tends to consume a lot of resources.
Scott: Well, basically what it would do right is your routers would just let through anything from a different IP address.
Scott: just fine But anything that's from that IP address would be slowed down as it was inspected
Rym: 4chan
Scott: would slow down but it would still be okay and the attack would cease to disrupt the network and it would probably just cost You like one piece of hardware to accomplish this.
Rym: now that sort of thing is not feasible to implement quickly.
Rym: No, it's not.
Scott: I could I could write it pretty easily.
Rym: Yes, you're gonna.
Rym: what are you gonna write it on?
Rym: you're gonna make it like a Linux running device that you put between everything On your network.
Scott: No, I just be one computer.
Rym: All right Well, how does the router know what to write like?
Rym: does it put in?
Scott: I put in one route that says if coming from This computer route to this other computer that I just plugged in All right I'm putting in a new route.
Rym: while that is trivial on a large network and a large infrastructure is not something you want to do Lightly let alone statically That's true, but you're only doing it.
Rym: one spot Just got believe me.
Rym: That's sort of that sort of response is not nearly as useful or effective as the blanket ban.
Scott: People just lazy.
Scott: now Rison's got money.
Rym: All right, they can handle it But it's not a matter of having money to handle its matter of.
Rym: they don't have infrastructure in place to have that selected.
Scott: They got the best infrastructure.
Scott: Everyone else is in the shitter.
Scott: So if they get the structure is so awesome, they should be able to do it, but they don't have that infrastructure in place.
Rym: There's no reason to have it in place.
Scott: for you know, blocking attacks like this without you know, they block the attack trivially Yeah, but they also blocked other things badly.
Scott: Yes one thing with a minor disruption of service That were blocked on that are on that IP address if my net theory is correct but only 4chan things.
Rym: and if if the attack was calm still I'm of the mind as an IT professional that the Cut the isolate and attack response to major Outages or major attacks from foreign IPS or whatever is perfectly valid.
Rym: if you're getting attacked by something cut it off immediately And then figure out what's going on?
Scott: Mmm, whatever the point is is that You know 4chan is not getting blocked for content reasons as people like to jump to that conclusion.
Scott: It is being blocked for other reasons, which are You know in some way or another for at least partially possibly very much So 4chan's fault and they got to do something about it.
Rym: I still attribute incompetence as opposed to outright malice.
Scott: Yeah, they're not.
Scott: I mean look at 4chan.
Scott: These people are not genius webmasters All right.
Rym: So do you have some sort of news?
Rym: Captain can't actually come up with this news because he made it up and then had to stall for time.
Scott: Well, because I could not find my news I just went to the sort of the default big news of the week, which is the Amazon book fighting what what's right?
Scott: The story basically is that you know, Apple comes out with their iPad and they're like, yeah Our ebooks are gonna be $15.
Scott: Meanwhile Kindle books are $10.
Scott: So the book publishers are like hey Amazon You better make those books $15 and not $10 like you are now and Amazon's like oh really?
Scott: Well, guess what?
Scott: Not only are we taking all your books off the Kindle, but we're taking all your book books off Amazon.
Scott: What are you gonna do about that?
Rym: Yeah, I saw that the so at least one artist guild actually put up some sort of notification system.
Rym: They call they're calling like where'd my buy button go?
Rym: so they can inform authors that hey Amazon took your book off for sale because they're strong-arming us because we're Greedy and we want to be able to charge more money for your books, even though you don't see any of that money.
Scott: I think the big problem here is that basically if you look at the like the the commentary on the internet Amazon is like taking all the heat like everyone's like oh Amazon you failed Oh Amazon.
Scott: You sucked, right?
Rym: I'm 80% on Amazon.
Scott: So I am so an Amazon made the consumer play.
Scott: They're like look right you sell us books.
Scott: We don't care what we pay you for the books, you know It's a wholesale deal.
Scott: and then we charge whatever the fuck we want.
Scott: We're gonna charge what's best for consumers.
Scott: Well, see here's the right, you know, this is the thing.
Scott: anyone who is in favor of a non Consumer centric policy fuck you.
Scott: buyer is number one seller is number two.
Rym: This is a much more complex issue and this ebook thing makes it all techie and people suddenly care about it.
Rym: But this has been going on forever and the root issue is that?
Rym: Manufacturers will often put forth some sort of quote minimum advertised price and they'll basically say Apple is like the king of that.
Rym: They'll say to anyone who wants to sell and this you know affects gaming to like the Warhammer stuff is Big one - yeah and even TVs.
Rym: so they'll have a minimum advertised price and they'll basically say Anyone who advertises a price lower than the minimum price we allow you to advertise We will never sell you any product to then resell again.
Scott: This is why iPods are never at a discount ever.
Scott: They're always a certain price because if you try to sell an iPod for like 50 bucks Apple just won't give you any more iPods.
Rym: Now the thing is there's a lot of consumer protection laws in place such that They can't bar you from selling things at the lower price.
Rym: You can sell something or whatever price you want unless you sign a specific Contract and even then those contracts if you do them wrong could very easily be construed as some sort of trust Or some sort of price collusion.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So what they'll do?
Rym: like the TV I bought?
Rym: I bought a super awesome 52-inch TV for the house.
Rym: They're all the apartment and The TV retails for like three grand but the what I bought it for was like $1,300.
Rym: but the minimum advertised price was like $1,600.
Rym: so I go to Amazon and I see a worse TV for like $1,600 and then I see this much much better TV, which a mutt with a much higher retail price.
Rym: But Amazon won't show me a price.
Rym: In fact, it has a little icon saying we're not allowed to show you the price.
Rym: dude a whole bunch of bullshit.
Rym: Click here to find out about the bullshit and find out who to complain to.
Scott: So I click on it and then it tells you the price.
Rym: Nope and click on it.
Rym: and it tells me why they can't tell me the price why Samsung is an asshole for making them such that they can't show me the price.
Rym: and they say to get around all this BS Put it in your cart.
Rym: say you want to buy it at checkout You'll see the real price and then if you don't want to buy it go ahead and back out.
Rym: So I do this.
Rym: and the TV was stupidly cheap.
Scott: So I bought it.
Rym: Yeah but the fact that Samsung has the power to force Amazon not to show a price that they're perfectly willing to sell this TV for is Ludicrous and laughable.
Scott: the other problem here right is that the the internet basically has Especially if you're selling digital goods as opposed to physical goods.
Scott: Middlemen are obsolete.
Scott: all middlemen are 100% useless, right?
Scott: So what we have here right is get this book publisher.
Scott: in terms of publishing physical books middlemen still have a purpose because they can provide services of printing and You know putting getting your stuff onto the shelves and borders and all that kind of stuff that they you know services they can provide.
Scott: Thus, you know Validating the fact that they get a cut of the sales and the author doesn't just get a hundred percent.
Scott: But if you were selling an e-book the bay the publisher is pretty useless.
Scott: What can they do for you?
Scott: advertise advertise?
Scott: But you can just why?
Scott: why have a publisher?
Scott: then just pay an ad agency or pay Google Adsense?
Scott: Or you know, you can just handle advertising on your own.
Rym: It's not our best.
Rym: I could see a publishing company offering a suite of Advertising editing and consulting all in right.
Scott: so Amazon I think I read.
Scott: you know that the split on the Kindle books is 70 30.
Scott: So Amazon gets.
Scott: you know If it's $10 book Amazon gets three dollars.
Scott: book publisher gets seven.
Scott: author probably gets like a dollar if not less.
Scott: Who knows what the author gets Depends on I guess the author's contract to with the publisher.
Scott: if you are just an author You just go directly to Amazon with a $10 book.
Scott: You're gonna get seven dollars per book Right.
Scott: So, you know you tell me what's better on both ends, you know is the lower book price.
Scott: book publisher goes out of business Author goes directly to Amazon.
Scott: That's what we need.
Scott: And in fact who even needs that right?
Scott: author sets up a website where you can just download Their e-book.
Scott: you pay them with PayPal or something.
Scott: So PayPal gets a tiny tiny fee for the PayPal fee and the author gets close to ten dollars on the sale of their e-book Directly to you on the author's website.
Scott: who even needs Amazon?
Scott: right all Amazon provides is you know this technological?
Scott: Expertise of creating an e-commerce store.
Scott: Well Amazon creating an e-book reading device.
Rym: What I would say is Amazon is one of the last middlemen that will exist at least in this era of the internet And it serves the same purpose that like a dig or a 4chan or a slashdot or anything served just in a different realm.
Rym: And what does slashdot do?
Rym: It's like a city on the internet where you have a whole bunch of people who want something.
Rym: So it provides the infrastructure within which all those people do all their business.
Rym: Amazon basically provides that for e-commerce for a lot of people.
Rym: now I think
Scott: basically the only reason that middlemen can exist in the technological times that we have now is because of the vast technological Incompetence of many people and also, you know so they can't provide the technological part themselves because they don't know how right and be for Aggregation and sifting purposes based on the user like Google search.
Scott: other than that like Over time anyone whose business is a middleman business It's just gonna go away.
Scott: all middlemen are gonna be eliminated in the long run like 20 30 years.
Scott: There just won't be any room for anyone who's a middleman every any.
Scott: if you're not actually providing a service Directly as in you are, you know, either the consumer or the producer You're just not gonna be around, you know.
Scott: I would if you're if you're looking at a long bet in the stock market any middleman business, you know Especially like, you know a middleman like digital goods business like a like a music record company or a book publisher.
Scott: I would if you could do like a long a sell-long if such a thing as possible Right.
Scott: That's what I would do.
Rym: You mean a buy?
Scott: No, that's that's that's a buy.
Rym: so you could buy their competitors.
Scott: I Guess you could.
Scott: yes, you could but the all the.
Scott: but the thing is if it's all whole bunch of middlemen verse each other They're all going down the tubes in the long run.
Rym: So will you buy the people that replace the middlemen?
Rym: So in this case, I don't know Amazon authors.
Scott: Can I buy some Stephen King stock, huh?
Scott: That maybe that's a way to kind of because I mean it's you know If the publishers all go out Stephen King is gonna make way more bank when he just sells his books directly to the customers.
Scott: Well, you know and all the money is gonna go to him.
Rym: unknown worlds kind of prove that this works.
Rym: What if you set up a system and going forward where?
Rym: Authors who who are established at least or even new authors if they want to make a book and they need money They basically form a company or a pseudo company.
Rym: We make a new instrument for the purpose of the creation of a work of art or even the creation of something else.
Rym: It's kind of like a new thing Like a new kind of corporation.
Rym: when you make it you sell you have an IPO and you sell shares of that thing And then basically people buy that and the money goes a hundred percent to the author and then based on the shares The author pays back out to these investors.
Rym: depending on however, they want to make their money.
Scott: That's not bad.
Rym: Maybe they pay out in non-monetary terms either.
Rym: you can make some really cool things.
Rym: We can make it ourselves.
Rym: if we wanted to let's put it in the hopper way at the bottom.
Rym: Yeah But there's another interesting aside on this because our friend Murdoch came out and said Quote, we don't like Amazon.
Rym: We don't like the Amazon model of selling everything at $9.99.
Rym: They pay us wholesale price of $14 or whatever we charge.
Rym: But I think it really devalues books and it hurts all the retailers of the hardcover books.
Scott: Yeah, I want to say that the retailers of hardcover books are morons.
Scott: right and my evidence is steam.
Scott: Right, what does steam do?
Scott: they take all these games that no one is buying?
Scott: Right and they the price.
Scott: the people are trying to sell these games for 40 bucks and X people are buying them.
Scott: So what do they do?
Scott: They cut the price to 20 maybe even 10 maybe even five dollars, right?
Scott: So five dollars that's I guess the eight times less the price than $40.
Scott: But guess what the percentage of sales that goes up.
Scott: It's way more than 800% more sales.
Scott: It's like 2,000 percent more sales.
Scott: So by lowering the price they make more sales and more money.
Scott: You know what if you've dropped the price?
Scott: or I think about this.
Scott: someone buys a Kindle, right?
Scott: Maybe they buy a book they read it they buy another book.
Scott: They read it They buy another book.
Scott: right?
Scott: if Kindle books were 50 cents or a dollar People who bought Kindles would just buy every book.
Scott: They'd be like, here's 50 bucks.
Scott: Give me fucking 50 books Holy shit, you know.
Scott: and they wouldn't even read half of them.
Scott: just buy a ton of them cuz they're so far even better.
Scott: How many games do I buy on Steam that I never play and suck but they're $2.
Scott: so I'm like whatever.
Rym: Even better for them the fact that with DRM and the loss of first sale I'll make more money because people won't be lending their books to each other.
Scott: Yeah, it's like why.
Scott: you know, I could lend you this book and I you know And I might be pissed that I can't lend you this DRM book.
Scott: But you know what if it's 50 cents?
Scott: who gives a shit if I can't lend it to you?
Scott: You can get it You know, I don't you know this DRM on Netflix streaming.
Scott: But who cares if I can't lend it to you?
Scott: right and it's streaming.
Scott: you can just get the same thing for so cheap.
Scott: That is you know, what do I need to lend for?
Scott: but caring about lending goes away if the price goes way down.
Rym: Let's look at the model of hardcover books even directly like Murdoch was talking about hardcover books now Really?
Rym: They exist to squeeze more profit out of a book.
Rym: They're like the DVD that goes on an artificial thing.
Rym: They go, you know Because basically what they do now is it in a long time ago at least in some markets the paperback would come out Yeah, and then the hardcover be like.
Rym: if you really like this book by the hardcover it lasts forever.
Rym: Yeah but at least right now a Hardcover comes out first and they sell that to the people who can't wait for the paperback and it just cost more and they make more money off of it and then they release the paperback as far later as they can.
Rym: and P I don't know.
Rym: for people like me other than our Scott backer books There's nothing worth the hardcover to me anymore.
Rym: It's not.
Scott: the only time I get a hardcover is if a book is like a only hardcover Be some sort of fancy giant coffee table type of book, you know Like I bought that like deluxe rocketeer something something or like the the art of Tezuka, you know Those are the kind of books that are hardcover.
Scott: Otherwise, I absolutely 100% avoid hardcover at all costs.
Scott: But we're seeing more and more space and cost more money for the same thing.
Rym: We're seeing more and more problems like this where a revenue stream was faltering and they someone some industry is made up for it By shifting sales by doing the hardcover trick or like now with the Netflix deal where they won't have new movies from certain studios For 28 days after the DVD comes out because DVD sales for anyone doesn't realize have been collapsing and not due to piracy.
Rym: It's due to the fact that people just rent stuff because they no one wants to buy DVDs anymore.
Scott: It just takes up room and you have Netflix streaming and Hulu.
Scott: So who needs to?
Scott: why should I buy a TV show box set on DVD?
Rym: I can rent it I can Netflix stream it I can Hulu and so I haven't pirated anything in a long time and I don't need to and I get everything.
Rym: I only pirated things that are unavailable that there is absolutely no way to get them Otherwise, but everyone's trying to protect these revenue streams in increasingly desperate ways and now we've got the.
Scott: it's not that they're trying.
Scott: Well, the thing is is not that they're trying to protect the revenue stream, you know That's what they think they're doing.
Scott: right is that they're trying to protect the structure of the revenue stream, right?
Scott: They could maintain the revenue stream by lowering the price to like two bucks and the revenue stream would probably increase and be very well.
Rym: Well, you're forgetting there are a lot of it is in the way.
Scott: They are very risk averse.
Rym: now Scott You're forgetting there's a lot of players in the way.
Rym: Rental DVDs at this point.
Rym: No one goes to Blockbuster anymore.
Rym: The only people who rent that matter are those red boxes because they're easy and cheap.
Rym: and Netflix Yep, so you go.
Rym: basically we go studios Netflix consumers.
Rym: And then the alternate hardcover book stream is you know studios?
Rym: Retailers DVDs and all these like yeah, it's author publisher retailer then customer.
Rym: But you're forgetting that the real men - even if the studios want to go direct the retailers don't want them to.
Rym: I mean Look at all the crap that happened when steam first started coming up and all the video game retailers Like this is gonna destroy us.
Rym: GameStop only exists because they're a pawn shop.
Scott: Yeah Pretty much.
Scott: a GameStop also only exists because punk kids who go to GameStop have cash and they don't have credit cards.
Scott: So they can't buy an Amazon if you give credit cards.
Scott: if we just got rid of cash and everyone had like a cash card.
Scott: They just kept track of how much cash you had and you could use it everywhere for you know And the government just took care of it and all it was was cash.
Scott: Basically You know GameStop would go out because all the kids would just have their allowance on a card and be able to buy online.
Rym: Yep, and there'd be marketplaces for used games and everything would be okay for kids to have it.
Scott: cuz it's cash.
Scott: It's not like a debit card with an account.
Scott: It's not a loan like a credit card.
Scott: It's just cash.
Scott: just happens to be on a card, you know, a little number shows.
Scott: Maybe there'd be like LCD display.
Scott: you push a button and it shows you how much money is on the card, you know Something like that.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: So Wilson Bentley is someone who was pretty cool.
Rym: in 1885 he put together a rig and photographed a snowflake in Really really really exquisite detail with an old-ass camera that goes poof with the smoke and everything.
Rym: This is back in a time when micro photography really didn't exist on this scale and he did it.
Rym: and Then over the course of his life He did more than 5,000 individual snowflakes and these were actually a really important contribution to science to art to everything.
Rym: He's a cool guy and these pictures even to this day are pretty freaking amazing.
Scott: They're all black and white though, right?
Rym: Yes, they're black and white.
Scott: So yeah, it's gotta have some color, you know, yeah I mean he was using like old bellows style cameras when he was a teenager doing this, you know It'd be cool if you can get one of those cameras and learn to use it and go poof.
Scott: That'd be cool.
Scott: Like we take a camera like actually took a real picture of like the modern day with that old-ass camera.
Scott: We could like take a picture of a digital camera with that camera.
Rym: just wait a few years And that's what the hipsters will be doing because it's the only authentic way left to take a picture.
Rym: Yeah Alright, Wilson Bentley is pretty cool much like the guy with the balls from before.
Rym: I put him on the same level as that guy.
Scott: So when I was in summer camp, we did some chemistry because it was nerd summer camp, right?
Scott: And we would do things like throw sodium in the lake and such, you know Put the lid back on, you know, stuff like that.
Scott: But one thing they like to do the counselors is they took some sort of powder I forget what it was and then they would pour some sort of acid on it I think it might have been sulfuric acid and it was like the powder started out as one color and it was a tiny little Mountain of powder and it would start going poof poof poof poof poof and it would be like a volcano.
Scott: and when it was done the powder all changed color and the mountain of powder was like Way bigger.
Scott: like it expanded tremendously and I was pretty cool.
Rym: I love stuff like that.
Scott: So I couldn't.
Scott: I still don't know exactly what that chemical reaction was, but I found a similar chemical reaction here.
Scott: It's called the Pharaoh's snake.
Scott: And what they do is they take mercury thios... ...ens... Something.
Scott: It's mercury something and basically what they do is they light it on fire.
Scott: And when they light it on fire a snake appears it decomposes and like expands tremendously.
Scott: It makes these really cool crazy shapes and it makes a snake noise.
Scott: and it's called the Pharaoh's snake and his YouTube video.
Rym: It looks exactly like some horrifying Cthulhu monster rising about the earth to eat us all.
Scott: Yeah The video is a little boring in the beginning because they spend all this time showing you the guy Sprinkling the powder into the tank.
Scott: So just fast forward until he starts the fire.
Rym: I kind of like the idea.
Rym: imagine in ancient times if they'd figured out this reaction and could do it.
Rym: You know Like the Roman army is marching on some Greek city-state and they just sprinkled this all over the field ahead of time And poisoned everybody.
Scott: I'm pretty sure this is really nasty and poisonous.
Rym: It does not look like something you want to be inhaling.
Scott: No, the guy's wearing gloves and they don't show his face.
Scott: But I'm pretty sure he's got some sort of mask and they're doing it in a tank like, you know They're doing it in a diorama.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: It's pretty cool.
Rym: There's a little cacti in there and everything.
Scott: Yeah I would have done it under like a fume hood and run the fuck away.
Rym: The thing is the guy gets minus points for making this little like environment with the sand and the cacti But he doesn't have a tiny Pharaoh running away from it already.
Scott: He also needs a tiny sky pirate skeleton with opening and closing treasure chest.
Rym: Ah, there's no water.
Scott: That's the point.
Rym: So, what do you got for me?
Scott: What do you mean what I got for you thing of the day?
Scott: That was my thing of the day.
Rym: Oh, didn't you have some news that you forgot in the beginning?
Scott: The news that Rym Reminded me of?
Scott: well in between the news and the thing of the day parts of the show I mean the thing that I was surprised you weren't doing is your news and was all over the news.
Rym: So I assumed you would have found it if you were looking for it somehow was not on the news I mentioned off-handedly in the course of talking about an unrelated thing.
Scott: So basically my news before I forgot it was going to be about Google store view which is not confirmed But it's looking pretty likely right.
Scott: they caught someone Daysley doing this in a store in New York City.
Rym: You realize all you would have to do is say you work for Google and you can probably get away with crazy stuff Photographing a store photographing the insides of people's houses.
Rym: I'm sure you could go all out on a lot of people maybe but anyway, don't do that.
Scott: It's probably illegal Yeah, but basically it's looking like it's very probable.
Scott: Google's gonna do store view.
Scott: So you have Street View But what you'll be able to do is basically go inside and look around the inside of a store From Google Maps, and I think that is super awesome.
Scott: because how many times like you see a restaurant?
Scott: But then you're like, is it nice on the inside or is it a dump?
Scott: and it's like Is it a sit-down restaurant or is it more of a takeout place?
Scott: and you can't really tell?
Scott: Just by looking at it from the outside.
Scott: You'd have to look on the inside or maybe they could even become more advanced.
Scott: Maybe they can get to the point where it's like if they actually update this stuff often.
Scott: Maybe they could even update they have like restaurant menus.
Scott: Maybe they could get like store inventories.
Scott: So it's like you can go look inside a hardware store and See do they have X in stock?
Scott: You can actually go down the aisles of like a Home Depot or you know be able to search like, okay Where is the nearest copy of X book?
Scott: and it can.
Scott: you can go to a borders and it'll actually know if that borders has That book on the shelf.
Scott: because they took a picture of the shelf, you know This can go crazy far and I think it's gonna be pretty awesome And there's really no privacy concerns with it really other than they might catch so-and-so shopping at X store at X time.
Scott: But they do that with Street View.
Scott: Anyways, there's no different.
Rym: Well, they blur out faces, which they'll probably do in this.
Rym: I wish they didn't even blur out the spaces.
Rym: I I'm more and more a few license plates.
Rym: if you're in public That's it.
Rym: You're in public.
Rym: Yeah, someone takes a picture of you.
Rym: That's awesome.
Scott: And I mean and you know, what's you know, they're not doing the people's houses.
Scott: They're doing the stores.
Scott: So it's like, you know, what store wouldn't want to be on Google.
Scott: You're basically hurting yourself by being off Google exactly more.
Rym: I love this whole trend and only Google is doing it.
Rym: Well, I've just let's catalog a whole bunch of Interesting information.
Scott: Let's give everyone equal and free advertising and then charge them for more prominence in said free equilibrium.
Scott: It's like let's make a yellow, you know, it's the yellow pages model.
Scott: Well, you know the yellow pages wants to have every frickin store in there.
Scott: But if you want to have the big square in the yellow pages got to pay more.
Scott: But the thing is in order to make yellow pages you need to find out what all the stores are.
Scott: so Google's just going around getting everything they can about every store and then Charging the stores money if the stores want to have more prominent placement.
Rym: now, imagine the far future of this Integrated with like Google goggles or some sort of augmented reality.
Rym: So you could see when one of your friends is near a store where you need something and you already know the thing you need Is in the store so you can just have it message them and say hey while you're out could you grab this for me?
Rym: and then they pay?
Rym: but it's through the Google system and you actually are the one who pays in The end and it even automatically pays them a small fee for getting it for you that you pre-negotiated.
Scott: What could even be cooler right is like if you know, they have grub hubs that just sort of like, you know It.
Scott: basically it's a go-between between you and restaurants.
Rym: I want that for everything.
Scott: No, but I mean like.
Scott: You could like buy like I don't know frickin like just anything.
Rym: Well, imagine here's what you would do.
Rym: you have Amazon, right?
Rym: Imagine a distributed Amazon that uses this sort of technology to where when you want to buy something it shows you two options the closest physical store to you that has the item or the closest physical store to you that has the item at the cheapest price or The cheapest online store or the online store that has the quickest shipping and you pick one of those four.
Scott: There's all sorts that you know.
Scott: They basically give you every single possible balance between saving money and getting something quickly that you could possibly want.
Rym: You can even go one step further and have an automated system of people like Like whenever you want something that's in the store nearby It just puts out a call to anyone who has their.
Rym: I am looking for delivery gigs app turned on.
Scott: Maybe we could just get rid of stores entirely and they'll basically just be a local warehouse that has a whole bunch of stuff You know that is very commonly wanted and then they will employ many delivery people and that'll just be it.
Scott: or even imagine this.
Rym: All right You got the warehouse.
Rym: Someone's walking by the warehouse or is bored and hanging out in the warehouse or is near the warehouse or whatever and I buy Something.
Rym: a chain of events occurs to where it pings them saying hey you want to make a little bit of money Pick up this item and walk toward where you know.
Rym: walk in this direction and then over the course of the way it looks for People who are already going toward where your delivery point is and pings all of them says hey pass it off to this guy.
Rym: He's willing to take it.
Rym: Microtransactions the whole way.
Rym: and then some bum near your house grabs it drops it off on your front door.
Rym: He gets five cents takes that, you know adds that to his total of.
Rym: I can go buy some same pain eventually.
Rym: And it's like this complete distributed society to where all the menial work is done through Microtransactions immediately on demand as people need it when they need work, right?
Scott: But then who's actually doing work that gets paid You know to earn money to actually buy things all the complicated work all the non-trivial work like, you know.
Scott: But we do what everyone is either going to be doing real work being a delivery person of some sort or warehouse worker or Being a homeless bum, I think it would be more distributing.
Rym: It would just basically be a universal gigging system of people doing things for money.
Rym: It'd be a great way.
Scott: and you extrapolated this from taking pictures of the inside of a store for Street View.
Rym: Yes Yes, okay, cuz I think they're in the exact same line of technology.
Scott: Alright, so we did it.
Scott: We did an extra news after the thing of the day.
Scott: What are we doing for a show?
Rym: Well last week we did the book club and we did not announce the new book.
Scott: Well, shouldn't we do that on Thursday?
Scott: considering, you know, I think we should visit Thursday thing.
Rym: I feel like we should announce it tonight and then I also.
Scott: I guess this is a meta moment.
Rym: It is the meta moment.
Rym: All right, so meta moment the book club.
Rym: We're having a new book announcement right now.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: So we debated for like an hour after we did the last book club show on what book to do because I read a lot of nonfiction and a lot of like dopey fantasy and between the two I couldn't come up with any book that I Expected the listeners to actually
Scott: read.
Rym: and at the same time.
Rym: I don't want to just pick a throwaway book.
Rym: I want to pick something that like I want people to read these books for a reason and I wanted to do something short and fun like the little prince.
Rym: But I'll let Scott pick that one because I know he will and if he doesn't I'll pick it next time eventually Independently and I just ordered a new copy cuz my copy from childhood is falling apart.
Rym: It is Emily and I are.
Rym: we are watching the old Carl Sagan Cosmo series from you know, 1980 on Netflix streaming Yes, yeah, which we just discussed.
Rym: cuz I've only watched about I don't know half of it in my life.
Rym: So I figure it's good time to catch up and like watch all the bits.
Scott: I miss I've only watched YouTube parts.
Rym: It's great.
Rym: It's amazing, but Carl Sagan for people don't understand especially I think people from Generations other than the generation that grew up in the 70s to become scientists.
Rym: Carl Sagan influenced an entire generation of scientists to become scientists to be all inspired about space and science and exploration and And figuring out what it is that makes our world tick.
Rym: Carl Sagan is one of my personal heroes.
Rym: He's one of the coolest guys to ever live.
Rym: He kind of sounds like a Muppet.
Rym: He looked he had a perpetual toupee, even though I'm pretty sure that was his real hair.
Rym: yeah, and I just I love him and his book.
Rym: cosmos is probably more instrumental to the rise of Scientific understanding among the masses and getting kids excited about science and going into scientific fields.
Rym: Possibly the most influential book along those lines of any book in human history or at least in recent human history and I worry Sorry about that had a little technological flub there.
Rym: I'm still new to audition.
Rym: Carl Sagan's cosmos is an instrumental and important book and the greatest thing about it is that to this day Very few things in it proved to be inaccurate.
Rym: the parts where it's speculated Panned out to be 99% true and the parts where it talked about existing science have almost entirely been not only non Disproven but more proven like proven to the degree to a startling degree.
Rym: The book is almost prescient and It inspired me to care about science in a big way as a kid and I feel like this should be required reading for every Single person in high school regard.
Rym: This should just be a book that when you're in 11th grade You just have to read it Maybe even not as part of a class.
Rym: you just have to read it.
Scott: because if you read this and by the end of this Book, I mean they can't even force kids to do summer reading How do you think you can force anyone to read anything gunpoint?
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: I never did the summer reading But I do a whole bunch of unrelated reading because I wanted to and then I just make I'd flub stuff for the summer reading When I got back into school like the week before school I would go and like flip through all the books I had to read and write dodgy vague essays that got a is.
Rym: anyway they didn't read that stuff, but Gunpoint I figure is the only way.
Rym: okay, seriously Carl Sagan's read it to them.
Rym: Well, you know what.
Rym: I have a feeling that at least a quarter of the listeners are gonna totally cop out and just watch the Carl Sagan cosmos Streaming series on Netflix.
Scott: you need to do some sort of thing where we can like figure out how many people are actually reading The books.
Scott: we need some sort of GeekNights listener survey.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, we'll figure that out.
Rym: We'll announce that in more detail.
Rym: But Carl Sagan's cosmos is one of the most inspiring books I've ever read.
Rym: if you can get through the series or the book Without feeling a sense of awe at how much and how little we simultaneously understand about the universe You are not a person and you don't deserve to be here.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: What'd you do?
Rym: Oh It's playing the closing music.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Okay Did it actually play that in the show?
Scott: Okay.