Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday September 14th.
Rym: I'm Rym Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: packs 2010.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we had packs and then we had the weekend you had packs.
Scott: Hey, how did you have it?
Rym: as in we were at packs?
Rym: We had packs happen.
Scott: In what way do you own it?
Rym: In that that is a common grammatical construct that is not a problem for most normal people.
Scott: I believe you would say you went to it.
Scott: so we had part.
Rym: you part took and then The following weekend without a break we had a nerd NYC board game night on Friday And then we had a nerd NYC recess.
Scott: that we did.
Rym: I basically haven't had a rest from gaming.
Scott: You're not plenty games today.
Rym: I played counter-strike as soon as I got home.
Scott: Oh that was your choice.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, no rest.
Scott: I notice you were playing a siege a very classic map.
Rym: It was a remake of siege.
Rym: I did not recognize it at first because I didn't notice the name.
Rym: I just joined.
Rym: it was a weird server.
Rym: There's a lot of weird new counter-strike servers, and it all seems to be like People who are noobs to counter-strike running servers, so they don't ban the auto.
Rym: they don't ban the AWP.
Scott: Why would you don't?
Rym: why would you ban that?
Rym: every server does that?
Rym: why just they do?
Scott: Why would you do that?
Rym: because they do everyone's stupid?
Rym: I don't.
Scott: that's not why that's just they do know because that's not the reason they do.
Rym: how am I supposed to know they're stupid every?
Rym: Counter-strike server I ever see.
Rym: bands the AWP they ban the autos.
Scott: well They're stupid is a reason.
Rym: they also give everyone 16,000 money every round.
Scott: what yeah?
Rym: a lot of them even banned smoke grenades.
Scott: What yeah why?
Rym: and half the servers don't even run real maps.
Rym: they either just run office 24/7 dust to 24/7 or they run those weird bullshit maps like jailbreak.
Rym: Yeah, jailbreak isn't?
Rym: it looks like a quake one map.
Rym: it is awful.
Scott: I mean gun games.
Rym: alright I like gun game yeah, but I like gun game and the more realistic maps more so than on like Tetris.
Rym: Tetris.
Rym: yeah, I don't like those Tetris weird-ass maps.
Rym: But anyway all the servers run by noobs are kind of default rules.
Rym: no bullshit, and it's great.
Rym: I get to.
Rym: so suddenly I'm playing all these maps that I didn't know existed in source.
Rym: So I'm on this map and I play like three rounds.
Scott: I think you need to run your own seat server.
Rym: I'm working on that but other things that the GeekNights server is so low on my priority list right now And once it five comes out.
Rym: It's basically at the bottom of the list.
Scott: so many goddamn games unfinished damn It doesn't matter.
Rym: sit five.
Scott: I know, but it's like I said five.
Scott: I never finished that borderlands game whatever.
Scott: so five I know whatever, but the point is I paid money for it, and I haven't finished.
Rym: I think my trouble with Borderlands is that once I got going in it.
Rym: It was fun, but every time I want to co-op everyone.
Rym: I know is that a different level and It's not fun to be the lowest or the highest level guy.
Scott: that is a problem.
Scott: Is that level matters.
Scott: instead of just FPSing it should really game had no levels and only equipment.
Scott: It'd be much better.
Rym: or if it did a Pokemon thing and just brought everyone to the same like equivalent level just to make It work man.
Scott: I think it would just be fine If there were no levels in the game and everybody just had equipment and the equipment.
Scott: you had any on it.
Scott: You could use any equipment no matter what but some equipment is just better right.
Rym: so the better equipment would be in the harder places Alright, so then I'm loaded out with all the crazy equipment And you don't have anything.
Scott: But the equipment doesn't make as much a difference as the levels do.
Scott: so even the crazy equipment is fully better But it wouldn't be enough.
Rym: so what about the player abilities?
Scott: the player What do you mean?
Rym: you got to unlock all those abilities.
Rym: you got a level up?
Scott: You just make them into items or some shit.
Rym: alright But they give you a huge advantage.
Rym: having those not really they.
Scott: it just like the auto turret and stuff like that isn't?
Scott: or the eagle?
Rym: They're not that as the siren mine are.
Scott: Main difference is that just as you get more levels you get more HP, and you do more damage just straight up.
Rym: And yeah, I know that's a problem.
Scott: They should just get rid of that entirely.
Scott: you just always do the same damage.
Rym: You realize most gamers want that even like Dave Riley and all them like.
Rym: they love games.
Rym: you level up and have tech trees.
Scott: Yeah The reason they like that is because it makes you feel like you're mad skilled and makes you feel like you're improving when you're actually Not improving it.
Rym: I don't think that's the reason a lot of people like it.
Scott: I'm a psychological reason that it's in there for some people.
Rym: that is definitely true, but not everyone.
Rym: some people just enjoy The like exploring the tree of abilities as you progress through a game, and that's a legitimate utility in gaming.
Scott: But that a tree of abilities is the exact same thing.
Scott: it psychologically they might you know not might not be conscious.
Scott: But that is the reason that that is enjoyable is because it makes you Way too many assumptions.
Scott: That's absolutely true.
Scott: That's why this is why get flash games that have that mechanic are the ones that are the most popular by an order of magnitude.
Rym: Yeah, but just because a implies B. Does not being mean that B implies a.
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: you're not.
Rym: I don't agree with your premise that all Exploration of tech trees is enjoyable only because of this one mechanic.
Scott: well, I mean there are things that you could call a tech tree such as for example the Technology in civilization.
Rym: Yeah, so I level up my sieve and my better than this.
Rym: if they didn't level up It's not leveling up.
Rym: So what's the difference?
Scott: a different thing?
Scott: How?
Rym: what's different?
Scott: there's a difference between Leveling up and leveling to the right right.
Scott: so for example Mario levels to the right.
Scott: He goes to the next level where things are more difficult.
Rym: all right What if so we're playing Mario, but I get the hammer suit and you don't have the hammer suit.
Rym: I'm clearly at an advantage.
Rym: I leveled up.
Rym: I explored that tech.
Scott: I got the hammer suit, but the hammer suit isn't something that you earn simply by time.
Scott: It is something you earn by skill.
Scott: So you have to get to actually do difficult things to get the hammer suit.
Rym: yeah You can do that with tech trees too in games Yes, like in civilization where you have to generate.
Scott: You know it's actually quite difficult to generate enough Beakers faster than the other people while also making sure everything else doesn't fall apart.
Scott: I I still disagree with your argument.
Scott: you get levels simply by Not doing anything more difficult by simply doing the easy things over and over again.
Rym: Yeah, I don't disagree with that.
Rym: what I'm saying is even in a game like that not everyone gets their enjoyment Just because of that one particular psychological thing.
Scott: I'm saying that that if in a game where you level up by doing something that is not more difficult Right in there the difficulty of Borderlands does not increase at any point.
Scott: Yeah, same difficulty throughout Yeah, and they simply scale up your numbers and the bad guys.
Rym: Yeah, I don't disagree with any of this and the only reason that that is enjoyable.
Rym: No I disagree with that.
Rym: It's not the only reason why would that be enjoyable?
Scott: for any other reason.
Rym: some people like unlocking stuff.
Rym: some people like you know.
Rym: Why do people like steak?
Scott: Steak?
Scott: is it because it tastes good?
Rym: what someone else doesn't like steak?
Scott: Yes, because it doesn't taste good to them.
Rym: Yeah, so what if leveling up tastes good to some people?
Scott: I don't know why it is leveling up taste.
Rym: Why does steak taste good?
Scott: because there's things in your tongue in your brain that you're you.
Scott: it touches your tongue And there's fat and sugar and good stuff in there.
Scott: all right, but not it tells your brain that it tastes good.
Rym: Not everyone likes that.
Scott: no because some people have fucked up tongues.
Rym: some people have different tastes right.
Rym: so Gaming as well.
Scott: the reason that leveling up?
Rym: Not everyone who likes steak likes it for that one particular reason.
Rym: some people might like steak just cuz they like fucking killing cows.
Rym: Maybe they just like eating that texture.
Rym: There's lots of different reasons someone might like something.
Scott: no It is.
Rym: I disagree with this premise that the only reason anyone could ever have for liking a tech tree in any Capability is there at stake.
Scott: first of all you're lumping a bunch of different tech trees together.
Scott: right the thing is is that there?
Rym: Clearly to find the difference?
Rym: the reason that games in which simply playing repeatedly I agree with you on this too, but you need enjoyable fire for many people not for all people It's for everybody.
Scott: now I don't.
Scott: there's no reason to enjoy that kind of thing for you for anybody.
Rym: now I disagree.
Scott: otherwise you just lie to yourself.
Rym: I don't like those games, but I'd still disagree with you.
Rym: But anyway, maybe we'll have to do a show on it do a panel on it regardless The complaint we get whatever we do Panel shows or con shows or event shows on GeekNights and it's always weird.
Rym: because if we talk about a con we went to and We just kind of talk about our personal experiences and review the con Half the people email us and say I don't want to hear about these bullshit cons cuz I don't go to them And I don't give a shit.
Scott: Maybe you should go to them and give a shit.
Rym: and the thing is they always say why do you do these shows and we?
Rym: Get an equal amount of feedback saying yeah, I'm glad to hear about it I was there and it was awesome, or I didn't get to go, but it was awesome hearing about it from you and Both sides don't seem to realize that it's 50/50.
Rym: It's not like we're catering to this audience of like four people who went to PAX.
Rym: when we talk about packs I would say that the majority of you guys want the shows about conventions, so shut up haters.
Scott: Yeah, but we have figured out a plan to appease both sides.
Scott: if you're one of those convention people You're probably you know who hates these shows.
Scott: Maybe you didn't even start listening to this one because you're like oh, it's about packs.
Scott: I'm not listening.
Scott: well You fail because in the first half of the show we're gonna just talk about games all the games We happen to have played at PAX, and then we will do the part that some people You know might not enjoy Which is talking about the things that happened at PAX in the second half of the show.
Scott: So anyone who just didn't listen to the show at all because they didn't want to listen to a convention show You missed half a show you probably want to listen to.
Scott: so fail on you.
Rym: Not that they'll ever know.
Scott: some of them might know because they might find out eventually.
Rym: So Saturday was like the gaming fucking night for us at PAX.
Rym: we basically had nothing to do except our panel and We pretty much hung out in tabletop almost all night playing.
Rym: in fact We were some of the last people out of the convention center.
Rym: the enforcers were like all right We're locking the door, and we're going to bed.
Rym: You've got to be out by to close the door behind you and then they left.
Scott: That's fun guess cuz we had enforcers with us playing so it was pretty rockin.
Rym: We played a free market.
Scott: Yep Well that was Saturday.
Scott: I mean what about the games we played on Friday?
Rym: I was just talking about Saturday to start you jumping over to Saturday.
Scott: that this doesn't matter cuz we're not talking about the convention yet.
Rym: Plus we didn't play that many games on Friday.
Rym: Saturday was like the game at night.
Scott: I can't remember which day I played which games or all the games I played because I played so many games.
Rym: the note for you because I actually remember on Saturday we played free market Bonanza power boats modern art push fight Dominion jungle speed.
Scott: We didn't play this because you probably sat there while I was biking over here and thought and tried to remember really hard and wrote Them all down.
Rym: No.
Rym: I just have a memory.
Rym: captain doesn't remember anything from any media.
Rym: We ever consume ever.
Rym: I remember name any Character other than your own from the last RPG that we played with Alex the burning wheel game The burning wheel game any character NBC PC their name I could tie getting.
Scott: I could tell you that like Adam was the wolf and Pete was the rat and Kate was bitch name more than two characters from the Prince of Nothing series the entire series.
Scott: nay, all right as Manet, all right The the crazy priest dude Starts an M.
Rym: My thinet Matt.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right, so far you've only got two.
Rym: You didn't even name the protagonist yet.
Rym: Oh Okay, you're getting there.
Scott: I came in all right.
Rym: Regardless this is not a member.
Rym: member of like super memory.
Rym: It's just a matter of remembering what games I fucking.
Scott: It's not it's not easy.
Rym: So yeah, Scott ran free market at PAX cuz we had like some hours to kill and we played with some listeners.
Rym: It was totally awesome.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the thing about free market is, you know, I'm trying to Gia.
Rym: I realized Scott You don't have any flavor text.
Scott: My GM is my GM skills are low.
Scott: So the thing is I realized.
Scott: also the only way to up the GM skills is practice Which is a chicken and egg situation because nobody wants to play a game with a shitty GM.
Scott: but the only way to make a good GM is either have Talent just you're born with it or Play a bunch of games with the shitty GM until the shitty GM isn't shitty anymore.
Rym: See now here's here's the real trouble.
Rym: if you want to run a shitty game with inexperienced players They're never gonna want to roleplay again.
Rym: If you want to if you're gonna do that with experienced players, they know and they're not gonna show up.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: You know how I learned.
Scott: it's a chicken and egg situation.
Rym: I GM really shitty games in high school.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It seems like that's the only way to do it because in high school People are getting the kids are gonna play no matter what right you can.
Scott: you can get away with shitty GM.
Rym: in my high school There's a king because they like the shitty GMing.
Scott: they'll enjoy it no matter what.
Rym: I ran the worst game ever.
Rym: It was this week.
Rym: We called it guns.
Rym: It was the system.
Rym: We made to fix D&D set in the modern era with d30s.
Rym: I'm not even kidding.
Scott: or even in college You know Alex got a whole bunch of GM and skills playing a bunch of D&D with us that increased in quality over time You know, yeah But free market, I don't know how much you want to talk about it now But it isn't like the easiest game in the world to GM Like it's so easy.
Rym: Well, it's easy as long as you are able to come up with very detailed and very creative flavor text No matter what the characters are conflicting.
Scott: Well, I have a new.
Scott: I came up.
Scott: I realized that my flavor text was weak and now I have come up with a flavor text strategy.
Scott: They're going on master now my flavor text strategy that I'm going to employ in the future.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, because I have a very simple one.
Rym: Let's see if it's the same thing.
Rym: Just make shit up.
Scott: No, because making shit up is hard And you need a. you need a procedure to follow so that it is easier to make shit up, right?
Scott: So here's my new procedure to make my flavor text not suck.
Scott: You ready for this?
Scott: Whenever anything is happening, right whenever you open whenever I open my mouth to describe anything that is happening, right?
Scott: I must pick at least three of five senses of seeing tasting touching hearing smelling right the five and I must pick at least three and say what they are and that is How you will get the good flavor text.
Scott: I'll be like instead of just being for example Here's the bad flavor text.
Scott: you go into the dungeon.
Scott: It's a dungeon.
Scott: There's a monster here, right?
Scott: So now I have to pick three senses ready.
Scott: So you go into the dungeon.
Scott: I'll do the seeing in the dungeon.
Scott: It is an incredibly dark dungeon.
Scott: You can't even see three feet in front of your face.
Scott: Right before you there are some slimy rocks and then I'll do the smelling.
Scott: it is really dank and there is a hint of Rotting flesh wafting at you from deep into the darkness.
Scott: and then the hearing you hear some growling from around the corner Is a monster Scott.
Rym: I head down to the loading docks.
Rym: I'm looking for some dust bunnies.
Rym: help me clean up a problem.
Scott: You go down to the loading docks.
Scott: you see you know many barges here and there are merchant Marines running about loading and unloading cargo containers onto the boats and You hear the sounds of the waves splashing against the the boardwalk and you smell the salty sea air and It is quite humid with all the the recent this coming storm.
Scott: All right, and you go to get some dust bunnies from the dust bunny dealer.
Scott: And he is.
Scott: he looks like a really he's a really old nasty man with a with a peg leg and an iPad.
Rym: You didn't tell me what he smells like.
Scott: I'm getting there Already.
Scott: I did the three senses for the docks and now I'm doing the three senses for the dust bunny salesman.
Rym: I'm good practice.
Rym: I'm thinking because that Arabian Nights game very pointedly requires you.
Rym: when you make characters You have to describe them in terms of five senses.
Rym: Every character has a sentence related to a sense and you have five sentences.
Rym: and that's it.
Scott: But do you see how this is?
Scott: this is the number one?
Scott: This is the key for the for the indie role-playing games is they give you a procedure some Rules to work with because nerds are good at rules.
Scott: They give you a instead of D&D which just says his rules for fighting.
Rym: and oh, yeah You should roleplay right thinking of which I picked up again.
Rym: You heard NYC another copy of the second edition advanced Dungeons & Dragons players handbook.
Rym: Yeah, then I opened it up and I opened it.
Rym: I happen to randomly open it to the page that says in the upper left hand corner weapon proficiencies and all this tag non weapon and on the bottom right of the next page non weapon proficiencies.
Rym: and it's like Cooking and swimming right?
Scott: The thing is the not the indie RPGs the good ones, you know Not all of them, but many of them give you an actual rules-based procedure for doing the role-playing Which turns nerds like me into quality role-playing.
Scott: Did you see how my shitty flavor text became?
Scott: satisfactory flavor text when I applied a procedure of Describe the three senses?
Scott: right if if I would if you know, just make shit up.
Scott: I'd be like, alright make shit up.
Scott: But instead I have a specific thing I have to do do seeing.
Scott: what does it see?
Scott: What do you see?
Scott: What does it smell like and what do you hear?
Scott: and I'm like, okay, what do they see?
Scott: They see this, you know and I picture it in my head and then it comes out because I have a procedure and that is The key.
Rym: but at least an experienced game master who knows the rules really well can whip out free market Including character creation at a con in like four hours.
Scott: I know the thing of the greatest thing about free market is that you really only imagine It's like learning a card game.
Scott: It is learning a card game, right?
Scott: It's like if you know how to play poker, you know, it's just a different poker not really related to poker But it's a card game like that and it's like those are.
Scott: that's how many rules you have to know.
Scott: Once you know all those rules You're good Because for example if you're GMing burning wheel or D&D their decisions the GM has to make that are sometimes difficult.
Scott: even in D&D It's like okay, you're gonna have to do a fight.
Scott: You're gonna have to do a skill challenge.
Scott: You're gonna have to do.
Scott: give me a this role.
Scott: Give me a strength check.
Scott: You have to figure out which rule to apply in which situations.
Scott: in free market You don't have to answer those kinds of hard questions.
Scott: as a GM All you have to decide is am I going to say yes and just let them do what they want at this point Or is it gonna be a challenge?
Scott: if it's a challenge?
Scott: It's all it's just.
Scott: it's a challenge.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: The only two rules are roleplay or have a challenge and having a challenge is also role-playing.
Rym: So I'm just amazed.
Scott: we pulled off a free market at a con because and it did it felt like when we were doing it I felt like oh my god I'm only have three days at PAX and I'm using like four hours on a free market.
Scott: But it totally in looking back at PAX.
Scott: It didn't take up that much time.
Scott: It was totally cool.
Scott: I mean we could have.
Scott: we should have done a few more challenges to really finish out the session But what we did was certainly enough.
Rym: Saturday night was the big like board gaming.
Rym: night though We played one round of this game called power boats, which actually was like it was a racing game.
Scott: And uh, you know, the thing is like.
Scott: I like racing games in theme, but not as much in practice.
Rym: See now this game had good mechanics because the mechanics of power boats is pretty simple You can roll dice to kind of build up speed but if you want to slow down, it's not so easy and if you crash too much you explode.
Rym: and it's kind of this like momentum math odds game and you're racing against other people and We play it on like baby baby baby mode.
Rym: and it was still pretty damn fun and I I sucked.
Rym: It ended like I was way ahead and then a bunch of people caught up and it was a good game and I lost in the And I like third place But Scott and one other player kind of got caught in the back and Scott just went around in circles Backwards around one buoy.
Scott: the problem is the problem is I tried to take sort of a Mario Party kind of route and that did Not work.
Rym: So then you killed yourself because that was easier than making it to the head.
Scott: You know what that game needs ramps.
Scott: You can jump if you hit the ramp Whatever your speed is.
Scott: when you hit the ramp plus one you jump that many forward.
Scott: But if you land on a rock you die, but if you land in the water awesome These ramps.
Rym: maybe if you land you should keep your momentum no matter what.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: so it needs jumps.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: I'm sure we can.
Scott: you can hit the side of the ramp and you would take damage But if you hit the front of the ramp you jump.
Rym: I say you should be able to ram other people, too.
Scott: Oh, absolutely.
Rym: It needs ramming and we need to be able to drop fucking mines.
Scott: Okay, it's a little bit too much.
Rym: no, I don't think it is.
Rym: I think oil slicks are enough plus imagine this taste.
Rym: So take the mechanics right?
Scott: Oh, no, you know what the game should be.
Scott: You don't control the boat.
Scott: You control a water skier, huh?
Scott: Attached to the boat.
Rym: No, so get this.
Rym: take the mechanics of the game with all the momentum and everything and make it a combat game.
Rym: It's basically Atari combat the board game and that can be pretty fun.
Scott: actually maybe I kind of just want to play Formula Day Because it has a better theme because formula racing is much better than power boat racing is pretty awesome.
Scott: I'm much more fan of Formula Race plus reading on board game geek.
Rym: It seems like people actually seem to prefer power boats as a better game probably because it has a lot more replay value.
Scott: I think so, but formula day has so many maps and like actual Monaco.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: But we didn't even we played on the baby mat and we put the buoys in the babyest baby places and I still sucked And I haven't played.
Scott: I don't have a lot of racing games under my belt.
Scott: so, you know It was hard.
Rym: we played with me Scott and Ian.
Rym: quick game of modern art.
Rym: now you did warn him.
Scott: Well, you said I quote watch out Rym is good at bidding games.
Rym: Yep, and he didn't listen and it was his game And he got owned.
Scott: I even owned him.
Scott: I was pretty close to you.
Rym: actually you were but I ignored you.
Rym: Cuz you suck at bidding games.
Scott: I I was doing good at that bidding game.
Scott: I figured it out mostly.
Rym: we learned this back in the day when I was undefeated at Pizarro and you were undefeated at power grid Not power grid the web of power I like.
Scott: I just really like modern art compared to the other bidding games because if you look at some of the other bidding games Like say Pizarro, right the values of things are pretty much set.
Scott: But in modern art the values of the things are bidding on might change in the next auctions.
Scott: Not only are you bidding on who will own this thing that is up for auction But you're also bidding on how will the value of the things that are currently available?
Scott: Change based on the results of this auction and what comes up for bid next.
Scott: So you might be bidding a whole bunch on something because you think it's gonna be really valuable and then it ends up being worth Shit, yep, especially when you bust out or vice-rare Picasso or vice versa, you know It's the game with good mechanics.
Rym: And I like all that has all the Rainier Kinizia.
Scott: How can you go wrong?
Rym: has all these different kinds of bids like the sealed bid the open bid the once-around that is.
Scott: That is something I also love about it is that a lot of bidding games only have one kind of auction.
Scott: You know every auction in this game is the is a one.
Scott: you bid once and whoever bids the most is it or a power?
Scott: Grid.
Scott: every auction is go-around, you know bidding.
Rym: But in this game you have the jumping bidding where one jump is huge and you can leapfrog people and all that.
Scott: Yeah, but in this game all that you do all different kinds of auctions all the time, which is totally sweet.
Rym: So it's a fun game.
Rym: I enjoyed it.
Rym: I actually bought it because it was really cheap on Amazon.
Scott: I want to make a side note here.
Scott: right because We do.
Scott: we buy board games British.
Scott: every board game we have we bought right?
Scott: Yeah, and we've only re-boxed a few games.
Scott: re-boxing is pretty popular.
Scott: That's when you have a board game that takes up a lot of room or has a really big box and you go to the craft store or whatever and you buy maybe a Compartmentalized plastic box or something so that you can store the same board game in a smaller area
Rym: row made for me as a gift A long time a while ago that Carcassonne bag.
Rym: Yeah, it takes up a lot less space than a Carcassonne but although it has the little patch on the outside for the starting Tile.
Scott: Yeah, because when you have a lot of board games each of those boxes a lot of air in it.
Scott: So if you can compress the games to a smaller area, you can save a lot of space in your board game shell.
Scott: However, I've discovered a new thing which is the printout board game.
Scott: Basically.
Rym: I was impressed by this.
Rym: that was Ian again.
Scott: Yeah, it's more.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's more common than I thought because people talking about it at recess to where let's say there is a board Game that is out of print or do or difficult to get a
Rym: dune
Scott: right or something like that Don't buy it at the store Alright Just print your own copy make your own box Get your own chits and pawns and make your own copy of the game.
Scott: Just get the rules off board game geek.
Scott: Look at the parts list.
Rym: get some dice and with the right kind of glue and a little bit of skill I mean he had this doom set and it looked really good.
Scott: like it looked at me I didn't realize that it was a printed out set.
Scott: I thought it was.
Rym: he owned the game as well as I said to him Hey that dune is in crazy good condition.
Rym: He's like, yeah, I made it myself Yeah, and I was like what?
Scott: no way.
Scott: so if this some out-of-print game that you just can't buy You know make it.
Scott: and the thing is you might think I'm making it is some kind of evil piracy.
Scott: The thing is making a copy of the board game will often be just as if not more expensive than buying a copy.
Rym: is Making a copy of a board unless the game is good.
Rym: I have a moral question for you is making your own copy of a board game from you know Engineering it on your own any worse than singing Britney Spears songs to yourself.
Scott: No.
Rym: Well, there we go.
Scott: It's nothing wrong with it at all.
Scott: I'm not.
Scott: I'm not putting it down in any way.
Scott: I'm lifting it up.
Scott: I'm saying people should do this.
Scott: Yeah, it's totally cool.
Scott: Especially because if you make it right not only let's say I make my own Carcassonne, right.
Scott: Okay, the Carcassonne guys are gonna miss out on a few bucks But you know what?
Scott: It cost me more to make it than it in time and money than it would cost to buy one.
Scott: so really I'm not cheating them out of anything.
Scott: I put in hard work for that.
Scott: and Secondly, I might put some probably gonna put some unique touches on my own carcass.
Scott: Oh, and so it's really a different game because I'm gonna make some better meeples.
Scott: Maybe I'll use camels Maybe I'll you make a different theme you get creative.
Scott: It's like artwork.
Scott: So it's totally cool to make your own board games, you know, why would you buy a monopoly?
Scott: make your own monopoly?
Rym: So we played this really quick game called push fight and it's kind of like a.
Scott: it is an online version.
Rym: I found out yeah, it wasn't in unity - yeah of all things.
Rym: Yep It's kind of like oshi not as good but it's pretty.
Scott: you don't think it's as good as oshi.
Rym: I think oshi is a much better game.
Scott: I think that it actually had a slight advantage over oshi in that you don't get the oshi has a special Exception rule so that you don't go back and forth.
Scott: push fight didn't even need that rule.
Rym: No push right has the rule.
Rym: you move that piece around and you can't remove a piece that has that piece.
Scott: But I think that the red the red guy was a little more elegant than the oshi rule.
Rym: I think we should just incorporate the red guy into oshi.
Scott: whoever you push with Whenever a piece you move can't be pushed.
Rym: Put the red guy on him.
Rym: We could try it or put the red guy into the spot where he came from or something like that.
Rym: Something we'll have to fiddle with it.
Rym: It was fun, but it's another one of those games.
Rym: notice I'm bringing up all the games that I was awesome at before.
Rym: we talk about all the games.
Rym: I lost.
Rym: I Was undefeated at this game.
Rym: I played Scott like six times.
Rym: I played a bunch of other people.
Rym: No one can beat me because this game.
Rym: you realize here's everyone's mistake, you know that game I always talk about with the sticks where you cross off sticks taking turns.
Rym: Whoever picks up the last tick lose.
Scott: I was the same.
Scott: Oh, they're the stable state in the unstable state.
Scott: I knew.
Scott: I knew it was that game right away.
Scott: The problem is I could recognizing the pad.
Rym: I could stable and I couldn't recognize the state.
Scott: I recognize some of the stable and unstable states.
Scott: Mostly I had a hard time recognizing the unstable states.
Scott: I recognized the stable states All right.
Scott: The other problem I had is there were some unstable states that were actually one turn away from an obvious unstable state But there was still no escape from them and I couldn't recognize those for shit.
Scott: Yeah, see but it was that.
Scott: it was one of those situations where there's things, you know There's things you don't know there's things you know, you don't know and there's things you don't know you don't know.
Scott: Yeah, this game was full of things.
Scott: I knew I didn't know.
Rym: See I guess the game actually broke down really simply pretty much two turns in.
Rym: I knew if I won or not and if I and if I knew that I Lost I knew that the other person sucked and I could just push it back I could flip the unstable state and then I'd win no matter what.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah It had the neat mechanic and like oshi though where you can basically move pieces anywhere.
Rym: So it's more about blocking off areas of the board Than it is necessarily about like push.
Rym: that was always.
Scott: if you got your guy you're square behind their lines.
Scott: That was it.
Scott: You're that was a huge advantage right there.
Scott: All right, what other games we play?
Rym: I don't know if I'll ever play that game again because I'm undefeated at it and I want to remain that way.
Rym: Yeah, we played Bonanza so of an end.
Rym: I want to talk about this.
Rym: Bonanza is a. it's a game that looks stupid.
Rym: It's awesome box.
Rym: You're like, yeah fuck this game.
Scott: and when they brought it out ultra rare cocoa bean I was gonna bring up the ultra rare cocoa bean ultra rare and cocoa is the best root bean in the game.
Rym: We started this game late like after this game.
Rym: We played like two rounds of Dominion and then it was two in the morning.
Rym: This is like the last real normal and we had like a ton of people playing.
Scott: It was a full loadout.
Rym: It was the West Coast crew the West Coast front row crew and the Azen posse.
Scott: It was loaded up big time.
Rym: So they whip out this game and I'm really tired Like they whipped it out while I was out getting the drink.
Rym: and I come back and I'm like, what the fuck is this game?
Rym: We're playing it and they're like we bid on beans.
Rym: and he explained to the rules.
Rym: and I'm like this look I don't remember who won.
Rym: I did handily.
Rym: I kicked everyone's asses.
Scott: I thought I did really well I don't remember now.
Scott: I'm pretty sure I did.
Rym: Well, I want hand over fist.
Rym: Whatever I did.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway this game they whip it out and every packs are.
Scott: now on we're gonna have a game log.
Rym: Yeah I'm very very very much a proponent of this because I won almost every freaking game.
Scott: I played a pack and now once you have a game log, you're gonna lose every game.
Scott: That's gonna be awesome.
Rym: So this game looked dumb and then it was row.
Rym: You know our West Coast front row crew friend and she starts off in the game.
Rym: You know, she's starting to play and I'm just like whatever.
Rym: I'm gonna bid on this and she turns to the guy She can bid from and she's like yo brother.
Rym: I need this bean.
Rym: I need some green beans.
Rym: right now I need the bean.
Rym: Give me the bean then fuck y'all B. And she got really into it and then they all got into it.
Scott: Everyone got into it big time.
Rym: The West Coast crew is into this game the way we're into our own games.
Rym: They had a shtick and the shtick is 90% of the fun of this game.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think the game would have been fun even without the shtick.
Scott: It wasn't even so.
Scott: it is a game where I think the best thing about this game Is that you look at other games that have trading settlers even traders of Genoa Genoa, right?
Scott: Is it's often a good idea not to trade and in fact it usually want to reject most trade offers in this game.
Scott: People are desperate to trade because the rules are so ingenious.
Scott: So you're basically trading constantly.
Scott: you want to get rid of this shit and in fact you need to get rid of it.
Scott: So you will try to get something for it, right?
Scott: hopefully there'll be competition for whatever there is.
Scott: you're trading away like say I need that Pinto be like.
Scott: if I really need to get rid of this Green bean and there's more than one person who wants it then I can get a good deal for it.
Scott: But if there's only one person who wants it or if nobody wants it I still really really really need to get rid of it.
Scott: So I'll give it away for free.
Scott: I'll give it as a gift I'll you know, and if it gets accepted I would get.
Scott: I just get rid of it.
Scott: So people are bargaining every single turn hardcore on every single bean big time So every.
Rym: you might wonder why we keep saying the ultra rare cocoa bean.
Rym: So every round it goes around and you can only like make actual trades with the active player.
Rym: So every round the active players trying to trade with everyone.
Rym: Everyone's kind of like I got I got pitobee I got black beans I got this bean I got that bean and then there'd always be a silence and then Scott would just say with the exact Intonation and pacing and everything.
Rym: Does anybody want my ultra rare cocoa bean?
Rym: and he would say it in that exact way Every single person's turn.
Rym: and it got to the point that like what he said it and we just like we all lost it I couldn't deal with the ultra rare cocoa bean.
Scott: Well, I mean the thing is is I drew this.
Scott: every card every bean has a number on it And that number is how many beans of that bean are in the dead black eyed beans.
Scott: So for example the game.
Scott: I use a lot of wax beans in the game and there are like a zillion wax beans in the Game like 20 something like a ton of them, but I drew early in the game the ultra rare cocoa bean.
Scott: It had the number four on it Which means there's only four cocoa beans in the whole game and it paid out real quick and I was like goddamn this bean It's in my hand.
Scott: I need to get it out of my hand and Anybody want my ultra rare cocoa bean, right?
Rym: so I'm like no one else has one and if they do big deal right cuz then he would hold his cards like in two fists and he Would like make this earnest gesture like does anybody want my ultra rare cocoa bean?
Scott: So what eventually happened though is I drew and I Randomly completely by luck.
Scott: I drew another one and another and then I had three out of the four cocoa beans.
Rym: So then you cashed in.
Scott: I cashed in cocoa bean.
Scott: it worked.
Scott: but the thing is I was trying to trade that first one away cuz.
Scott: it was no good if you only have one of them.
Scott: and Yeah, it was pretty ultra rare.
Rym: So I note this two bidding games at PAX.
Rym: I sat to the left of Ian who's good at bidding games and He ignored me because I was the new guy and then I won left-right mechanics Mechanics big big deal.
Rym: Yeah, we were talking about left-right mechanics a lot for some reason in fact Cuz we kept talking like it kept coming up.
Scott: It was weird Yeah, so I think it was Saturday morning before he played free market.
Scott: I played this game that I've seen around but I never played it before and it looked really stupid.
Scott: But I played it anyway, and it's called we didn't play.
Scott: test this at all.
Scott: Oh, no, we play and it has.
Scott: it has an expansion pack called we didn't play.
Scott: test this either.
Scott: now The way this game works is it's a lot like flux.
Scott: You have cards and every turn you play it draw a card play a card or I forget.
Scott: if you play and then draw Doesn't matter.
Rym: you say it's like flux, but I it is like flux.
Rym: if flux had almost no rules Well, that's the looks has so much more like game to it.
Scott: It's like flux in that the only rules are draw card play a card and all the rest of the rules are on the cards.
Rym: that's the similarity right, but there are cards like you win or You lose or Everybody loses or make everyone vote.
Rym: Yes or no.
Rym: if they all vote.
Rym: Yes you win.
Scott: Yeah, I love the voting cards or the rock-paper-scissors cards because there's like a whole bunch of different ones.
Scott: So it'd be like art everyone rock-paper-scissors and you have no idea which rock-paper-scissors card it is.
Scott: Maybe it's a card that says everyone who plays rock loses.
Scott: Maybe it's a card That says everyone who plays scissors loses.
Scott: There's all three of them are in the deck somewhere Unless you've seen what it got to
Rym: the point where you don't know the guy who happened to be the shortest person playing the game with us Drew a card that said something to the effect of if you just lost and you're the shortest person at the table you win.
Scott: Instead I think it was just play this card if you're the shortest person at the table you win.
Scott: It was something like otherwise you get five points and anyone who has 15 points wins But you can change that to 100 points.
Rym: now Scott played this game and none of us did so he whips it out like 11 O'clock after playing bonanza on like Saturday night, and we're all like.
Rym: I don't want to play this stupid game.
Rym: shut up Scott Go away.
Rym: Don't play this game with us, and he makes us play it.
Rym: and it was funny.
Rym: Everyone said this sucks this sucks.
Rym: Let's stop.
Rym: and yet when we said alright.
Rym: They all said now one more round No, let's play one more time.
Rym: Let's see this again.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's not a good game.
Scott: It doesn't.
Scott: it's not a skill game or anything like that.
Scott: It's just epic lols.
Rym: It's a game.
Rym: I think I might buy it.
Scott: I guess oh, that's a lol generator.
Rym: because if you buy it this game has one purpose you whip it out at a convention Once and you'll be the guy.
Scott: the thing is every convention I've been to has the game in their library.
Scott: So there's no reason for me to buy it because I'd only want to play it at a convention.
Rym: so here if you run a Convention buy this game.
Scott: Yeah, and put it in your conventions game library for open gaming.
Rym: if I were at Connecticut Let's make a tournament happen.
Rym: That's hard.
Rym: Yeah for serious.
Rym: It would take like 10 minutes.
Scott: All right sure I'll run it.
Scott: We didn't play.
Scott: test this at all.
Rym: tournament listeners We might forget.
Rym: remind me to run this tournament.
Rym: I totally will if you remind us.
Scott: there's another game I played the Rym didn't play called squirrels and the guy who made the game was there pimping it at a little table and robot it.
Scott: so we played it with her and some other people and Basically the way the game works is you're a bunch of squirrels fighting over nuts, right?
Scott: So what you're trying to do is you're trying to get sets of nuts in sets of three.
Scott: So you're looking for like, you know the card with four daddy three nut You'll have a card with four nuts on it and the number four.
Scott: so you want three of those right.
Scott: and then you if you when you get them you make sets out of the nuts and Basically, I didn't have a good time because I basically couldn't get a set to save my life.
Scott: But there are some special cards sort of like jungle speed, right?
Scott: So one of them it's like slap your hand down on the hoard and whoever does it first gets the hoard And stuff like that.
Scott: And there was a whole bunch of or there would be like a quarrel and the way the quarrel works.
Scott: You have a quarrel with somebody.
Rym: Oh squirrel quarrel is.
Scott: so If you have a squirrel with someone you play the highest card you have and then the second highest and so on.
Scott: and it's like War, you know, where whoever has the highest wins.
Scott: Ah, so I did a quarrel with someone and I got all the way down to the last card And then I won.
Scott: and then I got a whole bunch of cards and I laid down a whole bunch of sets.
Scott: You know, it's sort of like that.
Scott: So it's not a huge skill game It's a lot of luck, but it is still pretty entertaining if you play it a few times.
Scott: So, you know, it's if you're gonna play war you're better off playing squirrels time.
Scott: It's like war plus jungle speed plus Like, you know rummy is squirrels.
Scott: It's not bad.
Rym: So we played a whole bunch of Dominion and there's not a lot to say about it except that it was Dominion.
Rym: Scott and I had a joint victory because we exhausted the tiebreakers.
Scott: That's a good win.
Rym: That was a good win.
Rym: I was very disappointed at the lack of a final tiebreaker though.
Scott: Yeah, we played roll through the ages, but I think we've talked about that before.
Scott: Yeah, it's Yahtzee plus Civilization.
Rym: We played a whole bunch of jungle speed because you can just whip that out nowhere and it just works.
Scott: We played jungle speed.
Rym: Yes, you played I didn't play in this that catacombs game.
Scott: Oh, so catacombs a real interesting game because what it is is it's a dexterity game where you flick things just like crocodile But it's a dungeon crawler.
Scott: So you'll be there.
Scott: You'll have a wizard and you want to do a melee attack.
Scott: you flick your wizard and try to hit a skeleton.
Scott: That's a bad guy and the one person plays all the bad guys and four people play the heroes.
Rym: It looks really fun.
Rym: The game looked like it had problems.
Scott: It needed to be bigger.
Scott: Yeah, conceptually the game was mad fun, right because like I want to shoot a fireball So you take the fireball token put it down within an inch of your wizard and flick it at a bad guy and that does The damage to him.
Scott: and you do the day and I some of the guys have one HP and they just die.
Scott: and some guys Have more than one HP.
Scott: so when they get hit you flip them over and then you hit him again and then they die and they have different powers like Some guys will paralyze you or whatever.
Scott: and you know It was a dungeon crawl where you flick Your bat your got your heroes and your spells and your arrows at the bad guys to kill them and we got all the way To the Lich, but then he killed us, which is pretty good.
Scott: We got all the way that far.
Rym: Um, I want to see more games like this.
Rym: It's a really cool concept.
Rym: I just I want metal pieces and the board to be like ten times bigger.
Scott: Yeah, the board is really small and has the obstacles and it's not really precise.
Rym: I also want someone to make that game but make it shuffleboard size and run it at a con.
Scott: That is exactly what needs to happen because the game would be so much better if you you know There was.
Scott: the pieces are so small and sort of flaky and the board is small.
Scott: So it's really sort of imprecise, you know, not like crocodile, which is incredibly precise or shuffleboard, which is incredibly precise You know if you have a you have a dexterity game like this.
Scott: It needs to be like on the money, you know, so it needs to be bigger in the scale and everything.
Scott: So get it needs a ruler You know to make sure that you're putting the spell within one inch of you and all that kind of stuff.
Scott: But other than that, I mean it was you know It was mechanically sound and conceptually original and interesting and I applaud it.
Scott: I don't know if I'd buy it probably never.
Rym: but and I guess the only other game there was that poo flinging game.
Rym: We didn't actually play.
Rym: play the poof.
Rym: a lot of people were talking about it and playing it at the con.
Scott: The poofling game seemed like a random card game and the way it worked is.
Scott: you played cards But you would.
Scott: the cards would fling poo with the other monkeys and the other monkeys of the other players.
Scott: So you had these gems and you would basically put the gems on the other people to signify who got.
Rym: You know, why doesn't the game come with little pieces of poo?
Scott: because it doesn't have that high production value.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, are there any other games I can remember?
Rym: So things of the day, what do you got for me Scott?
Scott: So You know, I'm always complaining about those guys in the city who You know, they use the stupid track bikes, which are totally cool But they use them on the street where you're not supposed to use the stupid
Rym: hipster assholes
Scott: because there's you know I mean and I'm usually I'm not a person who's in favor of a helmet law.
Scott: I mean, you know because it's like hey, if you don't have a helmet, who are you putting in danger yourself?
Scott: It's your own decision, right?
Scott: Obviously a children is a little different situation like the helmet laws that say children have to wear them.
Scott: It's like okay because then it's a parent putting their child in danger, whatever.
Scott: There's arguments to be made.
Scott: The point is you want to put yourself in danger.
Scott: That's totally cool.
Scott: If you want to put other people in danger, that's not cool and riding around a bicycle on a street where there are pedestrians and cars Without brakes is not cool.
Rym: and you might think who would do that?
Rym: and the answer is New York hipsters.
Rym: I see them every day.
Scott: about like 25% of the bicycles that I see going around the city Have no brakes at all just because they're track bikes They're meant for.
Rym: they try like their stupid boot on the back to try to slow down.
Scott: No, they put their crusty old van They rub the bottom of their crusty old van on the bottom the back tire to slow down.
Rym: I I'll admit every time I see these people I want to just jump out in front of them.
Rym: Yep You're like, oh couldn't stop could you?
Rym: Yeah, but then they hit me.
Scott: so yeah, that's the thing.
Scott: and it's like Okay, if you hit the back of a car because you have no brakes The thing is oh you're hurting yourself, which is fine.
Scott: I don't mind that You're damaging this dude's car.
Scott: and what if you hit an old lady trying to cross that in the crosswalk?
Scott: I mean, come on, that's not cool.
Scott: but anyway There was this video.
Scott: It was on College Humor.
Scott: All right that showed an actual track race and I actually learned a lot about track racing.
Scott: I knew already the track racing is done in a velodrome, which is a nice smooth banked track.
Rym: That's where roller derby used to happen.
Rym: But now roller derby happens on a flat which is why roller derby is heaven.
Scott: It's actually helping it out because there aren't too many velodromes.
Scott: In fact, there's so few velodromes that in Wikipedia.
Scott: There is a page list of velodromes.
Scott: Wow Yeah, so anyway I knew that and I knew that it was incredibly fast and that they use these bikes with no brakes.
Scott: what I did not know is that the reason that the bikes have no brakes is because Moving backwards is actually ixnay.
Scott: You can't do that.
Scott: You get in trouble if you go backwards.
Scott: So if you had.
Scott: and the other thing is that they don't go fast the whole race They don't just go go go go go from the beginning.
Scott: It's actually the whole beginning of the race.
Scott: What they will do is they will purposefully go slow.
Scott: In fact, they will try to stop which is really hard to do with.
Rym: no play that game.
Rym: as a kid I'm going slower than you.
Rym: I'm going slower than you.
Scott: All right, they'll purposefully try to slow down Which is really hard when you know, the the the pedals are directly attached to the wheel.
Scott: You know pedaling backwards makes you go backwards.
Scott: It's you know, it's that kind of bike.
Scott: So It's really you can stop with the power of your legs and you know by going up high on the track on the bank You know oval and turning the tire inwards and physically holding yourself still now Why would you want to do that in a race?
Scott: Well, the reason is because of aerodynamics and other things.
Scott: you're.
Scott: it's actually advantageous to be behind the other guy because then you can get into his Aerodynamic trail and that'll and then you can use that to just boost around the side of him at the very end of the race.
Scott: All right, so you will try to purposefully these guys go slow on purpose to be behind to win and That's why there's no brakes.
Scott: because if you had brakes You could just sit there on your brakes without going backwards and it would be no point to the race at all.
Scott: So Is this cool video that shows a really sort of dramatic race?
Scott: And you know the stronger buffer dude is dramatic But other than the very end it looks like two kids playing a dumb game with their bikes Exactly, which is why track racing I think is not that popular in the u.s.
Scott: However When they do go behead hitting.
Scott: that's right.
Scott: when they do go fast They do go incredibly fast like oh my god fast.
Scott: Now the other thing about this is I actually looked up, you know by you know I was researching and I found out about this other kind of track racing called the care in and it's in Japan and The way the care in works is.
Scott: you actually have like say I think eight dudes maybe and they all race at once.
Scott: But the way it works is to prevent the going slow and the stupidness.
Scott: There's a motorcycle and the motorcycle goes in front of them.
Scott: It's not like a Harley, right?
Scott: it's like a you know a bicycle but it's motorized and He that guy will pace the race.
Scott: So he basically they go around one lap and you're not allowed to pass the motorcycle.
Scott: That's the only rule.
Scott: you can't pass the motorcycle and the first lap He'll go like 20 miles an hour and then 40 at what kilometers?
Scott: now, right?
Scott: Every lap he'll speed up and then on the final lap or two, right?
Scott: He'll just get out of the way and you can go nuts.
Scott: so basically everyone speeds up gradually to a ludicrous speed and
Rym: Then
Scott: and then everyone gets let loose and sometimes is amazing high-speed crashes which are epic And sometimes it's just a really fast awesome race where like eight dudes are on bikes go in like 50 kilometers an hour All right, maybe even 70.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: So here's some awesome track bike racing videos.
Scott: and if you want to be a track bike racer, that's totally awesome.
Scott: Go for it.
Scott: Keep that fucking bike off the street and get one with fucking brakes.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I gotta look for on YouTube now videos of hipsters on track bikes hurting themselves.
Rym: That would be totally out there gonna make compilation.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So pig with the face of a boy Is it just genetically modified or was a band?
Rym: Okay in the UK Alright and they made a music video that is entitled a complete history of the Soviet Union arranged to the melody of Tetris.
Rym: This is doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Rym: This is fucking awesome.
Rym: Like this is way off the hook.
Rym: How off the hook could it be one?
Rym: the production values are super super super high like it is Amazingly, well, that's I guess.
Scott: I guess pig with the face of a boy is a popular band like the big.
Scott: Or is it like an okay go situation?
Rym: I really can't tell.
Rym: but this is like it's off the hook that the quality is so amazing Like it looks really really professional and not only is the song good and the video good But it really is the history of the Soviet Union as set to the melody of Tetris and furthermore the metaphor of Tetris.
Rym: You know building these walls that disappear as you complete them never finishing.
Rym: Your only options are to play forever and achieve nothing or die trying Yeah, and apply that to the Soviet Union.
Rym: and it goes through, you know The czar all the way up to perestroika And they today are all the czar the last czar.
Scott: Oh, that's where it starts.
Scott: It starts right around with Nicholas the second.
Scott: Yes, see I won't.
Scott: why does it start with like Peter the great and shit you're missing all the good stuff I've in the terrible.
Rym: there was no Soviet Union.
Rym: Catherine the also great Starts with you know, the advent of the Soviet Union and the Bolshevik Revolution.
Scott: It's not the history of Russia is the history of the Soviet Union.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Okay, but every section of the song Covered like it's weird It embodies the the sentiment of that era and like what Russia was like but is also like a video period piece like it looks like video looked from that era
Scott: and it's
Rym: Stylized like it's from that era and like Russia in the 80s and Russia in the 50s and Russia's in the 20s
Scott: The video keeps getting better and better.
Rym: the video looks better and better But it looks better and better in the stylized way and it ends with Putin and it.
Rym: this is fucking brilliant And I think everyone's got to see this.
Scott: So if we were gonna make history of the u.s.
Scott: In You know starting I guess with 1776 right.
Scott: So what song would we do?
Rym: We need a song.
Scott: what would video look like in 70?
Rym: we need a song that looks.
Scott: think about that.
Scott: film is older than the Soviet Union.
Scott: well Soviet Union is also dead but Film is not older than the United States.
Rym: But they could do those silver prints.
Rym: even back then and in the Civil War we had photography.
Scott: There are no silver prints of George Washington.
Rym: Yeah, but we didn't have those then.
Rym: so you know what?
Rym: It's just black and then it's just paintings maybe Yeah in the beginning.
Rym: Yeah, we got to come up with a song there.
Rym: Remember, it can't just be a good song And it's be a good song that we cover.
Rym: that itself is a metaphor for everything that the United States stands for across all Of its eras from a video game cuz the lyrics are like I am the man who arranges the blocks and it's This is this is fucking brilliant.
Rym: All right, so we've played a whole bunch more games at PAX.
Rym: Oh Sweet and I don't.
Rym: yeah You know anything to say about the games we played.
Scott: I'm just trying to remember because they were all video games.
Scott: in this huge blur because the expo hall was double big Hall, I keep saying off the hook.
Rym: my friend Conrad I think infected me with that phrase.
Rym: But if anything at PAX was off the hook it other other than the omega-thon finale.
Scott: Yeah The omega-thon finale was on the hook.
Rym: It was only on the hook for the winner.
Rym: Anyway, if anything at PAX other than the omega-thon finale was off the hook It was the expo hall PAX East and the previous PAX Prime.
Rym: the expo hall was awesome But there were like two to four like big tall like crazy boots and everything else was awesome But it was like kind of smaller and normal This year.
Rym: it seems like everything in the entire place was just like gigantic Like every booth was crazy tall and filled with spectacle everywhere you went spectacle.
Scott: Yeah, and the thing is a lot of the spectral was for things I didn't know about or care about, you know.
Scott: And then even some of the things I completely ignored.
Scott: later I found out that they might have actually been good and some of the things I paid attention to that I thought might be good and maybe we're not as good.
Scott: I found, you know, it was like ah disappointing.
Rym: So we're not gonna talk about the expo hall We're just gonna talk about the games we saw that stood out beyond the spectacle in the expo hall Except of course Duke Nukem forever because Duke Nukem forever.
Scott: I played it technically so we can talk about it, but that is probably only time we'll ever be played in the history of the world.
Scott: It's an elaborate scam and it wasn't the full thing.
Scott: We should demo.
Scott: it doesn't count.
Rym: I was talking to people in line to play it, you know, I went in and just played it.
Scott: You know when you go in that room, they just gas you and rape you.
Rym: No, the guy in line like he was talking to his friend.
Rym: He's like, I don't think the games in there.
Rym: I think they're gonna tell us to lie to everyone else and give us a t-shirt and some money.
Rym: No, they gave me a t-shirt and some steroids But the spectacle of that booth is worth noting because it had it was a solid black booth.
Scott: You couldn't see anything that was going on inside.
Scott: So that was like adding to sort of the mystique of oh, oh what's in here?
Rym: all around the outside was security guards and this long queue and These portraits of Duke Nukem much much like the portraits of George Washington on the civilization booth.
Rym: I would not mind having one of those portraits in my apartment as a poster.
Scott: I'd buy one Astronaut.
Scott: one was pretty good.
Rym: So was the one with him accepting like every possible award ever at the same time.
Scott: Yeah, there was also.
Scott: they had two things, you know The things.
Scott: you put your face in it and then have a picture.
Rym: It was Duke Nukem with two Catholic schoolgirls.
Scott: Yeah, so you could put your face in the Catholic schoolgirl and have your photo.
Scott: take it that it.
Rym: that sounds really horrible.
Rym: They also had a whole bunch like this.
Rym: It was amazing.
Rym: But inside I did play Duke Nukem forever.
Rym: I played it.
Rym: I've actually played that game.
Rym: John St.
Rym: John was like, hey Rym, come on in.
Rym: I skipped the line.
Rym: I stood there.
Rym: I watched them talk about it.
Rym: And then I played it.
Rym: I urinated in a urinal and It was exactly what I expected.
Rym: it's really fucking dirty and really really tasteless in this kind of hilarious Homage kind of like how Duke Nukem 3d was almost this like homage to schlocky horror movies.
Rym: This was sort of homage to like Duke Nukem itself.
Rym: It's like this meta thing.
Scott: I Kind of I think I'm actually gonna buy it maybe not right away because I don't think the multiplayer is gonna go anywhere.
Rym: But I don't know cuz Duke Nukem 3d.
Rym: It's a fucking awesome multiplayer.
Scott: But I do want to play all the single-player just to see all the stuff that I know is gonna be crude.
Scott: But I will also find it hilarious and I'll probably buy it when it's like 20 bucks on Steam or whatever.
Scott: See, it's almost late.
Scott: through the whole thing It's almost a period piece because remember because I haven't had enough a single-player FPS action lately, you know I mean It's pretty much valve is the only one still cranking that.
Rym: so remember the 90s when video games that were violent like that was the thing Like oh my god Mortal Kombat on the Sega with the blood code.
Rym: This game is like homage to that era.
Rym: specifically I Feel like the whole game is just saying hey remember those days check this out hookers.
Rym: Oh my god She's giving you a blowjob and the Duke's just saying Duke stuff the whole time.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't actually go in to play it but I saw enough of it to know that it was real.
Scott: people actually played it.
Scott: I looked inside.
Scott: I saw people playing it.
Rym: Remember when I said hey, I gotta go and I ran down.
Rym: that was when I went in.
Rym: Yeah, cuz the Duke just texted me is like, hey, you want to see you want to come in.
Rym: and I was like, okay Yeah, and the the booth babes were funny because they were.
Scott: they were being very Want to talk about the booth baby.
Scott: This is the first year of packs booth babes.
Rym: Well save it for the proper review of packs.
Rym: But suffice it to say there were booth babes at many of the things and Duke Nukem I think had more booth babes than everyone else combined.
Rym: But when once the fanboys were gone like they let him into the next room and then it's just like us and like all the People who work for the company's involved in Duke Nukem forever The booth babes totally stopped smiling and are checking their Twitter and like, oh my god.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So did you?
Scott: um, did you play any the packs 10 games?
Rym: I played a whole bunch of them.
Scott: I don't have anything really.
Rym: they all were really interesting But I didn't have anything really to say about them other than the meat game was really fucking hard.
Scott: Yeah, the meat that's the one I wanted there.
Scott: a couple I wanted to talk about.
Scott: I don't wanna talk about all the meat.
Rym: game was advertised like hell.
Rym: I came with that comic book in the bag.
Scott: Right super meat boy, right looks like a really fucking good platform game like oh damn It's really good, but it's like.
Scott: it's not a puzzle platformer, which seems to be all the rage these days.
Scott: It's a real platformer.
Scott: aware Incredibly precise jumping is necessary and it is hard as balls Like you must jump precisely and with perfect timing and the right place in order to get past these levels.
Scott: and you know since you're made of meat you can sort of slide on the walls and that's what makes it a little bit interesting.
Scott: and I think I think I might buy it when it comes out.
Scott: It's gonna come out for pretty much all the downloadable so you can download it on Xbox Wii or PC.
Scott: I guess not PlayStation, you know, that's.
Scott: I think that's gonna be a good one.
Scott: The other ones that looked interesting were the Retro City rampage.
Scott: You see?
Rym: Yeah, that looked awesome Like it looked like the old Grand Theft Auto's mixed with passage.
Scott: Well, I mean, yeah, it's basically it's the original Grand Theft Auto games, right?
Scott: Not too many people have played them.
Scott: A lot of people have only played the 3d ones, but I hate the 3d ones.
Scott: I only really like the old 2d ones Especially the London one which I think not many people like or have played.
Scott: where there it's a top-down 2d game I love when I'd good voice act.
Scott: the original Grand Theft Auto was a top-down 2d game And this is basically the exact same game as that only obviously newer But it has 8-bit graphics whereas the original Grand Theft Auto games had DOS graphics it also.
Rym: what I noticed at least playing it a little bit was that the cops were smart and the AI like it felt like Those cops had a plan.
Scott: Yeah, even though the game was only 8-bit Style graphics not actual 8-bit but pixelated retro styling the game play was ultra modern Like way better than any Grand Theft Auto 2d game ever, you know.
Scott: And you can like go in all the buildings and there was stuff in there and the cops just chase you in and a corner.
Scott: It is damn good.
Scott: I'm looking forward to that.
Scott: It's gonna be we only though.
Rym: So speaking of top-down 8-bit style and games now, we're gonna get.
Rym: uh, we're gonna have an interview about this But we played this game that is basically 8-bit top-down Lupin the third mixed with Grand Theft Auto.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I it's called Monaco.
Scott: I've known about it for a while So when I saw it there, I really wanted to play it bad badly and I did.
Scott: But we're gonna interview the creator.
Scott: So I don't want to devote too much time to talking about it.
Rym: So we got to the expo hall kind of early and we played it with two other people and it was super fun But it blue-screened the first time we played it.
Scott: That's why don't we save this for the time?
Rym: we talked to the guy now But we can do.
Rym: it's the unbiased GeekNights opinion.
Rym: before we have him on to moderate our view I was gonna talk about the blue screen.
Rym: when he was on the show I tried to blue-screen it again and I couldn't.
Rym: I'm pretty sure their PC just overheated.
Rym: Yeah, probably that's what it felt like.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: next to it was a game that was incredibly popular called spy party Which I didn't get a chance to play but it was kind of like the ship but it was more from what I heard.
Scott: the way it works is this like a sniper and there's and there's a whole bunch of People and
Rym: the sniper has one bullet
Scott: and the sniper has one bullet and the other person is the spy the secret agent and they're Trying to do accomplish a mission Without giving away the fact to the sniper that they are the spy because the sniper will shoot them.
Scott: if they shoot the sniper shoots The right person then the sniper wins But the sniper shoots the wrong person or misses then or if the spy does what they're supposed to do Right, then the spy wins and it's it's.
Scott: it seems like a much better execution of Sort of the ship Concept by limiting it to such that narrow focus of the sniper.
Rym: and yes But I feel like if it does well what they could do is take that Focused like perfected game and make that a part of a larger game.
Scott: Oh, absolutely.
Scott: Like if it was a give us three things in sequence like a three-parter.
Scott: I would that be cool.
Scott: Oh if you took that sort of style of thing and mixed it with like rescue the embassy mission It basically is it a lot of it is I think now that I think about it.
Rym: Rescue the embassy mission.
Scott: Yeah rescue the embassy mission.
Scott: Why don't we?
Scott: there's a fucking egregious the unrealized potential.
Scott: Where's the new version of a?
Rym: Yeah, I would only chemco was my man.
Scott: rescue the embassy missions got to come back.
Scott: Let's just do it.
Scott: Let's just make a modern version of rescue.
Rym: So we also know this was cool.
Rym: There was a game called jam city roller girls and it is basically the real rules of roller derby Plus a little bit of Mario Tennis mixed in Mario Kart Mario any Mario sport.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I think that the the logic there.
Scott: we talked to these guys quite a bit for like five or ten minutes.
Rym: They actually is frozen code base and they actually had a real roller derby team the rat city roller girls.
Rym: They're like hanging out.
Scott: Yep, and basically we learned about roller derby recently from Luke Crane who you know and friends who are heavily involved With the Gotham City roller girls.
Rym: Yeah, Luke Crane, you know the guy who rode.
Scott: Well, the thing is I knew the roller derby was girls roller rollering guys So - I asked, you know, they rollerskate in a circle and they hit each other.
Scott: That's all I knew.
Scott: but he apparently there was a change in roller derby some years ago to where instead of using the bank track They just do it in a gym on a flat surface which makes it much more accessible and a lot more people can do it in different places.
Scott: and The rules changed.
Scott: and actually he told me the rules and just based on a pure theory.
Scott: It's way awesome.
Scott: Like because you're playing offense and defense simultaneously.
Scott: go look up the rules of roller derby and watch some of it on YouTube.
Scott: It's totally sweet.
Scott: I think I'm gonna you know, get more involved in it when I have more free time at least be a spectator.
Scott: It says something about roller derby when plus we have a team to go check out.
Scott: Yeah, we do.
Scott: It's not like we have to go figure out what team to root for But
Rym: anytime you can take a sport and turn it into a video game and the rules are awesome for a video game Independently of a sport like if you remove the athleticism and make it just about the rules of the game.
Rym: It's still a fun game.
Rym: Yeah, the game looked pretty good too when it's their first like big effort.
Scott: Yeah, apparently they had made a bunch of other games before on contracts to other people But they really wanted to make this game on their own.
Scott: So they did it and it's gonna be on the Wii as a downloadable You know WiiWare game and it's bit, you know.
Scott: They had to add something to it to make it a little bit more appealing to the rest of the world because they made it a pure simulation Which I guess they thought about doing.
Scott: it would really only appeal to people who already knew and cared about roller derby.
Scott: So they added some Mario Kart to it, you know.
Scott: So you can like put a boost to go faster and you know do like a big magical hit to freaking crush someone that kind of stuff.
Scott: But yeah, this game actually looks like it's gonna be.
Scott: at least it'll be equivalently fun to like Mario soccer.
Scott: I think you know Mario well.
Scott: Mario strikers like that level of game if that's you're looking for.
Rym: so sadly There's a ton of other stuff.
Rym: that was in the expo hall But it didn't like.
Rym: I'd either didn't play the games or I wasn't gonna stand in line to play the games.
Scott: Yeah, I mean for example portal too, right?
Scott: I mean it was there.
Scott: It was looking awesome from what I saw on one of the video screens, but you know what?
Scott: I'm not waiting in line to play a game that I'm gonna buy no matter what.
Rym: Yep, like Civ 5 I could have waited in that line forever to see but I'm I mean It's already on my computer.
Rym: if I could crack that fucking encryption.
Rym: I could play.
Scott: now one week from today is Civ 5.
Rym: By the way, yeah, their gig nights is done on that day.
Rym: The gig nights will be a 24/7 stream of me explaining my strategy as I play Civ 5.
Rym: You think we're fucking joking.
Rym: you think this is some sort of game.
Rym: even my co-workers they know me.
Rym: I was like, yes if I've comes out, you know Like it's actually gonna come out and my boss is like.
Rym: so you're gonna take like a month off.
Scott: Yeah Mom I've learned a long time ago Well a beer or two ago that taking a day off for a video game is a bad idea.
Rym: That depends on the game one.
Rym: You can't mess it up.
Rym: You don't want to take the 21st off if the game unlocks at midnight that night.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: You also don't want to take the day off for an alpha or a beta.
Scott: That's also true.
Rym: If I had taken the day off for the NS alpha.
Rym: I might have cried myself to sleep.
Scott: That's a waste of a day off I play.
Scott: so far The thing is in the history of gaming right.
Scott: there has never been a single day Where I've never actually taken a day off for a game.
Scott: There has never been a single time.
Scott: I have considered it though and every time I considered it in retrospect It would have been a bad idea.
Scott: It never would have.
Scott: I never regretted going to work.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: think about the fun, especially a single-player game like this where it's infinite.
Rym: It's not like portal where two hours and you've played it, but this if I take the day off It's not like I'm spending my entire Saturday in the apartment playing this game.
Rym: I have this day with nothing but Civ 5.
Scott: Here's the problem, right?
Scott: Problem number one You have to assume the game will actually come out in the morning.
Scott: number two If you do the no take the day after off take okay, so even if you do the next day, right?
Scott: Maybe the game will be all buggy because it's the.
Scott: it's just at the release time.
Scott: Is it really gonna work?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'll do that.
Rym: I'll just go into work.
Scott: Also, you need all your friends to take the same day off for a single-player game.
Rym: I gotta play a day's worth of Civ 5 before I start the multiplayer game.
Scott: It was a single-player game.
Scott: just bring your laptop to work and play it Probably can't play that game.
Rym: What I'll have to check my laptop.
Rym: It does okay with Civ 4 but it runs the battery out in like an hour and a half.
Rym: If you're gonna be sitting at your desk at work So plug it in and the video kind of stutters and I had to turn off a lot of the effects.
Scott: Yes, the thing is you can play it at work next to your work on your laptop your personal laptop.
Rym: Nah, I don't think my laptop can do it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I gotta try.
Scott: you can go buy a new laptop.
Scott: Yeah, I could buy a new laptop and then Play it next to your work.
Scott: My laptop's got like three more years of use though I would I would my laptop had more use too, but I bought a new one anyway.
Scott: But this one is definitely gonna last many years.
Rym: There's no doubt.
Rym: I'm holding off though I think I'm gonna get two more years out of this laptop because you know Unless it breaks now that I don't have the commute on the train anymore.
Scott: All you use it for is like presentations and stuff.
Rym: I don't even need my laptop to be small anymore.
Rym: My laptop is something I bring to like conventions for display.
Scott: Small is still better.
Scott: I would not get a big one.
Rym: I don't need a gigantic one, but I don't need like.
Rym: I don't need it to be tiny tiny tiny and weigh nothing.
Rym: In fact size matters more than weight.
Scott: now I was still would not buy a 15 inch.
Scott: 13 inches pretty much the man.
Rym: I would be willing to buy a 13 inch that weighed a fuck ton more and was more powerful.
Rym: Because now I'm not carrying it everywhere, but you wouldn't.
Scott: but sitting is if you're not carrying it everywhere You're never using that power.
Rym: because the thing is you know I use my laptop for I travel somewhere and I have a computer where I am or I'm on a plane or I'm on a boat, right?
Scott: So you in fact it'd be a better idea to just get a netbook which would be even lighter and he has not gonna place it.
Scott: Five that's true.
Scott: Yeah, but maybe by the time that this laptop is dead If six a netbook will place it.
Scott: five six six six won't be.
Rym: I I'm loving though like much like the pictures of the Duke Those pictures of George Washington and Bismarck.
Scott: I need that as my wallpaper, but I can't find it.
Scott: I could find other George Washington's and other Bismarck's.
Scott: they have a Bismarck wallpaper on the official sit by website Yep, but they don't have the George Washington and they don't have him pointing.
Scott: I looked if you're searching Google Images for like Civ 5 Washington He's there but he's not pointing.
Rym: but the the style be like art deco style like I kept walking over to the Civ 5 booth like All right, that's enough about that.
Rym: What we didn't get to see rage.
Rym: I kind of wanted to see that but we totally missed.
Scott: I totally missed it.
Scott: Yeah, it's a new game FPS from id software.
Scott: That's probably a skill based FPS.
Scott: Yeah kind of interested in that.
Scott: What other there was that firefall which I didn't even look at.
Scott: cuz I saw a big booth and I'm like firefall Whatever.
Scott: that sounds like shit and it had a big booth and whatever.
Scott: Yeah, and you know what it was actually apparently tribes.
Scott: ish.
Scott: So I'm kind of disappointed.
Scott: I didn't look at it, but it wasn't tribes.
Rym: No, I just remember when we did egregiously unrealized potential.
Rym: as soon as I said tribes to about a quarter of the audience went all tribes.
Scott: There was a game called Brink.
Scott: well I knew about brink because I saw some videos before the packs that talked about how it has an interesting thing to help noobs figure Out what to do sort of like giving them mini quests like hey go heal this guy or hey go defend this area.
Scott: Right and they would help the noobs out if they didn't know what to do.
Scott: But I went to watch it.
Scott: So we're standing there watching other people play because I wasn't about to wait in line and they basically were spending like five minutes Customizing their characters.
Scott: I was like, okay.
Scott: Fuck.
Scott: I don't want to watch this Lego universe Which is an MMO very disappointing.
Rym: Oh, here's here's what's wrong from a distance Just looking at someone else playing for more than five seconds.
Rym: It is.
Rym: it is entirely obvious why this game is completely not worth bothering with and that answer the.
Rym: the reason you're able to determine This is that the Lego characters are Lego characters and the enemies are Lego characters and there's Lego stuff around.
Rym: The ground was brown MMO dirt.
Rym: Yeah, it wasn't Lego ground Because the world is not Lego.
Rym: It is just a generic MMO where you collect Lego pieces and then build Lego shit in your sand.
Scott: It's really not really a generic MMO.
Scott: It's more of an action MMO right?
Scott: because it's basically like Lego Star Wars Lego Indiana Jones Lego Batman.
Rym: They go Harry Potter not worth play.
Scott: It's exactly that game.
Scott: You know that game you've played it, right?
Scott: It's that exact same game only Everyone in the world is playing it all at once in one spot And the only cool thing about it is that you can customize your own Lego guy your
Rym: avatar Just wait until with any
Scott: Lego piece and apparently you collect Lego pieces while by playing the game and you can take those Lego pieces back to a Private area where you can make anything you want out of Lego.
Scott: But it's like the whole game should be one shared area where anyone can make anything out of Lego and everyone has infinite Legos.
Rym: Imagine if I make my Lego clan and I build.
Rym: we build a castle out of our own fucking Lego and that is our base And people attack us and steal our Lego to make their own Lego base.
Scott: That should be the whole game.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's all they needed to do.
Scott: make one giant world where everyone can make anything out of infinity Legos anywhere.
Rym: So if you want if you think at all, I should play the Lego MMO.
Rym: No Just get like Lego Star Wars and Minecraft and World of Warcraft and between the three door fortress and war fortress.
Rym: between those four You will get everything that Lego whatever has to offer.
Scott: What other games are going there?
Rym: Nothing else really stands out in my memory to be honest.
Rym: Yeah, I did other than the games we played like the board games and stuff.
Rym: There was crazy gaming Thursday before the con like all day in the Sheraton Lobby.
Scott: Oh, the Sheraton Lobby was basically like but is where packs like it was like an extra tabletop area.
Rym: So before pack started gaming after packs ended gaming Monday, there were people gaming Sunday people gaming after the con.
Rym: I'm worried.
Rym: We want to do an after-party like a for real after party like all.
Scott: let's call the red line.
Scott: I'm telling you We don't know.
Rym: Here's the problem It's not over the holiday this year.
Rym: Are people gonna not stay all day Sunday?
Scott: No, let's just do the Thursday night to be safe as a trial Thursday night trial.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, this is critical.
Rym: We're on the show.
Rym: Now.
Rym: Are we gonna commit to something like we've committed to in the past?
Scott: No, we're not committing because we don't know how much it's gonna cost.
Scott: but okay, let's see what it would cost to get a ballroom with Rented tables and chairs rectangular tables six to eight chairs each.
Rym: I wonder if I can get the Sheraton now out from under pack.
Scott: You don't want to do that.
Scott: We don't want to interfere with packs, right?
Scott: We want to get.
Scott: let's go to one of the other.
Rym: imagine this So we get the Sheraton ballroom for Thursday and then cuz coo remember there's the problems.
Scott: I'll just take it from us.
Rym: No There was that other stupid convention that was in the way on Thursday that he couldn't get rid of if we got it and they Needed it.
Rym: We'd be like, here you go Yeah, yeah, what's that gonna do?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm looking.
Scott: I'm poking around but check the nearby hotels that are at the Sheraton.
Rym: We can talk about this off the show.
Rym: get a ballroom.
Rym: what we need to say Officially is that if it is feasible we will run a non sanctioned pre-party.
Rym: and if that works, what's a pre?
Scott: it's a pre packs tabletop event.
Scott: It's a pre PAX Prime party and we're looking for sponsors.
Scott: Anyone who wants to sponsor this?
Scott: we're looking at you RPG tabletop game companies.
Rym: more importantly if this succeeds Then I guess PAX Prime 2012. if it's back on Labor Day, then we're gonna do it after packs instead of before maybe both both.
Rym: Oh, man Why not?
Scott: why just one half just all week?
Rym: Why not just make a pack store in Seattle cuz it wouldn't be crowded all week.
Scott: It might be It'll be Thursday night and Sunday night after packs closes from like 7 p.m.
Scott: To midnight both times.
Scott: That's a good schedule All right.
Rym: So this was not obviously a review of packs.
Rym: This was a review of the games at packs.
Rym: We will soon.
Rym: I'm not going to say when we love a show.
Scott: I guess this sort of voids the the Opening part where we talked about how we were gonna talk about packs in the second half of the show.
Scott: We're gonna
Rym: talk about it in the second half of this show, which is a two-parter Though I do want to give a couple of shoutouts to Robert Greg Khalil Matt Graham Molly 23 And I'll have a reasons why I was shouting out to you and I'll shout out to more people in the next show.
Rym: But you guys rocked it for us.
Rym: Every single Aaron Z is shadow Every goddamn enforcer and everyone we played games with was awesome.
Rym: at no point Did anyone I interact with in any capacity annoy bother or offend any of my senses ever?
Rym: Yep, and I hate to say that.
Rym: I have to say that but I have to say that because other game dramatic theory and anime Conteo.
Rym: lady.
Rym: Yip.
Rym: Yeah, we're sorry.
Rym: We couldn't come to your wedding reception, but your husband Steve are omega.
Rym: not I'm sorry.
Rym: You lost in the first the random round, which is bullshit.
Rym: Zombie dice.
Scott: Oh, let's talk about zombie dice for a sec.
Rym: Zombie dice is a random odds game, but Steve Jackson is brilliant and he's going to make boatloads of money off.
Rym: he already did.
Scott: I mean the thing with zombie dice is it is a random game completely random, but it Is a lot of fun for I think gate.
Scott: This is what micro hoolick said, right?
Scott: He easily it's a lot of fun for a fucking cup full of dice and it is right is really fun.
Scott: And the thing is the first time I played nobody told me that the green dice have more brains and the yellow dice have a kind Of even and the red dice are all shotguns.
Scott: No one told me that right?
Scott: So if I would have known that I would have done much better on my first few playthroughs.
Scott: So if you play zombie dice, remember if you've got a lot of green brains out and you're right Then you want to stop rolling.
Scott: if you've got like a red and yellow brains fucking roll, baby roll and you'll get more brains.
Scott: That's how it goes.
Rym: So pecs review proper will be coming.
Rym: We'll talk about our panels the late show all that awesome stuff And another episode that you probably want to listen to.
Rym: Dude This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.