Scott: It's Monday, March 15th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Riff.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, whatever happened to programming?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: You don't know?
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So today is a day to beware.
Rym: You kept saying you had some sort of crazy thing to talk about.
Scott: I do.
Scott: And there's a reason you must beware.
Rym: Well, well, well, I point out it's no longer a secret to everyone.
Scott: No, it's not a secret to everyone.
Scott: But I don't know when, is the Ides just March 15th, or does it have some hours to it?
Scott: Like, you know, is it over at five o'clock or something like that?
Rym: I think Wikipedia can tell you that.
Scott: Oh, that's possibly true.
Scott: But anyway, the Ides are, if not now, recent.
Scott: And they are to be bewared for many reasons.
Rym: Can you name any reason other than one guy got stabbed a long time ago?
Scott: I will tell you the reason.
Rym: And it's raining.
Scott: So, on Saturday, in a precursor to the Ides, right, the clocks were marched forward, which is a double-edged sword.
Rym: So I actually had a problem this morning at work with that.
Rym: You know, we have, you know, a stock market and everything.
Rym: So we made the time change.
Rym: And we're, you know, we're not stupid.
Rym: We're not like another unnamed company I worked for that shut everything down for an hour every year because they couldn't handle the logs going back in the fall.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Rym: So we were fine.
Rym: But monitoring, you know, we have a thing that says, hey, if I don't see a log line from different things that are writing logs within, you know, a few minutes, send an error saying, hey, this thing's not logging.
Rym: They, and this is new monitoring.
Scott: Every single one of them went, oh shit, I haven't seen a log in an hour.
Rym: Yep, and then a minute later, they're like, no, everything's fine.
Rym: Never mind.
Scott: It's not that big a problem.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, you know, there was the, this, the, the prelude to the eyes in which the clock moved forward, which is good and bad.
Scott: It's good because now the sun is up at the correct time.
Scott: It's not dark right now, right?
Rym: I wish we'd just go to daylight savings time and never come back.
Scott: Let's never move the clock back.
Scott: Let's just keep it where it is forever.
Scott: That's what I would do if I was in charge.
Rym: Well, you know, they did.
Rym: And then it was undone.
Scott: We were that way.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, the, uh, but the problem with it is of course this weekend is an hour shorter.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So being an hour shorter, you need to get some more sleeps cause you lost some sleeps.
Scott: Right?
Rym: So when did you go to bed?
Scott: I went to bed pretty early last night, but then at four 30 in the morning, right?
Scott: Right.
Scott: I was awoken by a honking car horn.
Scott: Now at first, at first I thought this car horn was, you know, perhaps some hobo had bumped into a car and set the alarm off, in which case it would stop shortly, you know, but no, it was not a hobo.
Scott: So the horn honked a bit more.
Scott: And notice it wasn't honking with a pattern.
Scott: You know, it was literally a human being honking a horn, you know, at, you know, some patterns they just decided and they didn't seem to be moving anywhere.
Scott: It wasn't like they were going down the street honking, like their cucaracha horn, you know, it was someone's pretty much sitting still right nearby honking.
Scott: So eventually I look out the window to see what the fuck.
Scott: And I see this car at four 30 in the morning, pulling out of a garage, you know, one of these really tight garages with the car just barely fits.
Rym: You know, did you see that video?
Rym: The German guy?
Rym: No.
Rym: Oh, I got, I make it make a thing the day later.
Rym: It's the guy who lives.
Rym: his driveway is the narrowest thing in the world to the point that he drives in, opens his car door directly into his house, gets into the house and then rolls the car forward to close the door.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, so this van, it's like a mini van is trying to get out of this garage and there was a car parked right in front of the garage, but it's not blocking the garage straight up.
Scott: It's basically like the car is like, like six inches too far back.
Scott: So therefore the mini van can't get out.
Rym: So he's talking to make this jackass move his car so we can get out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But he's really, there's no guarantee that that jackass is anywhere within hearing range or will wake up and isn't in like a basement or drunk or who knows what.
Scott: And he, this guy's waking up the whole neighborhood at four 30.
Scott: Well, this is why guns need to be legal because I would have just sniped that guy in the mini van from my balcony to his credit at RIT more than once.
Rym: I would, you know, be ready to go to class and I'd pull out.
Rym: Remember in colony, we lived in that cul-de-sac and someone would be parked, double parked in front of my car.
Rym: I would basically just go to my car and hold down the horn and wait, but not at four 30 in the morning.
Rym: Yeah, if it had, I didn't have classes at four 30 in the morning, but had I see, here's the thing, right?
Scott: If just looking at the situation itself, the guy blocking the garage is the jackass.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: As soon as this guy starts honking, the horn is the solution.
Scott: He is now also the jackass.
Rym: However, what do you do?
Rym: What recompense can he get?
Scott: He could have just called three run one.
Scott: It's New York city.
Scott: It would have been taken care of very easily.
Rym: The dude would have taken a while.
Scott: There was a chance the dude would have gotten a ticket.
Scott: It would have done way more damage to that dude and note would have done no damage to the neighbors.
Scott: Now I know that garage.
Scott: See that guy who was parking there.
Scott: I'm probably never going to know who that was or see him again, but that garage, I know that guy now, right?
Scott: I know that minivan now because he, that guy lives there.
Scott: So now he is a hated figure in the neighborhood and I know who he is and I'm sure all the other people in my building who are looking out the rear window know who that guy is now and also the building next to that and the building next to that
Rym: to it.
Rym: What if he did not want to harm the jackass?
Rym: He simply wanted to, maybe he was in a hurry, something really important.
Rym: He had to catch a plane.
Scott: So, okay.
Scott: So in this case, so what he did?
Scott: instead of, instead of harming, he basically, I don't want to harm the jackass.
Scott: I'll just harm all the neighbors who are innocent neighbors and bring no harm to the jackass at all.
Rym: This man exercised his right to free speech.
Rym: He was basically on the street saying to anyone who wishes to care.
Scott: He actually broke the law of no honking.
Scott: There's a huge find for honking, especially at four thirty in the morning.
Rym: There's no honking zones.
Rym: You got to find out if that's no honking zone or not.
Scott: I'm sure four thirty in the morning, I, you know, police, they can come up with an excuse to charge you with anything they could have done, you know, disturbing the peace, whatever, whatever.
Rym: You're always of the mind that what if it was just free speech?
Rym: What if he was out spreading the word, the good word?
Scott: He woke me up, therefore he must die.
Scott: And the Ides of March shall be upon, I guess they were upon me, but I'll make it so that the next Ides are upon him.
Scott: Maybe I'll change his garage shut on March 15th, 2011.
Scott: Much sadder.
Scott: What's he going to do?
Rym: But also much more relevant.
Rym: You know, I built a new GeekNights computer and I passed off the previous GeekNights computer to Emily theoretically to use as a prime computer because it's a really fast computer.
Rym: Eh, USB bus dead.
Scott: How come all the computers remakes broken all the computers of Scott's?
Rym: The computer before this one still worked fine.
Rym: I threw it away because it was too old to be used for anything.
Scott: I would like you to prove that that computer would work.
Scott: I do not think so.
Scott: It
Rym: was working perfectly when I got rid of it with my faster computer
Scott: and then it sat in the hallway and
Rym: might've broke it at some point between when I took it out of the case and left it unprotected in the hallway for many, many weeks tripping over it several times.
Scott: All of my computers, no problems ever.
Scott: Zero.
Rym: The thing is I Googled around and the AB nine motherboard, which I'd picked for various reasons back in the day, I picked a shitty motherboard.
Rym: A lot of people had trouble with that motherboard.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: I never pick shit.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Back then though, when I bought it, the ratings were pretty high and all the reviews on new egg were like, yeah, it's a great motherboard and here's all the reasons.
Rym: And in fact, I got the AB nine pro because it was only like $5 more than the regular AB nine.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The thing is pro doesn't stand for professional on that motherboard.
Scott: It stands for piece of rotten rotten.
Rym: What rotten?
Rym: What?
Rym: That's right.
Rym: So I, what I'm going to do with it is I'm pretty sure that there's a voltage drop on the USB bus, right?
Rym: I actually, for the first time in forever diagnosed a hardware problem.
Rym: So what I'm going to do is either, if I can't fix that problem, it's like a problem in the motherboard.
Rym: I'm going to turn it into the file server because that thing has 10 status.
Rym: I can make it basically a raid and make it the file server for like videos and everything over the files.
Rym: But it might be that the power supply that is feeding the USB bus, cause you know, there's different rails and everything, different voltages.
Rym: that power supply is a piece of shit that I bought at a store, no name brand to replace the other one that was incompatible with the motherboard in the first place.
Rym: It's possible.
Rym: the power supply is the fault and not the motherboard.
Scott: You know, I don't have these incompatibility problems.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well I bought an AVID AB nine and that was my mistake.
Rym: I should have bought an ACEs with an Intel chip set.
Scott: Like I did.
Rym: You know, my new computer is ACEs.
Scott: Does that AB nine have a, uh, an enforce or something?
Rym: Uh, actually I don't remember or what?
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: It has an ICH8R, right?
Scott: Which is Intel.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: However, my new motherboard has the ICH10R.
Scott: I don't know what my computer, my computer, my, the HTPC I just built has the H55, which is very apparently the new hotness.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Sadly, you know, I was teaching Emily a bunch of stuff about why I built this computer cause she actually just ordered effectively the same computer I have now.
Rym: It's about $300 cheaper than it was before.
Rym: And she doesn't need a video card cause my old video card is fine.
Rym: The 7,900 will play half life too.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Rym: But, uh, you know, the, I was trying to explain like the differences, you know, Northbridge, Southbridge and SAC, CAS latency and everything.
Rym: And I realized that about 80% of that stuff is completely irrelevant to anyone making a computer nowadays.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Pretty much like one weird thing though.
Scott: I do want to point out though, uh, my computer, this on my desk, right?
Scott: Which has DR 800 memory, four gigs dual channel, right?
Scott: In the windows, like, you know, the windows performance score thingy, it gets a pretty high score for memories, you know, my new computer, which has four gigs dual channel of DDR, like 1066 memory, right?
Scott: With a, with a, with a, uh, um, I three, right?
Scott: Uh, the memory score in windows is way lower and it's like, why?
Scott: It's also a dual channel.
Scott: It's supposed to be faster.
Scott: What's that?
Rym: Triple channel.
Scott: No, not triple.
Rym: I got triple channel.
Scott: I didn't, this is a home theater PC.
Scott: It wasn't a, uh, you know, set the house on fire PC until some future crazy Matroska.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I just thought it was really weird.
Scott: I'm like, huh?
Scott: And I'm like, I'm sure I could manipulate cause the motherboard is all those overclocking settings, which I just don't touch at all because I don't want to, you know, I'm no interest and I don't want to, I'd rather have a computer that works in as quiet than is 1% faster, but I'm sure I could modify some memory timings to, to fix that situation.
Scott: But who cares?
Scott: The computer works.
Scott: I don't need the faster memory.
Scott: It works.
Scott: So all right.
Rym: So you got any news for me?
Rym: I do have some news that windows phone seven series, I got to admit, it's real high on my list of maybe when I buy my next phone, I might go that route.
Scott: I know.
Scott: It's like you never would have thought you would go for the windows phone seven series and it came out and it looked like I expected it to look, you know, it looks like, you know, all the new Microsoft stuff looks, but they just had big announcements about it today, including the current, the MX at mix 10, which is a Microsoft event, right?
Scott: The one thing it's got right now, you know, that they've showed, that's like no other phones got, that's like, holy shit is fucking Netflix.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: That's a holy shit right there.
Scott: Iphone don't have no Netflix.
Rym: Just Netflix streaming.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You can, you apparently you'll be able to watch streaming Netflix on your windows phone seven series.
Scott: That's that is Android.
Scott: Don't got that.
Scott: Iphone, Iphone has like Netflix app that lets you like, you know, mott fiddle with your queue.
Scott: Free doesn't have that right now.
Scott: And it's like, whoa, windows.
Scott: That is fricking strong.
Scott: Cause it has silver light on it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's why they were able to do this.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Because Netflix uses the silver light DRM.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it uses some other DRM when you're not using windows, but well, it doesn't work on Linux.
Rym: Well,
Scott: you can, I think you can install silver light on Mac actually, but, but yeah, it's like, you know, there, there are some Netflix streaming things that don't have silver light, but silver light is their default with the DRMs and such, but it's, uh, you know, Microsoft also, you know, they brought out this, uh, dev platform.
Scott: You can get today, you know, to start making apps for it and it's free.
Scott: So I'm going to try it out.
Scott: I tried out the Android one too.
Rym: I tried out the pre one and I was, it was easy to make apps, but I just have no desire to make an app because I realized the pre is basically being delegated all the way down to like the low end default crappy smartphone OS.
Rym: I think.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's, it's, it's like all the built in stuff on the pre works and is great, but that's all it does.
Scott: You know, it's like, it's like they made a bunch of stuff.
Scott: That's like the core functionality of a smartphone.
Scott: They polished it up real nice, but then they didn't give you any additional functionalities like say Netflix streaming.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean, it's really sad too because I can't do basic stuff like iPhone and everything.
Rym: There's a Scott trade app.
Rym: Like all this stuff I use, there are apps that just would do it for me.
Rym: And on the pre there's nothing like no reputable company has any app worth a damn.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And half the free apps have ads in them.
Scott: There's this whole iPhone apps also have ads.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, this is not a thing that is unique to the Palm, but I'm talking about like the, even like the free apps that basically do nothing.
Rym: Like it's just a stopwatch.
Rym: You can pay five bucks for the stopwatch or it's free, but it has ads in it and it doesn't even work.
Scott: You know, I'm really like, I can't figure out like why they failed because it's like they had a great, the smartphone did a lot of stuff that no one else still is not doing right.
Scott: The I amming, you know, unified the email unified.
Scott: They're doing a lot of stuff that is just better.
Scott: The UI is pretty great.
Rym: You think the Google phone would have the Android universal search, but no, the pre, if you just start typing, it is the smartest thing in the world and figuring out what you want to do with whatever you're typing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, all the phones have that, but the pre, I think I'm talking about the things that pre has, that no one else has, but nobody video.
Rym: I got to find if someone basically had a screen of like three smartphones and he types the same characters into each one, one by one and shows you how they're all reacting in real time.
Rym: The pre it reacts faster and picks better.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It also the camera is so fast compared to the other phones and they added video support to the camera that works just great.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well the iPhone three GS has video.
Rym: No, I'm saying the pre didn't until just recently.
Rym: That was like.
Rym: one of the biggest problems with the pre is that you couldn't record video and then one day a random update appeared and it added it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But it's like they have all this stuff, but it just like, I think it's just marketing or something that just, they can't get people on it.
Rym: You know, the other thing that bothers me is that the pre, I think at least the Palm pre that I'm using now has the best physical design of all the existing smartphones.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: The nexus one is pretty hot.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I like the fact that the pre has this tiny form factor.
Rym: It's really an itty bitty little phone.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's also, you know, the, but the, the pre does have the keyboard, which the other people do not have.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It is the keyboard that I like.
Rym: the fact that it's a vertical keyboard and not a horizontal.
Scott: It's probably the best one with a physical keyboard.
Scott: I would say that.
Rym: Yeah, you're right.
Rym: I should clarify.
Scott: If you have a physical keyboard, it's like if you want a physical keyboard, that's the best one.
Scott: You know?
Scott: But the thing is, I think the problem is even though it has a physical keyboard, right?
Scott: It seems to me like the people who want a physical keyboard, right, are, you know, there's, there is people who they like write hold big emails on their thing.
Scott: In which case that keyboard doesn't really good for that, you know?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I mean like what I do, my typical use is responding to basically GeekNights, PR crap.
Rym: Like I have to respond to people pretty quickly.
Rym: So I send fairly long emails from it on a regular basis.
Scott: The thing that really bothers me is not so much whether the, you know, I thought I really wanted a physical keyboard, but the thing is I never type anything really long.
Scott: The thing that bothers me the most is simply an unresponsive keyboard.
Scott: You know, it's like I want, I want, you know, on a phone, it's, why don't people program that, you know, every computer that has a user interface should be programmed in the following way.
Scott: The following way is user input takes precedence over all other processing.
Scott: If you're, my computer is encoding a video and decoding a video and playing a 3d game and I move the mouse, all of those processes should be paused.
Scott: Zero instructions executed.
Scott: If I need the CPU power to move the mouse arrow around the screen because the CPU is 100%.
Scott: if I start typing something in a box in a web browser, right?
Scott: In a text box and all like a hundred I'm computing like pie out to the billions digit and the CPU is locked up.
Scott: It should just stop completely.
Scott: Stop figuring out the next digit of pie.
Scott: Give no instructions to that.
Scott: No CPU cycles to that process whatsoever.
Scott: If that makes it so that my typing in the box is 100% responsive and all phones, all desktop user interfaces, every desktop user application should be programmed in this way.
Scott: User input always comes first, whatever I'm doing and everything else takes a backseat.
Scott: Zero priority.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: Minus a thousand.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And this is how phones need to be.
Scott: Even the iPhone.
Scott: Oh, it's so beautiful.
Scott: Oh, it's so perfect.
Scott: I go to like NOAA.gov and I try to type in my zip code to check the weather and I push one and I have to wait like two seconds before it actually enters the one into the text box because it's busy processing some JavaScript on NOAA.gov.
Scott: Pause the JavaScript.
Scott: Just zero.
Scott: No, I don't care.
Scott: I am typing here.
Scott: Typing comes first.
Scott: Everything else comes last.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Pro, you know, there is no reason that computers can't be this way.
Scott: What?
Scott: No one does it.
Scott: Right?
Scott: I mean the Linux kernel added the preemptible kernel option, but even so still sometimes you're not preempting when you should be preempting.
Scott: So fucking get it right.
Scott: If you could actually make a user interface always number one priority, I wouldn't care about a software keyboard.
Rym: So here's something really interesting that the PRI did.
Rym: They had an update, you know, recently the one that added the camera functionality and there was a note in the bottom about some weird UI update and I read into it a little bit.
Rym: Apparently people had complained that web OS was unresponsive and they made changes.
Rym: But as far as I can tell, they didn't actually in any way make it respond faster.
Rym: All they did was make it appear to respond faster.
Rym: Like they made icons load immediately even before like the frame inside of it loaded.
Rym: So it felt like it was a lot more responsive, but it didn't actually speed it up or anything as far as I can tell.
Rym: And that seems to have allayed all the complaints.
Rym: I think the best philosophy for this sort of thing is that if you can't actually get the OS to respond to something, cause you might have a legitimate situation where you can't respond to user input or you can't make like icons load as fast as you should.
Scott: As far as I'm concerned, if that happens, then that's a bug, you know, but that's just me.
Rym: But what you should do is at least fake it.
Rym: Actually, we have a projector at work though.
Rym: This confuses people often where before when you plug it into a computer, it shows a windows desktop on the display immediately based on the last windows desktop that it had displayed.
Rym: So it looks like it's there right away.
Rym: Of course, if you actually try to move something, you realize it's just a screenshot and we, we basically have a game of how long does it take for the vendor to figure this out.
Scott: Oh, the people coming to sell you stuff.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I had a couple of meetings with them today.
Rym: That's why I wore the black blazer as opposed to my gray blazer.
Scott: Because you have to look good for someone to sell you stuff.
Scott: You're not selling, you're being sold too.
Scott: You should dress like a schmuck.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Come on.
Scott: What do you got?
Scott: You were selling, then you dress up nice.
Scott: Like please buy my thing, please.
Rym: Here's some strategy.
Rym: So, you know, three of us go to this meeting, I dress up like this and I don't talk.
Rym: I just sit there and watch everyone else grill the sales guy.
Rym: And I just sit there looking kind of very disapproving with a clipboard and I'm writing out, I was just doodling.
Rym: And then I asked like one question at the end and the guy was basically scared shitless of me as far as I could tell.
Rym: So you got to play these things out.
Rym: And basically my question was, so how much does this actually cost?
Scott: So there's someone's, you always pick one person in the meeting whose job is to act for the price, act like the person who's actually making the decision who does not want whatever it is.
Scott: And then ask for the prices and everyone else has all the other non price questions or ask like the serious question like, so what do you mean?
Rym: this doesn't support sending S and MP traps?
Rym: It's a monitoring suite.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So I don't want to talk about all the whole history of this, but as you all know, there's been this long stupid history of the EU and the antitrust side of lawsuits with Microsoft.
Rym: And they came to the conclusion that, how are we going to get Microsoft?
Rym: We're going to force them to either not include IE, which is a stupid idea in windows or to include some various list of competitors to IE in windows.
Rym: And I think this is like the biggest example I've ever seen in technological history of completely missing the forest for the trees of completely saying, here's a problem.
Rym: The, you know, the Microsoft monopoly, we were going to solve it by picking the stupidest possible aspect of the problem and then having the stupidest possible solution to that problem, thereby solving everything.
Scott: So yeah.
Rym: All right, Microsoft, you have to put all the competitors, web browsers in your OS or, Oh, you shouldn't include a web browser.
Rym: So say Microsoft did the, all right, fine.
Rym: No web browser.
Rym: How are these people going to download Firefox?
Scott: Well, they gave you this.
Scott: That's the thing they did.
Scott: is when you turn the computer on, it makes you choose a web browser that it will then install.
Rym: So Microsoft in their infinite wisdom decided, and I think this is brilliant.
Rym: All right, we're just going to pick the top seven web browsers in the EU based on some dubious metrics, whatever they are, you got to pick one of them.
Rym: And the story here is that there are some weird freaking browsers.
Rym: There's no, no one's heard of in here.
Rym: And as far as I can tell, they're all basically either I E with a different interface or Firefox with a different interface.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, the thing is when you, when you load up this, you know, European windows seven, right, it lets you choose between, you know, Firefox, I E Chrome opera and Safari, right?
Scott: It says here, pick one.
Scott: And they're in a different order each time.
Scott: But the randomness of that is actually, it was supposed to be random, but whoever coded it did it wrong.
Scott: It's like Chrome is more likely to appear in the somethings.
Scott: I forget.
Scott: There's an article about it, but you can click more browsers and it'll give you like seven more choices of weird browsers that almost no one uses.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Like green browser, which I'm going to quote this article from pcpro.uk.
Rym: green browser is your best choice of flexible and powerful green web browser.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Meaning essentially internet explorer bash with an ugly stick.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And I don't know.
Scott: pretty much all the browsers that are in the, you know, more browsers section are either Firefox or internet explore that are sort of mashed up.
Scott: Like flock is a, is a is basically Firefox that's modified to have like all sorts of flicker and blogging integrated stuff.
Scott: It's basically Firefox with a bunch of extension.
Rym: Or a little bit of Polish schlepner gets the bonus points for good name.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But all it really is.
Rym: Oh, here's, here's the relevant quote from the article.
Rym: It's no racehorse.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think there's another one that has, it lets you switch between Firefox and IE schlepner.
Scott: It comes with like the, you know, IE tab extension pretty much integrated into it.
Rym: And it's like, how stupid is the EU?
Rym: You know, all this fighting about Microsoft and their monopoly and whatever, and they decide to force them to install competitors product.
Rym: What if you sell a Ford car and they're like, well, let's say Ford made tires.
Rym: Well you have to give people the option of having Mazda tires and those tires.
Scott: It should be more like if Ford made tires and they said, no, you have to let people choose between Goodyear and Bridgestone and something, something.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But our radio, say Ford makes their, you know, the default radio that they contract out, whatever.
Rym: And that's just in the car.
Rym: You know, buy a Ford car, you get the Ford radio.
Rym: And if they said, Oh no, that's anti competition.
Rym: You have to include these eight other radios, half of which either don't work or don't fit in the computer in the, in the car in the first place.
Rym: It's just, this is the sad conclusion of this whole Epic story.
Rym: And it's such a whimper, but I just, I foresee crazy problems going forward as people use these other weird web browsers and have, you know, there's going to be some sort of breach of IE and it's going to turn out that it's not a breach of IE.
Rym: It's a breach of one of these crappy web browsers that, I don't know, one third of people picked because it happened to be at the top when they pick web browsers.
Scott: Well, another thing is in order to, I think almost no one is going to pick one of those crappy ones because you have to click like, show me more to see any of those.
Scott: Most people are going to click IE, Chrome, Firefox, Safari, or opera.
Scott: Cause those are the only ones that show up in your face and you're just going to pick one of them and you're not going to click on the tiny thing that says, show me more that then going to show you the crappy ones.
Rym: I feel like the real solution.
Scott: So I think it'd be like less than one fraction of 1% uses something else.
Rym: The real solution was to let Microsoft include IE and not bother with the browser war at all and focus on some other, more fundamental aspect of this whole antitrust thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: How about, you know, focus on some Apple antitrust like, Hey, how come, you know, you can't sync your iPod with anything but iTunes?
Scott: and Hey, how come iTunes won't sync with anything but an iPod and doesn't have a commanding market share of computers?
Scott: They do with, I'm talking about iPods here.
Scott: I'm not talking about the computer Mac.
Scott: Did I mention the Mac?
Scott: I mentioned the iPod.
Rym: This was to address the fact that Microsoft has the majority of the computer market for consumers.
Scott: Oh, you know how you could fix that force, uh, force companies that make software for windows only to make it for every cross platform.
Rym: So, all right, this is the problem.
Rym: The EU also has very little power.
Rym: Microsoft basically in addressing these EU complaints was saying, all right, we'll play by your silly.
Scott: Yeah, do whatever we don't care.
Scott: Just go away.
Scott: We'll do whatever silly thing you want.
Rym: And really the EU, they screwed up and that they let Microsoft get away.
Rym: They didn't actually get Microsoft.
Rym: I don't believe Microsoft should have been gotten in the first place.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But all they did was force Microsoft to play by some arbitrary rule.
Rym: That's not going to affect anyone majorly in the long run.
Rym: And Microsoft said, all right, fine.
Rym: We did your stupid thing.
Rym: Are we done now?
Scott: It's pretty much just a stupid, you know, Europe versus us thing.
Scott: Basically Europe is finding that, you know, any us companies, right, that are so big and international that they need to do bit that they have a lot of business in Europe that the EU can basically extract money from the U S by regulating these U S corporations.
Scott: that happened to do a lot of business in Europe.
Rym: Look at how many times like say Germany is a big offender of this because they'll always try to hit some American companies saying, Hey, you showed some Nazi stuff that's against our law.
Rym: And luckily most American companies say, okay, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Germany,
Scott: you know, like if they, you know, they didn't like Nintendo, you know, they could, uh, you know, go after, you know, Nintendo of Europe or whatever, even though it's a Japanese company, you know, it's like, you know, if the, if the U S was upset, they could do the same thing to Japan, you know, via, you know, Toyota or any other sort of, you know, Japanese company that's operating in the U S. So it's basically just a way to disturb the economies and pester other countries by pestering companies that happen to do international business.
Scott: So whatever.
Rym: It's just this whole situation really just, it's nothing more than nothing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day, stuff like this does not happen nearly as often as it showed anymore.
Rym: And I th this has such an anonymous slash 4chan slash V vibe to it, especially if you look at this video or you look at these screenshots.
Rym: So I don't know how many of you are familiar with the max headroom broadcast signal intrusion incident of 1987 max headroom.
Rym: Are you familiar with max headroom?
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Are you?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Are you really?
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Anyway, so max headroom interrupted television in Chicago, Illinois, like real broadcast television on November 22nd, 1987.
Rym: So I'm just going to read from this Wikipedia article.
Rym: that basically sums the whole thing up.
Rym: This is like the bad-ass kind of futurism cyberpunk, you know, intercepting the broadcast and sending your own messages out.
Rym: But it's so random and 4chan-y and weird that I don't know, it's surreal.
Rym: It's surreal and cool in a way that very few pranks have ever managed to be.
Rym: So the first occurrence of the signal intrusion took place during a WGN TV channel.
Rym: nine live telecast of some prime time news show.
Rym: So the news shows on and then suddenly quote the station.
Rym: signal was interrupted for about half a minute by a video of a person wearing a max headroom mask standing in front of a swing sheet of corrugated metal, which imitated imitated the background effect in max headroom.
Rym: There was no audio, just a buzzing noise.
Rym: The hijack was stopped after 30 seconds or so when an engineer at WGN changed the modulation of their studio link to the John Hancock center transmitter blocking this interception transmission.
Rym: So think about that.
Rym: In the eighties, someone managed somehow to override real broadcast TV with his own broadcast TV.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: So later that night at 1115 PM, this is where it gets interesting during doctor who it was on TV.
Rym: The signal was hijacked using the same video that was broadcast during the WGN hijack, but this time with distorted audio, the person in the max headroom mask appeared as before, and this time he was saying that does it.
Rym: He's a freaking nerd for laughing and jeering.
Rym: Yeah, I think I'm better than Chuck Swirsky, freaking liberal.
Rym: He goes on to do strange things while periodically saying strange things like catch the way while holding a Pepsi can and he just gets more and more and more bizarre from there.
Rym: Some other person appears and this kind of happened and stopped and to this day no one has ever solved how they did it, who it was, why they did it, what they're trying to accomplish.
Rym: And the person, no one ever claimed credit for it as far as I can tell.
Rym: And that's the end of it.
Scott: You want to, you want to, do you know about the Heidi game?
Rym: The Heidi game?
Rym: Yeah, not.
Scott: So in the year of, let me read the Wikipedia.
Scott: I forget what year it was.
Scott: 1968 there was a football game between the New York Jets and the Oakland Raiders.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And this game was like, this was like a huge game, right?
Scott: Like gigantic, you know, the Raiders were the AFL champions in the previous year, right?
Scott: These teams both had seven and two records going into this game and the game was back and forth.
Scott: It was a competitive, great football game.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And seven o'clock came around and at seven o'clock there was a movie Heidi sponsored by Timex that was supposed to go on at seven o'clock, but it was still like the third quarter of this crazy game.
Scott: So they had instructions to switch to Heidi at seven o'clock, no matter what.
Rym: Ooh, I remember as a kid being mad, every time the Simpsons was supposed to start, but stupid football.
Scott: And now the thing is people started calling in as it got close to seven.
Scott: Some people were saying, are you going to cut the game off?
Scott: Is the game going to keep going?
Scott: And some people were calling in to say, is Heidi going to go on?
Scott: Right?
Scott: The network was trying to call the stations to tell them to not put Heidi on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: To change the instruction, but they couldn't get through.
Scott: And Heidi went on and it was the famous Heidi game.
Scott: And you can get the rest of the chat, the details on the Wikipedia's and such, but this is a famous, famous television interruption.
Scott: When Heidi went on in the middle of the football game and barely anyone saw the rest of the football game,
Rym: but that was not a guy in a max headroom mask
Scott: breaking
Rym: into real TV,
Scott: but it was incredibly, you know, when Heidi went on the phone calls went, Holy shit.
Scott: And it's the reason that they realized football was popular because Nielsen ratings, that's just bullshit.
Scott: Right?
Scott: But the Heidi game by putting Heidi in the middle of the football, they were like, Oh shit, the football is popular.
Scott: That's when they realized.
Scott: So anyway, my thing of the day, we've been singing Trilla, a little bit today, a little bit.
Scott: Do you know Rick Astley?
Rym: I may have heard of him.
Scott: Rick Astley.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Some guy, right?
Scott: And you know, he's kind of cool because when everyone started, Rick rolling, he never gave up.
Scott: He, he knew that Rick rolling was, was awesome.
Scott: He got it.
Scott: He was in on it.
Scott: He knew what was up.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: You know, he went along with it.
Rym: I have a feeling if you approached him and said, I would like to pay your appearance fee simply to Rick roll someone, he would say, all right, he's a gladly.
Scott: I'd be more than happy to.
Scott: Well, mr.
Scott: Tralala law, Edward Kiel is alive and well.
Rym: So does he speak English?
Scott: No.
Rym: Cause I would say if there was, somehow if he like lived in America now or for whatever reason, I would be willing to pay to bring him to packs and put him up during the Q and a and Tralala.
Scott: But anyway, here are, there are many videos and many interviews with him on the internet.
Scott: And I will link you to the specific one of him watching a bunch of other people trouble allowing on YouTube.
Scott: That's my fan while people are photographing him and talking to him and even trouble lows a little bit.
Scott: And he says, he says a bunch of stuff.
Scott: Like he's, Oh, that guy's got the good.
Scott: Oh, that guy's good at singing.
Scott: You know, all the guys get a yellow tie just like me.
Rym: One of my biggest fantasies has always been to see historical people watching internet memes about them like George Washington watching Washington.
Scott: But anyway, this guy when, you know, towards the end, he says something that's pretty fantastic.
Scott: He's like, I don't consider this parody.
Scott: He's like look at the joy that these people are having.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And now I know the Edward Kiel and Rick Astley are of the same.
Rym: I caught him in the same cloth.
Scott: We need, we need them to do a partnership.
Rym: Someone who has money.
Rym: Make that hat.
Scott: We need both of these talented vocalists to have some sort of duet situation of trullo law.
Scott: Never give you up something, something, never going to troll low, low, never going to something along these lines needs to occur.
Scott: Perhaps even something as simple as taking the two videos and copying and pasting them together, right?
Scott: If not bringing the two men together in a physical space.
Rym: Now this gives me two ideas for packs because you know, packs, unlike most cons we go to has that, uh, come up to the microphone and it's, I mean, it's nominally a Q and a, well there's two microphones.
Scott: We could get in the same position in both lines and one person go up to the microphone and troll law and the person goes to the other microphone.
Scott: and you know, Rick roll at the same time.
Rym: We could just time it and come up with some sort of bit where two people get to the microphone at the front at the same time and then do a bit.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: But one thing to do is dress up as troll a low and either have a little speaker that'll play troll a low or be able to sing and actually troll a low.
Rym: The other thing is find out what it would take to get Rick Astley to come to the con with us and get him in line and perform perhaps the most epic Rick rolling that has ever been done.
Scott: He could wear like a, like a V mask, right?
Scott: So as soon as he gets up to the front, start singing and then take the V mask off mid singing.
Rym: Think about it.
Rym: He starts singing and people like, Oh, it's just a stupid Rick roll.
Rym: You asshole.
Rym: But then it's really Rick.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Oh man.
Scott: Or it's the thing is I think he lives in the UK though.
Scott: Yeah, you got to pay him.
Scott: We had to get him to come to Boston.
Scott: This can be a lot of monies.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Maybe, maybe impacts west.
Scott: That's gonna be more money.
Rym: So you got to really set it up.
Rym: So you get two guys, right?
Rym: You'd combine the two ideas.
Rym: One guy is two people.
Scott: Where does he live?
Rym: Right.
Rym: So it's me in a V mask and Rick Astley in a V mass.
Rym: We get up to the microphones at the same time.
Rym: I Rick roll in the V mass.
Rym: People go boo.
Rym: I rip off the V mass.
Rym: People continue to boo.
Rym: He starts Rick rolling.
Rym: They go, ah, ha ha.
Rym: They coordinated it, but then they start to boo.
Rym: He rips off the V a mask.
Rym: It's really Rick.
Scott: That's a little complicated.
Rym: It is, but imagine the payout.
Rym: I'd be willing to put forth a secret.
Rym: If we took, the problem is if we took donations to try to do it, everyone would see it coming.
Scott: Oh, that is a problem.
Scott: Anyway, here's awesome videos.
Scott: And there's many linked YouTube videos.
Scott: If you go to the related videos section, you can see this, uh, Edward Kiel, Trello low man being very cool.
Scott: He is an awesome dude.
Rym: That's, that's pretty Epic.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So meta.
Scott: Oh man, we got met as we got conventions.
Rym: So this weekend is the last weekend where we are not going to be at a convention.
Scott: The convention after that will be PAX East in Boston the weekend after this weekend.
Scott: In other words, the weekend of March 19th to the 20th, nothing happening.
Rym: The weekend of March 26, 27, 28 PAX East and the arcade expo East coast in the, uh, Heinz convention center in Baltimore, Baltimore, Boston.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We may be live streaming as myself, but we're doing, we're going to try, we're doing 3.25 panels at PAX.
Rym: Most of them are on Friday.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: Uh, we're going to coordinate something, some sort of meetup, some sort of event where I don't know, we'll figure something out.
Scott: So in April two, three, four, the next weekend in the same, same bad place, same, well, almost the same bad time, same bad channel, anime Boston, where we are doing four panels.
Rym: We're doing five panels.
Scott: Oh fuck.
Scott: We're doing, I believe anime.
Rym: You should see, okay.
Rym: Bite-size anime, anime openers from around the world.
Rym: And I'll point out guys, I'm going to spoil a tiny bit of that panel.
Rym: I have the Gundam wing opener in German.
Rym: I have the Gundam wing opener.
Scott: People are just going to get it on YouTube themselves.
Rym: They won't need to come to the convention, but most people aren't going to know about this.
Rym: They're not going to listen to this.
Rym: We're going to get like random people at anime Boston.
Rym: Never heard of us.
Rym: That's come to this panel.
Rym: I hope so.
Rym: Gundam wing opener in Arabic from Saudi Arabia.
Rym: But then here's the gold.
Rym: So in Saudi Arabia, they have an English channel and an Arabic channel.
Rym: It was so popular that they then decided to put Gundam wing on the Arabic channel.
Rym: They took the Arabic opener to Gundam wing that they had made and translated that into English.
Scott: Oh snap.
Rym: Oh man.
Rym: And that's just the tip of the iceberg.
Rym: That's not even dangerous.
Rym: So we're also doing the secret guide to running an anime club, AKA the panel.
Rym: we've done more times than any panel ever.
Rym: And I think we're doing, this isn't confirmed the how to run a panel panel as our throwaway panel.
Rym: What?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Where did this panel come from?
Rym: I put it in there.
Rym: Cause remember we have to do a minimum number of panels to get paid.
Scott: So why are we doing how to run a panel?
Scott: We could do, we have better panels than that.
Scott: Why don't we do like a comics for the manga reader or something?
Rym: Cause I, I put that one in, but they didn't want it.
Rym: Also that panel, we got to step it up.
Rym: The panel is kind of lackluster.
Scott: No, but I mean, it's better than freaking, uh, uh, how to run a panel.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But what's going to come to how to run a panel?
Rym: What panel will have more impact?
Rym: Uh, Harris.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Remember we could just Rick roll that panel.
Scott: So the weekend after that, right, March 10th and 11th, I'm pretty sure, let me just double check it.
Scott: Is the mocha arts festival in New York city.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: 10th and 11th in the same building.
Scott: it was in last year.
Scott: It's gonna be a million degrees now.
Scott: Even if it won't be a million degrees because it's April, maybe that's why they move into comics.
Rym: I mean, this is ostensibly a comic convention.
Rym: It is awesome.
Rym: There is no human who would not enjoy themselves at the mocha.
Rym: If you're in New York city and you're a Linux nerd, you should be at the mocha.
Rym: You'll be pleasantly surprised.
Scott: You only need to come one day.
Scott: You know, you walk in, you look around, you check out awesome arts and comics and things and you go home and maybe go out to dinner in the city.
Scott: It's a nice day.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We'll be there.
Rym: You might be able to go out to dinner with us.
Rym: Uh, if you're not, if you can find us and we don't blow you off.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you know, you'll probably see us walking around at the very least.
Scott: I mean, I'll probably go there just Saturday.
Scott: I don't think I'll go Sunday also, but you know, it's an awesome time.
Scott: The mocha, you should go.
Scott: It's the win.
Rym: I believe the weekend after that, we have not confirmed whether or not we'll be there yet is nexus, which is a big rationalist thought atheist convention in the city.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I haven't really planned much for that yet, but I'll note it because there's a decent chance we'll be there doing something.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: And the final meta, at least for now, there is more metas coming later.
Scott: Oh no, there's a book club is Carl Sagan's cosmos, the book, not the TV series.
Scott: And we are experimenting with streaming still.
Scott: We're going to try to do streaming at conventions and we're streaming GeekNights is and streaming some other things, but we are currently experimenting with Justin TV and it seems to be working better than you stream.
Scott: So make sure to follow GeekNights on Twitter to be alerted to any streaming events.
Scott: And I'm going to try to like download all our recorded streams and put them some, you know, and work that all out.
Rym: So once I build that a server I was talking about, we're going to host video just straight up for streaming in addition to, you know, YouTube and whatever.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So keep your eyes on front recruit.com's news section and uh, you know, the Twitter slash twitter.com/geeknights and such and such.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean, don't expect, you know, we're, we're streaming this show, but it's basically just GeekNights.
Rym: We're not doing anything special.
Rym: It's mostly for us.
Rym: It's not for you if you enjoy it.
Rym: Great.
Scott: But this isn't, yeah, we're streaming GeekNights just to practice our streaming, but we are going to do other non GeekNights shows that are video shows specifically that are different.
Scott: So watch out for those.
Rym: So, uh, I believe you can introduce this because you're the one who brought this up when we were doing our, uh, our test screen test morning show the other day.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: So there was this article I read and the article was, is called whatever happened to programming.
Scott: And I read this article and I was like, good God, do I agree with this guy?
Scott: This guy is like speaking, you know, it's when you, someone says something and you're like, oh my God, you are so like speaking to me totally.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: You know, like a, like a valley girl.
Scott: We'll talk about like a pop star boy band or a hippie.
Scott: We'll talk about the dead or something like that.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So this guy was talking like that.
Scott: I was like, ah, he's so right.
Scott: And what this guy was talking about was how he learned to program, right?
Scott: When he was 14, he would write, let's see, I'll quote him exactly.
Scott: I'm not going to read his whole article, but he says when he was 14, he wrote space invaders in basic on a Vic 20.
Scott: He wrote a mud in sea on a terminal attached to a sun three, when he was 22, he wrote, uh, the guts of a text database system still in sea now on a sun three 80.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, this is the kind of coding that he was doing and the kind of coding that I learned to do right when I was a kid and also even in college was the same sort of stuff, right?
Scott: It's you, you have these basic constructs of software programming, you know, if while variables, right?
Scott: Functions, you know, for loops, right?
Scott: These sort of basic constructs, depending on what language you're using and at what level you are, you know, if you're an assembly, you don't have those, you don't have those functions.
Scott: You have, you know, jump and, and, you know, move memory and these sorts of things, you know, and addition and subtraction.
Scott: But programming was all about, you know, you have to, you have to build this piece of software and you have, you have these basic components to work with and you had to create an algorithm mixing, you know, these simple constructs together to build a more complicated thing.
Scott: You know, the complex emergent behavior of a, you know, a system that is just a bunch of simple things arranged in a complex way.
Scott: And that is what programming is all about.
Scott: And that is why programming is fun.
Scott: It's like, aha, I need to write a hangman game.
Scott: And all I've got is variables and loops.
Scott: You know, how do I do this?
Scott: And you solve this problem using these tools, right?
Scott: But nowadays at work, you know, the job that I have and most jobs that programmers have and most programming that is done is no longer this, right?
Scott: Most people who program are not doing this behavior that I was taught to do.
Scott: And most people were taught to do in, in college, right?
Scott: Or wherever they learn programming.
Scott: All people are doing now is they're taking libraries or frameworks and gluing them together, right?
Scott: For example, I recently, wrote a small script that would go to Google docs, right?
Scott: Get all, figure out what documents I had, right?
Scott: Download any documents that were up there in a, in a, you know, PDF format or whatever, or doc format or whatever.
Scott: And then save those documents to Amazon S3, right?
Scott: So normally, right, if I was going to program this and say C from scratch, how would I do this?
Scott: Well, I need to make a TCP connection to Google and that I would need to figure out their protocol and I would have to send over to construct a packet and send it over and such, right?
Scott: And I had to do all these, these little things.
Scott: And I had to, you know, with, with just the basic tool set, I'd have to construct all this stuff, but nowadays is the library.
Scott: So what I do in Python, I say, import G data, which is the Google data API.
Scott: Then I import Bato, which or S3, which is the Amazon S3 API, right?
Scott: And I say, G data dot, get list of documents.
Scott: Then I get this list of documents in memory.
Scott: And then I just have to manipulate it a little bit to change the format of it.
Scott: You know, maybe it's strings and, you know, I need to just change the shape of whatever that spits out and then need to take that new shape so that, you know, let's say Google data spits out a square, but Amazon S3 is a circle.
Scott: I just need to round off the square.
Scott: And then I say Amazon dot S3 put data, the square, the circle that I've now circled.
Scott: And then it's done.
Rym: Think about your work.
Rym: You're, you're a programmer.
Rym: You know all about programming, like the basics of it, like, you know, bubble sort and all that kind of stuff.
Rym: But, and then I, you know, even the code I write now is basically the same thing.
Rym: I spend the vast majority of my time coding in the design part first, which I like, you know, designing like, what do I want to accomplish?
Rym: What's my flow?
Rym: But then implementing it is 99% looking up the syntax of libraries.
Rym: Like what object does this take?
Rym: What does it output?
Rym: What's the name of the method I have to call?
Rym: What do I have to give this method?
Rym: It's there's at no point in my, like maybe 1% of the code I write is the part I care about doing the thing I want it to do.
Rym: But 99% of the rest of what I write is just the glue between the pieces.
Scott: Well, now see here, the, here are the problems with this, right?
Scott: Well, here's the good parts, right?
Scott: If you want to do something complicated, right?
Scott: Like, let's say, you know, copy all your Google docs to Amazon or something, right?
Scott: It's actually pretty easy for a normal person to read the documentation and sort of figure out how to do it, even if you're not so good at programming, you know, because you can just read and read and read and read documentation until there's an answer.
Scott: And they say, Oh, use this line and that'll spit this out and then use this line to send it over.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So it gives normal people who actually dare to venture into the areas of writing code, you know, in Python or Ruby or something like that, vast powers to do advanced functionality that is not available in other software.
Scott: So that is a good thing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And no one's going to argue that it's kind of like when we talk about, you know, changes in video games over the years or how eight bit 16 bit, we're never going to say you should go back to the crappy technology because it happened to make a few things better.
Scott: Now here are the problems with this, right?
Scott: Problem number one is that a lot of these libraries that you're, you know, importing to get these advanced functions from actually kind of suck ass.
Scott: So what happens is, you know, everyone out there who wants to do X, right, uses this library because it's the one, right, that's out there.
Scott: And it has all the functions.
Scott: But if it sucks, now everyone using it is writing shitty software and nobody's making library itself any better.
Scott: Cause no, basically anything that happens in the library, even if it's open source, almost no one actually looks at the source of it.
Scott: No one's investigating how it works.
Scott: They're only concerned with their own code and as long as no bugs in the underlying code.
Rym: I mean, my, my interaction with the Python SNMP frame or the SNMP like stuff is basically just, well, how do I make it work in my program?
Rym: I've never even looked at what it actually is doing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And if it had a bug in it, right, what would you do?
Rym: I would code around the bug in my code.
Rym: I'd be like, all right, if I try to send a trap out through it, it sends the trap wrong cause it doesn't spoof the ID right or something.
Rym: So I'll send it a fake ID and I'll make a wrapper around the library to send it this, the data it'll need.
Rym: So I know that then the output of it will be correct.
Scott: You might report the bug right on the, to the open source project.
Scott: If it is open source, right?
Scott: I mean the G data API, I don't know how it's, I think it's kind of open source.
Scott: I don't know exactly how open source it is.
Scott: You know, I don't see why it would be closed.
Scott: Google does open source a lot of things, but you know, there are some things that aren't open source.
Scott: So in that case it is a black box, but you know, very few people actually patch or will go and look at the code of anything, you know, to figure out what's going on underneath.
Rym: I think there's a far more subtle danger here.
Rym: And I run into this a lot and it, a lot of times programming tasks seem very daunting.
Rym: and imagine a non programmer and you're trying to show them some code or they're looking at some code, like not teaching code, but real working code.
Rym: It is 100% incomprehensible, even though most programming languages, like the structure of them is inherently readable, you know, make this variable, put something in this variable, do something with it, call this function, go here, you know, all this basic stuff.
Rym: But when your code basically is, use this function in this library.
Rym: Now take the output from that and use it in this library.
Rym: Now use this library.
Rym: It's all basically the wizard using magic words to make things happen.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's pretty much like it's just magic words.
Scott: You're not solving a problem.
Scott: You're not coming up with an algorithm.
Scott: You're basically looking up in, you know, a spell book.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: What spells are available, right?
Scott: And one spell is upload to this and one spell is download from that.
Scott: And all these spells are already in these libraries, right?
Scott: These spell books.
Scott: It's like, all right, figure out which spells to cast in which order and how to get the, you know, the rabbit that's created by the first spell to go into the hat that, you know, the second spell needs.
Rym: So I want to turn this rabbit into a gold for some reason.
Rym: I want to make a gold rabbit.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Or so, all right.
Rym: I don't have say the only spells I ever polymorph other, but it doesn't let me turn it into a mineral.
Rym: It only lets me turn it in another animal, but I have some other spell.
Rym: that's like turn person into stone and then I have some other thing.
Rym: that's all right.
Rym: Turn stone into gold.
Rym: So I take these three spells and make this really clunky framework that turns the rabbit into gold.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Whereas if you were writing and say assembler, you probably could have in very few lines, turn the rabbit into gold and it would be if you did, if you're a quality programmer, it would have been a much more quality solution.
Scott: And the thing is, this isn't just libraries either, right?
Scott: For example, let's say I want to make a website, right?
Scott: Now most websites out there don't really need to be high performance.
Scott: Super awesome, right?
Scott: You know, a blog, whatever.
Scott: But let's say you use Apache, the web server, you know, you put up some HTML files, the server serves them out.
Scott: Very nice.
Scott: But let's say you need to do something advanced, right?
Scott: Like let's say Twitter, right?
Scott: Instead of say, you could write Twitter in, you know, you could, there are Twitter clones in every language now, you know, and you could use like mod Python on Apache, right?
Scott: You could also just write Twitter as a standalone application.
Scott: You know, it would open up port 80.
Scott: It would accept incoming connections on port 80, right?
Scott: You don't have Apache in the picture, you know, get all that stuff out of the way.
Scott: I am writing a single program.
Scott: I could write it in freaking C or anything I wanted.
Scott: It opens up port 80.
Scott: It acts as a web server.
Scott: It reads HTTP, you know, headers coming in.
Scott: It figures out what to do.
Scott: And if I did do this, the performance of, you know, and the benefits of doing it well and the ability to scale and the ability to control every aspect of the program would be so vastly superior.
Scott: You know, I've heard things like mebo.com are written in C plus plus, you know, people are doing things like this, you know, it is not unheard of, but fewer and fewer people are doing things like this now.
Scott: One of the other negative effects of this that I see is that I think people are going to forget how to do this.
Rym: Well, no, I think you end up having two different kinds of coders.
Rym: I mean, people who are just practical coders, you know, working with real life code only who didn't study code independently of the real world applications who just have to get stuff done will be very proficient at knowing the names of all the modules and libraries and how to link them all together to be the glue.
Rym: But they can't actually address anything complex if the libraries don't already do it.
Scott: But I think that fewer and fewer people will, there'll be less and less people who know how to modify or write a library, you know, and then there'll be even fewer people who do it well.
Scott: So many libraries out there just suck.
Rym: Well, the people, I think a university education or, you know, any sort of like theoretical education in coding will give you that.
Rym: I think it makes it a more subtle problem is that it makes it very difficult for people who want to learn how to code to get into it.
Rym: because the old adage, and I used to agree with this a lot was, all right, if you want to learn how to code, the quickest way is to code something you need that works because you'll be motivated to finish it.
Rym: But if you just code something that'll do what you need it to do, you're just going to take libraries and bang them together.
Rym: But if you learn how to code in a very simple, like that basic thing that we were talking about the other day, if you learn how to code something in basic, you're going to learn all the basic logic concepts of what coding means as opposed to the practical glue crap.
Rym: Of course, in the end, the practical reality is that gluing different pieces of data together is 99% of what the world needs for everything.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, that's, you know, that's the other thing.
Scott: It's like, I'm sitting at my job, right?
Scott: And it's like, I have the skills to write a library, you know, depending on the library, of course, I probably couldn't write libraries for certain things, but for other things I could do a pretty good job.
Scott: And for other things I could do a great job, but I never do.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Well, because at work, no one's ever going to pay me to sit around and do that.
Scott: when I could just reuse something and get the job done faster and save more, you know, there's no money reason to do it.
Scott: So fewer and fewer people are going to pay anyone to write libraries and basically shitty libraries will dominate and software will get shittier and shittier.
Scott: And I think actually if software didn't get shittier and people actually were writing their code better that we could get a lot more out of the hardware that we've got, you know?
Scott: Uh, and right now I think that actually software might be getting shittier at a sort of, you know, dangerous rate to where like our hardware is, you know, we're not, we're really starting to lose, you know, it's like, you need to get that faster CPU only because the software is crappy.
Rym: I am somewhat hesitant to say that to go down that road.
Scott: It's not for, I'm not saying for like normal people, but you'll notice it and say large, uh, applications and scaling big things, you know, like people are out there and what they're doing to scale things like Facebook and such, you know, is, you know, my website is too many visitors.
Scott: So what do I do?
Scott: Well, I'll just have more web servers and a load balancer and I'll get more database servers and more, right.
Scott: And men cashed and all this stuff.
Rym: But at the same time, be careful because so many people make the slippery slope argument of, we should just write everything in assembler because that is the way to get, you know, we're some fast hardware made us lazy.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Sometimes you should though.
Scott: And I think the thing is.
Scott: the thing is people are doing it zero times and they're the cases where they should write it in assembler, they're not.
Scott: or the case of they should write it and see they're not.
Scott: Well, look at how Java does it with the Justin time compilation and like the way Java, a lot of those LLVM J I T things are going to help us out a whole lot.
Rym: But it's the idea that, you know, in an average program, you write 98% of the program uses like 1% of the resources.
Rym: You've got one tiny piece of your program that is the resource intensive part.
Rym: And it's usually orders of magnitude more intensive than everything else.
Rym: Cause that's where the work is done.
Rym: You know, that's like the loop.
Rym: In my case that scrapes the billion, well not billions, the tens of millions of log lines per second.
Rym: And you know, does something with them like that part of the program is 99% of the performance.
Rym: That's the case where you hire someone or you let someone write an assembler program that does that perfectly.
Rym: And then you have people like me do the glue around that library.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Well, I mean, you look like in Python, you can see, cause.
Scott: in Python and many other high level languages, you can write like a part in C, you know, a lot of people write a game and then put the really intensive part.
Scott: They'll write in C and import that as, you know, the library will be C. Like SciPy is a science library for Python, but SciPy itself is written in C, you know, so SciPy is really fast and kind of awesome.
Scott: And then you can just write easy Python code to use it, you know, and if people would do those things more often, even when they don't have to, right, we could get a lot more performance and a lot better things.
Scott: Now, the major problem that I have personally, and is why this guy, you know, with his article was speaking to me so much is that I hate writing this glue code.
Scott: It is not what I learned to do.
Scott: It's not why I like programming.
Scott: It's boring and sort of painful.
Scott: All I do every day is I have to look stuff up, right?
Scott: I look up the magic words and then I type them in.
Scott: I look up the magic words and I type them in.
Scott: I'm not solving problems, which is what I like doing.
Scott: It's not fun.
Scott: It doesn't satisfy my, you know, it's not why I like coding.
Rym: I'm speccing out a huge program at work right now.
Rym: Like I'm, I'm speccing out the stuff that we're then going to write and we're going to outsource to some people, you know, some of the writing of it and modules and everything and speccing it out.
Rym: When I finally had time to do it, you know, I sat down for three hours, like how am I going to architect the software?
Rym: That was super fun.
Rym: Like that was the most fun I've had at work in a long time.
Rym: And then it was like, all right, how, how are we going to actually code this?
Rym: And then it was just looking up libraries, looking up the capabilities of them.
Rym: Actually writing the code is going to be horrifyingly tedious because no part of what we're doing is novel.
Rym: No part.
Rym: What's novel is that no one has glued together all these individually solved problems together in a way that works before.
Scott: Now, you know, sometimes, you know, of course gluing, you know, creates many awesome things.
Scott: Look how many people have done some awesome stuff just by gluing Google maps to whatever or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, and that's it's so easy.
Scott: That's why so many people are able to do it.
Rym: Well, it's also the most important part of information technology right now.
Rym: today is taking data sets that are not connected and somehow connecting them to accomplish some third goal.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: And it is wonderful, except for the fact that it is really the actual act of doing it.
Scott: You know, coming up with the idea to do it is solving a problem.
Scott: How do I do this?
Scott: How do I, you know, make podcasting better?
Scott: Oh, well, you do this and this and this and this and this and this.
Scott: Well, think about a manual labor of actually creating that solution is horrendously painful and tedious and slow.
Scott: And this is why so many people just say, fuck it and install WordPress rather than writing a blog or, you know, fuck it and using Ruby on rails instead of, you know, this is the same reason it sucks to be a DBA.
Rym: And like at RIT, they tried to trick people into joining the database concentration and everyone took the first database database class and said, you know what?
Rym: Fuck this.
Rym: Because the fun part is I've got two data sets.
Rym: I want to mash them together and do X and here's my process and here's, I want to accomplish it.
Rym: The not fun part is select X from table outer join blah.
Scott: The thing is actually SQL is kind of fun for me, especially, you know, not just normal everyday mundane SQL, but sometimes it's like you have some data arrangements and tables and it's like, I need to get this complicated query, you know, I need to figure out how many of these per those on Mondays, you know, something like that.
Scott: And that, you know, SQL can be fun in that way, you know, and there's actually, that's sort of the problem is you look at things like, you know, there's a lot of ORMs out there and object relational mapper.
Scott: If anyone doesn't know what that is, Django and Ruby on rails have these as many other things do.
Scott: Basically you can interact with a database without writing any SQL like Django, you know, which I use and it's, you know, what the front recruit.com runs on and that's what I use at work is, you know, it's a Python web framework and basically if you don't want to, you almost never have to actually write SQL, but it's talking to an SQL database, but you don't write any SQL, you do something like, you know, episode, you know, if I'm doing GeekNights, right, I would do episodes dot objects, dot filter, uh, you know, category equals Monday.
Scott: And that would give me a list of all the Monday episodes behind the scenes.
Scott: It's generating, you know, select from episodes, underscore episode, you know, where category equals, right.
Scott: So it's generating SQL, you know, and it's on the front end.
Scott: I'm just dealing with objects and this is really easy.
Scott: The thing is, the SQL it generates is shit.
Scott: I can get just about any page on our site.
Scott: I can get all the data with one query, one clever query.
Scott: Most of the time it's making like 10 queries because it's just stupid.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the only benefit of using an ORM is that it makes things easier for the developer to glue.
Scott: It has no other benefit whatsoever.
Scott: And it has this severe detriment of making really stupid SQL.
Rym: So what if someone made better glue?
Rym: What if that wrapper was not technologically possible as a problem?
Scott: No, because objects don't match to relational databases and object model and a relational model are not correlative.
Scott: You can't do it.
Scott: You know, if you were going to use one of those no SQL databases, right?
Scott: Like let's say CouchDB or Cassandra, which are becoming very popular, then you could have an object, which of course, as long as it's a object, you know, can correspond to the schema-lessness.
Scott: if you're using a schema-less one, right.
Scott: You could, you know, have an object that maps, right.
Scott: And it works, would work a lot better.
Scott: The problem is, is that these no SQL databases are non-relational by nature.
Scott: That's sort of the point, you know, they sacrifice the relational features in favor of, you know, different abilities to scale and clone and have a bunch of servers really easily and such, you know, easier partitioning and things like that.
Scott: The thing is they're non-relational.
Scott: So what do I do if I want to say code Facebook where Rym is a friend of Scott and I have these relations?
Scott: Well, basically what you end up doing is instead of doing joins on the database side, you end up coding the actual logic of a join in your program.
Scott: And now the server itself is doing the joining as opposed to the database server doing the joining.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's going to be a lot less efficient than, you know, make a database of objects compared to Postgres, which is really good at fricking joining.
Scott: compared to your Python code that's going to join.
Scott: Give me a break.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So at the same time, the your Python code is easier for 99% of people to deal with than Postgres.
Rym: I mean, I have trouble even installing Postgres and I use it as a professional on a daily basis.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, it's, you know, it's just really, I want to write, you know, the kind of code that is, you know, the kind of code I learned, you know, take these simple constructs, loops, variables, you know, functions, et cetera, right?
Scott: Even classes.
Scott: And, you know, build up, write the algorithms, you know, make them better, make them fast.
Rym: You know what you're saying?
Rym: You're saying I'll paraphrase.
Rym: I should have stayed in college and gone into academia and gotten my doctorate in coding.
Scott: Not really.
Scott: I mean, there are jobs out there you can get where you're still writing low level code.
Rym: You know, you could have gotten a job like that with my company.
Scott: Uh, no, not really.
Scott: Yeah, no.
Scott: The guy needs to get a job, say like not writing, like an Android app, but writing Android itself, you know, like, you know, writing drivers for mobile handset,
Rym: but you're just gluing the software and hardware together by calling the hardware, you know, effectively API
Scott: sort of, but sort of not, you know, you, you basically,
Rym: I think the point I'm making here is just
Scott: the thing is the hardware API
Rym: hard different.
Rym: There's a long sliding scale.
Rym: And I think there are two factors here, two almost completely separate scales that right now, at least for what we do happen to correlate very strongly.
Rym: on one side, there's the, is this fun for me scale, which happens to correlate to, is this just coding around libraries and gluing things together?
Rym: And if we could somehow, I don't know if it's possible, break the two sliders so that it's fun to glue, which you know, what an example of that is.
Rym: Well, if everyone doubler and a very simple way, you, you made it really fun to glue things together.
Rym: Of course, you sacrificed every other aspect of gluing things together to do it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: The thing is, right.
Scott: It's like when you glue things together, you have to do that little bit of work in between the, in between the two things you're gluing, right?
Scott: To make the match, to get the square peg and the square hole.
Scott: And when you're working, say, to combine Google maps, that combining work is usually really boring and stupid.
Scott: You know, Oh, I have to remove the space from the end of the string.
Scott: Oh, I have to parse this XML to get the name of something, right?
Scott: It's just really stupid shit.
Scott: If you're doing something on a lower level, right?
Scott: That in between work of gluing, say a GPU to a game or something like that, right?
Scott: That in between square peg, you know, turn the square peg into a circle peg.
Scott: So if it's in a circle, whole work is actually far more interesting work.
Rym: Well, I think in that case, it's a lot more complicated.
Scott: There's actually problems to solve rather than just things to do.
Scott: You know, you have to figure out, Oh shit, you know, this GPU only does this and this, you know, so I need to figure out something.
Scott: There's actually a problem to solve as opposed to just, you know, uh, a magic word to figure out in some documentation.
Rym: Well, you could go back to what you were doing before when you were working on, you know, like embedded stuff, batteries, things like that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But I have to go figure out how to work on that again.
Scott: It's been so long, right?
Scott: That my skills in that area are depleted.
Scott: I need to rebuild them.
Scott: But yeah, in general, it's just, this is the way the programming is going.
Scott: And I wonder, you know, it could be, there's going to be goods and there's going to be bads.
Scott: And I hope that, uh, we can, you know, figure something out.
Rym: I think good in the long run, but not for, I think from third factors and just the advance of technology, making things act differently.
Rym: I think the really important part of this is not the technology because the wrappers will eventually be really good.
Rym: The problem is going to be the fun part because it'll never be more fun for people like you to write code, no matter how good the glue gets.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I think that's why you look at like, what was that game with the, uh, the alchemy game?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The alchemy game, the codex of alchemical engineering is basically just doing the fun part of coding.
Rym: I mean, I enjoyed that game.
Scott: Basically.
Scott: That's the epitome of what the fun part of coding is.
Rym: Is that the epitome of a good game too?
Rym: Because look, it was simple enough.
Rym: You could brute force it.
Rym: It was a game that anyone could play.
Rym: And yet it rewarded mastery.
Rym: If mastery was your goal, yeah.
Scott: So that's, you know, that's the kind of code I like writing, but nowadays is pretty much like, imagine if you basically, it's like playing the codex of alchemical engineering with cheating pieces, you know, like, like, but they don't work just quite right.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But it's all, it's basically if you had that plus cheating pieces, well, the game becomes sort of boring.
Scott: It's like, oh, I just take this cheating piece and I win this level up.
Scott: Here's the piece that beats level two.
Scott: Oh, I need to beat level three.
Scott: There's 10 level three.
Rym: You'll have five pieces and they're all black boxes.
Rym: And you put something in one side and do something to it and stuff comes out.
Scott: No, you go on Google and you say, which piece beats level three?
Scott: and someone says, oh, piece number four beats level three.
Rym: But then someone else says, yeah, it only beats level three at first, but if you let it keep running, it randomly spits out salt.
Rym: I just keep spitting out salt.
Scott: That's cause it's something bad in that black box that you'll never look inside something bad in method.
Scott: I think what I would just think anyone out there who was coding, you know, at the high level of gluing libraries together, my message to you is to just look when you're using something, let's say, you know, you're, you're writing something in, uh, you know, I guess, you know, try to use open source stuff.
Scott: First of all, that way you can look at code.
Scott: And then when you do use an open source library, let's say you use pie game to make a game, or let's say you use Ruby on rails to make a website, or let's say you use, you know, uh, Apache, right.
Scott: To make a web, you know, something, go look at the code of the thing you're using, cause that will help you a get a better understanding of what your program is really doing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Look at the code of Ruby on rails.
Scott: Look at the code of pie game, you know?
Scott: Uh, and then when you need to, don't be afraid to modify that underlying code because you know what?
Scott: That underlying code is written by schmucks just like us.
Scott: They're not some geniuses who are better than we are.
Scott: They're just other coders who decided to actually write something underneath.
Scott: You know, if you have maybe like some of them are geniuses, some of them are, but even so, the code is probably, you know, it's there.
Scott: You can read it.
Rym: The thing is geniuses, the code's probably really understandable.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And even then even geniuses, the code isn't perfect.
Scott: You know, it has gotta be something wrong with it.
Scott: Or you can, even if there's nothing wrong with it, you can probably, there's probably ways that you can modify that underlying code for your specific use case to make it a lot more useful to you.
Scott: And in which case, do it because, you know, as opposed to writing a huge, you might as a write a huge block of code on your side and the outside of the black box.
Scott: You could just write like one line inside the black box.
Scott: that does everything.
Scott: So why would you, you know, just cause you're afraid to look inside, you've written way more code than you need to.
Scott: Don't do that.
Rym: Let's just return device.urandom add that to everything.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So look inside the black boxes when they're open source, fool around with them, learn how, you know, and then you'll be able to write your own libraries and maybe you'll write the next thing that everyone uses.
Scott: That's like Ruby on rails.
Scott: That'll be, you know, as opposed to just being the next user of Ruby on rails.
Rym: I just think the key is to focus on the enjoyment part because if coders want to enjoy this one type of programming, as long as they know that it is like, it exists and they can still do it despite the glue.
Rym: and the glue will still get done because that's where all the money is.
Rym: The money's in the glue, the fun is in the rest.
Rym: And as long as coders like to code, the rest is going to get done.
Scott: Now the thing is the money isn't actually in the glue, right?
Scott: Well, I guess it depends.
Rym: If you want to make between, you know, 60 and 110 if you want a job, right?
Scott: If you are a gluer, you will probably get a job, right?
Scott: That pays money like me and Rym, right?
Scott: However, if you want to make a product that you can sell, you want to make the piece that is being glued.
Scott: Google makes pieces to glue, right?
Scott: Django and Ruby on rails are pieces that you glue and those people who make these things are making mad bank, right?
Scott: You know, through having consulting businesses or selling the product straight up or selling services associated with the product, right?
Scott: So, you know, there is money in making the pieces to be glued, right?
Scott: And there, you know, Twitter is a piece to be glued.
Scott: Think about it that Facebook is a piece to be glued, not the glue itself.
Scott: And there is jobs, you know, if you want to work for someone else in being a gluer.
Scott: So there's money all around, but a lot more people make money being gluers than making, you know, popsicle sticks.
Rym: There's no more demand for it.
Rym: I mean, I guess when I say that's where the money is, is that 99% of what businesses need and what the economy, what everyone needs is two things that aren't glued together to get glued together.
Rym: So that's always going to be where the money is.
Rym: Cause someone's always going to say, I want my sales force to connect to my blah.
Rym: And then someone's gonna have to write some JMX adapter to or JDBC thing to like get the data, massage it and stick it in the other thing.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And a lot of these things will get more and more custom as people, you know, internal, like I got to connect my particular sales force.
Rym: That's these weird fields to this particular ticketing system that has these particular fields.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And that'll never be fun to do for anyone.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: I think that's good enough.
Scott: That was good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Scott: And I purposefully didn't put chase Gordon in this meta moment.
Scott: I was going to do him in the Wednesday, Wednesday.
Rym: I noticed something strange just because the people pointed it out in this, you stream, you basically close your eyes while you're doing the show.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: What am I looking at?
Rym: I don't know, but it just, it kind of, it looks funny cause your eyes are just closed.
Rym: You're kind of just like looking down like I'm doing GeekNights now.
Rym: I'm nodding and I'm acting like I'm talking to someone, but as a closed, yeah, I'm not looking at anything.
Scott: If I was on video, I keep the eyes open.
Scott: Well, you know, I think I kept my eyes open when we did the show the other day.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, you know, see what you should do is close your eyes during a panel.
Rym: Cause it's really unnerving.
Scott: Why would I do that?
Scott: Imagine that if I, yeah, I don't close my eyes during a panel.
Scott: Maybe if we did a whole panel, I don't think I've ever closed my eyes during a panel.
Rym: And we did close our eyes.
Scott: Cause I always look at the back wall or I look at people in the audience or hot girls in the audience or whatever.
Rym: What if we did that?
Rym: We just, you know, we know what our slides are.
Rym: We haven't memorized.
Rym: If we just kept our eyes closed for the whole panel, we'd fall off the stage.
Scott: You go, oops, trip over the wire.
Scott: That'd be great.
Scott: No, you can fall off if you want.