Rym: It's Tuesday February 23rd.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Why are there no popular griefing games?
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know I was playing Bioshock way back when I bought it And I was also playing fallout 3 and I never finished either game.
Scott: I You know it's just something.
Scott: those games.
Scott: I beat them both, and I bought them both, but you know looking back I should have waited until they were way cheaper than yep.
Scott: well I realized now the other like they're the kind of games where I play.
Scott: I just rush through and Well, I realize the full.
Rym: the fullness of playing a game like that is unless it's multiplayer.
Rym: You'd might as well just wait and buy it like exactly one generation back.
Rym: So if I Bioshock one now that Bioshock 2 is out by fallout 4 Right after fallout 5 comes out and the main reason is my old computer.
Rym: You know all performance stuff aside.
Rym: You know you always say I need more FPA.
Rym: I don't need as nearly as many FPS as I say I do but regardless Fallout 3 was stuttery as crap on that old computer.
Rym: So I played through a bunch of it, and it was just kind of like ugly.
Rym: I had to turn a lot of the settings down Playing it now on this computer like everything's turned all the way up And it looks great and the games a thousand times more fun, but still not that fun.
Scott: I'm sorry Yeah, none of the neither one of those games really fully excited me because I think the big thing that bothered me about Bioshock Right is that you basically you're going through you're doing all right.
Scott: It's a little bit of system shock eNOS, but not so much.
Scott: And I you know wish it had co-op because system shock 2 was only good with the co-op yeah But it didn't.
Rym: well well well to be fair system shock 2 and games like that filled this.
Rym: I don't know like need I had in gaming when I was younger that I no longer had.
Scott: I played system shock 2 recently.
Scott: I'd never played it when I was young and it was.
Rym: it was pretty great with co-op Yeah, but even by yourself the whole like leveling up and skill trees.
Rym: I cared about that stuff a lot more 10 years ago.
Scott: Well the thing is it's like a. you know I I don't really care about leveling up in the skill trees, but it's sort of.
Scott: you know It's.
Scott: it's when it's a when it's not a grinding situation it can.
Scott: it's still kind of fun You know especially because it's that same thing you having like a shmup right and a shmup There's no not really grinding because you're always dodging and shooting and you're constantly using your skills.
Scott: But it is fun like when you finally get like six power-ups and the gun Spreads more and now it's just like.
Scott: so it gets really hard it gets really hard And then you're able to you get an upgrade and you can hose the enemies down Yeah, and then it's it's like it gets easier and easier But then they just up the difficulty.
Scott: so now you need to get another upgrade and it's this constant.
Scott: You know it's like some games like say Mario 1 Super Mario Brothers Or it just gets harder and harder and harder and harder and harder and harder harder, and then you win Yeah,
Rym: but when you give you like an expanded
Scott: skill set then there are games where there is there is grinding right?
Scott: And the grinding is just sort of like well It's it never really harder or easier.
Scott: you just keep playing and playing and doing the same exact thing over and over But in a game that has proper upgrades It's harder and harder and harder And it comes back a little bit easier But not as easy as it was the beginning and then harder and harder and harder and a little bit easier.
Scott: and these like moments Of relief and then building difficulty.
Scott: you know it makes it.
Scott: it makes the climb to the higher difficulties much more Tolerable and it also gives you these sort of fun moments of We.
Scott: because like if you just open up say desktop tower defense right as an example And you just choose like sandbox mode where it gives you infinity dollars.
Scott: It's completely boring as all fuck.
Scott: Just like I'll build the most powerful tower a billion times and that all the bad guys just die instantly.
Scott: and who to do?
Rym: But didn't you do that exact same thing when you used to play Civ 2?
Rym: You put yourself on a giant continent full of perfect land resources And you put every single enemy civilization on a one square island in the middle of the ocean.
Scott: This is when I was younger and not as smart.
Rym: What changed?
Scott: That got boring real fast.
Rym: well think what if?
Scott: but let's say you're playing desktop tower defense right and it's like.
Scott: you know you You play and play and play and it's hard But then you get like a level or two or a couple waves where you've got extra money And it's sort of like we.
Scott: I can upgrade a whole bunch and the guys just getting hosed now Yeah, and then it gets hard again.
Scott: You know it's like kentro.
Scott: He doesn't fight row every single time He's got a fight.
Scott: You know normal schmucks and then fight a hard guy and then normal schmucks you.
Rym: one other thing and like Fallout does this pretty well and castle crashers actually did it really well in the beginning where you unlock kind of?
Rym: Advanced functionality like you start unlocking combos and different moves as you you know quote-unquote level up.
Rym: so you're given like a basic skill set like imagine a mario game where you start and you can only do all the basic mario 1 Stuff and then halfway through it's like you figure out how to do the wall jump you figure out how to do the ground pound.
Rym: So it builds upon a skill set, but it introduces them one by one.
Scott: That's I kind of wish right.
Scott: that street fighter would do that where you know you start the game a street fighter And it's like okay You can punch and you can kick and that's it if you made it
Rym: Like some sort of novel game where you have you have Phoenix Wright style But then you fight instead of having courtroom and then as you level up like the fights are just normal fights right
Scott: in that Case leveling isn't really a grind what it is.
Scott: It's a. it's a slowly.
Scott: It's more.
Scott: It's a tutorial.
Scott: You're slowly inter giving the player more abilities so that they can learn to use them one at a time.
Scott: And that's actually.
Scott: I've been playing a few action games lately.
Scott: I played there's no more heroes game and there's been.
Scott: I played a demo of this Bayonetta game.
Rym: I got to play Bayonetta.
Rym: everyone says it's great, and I haven't played it yet.
Scott: It's just walk around and hit things It's not.
Scott: I don't know why.
Rym: people I don't know people people I trust have been I don't know.
Scott: I played the demo.
Scott: it was walk around and press a and bad guys die is no different than you know.
Scott: Brutal legend exactly.
Scott: it's the same exact thing.
Scott: walk around and hit bad guys.
Rym: You know brutal legend at least everyone said that later on and had this cool RTS mechanic.
Rym: But are all those hitting guys the whole game all those same people same is.
Scott: um What's the game with the guy with the guns?
Rym: Devil may cry Same shit now devil may cry way as far as I was concerned was the game of jump in the air and then fall down In slow motion while you shoot guys, that's Bayonetta.
Rym: I did that for my Nettie.
Scott: you jump in the air and fall down in slow motion and shoot guys.
Rym: I did that for like three hours, and then I didn't care about.
Rym: the rest of devil may cry.
Scott: well They know the same thing.
Scott: anyway the point is in these games right especially like no more heroes for example.
Scott: Right this is tutorial.
Scott: at the beginning of the game the tutorial teaches you every single move that you have right away.
Scott: Okay, so it's like you learn.
Scott: It's like okay first.
Scott: Here's how to hit a guy.
Scott: okay now He's here has that charge up and hit a guy.
Scott: it just teaches you them all one after the other immediately And then it says okay now play the game.
Rym: It's like no no no no no no no no think about it.
Rym: Though who does that cater to imagine?
Rym: you like imagine FPS?
Rym: We're good at FPS.
Rym: if I play a new FPS once I know the controls I can do all the crazy stuff unless the game does something really you know.
Rym: weird.
Scott: no They got to give you.
Scott: if it's a single-player FPS They give you one weapon at a time like here's the pistol.
Scott: learn how to use the secondary?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: what is the crowbar?
Scott: what is the grab?
Rym: there was an FPS where they were like all right?
Rym: You can you can only turn and walk and shoot.
Rym: you cannot strafe yet, and then later.
Rym: They're like all right.
Rym: You've gotten good enough.
Rym: We're gonna teach you.
Rym: move in you straight.
Rym: Well.
Scott: That's you know.
Scott: That's basics.
Rym: It's the same thing no.
Scott: It's not cuz same.
Scott: no It's not.
Scott: there's basics, and then there's everything.
Scott: you have to teach all the basics at the beginning But you don't teach everything.
Scott: not.
Scott: there's basic moves that are fundamental to playing and then there are moves that are not Fundamental to playing that are advanced moves right.
Scott: so in half-life you need to teach moving which includes strafing aiming I'm not saying half.
Rym: imagine some other kind of FPF.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: maybe it's an FPS where you're piloting a robot, and you just don't have the strafe capability yet Because the rate is a basic capability.
Scott: It would be okay.
Scott: If you don't have the double jump capability It's not an absolute basic capability.
Scott: strafe is a basic capability.
Rym: You're saying that you have no like.
Scott: objective stance on a basic capability means It's fundamental to the game.
Scott: your you know movement period is a basic.
Scott: Imagine.
Rym: you're good already good at these.
Rym: walk around beat-em-up kill guys by pressing a kinds of games.
Rym: So if you play a new one Do you really want to start where you've only got three moves?
Rym: you got to go through all this BS with these three moves Before they give you like all the crazy combo.
Scott: to go through all this BS You just have to.
Scott: the scheduling of when the moves are you know granted to you and taught to you has to be spread Out proper like you know.
Scott: you know it doesn't mean that you're gonna have to beat ten levels before you can get the strafe Right.
Scott: it could you just give it to them.
Rym: You know you're just.
Rym: I mean It's.
Rym: it's the same thing just on a different scale.
Rym: for someone who's really into games like this already This game is aimed more at them.
Rym: if it gives you all this stuff right off the bat I mean someone who's never played a walk around hit people game before is gonna be overwhelmed.
Rym: They're like what?
Rym: what's all this tutorial and all these million things?
Rym: don't remember all of them.
Rym: If you care about this kind of game, they give you everything you care about and then you go nuts with it.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: It's prop.
Scott: notice how the best games right the games on your eyes the games that are the most popular and Consistently the highest rated and most enjoyable are games like Farmville.
Scott: No That's not getting good reviews in the game right, but even Farmville right.
Scott: Farmville does this where it teaches you things one by one.
Scott: It's like here's plowing all right.
Scott: Here's harvesting.
Scott: okay now Here's how to use the.
Scott: you know.
Scott: there they constantly build up the number of things that you can do.
Scott: They don't just start you with everything they build you up Right.
Scott: they teach you more and more things as you go on.
Scott: harvest moon even does that.
Scott: but it's like okay.
Rym: player game a game Or you will be competing with other players.
Rym: Do you want to have to go through all that just to play against other people?
Scott: well if it's a multiplayer?
Scott: This is why the best multiplayer games are ones that have single-player games attached to them.
Scott: even tribes 2 has a Single-player game in which you may learn the things that you need to know to play tribes.
Rym: to remember when that died you can.
Rym: it's very specific.
Scott: counter-strike had half-life in which you could learn to play.
Scott: count.
Rym: but think back it was when quake 3 came out and they Were like look we made quake 3 But we didn't bother with the single-player because no one cares still was a single-player.
Scott: So you could learn to play quake, but the single-player was just multiplayer with bots.
Scott: Yes, but it allowed you to learn, but I do.
Scott: Quake 3 did lack a tutorial which was sort of bad.
Rym: quake 3 assumed that the that everyone who care about FPS is Already played FPS and was just waiting for quake 3 to come out And they were just gonna all play quake 3 instead of quake 3.
Scott: this is why quake live is much better.
Scott: quake live actually has A proper tutorial.
Rym: yep of course it doesn't teach you how to do some of that advanced stuff at the end.
Rym: It just says if you can do it.
Rym: We put you in a higher difficulty echelon.
Rym: Yeah, remember.
Rym: It gives you that long corridor.
Rym: It's like if you've rocket jump down.
Scott: I could never make it all the way to the end.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I could not.
Scott: I could only make it to write that there's only one more test than the one with all the walls that came Down from the ceiling right.
Scott: was that?
Scott: was it.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is I'm not even hardcore.
Rym: I mean I could bunny hop in quake 2 but in quake 1 I wasn't that good at it and everyone who played quake 1 would say yeah quake 2 they dumb down the bunny hopping cuz people Couldn't do it.
Scott: hmm Whatever yeah, so news is well.
Rym: You know we keep.
Rym: we've been saying forever There should be a Pokemon MMO.
Rym: the day They make the Pokemon MMO is the day GeekNights ends, and I play an MMO for the rest of my life.
Scott: That's just another one of those items on the checklist of game companies not fulfilling their potential.
Scott: It's like well.
Scott: You could do this and make a billion dollars But instead you just incrementally update existing franchises with minor changes and sell them for $50.
Rym: I mean you guys know us we hate MMOs And we don't even like Pokemon that much.
Rym: But damn if I wouldn't play it a Pokemon MMO if it was the definitive.
Rym: And this is it.
Rym: if I level up a pokey man in this game It is my pokey man and every pokey man forever And I can never gonna make some new pokey man series that I can't transfer up to.
Rym: you know yep And you're gonna.
Rym: Let me talk to people like an adult.
Rym: Yeah, I need that.
Rym: I need to be able to actually say the word penis to other people while I'm playing.
Rym: That's I don't need to be able to name my Pokemon penis and know that while they can't see the Pokemon's name.
Rym: I know the name But they finally did not know no digimon MMO.
Scott: Ah All right, but I you know.
Scott: all I know is that digimon was copy and Pokemon.
Scott: I don't know anything else about it.
Scott: I know that some people actually like it.
Scott: Well, here's the deal if it's good or bad or what people like the Pokemon games.
Rym: for Pokemon people may or may not like the anime The the lifers as penny arcade calls it.
Rym: you know that kids got six pikachu's.
Rym: he can't lose.
Rym: Those kids watch the anime and probably read the comics and play the game.
Rym: they care about all of them.
Rym: But I think most Pokemon people don't care about the anime at all if they even know it exists.
Rym: Or maybe they they vaguely know, but they pretty much just play the game.
Rym: But digimon I feel like most people either don't like the game don't care about the game don't know about the game But they like the cartoon because the cartoon is a lot darker than the Pokemon cartoon a lot more serious And there's a lot of at least according to bay image a lot more digimon porn.
Rym: I don't know what that says about Mean.
Scott: there's a lot more digimon porn on Bay image.
Rym: Yeah Well, I think there are a lot more digimon that are like Lucario or the bunny Pokemon.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is whenever I look at artwork of digimon I'm like yeah, those are completely not appealing in any way.
Scott: shape or form 50/50 half and the thing is right.
Scott: Pokemon It's like.
Scott: sure I might have an emotional attachment to old Pokemon, but even new Pokemon are awesome.
Scott: It's like man spirits whom check that shit out fuck.
Scott: Yeah, but combi.
Scott: That's a new Pokemon fuck.
Rym: Cannot deny that Pokemon has moved more toward more complex and sometimes human.
Rym: I don't like every Pokemon.
Scott: I'm saying they're moving toward that but I feel like I mean it would be hard to like every digimon I've ever seen.
Scott: I don't like but if there are you know they're a good Pokemon.
Scott: They're a bad.
Scott: Pokemon said there are no good digimon at least as far as I've seen.
Scott: see the trouble is think there's a good Poke of get a digimon that I will like send it on over.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: I thought the same thing.
Rym: I was thinking about digimon and I started looking online just had pictures of digimon that weren't porn and I realized that my image of what a digimon looks like in no way matches the vast majority of digimon.
Scott: now mine mine matches The way did you man look?
Rym: Pokemon I guess I'm used to seeing these vaguely humanoid big deal.
Scott: I'm just in all sorts of digimon.
Rym: what I'm used to seeing from digimon is the equivalent of just the epic Pokemon from Pokemon.
Scott: Now yeah, I guess if you only looked at Pokemon right based on the ones that are on the covers of the boxes You know yeah, and you wouldn't you.
Scott: but then I went looked and most of the digimon are more Pokemon like a lot of them are but I still none of them are.
Rym: I don't like like a more complex Pidgeot But he's got a belt over his forehead for some reason, and he's holding something.
Rym: yeah But the digimon MMO came, but not the Pokemon MMO.
Rym: well.
Rym: Oh well before anyone even bothers I figured out the deal in Korea.
Rym: There is a digimon RPG.
Rym: It's a free area.
Scott: They have everything.
Rym: it's a free-to-play MMO that's based on digimon and it's been around since like 2002. and apparently the digimon battle this MMO of digimon that's coming out in March in the u.s.. According to this European gamers blog quote digimon Battle is the Western revamp of digimon RPG a free-to-play Korean MMO that's been around since 2002 and This explains why all the screenshots and character designs and models and everything from this digimon MMO Look a little bit old and a little bit hokey.
Rym: because this games old and hokey and that they're just revamping it uh-huh.
Rym: So what I wonder is does this game follow the format that every Korean MMO does where the game is mostly free And then they charge you like for five bucks.
Rym: You can add a red color to your guy for ten bucks.
Rym: You can sit down for ten bucks.
Scott: You can get some digit steroids.
Rym: So, I'm really curious if they follow.
Scott: I think though what we should consider right is there's probably a hundred Korean MMOs right out there.
Scott: We could just buy one of them from the company that made it and call it real game.
Scott: I revamp it for the US and make money without having to write our own MMO.
Rym: The thing is that market space is already pretty crowded unless you associated with some property.
Rym: I mean digimon is relatively pop prop like popular among kids.
Rym: Pokemon is really popular.
Rym: You have to tie it into some franchise the kids care about.
Rym: we can get some sort of license But what he gets care about other than Pokemon?
Scott: spongebob spongebob MMO, huh?
Scott: Take a Korean MMO.
Scott: Just take on Bob.
Rym: Forget about just take gun bound and call it like sponge bound.
Rym: Yeah, and just change all that.
Rym: make everything look like spongebob characters.
Rym: There you go million dollars.
Rym: Yep Maybe we should just do that.
Rym: Why am I working at some job?
Scott: Because you need a lot of money to buy the spongebob license.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, unless I could be had the money to buy the spongebob license.
Scott: You wouldn't make the spongebob MMO retired tropical paradise exactly.
Rym: So, yeah digimon MMO not excited about it, but it should be the Pokemon in the bow, right?
Scott: So I did I talk about Street Fighter 4 on the iPhone on the show.
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: I don't know if I did but they're making Street Fighter 4 for the iPhone Which is now that I kind of know how to play.
Rym: Street Fighter 4 is like wow Well, here's the question will they make an interface such that you can have a full-size Bluetooth stick that you carry with you?
Scott: No, you just sort of use the touchscreen and it looks like there's only four attacking buttons and then you know a touch stick.
Scott: You know You move your finger around this area and that counts.
Scott: the real question is will it include all the stuff that's in Street Fighter like Tekken in and out of it has eight characters and apparently those eight characters have the full of their full move set and it Has you know super bars and the whole thing.
Scott: it just.
Scott: it seems like they've taken out.
Scott: You know, there's only four attack buttons.
Scott: so it's light strong light strong instead of light medium strong light medium strong the punch and kick.
Scott: and other than that it looks like It's.
Scott: everyone has all their special moves and everything and there's a video here of someone playing it.
Scott: and I'm just like Who?
Scott: Who's who's gonna play this?
Rym: the same people who buy like the avatar game on the pre for eight bucks?
Scott: But I mean anyone who actually cares about Street Fighter is like, yeah this doesn't count and You're funny.
Scott: Anyone doesn't care about Street Fighter is not gonna play it.
Rym: You're forgetting the weird, you know, there's people like us.
Rym: Well, I like me at least who don't play fighting games and like did the Capcom people who made this game?
Scott: Have they played it and like, you know actually like tested it out and realized it's a horribly uncomfortable?
Rym: Well think of this class one people who are actually good at Street Fighter.
Rym: They won't play this.
Rym: Yeah, they just won't they don't care.
Rym: Class number two people like me.
Rym: I'm not good at Street Fighter and I never planned to me.
Rym: So I don't care It doesn't matter.
Rym: but I'm also savvy enough to know not to buy games on the iPhone Unless I know that they're good independent of some stupid licenses tied to them and I highly doubt this will be good.
Rym: Class three people who know what Street Fighter is played Occasionally have iPhones and just buy a ton of games on their iPhones because they like to have games on their iPhones.
Rym: They're not hardcore, so they don't care about the.
Scott: I just don't know how many of those people would buy.
Scott: You know Street Fighter 4.
Rym: I'm pretty sure it'll be enough because I don't think any of the people involved in this would be stupid enough to release it Unless they knew they'd recoup their losses.
Rym: Unless this is a situation where someone who didn't know better went to the company said look we want to license Street Fighter to do blah.
Rym: And they said you know what give us the license money and have fun.
Scott: Well Capcom made this I'm pretty sure so.
Rym: but what happened internally?
Rym: may I'm for all you know, something weird.
Rym: shenanigans happened internally.
Scott: They're probably just like.
Scott: well, we got to get on the iPhone.
Scott: How about Street Fighter 4?
Scott: Alright, let's do it Should've made, you know Megaman instead.
Scott: I don't know Megaman 9.
Scott: I don't know is Megaman even on the iPhone?
Rym: I have no idea wasn't?
Rym: it was on the bunch of other weird Put on Puzzle Fighter or Megaman battle that didn't?
Rym: they sell Megaman on the the engage way back I don't remember.
Rym: I was pretty sure there was some Megaman that was on the engage and I remember thinking wow If the engage weren't the worst thing in the world, I would consider this.
Rym: I don't remember Things of the day.
Rym: as I fall back to using College Humor because it's easy All right.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So College Humor has this whole this video of some TV show or maybe more than one TV shows.
Rym: I can't tell.
Rym: I don't watch TV.
Rym: I don't even know what show this is from.
Scott: Say in the comments or the.
Rym: it didn't say in the title It just said TV without the green screen.
Rym: But basically all it is is clips from TV shows showing back and forth.
Rym: What is green screen and what isn't and It's just kind of interesting to see.
Rym: you know Shows and backdrops and things juxtaposed with how much of it is actually just a composited image.
Rym: paste it onto a green screen Yep, and if you doubt how extensively these things are used nowadays.
Rym: I submit to you the fact that as far as I can tell the old movie Bruce almighty Had almost zero sets and the entire movie was filmed in front of like one green screen.
Rym: They just made scenes in the background later.
Rym: Mm-hmm I thought this was cool and I totally copped out because I have a better thing in the day that I'm saving Get someone to listen to every episode maybe or just check the website.
Scott: So, you know people we keep talking about, you know tablets this and that right.
Scott: so Apparently there's a company.
Scott: they made something called the boogie board and It's so popular.
Scott: just keeps selling out and you can't get one.
Scott: But you know when they're not sold out you can buy one on Amazon and I'm not even sure what the price is because I can't.
Scott: They're sold out on Amazon.
Rym: So how much do they go for on like eBay?
Scott: That's a good question.
Scott: Let me check eBay, but basically what this thing is is it's an LCD screen, right?
Scott: That's only one color green, you know, usually an L sell LCD screen.
Scott: Each pixel is red green blue.
Scott: This is just green green green, right?
Scott: Uh Let's see boogie board on eBay.
Scott: So the it's also a tablet so you can draw on it.
Scott: All right, it has a button that resets it and makes the whole thing black.
Scott: Uh-huh, and that's it.
Scott: It doesn't like out as far as I can tell.
Scott: it doesn't output to.
Scott: you know Anything anything, you know, it's basically just a pad that does not require.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It's a hundred and I see Oh, there's one for 50 wait.
Rym: Wait, so clearly whatever this thing does There's a market or maybe there's one for $26 so it can get really cheap.
Scott: is one for $20 new in box?
Rym: So here's my my thoughts.
Rym: one The reason you're finding them cheap is because while they're popular people realize right away They're useless.
Rym: and two there is a market for the same thing with a USB hole on the side.
Scott: Well, I do think that if they added the ability to just you know export a JPEG Let's give it an SD slot or something and let someone give it one more button and that button will save the current Image to the SD.
Rym: give it two more buttons.
Rym: Let it load images from an SD and display them.
Scott: Yeah, but they could only be one color.
Scott: So what would it do if you gave it like a multicolored ping?
Rym: It'll only load images that are the right format.
Rym: use that to save your gigantic penis and then you show it to people When you're standing at a concert and you hold it up like, you know, we people used to hold up light.
Scott: Basically, what's cool about this?
Scott: right is like the makes me kind of want one But I'm still not gonna buy one until they have the saving ability.
Scott: if they ever add the saving ability Huh is that?
Scott: you know, basically as a battery it lasts for fucking ever and you just don't need pens Or or paper.
Scott: you can just draw and erase and draw and erase and draw on a race like, you know if you're Like I wouldn't need a pad on my desk at work Like if I just had one of these I wouldn't have to keep going down the office supply cabinet or use pens.
Rym: It's useful for me.
Rym: at least.
Rym: I have my previous days shit laying around so every day I flip to a new page so I can go back and look at what did I write down on Monday?
Rym: That might have been important.
Scott: Oh, yeah Like if I sit there all day doodling why should I waste pens and paper doodling?
Rym: Well, well, well You know what?
Scott: This is if you're playing like an RPG a tabletop RPG, right?
Scott: You can draw like, okay You're here and the other guy's there, you know, and why should you waste paper?
Rym: Remember at Katsucon way back?
Rym: We were running the old-school retro video arcade and we had all those prizes to give out and one of them was that Okami Like Buddha board.
Rym: I forget exactly what it was called.
Rym: It was just a piece of rock that was flat like slate and a thing for water.
Rym: All right, right and you can draw on it with water and an image would appear But then it would eventually dry up and go away so that the point was you would draw But whatever you drew was by nature ephemeral and was the same sort.
Scott: This is the same sort of thing.
Rym: It's just that thing made digital.
Rym: So you probably don't actually want to save function because that makes it something entirely different from what it is.
Scott: Yeah, but you know having it would be different from what it is A better thing.
Scott: that would be more useful.
Scott: I mean one of the examples.
Scott: one of the examples they show here though is Like, you know doing some math, you know Like homeworks.
Scott: and they show an example of like drawing a football play like if you're the coach you'd be like, alright guys You know, you know, you do a wideout you do it cross over, you know, and then push the erase button, you know Cuz it's not something you actually need to save.
Scott: So, you know if the price really is this low like friggin 20 bucks, right?
Scott: You know $20 new in box on eBay one bid.
Scott: Well, it's got six days left and they're sold out on Amazon.
Scott: I think the reason they're sold out is because just they're so ridiculously cheap right for an LCD screen.
Scott: That's a tablet you can draw on and push that have an erase button.
Rym: I wonder how sensitive it is all that stuff.
Rym: I wonder if you can.
Scott: it looks it looks pretty sensitive.
Rym: are people buying them really to mod them into other things.
Scott: Oh I just you know, maybe I should buy two and try to hack an SD slot onto one of them and You know if I could.
Rym: that's hard to say cuz it probably just has some kind of direct output.
Rym: I mean, I don't know what kind of chips are in there.
Rym: It might not have anywhere.
Rym: You could easily get data off of it.
Scott: Yeah, it might require like that.
Scott: You actually add a bunch of electronics to it that it doesn't have.
Scott: Yeah, it might be a tree might increase the price like fourfold to add that functionality Cuz it would need.
Rym: I mean it might just have one.
Rym: I see that stores like all the pixel data and then just then.
Scott: that'd be really easy cuz you would just need to read from It and write it to.
Scott: you know You know any sort of storage and that's it.
Scott: you just need to add an SD controller.
Rym: Yeah, but depending on if it's nice see there's like solder down to some.
Scott: so these are 20 bucks.
Scott: Why not buy two?
Rym: Yeah, why not buy all of them have a monopoly?
Rym: I think this is why they're sold out and then sell them on eBay.
Scott: They're already being sold on eBay.
Scott: But anyway, I just you know, it's my thing of the day.
Scott: It's a. it's a thing you might want one.
Rym: so I want to take the time to read at least much of The post that caused me to come up with what we want to talk about.
Scott: people can read it themselves.
Scott: You're gonna read a whole post.
Rym: I want to skip through it because I basically I Realized that this sounds exactly like someone I know if you change all the proper nouns And this is someone asking slash job something about gaming.
Rym: I have a slightly older friend who plays through the glory days of Ultima online.
Rym: Yes, their servers are still up and running but he waxes nostalgic about certain gameplay functions of you.
Rym: Oh that he misses.
Rym: I must say that these aspects make me smile and wonder what it would be like to play in such a world.
Rym: Things like housing thieving and looting.
Scott: they don't have those anymore.
Scott: I thought they still had those.
Rym: None of that stuff is in World of Warcraft.
Scott: No, but it's in Ultima online, right?
Rym: Yeah, all them online has all that stuff still.
Scott: So why is he wag?
Rym: It doesn't need to wax nostalgia cuz it's an old busted game that hardly anyone plays.
Rym: So I followed him through a few games like Darkfall and mortal online and these games are consistently failing of pop Fading into obscurity and never catching hold.
Rym: We constantly move from one to the next.
Rym: does anyone know of a popular three-dimensional game that has you oh like rules and gameplay?
Rym: and he goes on to talk about all the stuff he likes about Ultima online and Basically his point seems to be that old school MMO.
Rym: Ultima online Was a different kind of game from modern MMOs like World of Warcraft that are popular.
Rym: He likes the old MMOs and he doesn't like the new ones.
Rym: He wants to know if there's anything to play now, man I really like those old hardcore.
Scott: FPS is not unlike these newfangled wussy.
Scott: Halo ones are too bad.
Scott: No one's making games for me anymore.
Rym: Is this not just me?
Rym: he even goes further.
Rym: Darkfall mortal online all these games that do what he wants and then fail.
Rym: quake live.
Scott: Yeah, basically I wonder why these games fail.
Scott: the same reason that like tribes to release today would fail because it's too complicated for anyone to play.
Rym: Realize that everything I say about FPS is and what I want and how.
Rym: I realize that that is not viable in the modern market.
Rym: There are people in every other gaming genre who feel the exact same way.
Rym: They look at old RTS's and say wow Everything back then was awesome and everything today.
Scott: So I think actually RTS people are pleased because you know, they have someone serving them, you know Starcraft 2 isn't serving like the mass market.
Scott: Starcraft 2 is.
Scott: so yeah the hardcore.
Rym: Well, I guess part of that is that Korea is kind of like an Eastern Roman Empire.
Rym: it's a Byzantium.
Scott: It's a place where there's just just the mass market is hardcore.
Rym: It is it's a Byzantium of RTS's, you know the West fell.
Rym: RTS's fell here except for a few holdouts and barbarians everywhere playing like brutal legend with quote RTS elements.
Rym: But in Korea, they've got walls around this old-school city of people who play real old-school RTS's and the Renaissance never will happen because Korea will never fall Mmm, but of course if Korea fell there's wouldn't ever be RTS's again.
Scott: in terms of FPS's, you know There's not to.
Scott: you know, the percentage of people who are hardcore into FPS is still is relatively small Compared to the people are into.
Scott: you know.
Scott: halos and calls of duty are selling way way more than you know quakes and such.
Rym: Well, look at East Asia FPS's are not super popular.
Rym: No, they're popular in the Europe where the FPS's are hot and in Europe too apparently is where these old weird style MMOs that no one likes anymore keep coming out of.
Rym: And I also note that a lot of our own friends in the crew who like those old-school kind of games They always tell me about like Darkfall like all these games that come out They're like, yeah, this is gonna be the best MMO ever.
Scott: It'll destroy Wow, and no one plays.
Scott: Yeah Yeah Nothing's gonna destroy right the games that appeal to the mass market and make more money is what people are gonna make and no one.
Scott: You know if you want to make an MMO the problem with an MMO as opposed to some other game, right?
Scott: It's like even though we talk about hardcore FPS's people still make them, you know.
Scott: Not a lot of people play them But people still make them and the reason that people still make them is because you only have to make it and then it's it's set.
Scott: It's like you can still play tribes - there's some open-source hardcore FPS's out there, you know.
Scott: and But an MMO requires a lot of money and servers to keep up.
Scott: Even if there aren't a lot of players you still have to have a server.
Scott: and you know It's much more Technologically intensive even though the game is.
Scott: I mean look what hand mechanics are simple But the 3d and the whole thing it's like the guy specifically said 3d.
Scott: he could get the exact game He wants with players in a mud, right?
Scott: It exists out there.
Scott: He could play it right now You know what?
Rym: He could play the realm.
Rym: It's still up the fans of the realm.
Rym: the first MMO Well the first graphical MMO, you know.
Scott: modern playing Ultima online.
Scott: Yeah Why does he need to play something, you know his insistence on it being a 3d one Means that it's not going to exist because for such a thing to exist It would have to be popular enough to pay for it and to be popular enough to pay for it It would have to not have the mechanics He wants.
Rym: but at least with the realm the fans that were left there weren't that many Actually bought the rights to the game and maintained the server at their own expense Mm-hmm.
Rym: And as far as I can tell there's a small community of really really weird people who play the realm Regularly to this day.
Rym: Yeah, so I'd still up and everything.
Rym: but you know There's a whole bunch discussion on slashdot and I went to like this guy's blog and other people's blogs And I followed this thread for a couple hours and I realized something really interesting.
Rym: Everything I liked about MMOs back when I played MMOs does not exist in modern MMOs.
Rym: however everything that I liked in old MMOs basically boiled down to Griefing and the and not just griefing but all the like accoutrement of griefing.
Rym: I mean in the realm I ground up my guy, you know I had to grind up to get like level 60 70 80 with my gold Baldrick and all that bullshit.
Rym: I didn't like grinding.
Rym: I hated it.
Rym: Everyone hated it.
Rym: You know why I ground?
Rym: because I was scared shitless that if I walked somewhere dangerous out in the woods and someone stronger than me Came by they might just kill me.
Rym: I'll lose like three levels and all my magic items and I'm fucked.
Rym: That's like 40 or 50 hours of my life gone.
Rym: And that dynamic made this interesting situation kind of by accident.
Rym: where?
Rym: Exploring these old MMOs was interesting and scary because they were dangerous and you had a lot to lose.
Rym: if you wandered into some scary like if you went into the killing fields and You were invisible and some level 80 like paladin dude saw you and he wanted to kill you.
Rym: You were basically done.
Rym: Yeah, it was scary to be out there and you actually had things to lose.
Scott: I mean, this is what I sort of like about, you know, the I mean the part of fallout 3 we discussed You know earlier in the show, which is good is the exploring part.
Scott: The problem is is that in Exploring fallout 3 it's sort of all pre done and a lot of it's just repetition of existing stuff And it's not very big.
Scott: like you can't explore it all.
Scott: and then what?
Rym: the first time I played fallout I had a guy was really good at sneaking right?
Rym: So well fallout 3. so I went out and I just walked north as far as I could go because I was curious and After inspecting like six or seven identical burned-out barns.
Rym: I stopped inspecting anything because there was nothing anywhere except plot.
Scott: but it's like, you know exploring just and you know a terrain is Can be fun, especially if the terrain is interesting and varied.
Scott: I mean Zelda 1. the reason it's so awesome is because they only gave you part of the map.
Scott: and if you didn't even if You didn't have a map.
Scott: It was all exploring.
Scott: you explored all these dungeons and yet a second quest you find you find that graveyard.
Rym: That is some scary shit.
Scott: Yeah, you get to the graveyard.
Scott: It's like whoa.
Rym: shit, you know You bump into a gravestone a ghost comes out.
Rym: You just run away exactly.
Rym: I'm never coming back here.
Scott: You know that.
Scott: just exploring stuff and finding weird things.
Scott: It's like, you know You find a secret and you go down there and it's actually weird and not like other places you've been.
Scott: and this stuff down there It's like whoa, ah, you know, whereas you'd say look at D&D online, which we did a show about right?
Scott: You go and every single level looks exactly like every other level except it's you know, the same sarcophagus.
Rym: a hundred times It's like yeah, thanks, but think about this this was not necessarily intentional that it caused this.
Rym: I mean no one is going to argue that Griefing made these old games better.
Scott: No griefing made people not play those games And that's why the games that now have no griefing.
Rym: Well, what I'd argue is that a lot of people did play those games and some people like the griefing and some people didn't.
Rym: I Think that griefing did not.
Rym: I think that the griefing that happened was just immersion behavior.
Rym: But as a result of that immersion behavior all these other secondary behaviors appeared around the griefing.
Rym: that Kind of accidentally caused things that certain people remember and like.
Rym: wow, I remember this feeling and it was awesome.
Rym: Why don't I get that from modern games?
Scott: Yeah, but the griefing didn't.
Rym: it caused it but not in a good way and not directly.
Scott: It's basically you had you know You have you add a certain feature to a game and the game and that feature has bad Consequences and good consequences.
Scott: the bad consequences are that big powerful players were playing for a long time will just kill noobs which means that the more powerful players will continue to get more powerful more easily and they basically have this huge momentum advantage.
Scott: and weak players can never become More powerful because they keep getting killed by people who are already powerful and it just creates this sort of.
Scott: you know Rich guys stay rich poor guys stay poor situation except they can't.
Rym: what it enforced was a weird community.
Rym: I'm not saying this is good, but this happened in the a lot of these old muds and MMOs where The high-level players would kind of form factions, you know, you know, they'd hate each other.
Rym: like I'm with this guy I'm with this guy their clans their tribes all that stuff and Then new players and young players kind of come under the wing of one of them and like I can't go into the scary bad Lands unless I have a paladin to take me
Scott: through.
Scott: side effect is that you know It created this, you know danger and that danger of being out in the world created.
Scott: You know that same sort of excitement you get when you're in Zelda and you find the graveyard for the first time.
Scott: So, you know this horrible griefing mechanic had to cut, you know multiple consequences some of which were good for the game and some of which were bad for the game and You know It's like how can we somehow?
Scott: Get those good parts back into the game without also bringing these bad parts that scare players away back in?
Rym: Yeah, and it's not just the griefing in the danger.
Rym: Think about the the force socialization.
Rym: and let's compare an old MMO to a game like Wow.
Rym: in Wow If you you gang up with like a high-level player to power level you through, you know to grind up Usually don't they not?
Scott: let you do that.
Scott: They like yell at you if they catch you or I Don't think there's anything like I remember like in old muds.
Scott: What would happen is you could join a group of a very powerful player like you would actually in the game type group and the?
Scott: Players name and they'd be level 100 and you'd be level like one and then they would kill a monster and you would get half The XP and then you'd be level 20 after like one monster, you know, you could do stuff like that But then it's someone caught you doing that they would just like, you know Ban you or delete your
Rym: And
Scott: then like you what you could do is they said, okay you can only group with someone if they're within 10 levels of you and they put all these rules in and stuff and
Rym: But people group like that and and do their clan stuff just to grind up to be able to do like these raids and to Do other things.
Rym: so it's kind of this very functional meta Construct.
Rym: in old MMOs if you grouped up like that often the grouping up was hey, I'm a high-level guy.
Rym: You want me to let your cat like take your character with me so I can show you all the crazy stuff in the killing Fields that you can never see on your own.
Rym: You want me to take you through the fucking ruins of blah and then after you get them out there?
Rym: You're like, alright, give me all your gold or I'm not taking you back.
Rym: Yeah Or just alright.
Rym: See ya.
Rym: Yeah, I Did that.
Rym: you know how often I would take so course.
Rym: this was a glitch.
Rym: I would find some bad guy don't enemy of my clan.
Rym: I was a wizard and I'd be like, hey, I'll power level you I'll take you out blah and I'd take him out somewhere.
Rym: I use a teleport glitch to teleport them home But instead of taking them home I took him to the glitch city that there was no way out of and then I just teleport home and leave him there.
Scott: I think that one Solution to this right.
Scott: this particular specific thing is actually to fix the numbers.
Scott: Right, if you look at these MMOs, right the way they work with the numbers and the levels and the damage and the two hits Right, is that the numbers basically go up exponentially right?
Scott: No number of level one guys can beat up a level 20 guy.
Scott: Right, but if they fixed all the numbering it would still have that same, you know carrot and stick You know What's it called the inner box mechanic?
Scott: I want to jump in right now continuing to level up right and getting more and more powerful.
Scott: But I think there's guys could gang up and beat a high-level guy Which would mean that you could allow the griefing but people wouldn't do it because you go into town and start killing off level one guys.
Scott: Five of them would just all stab you and then they'd be like sweet and maybe even a bunch of low-level guys would Intentionally get together and go around killing high-level guys in an angry mob.
Scott: I think the numbers would not be out of scale.
Rym: the other component to this the reason Griefing mattered and happened and the reason there was the sense of danger wasn't just that you could die It was because in old MMOs.
Rym: when you died it mattered a lot like if I was level 70.
Rym: I had to kill like a Thousand of the baddest monster in the game to go up a level and if I died, I lost the equivalent of like 5,000 guys worth of experience.
Rym: I would go down like three levels and it would take me like 20 or 30 hours to get that back.
Rym: I would also randomly drop items that I was equipped with like my two-handed deluxe sword of power That was really fucking hard to get or the magic item.
Rym: I got in a special drop.
Rym: That's gone now.
Scott: Well, that's just you know, that's just the nature of a grinding game.
Scott: It's like well, you're you're not investing any skill You're investing time and if we D level you are basically taking time away from your life.
Scott: But that's that you've already given up because you're an MMO player games.
Rym: It was bad I'm not going to argue was a good thing But the fact that you had something Tangible to lose you when you died meant that you were scared of dying.
Rym: if you wipe in a while raid like People don't care if they die.
Rym: Oh, we lost the wow raid or oh you killed me.
Rym: I'm just gonna respawn and keep going to do whatever I was gonna do.
Rym: All you did was slow me down in the grinding that I'm trying to get to.
Rym: All you did is delay me momentarily.
Rym: now I'm bored in the meta.
Rym: losing is boring.
Rym: in the old games losing sucks.
Rym: The real answer is that losing should be interesting.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: See I actually you know.
Scott: the MMO that I've always wanted to make solves all these problems at least in my opinion, right?
Scott: The game I've always wanted which I've discussed many times right?
Scott: is some sort of action survival game right.
Scott: where you know fighting is is FPS skill, you know.
Scott: And you pay money every time.
Scott: you let you spawn just like an arcade and as long as you don't die You don't have to pay ever again.
Scott: And when you die, you're just dead and you have to pay money again.
Scott: You get a brand new character with nothing.
Scott: There's no levels experience or skills because all the skills are in you because they're your FPS skills.
Scott: But there is equipment and ammo and level and you know levels but weapons and armor and those sorts of things.
Scott: So if you die out in the middle of snow where because you were exploring the gigantic map You know and a giant robot came and crushed you Well, you were you have your.
Scott: you're basically a brand new character now with nothing.
Scott: Maybe you have a pistol from town or whatever and if you can get back out there Pick up all the stuff off your corpse and no one else is taking it yet and the robot doesn't crush you.
Rym: and good for You know, well think about the like the weird economics of Greece griefing like how come Wow and all these games?
Rym: don't have your house.
Rym: You don't remember all the old mo's?
Rym: you'd like.
Rym: build your house build your fort.
Rym: I guess Eve online has that to a degree.
Scott: actually if online is you have a ship right implemented in spreadsheets, but yeah Yeah, well, I think the reason that Wow doesn't do that is because they want to control the game world.
Scott: They don't want you to control the game world and the maps and all that stuff and it adds a lot of complexity And it's not gonna get them much more money.
Rym: Yeah Well this this this is the crux of everything because what I realized and I realized this and then later like just now I was Going through the slashed out article and I pull it up.
Rym: Someone else said the exact same thing The reason for all of this is that South Park episode on World of Warcraft.
Rym: because look at what happened in that episode, right?
Rym: You've got one character who becomes a badass and starts griefing in game in a way that matters.
Rym: He's killing characters in a way that matters in the context of the game not in some meta.
Rym: You've slowed me down in the single-player game.
Rym: I'm playing with all my friends in the co-op game that I'm playing independent of all these other million people playing.
Rym: Wow You've been convenience me you asshole.
Rym: It's you fucking killed my character and most people do not want that out of a game.
Rym: They do not want direct Griefable competition among players.
Rym: if in Wow when you found like you're you know You're the Alliance and you find some whore guy just wandering around out in the wilderness and you fucking kill him and take all this shit People would hate that because they lose a big game.
Scott: Yeah be a game only for super nerds.
Scott: Right and very few people would play just like very few people played.
Scott: You know Diablo on hardcore mode where if you die, you have to start over from the beginning.
Rym: Yep, a single-player games like dungeon crew, whatever.
Rym: I forget when that hack but there was some game I own.
Rym: it was basically a net hat clone in 3d way back and had an option hard car mode.
Rym: That said it would literally physically delete your save file and it had all these protections for if you tried to like turn the game Off it would just delete your save file.
Rym: Anyway, yep, and it basically made sure if you die Your character is dead and there's nothing in the world You could possibly have done short of like writing the contents of your RAM to a disk periodically.
Scott: Dwarf Fortress does the same kind of thing.
Scott: It's like you save but you can't like have multiple saves and load up an older one unless you start hacking around, you know By default, it's just you save and you can have.
Scott: you can save multiple different dwarf fortresses But that one fortress has one save and when it's dead, it's dead.
Scott: You can't like go roll it back.
Rym: But the reason Wow took off is that what most people want is a single-player game.
Rym: effectively It's a single-player narrative where you play through this entire narrative and you don't care that everyone else played through effectively the same narrative.
Rym: you played through the narrative and that's all you care about and then you effectively play this kind of co-op game where The only people you interact with are all your friends who are also playing through this narrative and then you play these raids together and do This stuff together, but they don't actually want a real economy of revenge and fighting and inter-character conflict except in these like instantiated and not just instances in MMOs.
Rym: But I'm talking because people paid money.
Scott: and if it's a game of investing, you know if it's a game of skill Right like counter-strike people have no problem dying in counter-strike because a you're gonna come back to life pretty soon, right.
Scott: and B What do you lose when you die in counter-strike besides the round?
Scott: but people want this Game where it's about investing time and not investing skill.
Scott: Right, if you lose you just lost time in your life and you've been made to see.
Scott: you know The the how stupid you were for wasting all your time and money on this game.
Scott: You've been confronted with your own stupidity.
Scott: They you know, people don't mind doing stupid things or being stupid.
Scott: They only mind when you point it out to them then they get indignant and angry.
Scott: So you can't point it out to them.
Rym: See I'm thinking more.
Scott: you can't make them realize their own, you know failures.
Rym: It's not just you're only here, you know.
Scott: If someone's you know has a fault and you point it out.
Scott: You're a jerk even if the fault is true because you're not supposed to point out people's faults because it makes them feel bad.
Rym: I'll be honest though.
Rym: I don't think that's terribly relevant to what's going on here at least not directly Well, but I mean that's what.
Scott: that's what you know.
Scott: If you die in an MMO and they actually penalized you with levels it makes people feel bad for that same reason.
Rym: Well, it makes them feel bad directly just because they don't necessarily feel stupid for having invested the time.
Rym: They feel mad because they lost something tangible But it's not something.
Scott: they'd already lost it though, but they just made to realize that.
Rym: they know You see in your mind, but they feel like they got something.
Rym: they played the game.
Rym: They got you know their trinkets.
Rym: They got their stuff.
Rym: They have this tangible thing that they got and they invested time to get it.
Rym: if you take it away They've lost it and the time and they have to spend more time to get it back.
Rym: You're just expanding that into your.
Scott: I hate MMOs argument, which is a separate argument But I mean the thing is they didn't actually get anything tangible.
Rym: See that's again to them.
Rym: It's tangible That they couldn't have gotten some other way short of like spending money and buying it on eBay.
Rym: but what I'm saying is that what people want out of a game like Wow is this instantiated danger where they only want danger when they're ready for danger.
Rym: They want an instance of danger where the danger is contained to that instance.
Rym: time to do a raid time to do this thing There's.
Rym: you know We're all gonna get together and do something in Wow If I die here.
Rym: the consequences of that don't extend beyond what I am doing here right now.
Rym: But in old MMOs, there was no instantiation like that.
Rym: if you died somewhere the consequences were the same No matter where you were and they were like part of the overall experience.
Rym: People don't want houses partly because if some people had houses Unless there were a mechanism for like robbing those houses griefing those houses the players who want that stuff wouldn't care about them.
Rym: People want this instantiated parallel experience and Wow is just parallel play.
Scott: Well, the thing with the houses right is that you know, what is a house?
Scott: get you in game, right?
Rym: Well, it gets you nothing except dollhouse.
Rym: Basically unless you make some sort of clan thing where I defend my house We have this group house where we store all our stuff.
Rym: if you attack us and take our stuff now We don't have stuff but that again introduces the griefing Ella, right?
Scott: So what they have in Wow is they have things like, you know, the mounts and stuff Which is you know, which is better than a house because when you walk around People can see your mount.
Scott: when you're going, you know, when you're out and about people don't see your house.
Scott: Where your house Currency with the house.
Scott: the
Rym: special sword that I got in some drop on Easter from an easter egg that I found after I killed a fairy and ripped it out of her still beating chest and Then I used a glitch to put it in my wall in my house and it was all cool-looking.
Rym: I had to like invite people to my house bring him in and be like check that out and then watch them to make sure They didn't like steal something from my house while they were in there.
Scott: Yeah, and if Wow just you know made houses as places, you know They gave people a space in the game that they could just decorate like dollhouse and that was it and didn't do any of the Griefing stuff because they would never do that because it would lose the money and make people upset then Basically people would get houses, you know, just cuz they had nothing better to do.
Scott: But if the houses didn't do anything, you know, it'd be like, okay.
Scott: I've got a house.
Scott: No one ever looks at it and it's taking up space in the game and no one ever goes here.
Scott: What's the point now?
Rym: think about what people consider griefing and Wow - they kind of they've decontextualized Griefing the only.
Rym: you can only grief Via the microphone by a chatting and by slowing people down in their grinds and things like that.
Rym: in old MMOs griefing was Directly contextual in the game.
Rym: I fucking killed that guy.
Rym: I stood I went to your house stood outside the door and killed you every time you tried to leave until you cried.
Rym: and while that wasn't good contextualized griefing is Effectively just competition and hardcore players or people who call themselves hardcore in the old sense They effectively want that.
Rym: they want brutal competition between players directly.
Rym: That is contextual within the game and games like wow We're so successful because they remove all ways to grief in the context of the game.
Rym: It's only griefing that's left is like emailing people pictures of penises or saying penis to someone while they're while they like kill you once And laugh at you after you died.
Rym: They've removed all the griefing elements And I think those griefing elements are kind of integral to what these people like the guy in this article want from old MMOs and want from new MMOs, but World of Warcraft Blizzard just realized that there's much more money in catering to Single-player shared experiences that are parallel as opposed to truly massive multiplayer experiences.
Scott: Well, it's done.
Scott: We've you know, this is just applies to gaming in general is something we've always you know.
Scott: No, and I guess we I don't know if we've talked about it that much on the show.
Scott: Is that this?
Scott: you know, there's some gamers who actually want legit Competition some sort of test of skill win and lose and there are other people who just want to play around and they don't you know.
Scott: and if you try if they if you play with Those people and you're actually trying to win they'll and you're like you're competing seriously They'll just become upset.
Scott: they you know, and those people are the kind of people who really love games like, you know Apples to apples or the game of life, you know They just they just want to just sort of go and do stuff and they don't actually, you know winning it They're not trying to win They don't think about trying to win and they don't you know, they're not playing for serious They're just playing, you know, because it's a fun mind occupying thing.
Scott: There's just something to do to occupy your brain is doing fun stuff putting little people in a car you know saying funny things rolling some dice because rolling dice is fun.
Scott: and You know these kind of gamers can't really play the same kind of games and get along.
Scott: but you know I mean I can enjoy an apples apples and such, you know.
Scott: But I don't play it to win because it's not a play to win game.
Rym: I do because it is.
Rym: it is definitely a game to play to win you Don't?
Rym: all you want to do is try to figure out the site guys to the group and figure out how to get the other Person.
Rym: and yeah, but it comes on.
Scott: you play you already, you know, it's what card you have You can't?
Scott: you know, if you don't have the card what see?
Rym: but that's why you mod the game.
Rym: You have some rule where every round you can discard like two of your two cars.
Scott: and I'm not talking about a mod of the game I'm talking about the game itself.
Scott: Yeah, and then the game itself is not a game.
Scott: That's really a winning and losing game.
Scott: It's just sort of a have fun.
Rym: Yeah game mostly just this and this.
Scott: but I notice that you know There's people who just they don't like playing competitive games period and there are people who they really just want Competition and they get upset when there isn't any.
Scott: and then you know, I can play both but I recognize the difference between each.
Scott: and if I'm playing a competitive game and someone else is not playing it competitively that is a Problem.
Scott: and if I am playing a non-competitive game and someone else is playing it competitively.
Scott: That's also a problem.
Rym: Well, the article just made me really realize Why.
Rym: you know I always talk about how the realm the first MMO is fundamentally no different from Wow.
Rym: And that's true primarily because all the same things are in both games Except that the old game the realm Had all these griefing elements that were kind of there and I had to do the grindy stuff to be able to compete in the Griefing which is what I really cared about.
Rym: I didn't realize until now that what I all I cared about in that game was the player Interactions and the griefing and I ground because I wanted to be powerful enough to enact my will in the game.
Rym: that actually mattered to me And everyone playing this old game.
Rym: you owe and the realm wanted that.
Scott: but 90% of people play Aren't powerful enough to play the griefing and just immediately quit because they just get killed by you.
Scott: That's why I need a few people crazy enough to actually Level up and deal with getting killed constantly by big powerful players who got there first Are the only people we're gonna play and that's why the game is gone and Wow has a billion players.
Rym: Yep I mean look at the questions at the end of this quote unquote article I was talking about.
Rym: if you think the very things that have been removed Housing and thieving will be two good examples caused Wow to become the most popular MMO.
Rym: Why is that?
Rym: do Ultima online rules not translate well to true 3d environment our people To do with 3d.
Rym: Yeah, he's done Wow retarded, but are people incapable of planning for corpse looting?
Rym: our players inept Such that developers don't want to leave them in control of risk analysis?
Scott: He is thinking this unlike a way too detailed level You know, he is is basically people don't want to compete period they just want to play with you saying Why do people like Final Fantasy 7 more than they like Final Fantasy 1?
Rym: Is it because the hit points only went up to 999 and Final Fantasy 1?
Scott: this guy's just doesn't get it.
Scott: He's too into it.
Scott: So he doesn't under.
Scott: you know, that's the problem.
Rym: He almost gets it though.
Rym: He almost gets it because he talks a lot about like the housing stuff and the thieving and the griefing But then he doesn't extend it and realize that all he cares about is the griefing.
Rym: Well, this is something.
Scott: This is the problem.
Scott: people have you always see this with the guy who's playing D&D and he knows something's wrong with D&D And he says how can I fix it?
Scott: But he's his mind is so deep into D&D that he's like, okay What if we changed the amount of damage on the longsword, you know, what have we changed this spell?
Scott: It's like no no, no, you got to bring your brain back out.
Scott: Look at it from the zoomed out perspective.
Scott: Look at the more fundamental things.
Scott: It is not the details of Corpse looting strategies right that are making the game, you know a problem for some people.
Scott: It is the fundamental that people don't want to lose.
Scott: You know, you can't lose in Farmville.
Rym: I was about to say look at the example of Farmville.
Rym: Farmville is the game.
Rym: It's what it's arguably one of the more popular games in the history of gaming at this point.
Scott: Yeah, I think you know, the Sims is pretty close.
Scott: What's the Sims?
Scott: a dollhouse?
Scott: Well, even we thought we just saw Will Wright the other day.
Scott: He said the Sims of the dollhouse.
Rym: In fact, we had to not call it a dollhouse because guys wouldn't play it.
Rym: So we had to change the names and everything.
Scott: Yep, but the Sims of the dollhouse That's all it is.
Scott: and it was the crazy popular because it's not something you can win and lose or compete at It's just you just play around with stuff.
Rym: But you can compete a little bit.
Rym: you can show off what you've done You show off your farm you trade with people.
Rym: they people want all the benefits of winning But they don't want any serious complications from using.
Rym: they want losing Not to change their course and not to stop their course and not to destroy anything they have.
Rym: But they want it only to delay them in their eventual winning Like they want like kind of like a Mario where I fall in the hole.
Rym: All right, I'm delayed But I will eventually win no matter what.
Scott: Yeah I mean even our losing should be fun.
Scott: that really only also works for people who actually care about gaming most people Right.
Scott: The idea is that you're a game developer.
Scott: if your goal is to make a good game quality game then do all the stuff.
Scott: We say well, yeah skill challenges, you know coming that's fun I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna for once take the less ego filled route.
Rym: Do what we say or in the very least what people like Will Wright say?
Scott: If you want to make a game that makes a shit ton of money and has lots of people playing and playing a lot Then all you have to do is basically make the game such that no matter what players do you give them a reward That'll make them happy, right?
Scott: So it's like they.
Scott: they're sitting in a box with a whole bunch of buttons.
Scott: They push buttons food comes out.
Scott: They push a different button food comes out.
Scott: Of course everyone food comes out.
Scott: Look at the genius.
Rym: Look at the difference.
Scott: It is having so much fun playing your game.
Rym: food keeps coming out Between the sims versus Farmville.
Rym: a game like Farmville the food comes out no matter what but in a game like the sims Sometimes good food comes out as in.
Rym: you know My character succeeded or I made a cool thing and sometimes bad food comes out Like I set my character and all their friends and family on fire and watch them die.
Rym: And you know what players like but they do it.
Scott: That's why Sim City, right?
Scott: You can have Godzilla crush your whole city, but you do it on purpose and it's fun.
Rym: but that's why you can have a game that rewards players no matter what they do and it's still a great game because if they Succeed you reward them with good endings and if they fail you reward them with bad endings.
Rym: But both good and bad endings are interesting and worth exploring.
Rym: It's it's.
Scott: it's just that even you say bad ending but the bad ending is a reward.
Scott: getting to see Godzilla crush Your city is fun.
Scott: You're seeing Godzilla going to.
Scott: it's like oh, it's so fun.
Scott: It's like a role-playing game.
Scott: I mean no matter what you do is fun.
Rym: Yes where you know, if you succeed and get the McGuffin It's awesome and everyone had a good time.
Rym: if you fail in the world ends.
Rym: It's awesome because you told a great story and everyone died.
Scott: getting getting killed in an MMO and losing three levels isn't fun.
Rym: so people want to get all the benefits of getting all the levels and get a Reward that they perceive as valuable for the time they spend.
Rym: so they have this sense of accomplishment.
Rym: But they don't actually want to lose anything or every risk of losing anything tangible.
Scott: You people just you know, if you want to make a game like it's very it's ton of sales.
Scott: It should be fun all the time.
Scott: the amount of fun at different ports.
Scott: You know this part can be less fun that other part which is super fun.
Scott: But there needs to be fun all the time.
Scott: if there is any part that is not fun or anti fun People are gonna quit your game.
Scott: You know if they lose three levels, they'll just quit right then and there and cancel.
Rym: So I feel like the answer for this guy is to get good at FPS and just like counter-strike.
Scott: That's why I'm playing Street Fighter and be a team flasher.
Scott: Yeah Team flashing.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate.
Scott: Thursdays GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.