Rym: Hey, it's Thursday, May 20th.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight one of the most important things in all of human civilization That has brought us from the depths of bread.
Scott: Let's do this Way to go Rym the manly.
Rym: I see I feel weird if we just say bread.
Rym: It's too short.
Rym: You know the music comes in.
Scott: we're gonna know that's not it.
Scott: Oh, you know you're bullshitting.
Scott: you told me two seconds ago It was because like you couldn't figure out how to get the opener to sound better.
Scott: your technological failure.
Rym: now It's more.
Rym: It's just a cadence fail.
Rym: You know if you say the opening and it's too short in GeekNights Then the music sounds weird.
Rym: if you come to cut it off right away And if you let it go on too long after that it also sounds weird because you said so little.
Scott: I'm sure there is a. This is a false dichotomy.
Scott: There is a. there is a third solution.
Rym: I think it just.
Rym: it's fine, and you're just weirdly oversensitive to things that you find corny.
Rym: We're not.
Rym: we're not doing the show on stool.
Rym: You laughed at that.
Scott: you left.
Scott: That's a Poop.
Scott: joke is like the opposite of corny unless of course there was corn in the poop which is a totally different situation.
Rym: So all that aside I realized you know we did the show last night, and there's an there's an anecdote in my life That is it's very rare that I ever have an opportunity to use it in any capacity Because the situation the setup for it basically can't happen anymore, and it's such a specific.
Rym: So I what are you talking about?
Rym: so in the last show we're talking about command and conquer and like RTS's and things right.
Rym: So when I had command and conquer this is this is a witty ball Mo from early Rym.
Rym: I was playing with my friend in high school And he was using the old 486 in our house And I had the Pentium Pro with a null modem between him.
Rym: now the Pentium Pro was fine But the 486 had a trouble where sometimes the mouse driver Which is freaked the fuck out and the mouse would go all over the place, and you couldn't do anything.
Rym: So we flipped coins.
Rym: he got the 486 and we started to play.
Rym: command and conquer.
Scott: Do you ever have a boot disk that was like mouse dot exe followed by the game?
Rym: Yep?
Rym: That's how I ran doom 2.
Rym: Okay, or sometimes I hold f5 to boot.
Rym: type mouse dot exe then type high mem then type mem maker then type doom 2 dot exe.
Rym: Sometimes I often would not load the sound card driver if I was playing multiplayer because it slowed me down too much.
Rym: So we're playing and in the middle of the game You know a game of command and conquer the mouse bugs out on him And there's no way to fix it short of reboot, so he says Rym what the fuck.
Rym: How am I supposed to play command and conquer if the shitty ass computer's mouse just breaks, and I said well I guess your only option is to conquer.
Rym: Since he couldn't command anymore I thought it was great And I had to get that out because I will rarely have times in my life where I can ever even get you like you Took the corny pills this morning.
Scott: I think that's what happened.
Rym: Well, we'll see this afternoon.
Rym: It's it's.
Scott: it's already like 6 p.m All right captain.
Rym: so what do you got for me in this Thursday front half of GeekNights?
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: It's so boring.
Rym: There's plenty of stuff on the internet.
Rym: You're just jaded.
Scott: There's nothing.
Scott: anyway I could tell you a weird story about the subway.
Rym: It doesn't involve a fat and/or crazy lady.
Scott: No, it was actually just one of those slightly weird situations.
Scott: You know we're standing on the subway I'm playing some game on my iPhone and suddenly a couple of people are like whoa whoa.
Rym: So there was.
Rym: there was a hubbub.
Scott: I turn around and like this you know I'm trying to figure out what's going on.
Scott: But apparently they're paying attention to this girl Who looks like she's just hugging this dude that she was with and I think they would.
Scott: those two people were talking when I got on the subway, so I was like uh But apparently like she had some seizure or something And she just like leaned on the guy and then she was better.
Scott: yeah, that's sort of thing gonna happen Yeah, but then it was all like the two people who were involved.
Scott: You know the the dude and the girl who like had the problem were all like making nothing of it.
Scott: They were like yeah, whatever and that some other people were like you should go the hospital, dude Probably and they're just like whatever.
Scott: It's all good.
Rym: I mean if they have a problem that they have under control then they probably know exactly what they need to do.
Rym: I'm sure this has happened to them before yeah But it's like.
Scott: you know she got off the subway and was all wobbly and it was just like uh It's really not a problem Are you sure?
Rym: well at least you know it does speak of New Yorkers and the whole people.
Rym: Despite the common perception of New York City people basically jump.
Rym: if there's any excuse for a hubbub to happen and for someone to be The good guy like a hundred people are jump on it.
Scott: It's pretty yeah, I mean, it's it's like people mind their own business Unless there's a problem in which case they want to fix it.
Scott: You know and the thing is quite often people are stupid like remember.
Scott: This is very similar story.
Rym: I think I know which one you're gonna train.
Rym: when the woman's like friend was having a heart attack or something She went to go pull the emergency brake.
Scott: No, no the one where you had like the weird guy who wouldn't tell what was wrong with the woman.
Rym: Oh, yeah Yeah, that was even worse.
Scott: Yeah, same kind of thing those were.
Rym: you know where the dude was?
Rym: just you know with a girl who was kind of moaning in Pain.
Rym: and then when someone asked him like hey, is she all right?
Rym: Do you need any help?
Rym: He was like man.
Rym: mind your business.
Rym: Just leave us alone.
Rym: mind your business Yeah, which immediately aroused the suspicion of everyone in the world And the guy just got more and more loud and angry the more people tried to help out.
Scott: This guy wasn't loud and angry.
Scott: They were just sort of quiet and like whatever, but it was still weird.
Rym: Yeah, well you know it brings me back to when we were in colony, and that's the biggest thing I miss about college.
Rym: isn't so much the clubs the hanging out or the infinite free time.
Rym: no responsibility I miss all those things But I miss living in a world where just random crazy bullshit will happen to you like you know coming home one day And there's just a couch out of fire in front of the door.
Scott: That was.
Scott: that was at night while we were sitting in our you know Apartment.
Rym: I remember the next morning when I go out And there's the skeletons of a couch out there because they hadn't gotten rid of it.
Scott: yet What did you think would be out there?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: maybe they'd moved it Maybe two couches.
Rym: what would have been funny if there was another couch unburned and the burn couch was gone Like a practical joke or maybe a Phoenix Phoenix couch.
Scott: So I think you know you know couch.
Rym: I Think it is worth noting at least that today was in fact the much controversial Draw Muhammad day or everybody draw Muhammad day Which seems to have drawn a Facebook group for it and an equally large Facebook group against it.
Rym: People in Pakistan lost their shit and Pakistan like banned face.
Scott: none of the other Muslim countries lost their shit I don't know.
Rym: I think.
Rym: one Pakistan is more Actually has internet.
Rym: Yeah, yeah that I think that's one big part of it and to Pakistan is probably not as good at covering up dissent as say Saudi Arabia or Iran.
Scott: Mmm, and three Pakistan was video of this lady driving a car in Saudi Arabia Which she's not allowed to do.
Scott: yeah, because she's you know has boobs and vagina.
Scott: Yeah, that is against law.
Rym: I also have boobs, but not having a vagina is key.
Scott: It's against the law there, but she did it anyway, and there's a video.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Rym: She just driving around like like you do at least like you should be able to do.
Rym: yeah, but also Pakistan I think a couple years ago banned YouTube for a while.
Scott: Yeah, didn't they break YouTube because someone fucked up the something something.
Rym: Yeah, there was all sorts of weirdness with Pakistan, but now this time they went crazy.
Rym: like they banned Twitter They banned blackberry.
Rym: apparently they were blocking blackberry messages into the country and all sorts of craziness at least until the end of the month to Prevent anyone from getting more angry about the fact that people in America and much of the rest of the world where people are free Are drawing pictures of Muhammad like hugging kittens and eating ice cream?
Rym: It's pretty epic though, I wish I would have had time But now that I have a real job where I can't just like BS around at work I wanted to make a Muhammad on the go much in the vein of Lord of the Rings on the go or Prince of Nothing On the go, but I didn't have time to make the seed picture.
Rym: so all of you out there Make Muhammad on the go.
Rym: you would make me so happy.
Scott: I think what disappoints me the most is that everyone draws Muhammad in sort of a stereotypical way.
Scott: It's always like a bearded.
Scott: You know you know Skin dark skinned guy with the turban.
Rym: I drew a dot and a cat all right that I called Muhammad.
Scott: So I mean people I want to see like like wasp businessman, and then it says Muhammad.
Scott: underneath I want to see like you know a little girl in a frilly tutu, and it says Muhammad.
Scott: That's what I want to see right.
Scott: I mean why everyone's just sort of you know at the one hand.
Scott: It's like aha We're getting their religion blah blah blah.
Scott: We you know we got them, but on the other hand We're just propagating this you know stereotype Which is sort of not.
Rym: well it depends.
Rym: I mean in the very least historically we have a good idea of the vagueness of what Muhammad would have looked like.
Scott: yeah Cuz you know Jesus looks a lot like the pictures of Jesus people draw are a lot like what Jesus looked like.
Rym: Well the thing is there are there have been pictures of Jesus continuously And they're all influenced heavily by Byzantine art and all that stuff.
Rym: so we lease we know the artistic progression of like kind of.
Rym: why That fictional characters portrayed that way.
Rym: But with Muhammad like some I mean the problem is some people are just drawing like turban guy.
Scott: Yeah, but I wonder like what if I draw Muhammad?
Scott: right, but it's not the Muhammad It's just this guy.
Scott: I know his name is Muhammad.
Scott: He works at the bodega.
Rym: well What is another prejudice stereotype?
Rym: what I should do is take a picture of Muhammad Ali and say I assert that Muhammad Ali is in fact the reincarnation of the Prophet Muhammad who looks identical to him.
Scott: I could just draw Muhammad Ali and then be like aha lol yeah.
Scott: Or what if I draw right?
Scott: like you know the the the wasp businessman a little girl in a tutu right with boxing gloves and I say Muhammad parentheses Ali.
Rym: It's interesting how this you know.
Rym: the mainstream media talking about this They didn't have a lot to say.
Rym: they mostly focused on the fact that Pakistan lost their shit and the controversy surrounding it.
Rym: this Holiday really only existed on the internet where it's a big deal, and I have a feeling it's going to happen every year henceforth.
Scott: Yeah, just right next to talk like a pirate day.
Scott: Yeah, maybe we should have talked like Muhammad day.
Rym: What would you say?
Rym: how about dress like Muhammad day?
Scott: I Would be.
Scott: I would just wear my normal clothes and be like hey How do we know mom?
Scott: it didn't have awesome geeky t-shirt?
Rym: What is interesting is that it's kind of dressing like my friend Muhammad.
Scott: He works at the company on the next floor.
Scott: He's also a programmer.
Rym: this can almost be used.
Rym: It's gonna cut a lot of cool people off the internet But it's sort of a litmus test of whether or not you can actually engage in a free society.
Rym: Because look if the nations where people are so angry about it block all the means of free exchange where these pictures might appear They're basically cutting themselves off from what is the internet?
Rym: And I wonder what the consequences of that are going to be 10 or 15 years down the road.
Rym: if so
Scott: if we if the free Countries just continually to freely express themselves, and they keep doing it a whole bunch and not
Rym: just this but
Scott: The non free countries will will just keep having being forced to basically you know they won't be able to filter They'll be forced to completely cut themselves off And we'll like split the world into the free world and non free world and the divide will grow.
Rym: I mean, I think that's the way to go with China especially I mean Google took the first step.
Rym: But imagine if bit by bit no no outside entity in the world would kowtow to China's censorship demands.
Scott: They wouldn't have an internet.
Scott: They would have intranet of China.
Rym: Yep, now the thing is China scarily is at least technically competent enough to have a reasonably workable national firewall Which is kind of sad, but that's cuz Cisco did it for them.
Scott: It wasn't China being smart It was paid someone you know a zillion dollars to do it.
Rym: So I don't know it.
Rym: I just it was worth mentioning.
Rym: I don't want to turn the whole show into a Muhammad show though I will note right now that if you're watching the you stream that is not in fact Rym and Scott But it is the exact representation of Muhammad sitting next to Muhammad Talking into microphones.
Rym: Oh, and I'm drinking alcohol.
Scott: I think we need you know.
Scott: I mean the you stream is awesome and everything and it's it's helping us out and more people are Watching it, but I want to.
Scott: I don't want to interact with it.
Rym: cuz then it's like we're never You know.
Scott: because it's like.
Scott: then the people who most people isn't the podcast just that doesn't.
Scott: it's not good for them.
Scott: It's the same way.
Scott: I don't like to do stuff that Acknowledges the community or the forum or anything.
Scott: cuz then people most people aren't in that.
Scott: so if they listen to the show and we Do that all the time it really makes them outsiders.
Scott: I guess some of them will you know take that as a clue and join in but most of them will just be like turned Away, well one way to handle that.
Rym: I guess you know it's Thursday.
Rym: We talk about whatever we want instead of you know sequestering it all in the meta moment.
Rym: I feel like the best way to handle that.
Rym: if you have the you know the resources to make all the media you want to Make is to have your real thing.
Rym: You know like GeekNights the show and then independently you have like one other show that is the community show that's focused at those people.
Rym: Yeah, well, I mean this is what stack like if we did the couch Which is the video of us hanging out on the couch?
Scott: This is what Stack Overflow learned right is they made Stack Overflow and the thing was is a lot of people would make post questions on Stack Overflow about Stack Overflow.
Scott: They'd be like should Stack Overflow Changed this to work this way.
Scott: right and the thing is people who come to Stack Overflow itself.
Scott: They're not supposed to be talking about Stack Overflow.
Scott: They're coming to get help with their technical problem.
Scott: So eventually they made meta that Stack Overflow Which is a Stack Overflow for Stack Overflow and nothing else right to talk about.
Scott: it's that right and?
Scott: Keeping the meta separate from the actual thing is incredibly important because the meta 99% people don't care about that.
Scott: yeah I mean like all our listeners who are in the put it in the face of the people who don't care about it at all.
Scott: Right then it really makes your thing shittier.
Rym: There has to be a big separation between the meta and the thing which is also kind of a shout-out now to all of you Listeners who aren't in our.
Rym: you know the GeekNights community in the forum and all that BS.
Rym: because you know our Hardcore listeners the ones that hang out in our forums always ask us things like why didn't you do a show on X?
Rym: You know we all want a show on X And they'll all talk about like do this do this do this do that.
Rym: But the emails we get from all you guys and the interaction with them like the majority of the listeners is Very different from them and you guys want very different things.
Rym: as far as I can tell.
Scott: Yeah, you know you see the same pattern over and over again like uh you know people on the internet They complain about X. You know, but 99% of the people don't say anything and you know what they want the opposite of X. or You know everyone says oh Nintendo do this, but what sells you like we fit which nobody wanted right?
Rym: We fits not a bad game the thing is what bothers me about it.
Rym: The only thing that bothers me about it is that DDR is a much better exercise platform.
Scott: It's not about real exercise about pretend to exercise.
Scott: you wouldn't be able to sell real exercise.
Scott: It wouldn't be fun.
Scott: It would hurt the fat people.
Scott: Plus you know DDR is not accessible.
Scott: It's very difficult.
Rym: Yeah, it always amazing.
Scott: anyone can do.
Rym: step on the things I always kind of forget.
Rym: You know we've been playing DDR for like a decade and yet You know like Emily's playing DDR again now that we've got to set up in the apartment and everything and you know watching her learn and progress like through like a one foot to a two foot to a three foot to a four foot and Reminded me of how much of my life.
Rym: I kind of invested in DDR.
Scott: It's it's how much you fell under the spell of DDR.
Scott: you allowed the computer to infect your brain.
Rym: Well regardless your body in one way or another I spent a scary amount of time mastering that skill.
Scott: Yeah anyway, yeah.
Scott: So I want to talk about.
Scott: so I get there's so much tech stuff going on especially with the Google I/o that I got to offload some of it to today.
Rym: Oh, no it is Thursday.
Rym: Well.
Rym: You know affectionately I like to call Thursday the lounge.
Rym: whatever like that whatever.
Rym: that thinks everything's corny.
Scott: You're being real corny.
Scott: right now I can tell you that you're being like ultra corny.
Scott: So there's this problem.
Scott: that was basically the problem of Google accounts that has existed for a long time And it goes something like this right you have a Google account.
Scott: It's your you know.
Scott: use it for Gmail use it for reader use it for wave use it for everything.
Scott: That's Google all right, and then you have Google apps.
Scott: because you don't want your email address to be at gmail.com You want it to be at your own domain.com, so you get Google app which is still already.
Rym: That's the minority of.
Scott: yeah, Google apps is meant for schools or offices.
Scott: right can get their own private Google So they can use all the Google stuff, but it's their own right.
Scott: so we have one of those.
Scott: It's totally sweet, and you get.
Scott: you know.
Scott: you get You know mail and Doc's and calendar and all you know all the good stuff is in there.
Rym: I mean like all the front row crew.
Rym: people have front row crew email address.
Scott: the problem Is is right like I'll go and I'll try to use like some Android phone or something and it'll be like yeah You want to use Google latitude.
Scott: give us your Google account, and I can't use my apps account.
Scott: I got to use the regular one.
Rym: a couple of things were smart now.
Scott: I got two accounts.
Scott: It's like ah fuck me.
Rym: Yeah, a couple of things were smart and if I put in the full address with the at they would figure it out.
Rym: But most things would not.
Rym: especially Google made things yeah like Google reader.
Scott: You can't use my app.
Scott: good.
Scott: There's no reader in apps right.
Scott: all we want is to be able to use our Google apps Account with all the Google stuff And I won't need a regular Google.
Rym: is I got to get rid of my old gmail account?
Scott: even stuff like feed burner or Google Analytics or ad.
Scott: where to be YouTube yeah?
Scott: I gotta have like these separate account.
Rym: our YouTube is associated with some bullshit account that I made a long time ago to set up YouTube.
Scott: yeah, so I think they've made some progress in fixing it.
Scott: for example They just added wave rights now.
Scott: We have you know we got front-row crew wave But from what I can tell front-row crew wave is just wave and I can totally it.
Scott: totally you know mixes in with the actual Wave.
Scott: just fine, so I never need to use the other account on wave.
Scott: I can use my front-row crew account on wave and it's all good, and I logged into something else I think it might have been calendar or Docs And it said which account do you want to use?
Scott: and it said this one or the front-row crew one?
Scott: And I was like oh my God I've never seen this before.
Scott: so I think there they might be Spreading that out across the board, and I hope that I can one day like try to use.
Scott: you know Google I don't know feed burner And it'll say which account you're actually what I really want to use.
Rym: I want to wait.
Rym: I want to talk about this a lot on Monday.
Rym: Is that Google predictive engine Google voice Google latitude Google Google predictive that I really want access to that, but they're not going to give it to me.
Rym: I'm a terrible coder.
Scott: Well, you can just get it right.
Rym: I mean no there.
Rym: It's right now.
Rym: It's super invite only and it's kind of like you know.
Rym: propose like what do you want to do with it?
Scott: And I don't know what are you gonna do with it?
Rym: I got some ideas.
Rym: basically I want to put in stock market data and see what it predicts in a black box Whatever that.
Rym: and I want to put in listener.
Rym: I want to put in basically listener numbers from GeekNights right because I can Export that from the feed burner and the libsyn and everything and I want to compare it to The titles of the episodes and the text of the thing and see if there any weird correlations.
Scott: Mmm.
Scott: That's not a bad idea.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: I want to just do cool stuff like that.
Rym: I mean, it's just an API.
Rym: I can write little Python apps to like interact with it, but we'll see.
Rym: maybe I'll get in.
Rym: So to get back on track.
Rym: I think we're derailing a little bit things of the day.
Rym: I tried to say that as corny as possible.
Scott: Are you trying to be corny gray?
Rym: Yeah now I am.
Scott: You know like I have to in response to your anti corn You want to read some some like Marvel two-in-one?
Scott: 80s and 70s and whatever.
Rym: so you got a thing of the day for me because I got something pretty amazing here.
Scott: Yeah, I just want to you know, I couldn't really find an awesome thing a day.
Scott: But I just want to you know remind people that in the California far away from here All right.
Scott: this weekend May 22 and 23 is the Maker Faire Which is you know, always the awesome.
Scott: if you want to see Shit people made in you know, the Arduino.
Scott: is it full of corn?
Scott: make magazine boing boing kind of style Of making stuff.
Scott: then you want to go to the Maker Faire.
Scott: It's in San Mateo County event center from 10 to 8 on Saturday and 10 to 6 on Sunday.
Rym: It is funny how that kind of really does define a genre of making.
Scott: This is like the one kind of thing that we don't have here, right?
Scott: It's like we've got comic cons, you know, even though San Diego's out west we got New York.
Scott: We got some other ones, right?
Scott: We got anime cons.
Scott: We go to con.
Scott: we got gaming.
Scott: now that we got PAX East and such We don't have like a Maker Faire in the east or things like burning.
Scott: Oh, no way.
Scott: It says world Maker Faire, New York City 2010.
Scott: Wait, I gotta go look at this.
Scott: Whoa, wait, okay September 25 and 26 at New York Hall of Science.
Scott: Oh crap.
Scott: I guess we're going to that.
Scott: Yeah, there's a double thing of the day.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: When is The New York comic-con.
Rym: I think it's October.
Scott: It's October, okay, it's soon after the world Maker Faire, but okay, we're going to the world Maker Faire, New York City 2010.
Rym: so In Philadelphia an event happened that will basically settle anytime you ever argue like, you know I'm from Detroit and the cops are real hardcore there now.
Rym: I'm from LA.
Rym: the cops like we'll just beat you up for nothing there.
Scott: Well, no, what do you mean?
Scott: We're not.
Scott: we don't care how how tough the cops are.
Scott: we care how disgusting the people are and we know that in Things Philadelphia has the most disgusting thing.
Rym: Uh, I would take issue with that.
Scott: Who do you think is more disgusting Oakland?
Scott: What's wrong with Oakland?
Rym: the Raiders mostly.
Scott: so that's it.
Rym: so anyway Philadelphia actually wins this fight because there was a situation and this is my thing of the day Just the whole.
Rym: you can read the entire story.
Rym: I will summarize it.
Rym: There's a group of people who are members of an organization that they called move.
Rym: in the end of the 70s a bunch of them were arrested after a shootout that ended with a police officer dying and nine of them went to jail.
Rym: and the ones who didn't go to jail moved to Philadelphia moved to her neighborhood bought a house and Preceded to be jackasses.
Rym: They fortified it.
Rym: they stocked up supplies.
Rym: They had loudspeakers that 24/7 played weird like anarchist propaganda.
Rym: They built like steel bunkers on the roof and Basically the stench from this place coupled with the severe health hazard and the rats and everything what was coming to a head Mmm, so Philadelphia police went to deal with that.
Rym: I'm gonna fast-forward through the part that you can read on Wikipedia.
Rym: They bombed the entire city block.
Rym: Everything burned down.
Scott: they fucking way with an airplane that had a bomb that falling out of it.
Scott: So they basically they just walked in.
Rym: they put a bomb on the ground and wine trouble Evacuated the entire city block the night before saying yeah take a change of clothes We're gonna get rid of those jerks and then you can come back in the morning you know the next day.
Rym: and then there was a shootout and During this a police helicopter or something like that with a guy who had made a bomb officially out of c4 a large amount of c4 a Surprising amount of c4.
Scott: they don't take that much at c4.
Rym: They dropped it on top of the building to blow up the bunkers so they could then finish the gunfight.
Rym: The bomb blew up much of the building and set the rest of it on fire.
Rym: The fire spread to the entire city block.
Scott: So the bomb wasn't.
Scott: they didn't make a bomb.
Scott: That was too big.
Rym: So the bomb was too big.
Scott: the fire was too big.
Scott: The bomb was also too big But the explosion isn't what got the rest of the block.
Rym: It was the fire no, but yeah, yes, but the explosion spread.
Rym: the fire caused the fire and Despite all the fire department hanging out right there So the fire department tried to fight the fire and the people inside kept shooting at them.
Rym: Oh so I.
Scott: Why didn't they use poison gas right with poison?
Rym: Yeah, they already fired tear gas at the building.
Rym: That's not.
Scott: I mean poison gas like you're right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean you're shooting at them.
Rym: You're already children in there.
Scott: You're already shooting at them.
Scott: You're already trying to murder the women and children.
Scott: I murdered them too, right?
Scott: Least with the poison gas you would do the same amount of murdering but you wouldn't burn down the whole block.
Rym: Basically what it came down to is this was the most over-handed Inept police respect, you know people talk about like Waco and what was good what was bad and you know the catastrophe there or a Ruby Ridge.
Rym: This one takes the keg.
Rym: This is just police and civil servants Dealing with the situation in perhaps the worst Possible way and it ended up in just disaster.
Scott: and it I mean they could have like thrown like if they just wanted to set It on fire.
Scott: They could have just thrown like one molotov over there.
Rym: They could have just waited.
Rym: They didn't have that much food in there.
Scott: I thought you said that they stocked up.
Rym: Yeah, but not enough they could have.
Rym: they could have.
Rym: it would have been cheaper to just surround the place.
Scott: Keep it.
Scott: Well, I assume they cut off the water and the electricity, right?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I mean you cut off the water and it's only a matter of time.
Rym: cut off water cut off electricity Tear gas constantly and terrible music.
Scott: Oh, and if they have a well though, you had to like poison it or something.
Rym: I'm sure they could have dealt with the well or special forces or something.
Rym: This is amazing and you should read the entire story of this.
Rym: and it gets worse.
Rym: the city Rebuilt the whole block for all the people who got kicked out With some of the most shoddily put together houses the world has ever seen to this day.
Rym: That neighborhood is a festering disaster.
Scott: We should go to that neighborhood just to be lol.
Rym: The story that the multi decade-long story of this debacle is an amazing thing to read about Mmm, so that is my thing of the day.
Rym: So the meta moment.
Rym: next Thursday's show which is two Thursdays from now, we will be doing the GeekNights book club cosmos.
Scott: Oh shit, Carl Sagan's cosmo had a lot of time to read this people a lot of time.
Scott: If you care at all about science about humanity about astronomy If you're a human being and you're listening to this show and you didn't read the book you suck.
Rym: It's one of the more important books ever.
Rym: read it.
Scott: I wouldn't say that.
Rym: I would say that because it got an entire generation of American scientists a world Scientists into science.
Rym: it spawned a generation that I don't think we have an equivalent.
Scott: No, it's no Shakespeare It's no Out there in importance, I mean, you know, it's.
Scott: it's not any more important than earlier.
Rym: best-selling book Well, but best selling.
Rym: in what regard?
Rym: I mean New York Times bestseller.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's a best seller.
Scott: Who knows what that here's?
Scott: a lot of books are best-selling.
Rym: Also meta probably the last time we're gonna mention this there's a you stream.
Scott: if you want to watch the show live Yeah, also where you know the website front recruit calm.
Scott: I know that none of you visited.
Scott: I'm gonna do some stuff to it to try to make it so that you visit it.
Rym: Archives of the you streamer there.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you should You know, I hope people like send in suggestions.
Scott: just email us, you know GeekNights of our crew calm with.
Scott: you know What would?
Scott: what could be possibly put on the site that would make you go there as opposed to just you know Only going to your iTunes and that other than pornography You can go to other sites for pornography, you know, I mean we're looking for some good ideas.
Scott: what would make you go to the website every day and So tell me and or at least not once in a while, of course along those lines We're not.
Rym: I mean, do you want to talk about the wave you gonna wait?
Rym: hmm, if you got basically if anyone out there wants to Collaboratively help us make show notes and things just you know, we're gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna start doing all that kind of stuff.
Scott: Yeah, the site is gonna have a lot more stuff.
Scott: I got some ideas, but I need other ideas.
Rym: We got a pipe and a hopper and the hoppers is coming along more than you'd expect except Rym's hopper Which he just shit talks.
Rym: My hopper is basically completely clogged until Connecticut happens.
Rym: Yeah, you're just at least until the schedule goes to print.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, so so bread bread.
Rym: Oh, man You guys definitely people.
Scott: there's the two things people ask for right our food shows and zombie shows.
Scott: and the zombie shows are never gonna happen.
Scott: It's never.
Scott: but you know food shows.
Scott: we thought the food shows are played out But you know what we'll give you is by the last food show ever at least for a while.
Scott: Yep But anyway, we'll talk about bread.
Rym: Bread is in fact a staple food prepared by cooking a dough of flour and water and possibly more Ingredients.
Scott: Rym said that he was gonna read Wikipedia whenever he had nothing to say.
Scott: So now here he goes.
Rym: It is amazing.
Rym: what if you ever get really bored find a Wikipedia article on something just so basic like bread or walking.
Rym: and It is interesting to read a very deep discussion of something so simple and kind of the weird Associated facts and just sentences you would never expect to see in the rest of your life.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: The thing is let's talk about some breads, right?
Scott: It's a bread your favorite bread Scott.
Rym: if you had to pick right now one bread with you had to pick one bread right now.
Rym: Oh, I don't know.
Scott: I can't pick one bread.
Scott: That's impossible.
Rym: I think I would just have to go with some sort of like peasant bread.
Scott: It depends on what you need right like.
Scott: if I need a sandwich right like a big long sandwich I got to get that de Bellas bread, but if I need like, you know Sandwich right then I got to get my home pride, but if I need to Get some pastrami you need some Jewish right?
Scott: I need like.
Scott: yeah, I need like a ride.
Rym: Maybe a marble rye.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's a different bread for a different time, you know.
Scott: and to stain You know, maybe I need a garlic bread.
Scott: Maybe I need You know a bread, you know, if I'm having a burger I need like a bun with all sorts of sesame seeds all over it.
Scott: But if I get in a bagel, I might need everything bagel.
Scott: I need all kinds, you know And it's each variety of bagel a different bread.
Scott: or is bagel a bread?
Scott: bagel is a bread But everything bagel is not a different bread.
Rym: Bagel, you know, I think the toppings of a bread are independent of the bread itself.
Scott: So two different rise, right?
Scott: So it's not two different kinds of bread.
Rym: I think a rye is rye.
Rym: now there's different grades of rye.
Rym: I mean at the top is like but I mean you got.
Scott: you got rye with seeds.
Scott: you got rye without seeds.
Scott: You got rye with like that.
Scott: They had a rye at the store.
Scott: They like a euro rye rye, which wasn't real pumpernickel and then they had real pumpernickel rye and then marble rye.
Scott: You know, I mean those different bread.
Rym: Yeah, cuz they all have different constituent elements But they're all under the subset of rye.
Scott: but but everything.
Scott: bagel and garlic and garlic bagel and onion.
Rym: Well when you when you make a seeded rye you put the seeds in as an intrinsic part of making the bread When you make everything bagel, you kind of add them to the already effectively bagel bagel.
Rym: What if you got?
Scott: Raisin bagel that are actually is.
Scott: there's something in the bread now that's different cuz it's mixed in our whole grain bagel.
Rym: I don't know about whole grain bagels.
Rym: That's some bullshit right there.
Scott: You know, you got it in free.
Rym: go to subway.
Scott: They give you like five choices.
Rym: There's no breaded subway.
Rym: Yeah, there is Bread.
Rym: That is a bread like substance.
Scott: No, see, I mean Taco Bell.
Scott: you could say that that is a Mexican food was the last time you ate at a subway Quite recently.
Rym: when cuz I ate at a subway a couple days ago cuz I was desperate and I was in a hurry.
Scott: I was in Brooklyn a couple months ago.
Scott: I had a subway that bread just and actually know it.
Scott: I'm feeling like going to subway right now after the show.
Scott: Really?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I just feel like it.
Scott: Ah What do you mean?
Rym: Uh, it's just.
Rym: it's so I'd all Wonder bread is below subway bread.
Scott: Okay, that's true.
Rym: I think what's ruined me is I have a very skewed perspective on bread now.
Rym: But right by the way is probably the most important food to be like.
Rym: I eat more bread than anything.
Scott: Yeah, I know right and the thing is like I eat more bread than anything But it's also even in the city.
Scott: It's like hard to get.
Scott: you got to go like the place.
Rym: What are you got?
Rym: Well, maybe just cuz I work across from Grand Central I go to the hot and crusty.
Rym: the hot and crusty is great or I go to the Grand Central Market.
Rym: There's even more bread in there.
Scott: Yeah, but there's also sorrows.
Scott: if you really want some shitty bread Overpriced shitty bread, but I mean, you know, it's hard, you know, there's places that have breads But it's hard to find the exact breads that I want at.
Rym: you know, like what bread do you want?
Scott: Like I can't find a good rye bread that's fresh near me, you know hot and crusty has it Yeah, but nowhere near me.
Scott: Can I or near my work or near my apartment?
Scott: Can I find or near your apartment?
Scott: Can I find the good you're in a story?
Rym: There's got to be a Jewish bakery around.
Scott: Trying to find what I'm going to all these different places.
Scott: I haven't found one yet.
Scott: I gotta keep I'm keeping looking but across the street from you.
Rym: There is that Greek bakery, but they don't got rye No, but they got that good Greek bread and they're not the bread.
Scott: I want I'm looking for.
Rym: they got a panda campagna.
Scott: I'm looking for like a challah.
Scott: Where can I get one?
Rym: They got.
Scott: you bought something else you can get at the hot and crusty that I can't get anywhere.
Scott: You know, I gotta go find a place in the places that have them.
Scott: There's plenty of them.
Rym: You know the other way around this.
Scott: they're not near me and they're not near my work.
Rym: The other way around.
Rym: this is fresh direct.
Rym: They'll just deliver fresh bread to you.
Scott: Yeah, but what do they have?
Scott: a good rye bread?
Rym: Yeah, I think so I haven't gotten it from them because I buy bread fresh from bakers right there next to my work.
Rym: Yeah, but one place the hot and crusty which also there's two other bread places not counting the shitty sorrows in Grand Central Market.
Scott: So you're at one place.
Scott: basically that's far away from me.
Rym: Yeah Of my way, it's right next to me.
Rym: So screw you.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, I could go down to Brooklyn to like the Jewish whatever Scott.
Rym: Don't you bike home you go past?
Rym: Grand Central, oh, I don't not at all.
Scott: I'm up on 49th Street All right, I'm seven blocks north and then the bridge is even more north.
Scott: I'm not going south seven blocks then going back up north, you know, not even not even for fresh bread.
Rym: I'll go way out of my way for fresh bread.
Rym: Plus.
Rym: also next to me is the Zaya.
Rym: I can get the the sweet Japanese white bread that I love so much Bread too, but it's also.
Rym: I can also get the bread like things.
Rym: I can get a melon pan.
Rym: It's far out of my way, you know what that sucks.
Rym: I'm just saying you know what that sucks.
Scott: There are no you do.
Rym: you chose poorly in your place of work in your place of living.
Scott: there are.
Scott: there is like.
Scott: No, like if I was having a dinner and I needed like, you know Like a bread to go with the dinner depending on what the dinner was.
Scott: They got that kind of bread.
Scott: They got that bread, but they don't got like the everyday bread.
Scott: You know the bread that you keep there and slowly eat away and then replace when it is done.
Scott: see they don't got that.
Rym: I don't you the only.
Rym: I don't very rarely get bread like that anymore.
Rym: I basically every time I want bread I buy a fresh bread with it by the second day.
Rym: It's all eaten Mm-hmm.
Rym: So it's always fresh bread.
Scott: I don't need that much bread.
Scott: I like four slices a day.
Rym: I mean, I'll come home from work You know, I want a little repent a little snack before we do the show before we do stuff.
Rym: So I'll basically cut like a couple of pieces of fancy like nice bread and I'll cut up some cheese Get some olives some nuts for that and eat all that together.
Rym: So I'll eat like three or four slices of bread every day.
Scott: when there's bread I'll eat like, you know that and it's not just hanging out of my mouth in the morning.
Rym: if there's bread I'm gonna make that like garlic bread or something with dinner.
Rym: That's just obvious I don't know.
Scott: I'll eat like, you know, the the Sutton coming out of my you know, a piece of toast.
Rym: Actually what I'll do a lot too is the toppings on the bread I'll take like one of those peasant style, you know Like the big round white like kind of doughy open bread like you had an Italian restaurant.
Rym: I'll do the the olive garden or the macaroni grill thing or I guess the Italian thing.
Rym: you put the olive oil and the pepper And the vinegar on a little plate.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: I'll have the piece of toast hanging out of my mouth in the morning and then you know on the way home You know when I get home, maybe I'll eat something a little bit more bread and then I have a sandwich for lunch at work.
Scott: You know, it comes on some breads, but that's pretty much it.
Scott: I don't you know, I don't eat, you know vast quantities I eat, you know the correct amount Quality fairly vast quantities of bread.
Scott: then compared to you you do I think you need vast quantities of bread compared to most people.
Rym: People showed him you supposed to see what.
Rym: like 11 servings of grains per day.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean I eat lots of grains that are not bread like what like a melba toast That's a bread or a corn chip.
Rym: Do crackers count.
Scott: Yeah, of course, you know He's a bowl of cereal, you know, all these things are grains but are not.
Scott: you know bread straight up.
Rym: So I actually don't eat many of those things except crackers.
Scott: Oh, see I eat lots of things that are grains but are not.
Rym: I don't eat cereal because I can't stay.
Scott: no bread.
Rym: I just can't drink milk Like cheese.
Rym: you're supposed I like milk in things like god.
Rym: well coffee effectively, but I don't like just milk.
Scott: You got a dry cereal.
Scott: It's just like bar.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I usually eat cereal dry.
Rym: I'll get like granola or something.
Rym: Just put it in a cup and just drink it.
Rym: Yeah, you drink you just drink Into my mouth, I mean why dirty a spoon?
Scott: Well, I mean you could just get a granola bar.
Scott: in that case Why no granola bars are so fucking dry.
Rym: every granola bar I find is either moist and juicy in that fake way that I can't deal with anymore.
Rym: It's the same moistness that you get in like a Twinkie.
Scott: No, the moistness of a Twinkie is different from like the kudos bar.
Rym: Yeah, the kudos bar still feels like weird to me.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I like the kudos bar because I like chocolate or or the the The what's the name?
Scott: the captain the the oatmeal guy the chewy bars.
Rym: Those are good Yeah, but they still.
Rym: they feel weird to me compared to fresh granola, which is not dry ass But it's not wet either just kind of in between.
Rym: I can't stand those dry bars Like the nature's harvest whatever.
Scott: Oh God there that stuff.
Scott: I can't eat.
Rym: They basically just cut my throat all the way down.
Scott: Yeah, too scratchy.
Scott: and you know, I gotta have the chew with this chewy ones.
Scott: But I could see I do know the fake chewy like the cupcake with the white swirl on top, right?
Scott: Yeah, that's that fake, you know, okay, that's that preservative mushiness That's just discussed.
Scott: when I was a kid.
Rym: My favorite thing in the world was the orange version of that Cuz there's the chocolate one that all of normal kids ate.
Rym: then I had the orange one.
Rym: This day I could not tell you what that flavor was.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: It was not orange nor was it vanilla at RIT.
Scott: I ate like the you know, fake preservative donuts and Cupcakes a couple times.
Scott: I never had a vending machine when I was desperate for like something that actually had weight to it.
Rym: So I never ate those.
Rym: but what I would eat is Krispy Kremes in explicable.
Scott: I ate all those a whole bunch too.
Scott: Is there any?
Scott: there's got to be one in the city somewhere right I did.
Rym: Krispy Kreme is shit.
Rym: No, it's only good at RIT cuz we were poor.
Rym: There's a lot of calories in those things.
Rym: Those are some shit-ass.
Scott: no No, they're awesome.
Scott: They're terrible.
Scott: No, they're amazing.
Rym: They're terrible donuts.
Rym: Why do you think the company is doing terribly?
Scott: Because they've screwed up business-wise not because there was anything wrong with the product.
Rym: Those are not donuts.
Scott: They're just you and your donut, whatever.
Scott: Nobody agrees with you.
Rym: What do you think a real donut is fried dough from a baker?
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: Listen, most people they like the kind of donuts that you don't like.
Rym: Yeah, I know but that day if you if you want to eat some weird at like, you know The things Dunkin Donuts makes you're fine too, but that's that's some bad stuff.
Scott: It's awesome.
Rym: I don't know how you can eat that stone and Dunkin Donuts.
Scott: bagel hover on the other hand is the worst bagel in The entire universe.
Scott: I don't know anyone eats that bagel Like.
Scott: I'll eat those like I've.
Scott: you know.
Scott: bagel from the grocery store is it can actually be pretty damn good.
Rym: Bagel from Dunkin Donuts is like oh god I mean to me like a real donut.
Rym: like take a cider donut.
Rym: that is a form of a real donut.
Scott: cider donuts.
Rym: a donut It is but it's a special kind of what is a normal donut You know makes it good donuts a glazed donut from Krispy Kreme.
Rym: You know what top-hot donuts are real fucking donuts.
Scott: You know Krispy Kreme also a donut.
Rym: Nah, it's not a donut.
Scott: Krispy Kreme is a donut.
Scott: You're making like a No True Scotsman argument.
Scott: You're just done.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: Go look at the definition of a donut and how to make one and look at how Krispy Kreme makes a donut.
Scott: You're done.
Rym: Krispy Kreme is a donut in the same way.
Rym: No True Scotsman game over Scott, Krispy Kreme is a donut in the same way that Taco Bell is a taco, but it's not.
Rym: well How not?
Scott: no true Scotsman no true taco Because the Taco Bell does not actually contain what is required by the definition of taco.
Rym: What is the definition of a taco?
Rym: What is not in a Taco Bell taco, it's fun to say there's no meat in but you know what there's meat?
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: That's me.
Scott: It's not.
Rym: it's better meat in there than there isn't a Burger King.
Scott: It's soy It's it's not.
Scott: there's no actual meats.
Scott: The percentage of meat is not high enough.
Scott: You can measure.
Scott: you can measure with a ruler.
Rym: Wait, you just went from no meat to small amount of meat.
Rym: You're slipping.
Rym: Well, I mean there might be Yours clearly committing the no true taco fallacy.
Scott: Well, I mean how much grain does it I mean?
Scott: is a bread still a bread if it has like corn syrup in it?
Rym: Well, I guess we have to go by the definition of bread.
Rym: So to go back to Wikipedia bread is a staple food prepared by cooking a dough.
Scott: Nothing's bread because there are definitely no staples in the bread that I eat.
Scott: I don't know if you got some swing line in your bread by cooking a dough of flour and water.
Scott: So what if?
Scott: so if you make it with corn chip is not bread.
Scott: No, so what if I make corn bread?
Rym: No, no corn flour corn bread is not flour.
Rym: You're fine.
Scott: So it has to be flour of some grain.
Rym: So yes, but if I flour flour is a powder made of cereal grains other seeds or so What roots?
Scott: or seeds or roots?
Scott: so it has to be milled?
Scott: Yes, you actually have to mill the grain.
Rym: So if you whole grain bread is not bread because there's no flour, you know, cuz they know the whole not Scott they're not just using the whole grains.
Rym: if they were doing that it wouldn't be bread.
Rym: It's mostly milled grains and they leave some of them unmilled which is fine in all these definitions.
Scott: So the breads that say 100% whole grain are false advertising.
Rym: Well, the whole grain also matters whether or not they leave like the husk on whether or not they leave the germ in there.
Rym: There's all sorts of stuff.
Scott: I don't know enough about grains really except they taste good.
Rym: I mean great.
Rym: We do not know if it was beer or bread that came first But beer or bread according to a lot of people is the absolute origin of human society and settlement.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much we couldn't have that until we invented one of the two.
Rym: beer probably came first At least from the things I've read but those could be biased.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Oh Apparently bread should be stored in a container such as a bread box.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: I don't store my bread in a container.
Scott: I just sort of leave it in the plastic bag and make sure it's tied up.
Rym: Uh, I actually put it in the bag, but then I put it in a small cabinet.
Rym: that functions much like a bread box.
Scott: Mmm, why?
Scott: why do you need to store your bread in a bread box?
Rym: Less chance of contamination by what other bread mold?
Scott: You know bread just gets moldy no matter what I do with that.
Scott: my bread doesn't you know, it takes You know, the thing is it but by the time it gets moldy, you know If it gets moldy, it's been there for a long time and it's usually because I want to.
Rym: I will differentiate.
Rym: there are two completely different kinds of bread thing.
Scott: Is that looking at you're like, oh my bread doesn't get moldy.
Scott: Yeah, well you eat the bread.
Scott: You need a half a loaf.
Rym: That's what I'm saying to bread.
Rym: I don't buy pre sliced bread.
Rym: Uh-huh ever I buy loaves of bread and I use that ugly knife to cut slices every time I want them.
Scott: See I We got to talk about the knife in a second But I like to buy a pre sliced bread depending on the kind of bread You know like the only see.
Rym: even I learned at the Zaya.
Rym: They don't make that many of them but that fancy the bread I get the sugar bread the white bread.
Rym: You can get that on slice and on sliced bread like like a rye bread.
Scott: I try to slice the rye bread with a knife.
Scott: that slices come out too thick.
Rym: Get a bread mitre a mitre.
Scott: Yeah, what the hell is that?
Rym: You've obviously never done woodworking.
Scott: I don't think you have.
Rym: I don't have one because I can cut fucking straight.
Scott: But if you can't cut all the slices it perfectly.
Scott: every slice of rye bread when you go through that machine is like exactly like One centimeter.
Rym: So if you really can't do that and you want to have the perfect bread just get a bread mitre.
Scott: The other thing is that when I cut the bread right with a knife you make a mad crumbs fucking everywhere.
Scott: All right, and if I let them pre slice the bread crummage not an issue.
Scott: So I like to keep the crummage to a minimum and get the pre slice bread depending on the kind of bread You know I realize people might be thinking I'm talking about the hats.
Rym: a Mitre is basically a box and use a special saw in it that has slots to make sure you cut things in the exact right Positions.
Scott: see I can cut the you know straight up and down.
Scott: The problem is cutting exactly one centimeters with.
Scott: so that's why I guess I'm having the bread, you know Be it takes care of that situation.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: We got to talk about the knife.
Scott: So this is knife.
Scott: What's the find the exact name of the knife?
Rym: Oh, yeah, I'll look it up.
Rym: you talk about.
Scott: it's this yellow knife.
Scott: It looks.
Scott: you look at this knife and it looks like the kind of thing that being grandma's kitchen Like.
Scott: it's all ugly and yellow and you're like what the fuck is that thing?
Rym: It's part of a whole set and all the other pieces in the set are really cool-looking.
Rym: The what the bread knife is just weird-looking.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like this yellow knife.
Scott: It's totally weird.
Scott: It is the best bread cutting knife in the universe in terms of like cutting a loaf The pure komachi bread knife by shouldn't.
Scott: yeah, that's it.
Scott: so The thing is with this knife, it's serrated in such a way that you never had to sharpen it, right?
Scott: Well, it's serrated.
Scott: knives usually don't sharpen anyway, but it's serrated in both directions was sort of like these humps.
Scott: So when you push it forward it cuts and when you pull it backward it cuts but it cuts the same way whether you're going Backwards or forwards.
Scott: so when you cut a bread with it you look at the bread and it's like this absolutely smooth cut.
Scott: It looks like you cut it with like the bread slicing machine.
Scott: It's like so smooth.
Scott: It's straight down the middle and it makes minimal crummage compared to other knives Of course depending on the kind of.
Rym: well The reason for that primarily is that any time you've had trouble cutting bread with a bread knife It's not really a bread knife.
Rym: Look at the.
Rym: look at the.
Rym: we'll link to this.
Scott: We learned this.
Scott: we went to the store right where I bought a bunch of knives.
Rym: I wasn't even there as you and Emily.
Scott: Yeah And this guy he's like we're looking for a bread knife and a whole bunch of them say bread and we're like which one should We get?
Scott: that one looks weird.
Scott: He's like no, that's a deli guy finally comes to help us.
Scott: He's like that's a deli knife.
Scott: It just says bread on it so we can actually sell it, you know He's like here.
Scott: you want this one.
Scott: It's an ugly duckling, but it works and I'm like you sure he's like Oh, yeah.
Scott: So I trusted the big fat knife selling guy at the store and boy am I glad I trusted that guy Because he knews about knives.
Scott: He works in the knife store.
Rym: So well, how many knives did he have?
Scott: kitchen store?
Scott: Yeah, like a hundred knives.
Scott: It's the kitchen store.
Scott: but as like this great knife section they actually have a knife club and I'm in the knife club there.
Scott: It's pretty awesome.
Rym: Plus this bread knife 20 bucks.
Scott: Yeah 20 bucks for the only bread knife You'll ever need for the rest of your life.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: You might eventually bust it and have to get another one like 40 years.
Rym: How could you possibly break it?
Rym: I don't know if you don't.
Scott: if you have a marble cutting board It's a good thing to get as a gift for people, you know.
Scott: Like if you don't have one cuz like here I bought you this bread knife.
Scott: It's.
Scott: and then they use it and like holy shit, you know and you add it.
Scott: see if they eat bread It's something they'll actually use a lot and will actually make a difference in their lives as opposed to if you get them Like I don't know an expensive appliance.
Scott: They never.
Scott: they use like once in a blue moon like a bread maker.
Scott: Yeah, it's a great the great knife the pure komachi Awesomeness.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Ah, you should get a bread.
Rym: minor though Cuz remember if you don't slice your bread it lasts a lot longer.
Scott: Let me go on Amazon and search for bread miters.
Rym: I don't know if anyone makes bread miters specifically.
Rym: I mean it develops.
Rym: we had one we made ourselves that we use forever.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: They have those those bread like shoots.
Scott: you like send the bread down the chute and there's a chainsaw in there Basically or spinning and it goes near and slices it perfectly in half.
Scott: I like that action.
Rym: You just get a whole bread cutting machine this element like creating barrel.
Scott: Yeah, but that's not something you have for a house with what an apartment would be awesome.
Rym: No, you know you have your loaf of bread.
Rym: people come over.
Rym: You're like, all right guys want some sandwiches.
Scott: Oh I see how the bread miter works.
Scott: Yeah, that's not really gonna work.
Rym: for the rye bread though You'd have to get one that was the right size and shape.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think they have one day.
Scott: Oh, there's only three on Amazon.
Rym: You can make one.
Rym: when I was making.
Scott: there is this one that was good for cutting bagels exactly in half Wouldn't bagel miter.
Rym: I actually get a bagel miter.
Scott: They also have baguette miter and a French minor, but they don't have a rye miter.
Rym: I'm surprised.
Rym: didn't you ever take like a shop class?
Rym: Miters sawing is like one of the first things you learn with that flat backed weird back.
Scott: Yeah, now I know what a miter is.
Rym: It's also a funny hat.
Scott: It is indeed.
Scott: Okay, so this I can't find a rye miter.
Rym: Uh, there's got to be some like Jewish deli site that has like the miter the perfect miter.
Scott: I can't find one anyway Do we?
Scott: how much longer do we have to talk about bread?
Rym: I think we can cut it off.
Rym: We I really fucking like bread.
Rym: I think my let's just go down, you know favorite breads like overall man I like so many bread cuz I really like like peasant bread like the white.
Rym: I like like they're really crusty on the outside like spirally rolls with poppy seed on the inside.
Rym: It's like really airy and loose, you know, basically I don't like any bread.
Scott: That's like.
Scott: I like breads that have a lot of substance, but I don't like them to be like heavy in the stomach You know, it's like.
Rym: well, it depends.
Rym: I mean, I like a good pumpernickel.
Rym: if the mood is right pumpernickel is not heavy in the stomach of real pumpernickel is.
Scott: no It's not I'm talking about like these breads.
Rym: We didn't even tell you know, what pumpernickel bubble.
Rym: save that We don't tell the list.
Scott: I'm talking like you go to the grocery store and there's a bread and it says like 12 grain and you bite into it like One bite and you're full cuz.
Rym: well that is a separate issue.
Rym: I found that seems weird lately and a lot of foodies are talking about this more and more.
Rym: There seems to be this war on white bread because you know Most people think white bread think Wonder Bread or you know slice bread in a bag from the grocery store.
Scott: The thing is the problem with those breads is white bread, you know Wonder Bread I think to white bread in general I don't like.
Scott: but like I get like, you know home fried wheat bread Which you know, I mean it still has corn syrup in it.
Scott: It's not like a fancy high-grained bread, but it's totally awesome.
Scott: and white bread Wonder Bread is totally disgusting.
Rym: Well thing is there are many like a baguette is technically a white bread.
Scott: baguettes are awesome.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but a lot of people are using non white bread.
Scott: man They need to open up a pond cotillion in Queens.
Scott: Instead of going to Subway after the show I could go there and get the baguette sandwich another poor place to work.
Rym: There's one right next to my office.
Rym: I eat.
Scott: there's one right next to my office, too But there isn't one right now.
Rym: Yeah, actually I wouldn't get a sandwich though.
Rym: I'd get one of those tartines instead.
Scott: Yeah, but you got to sit down to get that.
Rym: No, you can get that to go.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah, oh, I always get the one with the frickin like cheese on it.
Rym: No, I get the one with the like the salmon and all that one.
Rym: I like that one.
Rym: Okay, my favorite is the baguette.
Rym: just you know the baguette and it's got cheddar and Pesto, no, I don't want that.
Rym: no or the ham one I get.
Scott: All right, the Sun is like shining at me and I'm starting to melt a little bit.
Rym: Is that the end of Scott?
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: I like friends that are really crusty on the outside, but then really like warm and doughy on the inside.
Scott: Yeah, it's all about the high quality crust But the thing is the crust has to have like a flavor.
Scott: a lot of times you get like a charred crust or a tasteless crust.
Scott: yeah It's like.
Scott: no the crust like brings all these great flavors, and then the inside has to be nice and squishy But it also has to have you know a flavor.
Scott: But hey, you know the thing is I don't like it.
Scott: when the inside has a weird flavor like a sourdough It's like all right.
Scott: That's a good kind of.
Scott: it's got some flavor in there.
Rym: Weird bread you don't like like your weird flavor I don't know.
Scott: There's some breads were like the inside just like they put some like all.
Scott: it's like strange Spices in there, and you know if they got like pepper in there that could be good.
Scott: No, no, but if they got like it's just some some breads.
Scott: I've had where the inside is like off.
Rym: I wouldn't even talk about naan and pudi.
Scott: Oh shit fuck.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I could use some puri.
Rym: right now I don't know.
Scott: does puri count as bread.
Rym: I think so yeah unleavened bread But it doesn't it.
Scott: in one big bucket It's one giant air pocket.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: Oh Naan is actually the second picture on the Wikipedia page.
Rym: It's like various kinds of leaven bread naan Eleven flat bread.
Scott: I'm getting so hungry fuck.
Rym: Oh my god What if there's a place that just delivers Indian food right here right now?
Rym: get some.
Scott: we can get the Thai food though Which is noodles which are bready.
Rym: damn it though.
Rym: That's the one thing you can go home And you could just go to like the roadie boatie and get a bunch of naan.
Scott: I could go to the roadie boatie and get naan.
Rym: I can't do that.
Scott: I'm hungry like this instant though.
Rym: Oh my god bread was a poor topic for a show.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: We should have eaten first.
Rym: Yeah Lately though one thing I do want to say Living here.
Rym: I don't have a toaster.
Scott: I've always had a toaster oven.
Scott: no I don't I do.
Rym: yeah I don't.
Rym: But when I live I used to blues brother when I lived alone in fish kill because I didn't buy a toaster then and I had A wire coat hanger, and I'd blues brother it and I got a gas stove.
Rym: I could blues brother it But I've taken back up an art that I'd lost from when I was in high school Which was instead of using a toaster I would always make toast with a little bit of butter on a skillet, and I have refined that art again.
Rym: And I very much love butter toast.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you can't put butter on something you put into the toaster.
Scott: otherwise fire yep So you got to toast it then butter it, but if you do the butter toast obviously making grilled Non bread you know cheese without the tomato or the cheese.
Rym: Oh, you go one step further and fry the bread and like bacon grease, but I usually fuck that up The guy.
Scott: there's the guy who ate like bacon fat back Lose black.
Rym: yeah, oh My god.
Rym: I gotta go eat.
Scott: I'm done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.