Rym: It's Thursday September 30th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We have our thoughts with the GeekNights book club on the golden apples of the Sun by Ray Bradbury.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so our work for project st has Been annoying mostly for the fact that the only lights we own are These kind of work lights that are not designed for video work in any way.
Scott: I mean did we buy them because you're trying to save money, and yeah, they were like 20 bucks.
Rym: They came on the stand.
Rym: They're super bright.
Rym: They're hotter than the fucking Sun.
Scott: Why don't we just put like something in front of them to you know even you know to make it?
Rym: even we did that Still wasn't good enough Because then they weren't bright enough, and they weren't that good, and they were still fucking hot.
Scott: Maybe we just need a better shield.
Scott: I mean any lights you get any be fucking no no LEDs That's true.
Rym: See the thing is we were trying to save money back then when we bought that and we were first delving into video And then we gave up.
Rym: now that we're smart and serious.
Rym: We're doing the Moran strategy.
Rym: I'm just buying a real fucking set of lights and Actually, I learned something scary, but I mean LEDs.
Scott: I mean while that's well and good with the heat and the electricity usage and such they're also much brighter than those lights Yeah, but there's no professionals using LED.
Rym: Yeah, they do use them all the time really.
Rym: yeah I found some very high-end LED lights.
Rym: Here's the trouble.
Rym: I was looking on Amazon because I I couldn't find many places to buy Professional video lights online that weren't way overpriced way beyond what we need or Very shady looking sites that I do not trust for one shit mm-hmm.
Rym: so on Amazon I find all these kits like video kit from this one company and like every set of studio lights for photography or video is this one company and they sell like these two light three light four light kits for like two three hundred bucks and A little investigation show that not only are these kits the biggest pieces of shit you've ever seen But you can get professional equipment With the same number of lights that are a lot brighter and a lot better for the same price.
Rym: just not on Amazon Uh-huh, but the only place.
Scott: these aren't sold by Amazon.
Scott: They're sold by other companies that are just selling through Amazon.
Scott: Yeah exactly Yeah, I mean, it's not Amazon isn't trying to rip you off Amazon was.
Rym: it's some other guy, but and I so you know doing some research I found exactly what to get.
Rym: for like 300 bucks I can get a pretty professional like video studio setup like everything I'm gonna need and the best part is they're portable.
Rym: they take freaking batteries if we want.
Scott: Oh, it's not like four hours of light.
Scott: Whoa, but yeah, cuz they're LEDs you can get away with it.
Rym: Yeah And they're still way brighter than what we have now and we can use what we have now as a backfill light.
Rym: All right, we need to.
Rym: so it's all good.
Rym: The only place online so far that I can find this one light that I actually want to buy is B&H.
Scott: Ah Bastard in hell.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know I Can't.
Rym: B&H has been my bet.
Rym: I've never Successfully entered a B&H.
Scott: It's all wait.
Scott: Well, there's only one festival All right, and the thing is people in New York are like such fans of this place, right?
Scott: I went there once.
Scott: I've never bought anything there and like You know the good things about it.
Scott: It's a physical store and it has stuff that no other physical store has in terms of like.
Scott: it has professional equipment.
Scott: You know, if you look around New York City most electronics places are.
Scott: they're either Best Buy kind of places where they have consumer stuff right or They are the sort of you know those places the touristy ones.
Scott: they just have like a million cameras in the window.
Rym: understood those places because I've gone into them several times Before I eventually stopped.
Rym: they never had a deal that was better than Amazon.
Scott: I mean, they're not about deals.
Scott: Those are places about being overpriced and to sell the tourists, but they act like check out all this cheap electronics We got.
Rym: we got tons of stuff.
Scott: No, I got tons of overpriced stuff like two years old cameras for twice as much as original price.
Rym: But they the way you talk to the salesman and they act like they've got.
Rym: they're like, yeah We got these off a truck this crazy deal.
Rym: Check it out.
Rym: Yeah, right now but with audio and with other sorts of professional things like.
Rym: there's Sam Ash but there's like five or six other places I can go to and I can get all the stuff on Amazon or same-day music or Whatever.
Rym: but the stuff I want these particular lights I can only get from B&H and all those shady places.
Scott: Well B&H like they actually have everything and their prices They're not as good as internet prices except for this thing because I can't find this thing anywhere.
Rym: So I guess that's the best price which is much lower than these shitty kits that are the same thing But worse.
Scott: on Amazon, for example, I went to look at my TV at B&H and I bought it on Amazon for less.
Scott: Yeah, that's like.
Rym: that's the internet future until everyone does that and then the stores are gone.
Scott: Yeah, but B&H is like this big weird store that just happens to have everything from consumer to professional level stuff.
Scott: And the thing is they make a ton of money because some people still like to go to stores I don't know why and other people like professional TV and radio people and photographers in the city all go there to you know Look at stuff and buy stuff and whatever, you know.
Rym: Well part of the reason they go there is that some of this stuff I can't find anywhere else I guess.
Scott: but I guess if also if you're a professional you need it now and your company's paying for it.
Scott: So what do you care if it's on the internet for ten bucks less?
Rym: So I think we've covered all the good things about B&H.
Rym: Yeah, so I go to their website today, right?
Rym: I'm at work and I'm like, alright, this is what I'm gonna buy after work.
Rym: I'll just go over there and just buy it.
Rym: Yeah, they're like, oh wait now even better.
Rym: I'll just order from their website.
Rym: They sell stuff online to go to the website and there's a pop-up over it That says online ordering is unavailable until Saturday at 8 p.m.
Rym: Eastern Time.
Rym: Yep, please blah blah blah.
Rym: sorry for the inconvenience and I forgot about the deal that we haven't talked about yet The real reason why I hate the NH.
Rym: so I was like, oh crap.
Rym: Oh, well, I'll just go to the store.
Rym: It's right there.
Rym: Well right there meaning it's on the fucking west side.
Scott: It's on the.
Scott: it's on the other side of Madison Square Garden.
Rym: Yeah, it's like 9th Avenue and 34th or something like that.
Rym: I walk over there and Closed.
Rym: of course, it's closed and I realized it's been closed for the last week and a half because of suckus.
Rym: No, it's suckus suckus or sick coat and right before that it was closed for something else.
Rym: And of course, it's closed every Friday.
Scott: You see being a well, it's Friday night and Saturday.
Rym: It's super Jewish.
Scott: It's owned by like the most religious Jews.
Scott: you can imagine.
Rym: they bring the online store down for holidays and the physical store.
Scott: Yeah, and Basically, you know, I think there's nothing right.
Rym: I know I can't go there Friday.
Rym: I'm already aware that yeah, they're Jews.
Rym: I can't do business with them on Friday.
Rym: I thought I'd be safe Thursday, but Scott your people have so many holidays.
Scott: They don't have that many holidays.
Scott: Did you know did you see that the thing is when they do have a holiday?
Scott: It's many days long.
Rym: That depends.
Rym: there's got to be some one day.
Scott: No, no, there's not that many.
Scott: most of them are like.
Scott: for example Yom Kippur is a one-day holiday Yeah, but Rosh Hashanah right is a multi-day holiday and the last day of Rosh Hashanah is immediately followed by Yom Kippur.
Scott: So it's actually part of another multi-day holiday thing.
Rym: is I think nerds are gonna.
Rym: We have more holidays than the Jews at this point.
Rym: I think oh, yeah, I mean talk like a pirate day.
Scott: Well, we got.
Scott: actually our problem is we make everything day.
Scott: The Jews are like, yeah, uh-huh day Okay.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yell at the sky week.
Scott: That's how you get it.
Rym: Yeah to work I had to yell at the sky five years and you know living in Rochester.
Scott: Yeah, Jews are like, you know what no work every Friday night or Saturday Impossible, you know, it's like they just like crank up the days on purpose.
Rym: So I can't get these lights now.
Rym: I was gonna have them and shine a mind.
Rym: you all were doing the show.
Scott: just it's like parameters that closed on Sunday and I Can't order them online.
Rym: and this is bothering me You know, we were both really like not shit-talking lately.
Rym: and yet finally I'm like, all right I'm getting off my ass and I physically and incapable of doing the one thing I tried to do today.
Scott: I don't know why I even tried to go there because I can't find anywhere else to get this fucking light.
Scott: Here's what you do.
Rym: you ready you go and you buy a similar light that I can get in another store.
Rym: But they don't have the light I want and the similar light is the next step up.
Scott: It's eight grand.
Scott: Here's what you do.
Scott: you go and you find what kind of light bulbs are in there?
Scott: No, it's.
Rym: there's no light bulbs an LED.
Scott: you buy the center.
Rym: No, it's an array of LEDs.
Scott: You go buy a huge box full of LEDs.
Scott: Yes, and we can light them up now Why not?
Rym: You know how pain in the ass would be to set that up.
Scott: I have soldering iron.
Scott: I can do it.
Rym: You do it then I'll work on something else.
Scott: go figure out what LED we need and buy enough of them and doesn't say What do you mean.
Rym: doesn't say what LED uses.
Scott: go buy the brightest white LED you can find and get a whole box full of them.
Rym: Yeah and you're gonna solder these in and have the right light balance and the white balance the right temperature color and have them focus that They're diffused properly without needing a screen or a gel or anything.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: You just put them in a grid on a circuit board.
Rym: What do you know exactly what to do to get them correctly?
Scott: we get it one resistor.
Scott: I hate double-a batteries.
Scott: you get a resistor on each one and you're gonna make my AC adapters And you're gonna make the poles and the stands and you don't get an AC that you can get.
Scott: you just buy DC there.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna.
Rym: what the fuck am I gonna plug that into my power supply fire?
Scott: Well, no, you just buy one of these guys and it goes in the wall.
Scott: then DC comes out the other end.
Rym: Yeah, Scott you get on that.
Rym: I'm I have one.
Rym: I'm just gonna wait until they stop doing their holiday BS.
Scott: You're actually gonna go there.
Scott: Okay, but you won't shop in Paramus.
Rym: No, I won't shop in prime But you'll shop at the juice store.
Scott: Well, which is far worse.
Rym: Here's the secret.
Rym: I am very very willing to jump on to protests and things like that When I am protesting something that I would not have engaged in.
Rym: Anyway, there is nothing in premise.
Rym: I want or need There's.
Rym: I don't need anything from Scientology.
Rym: So I boycott the shit out of them.
Rym: You're not gonna see me boycott an Amazon for much.
Scott: Yeah Such such a such a high moral Convictions.
Rym: so you got any any news here and it's not really news.
Scott: This is article.
Scott: I wanted to discuss, right?
Scott: It was in the Sunday book review of the New York Times and the Internet's And he basically talks about how because you always yell at me for like forgetting everything I read in a book.
Scott: pretty much it amazing.
Rym: It's okay to forget like oh, what did he go to?
Rym: the town of Bethlehem?
Rym: Nazareth?
Rym: it's another thing to forget like the name of the protagonist from a series of books you read.
Scott: but the point this guy talks About how you know, he has the guy who's the main character in Locke Lamora.
Scott: Locke Lamora, okay?
Rym: Who's a sidekick?
Scott: Jean?
Rym: Okay, Jean what were the twins names?
Rym: You don't remember do you?
Rym: The twins?
Scott: what were their names?
Rym: the twins?
Scott: Well, they had names the twins someone so and so and so.
Rym: yeah the twins.
Scott: Yes, you don't remember.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: Anyway,
Scott: the point is this guy has this whole article here and he talks about how while he remembers reading books and he remembers moments Of in them and feelings and in these sorts of things he can't like even like a book He just read or a book that had a huge impact on him or like, you know He can't really remember that many specific things like you can't tell you every scene in order You know is the same and I was like, oh man, that's just like me I can't remember shit.
Scott: and he went around asking all these people like hey You know, is it okay that you don't remember anything in the book and they're like, yeah, of course It's like everything that you don't remember from all these books still like gets into your subconscious And they all get added together and just sort of like, you know And they change you in some way that you can't.
Scott: I just cuz you don't remember a fact.
Rym: I definitely agree with that.
Rym: and also, you know, it's kind of like you have a pointer array in your brain But you might not have the pointers to.
Rym: you know The names of these characters or whatever but like on the surface or connected to the name of the book even anymore.
Rym: But there's a pointer there somewhere and you might hit it while you're looking for something else.
Scott: Yeah There's an interesting little two-page dealing about how you know.
Scott: at the same time It's important and good to read books Even though you don't remember anything, you know You might not remember facts or you know details from books like characters names or places or sequences of events.
Scott: It doesn't mean that it wasn't worthwhile to read that book, but at the same time No meaning.
Rym: I only have this problem with books that I didn't particularly like or they didn't speak to me.
Rym: I can go into great goddamn detail about everything in The Prince of Nothing.
Scott: How many times did you read The Prince of Nothing once?
Scott: Lord of the Rings, yeah, what about it?
Rym: What was the dwarf's name?
Scott: Which one though?
Rym: the one Gimli?
Scott: Oh Because I was thinking because yeah, I Realized.
Scott: I said Lord of the Rings.
Scott: my brain went to the beginning of the story and it always goes to the hobbit.
Scott: so I was like, so lumen and lumen and Thorin and It's like a whole pile of dwarves now.
Scott: It's like friggin snow.
Rym: white dwarf fortresses ruined me.
Rym: whenever I picture the hobbit now I can't but imagine like Thorin just losing his shit like killing five or sixty other dwarves Walling himself up in a room and crying herself to death.
Scott: That's what happens.
Rym: It's like out of nowhere.
Scott: That's what happened.
Scott: That's the book.
Rym: All right, so you should read this because it's book club appropriate news, so our government Decided that they have to deal with a very serious problem and they actually serious.
Rym: They actually got together and they put together a law a bill.
Rym: as far as I can tell.
Rym: is it passed there?
Rym: Don't know it's not passed yet.
Scott: It's a federal.
Scott: It's a federal situation.
Rym: So it is called the CA LM the commercial advertisement loudness Mitigation acts.
Rym: so the coma.
Scott: Oh, it's all.
Scott: this is because commercials on TV purposefully make their audio louder than the TV episodes.
Scott: so stand out.
Rym: and so here's my my problem here how When did the first television enter American households like the 450s?
Rym: When did ads start appearing on TVs?
Scott: Immediately?
Scott: because they would have the people in the show because all the shows are live.
Scott: They had the people Stop doing the show and do a product promotion like right in the middle of the show.
Scott: like and the news tonight is blah Blah blah blah blah and you should buy Wheaties.
Scott: check it out.
Scott: I got a box of Wheaties from a guy who handed it to me offstage.
Scott: You should buy this.
Scott: Okay back to the news by the meet-a-vegetin.
Rym: Okay, so to to skip the leading questions.
Rym: I was going to keep asking you.
Rym: Commercials have been way louder than everything else for fucking ever.
Scott: They didn't raise the volume on the commercials in the 80s.
Rym: They were like that.
Scott: That's true All right, so it's not that new but it is 70s 80s 90s 2000s 2010s.
Rym: we're now in the era where broadcast television is on the way out.
Rym: people are moving to the internet and Congress is like we are gonna deal with this problem.
Rym: Now.
Rym: We got this shit.
Rym: We're gonna protect you from those buggy whips.
Rym: The buggy whip mitigation act is here.
Scott: I mean, it's a good thing right, but it's still.
Scott: it's fixing a problem.
Scott: It's too old.
Rym: Yes, I mean even worse.
Rym: Technology already solves this.
Rym: it's trivial to just put a limiter or a lot of TV.
Scott: a lot of TVs Have those
Rym: they
Scott: have like a button you push and it basically keeps all the sound, you know Even I don't
Rym: have anything else to say about make
Scott: sure the highs aren't too high and lows aren't too low
Rym: other than that Way too little way too late and this is why I'm so fed up with our government that this is their issue.
Scott: It's all old people.
Scott: they need to I'm telling you they need.
Rym: every generation gets into power and then tries to solve the problems of The jet of when they were kids and then they seem to forget that kids when they're old Have other problems and they seem to forget that they used to be the same way.
Rym: I
Scott: think I think I finally because I've been trying to figure out a way right how to get people out of government that are old and I think I finally figured out a way and I think the way
Rym: I Came up with so many jokes, but all
Scott: no I finally figured out a reasonable way to get people to get the old people out right.
Rym: just no elevators all stairs No ready for this.
Scott: This is the most reasonable idea yet.
Scott: Okay, you ready?
Scott: Are you sure?
Scott: I'm sure if you are going to be Logan's right in government like a mayor or a congressperson or whatever You also have to have a job a real job.
Scott: So your places are like that.
Scott: Yeah It's like if you are not employed if you're retired or if you're homeless or you cannot be a congressperson.
Rym: All right.
Rym: All right Scott.
Scott: It has to be something to do in addition to your real work.
Scott: I work as a consultant and no you have to have a real job that you actually work at nine to five.
Rym: Oh, so you're discounting lots of perfectly legitimate actual jobs.
Scott: It has to be a job where you're actually working like for reals not just a. you know I have a job on paper.
Scott: You have to prove that you are working for real.
Rym: So I think a better.
Rym: you just have to be able to open a childproof pill case.
Scott: You See my boy, right if you don't have a real job that is your primary work that you are doing.
Scott: and then what you do.
Scott: then when you can have time to legislate if you're Working nine to five because you would also when the young people got in power We would put through the two months three months guaranteed vacation and you would use your vacation to govern.
Rym: So governing only happens three months out of the year.
Scott: if it's young people governing they could get all the governing done in a week.
Rym: Yeah, this is what always bothers me like if I were the president of the United States, right They always take all this vacation.
Rym: They relax a lot.
Rym: I've got it most an Absolute most if everything goes perfectly.
Rym: eight years in power Yeah, I would use every goddamn waking second of my life to call everybody on their bullshit 24/7.
Scott: you would be out of power Before you could take a vacation.
Rym: I get at least four years.
Scott: Yeah, they would impeach you just for being a jerk.
Scott: They could but I Congress as soon as you called the first person on their bullshit everyone.
Scott: because how many people in the House of Representatives like 400 Johnson tried to do that.
Rym: They called him on his.
Rym: it wasn't even bullshit.
Rym: They called him They're like we're gonna impeach you because you're dick.
Rym: Yeah, and he was like bring it.
Scott: and then they didn't because anyway, but they in nowadays They totally would.
Rym: was it Weber who voted against it?
Rym: the one vote against impeach whatever?
Rym: I forget.
Rym: I read this book profiles and courage that talked about him a lot and you remember all these details from it.
Rym: Yeah So things of the day.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I actually I'm pretty sure I did this as a thing of the day, but No, I'm I you know, but I don't have a thing of the day.
Scott: search.
Rym: yet If only we could search the things of the.
Scott: actually I think I can.
Scott: let me let me do it.
Rym: I just tried I searched.
Scott: well, you know, yeah, I think you can do it.
Scott: I think you can do it in the.
Rym: yeah No in the in the admin part of the website.
Rym: All right, so you're gonna do this.
Scott: I know already doing it right editing out this.
Scott: Well, I haven't done it.
Scott: apparently Okay, so I thought I did this as a thing a day, but apparently I did not or the search didn't work.
Scott: No, it worked.
Scott: Um, so I don't know why I thought I did this as a thing of the day, but I didn't.
Scott: and It was weird because I went.
Scott: it's a meme kind of video from College Humor and when we were in Seattle, right?
Scott: Yeah, I was reminded of it and I was like you guys don't?
Scott: I did this thing today.
Scott: you remember it.
Scott: they're like.
Scott: no It was like.
Scott: it's funny.
Rym: You're walking by and you're like, I got it at a Ross and all of us Look at you like got what?
Scott: Anyway, it's this awesome Music video to this rap song.
Scott: These guys did the guys.
Scott: the name of their band is Abraham Lincoln and They have this song.
Scott: I got it at Ross and Ross.
Scott: Ross is you know, my My grandma's last name, but it's also The The name of this bargain like discount store out west.
Scott: It's basically like Marshalls in the East Coast.
Scott: It's like a place you go to get cheap clothes and crap.
Rym: Oh, wow I realize I've never in my life been inside a Ross or a Marshalls.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically like a bargain basement kind of clothing store, right?
Scott: So the whole song is about how he got it at Ross.
Scott: Yeah, you'd be stupid if you paying right a zillion dollars for clothes like clothes, please you tripping you know and He's like.
Scott: you think I'm about to spend my whole check please.
Scott: So he goes to Ross.
Rym: dude Where'd you get those nonstick pans?
Scott: I got it at Ross.
Scott: It's a pretty I like.
Scott: I always like Hip-hop and rap songs.
Scott: They're like about just a generic topic.
Scott: Like.
Scott: it doesn't have to be nerdcore hip-hop, you know.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the thing is metal.
Scott: joy is almost every rap song right from the 80s and 90s.
Scott: Okay Drugs and crime and screwing and killing people and not so interested, right?
Scott: But there's a few out there that are actually about stuff, you know It's about a particular thing like a robot or something like that, you know And those are the ones that I like best, you know lyrically at least.
Rym: and this like being on a boat.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: Like I'm on a boat.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: You know, this is the same kind of deal.
Scott: So I like this song and this thing today much delayed And I got it at Ross.
Rym: you got it at Ross my yoga DVDs.
Rym: So my thing of the day because Scott and I know about this guy I learned about him a long time a long time ago.
Rym: three or four years ago I ended up on a Wikipedia page about him and I was like, oh this guy's awesome The king of Jordan is an awesome guy.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and if you did not realize that King Abdullah the second of Jordan is an awesome guy You should watch this Daily Show episode.
Scott: I'm linking to oh and his wife.
Rym: Yeah daughter yeah, I think he has hot daughters - I don't know much about that but They if you don't watch the Daily Show already I'm not saying you have to watch the Daily Show.
Rym: this one episode is really good because he sits down with Jon Stewart.
Scott: This king of Jordan actually came to me.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: Cuz he was at the UN.
Scott: That's cuz.
Scott: every last week I fucking everything.
Scott: who's all backed up with the traffic all these fucking UN bastards.
Rym: Yeah, they have that like Lane.
Rym: I'm still the guys who went down the street with those machine guns Not submachine guns were they there for the king of Jordan?
Scott: I mean, it's it's weird to see who has more and who has less security than other guys.
Rym: Yeah So he's on the Daily Show and he does a really sober interview about the state of the Middle East right now in Israel and Palestine And how.
Rym: basically today's the day.
Rym: today September 30th is the deadline for the settlement issue.
Rym: And he says straight up if they walk away from the table There's gonna be war in the Middle East major war within a year.
Rym: Absolutely 100% probably.
Rym: and the interview is fantastic and there's an extended interview and it's fantastic.
Rym: I don't think I need to talk about how.
Rym: why is Jon Stewart the comedian?
Rym: Doing more poignant and real interviews than anyone in the so-called legitimate press or any of that bullshit, but I'll point out something else.
Rym: Obama was given people shit at the UN and they talk about this here.
Rym: He calls out North Korea for enslaving their population in Congo for raping people while they're in the audience listening to his speech.
Rym: Yeah, but he calls out Israel on the settlement issue and they're not even fucking there.
Rym: You know why they're celebrating suck it or whatever.
Scott: Oh, I guess it's the holiday.
Scott: Yeah So look, this is actually let me talk about slick us for like a minute.
Rym: Just like the palm and the.
Scott: yeah It's actually a fun holiday, right?
Scott: You get to build a little hut in your backyard Right and you get like lemon and salt.
Scott: you get you get like a frond and and and this lemon thing It's called the luluv and the etrog right?
Scott: I think the etrog is the fruit.
Scott: It's kind of like a lemon but not exactly.
Rym: it sounds like something I get 500 experience
Scott: I know and the luluv is the is the is the frond and you wave the frond and I guess you do something with the fruit And you basically you need to go eat dinner in this little hut in your backyard every night.
Scott: It's totally chill, you know And that's the thing.
Scott: It's like they come up with these awesome holidays.
Scott: It's just like party time, you know, it's like oh man What are we gonna do on this holiday?
Scott: I know Let's eat fruits Because I mean, you know in the middle, you know, if you're in the desert.
Scott: fruits are luxurious, right?
Scott: It's like oh sweet fruit.
Scott: Yes, they didn't have candy then right?
Scott: So it's like yeah eating fruit that make an awesome holiday.
Scott: All right, we'll save up all the fruit and eat it on this awesome day.
Scott: Well, hey, I got a better idea on this particular Holiday, we got to dip the fruits in the honey.
Scott: Oh shit fruit and honey is like the best fucking holiday.
Scott: You're just kidding me.
Scott: So I'm not shitting you.
Scott: In fact, it is mandatory for everybody to eat fruit with honey on it on this holiday.
Rym: Scott Where did the Israelites get all that fruit?
Scott: from the green side?
Rym: I set you up.
Rym: I set you up and you didn't bite.
Scott: They got it at Ross.
Scott: Oh shit So cheap does almost free.
Rym: There are multiple layers to that joke.
Scott: All right, so very briefly the meta moment.
Rym: this is probably the last book club episode that's going to be as a Thursday Episode.
Rym: we're splitting it off.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna make a book club section on the website and that will contain the book club.
Scott: Right and those book club episodes will still be in the gig night's feed.
Scott: But they're just.
Scott: they're not gonna have news or things today.
Scott: It's just gonna be book club episodes and it's gonna be all you know.
Rym: It's not gonna be a Monday Tuesday Wednesday or Thursday But this weekend on Saturday at Kino Koonia in New York City and Bryant Park Yep from 4 p.m.
Rym: To 7 p.m.
Rym: There's a pre New York anime festival Event with a whole bunch of cool stuff going on.
Rym: We'll be there from 6 30 to 7 doing the New York anime festival New York comic-con pregame show.
Scott: When does the event start though?
Scott: like 4 starts at like 4. there's food.
Scott: Yeah, do we want to get there?
Scott: for?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: are the only official thing we're doing other than eating the food is Talking from 6 30 to 7 and then from 7 to 7 30.
Rym: I think the New York anime festival people are gonna be there.
Rym: They're gonna give away a bunch of free passes and stuff like that.
Scott: That sucks.
Rym: if you already bought your pass, which you probably should Any kind of enemy con any con you should buy your badge.
Scott: Yeah, but then what's the point of winning a free one?
Rym: Yeah, give it to someone else.
Scott: Hopefully you can sell it and buy stuff at Kino Koonia Wednesday.
Rym: So second Speaking of buying badges.
Rym: You should pre-register for PAX East if you're not sure.
Rym: Yeah sure you're gonna go.
Rym: It's gonna sell out you're allowed to resell the badges straight up.
Scott: So even if you are one fact is encouraged that you resell the badge as long as you were doing it Legitimately and you're not doing it for more than what the badge.
Rym: if there is even a 1% chance that you think you might go To PAX just buy your bags But pre read just open for PAX West 2011 yet.
Scott: No, so pre rage for PAX East now Just go to the website and buy badges You know and you'll get the badge in the mail and you know what.
Scott: if it turns out that you can't go There will be someone who wants it, you know, the pre-reg is now.
Scott: do it now.
Rym: now also along those lines We're gonna be doing way back.
Rym: We did a PAX East survival guide because PAX East was new and this coming year this coming PAX East PAX Boston bitch packs.
Rym: It is in an entire.
Scott: It's not bitch packs.
Scott: It's bitch in pay.
Rym: It is going to be in yet a different venue because the high knees is way too small.
Scott: this is going to be very Shaky.
Rym: so we're going to do a an addendum to our packs a survival guide with updated survival info.
Scott: Then you're going to need the survival info because let me tell you this PAX East will be Most dangerous gonna be off the hook most dangerous.
Scott: It's you know, you know, you know, it's off the hook.
Rym: Okay, I Don't know what you're going for.
Scott: You don't want a hand when a phone gets off the hook.
Scott: It goes.
Rym: Oh Yeah, that's what.
Rym: And last but not least by any stretch the New York Comic Con New York anime festival itself is next weekend October 8th 9th and 10th in New York City in the Jacob Gavin Center.
Rym: We will be there on Friday night doing a panel from 7 15 to 8 15 p.m.
Rym: Anime, you never thought you'd like in room 1 e 1 4.
Scott: also the 10 10 10 burning wheel convention is the same three days but I think it's all filled up.
Scott: so you can't go if you're not already going.
Rym: and Friday night October 8th is board game night and you will not be there, but you should be there.
Scott: I can't think of anything else matter right now.
Rym: So I feel like we should do the entire meta moment in that voice.
Scott: every time I go machine guy doesn't met him.
Scott: Oh my god, like twice micro machine metamoment.
Rym: That guy talks like twice as fast even us.
Scott: He's like the most professional fast talk in the world.
Scott: Yeah, you know what he could.
Scott: totally I don't know.
Scott: But you know, he could do.
Scott: he's dead.
Scott: He could do with the awesomest axe cop cosplay.
Scott: now that I think about oh my god It would be the best axe cop Except maybe like Burt Reynolds or whatever.
Rym: So the book club itself.
Scott: Yes Do we want to talk about the next book club first or do you want to do that after?
Rym: Ah, Maybe we should do that first.
Rym: It's a separate thing.
Scott: It's up to you.
Rym: It's up to me.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's off to you.
Rym: Okay, I say it's up to you because it was up to me.
Rym: I can do whatever I like.
Scott: Let's try doing the next book club before we do the book club.
Scott: All right and because that way I'm the way I'm thinking the reason I came up with that decision is because then maybe people haven't read the Current book that we're about to talk about, you know the golden apples of the Sun They can get the value out of this episode and just stop instead of having to fast forward If they want to know the next book club,
Rym: so I just want to point out this book is all Scott
Scott: This book is all me.
Scott: All right, so basically, you know lately for the past two or so book clubs.
Scott: I've been choosing books with the intent of getting the readers to read.
Scott: I'm like, I'm not picking them for me.
Scott: I'm picking them for the people, you know I'm like.
Scott: what book will get people to read?
Scott: I pick Locke Lamora not because the greatest book in the world Because it was way fun and I'm like people will read something that is fun in fantasy.
Scott: They're nerds.
Scott: They'll read this, you know, I picked.
Scott: what was the book I picked before that?
Scott: I don't remember but I picked something short.
Scott: Cuz I was like, this is short.
Scott: they'll read it cuz it's easy and short, right?
Scott: So this time I'm like people will read this book because it's such Fan service as in us serving the fans of GeekNights or at least a particular portion of the page Still alive.
Rym: Oh nice as far as I can tell.
Scott: So anyway, this book also was recommended to us in by the Marco Sullivan in the vanilla interview.
Scott: But anyway, the book is called World War Z an oral history of the zombie war By Max Brooks, who is the author of the zombie survival guide?
Scott: It is a New York Times bestseller And let me tell you I predict that this book will not be so good Even though it is a bestseller and has all these quotes on it from New York Times Book Review and Onion AV Club and Entertainment Weekly and it's a bestseller and all this stuff, right?
Scott: I don't I'm not have high expectations, but I'm not judging it cuz I haven't read it.
Scott: I'm just saying the expectations They are low.
Scott: but I think that because it is a zombie book and the zombies are so much loved by the fan base of GeekNights and There is constantly asking us for a zombie episode and
Rym: they just never happening by the way They
Scott: just can't deal, you know, they can't get enough of this shit.
Scott: Right that this book will be up their alley and you know what?
Scott: It's not a sports page and it's not a magazine.
Scott: It's a book and you know what fucking book even though it might be I expect not a good book, you know They're gonna read a book.
Scott: if they if they read this book, they'll be reading a book.
Scott: So that's good.
Scott: It's better than not reading a book.
Scott: So hopefully by going with the fan service route I can get the people to read a book and you know what also It sort of goes in line with the fact that more recently I've been you know Branching into the things I'm not good at like playing to Starcraft, you know, and that sort of thing try to do the genre I'm not good with right?
Scott: So I'm gonna read the book that I probably would never want to read Almost ever just to show that I am NOT the knocker before trier Right, and then after this book, I think I'm gonna go back to just picking books that are actually good and actually like.
Scott: And I'll give up on trying.
Scott: because the people I've tried three different methods to get people to read and if they have not become book Readers after the three methods or ever many methods I've tried They're not gonna.
Scott: so I'm gonna go back to good books again after this one.
Rym: So I chose Ray Bradbury's golden apples of the Sun the book we're talking about now Primarily because I'd read some Ray Bradbury, but I hadn't read a lot.
Scott: I read Fahrenheit 451.
Rym: Yep That's pretty much it.
Rym: I hadn't read a lot of his, you know short stories, especially these ultra short stories like Wario.
Rym: We're stories.
Rym: Oh sweet, but I got the impression when I think about it and I look at what people say about science fiction authors I don't think many people Really are able to differentiate between Heinlein Asimov Bradbury all these different people.
Rym: I don't think a lot of people actually know that they had very different styles of writing.
Scott: Well, I mean cuz nobody reads enough, you know, very few people who aren't nerds read enough of all of them to sort of You know figure out the styles and compare them and contrast them, you know Cuz if you read just one book by someone You need to read like at least three or four books by one person to sort of see the commonalities to figure out What are the trademarks of their style except
Rym: like.
Scott: if you just see one Mamoru Oshii movie?
Scott: How do you know that?
Scott: that dog is a trend?
Scott: you don't?
Scott: you don't know that.
Scott: but if you watch three You see the dog every time you go.
Scott: I got you.
Scott: Oh, she I see you I see what you did there the first prince of nothing book.
Rym: You're like, alright really into rape.
Rym: Second and third book.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's a trend.
Scott: Yeah, you know, so if you just read like, you know one Asimov book one or even like if you read foundation trilogy, it could just been a foundation trilogy thing.
Scott: You know if you just read, you know Toki and Lord of the Rings and you don't read is somewhere alien or a Tom Bombadil.
Scott: what the fuck you don't know What's a token thing and what's something he did in just that book.
Rym: at the same time I could not Force myself to read the summer really and I tried I read it.
Rym: I just guy got bored Didn't care man.
Scott: I could tell you know what?
Scott: talking about remembering things from book you want to know about like Louis Vuitton and the the the main or in the a nor and all that shit.
Scott: I can I can bring it down anyway Some really in book club.
Scott: Yeah, what do you do about that?
Rym: read it unhappily?
Rym: I Was in like third grade.
Scott: it's too much poetries and shit.
Rym: Anyway, I like that stuff.
Rym: Yeah, well, maybe we should do an animation club once and we'll watch the cartoon hobbit.
Rym: No I'll read it first but golden apples of the Sun if you guys didn't know is From a Yeats poem not Keats from Hyperion Yeats.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: I didn't even.
Scott: I don't even.
Scott: okay You got to educate me about this.
Scott: Really?
Rym: You didn't know about Yeats.
Scott: I knew the name Yeats, but actually I was like You would.
Scott: if you would not have clarified just then I would have been like Oh Yeats from my.
Rym: Wow, okay, so to be fair, I'm not nearly as culture we see friends with go with Yeah, they directed pessite show.
Rym: Okay, so until about five years ago.
Rym: I heard every time I heard Yeats I thought oh you mean Keats.
Rym: and every time I heard Keats I thought oh you mean Yeats and I thought they were the same person because they were kind of similar poetry With the East.
Rym: but Yeats is probably one of my favorite poets ever.
Rym: just I really like eats.
Rym: You can learn all about Yeats if you want, but he has a poem a short poem.
Rym: The last stanza of it reads though.
Rym: I am old with wandering through hollow lands and hilly lands.
Rym: I will find out where she has gone and kiss her lip and take her hands and walk along Among long dappled grass and plucked till time and times are done.
Rym: the silver apples of the moon the golden apples of the Sun?
Rym: Yeah, yeah, it says golden apples of the Sun.
Rym: that's how it ends.
Rym: It's.
Rym: it's very relevant to the last story in the collection of short stories the golden apples of the Sun which Coincidentally is called the golden apples of the Sun Gasp, all right, so you wanna talk about that light.
Scott: you want to go through the stories one.
Scott: But actually I want to talk about one thing that's come.
Scott: should we do that first or last?
Scott: the things that are common among all The stories get all over the place.
Rym: one thing that's what I like is the illustrations in the book.
Rym: They're very stark.
Scott: Each story has exactly one illustration and they're pretty good because they sort of let you there at the beginning of the story.
Scott: So you sort of know, you know, because the titles don't usually give away that much.
Scott: but if you read the story then the title makes sense afterwards and So the picture at least gives you sort of some idea what that story is gonna be.
Scott: You know what the setting is gonna be at least pictures just I don't know.
Rym: I like the style.
Rym: They're very stark and thick lined and I don't they remind me of the kind of.
Scott: it's the kind of thing that you can print In a cheap old paperback, yeah, I mean this thing originally came out in like 1953.
Rym: well, it's old and it's a collection of all Alive, I mean, it's a collection of stories.
Rym: He wrote in the 40s and 50s.
Rym: yeah, damn and it really puts it in perspective kind of like reading snow crash going Yeah, that was pretty crappy.
Rym: and then looking back and seeing what it was written and going.
Rym: Oh, yeah It's kind of the same way here like oh, yeah when you wrote this World War two Was happening.
Scott: yeah It was then recent memory.
Scott: at the same time Anyway, no The one thing that I noticed in all the stories the one common thing at least was this sort of literary technique He used at least if not in every story in many of them where he wouldn't explicitly Like set the setting or tell you the characters were anything like that.
Scott: He would just sort of like there would be a scene and he would just start telling you the verbs like someone was doing something.
Scott: And as they would do something and as they would interact you were able to easily unless you're retarded to figure out What was going on?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Like there was a story.
Rym: You know, they're like the pedestrian guys just walking guys walking looking in houses.
Rym: Everyone else is watching TV.
Rym: I See where he's going.
Scott: Ah Yeah, or there's the one with the the girls who?
Scott: Their their boyfriend like moved to Mars or whatever.
Rym: Oh, yeah
Scott: Yeah, and so it's like they got a letter from the boyfriend and they read it and then they were like, oh You know and it's sort of like you were like, oh the boyfriend's on Mars He didn't say here he could have D could have summed up the whole story literally is These are there are these girls?
Scott: their boyfriend moved to Mars.
Rym: That's the whole story.
Rym: The story of embroidery is worlds fucked old ladies.
Rym: Wait for it.
Scott: Yeah, old ladies are sitting on the porch embroidering and then nukes go off.
Scott: That's the whole story.
Scott: That's all that happens Right.
Scott: So how do you extend that to a good quality three or four page short story?
Scott: And basically it.
Scott: it he's basically like.
Scott: he doesn't explicitly come out with.
Scott: you know It's such the kind of bland language I would use because I can't write for shit.
Scott: He's like, you know, he's like, you know, he's like this here's an old lady and she's talking, you know He just has the old ladies just start discussing things, you know And they're just talking to each other.
Rym: that one in particular reminded me very much of hills like white elephants.
Scott: What cells like white elephants?
Rym: No, never mind then.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I Want to you know, at least talk about each story at least once a little bit, right?
Scott: Well, let's do this.
Scott: Which one did you think was the awesomest?
Rym: See, it's tricky because I like some for the style and I like some not necessarily for the style or the story itself.
Rym: But for the message of the story, all right.
Rym: So why don't you you could give like the best in each cat straight up my the story that I think is the most Relevant or the one that I would probably use in arguments or quote at people the most.
Scott: Oh the one that has the best message hands down is the flying machine.
Scott: I had to agree.
Scott: message wise.
Rym: The Emperor is you know, he murders the guy and he's like, all right I've murdered the guy everything's safe.
Rym: and then it's just like.
Rym: and then the Emperor regarded the birds.
Rym: Yeah, and it's.
Rym: it's like it doesn't?
Rym: does the Emperor get it?
Rym: if he does or if he doesn't he's fucked.
Rym: The Emperor might as well be the RIAA.
Rym: It's such a Perfect story and it's the fact that he wrote this 50 years ago and nobody has learned this lesson today.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: I mean basically the flying machine is about this this Emperor of China.
Rym: You've all read the book.
Rym: It's not like.
Rym: we need to explain to you what the stories are.
Scott: Oh, hopefully yeah.
Scott: But the point, you know, the whole thing of this guy's invented a flying machine and he's like, oh my god The flying machine obsolete's my great wall.
Scott: I need to make sure this technology doesn't get out because then my great wall is fucked.
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: so I'll kill the guy.
Scott: I'll punish the guy who's using the flying technology.
Scott: It's like dude, the flying technology is out of the bag.
Scott: I hate the birds.
Scott: Anyone can look at the birds and figure it out.
Scott: Great wall is already fucked.
Rym: the more deep message I think is simply that any truth can never be hidden because truth like truth about a fundamental universe is Fundamental truth.
Rym: It's a tautology.
Rym: Yeah, if it can be derived if it can be deduced it can be deduced It will be.
Scott: yes, and you know, it's sort of weird because I'm on the Emperor's side, right?
Scott: You can take it as sort of the message of the greater good message, which is like maybe even if you agree with that It's like okay.
Scott: Yeah, even if we should go for the greater good Right, what you should do is not kill the guy but use him to figure out a way to stop flying.
Rym: Take it from that like when that when back in the day we made PGP and encryption well GPG and all that Munitions and was illegal to export to certain countries.
Rym: Yeah, so Alright, you're saying that there's nobody smart on the bad guy side who can figure out math.
Scott: Yeah, right And it's like Okay, so I don't I won't send the actual software to Europe on a disk or anything But you know what?
Scott: This professor called that professor on the phone and now he knows and they just wrote the same exact software.
Rym: It's not like people can't figure it out.
Scott: He just looked in the academic journal which is published freely around the world in terms of stories that I found Amusing.
Rym: the first one the foghorn was the most amusing I think yeah In terms of just the physics because it had the Cthulhu feeling.
Scott: in terms of just the physicality of what happened.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean it had action, you know this freaking dinosaur comes from out in the bottom of the sea but it smashes lighthouse,
Rym: but it also felt very Cthulhu II and very Interesting and that the scene was very well set and very well described and all it was kind of funny of you know What the thing wants but also very poignant of how sad that is.
Scott: Yeah, it's you know, it's it's.
Scott: it's like all messy.
Scott: The One that I actually thought was the most sort of fun to read was the fruit at the bottom of the bowl Where this guy be basically right.
Scott: you you.
Scott: he does that same trick where he doesn't tell you exactly what happened.
Scott: you sort of figure out that he murdered this dude, right and He's like super paranoid that he's left his fingerprints somewhere and he's got a doubly.
Scott: make sure he hadn't leave him somewhere.
Scott: So he like goes around and he's like polishing the whole apart house like every single thing.
Rym: I love how they do not say that he went into the Attic but yet at the end they found him in the Attic.
Scott: Yeah, exactly, right.
Scott: He's actually polishing every single thing in the whole house and he's like flashing back to.
Scott: he's like that dude knew I was gonna kill him and he Tricked me into touching everything in his house.
Scott: And is it like?
Scott: it shows you.
Scott: you know how this guy not only murdered someone but was so Crazy in his mind and you know and so obsessive that he had to like cover up this murder.
Scott: and it took him so long To cover it up that he got caught in the morning.
Rym: If he obsessed over that he must have obsessed over others.
Rym: Obsessive kind of personalities Really say it wasn't science fiction.
Rym: It was just a really interesting vignette.
Scott: No, not all of these were science fiction.
Scott: I don't think he claims that all of them were science fiction either.
Rym: I mean the one with the witch and the invisible boy was really funny.
Scott: Oh, yeah That was just sort of like a fable almost.
Scott: Yeah of like Was she actually trying to trick him to eat him or not?
Scott: It's like I couldn't you know, or did she really just want his company?
Rym: I think she was just a lonely old lady.
Scott: Yeah, she's lonely old lady.
Scott: She tricked this boy into thinking he was invisible to keep him around Right, but then eventually like the invisible boy started, you know, he got.
Scott: he was fooling around with his invisibility.
Scott: She couldn't take it anymore.
Scott: So she got rid of him and then she was lonely again.
Rym: the April which one was really cute.
Scott: I don't know how cute that was.
Rym: I it was me.
Rym: I mean it entered a little message.
Rym: It wasn't.
Rym: it was the departure from the rest of the stories.
Scott: The other one was more whimsical.
Scott: Yeah, the one where What's it called?
Scott: Cuz they were weren't there - there was the one where the April which is where she like possesses someone to learn about.
Scott: right.
Scott: like cuz she wants to fall in love with some Makes them fall in love and you can talk about.
Rym: oh, it's springtime, you know 5th of May.
Scott: Yeah, but then the great fire right that one that one was about getting it on That one was about getting it on right.
Scott: is these people?
Scott: they really wanted to get this girl out of the house.
Scott: So, you know, they're like, oh she's got a boyfriend.
Scott: Hopefully they'll get married.
Scott: Yeah, hopefully.
Scott: but they didn't want to interfere because they might ruin it or embarrass her or something and they failed to notice that she was Getting on with like every boy in town.
Scott: Yeah, and only grandma knew what was up because grandma actually went out on the porch and was like saying hi The dinosaur one was not particularly good, but it gets points for being kind of dumb in a fun way.
Scott: the time Safari Forget the time Safari that was just sort of Reading.
Rym: I was like really really?
Scott: Yeah, and it was so You know.
Scott: and then the fact that you know, okay, they they they they messed up history They can't.
Scott: I like how the guy came to the few asshole and when they came to the future all they change was like the Political result.
Rym: It's like really The other guy with him is like you fucking asshole.
Scott: They were so upset about which guy became president.
Rym: Well, there's a bad guy.
Scott: Yeah Actually, you know the one.
Scott: you know the goal.
Rym: I figured the one you would like the most would be the one about the guy who didn't like to watch TV.
Scott: that yeah I mean that one and just in terms of having something relevant was the TV one.
Scott: But it wasn't really that as good as like say the one that reminded me a civilization the Golden Kite in the Silver Wind.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that was me.
Rym: I thought it was gonna be more complex.
Rym: I thought that it was a trick by the advisor to get the one nation to keep rebuilding.
Scott: I thought so too.
Rym: retired then they'd invade or it'd be like you must make a wall like the wind.
Rym: Because then blah blah blah and then as soon as there's no wall cuz it's like the wind Invasion.
Rym: and the fact that that didn't happen took me aback.
Scott: Yeah, I know right I thought it was gonna be one of those trick ones where a guy, you know But instead it was pretty much I made a wall and then you're beat up made a wall to beat my wall.
Scott: Then I you know, those rock-paper-scissors back and forth until they cooperated.
Scott: so it's sort of a prisoner's dilemma.
Rym: Yeah, but the moral was assholes.
Rym: if you both write Apple, we're all better off.
Rym: You've read orange.
Rym: We're fucked.
Scott: Yeah, that's it cuz that's true.
Scott: yeah, and it's pretty much they would.
Scott: one guy would write orange then the other guy right orange again Orange at the bottom of the bowl.
Rym: So, you know why I always use the Apple orange analogy?
Rym: because there's.
Rym: there are probably better analogies.
Rym: I use that one because that analogy was used in.
Rym: I'll choose your own adventure.
Rym: I read in like second grade And that taught me the prisoner's dilemma and that started me on the long road to game there.
Rym: I remember when I started reading game theory right like in high school and then at RIT when I got that scary book of game Theory, it was like prisoner's dilemma.
Rym: I was reading and I was like, wait a minute.
Scott: I know this.
Scott: Actually, you know to continue those one story that I sort of disagreed with the message, right?
Scott: The pedestrian was about the guy who didn't watch TV.
Scott: He would.
Scott: he just walked around.
Rym: Oh, I know exactly what you hear.
Scott: pieces, right and everyone else watched TV.
Scott: So he got like arrested for being you know, totally fucked up by the one automatic police car.
Scott: But the murderer was the.
Scott: what was about this guy who just couldn't stand all this technology Everywhere like making noise and he just wanted to see.
Rym: I do agree with the message of that one.
Rym: I do not know because I think you misunderstand the message.
Rym: Here's what I got out of it that guy his Luddite bullshit is crazy.
Rym: Yeah, and he is the bad guy of that story.
Scott: Here's my rationale, I think it's not definitely.
Rym: I definitely think Ray Bradbury is the kind of guy who would be like No, but at the same time my rationale is the up for this at least my reading of it now.
Scott: What's weird is they wrote this in what year cell phones weren't even on the chart.
Rym: I know this is great.
Rym: Bradbury was a very intelligent.
Rym: Well is a very intelligent.
Scott: you think that someone wrote this to complain like an old man wrote this recently to complain about cell phones And I pods and show.
Rym: you might as well be complaining about Twitter.
Rym: I could probably change some proper nouns and you would not even be able to know that was written, you know Plus years ago.
Scott: Yeah 60 years ago.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: Yeah but the way I read it whether or not Ray Bradbury intended it because if you ignore what his intent may or may not have been and read it it is easy to read this as this dissatisfied guy and the people who identify with him are the ones who haven't adjusted and everyone else has adjusted and is using this technology to their advantage and they just think this guy's crazy because He is crazy.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I tend you know, what I think it is is that in almost any sci-fi Twilight Zone anything like that, right?
Scott: You generally have this sort of Society and then you have the one guy and the one guy is always the thing that's right in society is always crazy Right.
Scott: It's all.
Scott: it's never there.
Scott: It's almost never.
Scott: the reverse of that You know, it's like look at like brave new world.
Scott: The one guy is like, all right, this brave new world is crazy and everyone else is like odd drugs and feelings.
Scott: Fuck yeah You know.
Scott: and it's like you look at like a Twilight Zone and it's like this one guy and then the whole world Explodes except for him of course.
Scott: then his glasses break the burbs.
Rym: if you ignore the you know Just I watched it again recently if you ignore the last like 30 seconds of the movie is The same kind of thing.
Rym: the one guy know that one guy is just crazy Okay.
Scott: Yeah, it just seems.
Scott: usually in the vast majority of sci-fi if there's so.
Scott: if there's one guy, you know Just like in Jeff Jeff Goldblum pedestrian then he's right.
Scott: You know like in the second story the pedestrian right the pedestrian is the guy who knows what's up and all the other people in Society are the ones who are not good, you know, they always portray society.
Scott: They always put the evil thing or the bad thing onto society and they put the good thing onto the one protagonist character.
Scott: They never.
Scott: they never put the bad things on the protagonist character and the good things on well I guess actually in the murderer they put the good things on this side.
Rym: I guess I just saw the story the murderer as being a little more even in the sides.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't you know.
Scott: The thing is mostly because the adjectives that they use to describe all the beeping and the buzzing wristwatches and the machines that were Generally negative and annoying.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but at the same time No, they didn't spend.
Scott: he didn't spend a lot of time talking about how these things were helping people.
Scott: They spent a lot of time discussing how they were annoying and bother.
Rym: if you read it from a transhumanist perspective Reading that made us feel annoyed.
Rym: It made me feel really annoyed at these talking things.
Rym: I probably would have smashed him, too Because I don't need help.
Rym: we have better ways of doing that.
Rym: I have my phone Yeah the screen.
Rym: but it's more the idea that if you read it from a transhumanist perspective that guy harkens back to our era and People from our era would not deal well with the future era with all these different ways.
Rym: You know this totally different societal framework Maybe and I guess I can.
Rym: the fact that the professor is looking at this guy like wow, he's crazy.
Rym: He walks out picks up a new phone a real new thingy and just continues his business like yeah, like whatever.
Rym: I don't care.
Rym: I'll ignore that guy I may.
Scott: actually there was one.
Scott: were there any ones like you just didn't get.
Scott: you were just like because it was one for me That I was just like.
Rym: well golden apples of the Sun.
Scott: No, no, no, the one that I was just like wah was the.
Scott: it was the powerhouse one.
Rym: I don't know I don't have anything.
Rym: I don't remember much about that.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's like cuz basically the whole story.
Rym: I got the book here.
Rym: Let me see if I can jog my memory.
Scott: Basically, they went and they stay wet.
Scott: there was this powerhouse and I thought it was gonna be about getting electrocuted or some shit.
Scott: Basically, it was like they they were traveling and they spent a night in this electrical building.
Rym: All right This was a long one.
Scott: It was like five pages and then they left and then she was like, oh, can we come and spend a night here again?
Rym: okay, the best I got out of it was that maybe Demystification makes people less afraid of things.
Scott: It didn't seem like they were afraid.
Scott: I don't know either.
Scott: Yeah, I just did I read this thing.
Rym: is?
Rym: I read this whole compilation a long time ago So I'm trying to remember details of that story.
Scott: I didn't get it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe someone can I got all the other ones.
Rym: I'll read it again.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh You know, which one was was fun.
Scott: was the the meadow right where the guy?
Rym: Oh, yeah I really like that one.
Scott: He's trying to save the movie sets from being torn down and about again Ray Bradbury.
Rym: It wasn't obvious.
Rym: It was movie sets right away.
Scott: No, of course not right but what was really cool was that it's sort of that thing happens that you always want to happen But never does.
Scott: in any other story where he basically gets the producer over He actually shows up the producer actually goes and talks to him and the producers actually a reasonable guy and then he's like, okay Well, we'll make good here.
Rym: and they did plus that a good picture with the Dragons and him kind of as the night.
Rym: Look at this picture.
Rym: That's a good picture.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: It's a high quality.
Rym: I think it's it's my one of my favorite pictures from the book.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely One of the better stories in there, I think in terms of you know, just enjoyment and something I'll remember too.
Scott: You know, I don't know if I'll remember the powerhouse.
Scott: What about the baseball one?
Rym: I really like to but it was just a good short story the bit the the baseball one the big black-and-white game.
Scott: Yeah, red.
Rym: I feel like that's the kind of thing if I was in like fourth grade.
Rym: We'd read in class and then talk about.
Scott: you should read America gods gold and golems by James Sturm.
Rym: Ah, that sounds up my alley.
Scott: Yeah, it's a comic.
Scott: That was the guy I went.
Scott: I bought his market day comic the new the newer one He came out with at the mocha.
Scott: He was there remember?
Rym: I was about to say yeah, but then I realized I was remembering something completely different.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So anyway, yeah He's any.
Scott: if a comic book says James Sturm on it.
Scott: It's usually gonna be a hardcover book.
Scott: You're gonna see you.
Scott: Oh, you should buy that.
Rym: the one about letter writing via the great wide world over There is so desperately relevant to old people dealing with the internet today.
Scott: Oh god fuck.
Rym: Like to a degree that was startling.
Scott: Well, it's not just old people.
Scott: the internet right and you could take that as a metaphor for so many things.
Scott: today.
Scott: We're just people being behind the times or people being uneducated and unable to you know Get with it.
Scott: or people just being separated from the world as the world passes them by.
Scott: Or you know.
Scott: and it's not just you know That's only the stories you get.
Scott: if you look at the main character the wife I don't even remember her name, of course, right?
Scott: But if you look at say the husband who's just like I who needs that shit, right people who don't even wanna Get with the time Yeah, the wife was the hero for at least wanting to get it and for understanding the other old lady.
Scott: Yes, and it was making it and we're the visiting nephews, right?
Scott: Yeah, but the husband he's like the the villain cuz he's like fuck.
Scott: He's like fuck, you know, you know.
Scott: everything we need in the world is on this farm.
Scott: Let's concentrate on our farming.
Rym: who notice what is what's the biggest problems we have today?
Rym: old people click on spam and listen to telemarketers Because they're lonely oftentimes and look at what she does she gets.
Rym: she asks for spam just so she has something to read.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: and then how about the old lady next door right who isn't?
Scott: he can't eat.
Scott: she knows she's not literate But she's pretending to be right just so she can pretend.
Scott: she's with the times To say she can feel like she's better than other people and she'll have something to talk about with the next-door neighbor.
Rym: that story though Reminded me how optimistic I am about not necessarily our whole generation But us like you and me and all the people like us.
Rym: when we're gonna old, you know, 70s 80s, maybe 90s retiring I'll never be bored.
Scott: when I'm an old man I'll never tell no at the very least right even if I'm grouchy and I hate everything new in the world and I think it's for the devil.
Scott: I still have the hundred two hundred years worth of entertainment media that I have consumed only a small portion of so I could just read comics and Watch movies and and play video games until I'm dead.
Rym: Yeah and if I can't play the video games anymore at all and I have to go to like board games or get like robot thing is Ones that take the longest are the ones that need the least manual dexterity like JRPGs and shit.
Rym: Go to the nurse like just take my Thumb to this.
Scott: a I might not be able to play quake anymore, but god damn it.
Scott: I'm gonna play Final Fantasy 30.
Rym: We'll still play quake, but we'll only play with each other.
Scott: Old man, we should make a video of old man quake.
Scott: Are you shiny?
Scott: watch out my rocket launcher.
Scott: Oh my finger.
Scott: I can't.
Scott: oh the fingers twitching.
Scott: I can't hit the right, okay I'll tell you what.
Rym: even if I'm 90 ground pound down no one's ever gonna beat me at that.
Scott: All right, let's let's talk about the the garbage collector right if you're the garbage collector, right?
Scott: I like this story because it in one way it showed like how you can have You know sort of a regular old job like collecting garbage and find some joy and awesomeness in it.
Scott: It's sort of just like office space right just be a construction worker, and there are some days I feel like that and then I remember I need rent, and you know those jobs.
Scott: Don't pay as much yeah, but anyway At the same time though it brings into this dilemma of you know what if you know suddenly your job?
Scott: Isn't what you signed up for?
Rym: well that happens to a lot of people.
Rym: I mean look at in Vietnam a lot of people who thought they were fighting of war worth fighting And then they ended up you know doing the like.
Scott: I didn't sign up for this shit Yeah, so what do you like?
Scott: What would you do if suddenly your work wasn't you say what you signed up for?
Scott: would you quit and go away like the garbage?
Scott: Man, or would you get used to the idea?
Rym: Well, there's a third way of going with it and trying to change it from within Which usually is a cop-out because usually people who say they're gonna do that never do that or they fail to do that.
Rym: I play.
Rym: there's a choose your own adventure.
Rym: You're in a Wild West long time ago.
Scott: Why choose your adventures coming up a lot here?
Rym: And there's a bandit gang and there are three choices with the bandit gang one fight the bandits run away.
Scott: Join the bandits.
Rym: fight the bandits.
Rym: join the bandits for real join the bandits and pretend to be with them and then to betray them later Uh-huh, and if you join them for real you die, okay?
Rym: But if you join them and pretend you totally win, okay, at least I think I don't really remember that.
Scott: What if you just try to fight them?
Rym: I think you die there, too Yeah, but no I I Don't know.
Rym: I've never been in a situation.
Rym: Well, the closest I got was when I worked for a company I worked for before I got to the company I work for now obviously not naming any names here I took moral issue with what I thought that company was doing and I fucking quit.
Scott: right quick All right, how about that?
Rym: In fact, I quit finger held high blaze of glory Nice.
Rym: Yeah, so all right.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Let me go down the list.
Scott: Make sure we didn't.
Rym: I think I've talked about everything That really I did.
Rym: like the embroidery one is that was just very just.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: That story was very touching in a way that the rest of them weren't and I was really kind of sad after reading that One.
Scott: let's let's just cover the last few.
Scott: we didn't discuss, right?
Scott: So the Sun in shadow was the one where they're like.
Scott: don't take your photos here Right.
Scott: and on the one hand it was sort of like, all right I think the people should be able to take photos over the hell they want.
Rym: See that goddamn note.
Rym: like when I took my bike over the RFK the triborough bridge.
Rym: It was like no photos for will prosecute.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: So, of course, I took pictures of that and videos all over the place.
Scott: Of course, I mean I have no problem taking photos.
Scott: But the thing was is I sort of agreed with the.
Scott: you know That this guy wasn't upset with the actual act of photo taking.
Scott: he was upset with that.
Scott: The fact that they were taking photos there showed their attitude towards him and his neighborhood and his neighbors.
Scott: and you know And I was sort of like yeah, you're right.
Scott: That guy does have the wrong, you know, he's treating you.
Scott: He's treating these people like they're you know a set piece as opposed to treat it.
Scott: You know, he's not thinking of them as human beings.
Scott: But at the same time he's like, oh look at these quaint villagers.
Scott: They will make an awesome photo background next to my you know, fashion model at the same time.
Rym: I mean, that's our world now I know right.
Scott: It's like while I'm for taking photos over the hell you want, right?
Scott: I'm you know, it is sort of.
Scott: I am against that attitude of looking at people as if they are.
Scott: You know not people as if they are, you know set pieces or whatnot.
Scott: And that was alright.
Rym: Yeah, of course we can solve that problem.
Rym: If Google at least the direct problem, they won't know we're taking pictures about pictures of them because Google takes them from space.
Scott: Yep Let's see, oh there was the one where the boy doesn't age.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you never read everlasting talk Did you know?
Scott: but it reminded me of that that recent movie with the the guy who ages backwards the?
Scott: the one with Robin Williams The I don't very recent one.
Rym: I don't think I saw this movie.
Scott: I saw it.
Scott: It was it was like popular for for like a couple weeks.
Rym: I was gonna talk about everlasting talk, which is a story about a family that just doesn't age Mm-hmm.
Scott: It was the night was a movie that was also based in a short story and it basically the beginning was full of Excitement, but then the end of the movie was sort of like a bleh Whatever.
Scott: Oh, I can't I remember the name of this thing.
Scott: Someone in the form is definitely gonna know it immediately.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: Oh, well, I don't have much else to say other than that.
Rym: I hope you guys enjoyed this collection of short stories.
Scott: Well, what about golden apples of the Sun itself?
Scott: I don't know that one didn't.
Rym: It didn't strike me other than that.
Rym: I like the way it was written.
Scott: really you didn't like.
Rym: I really enjoyed the way it was written and I got a really powerful feeling from it.
Scott: Oh, I got this really strong message of.
Scott: it's like you want to do something so awesome, right?
Scott: It's like you got to put everything on the line.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like it was like climbing Mount Everest.
Rym: almost, you know Same kind of all I can think reading it was we're heading off to Iskandar, right?
Scott: You know, it's like, you know, you're you're climbing Mount Everest.
Scott: if someone dies you leave them there, you know.
Scott: You know, there's gonna be dangerous shit, but you know what you have.
Scott: I can do it.
Scott: You know and like the.
Scott: it was so awesome Like the one really clever thing where it's like they're going to the Sun to get a scoop of the Sun, right?
Scott: And they go there.
Scott: So of course, they have a spaceship that's wicked cold.
Scott: They have this ultra cold ship and then there's.
Scott: so they're in this ultra cold spaceship and the spaceship is ultra cold.
Scott: So they can survive the Sun but they need to survive in the ultra cold.
Scott: So they've got protective suits to protect from the cold because they can do that.
Scott: They can insult they can insulate from that.
Scott: You know, of course, it's not realistic, duh, but whatever right and then the sky suit breaks and he dies from the cold When he's on the Sun.
Scott: I was like, oh, that's so awesome.
Rym: I guess the part I liked about that story was the whole we're going south.
Rym: We're going north.
Rym: Thing I just said the captain is like where are we going north?
Rym: and all the things like what time is it?
Scott: Yeah, the thing is if he was from the southern hemisphere, you'd have to reverse Yeah those directions, but at the same time it was coach like north.
Rym: It doesn't matter which direction you're going.
Scott: Well, I mean you're going towards the Sun or away from it.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: but no but think about the metaphor towards the Sun converges on a place you can be a destination that is a real destination by.
Rym: If that is south then north.
Rym: it doesn't matter which direction you're going because there's no destination.
Rym: It's every direction everywhere, but here is north.
Scott: Yep That's cool.
Rym: Yeah, that's just that's a vibe.
Rym: I like it when I used to.
Scott: I also like the idea of fucking scooping the Sun.
Rym: We know you can't do that But like it's the thing I used to do when I was a kid is I would get in my bike and I would pick A direction and I would go as far in that direction as I possibly could.
Scott: well At the North Pole everywhere you go is out, you know, yeah as you spin in a circle Yeah, or you take one step south and now you can turn around and go back north.
Rym: Yeah, East and West again.
Rym: so but I would literally pick a direction because far as I could in that direction and Eventually, I had gone as far as I could in every direction short of running away from home Coming I
Scott: was gonna say really how's that Pacific Ocean different point
Rym: as in like I'd bike.
Rym: All right I'm 40 miles away from my house.
Rym: I have to go back to my sophomore.
Rym: You know, I'm in high school I have classes tomorrow And it's midnight and I'm in the dark.
Rym: I don't know where I am because I know GPS is back.
Rym: then.
Scott: Yeah, what would your GPS do if you're on the Sun?
Rym: melt I Think we're done here.
Scott: Yeah This is fun doing a whole bunch of short stories because you didn't have to just keep find a whole bunch to say about one Story.
Scott: we could just say a whole bunch.
Rym: You can definitely tell that some stories affected me or Scott Moore because like I'd have a lot to say about one Scott I mean, there are some short story collections out there.
Scott: We're like every one is like a smash right and there are other ones Like.
Rym: there's one really awesome one and the rest are kind of yeah The only one that was Ed was the dinosaur one, but it made up for that by being so stupid.
Scott: What the time?
Scott: Not the lighthouse dinosaur dinosaur was awesome.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know I didn't Just for that moment at the end where he's like you fucker, I'm gonna time-traveling dinosaur when it's basically Jurassic Park, right?
Scott: I mean plus time travel.
Scott: Yeah, I mean which is actually weird because Michael Crichton's like he did Jurassic Park and timeline.
Scott: So he did a time travel and he did a die with with night arrows.
Rym: Anyone remember night arrows?
Scott: I read I read the book and you know I don't remember a single thing from except that there was night.
Scott: They went back to medieval times and there were night arrows.
Scott: I don't remember the night arrows arrows.
Rym: So night arrows is a shtick from movies.
Rym: You should say all right remember that We're in the movie.
Rym: At least I never read the book movie fucking sucks, by the way.
Rym: So they're fighting, you know, the the French and the French are out there.
Rym: Oh, and they're like, all right We've got to use the bad weapon.
Rym: We're going to use night arrows and everyone's like, oh fuck night arrows.
Rym: Wow What have we become night arrow?
Scott: They just fire arrows on fire.
Rym: They're like this died arrows.
Rym: I don't know if I'm comfortable using night arrows.
Rym: This is like the worst weapon in the world.
Rym: and then it cuts to like the French soldiers standing out there and apparently Normal arrows are just arrows that are on fire.
Rym: so you can see them coming night arrows.
Rym: They just don't light them on fire.
Rym: so it cuts to the French soldiers and they're like standing there and Suddenly like arrows fall and like a soldier falls down with an arrow in him and someone's like night arrows.
Scott: Okay, who did that and thought it was serious?
Rym: I don't even know if night arrows was a real chivalry thing or not.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: but night air that is one of my favorite episodes of movies.
Scott: You should see simply syndicated Yeah, but yeah, if you're right, you know, if you like some of the stories in here You should read anything else with Ray Bradbury his name on it.
Rym: Yeah, right, right, right.
Scott: You know, I'm really.
Scott: you know, I read Fahrenheit 451.
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Rym: he's very creative and he I feel like I really.
Scott: what I wonder is if he uses that same technique of Revealing the setting like that, you know in other works or if it's just something he did in these set of short stories Like you know, what a one of the books is he written?
Scott: I Don't even know them.
Scott: That's because I haven't read them and on that note.
Rym: That was the golden apples of the Sun Ray Bradbury.
Scott: the next book is Oh at the World War Z Z Z zombie.
Scott: World War Z zombies.
Scott: You're getting your zombies All right, so shut up is?
Rym: I swear to God you assholes if this book isn't good Ah, it's probably not gonna be good.
Scott: But you know what you asked for fucking zombies.
Scott: You're getting your goddamn zombies so you can shut son of a bitch.
Scott: from now on you're only getting what I want to give you You're gonna do.
Rym: here's the medicine you asked for you watch out because if we're playing bad medicine again I'm bringing out the fucking sutonius.
Scott: What the fuck sutonius?
Rym: or maybe the Odyssey?
Scott: you got to bring out something's Elise.
Rym: All right, you know, hey, but the Odyssey you're saying the Odyssey isn't awesome.
Scott: It's pretty big.
Rym: It's not that big.
Rym: The Odyssey is not that long.
Rym: Actually.
Scott: What if the sirens?
Scott: I heed their call?
Rym: All right, I'll bring out.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: fucking war and peace.
Rym: Maybe that look called a Monte Cristo crime and punishment.
Rym: crime and punishment is not that long either.
Rym: It's actually really good.
Rym: And actually I think people really enjoy crime and punishment.
Rym: It's the story of a guy who thinks thinks he's the uber mesh.
Rym: He's fucking not.
Scott: Why don't we do?
Scott: why don't we do Tesco's crime and punishment?
Rym: Yeah, I heard that's not that good.
Rym: No Wait ambassador magma.
Rym: There we go ambassador.
Scott: We should do What the fuck I feel like I should do the days in front of.
Rym: I didn't like Dante's Inferno.
Rym: I didn't enjoy reading that paradise lost.
Rym: I didn't enjoy paradise lost either Milton.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: I don't like your writing.
Rym: There's some Hawthorne.
Rym: I'd save on Hawthorne.
Scott: Why don't we do some letter up ins?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.