Rym: Hey, it's Monday August 2nd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight a Monday episode.
Rym: For the first time in a while.
Rym: Automated killing machine.
Scott: for the first time in a while Let's do this.
Rym: Hmm do the bender help that?
Rym: do the better start Scott to draw penises on your boogie board.
Scott: What I mean?
Rym: you're ready to do a shower.
Rym: you uh you finish there.
Rym: That's a quite a cock.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Rym: You see it's too bad that this is just a radio show.
Rym: Scott drew a magnificent penis on his boogie board.
Rym: This is like the fourth one.
Rym: He's drawn while we were doing pre-production.
Rym: In fact, he drew so many hairs on it that it started to obscure the very nature of the base of the phallus.
Scott: What is what is wrong with you?
Rym: Scott I could just take a picture with my phone anytime.
Rym: So you might want to cut that a picture of what that penis.
Scott: Why you want to take a picture of my penis, okay moving on We've done a Monday show so I guess you start off with penises.
Scott: that's just wonderful.
Rym: we we we I Believe it is you and you alone who brought the penis into this conversation.
Scott: what penis?
Scott: I didn't even say anything.
Rym: Of course you drew it.
Scott: What did I draw Scott?
Rym: You're obsessed with this like off-band sub channel communication.
Rym: Uh-huh Okay, we'll see when you draw another penis.
Scott: I got my eye on you.
Scott: So anyway, we haven't done a Monday show and like for fuck ever.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's actually Tuesday, isn't it?
Rym: We were gonna pretend that we put this show up yesterday and see who noticed.
Scott: I like how I want to pretend and keep something secret.
Scott: We don't but when you want to pretend we also don't.
Rym: yeah Well, we I mean our review of Otakon will be up cuz we were there and it was awesome.
Scott: I know you weren't.
Rym: you weren't there.
Scott: No, it sounded pretty good though.
Rym: Yeah There were no new complaints.
Rym: that has nothing to do with Monday now, but it's weird Usually at this time of year, right?
Rym: Otakon Otakon GeekNights gets totally screwed up because like we go to Otakon then we go to the week of awesome our writers Retreat and then pags at all these conventions.
Rym: So we'll have like a week or two where GeekNights is just like gone and then we come back this year.
Rym: Fucking nothing happened.
Rym: We just didn't do Monday show forever.
Scott: We're going to PAX though in a month in the month and that will definitely interrupt the the GeekNights.
Rym: Also, I'm going to the writers retreat next week.
Rym: So I'm gonna be gone.
Rym: I don't know what'll happen.
Rym: We there may or may not be GeekNights.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Yeah, we haven't done a Monday show and fuck ever.
Scott: just cuz it was always like coincidences that we had things to.
Scott: you know It was either you know Monday night wasn't on the schedule or we had an actual thing to go to.
Scott: So it was like We're either going to a thing when we're supposed to do a show or it's not time to do a show.
Scott: and no Monday Shows got made for over a month and a half in every instance.
Rym: It was a situation where normally would say Well, we'll just do a Monday show next week and even it out the next week.
Rym: There was something else on Monday Yeah, including yesterday.
Scott: There was something on Monday, but it had been so long since a Monday show.
Scott: We just had to do one anyway, and we'll just back date it so that it goes up.
Rym: I think what hurts too is that I do have a lot to say about tech.
Rym: like there's a lot of tech news there's stuff going on, but It's been not just gaming season.
Rym: It has been PC gaming season.
Scott: for me for a while now It has been PC.
Scott: It's been everything season.
Scott: Wait, wait gig nights.
Rym: 2006 called PC gaming is dead.
Scott: I know right now.
Rym: It's back.
Scott: Not really steam saved.
Scott: a thing is steam that I love that everyone else hate.
Rym: as big as my PC gaming is right now It's still a drop in the bucket compared to console gaming everywhere else.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much It's a PC gaming Renaissance for us and Koreans.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah, Scott John's you just popped up playing Starcraft 2.
Scott: You know, I haven't played Starcraft 2 yet.
Scott: cuz I'm playing Starcraft You shouldn't?
Rym: you should make that configuration change first or it'll make your video card overheat.
Rym: All right, there's a problem.
Rym: It's ruining people's video cards.
Scott: Is this true?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Well, here's the deal.
Rym: It does not have a frame cap.
Rym: So a lot of people with ATI cards or with laptops or anything like that When they're near in the menus if you sit in the menu too long, it runs at a near infinite frame rate.
Rym: So the video card says I gotta pump out as many frames as I can and max.
Scott: what if I just enable vertical sync?
Rym: Uh, I don't know if that fixes it.
Rym: There's some particular I and I follow.
Rym: you have to update.
Scott: Why don't?
Scott: they just put it a patch they haven't yet?
Rym: Okay, I imagine they will.
Rym: I Changed this configuration setting like slash job told me to and my computer stopped overheating playing Starcraft.
Rym: So I'd recommend all of you do that.
Scott: All right, I guess that's technology related.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah So anyway, so the worst thing is I'm at work, right and my co-workers like yeah Starcraft 2 keeps making my PC crash But nothing else does.
Rym: and I was like, well clearly you have an ATI card He's like that's not the problem.
Rym: But I do have an ATI card and I was like, it's totally your drivers.
Rym: He's like, no, you're full of shit.
Rym: and then Yesterday, I was like, yeah, you know what?
Rym: ATI sucks, but Well, I had to clarify to qualify that again.
Rym: ATI sucks at certain price points.
Scott: And this is that all.
Scott: right now ATI is actually beating Nvidia at the price performance ratio.
Rym: Yeah at the specially at the high-end ATR cards.
Rym: kick the ass.
Scott: the problem is the drivers suck.
Rym: They don't suck nearly as much as they used to to the point.
Rym: suck that it's pretty much a non-issue Unless you use Linux.
Rym: Yeah, and even then it's not that bad.
Scott: I Still wouldn't get one.
Rym: I wouldn't get one either but you know what?
Rym: I'm in a position where price doesn't matter anymore.
Rym: If I didn't have the money I have I would still consider AMD.
Rym: every time I build a computer I buy Intel just because I can pay money.
Scott: to not worry I just want to point out right of all the can we've been building computers for like over a decade, right?
Scott: And So in the late 90s, I bought I made a Pentium 3 and after that for the next decade.
Rym: Well that had what that Intel BX board.
Scott: Yeah, the one that still works probably.
Scott: Yeah, every a bit I only replaced it because it was old and slow not because it stopped working.
Rym: I've got like three a bit.
Rym: It ran a really kickin icy world server that I built along the way That have come and died in the span of that BX board continuing Yeah, and meanwhile right for a decade.
Scott: I kept buying AMD computers And they all failed.
Scott: and then I just bought an Intel computer and it's a hundred percent perfect in every way.
Rym: Yeah I think the difference is I Don't put as much effort into building computers as I used to because it doesn't it.
Rym: it's weird.
Rym: It's like it doesn't matter as much when I was building my first computer and I spent like four grand and I got that Scuzzy card and that holy shit Rym has a CD burner.
Scott: I had a CD burner is a hundred and fifty dollar.
Scott: Plex door.
Scott: Yeah, 8x.
Rym: Remember when it mattered like you'd?
Rym: you'd be like I'm buying the Plex door.
Rym: It cost ten times as much but it doesn't coaster now.
Rym: I buy the cheapest piece of shit burner.
Rym: that's on new.
Scott: a well That's because you're hardly burning right?
Scott: And even if I burn is those days you were burning it the fuck up.
Scott: But nowadays your heart you you know, what's the last time you burned anything?
Rym: I was gonna make a joke about dinner, but Yeah.
Rym: or the more meta joke AMD the further repeat meta joke I burned out my video card playing Starcraft.
Scott: Yeah I've burned your face off with my flamethrower.
Scott: burns your mom with what?
Scott: Your mom you got to use some lube so you don't get burned.
Rym: If your mom wasn't so dry wouldn't be an issue, okay But and so small.
Rym: but like I used to agonize over like do I get this cast latency?
Rym: that cast latency?
Rym: I'd look at benchmarks now.
Rym: I can look and say you know what.
Rym: a hundred bucks more I'll guarantee I don't have a problem with X and I'm just like, alright a hundred bucks or four hours of research.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, so I'll say this all of you out there GeekNights listeners if you're building a new computer Go to our old episodes for advice because now my advice really boils down to spend money or spend time.
Scott: Researching thing is remember those guys at ConnectiCon I wish I remember.
Rym: Oh, yeah, go to those guys those guys, right?
Scott: So these guys get did a panel about building a computer and I think they run a computer building company.
Rym: I was for gamers and Scott And vocal.
Scott: they completely agree with with us Even though it's their jobs and it's our like fifth or sixth hobby.
Rym: Thing is they agree with us on the high-level stuff, which you know.
Rym: people who disagree I think are pretty much just wrong.
Rym: But on the low-level stuff, it's not that we disagree it's that I don't know anymore.
Rym: Mmm, I don't know what cast latency to get or if it even matters.
Scott: Yes, get the best RAM that works in your motherboard and get enough of wait Wait the best RAM.
Rym: so you get the RAM that's rated for way over your clock speed.
Scott: No, that cost ten times as much the brand whatever your motherboard says.
Scott: So the motherboard says get DDR 800 then get DDR 800.
Scott: What are you gonna?
Rym: What are you gonna get?
Rym: Viking Corsair?
Scott: You get whichever one's cheapest.
Rym: it used to matter.
Rym: I used to be at RAM and it would fucking break.
Scott: Well nowadays ram has you know doesn't break.
Rym: I'll have to buy like G-skill whatever this ran.
Rym: that looks so rice re and I look at I'm like do I really need that?
Rym: and then it's the cheapest And it works.
Rym: So okay guys, I've got blingin ram in there.
Scott: I also have some blingin ram.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, the where were you on Monday?
Scott: Oh So Basically, I'm like reading way less and less internets every day.
Scott: So I'm trying to.
Rym: I don't go to FARC anymore except when I need a thing of the day.
Scott: You know what my strategy is my long my strategy right in the beginning.
Scott: I was reading way all the internets.
Rym: Oh, yeah, go back to the beginning.
Rym: I read the entire internet which back then back then it was easy.
Rym: the internet when we were at RIT was comprised of BB spot meme pool Facebook.
Rym: No, not even Facebook Slashdot dig.
Rym: Oh, no, there wasn't even dig yet.
Rym: There wasn't much internet to look at now.
Scott: So anyway, I read all the internets and then I got a Google Reader and I was like reading all the internets And then I was reading dig and all the internets and then I stopped reading dig And then I stopped reading a bunch of stuff.
Rym: I can only read so many articles about how Ron Paul's gonna know.
Scott: So I was just reading in gadget Kotaku and boing boing and that's it.
Scott: And then when I got home at night, I would like watch CollegeHumor once and watch Cinemassacre if there's something new and that was it Right.
Scott: I even I even had a shit ton of podcasts.
Scott: now I've got like almost no podcasts cut them out.
Scott: and then.
Scott: So what I did recently like a few days ago is I started using Google Reader again.
Scott: So you think oh, no, that's more Internet's not less.
Scott: But here's what I did is I put oh I put in gadget Kotaku and boing boing in the Google Reader.
Scott: So I was really only visiting one site.
Rym: That was my biggest problem with Google Reader at first when I thought I need to consolidate my website reading to save time.
Rym: So I put all my websites in Google Reader and the same articles.
Rym: They're like a thousand times.
Scott: So now I was reading three.
Scott: I was reading the same what three websites.
Scott: but I was doing in Google Reader and the difference was instead of scrolling past all These pictures and stopping at all these interesting things.
Scott: I was reading way less articles.
Scott: Like.
Scott: this is only like a couple weeks ago.
Scott: I did this right like I would read almost none of the articles and then I would click mark all is red.
Scott: They would all go away, you know, unless something really jumped out at me with its title not with its picture.
Scott: Just gone, right?
Scott: And So now I stopped going to the Google Reader.
Scott: so the only sites I look at are I look at my tweets like once or twice a day and College Humor once a day and Cinemassacre if there's an update and the wow and the
Rym: Scott checking the internet things like Cinemassacre that don't even update that often are beating out things like the news.
Scott: Yeah Google News done.
Scott: Forget it.
Scott: I'm just done reading.
Scott: I go to Google News once a day, but That wouldn't be so bad.
Scott: But the thing is it's like destroy.
Rym: I'm in.
Rym: I need to.
Rym: I need to be aware to a degree Like it's not like I can be aware later.
Rym: Like I can't get home from work and like skim the news.
Rym: I got to know like today what's going on?
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is is That?
Scott: well, I guess I spent all this time reading news that was could spend doing something.
Scott: So now I'm done just reading all this bullshit.
Scott: Well, I guess I should qualify that when it's time to find a news or thing today I'll load them up and look around.
Rym: but everyone should be informed of like current events because you know what's going on in the world.
Rym: But the difference is most people also are kind of addicted I think to the emergence to where they don't need to know the state of the world.
Rym: They need to know what's the most interesting thing right now, and I think that is very counterproductive.
Scott: Thing is I don't think I really need to know, you know, let's look on Google News.
Scott: Let's see what is important for me to know.
Scott: Let's see That there was a killing in Connecticut not important for me to know.
Rym: I think knowing about the status of the Gulf oil spill is good to know.
Scott: At least I don't need to know the status of it.
Scott: I mean, I know there's a Gulf oil spill.
Scott: what that's enough.
Rym: I need to know for the industry I'm in.
Rym: that'll really affect my day-to-day life.
Scott: All right, there's a new blackberry.
Scott: don't need to know that bread carve.
Rym: I was interested in the new blackberry because there's all this.
Rym: you see you this is interesting.
Rym: This is your skewed view.
Rym: There's a new blackberry my view.
Rym: all this crazy stuff is going on with Rym and Saudi Arabia and I can't talk about it But it there's.
Rym: there's a lot of important stuff going on.
Scott: It's funny that your name is Rym and their company is Rym anyway And I don't use a blackberry because I hate blackberries.
Rym: bread farve not important But Scott Bristol Palin is I think breaking up with someone.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: I Boston Celtics might sign you cares jailbreak.
Scott: I'm never gonna jailbreak ever.
Rym: You're looking at just Google News.
Rym: I subscribe to very specific Google News feeds Finance because I need to know that.
Rym: I don't need to know that Yeah, but I need I do world politics because I want to be aware of that.
Rym: Okay, that's it.
Rym: And domestic Oh, I guess world foreign relations and like domestic politics and finance and that's it.
Rym: and science.
Rym: But I have a feed that blocks out BS science.
Scott: Well, the Sun eruption spits plasma at Earth.
Scott: So there's one story that might be important.
Rym: That's the story.
Rym: that story will have no impact on you.
Scott: You don't think it's gonna cause a disruption.
Rym: not to you maybe to me, but not to you.
Scott: Why do you care?
Rym: How is that going to impact your life?
Scott: If there's a it there's a big solar flare.
Scott: It could totally fuck up like, you know the Internet's Probably not.
Scott: No, you don't think so now.
Scott: All right, then that's not important.
Rym: All right I Read Google News like but once a day, I think I'm trying to kind of get into knowing or not knowing It's a matter of.
Rym: I think a lot of the people who spend a lot of their time reading the Internet are Reading.
Rym: they read the news not to be informed about the world.
Rym: They read the news to get the serotonin fix.
Rym: They get the same thing from going to Google News that I get from going to FARC.
Scott: So there's nothing on Google News I needed to know.
Scott: let's look at you know, even in the Hacker News.
Scott: I was reading the Hacker News a while.
Scott: That's actually a fourth site that I added.
Rym: the honestly the biggest site that I gave up was BB spot and not BB spot.
Rym: Boing boing.
Rym: BB spot is like it used to serve the purpose that boing boing serve.
Rym: boing boing is nothing more to me than a Serotonin fix.
Rym: you want to see something interesting?
Rym: Here you go.
Rym: Always something interesting but never anything useful because if anything useful is there.
Rym: it's also on slash dot and it's also in all my other Aggregators.
Scott: the problem with the Hacker News right is that it has really good stuff But the thing is most of it it's actually run by this Y Combinator startup thing.
Scott: So like it's it's rough because if you go to any tech news site It's like all the tech news is getting intermingled with all this startup business news.
Scott: It's like get the fuck out.
Scott: Just tell me you know about programming or cool open source thing.
Scott: That's so.
Scott: so so don't give me all this.
Scott: You know, here's how to get rich bullshit.
Scott: get the fuck out of here.
Rym: This is us the utility to this day of Slash dot.
Rym: now hear me out.
Rym: I read slash dot is one of these so slow?
Rym: exactly This is one of the few websites.
Rym: I actually read.
Rym: I mean I skim FARC, especially if I need to think of the day.
Rym: and FARC updates faster than the real news.
Rym: Like if there's something emergent, I read the real news looking for articles that will affect me and I have filters for that.
Rym: But I read slash dot because it does not have the emergent news.
Rym: I do not get the serotonin fix.
Rym: slash dot does not update fast enough to have the serotonin fix.
Rym: it gets news days sometimes weeks late
Scott: But
Rym: if you read slash dot Regularly like once a day you go to slash shot and just read everything or at least look at all the titles You will get within the span of a couple weeks Everything noteworthy in the tech world.
Rym: a nice summary of it.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So as a result, I don't get my serotonin fix.
Rym: I break my addiction to the internet, but I'm still informed of everything going on in the tech world.
Rym: I may be about a week late to everything But if something's emergent enough to where me finding out about it now as opposed to a week later matters I have other streams that get it to me faster.
Scott: The thing is I could just read like engage it once a week and I'll be good, you know It's like if I need to know there's too much bullshit in it and get half the stuff on.
Rym: engage it I don't care about no.
Scott: No, but here's what the thing with engage it Is that you can you don't have to actually scroll down just look at like the top stories like the little grid of pictures at the top and those are all the big stories also and gadget has these daily posts that say if you look the Last post of every day right before midnight and gadget makes a post that shows the popularity of all the stories of the day.
Scott: So all you have to do is read this maybe two stories in the red per day on average.
Scott: so really if you know if you don't read and gadget for a week go look at all those posts and click on all the Red dots and you'll get like the 14 biggest freaking stories in all of tech, you know and gadgets electronics.
Rym: I think we should cut this conversation off because that was almost a show.
Rym: Yeah Okay, we should probably do a show on reading the internet because I'd look maybe that should have been this show.
Rym: We did a show on reading the internet a long time ago.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I bet if we listen to it, we will not agree with ourselves.
Scott: That's probably true for most of the old shows.
Rym: yeah, so I feel we should revisit old shows do the topic again and then post the old show in the feed again and then We will listen to it and then react to our old bullshit.
Scott: Should we?
Scott: Alright, should I talk about where I was yesterday or not?
Rym: You want to?
Scott: I don't know how much time do we use?
Scott: We've got.
Rym: this has been like 24 minutes.
Scott: All right, let's let's forget it.
Rym: We'll move on very briefly.
Rym: I do have a news it's worth talking about but briefly brief briefly Brief arena, I don't know why I got on some briefs.
Rym: No, god, no only little only like I can't to this day anyone in what tighty whities like just you know briefs.
Rym: I Cannot imagine you as being anything but an eight-year-old boy.
Rym: Seriously tidy whities That is what you're wearing.
Scott: this reasons.
Rym: Yeah, you know what men wear boxers Unless they're running.
Rym: then men wear Boxer briefs.
Scott: Boxer briefs are no different than briefs.
Scott: They just have leg parts.
Rym: Yes, and you only wear them running.
Rym: No other situation warrants them.
Rym: Anyway, so you can't charge your Apple stuff with commodity stuff for no good reason.
Rym: and here's proof.
Rym: This may not the minute because it'll say if you plug certain like just a random USB charger Into an Apple device a lot of times it'll say something like not supported charging device.
Scott: No, the reason that'll happen like for example I had I had some like old iPod accessories.
Scott: Right that would and you know, there's all these pins in the dock connector.
Scott: Yeah, and a lot of these old accessories would try to charge the iPod on the firewire pins, right?
Scott: But I Apple has removed firewire support from the iPods and iPhones and that was just USB support.
Scott: So the thing is is those pins are still on the dock connector.
Scott: So if the iPhone or a newer iPhone or iPod detects charging on the firewire connector It'll put up an error message like hey, just so you know, we can use this accessory But we can't charge from it because it's charging the old way and not the new way.
Scott: But if you charge on the USB pins it where it charge now, this is much more insidious.
Rym: So say someone, you know, you can USB cable to an iPhone, right?
Scott: Okay, you need the dock connector though.
Rym: Yeah, so you know what.
Rym: the dock connector aside.
Rym: It's just USB.
Rym: plug it into a computer it charges, right?
Scott: If you hook up the the correct pin to the correct Yeah, nobody.
Rym: you have the Apple thing the USB cable.
Rym: Okay, plug it in your computer just charges, right?
Rym: Yep
Scott: so
Rym: if I make a device that isn't a computer and I want it to like the minty boost and I want to just charge my iPhone from it and I have an adapter cable and Everything uses the right pins because it's just USB it acts just like a USB device.
Rym: Yeah, you'll usually get a screen that says charging is not supported with this accessory.
Rym: Uh-huh, so minty boost there's this whole expose and I'm linking to it.
Rym: You can watch it.
Rym: It's pretty cool.
Rym: Disassemble the device that works and figure it out that Apple requires some weird low voltages Just to as far as they can tell prevent non licensed devices from charging the iPhone directly.
Scott: I don't know you had to be licensed to make an iPod accessory.
Scott: There's so many fucking accessories out there.
Scott: So if
Rym: you plug your iPhone into my like crap wall USB charger that Chinatown deal I bought it probably won't charge
Scott: Really,
Rym: but the minty boot they figured it out and this video shows how you how they figured it out how they got around it And it's why don't
Scott: they just take like?
Scott: I have a thing from Apple.
Scott: That's basically an AC.
Scott: It's an AC.
Rym: They took one of those broke it open.
Rym: Yeah figured out what was different.
Rym: It was a couple of resistors to change the voltages slightly.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah, it's a pretty cool.
Scott: Then why then how come a computer works?
Scott: Computers not changing the full?
Rym: I'd recommend you watch the video.
Rym: It's a pretty good.
Rym: I don't want it's a long video.
Rym: I was watching it as you arrived tonight and we've gone on for a while.
Rym: so It's interesting because I think what we need is a universal standard somehow for Chuck Oh USB, huh?
Rym: I feel like all devices should have the same way to charge and they should have to handle the circuitry internally Whatever bullshit battery they use and that'll be the end of it.
Rym: We'll just have USB.
Scott: Well, the thing is even depending on what battery you got.
Scott: you might need different chart, you know.
Scott: Yeah, you gotta have.
Rym: I think the circuitry should be required in the device and maybe you can file for an exception if your device Special.
Rym: yeah, China's already trying to mandate universal chargers for all cell phones.
Scott: That's a pretty good thing.
Rym: Imagine if we got to a point where you have wall outlets, right and you have a USB hole in every wall outlet Just for charging USB enabled charging devices.
Scott: or what if we got to the point where there's no AC power in the wall.
Scott: It's just USB everywhere.
Rym: Well That's problematic for a lot of reasons.
Rym: I hope you know them.
Rym: So Things of the day.
Rym: this is pretty badass.
Rym: some Russian guy and he took Photographs from World War.
Rym: two black and white real photographs of places found the places the buildings these steps In fact, what about ones that got blowed up?
Rym: Well the he handles that.
Rym: he finds the physical location where these photos were taken Takes just a photo in the modern day and kind of maps them together perfectly But leaves the black and white there and made this series of photos entitled the ghosts of World War two.
Rym: It is pretty amazing to see these juxtapositions.
Rym: this is a really cool photo gallery and Kind of like.
Rym: remember that site that would take a picture of a street corner in New York City from like 1902 And then show you a shot from the same angle at the same corner today.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's the same thing but kind of done even more elegantly.
Rym: The first one's the best.
Rym: it's just this.
Rym: this building and these Soviet officers kind of walking down the steps and Around them are just all the tourists at this building in Germany in modern day.
Rym: Yeah, it is like a part.
Rym: It is so cool I don't.
Rym: there's nothing else I can say about it.
Rym: I mean, I guess I could describe all the pictures.
Rym: You should totally check this out All righty.
Scott: So here I have an animated gif gif whatever.
Rym: But you think otherwise you are all.
Scott: I say gif but actually Actually, you know, correct term is gif yes, and you know what bullshit cuz jiff is peanut butter.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: The correct term is GNU Linux.
Scott: Yeah, fuck.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: Well then if you say gif You're obligated to say GNU Linux.
Scott: No, you're not.
Rym: anyway say gif you can say Linux.
Scott: so the.
Scott: Anyway, what if I'm just referring to the Linux kernel and not to the whole thing?
Rym: You have to say the Linux kernel has differentiated from the GNU toolset.
Rym: Uh-huh Anyway, I'm curious pull respond in the forums.
Rym: How many of you actually know what we're talking about?
Rym: I'm really curious.
Rym: Let us know if you do in fact know what we're talking about or if you don't say anyway You know the theorem of Pythagoras.
Rym: Pythagoras is there about a bag of reading there?
Scott: No about the the the proportion of the sides of a right triangle.
Scott: how you know the the hypotenuse will be equal to.
Scott: well the square root of the Hypotenuse is equal to the sum of the non Hypotenuses.
Rym: both each squared a squared plus b squared equals c squared is something to that effect that effect, right?
Scott: You know, I learned it in the schools.
Rym: I think in ninth grade into geometry class My eighth grade teacher didn't teach it to us.
Rym: I already knew it like everyone in the class knew it but he pointedly would not let us use it until we could prove it.
Scott: No, anyway, I learned it in that in you know ninth grade and I learned it pretty quick.
Scott: It was pretty easy to do.
Scott: I understood it.
Rym: That was that I cited history textbook as proof And I failed a test.
Scott: not not everyone in the class really understood it so quickly You know, we had to keep working on it for quite a while.
Rym: But at least think about the difference between math classes and science classes.
Rym: No one in the math class was like I. just I'm not convinced.
Rym: They always accept it as true.
Rym: They might not understand how you got there, but no one's like yeah the theory of Pythagoras.
Scott: I'm not buying it Anyway, it's just a theory It's not a fact.
Rym: I'm gonna keep measuring him.
Rym: I think you're wrong.
Scott: But anyway, you know, it's not everyone in the class understood it right away.
Scott: and I saw this animated gif here.
Scott: Yes, and This image this this little animation pretty much just shows you the Pythagorean theorem and how any Moron can understand why it is true and how it works and all that.
Scott: and why didn't?
Scott: they could have just showed this to my freaking class And it would've been ten times better than what the old lady teacher was doing.
Rym: I'm a big fan of teaching the same thing if it's a complex topic or in public school Even if it's a normal topic.
Rym: now teachers to teach the exact same concept three times with like three completely different means.
Rym: Because think about what that'll do for a smart kid.
Rym: It'll show them kind of different applications or different ways to approach For dumb kids.
Rym: What are the ways is probably gonna work?
Scott: It's win-win Yeah, but this image it's like if you don't understand the Pythagorean theorem and even if you do understand it but you just want to be like Just just like.
Rym: remember that thing in the day I had a long time ago of the three dimensional shape and could you turn it inside out and the proof of how to do It.
Scott: it's kind of like that.
Rym: Yeah, only this makes sense.
Rym: Fuck that.
Scott: Yeah I think all math classes really need to have that sort of and this sort of thing going on.
Rym: well everything class Cool math.
Scott: it's like, you know, this makes math fun.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: usually math is not fun But this is the kind of thing you see it and you're like, ah, it's fun.
Rym: math physics classes Did that.
Rym: they'd always use the simulators where they you know, we'd simulate like the thing falling.
Rym: and yeah something You know.
Scott: and the thing is it always be a gun shooting a monkey in a tree or an explosion or something like that.
Scott: You know we did so.
Rym: we had to do the monkey experiment.
Rym: We know we will know the experience.
Scott: shot a real monkey out of a real tree.
Rym: So we did the monkey math and then we set up a gun and a stuffed monkey outside real gun.
Rym: It was a BB gun.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I was the first second.
Scott: I considered lying being like, yeah Yeah, yeah, you should just use you know, you should use though to be far cooler.
Scott: real monkey.
Scott: No trebuchet.
Rym: I Wanted to make a trebuchet.
Scott: You don't aim the trebuchet at the monkey.
Scott: you put the monkey in the trip.
Rym: I also wanted to make a betatron and I came up with plant me and a couple of kids in AP physics.
Rym: We're like, we've literally made a droop plans to make a betatron around the football field and the school was like, yeah.
Scott: No Just do it at night.
Rym: We needed like five thousand dollars for parts.
Scott: So your computer.
Rym: Yeah, now I built that computer anyway But yeah, so the metal is a thing of the day.
Rym: Yeah, okay Moment.
Scott: Oh, I forgot.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: We said the thing Wow unprofessional.
Rym: Are we?
Scott: what's the book?
Rym: The book club book is the red apples of the Sun by Ray Bradbury.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: We're gonna do a show that Ray Bradbury was at comic-con and was totally awesome.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: He's totally awesome He's.
Scott: I didn't know he was alive, but he's like 90 something.
Scott: Holy shit, man.
Rym: Ray Bradbury his sci-fi It's.
Rym: it amazes me revving discussion.
Scott: That's the real sci-fi right there.
Scott: Yep
Rym: well, we're having a discussion with some of our friends over the weekend while we're out hiking and Basically, I've realized that the majority of people I know have not actually read very much hard sci-fi at all and
Scott: even very much I mean, I've recently learned I used to use the term hard sci-fi incorrectly.
Scott: I used to use the term hard sci-fi to separate actual science fiction from Book that just happens to be about outer space or has spacemen in it and isn't actually science.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I've noticed the more space ships and space things are on the cover the less about space it is Unless it's about physics.
Scott: Yeah, it's like okay Star Wars not science fiction.
Scott: Really?
Scott: It's it's sort of an adventure story that just happens to be in space with spaceships.
Scott: That doesn't space and spaceships.
Scott: don't make it science fiction.
Scott: You could have science fiction without any outer space at all.
Rym: Star Trek much more science fiction, but of course also soap opera.
Scott: Yeah You know.
Scott: and then you've got something like brave new world totally science fiction all the way through.
Scott: no outer space none zero.
Rym: Anyway, but so, you know, I used to use hard science fiction when I meant But I'm not talking about people reading crap instead of good stuff I just realized that most people if they've read Asimov have maybe read one work.
Rym: if they've right they've most he's got.
Scott: so Fucking many is like fucking Tezuka.
Rym: Most people I've run into to have never read any Ray Bradbury Yeah, I've met very few people in my life who have read any Bradbury.
Rym: Ah Yeah, anyway, yeah, so red apples of the Sun you will enjoy it.
Rym: maybe was golden apples, I think it's red apples I keep forgetting.
Scott: it's apples of the Sun.
Scott: search for Bradbury on freaking Amazon.
Rym: Watch.
Rym: He's got like 10 Apple books.
Rym: It's the Apple continuum.
Rym: I don't know about it.
Scott: Anyway, here's some events schedule.
Rym: Otakon was last weekend.
Scott: Yes, that's a lot.
Scott: We're talking about future events this Saturday August 7th, there's something this Saturday.
Scott: Yeah, there's a Mozilla drum beat.
Scott: All right in New York City.
Scott: It's a free open-source II kind of event.
Rym: John Britton is gonna be there.
Scott: He's running.
Scott: He's organizing.
Scott: Yeah, it's noon to 5 somewhere in New York City.
Scott: Find the website.
Rym: I may go but at the same time I may be in Wildwood.
Scott: Friday August 13th, New York City board game night.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: Hopefully soon we can announce this thing.
Rym: We're doing it.
Rym: packs.
Scott: Saturday September 11th recess More gaming.
Rym: October 8th 9th and 10th fucking everything everything.
Rym: 10 10 10, New York Comic Con New York Festival board game night.
Scott: There's a maker fair in New York City.
Scott: I love how we're only giving the New York events.
Scott: Like we're not giving nothing else matters.
Scott: The I guess it's events we're gonna be at or might be at September 25th and 26 maker fair in New York City.
Scott: There's an open-source Hardware Summit.
Rym: I'm probably not gonna go to maybe because during the week on September 23rd I think oh and random meta if anyone this Thursday The 5th of August is going to be at the Scott Pilgrim pre pre pre awesome screening I'll be there with Emily.
Rym: So let me know and we'll totally hang out.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I didn't I didn't win tickets.
Rym: Yeah, I Won tickets.
Scott: I was like my message Rym.
Scott: I'm like, hey Rym.
Rym: There's a chance to win tickets messaging back two minutes later I'm like, yeah, I want some.
Scott: I didn't win any.
Rym: It's alright anyway, so Killbots Yeah, automated killing machine.
Scott: I mean this is no one in your bed and watch out.
Rym: This isn't even like far out science fiction.
Rym: We've had kill bots for a long time.
Rym: We've had the capability for kill bots for a very long time.
Rym: But this this is like right now.
Rym: we use automated robotic killing machines to murder humans.
Scott: Well, you know a lot of them are remote-controlled.
Scott: even if they're remote-controlled from around the world There's still as a person controlling it manually a lot of the times.
Scott: It's very few that just sort of make their own decisions.
Rym: Well, the thing is they exist, but we don't use them.
Rym: I remember a long time ago This was like a decade ago reading about a system and it was designed for two purposes.
Rym: The first purpose was Identifying threats of assassination and what it does is if there's ever a gunshot it determines that yes That was a gunshot Determines roughly what kind of gun it was and more importantly it Triangulates and immediately shines a spotlight where the gunshot came from.
Scott: Mm-hmm See it could.
Scott: if he can shine a spotlight it could also fire a gun.
Scott: There's no there is not does nothing preventing you for making that exact same machine and making it shoot in that direction with a gun.
Rym: So it was made that way as well as an area denial system.
Rym: Imagine this you're in a war zone in Africa.
Rym: There's a bloody civil war Rwanda situation.
Rym: All right one of our at least Scott and I our ideas for peacekeeping is that we sometimes there's probably cause for United Nations peacekeepers to enter an area with the intent of eliminating all active hostiles.
Scott: Yeah, they never.
Scott: they never shoot anybody.
Rym: Yeah, we're talking Gundam double-o style.
Rym: so imagine if there's a situation like that.
Rym: you could deploy these systems as area denial to Hostiles and what they would do is in within the area, you know clear warning.
Rym: It's a system if there is gunfire, whatever fired that gun is immediately terminated by a robot.
Scott: Alright, so I don't fire a gun.
Scott: So it's not gonna shoot me, right?
Scott: If I'm just walking it's not gonna shoot me, right?
Scott: I won't even know.
Rym: you're there doesn't care.
Scott: So what prevents you from walking up to it and hitting you with a fucking hammer?
Rym: So maybe you have a couple of guards but think of this thing you.
Rym: so you have the system set up.
Scott: So if there's guards, right?
Scott: Okay, so here's a gunshot and it aims in the direction of the gunshot and start shooting.
Scott: What if there's a non gunshot a person in the way?
Rym: the demonstration I saw was surprisingly accurate.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: if someone's in the way, it's a fucking war zone.
Rym: But imagine forget the civilian peacekeeping Ramifications, what if you were a retreating army?
Rym: Okay, your area denial systems like that are not nearly as dangerous to civilians as landmines.
Scott: Mmm, that's true.
Scott: and landmines are automated robot killing machines.
Rym: you put it there someone steps on it fucking kills him.
Rym: How is that any different?
Rym: It doesn't even make a decision.
Scott: I think is that the landmine isn't Ranged.
Rym: well, there are range landmines tripwires claymore stuff like that.
Rym: Leave a booby trap behind.
Rym: someone's gonna trip over that someday.
Scott: and it's true.
Scott: and landmines are basically a huge problem, right?
Scott: So the the you know that there's still landmines all over the world that are killing people because they're left over from wars long long ago, so wouldn't this be?
Scott: you know a Killing machine with a gun would be even worse if they're left over from wars.
Rym: You know now, of course theoretically the battery is gonna run out into the killing machine with a gun.
Scott: Well, it's a bit soon as a battery power.
Rym: But what if it's set up to only attack where gunfire comes from?
Rym: I mean, maybe a hunter will get it.
Rym: Yeah, but a little kid won't?
Rym: little kids not gonna get shot.
Scott: well the little kids got like a BB gun.
Rym: I I think it could tell the difference.
Scott: I don't know what if he's got a cap gun?
Rym: What if he's got a gun?
Scott: So, I think we really really that funny.
Rym: I think what we really need to do is because they're We need to narrow this a little bit because there's a difference between.
Rym: kind of like in the stock trading market There are hot low latency traders.
Rym: these are where a human decides buy this or sell that you know execute this strategy and then Algorithms just execute the strategy as perfectly as possible.
Rym: Then there's high frequency trading where computers decide both what the strategy is and how to execute it.
Rym: Mm-hmm and with kill bots is kind of the same thing.
Rym: right now We have drones.
Scott: the situation where someone's controlling the drones though, right?
Rym: Yes a robot will identify threats or do something to that effect.
Rym: let's just let's forget about the current.
Rym: let's talk about the theoretical a robot that is armed that identifies threats and Presents them to a human remote operator and a human makes the final say of kill or not kill Mm-hmm, that is kind of automated execution.
Scott: They're actually more remote controlling and like it's a video game.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but still there's I think the clear like the line we should differentiate is Automated killing machine where a human makes the kill or not kill decision Versus automated killing machine that has the discretion to kill on its own.
Rym: Which one do I talk about first?
Rym: Well, there's obviously the more interesting one.
Scott: Well, no, but even the ones where a human is making this decision The human is very much separated from the decision right?
Scott: You know, you could even like let's say You know just theoretically I made a machine where you make the kill or not kill decision, right?
Scott: But the video it displays is an actual video or maybe even if it is actual video It just always shows a picture of a crazy guy running at you with a gun.
Scott: Yeah, if we have some sort of technology Enders game You know, it's like, you know You don't think you might.
Scott: I might be able to trick you into thinking it's a video game when it's actually for real and now You're killing people.
Rym: I would argue that that's almost an entirely separate debate the question of whether or not the System that is killing is Actually verifiable to the people using it, you know, if there's some layer of deception that's independent of the technology.
Rym: almost That's more of a government corruption issue.
Rym: Well, you know, it's it's it's possible but I mean at the same time you can order soldiers go wipe out that village.
Scott: We know they're terrorists Yeah, but at least if they know, you know, if if a soldier knows what he's doing, right?
Scott: I mean theoretically, you know, you're supposed to like, you know, not follow the evil order, right?
Scott: Like if some if you're if only the illegal order Someone if someone fought tell orders you to violate the Geneva Convention, right you you as a soldier you can not do it.
Scott: you might just get shot, but you can.
Scott: you're supposed to on paper not do it.
Scott: and But what if you are violating the Geneva Convention and you don't even know it you're gonna do it Even though you would have if you had known not done it.
Scott: So thus there can be war crimes by people who didn't even know they were committing war crimes and would not have committed war crimes Had they known they were doing it, but but to back up a little bit There was.
Rym: there's a lot of evidence that being remote because that was your first argument that being remote can also.
Rym: You know it colors things in so many ways.
Rym: being remote leads to much more calculated decisions that aren't based on adrenaline.
Rym: a human soldier in a situation where there's someone who may be a civilian or maybe a hostile is Going to protect their own life above all other concerns.
Rym: So if the situation is ambiguous or dangerous, they are much more likely to kill even if killing wasn't necessary.
Rym: Piloting a drone one.
Rym: You've got an officer over your shoulder.
Rym: Someone's watching what you're doing.
Rym: Every movement is being recorded and You're safe.
Rym: The worst-case scenario of you not firing it for you is my drone blows up and I take a coffee break.
Scott: No, I've actually heard that the guys you know who are working the drones actually have a lot of psychological difficulties It but I haven't seen any study that says those are more so than the soldiers in the field.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: Yeah It's.
Scott: it's just you know, it's.
Scott: it's not like you're eliminating that problem though.
Rym: Oh not at all But at least it's just as rough, but at least you're either way the personal like the self-preservation Problem of.
Rym: I don't want to die Mmm because I can very rarely blame a soldier who thinks he might be in danger Hurting someone even if that you know, you can still have the same situation where you know, maybe you're saving someone else's life.
Scott: You know you think I need to because that person will die.
Rym: Yeah, but those situations happen with soldiers in person, too.
Rym: But there is a lot of evidence that removing soldiers from themselves being in personal danger limits the the amount of Influence of self-preservation instinct and reduces the number of kind of violations or incidents that went poorly.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: But if it's a computer and is no soldier involved at all, so that's an entirely separate situation.
Scott: and you got a problem.
Rym: We just say it's like in populace when I send the night into the other guy's side.
Rym: It's automated and it just fucking kills people until it falls in the swamp.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know the computer.
Scott: even if you could program it somehow perfectly right it wouldn't have any of those problems Doing anything in the heat of the moment or anything like that.
Scott: You could even program it to follow the Geneva Convention, you know in a some sci-fi world, right?
Scott: So it would never do any.
Scott: it would never make a war crime.
Rym: Well, it would never make a war crime in the same sense that the three laws prevented robots from ever hurting humans?
Scott: Yeah, exactly, right.
Scott: You know what happens if it breaks or fucks up or who knows what?
Rym: what if a tank fucks up?
Rym: What if a soldier goes crazy?
Rym: Well, it's a lot harder soldiers going.
Rym: It's not a lot harder for a soldier to go crazy.
Scott: No, but it's hard for a tank to fuck up, right?
Scott: I mean, you know a tank doesn't just fire it can't fire its gun accidentally really, you know, so it has to be loaded You know mechanically.
Rym: so what if we get to a point where we can?
Rym: our programming is not perfect and the robots kill in Mistake, but they kill in mistake objectively less often than humans Then what then?
Rym: aren't we morally obligated to use the robots instead?
Scott: Yeah, but I think people are obviously more disturbed by any.
Scott: You know miss.
Scott: it's like you make one mistake with some new tech.
Scott: It's like air.
Scott: It's like one plane crash, right?
Scott: How often are plane crashes so rare so rare?
Scott: how often our car crashes so common every day tons of them all over the place.
Scott: But when you hear about car crashes like a car crash plane crash Oh my god.
Scott: now granted the damage of a plane crash is much larger, but people go crazy even over like these Cessna.
Scott: You know accidents which actually probably have less damage than you know a car crash on the highway.
Scott: But people are so scared and Incredibly frightened and it's huge news when there's a plane crash even a small one and a car crash is like back page Right.
Scott: So a robot even making one mistake would be fuck get the robots out of here.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: killing robots, but a person fucking up but human.
Rym: that's one of the things that always bothers me.
Rym: It's in your history books.
Scott: It's not even in the newspaper.
Rym: We can't always do the obvious Objectively correct or objectively better thing because people have preconceived notions prejudices and irrational affairs.
Rym: Yes I don't know what to do about that.
Rym: I mean like look at how we execute.
Rym: we should program a robot to kill anyone with the rational that we as Enlightened society to this day think that lethal injection is somehow more humane than I don't know.
Rym: carbon monoxide poisoning Or the boulder method.
Scott: What's the boulder?
Rym: drop a boulder on someone?
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah Or even firing squad.
Scott: yeah, as long as they have aim, yeah They suck at aiming.
Scott: I mean they might just shoot you in the junk.
Scott: and then what?
Rym: and John the serial killers died of eight gunshot wounds to the heart and one to the testicle.
Scott: That's some good aim You know.
Scott: considering, you know how small.
Rym: so even you know The far-out discussion is what about when we just send robots off to do everything for us Robots versus robots.
Scott: We're just building robots to fight other robots, right?
Rym: Should we?
Rym: well now we could have that.
Rym: Anyway, should we be concerned?
Rym: I mean it's we're from the perspective of we're the superpower.
Rym: We're in America We have the best military technology.
Rym: There is far and away.
Rym: We're the ones using this technology against people who can't have it.
Rym: I mean, there are no more wars between two fully industrialized modern civilizations.
Rym: It just doesn't happen.
Rym: Hmm I don't know if it'll ever happen again, I don't know.
Scott: But no one wants to get into a fight where that's actually gonna be a real fair fight You know, they only want to get into a fight where they pick on some wuss.
Rym: I mean imagine a war between two nations that have force projection capabilities and carrier fleets and drones and nuclear weapons and cruise missiles.
Rym: But that never happens.
Rym: I mean we wage war against countries that don't even have night vision.
Rym: So Morally is there a concern from the fact that we're moving toward a military where there is no danger to any human on our side.
Scott: There is it.
Scott: there is danger to humans on our side because they just use you know different tactics like, you know Putting a you know bomb and you know on the road or whatever that you know, it works.
Scott: They're getting us All right.
Rym: So what if we we eliminate that by we say we occupy a country and I have just you know We have robots in the surrogate style.
Rym: So it's so no, let's go full-on.
Rym: Let's go all the way out because it's the why it's the sir.
Scott: We have a surrogate army.
Rym: Yes, we have a surrogate arms.
Scott: All right, it's all the major.
Rym: so we can wage Warfare the same way that we do now.
Rym: we can occupy we can help people we humanitarian aid everything But at no point is any soldier from our country in any danger of physical harm More so than maybe a paper cut when they fill out their time sheet.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Well, you're ignoring of course psychological trauma.
Rym: We're ignoring that then because that's kind of a separate that happens now.
Scott: Anyway, well if you got that and no one else has that then you just basically you can just conquer the world.
Scott: No one can stop you.
Rym: But what does conquering mean in the modern world?
Scott: It means it's gonna be one government for the entire world because you just know because we probably wouldn't do that because doesn't mean much.
Scott: Yeah, I know It's so.
Rym: I mean imagine now if you're what would the Iraq War be an issue if it just cost money and time?
Scott: It would because what about these Iraqis that are dying?
Scott: It doesn't mean that Iraqi civilians are gonna get killed.
Rym: You people in the American political discourse even are concerned with that.
Scott: That's because they're horrible people.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes, exactly.
Rym: But would we possibly be in a worse situation?
Rym: like would we be able to?
Rym: Would war be able to be waged effectively eternally if there was no longer in the American political objective like consensus Any factor of kids not coming home from the war?
Scott: Oh, you're kidding They would go they would do even more war because a it would be mad monies for our economy.
Scott: It was really if we were using all this tax money to get basically get jobs by people manufacturing Argues that war is the health of the state, but I don't know if that's necessarily true economically.
Rym: I think the real concern.
Rym: I mean what if instead?
Rym: All right, our Perspective there is skewed by the fact that we had Republicans who waged two foreign wars of aggression.
Rym: what if we have a surrogate army and we Engage in the kind of peacekeeping that is infeasible now because people aren't willing to risk their lives for it?
Rym: Would Rwanda have been able to happen if the US or the UN had a surrogate army?
Scott: Well, Rwanda didn't even need to happen without a surrogate army.
Scott: It was a matter of you know laws and things, you know It was simply a matter of political expediency.
Rym: Yeah States did not want to get involved because we had already fucked up.
Rym: a bunch of other UN guys were there couldn't do anything because the Because no one wanted to risk UN lives.
Rym: and yet what if it was just money and not humans?
Scott: alright, so now we spend all our money making robots and But it cost the same.
Rym: we've changed the equation.
Rym: the equation now for getting involved in a peacekeeping war for the United States even forget the United Nations is Soldiers will die which limits the scope and span of the war because political unrest increases the more soldiers die.
Rym: and Independently, we have the cost.
Rym: What if it was just the money cost and not the human cost on the on our side?
Scott: So what happens when the people on the other side like, you know You know, okay, so we send a bunch of robots over there and they dismantle all the robots But the robots do the same thing.
Rym: the humans do.
Scott: that's the same as dismantling a soldier and they're doing pretty good job of that.
Rym: How could they though?
Rym: We're effectively unbeatable.
Scott: How are you?
Scott: You're not unbeatable just cuz you're just cuz you're a robot.
Rym: It's not just cuz you're a robot.
Rym: It's a robot with the same advanced.
Rym: I mean, it's just take our current military.
Scott: The only thing is alright, so if it's a robot actually has even more weaknesses cuz you can just hack it.
Scott: You know, it's not the same as a soldier Is that?
Rym: is that even an option?
Scott: you could you know?
Scott: If it's a surrogate right you assume someone's can.
Scott: if it's like the surrogates and someone's controlling it from far away laws of physics You can jam it.
Scott: You can take it offline.
Scott: You can just you know, lock it up somewhere.
Rym: Look at the asymmetry of the warfare currently.
Rym: take our current army to replace it with surrogates.
Rym: We're fighting against combatants who do not have access to any of the countermeasures for our technology I mean our stealth technology Especially the older stuff works primarily because it's trivially defeated by our military and modern militaries But their militaries can't see those planes.
Scott: So it's not really that it's just one It's basically then it's the same as we have now plus one, you know, it's not way to look at it.
Scott: It's not really a big difference.
Scott: It's like, okay, we have so much technology.
Scott: They can't compete with us.
Scott: So what if we had even more technology?
Scott: They would have it even a harder time competing with us.
Rym: really what it comes down to our use of drones Basically reduces the cost and the risk of warfare.
Rym: But otherwise, it's just one factor in a long litany of the fact that we have total world military supremacy.
Scott: No, China could put up a fight.
Rym: They don't have any force projection capabilities.
Rym: And if spending patterns continue unless we hit kind of theoretical limits they got nukes.
Rym: Yes, but I don't think that you can project a nuke anywhere in the world.
Rym: But that's a different kind of force projection and I don't think it is possible to have war nuclear war among ICBM capable nations at least not for the foreseeable future.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think anyone's really thinking about it because it there's nothing to gain.
Rym: It's kind of the.
Rym: that's like the game over situation.
Scott: if I would basically, you know It costs so much money to maintain them, right?
Scott: I would you know and what I would do is if I was in charge is I would basically just stop maintaining them But pretend I was.
Scott: You know save all that money and use them on robots or something and then I would everyone still thinks I got him.
Rym: You know, but that's interesting because in the old world, you know the Cold War Game theory, you know, that is where a lot of our modern game theory came out of.
Rym: is what do we do in the Cold War?
Rym: That was just a big paper rock.
Rym: Fuck you game.
Rym: Yep So Paper rock.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: We should play that instead of paper rock scissors.
Scott: All right, I'll pick.
Scott: fuck you every time as will I.
Rym: We appear to be at an impasse But but there was the argument that the primary reason to have nuclear weapons is to never use them But that they are a deterrent from other people using nuclear weapons.
Scott: so The best possible scenario maybe having robots could be a deterrent against anyone else.
Rym: The best possible scenario is the other nation your enemies believing you have the capability to destroy them and Acting accordingly and yet you don't actually have this case and you save your money for something better.
Rym: The worst case scenario is you having the capability and them not thinking that you do Mmm, because think about it then they will act in ways that might force you to use it.
Rym: Mmm because they don't think you have it And then the only way to use it the only way to prove that you have it is to use it Mm-hmm, and we could go on about that.
Scott: create an illusion that you have it when you don't.
Rym: yes like in the mouse that roared You can make a show.
Rym: remember that movie with the cue bomb with the crazy people.
Rym: Yeah, and the cue bomb?
Scott: I forgot the name of that movie, but I Roared.
Rym: or the mouse that wrote at the line.
Rym: I think it had a longer title, but it's the mouse that roared.
Rym: Yeah Regardless, so I think what I would do?
Rym: I'd go something similar.
Rym: I would maintain a top-secret Hyper like a continued advancement of you know mass destruction nuclear technology.
Rym: But I would maintain a very small advanced actual capability and a very large perceived capability.
Scott: But yeah, I mean if it's robots right and someone else gets the robots right then what can happen is any nation get the robots.
Rym: That wasn't an industrialized nation such that they would never wage war with another modern Let's say it was the war of the robots.
Scott: the robots first the robots right and it's like okay You so could that be just a proxy war?
Scott: no, but here's the thing.
Scott: So let's say there's robots versus robots, right?
Scott: It's like okay you look at the other guy and you say dude, really?
Scott: It's like we're just spending money on robots that are destroyed or basically both flushing money down the toilet.
Scott: Why are we even doing this?
Scott: Let's just stop and the thing is like, okay you stop.
Scott: now The robots are killing your non-robot people.
Scott: Haha because they you didn't put any robots in the way to stop them.
Scott: So It's it's like on the one hand.
Scott: It's completely silly.
Scott: you got you know, one or more groups Spending money on robots that kill each other.
Scott: But if any one person stops spending the money suddenly those robots are now killing people and it's just like.
Rym: I don't think it'll ever Get to the shock of Zulu's.
Scott: we're forced We're forced to do this stupid thing of flushing money down the toilet because the other guy is also doing it.
Scott: We can't convince them both to stop because if only one, you know, it's this prisoner's dilemma if I stop and he continues He's killing me.
Scott: I'm done.
Scott: But if we both continue then we're both sucking, you know, it's almost oversimplified.
Scott: we can't get the people to both.
Scott: continue to stop.
Rym: you have to think about what is.
Rym: what is the purpose of warfare and Warfare between two modern industrialized societies is very different from the vast majority of warfare That is engaged in the world.
Rym: Usually it would be peacekeeping operations.
Rym: It would be one large power fighting against a small power that is causing harm to its neighbors.
Rym: things like that.
Rym: It's not going to be two equivalent nations sending robots to fight in Antarctica for a hundred years.
Scott: It's so good, Antarctica.
Rym: What are they fighting over now?
Scott: running over Antarctica, dude?
Scott: Force.
Rym: a war between two modern industrialized societies could be the resource war situation Mm-hmm, but even then they're fighting over something.
Rym: There is a there is a victory condition other than I defeated your robot army.
Rym: It's never I defeated your robot army.
Rym: It's always I defeated your robot army in order to get the vuvuzela.
Scott: Mmm, I gotta get me some vuvuzela.
Rym: Really?
Rym: That's really what you want.
Rym: No, I think anyone wants that.
Scott: you do Vuvuzela, oh man vuvuzela robot of war.
Scott: they just go out and they just they have built-in vuvuzela.
Scott: I mean that is more deadly than any weapon that has ever existed and just roams around your country with who's willing and you can't Stop it.
Scott: It's unstoppable.
Rym: We should make that.
Rym: you know how much press that would get if we just made a vuvuzela bot It'd be on slash shot and BB spot and boing boing.
Scott: We need like.
Scott: we need like an air compressor and a read.
Rym: It's not read driven.
Rym: We need a fake.
Rym: No.
Scott: No, we need yeah, basically the reeves reads to me.
Rym: I would do.
Rym: I would just put a speaker in the end of the vuvuzela the place of a vuvuzela sound.
Scott: Would that work?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah slightly modified.
Rym: So we're when it comes out.
Rym: It sounds like the vuvuzela All right.
Scott: So you blow the vuvuzela we put a microphone on the other end and then we take the speaker and we you know You stop and
Rym: I think the real presentation of it is making the rest of the robot that roams the street identifying faces Approaching people and then vuvuzeling them in the face.
Scott: We could just use any old wheeled robot to do that.
Rym: Yeah, but no one's done it.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Luckily.
Rym: We have not weaponized this.
Scott: Yeah, let's do it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: We've talked for a while.
Rym: I think we touched on a lot without actually answering anything.
Rym: We got we're gonna answer got him.
Scott: We got a Monday show out, which we haven't done in a while.
Scott: Please send your Monday show ideas.
Rym: I thought you were gonna say please send your money.
Scott: Also send your money if you want.
Scott: I mean, I don't really need any more.
Scott: But if you sent in enough money, it would be totally awesome, you know.
Scott: But I don't think that amount of money is gonna come in anytime soon.
Rym: All right, so we'll see you guys.
Rym: We may or may not do shows next week.
Rym: Everything's kind of up in the air.
Scott: We're doing a Wednesday show this week.
Rym: things are I don't know.
Rym: things are getting gonna be really bouncing around.
Rym: After packs things will be normal for about a month And then after the New York Comic Con after the weekend of 10 10 10 Everything will be normal until mag fest magma mag fest.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.