Rym: Hey, it's Monday November 15th 2010.
Rym: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight the Internet's.
Rym: Let's do this Woman.
Rym: it is dark.
Scott: Yeah, it's the Sun and it is not up.
Rym: I'm not enjoying this.
Rym: I mean, I work like seven to four and it's dark when I get home at like four or five.
Scott: I don't know why they don't go with my strategy right daylight saving time?
Scott: No, well no acts have a better strategy.
Rym: double daylight savings time exactly right.
Scott: we should leave daylight savings time as Daylight saving at time.
Rym: There's no s whatever.
Scott: We should leave that as is but then on the other right and the north and where the quote normal time Which is what we have now, right?
Scott: Aren't we currently in normal time?
Rym: Yes, we're in normal time.
Scott: We should make normal time actually an hour earlier in daylight savings time.
Scott: It should be double daylight savings time.
Scott: I Just think in daylight savings time could be normal time.
Rym: We should go back to the when it was such that we switch to daylight saving time and we never switch back because it's awesome.
Rym: It's always better to be on DST.
Scott: Oh, here's another is another idea right?
Scott: How about this?
Scott: How about we just You know when it's not double daylight savings time saving whatever booting to like.
Scott: if I owned a company right now I'd be like everyone.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: We're just gonna work from seven to three because yeah bullshit I would do that except for one.
Rym: I'd be like, yeah work seven to nine Or work until you finish your work and then go home.
Rym: But now stock markets open 930 to 4 so I'm kind of so even if your company was cool.
Scott: I mean, it's a stock market company, so they can't change the market.
Rym: However, the day after Thanksgiving every year and every year I forget about this until like right before it happens The markets only open a half day.
Rym: So I get a half day.
Scott: I get it zero day One of the few zero days I get.
Rym: yeah, cuz you technically worked from home while we were in Boston that week I used a week of vacation.
Rym: Yeah, I'm out of vacation days.
Scott: Well, I wouldn't use a vacation day and a half day.
Scott: Anyway, even though you'd only have to use half a vacation, but if I work a full day, I get a vacation day.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, it's dark.
Rym: Yeah messing up my mojo.
Scott: I know not a fan really.
Rym: I got of course being brilliant I bought my bike lights right before the end of biking season.
Rym: They're sitting in my drawer.
Scott: I know I stopped biking about a month ago.
Scott: I'll start.
Scott: I'll start again when it's warm again.
Rym: Yeah, so we stopped biking.
Rym: It's super nice out today.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: What can I do about that?
Scott: I already bought an unlimited subway pass and I had to go to this conference thing.
Scott: So I wasn't about to bike today.
Scott: Yeah, then I'll bike again as soon as the.
Scott: you know, like mark.
Rym: So I got some news some tech news that I think is worth talking about.
Rym: But I want to take an aside and aside.
Rym: I was looking at this as a thing of the day because you know I like those nerd kind of tests like remember that old like super nerd test.
Rym: That was like all text a thousand questions long.
Rym: No, really.
Rym: That was the kind of a big internet culture thing.
Rym: Okay, late 90s never heard of it.
Rym: Really really really major geek tag out of it your nerd tag any of that stuff?
Scott: Yeah, Wow.
Rym: Well, did you ever hang out on usenet?
Scott: No.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: Anyway, so info world which ostensibly and I say ostensibly because we know that that is in fact not true Knows something about technology.
Rym: It is a technology magazine and they made their 2010 info world geek IQ test.
Scott: Apparently they made a 2009 one also that shows up in a Google search.
Rym: So I saw it.
Rym: I was like, alright I'll take this test.
Rym: It'll be funny be a thing of the day.
Rym: It'll be cool.
Rym: You know something.
Rym: we can all take and share our scores.
Rym: This test proved to me a couple of things.
Rym: one whoever wrote it has no idea what Linux is or how it works.
Scott: Well, I mean bear.
Rym: he's probably not used Linux since about.
Scott: Yeah Or you know, this is one of those situations where it's like somebody just throws something together.
Scott: Right for you know, just because they're going to throw it together, right?
Scott: They're not actually trying hard at it.
Scott: They're not trying to make it good.
Scott: They're just trying to get some hits.
Scott: It's probably got him a lot of hits last year.
Scott: They're probably hey, let's do it again this year.
Scott: You get the same awesome number of hits We got last year, but what?
Scott: I just slapped it together one, two, three.
Scott: real quick Easy peasy took him ten minutes at work so you can go play solitaire again.
Rym: See, but I'm gonna go one step further and it totally worked and got a bunch of hits.
Scott: and now you're talking about it.
Rym: That is probably true actually only like less than 200 people noted it in like Facebook and it's actually not Getting that many hits as far as I can say.
Scott: info world.
Rym: That's a lot but it shows something more interesting to get.
Rym: whoever it is who actually made this thing clearly is a Mediocre to average Windows IT sysadmin who has used Linux but does not know anything about Linux and Probably either played D&D or more likely knows someone in the office who has played D&D and asked him for a question.
Scott: Yeah, also, this is a person doesn't understand what IQ means right?
Scott: I mean at least if you get you know Obviously you can call it an IQ test and it's never gonna be a legitimate IQ test But you can at least make it resemble an IQ test.
Scott: 90% of these questions Most of them are basically do you know this, you know, do you have this fact memorized?
Scott: But it's not.
Scott: if not search on Google and you will find out it.
Rym: the facts themselves are just very like old Busted Windows system centric.
Scott: Maybe that's just the audience for info world.
Scott: is that kind of person?
Rym: That's what I hope.
Rym: that's what I was getting to.
Rym: my conclusion based on all of this Is that info world is out of touch and is basically the magazine for people who learn Windows administration in?
Rym: 1999 yeah, and if touch Linux once or twice.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: I mean 10 base - really I Was just.
Rym: I was taken aback by this to where I wanted to call it out for being stupid.
Scott: It is quite the stupid test.
Rym: So whoever wrote this?
Rym: if you uh, this comes to you the wind of our anger.
Rym: I'd like to talk to you.
Scott: I'd like to find out more about why you made this and of course if anyone wants to just make fun of Rym Just say all Rym.
Scott: you just call the test stupid cuz you sucked at it.
Scott: You got all them right.
Scott: you would have said it was an awesome All right.
Rym: So I miss.
Rym: I miss number three how much RAM does 32-bit Windows 2008 server handle?
Rym: because I don't I didn't fucking know I.
Scott: the only question I really wanted to say an error wrong because that's bullshit.
Scott: The only question I want to dispute is a final question question 20 and it says which is the following has the best chance to Protect your users identities?
Scott: and the choices were like virus scanners spyware detector Rocco the bodyguard and something else.
Scott: And the fact is I have.
Scott: I have a strong argument that Rocco the bodyguard can protect the users identity better than a spyware Detector because what will happen is the anytime the user goes to type in their name or any personal information into their computer Rocco
Rym: will hit them
Scott: in the face And it won't matter how much spyware viruses are on the computer if Rocco prevents them from typing in any personal information on the keyboard.
Scott: That will perfectly protect the users identity even with a spyware detector if Rocco's not there.
Scott: if they type in Any personal information to any website ever they basically just giving away everything.
Scott: So the correct answer is Rocco.
Scott: the my city didn't get all their answers, right?
Scott: You know?
Rym: especially interesting was the question about how do you restart a printer service on a lip it?
Rym: Like none of the answers actually really work on modern systems and the real answer is you go into your GUI and hit restart.
Scott: Yeah This is the web interface and the restart button.
Rym: this was kind of like punching a guy in a wheelchair.
Rym: but So you have any real news ever?
Scott: real news, you know, it's.
Scott: it's sort of a news.
Scott: It's on the star calm which I assume is a local newspaper Orlando star.
Scott: It just says the star.
Rym: It's only star.
Scott: I know I can't really tell where this is from.
Scott: Ryan Toronto it's a Toronto star.
Scott: Anyway, they have an article I think it might.
Scott: oh it's a staff reporter so it's not even AP good for them.
Scott: At least it says Cathal Kelly staff reporter and basically this article doesn't talk about anything new.
Scott: I just wanted to discuss the things that we already you know, this old news, but I want to discuss it, right?
Rym: But how old news?
Rym: we talking like 90s vintage?
Scott: I mean first of all, the article was published on December 30th.
Scott: Oh 9, right Wow.
Scott: And second of all, that's for you retro.
Scott: the information in this article is information that I've known since 2000.
Scott: So this is like decade old news, but it's new for a lot of people.
Rym: We just said 1999 2000 That's a decade.
Scott: Yeah, we're old.
Scott: So anyway, basically what this article talks about is how Israeli airports pretty much.
Scott: There's only one of them, right?
Scott: This is only one really important one.
Rym: This is airport security, isn't it?
Scott: Yeah, which I went to in the year 2000, right?
Scott: So I know all about it.
Rym: You know, well, you know all about it from a decade ago.
Scott: It hasn't changed that much.
Scott: Basically they have incredible security.
Rym: It's it's like off the charts One of the places that is most likely to have problems.
Scott: they have basically problems all the time.
Scott: It's basically like this huge target and it hasn't been breached since.
Scott: Oh - so somebody Accidentally carried a handgun onto a flight.
Scott: It wasn't even a terrorist or anything.
Rym: I can just picture a guy You know the the Secret Service bus in and they're gonna kick his ass.
Rym: He's like, dude.
Rym: Sorry my mistake.
Scott: And basically they have no lines at least not compared to us.
Scott: right and there's a few.
Scott: there's a few things here.
Scott: I mean if you want the actual details of how they make it more secure Right, you can read this article and it talks about how most of what they do is.
Scott: they just look at people Like look them in the eyes and talk to them because if you're a terrorist you're gonna be mad nervous.
Scott: And if you're mad nervous watch out cuz they're gonna run out and grab you, right?
Scott: But if you're just a normal person like what's up?
Scott: Yeah, I'm going to friggin, you know, New York.
Scott: They'd be like, alright go on.
Rym: Well, I have this funny feeling that there's some things they don't do that we could.
Rym: probably I'll bet they don't frisk paraplegics No, they don't really right What?
Scott: basically what they do these?
Scott: the one secure thing that they do is they scan your bags basically immediately, right?
Scott: It's like you bring a bag in scan it, right?
Scott: You know, that might be a good idea because there's a bigger line in security In the airport the places where there are lines the lines are staggered so you can't attack the line itself, right?
Scott: You can attack a small portion of the line, but you couldn't get all these people in line all at once.
Rym: Smart that makes sense.
Scott: He gasped.
Scott: They're smart anyway.
Scott: And when they scan the bags, right basically, let's say there was a bat.
Scott: Let's see you're in the jet blue terminal at JFK, right?
Scott: Yep, and they were scanning a bag and had a bomb in it.
Scott: bowling ball candle bowling ball candle.
Scott: What.
Scott: what would they do?
Scott: What the TSA do if they saw a bomb in the x-ray machine?
Rym: probably go And then call for a supervisor to come over and go.
Scott: No, well, they would have to evacuate the whole place, right?
Rym: Yeah, once they actually say yes, it's a bomb for sure, right They would probably ground.
Rym: every goddamn flight will cancel everything.
Scott: point is is that at the bare minimum?
Scott: You have to evacuate the whole terminal because that bomb is threatening every the entire area where the people are crowded, right?
Rym: But I have a feeling that flights would be stopped for like a day.
Scott: So the Israeli people right that when they scanning these bags They're in a little room and the room can withstand like a ton of explosion, but you know before actually You know getting out of the room It's not a you know bomb proof room But it's you know, it's it's a strong
Rym: like my watch.
Rym: It's not waterproof.
Scott: And then is this basically the people that are in the room doing the scanning?
Scott: They're trained if they see something suspicious to drop it in the bomb box, which is basically a blast proof box.
Rym: I want a bomb box.
Scott: It's basically an invincible box.
Scott: They drop their pet.
Scott: They'll take your bag They'll toss it in the bomb proof box and then they call the experts to come and deal with it And then they'll leave the room and then a bomb squad will just come and take the bomb box away.
Scott: I'll bet when that happens, you're not even delayed your bag You just keep going in line.
Rym: see I actually have something to say.
Rym: I mean aside from all the obvious in America and they don't take your shoes.
Scott: They don't check any of that.
Rym: One dude fire once.
Rym: and and actually I saw all these like we got a notice at work even about how this holiday season because they have the backscatter which actually Not being you know, there are there's things now where they say it's not safe.
Rym: Yeah, I was gonna say straight up not being like pseudoscience aside There are legitimate health and safety concerns about those backscattering machines and I would not consent to going through one.
Scott: I would also not go through one.
Rym: So there is a national opt-out day because apparently I at least I thought that all the pilots were opting out.
Rym: Yeah, they are.
Rym: there's a big but now passengers can opt out to.
Rym: the rule Is that if you opt out then they'll grope you and they fucking grope you.
Rym: they they even warn you that your genitals will be Touched.
Scott: All right, so I should be like hey, no you should do you till a kill.
Rym: No underwear.
Rym: and FARC had the added bonus of don't wipe.
Scott: They wear gloves.
Scott: they wear gloves.
Rym: Yeah, but that would still make at least one FARC.
Scott: I'm not gonna give myself a diaper rash No, I'm not gonna ruin my utility, but I would gladly I'll let him grope me.
Scott: I'll be like, yeah.
Rym: No, but think about this.
Rym: if everyone opts out It's a disaster for the airport an absolute disaster.
Scott: They don't have it all because they don't send everyone through that machine So not everyone has the opportunity to opt out.
Scott: most people just go through normal.
Scott: Like yeah It's only some people get sent to the machine.
Rym: I mean What else can I say?
Rym: I'm sick of this bullshit.
Rym: I only fly because it's the only vibe.
Scott: But anyway, basically the why did you know the airport in Israel do this, right?
Scott: Why didn't they do it the way we do it?
Scott: well, basically what happened was and this is what I really want to touch on here right is that You know originally they had the kind of you know security we had and basically This is like 50 years ago, by the way, right and the Israelis are like half-hour wait Fuck that shit.
Scott: and they were pissed and they were angry and they were like fuck you, right?
Scott: And the big problem I think is that people in the US and also Canadians it says right here.
Scott: We're just too nice.
Scott: It's like we'll be like, okay Okay, I'm not gonna be I'm not gonna start a fuss.
Scott: Israeli guy would just be like you want to grope me.
Scott: I dare you grope me.
Scott: I'll just punch your lights out.
Scott: Fuck you Here's.
Rym: here's I think why I don't think Americans are nice.
Rym: I think Americans are afraid of getting arrested.
Rym: Well, I mean that's I'm real nice to the TSA mouth breathers.
Scott: Well, that's another another factor right.
Scott: is that the Israelis right these people doing the scanning, right?
Scott: This is this is one of the reasons why I don't think it'll work in America.
Scott: trained professionals trained professional, of course.
Scott: Look they're looking at people in the eyes ask them questions and judging them.
Rym: this takes a skilled Intelligent person who's sorry, you've got a bowling ball candle in your bag.
Rym: What the fuck?
Scott: Yeah Well, you know this is before.
Scott: this is like when you're in your car You drive it to the airport someone comes over and it looks at you and judges you psych You know gives you you know evaluates you by looking at you and judging your mannerisms, right?
Scott: This takes a trained professional someone who is not just a minimum wage TSA person, you know I'm sure there are plenty of TSA people who are not minimum wage morons, but there are many who are you know What.
Rym: even if they're smart, it's not like they have any discretion and the Israeli like they can be like.
Rym: I'll do it Smartly.
Scott: Israel has mandatory military service, right?
Scott: So everyone pretty much is a security professional.
Scott: See actually and the people who have this as their job, right everyone, you know.
Scott: It's like they're trusting them because they're all skilled.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like if you're all military guys and this military guys You know scanning your bags.
Scott: It's like you trust that they're professionals cuz you know, you're a professional and they're with you, right?
Scott: But when you're in the US, you don't trust the TSA.
Scott: They're all morons and you're right not to trust them.
Rym: I don't even trust them with my bag.
Scott: So the fact you know, it's because you don't trust them, right?
Scott: You basically you need a procedure that you can trust because you don't trust the people.
Scott: or in Israel you can trust.
Scott: you can trust the people so you they don't really need the the procedure We don't.
Rym: we can't trust the people so we make a procedure that theoretically we can trust.
Rym: Yes, like zero tolerance policies in our schools exactly like pretty much everything in our society.
Scott: So, you know two problems.
Scott: this illustrates number one.
Scott: We're too damn nice.
Scott: You got to get pissed off and be a bad job to get even even if you don't.
Rym: you know A lot of people.
Scott: they just have the opinion that like you have to be nice.
Scott: being nice is important.
Scott: Look at like the whole south of the US where they value having good manners Even if they're actually races.
Rym: wait now Scott that all of them are.
Rym: you might go a little too far.
Rym: I'm happy with the fact that when I'm in line at Starbucks and the guy in front of me is slightly delayed He doesn't flip the fuck out.
Scott: You don't need to flip the fuck out.
Scott: There's a such thing as going too far, right?
Rym: I don't even want to hear him yell.
Rym: I just want him to just quietly be like, thanks Yeah, and then I get my coffee.
Scott: No, but I'm saying is that there is you know Like for example, right there is there is a line right?
Scott: I mean like you you can't be.
Scott: it's not a good idea to just flip out and be unproductively angry and disruptive.
Rym: Actually now I take but I want to see people flip the fuck out because I just remember the last time I actually saw Someone flipped the fuck out in line.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: It was awesome.
Scott: It was hilarious Right, but it's flipping out and yelling and making a scene are not productive.
Rym: What is dude, but Didn't have whipped cream in it, right?
Scott: But at the same time just being tolerant and taking it up the ass willingly and then saying thanks Right and having good manners about it.
Scott: It's also not helping.
Scott: but something is Inconveniencing to the point there.
Scott: It's a problem.
Scott: You need to be like, hey, this is a problem If Starbucks is taking too long sleep without paying.
Rym: Yeah Here's the problem with that one Starbucks.
Rym: if you have a problem you go to leave.
Rym: they not only do they not care But they give you a thing.
Rym: They'll give you free coffee at any Starbucks.
Scott: That's true But that's that's a good reason to be rude at the Starbucks, you know, I mean, you know just The Commons.
Rym: it doesn't actually works out pretty well.
Scott: the problem still but it was not it.
Scott: look in Israel Everyone is so angry about a half-hour wait.
Scott: Yes that it fixed things.
Scott: No break them.
Rym: Here's where I disagree with you because it's not that Americans are nice.
Rym: We're not buying large.
Rym: It's that we're afraid of getting arrested and we don't have an alternative to flying.
Scott: That's also true.
Scott: is that you know anyone in Israel only really flies to go somewhere else other than Israel Whereas in the United States, right?
Scott: I feel like I get anywhere because it's so damn big and I think that is you know That's.
Scott: one of the fundamental problems of why is the US not different from all other places is because it's so goddamn Geographically big, you know, even someplace like Russia you like all Russia's geographically big China's geographically.
Rym: Yeah, no one lives out there No one lives out in the right.
Scott: It's like people don't live in Siberia.
Scott: you take Russia.
Scott: It's like well, where's the places where people actually live?
Scott: Well, really only this area.
Scott: Oh, well, it's not so big then is it?
Scott: I mean, it's still big but it's not as USB.
Rym: Of course, we could have those things if we localize them.
Scott: It's like China.
Scott: people really only live mostly on the East Coast Like I would I.
Rym: I hope this initiative to have high-speed rail actually comes to fruition in the Northeast.
Rym: Imagine if we had high-speed rail connecting all the major cities in the northeastern seaboard.
Scott: I use that shit all the time.
Rym: Yeah, actually now bolt bus.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm not flying to animate Boston.
Rym: at least I don't think I'll fly to PAX East.
Rym: we gotta sort that out.
Scott: We'll figure it out.
Scott: Anyway, if you if you didn't know this stuff already because this is old news It's you know now and now it's new news to you.
Rym: But I highly recommend if nothing else opt out if you can if you are.
Rym: if don't let them back scatter you.
Scott: Yeah, and don't you know?
Scott: be groped instead enjoy the groping.
Rym: so you wanna have some real fun.
Scott: as soon as they grope you scream Dude I got a better idea ready.
Scott: Yeah chop them off be a eunuch and then get grope.
Scott: They'll be like whoa.
Scott: Yeah, that's worth it or no even better.
Scott: Just cross dress and go for the groping much easier.
Rym: That's brilliant cuz.
Scott: then you're a dude.
Scott: you'll get a girl.
Scott: I can't get the other person to grope you.
Rym: every single one of you cross players who flies to an anime con.
Rym: Wear your shit on the plane.
Rym: This is gonna be awesome.
Scott: It's gonna be like I'll get groped if I go this right this way ma'am.
Scott: And it's like you go and you get the girl comes to grope you and yeah, that's right.
Scott: So or right even just as good right you're it.
Scott: you're dressed like a woman Right or your dress is the opposite and you go to the correct person.
Scott: So you're a girl.
Scott: you look like a girl.
Scott: you go up to get groped by the guy.
Scott: He's like And he gropes you in this junk and you give him like a wink.
Rym: I Just every vision of this in my head is willing to file.
Scott: You can get a lot of a lot of good stuff going on there.
Rym: So I don't want to talk about this too much because we have to actually see.
Rym: this is going to be staged in over time Like in the coming months, but the headlines were Facebook's making a gmail killer, which is not true Not even close to true.
Rym: Basically Facebook is trying to make a product called ICQ all over again and integrated with Facebook.
Rym: Basically Facebook originally the announcements for all the Facebook's making an email system compete with Gmail.
Rym: It's actually much more interesting than that and the TL;DR version of this I guess TL;DL.
Rym: Okay, TL;DL too long to listen.
Rym: Is that what they're making is A good idea for people who don't understand technology and don't use the technology They already have?
Rym: effectively?
Rym: it is not that useful for people who do both of these things.
Rym: They're adding a sort of email you can use their Facebook that has a social inbox Which is basically a filtered inbox.
Rym: So instead of getting all your mail in one inbox all your social mail meaning anything that came from any of your friends Goes into one mailbox and everything else goes into a general mailbox.
Rym: Of course, it's Facebook gonna be full of spam.
Scott: Well, I could just do that with the Gmail filter.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you could.
Rym: So it automatically will show you anything from a friend or a friend of a friend to the bane of orchid.
Rym: So we'll see how that goes.
Rym: and you can like kick people out of your inbox and back in and you can import people.
Rym: the other thing it's doing and again, these are all just incremental improvements that are being done together is Aggregation much like what the palm pre did where if I SMS you and you G talk me back It just keeps it all in one stream.
Scott: That's like Google voice.
Scott: Yeah and Google plus Gmail plus Google time.
Rym: So they're doing that a little bit better and that they're actually just making one contiguous stream.
Rym: But the way they're doing it is really geared towards short conversations.
Rym: It's pretty much exactly what ICQ was.
Rym: only it's as though you had ICQ on every possible device all the time.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and The weird part is.
Rym: the third like aspect of this is the box of letters and they make this point that in the old days You know, wouldn't it be great if you had a record of every conversation you ever had with your best friend or with your girlfriend?
Scott: Yeah, I do too and they're like and you know, I deleted a bunch of them over time But I still have a lot.
Scott: they're like my grandma.
Rym: I had that.
Rym: it was called a box of letters.
Rym: No one does that anymore and it's so sad.
Rym: and all I could think was I have every chat and email I've ever exchanged in my entire life.
Rym: Yeah all the way back to when I first got a nice.
Scott: All them ever.
Scott: but I still have a lot of them and I had logs at various times and I just deleted or got rid Of them or whatever, but I still have.
Rym: hey, I'm that guy with the hat who was at the gaming night.
Rym: You want to go to the anime club after dinner at Gracie's?
Rym: Yeah, that is the first thing I ever chatted to you.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: Did you just look that up now?
Rym: Yeah I looked it up a little while ago because I knew I wanted to talk about this.
Rym: Okay, but it basically they're taking all the way once you get the head again that I got the head around somewhere.
Rym: Actually, Emily got me a new hat.
Rym: It's much more comfortable than that one gonna strap a dinosaur.
Rym: Don't remind me about that guy.
Rym: or else after talk about duck boy.
Scott: You can strap a wooden duck to the head.
Scott: Wow, the rubber ducky to the head.
Rym: that was a decade ago.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, so Facebook's thing is going to make people who are already Facebook people more Facebook people.
Rym: It's not going to affect other people and it's actually a good feature, but it's not a gmail killer It's not anything new even it's just Facebook doing incremental and obvious improvements.
Scott: You know I don't like is this trend now of Rolling out a feature to some people and then some more people and some more people right because Twitter did this with the new Twitter?
Scott: Look, yeah, it's like the people who it just it was so random.
Scott: It was like people who actually use Twitter and wanted it just wouldn't get.
Scott: I got didn't get it for the longest time But other people got it right away.
Scott: It's like and they took him.
Scott: So, I mean obviously it's better for keeping their systems up and to test things out.
Rym: I didn't know.
Rym: I thought people were stupid one day.
Scott: all I see all these tweets like And to expose people to like less, you know bugs because it's always good to run in a beta you want to do.
Scott: the reason they do betas and stages is because what happens with the beta is you put a beta out and Everyone reports the same exact bug and then you fix it and it's like.
Scott: those people already reported a bug.
Scott: They're not reporting anymore.
Scott: So you got to roll it out to even new people and they'll report the second bug and it's basically each wave.
Scott: It's one more bug reported.
Rym: almost, you know, I like NS to every time this new build.
Rym: I play it once I hit a game-breaker.
Scott: The thing is a slow release is very very good for the company doing the release, right?
Scott: You know for many reasons like it won't bring the systems down and they can test things out and if there is a bug they expose fewer users to it to decrease people being upset and it's easy to roll back and undo because you got both things up at the same time and working simultaneously, right
Rym: but
Scott: It's much better for the users If you find some way for them to be like, you know Like a good a good example of the right way to do.
Scott: is you stream right?
Scott: you streams like hey Try our beta show page if you want and it's like.
Scott: you can click beta show page to use the newer better page at any Time.
Scott: but most are good.
Scott: YouTube with HTML 5. you want to use YouTube HTML 5 go for it, right?
Scott: But we're not switching everyone over and so it's like they put it out there.
Scott: Anyone who wants to use it can use it and anyone who doesn't know where doesn't care doesn't and that's the better way to roll Out I think because it makes it accessible to everyone who wants it immediately.
Scott: They don't have to wait, right?
Scott: They're not saying where the hell's the new Twitter?
Scott: Where's the hell this new feature?
Scott: Everyone's got the new feature right now, but You know You can still get the same effect of rolling it out slowly.
Scott: We're instead of having everyone in the world use it immediately and then it goes down.
Rym: So things to watch for with this to see where this is gonna go is How quickly they roll it out and how quickly it gets spanned to fuck?
Rym: Yeah, those two factors will determine whether or not this exceeds how quickly people stop, you know using you know more.
Scott: How much more do they stop using their other communication things?
Rym: Yeah, because I've noticed this trend among even the front row crew.
Rym: We're gonna our personal group of friends.
Rym: in college I used ICQ and about half of us use that and the other half of the school used aim and Eventually aim won out for various reasons and then I see cute ICQ died.
Scott: Yeah, Google Talk came in.
Scott: So now it's like half Google Talk half aim and even though a bunch of people have gone over to Google Talk There's still a bunch of aim which is
Rym: but even worse a lot of the people I know Who are otherwise really techie cool smart people just aren't ever online in any sort of I am system anymore.
Scott: Yeah, people have.
Scott: basically I am is almost dead.
Scott: It's like people just use Facebook and that's it Which is interesting.
Rym: check
Scott: their emails
Rym: because the way I used instant messaging The only reason it aimed worked was because my computer was always on But with ICQ the only difference really that mattered in this context was that you could send a message and it would be delivered once Someone came online if they weren't online Automatically, so as a result, it was like time bit like you could talk to someone But if they weren't there you could just send them a message.
Rym: Anyway, you'd know they would get it eventually.
Rym: and it was kind of this, you know on demand You can talk when you want.
Rym: conversations will start and stop over the course of a day and I am as we have it now Doesn't do that very well actually.
Rym: Yeah and Facebook and things like it do that much better.
Rym: But Facebook is the stupid walled garden problem and Twitter is the wrong tool for that.
Scott: Yeah, and the problem is is that you know Even if you could make something that was a much better I am in.
Scott: tool like you just made the perfect.
Scott: I am.
Rym: Oh, it's great.
Rym: And I'm the only one on it.
Scott: Yeah No one's gonna use it because you don't have the it's.
Scott: the thing is because face it's the same sort of situation We're having a Facebook.
Scott: now is the problem we had with Windows in 1995. right Windows was so dominant that anything they attached to Windows immediately got all these people on it.
Scott: AOL being on the Windows desktop just was like boom IE being the built into Windows.
Scott: boom It made IE an instant success.
Scott: So now because everyone's on Facebook because it's Facebook Facebook is just anything they put on.
Scott: Facebook is also but it wins because it's on the Facebooks, right?
Scott: And it's it's really hard for anything that isn't on the Facebooks to have any sort of competitions really.
Scott: and the Twitter?
Scott: You know Twitter came out and went.
Scott: oh four 707 was Twitter, right?
Scott: So even though Facebook was older than that It was still.
Scott: Facebook was not as dominant as it is now.
Rym: Well I think what the next thing is going to be at least the thing for us.
Rym: the thing that'll actually change things will be when people start seriously making ways of Integrating and aggregating things from all these walled gardens to where I can have my one thing But that's the thing is every walled garden is smart enough to have openness.
Scott: in terms of you know You can build on our platform in a way that benefits us by building on our platform But you cannot build on our platform and they limit it in this very smart ways to prevent you from basically Taking all your information out of their platform and dumping them, right?
Scott: So for example if Facebook let you you know, and this is what the Facebook Google fight was about recently.
Scott: Do you see that?
Scott: Yeah, basically Facebook had a thing like hey find friends using your Google contacts and Google was like, alright We're not gonna let you use our Google time contacts information anymore Unless you start giving us your Facebook information, right?
Scott: It's only fair.
Scott: and Facebook was like, alright stop, you know and they're like.
Scott: We'll just set this different page up where people are Instructed to download their Google contacts and then upload them to Facebook on one easy to do page and Google basically said alright You can do that But we're gonna put a big old message that tells the user is like hey Are you sure you want to download your Google contacts and send them to Facebook?
Scott: Cuz they're not gonna let you export your contacts ever again.
Scott: Cuz what could happen is if Facebook let you export that stuff, right?
Scott: Like let you.
Scott: if Facebook let you export your data.
Scott: I could set up a social networking site tomorrow where you would sign in with Facebook Connect.
Scott: it would export all your Facebook data to this other site and you can close your Facebook account and People.
Scott: I'd actually have a pretty significant chance if I was able to Copy all those features of Facebook of people jumping ship or what I would do.
Rym: much more I guess more practical as in I think this will actually happen.
Rym: if you bust in and get integration to work Smart people like us will have our whatever account and it just publishes to all the stupid walled gardens that I have an account in All publishing - is never a problem.
Scott: They love information coming in.
Scott: Yeah, but I just Come back.
Scott: I don't like that.
Rym: I could get a Facebook and have all my stuff just go into Facebook But then you assholes are gonna like message me in Facebook and I'm not gonna get it and I don't want to deal with setting.
Scott: Yeah, basically what I've done is I have you know Facebook emails me on occasion and that's the only time I ever look at is if it sends me an email.
Scott: So I never checked the Facebook, but I get emails from the Facebook that have links to the Facebook.
Rym: I have a hidden shitty Facebook account.
Rym: I only use to look at other people's crap when I need to.
Scott: I have a Twitter that sends to a Facebook, right?
Scott: But I you know, I don't actually ever post manually on the Facebook itself.
Rym: So whatever so things of the day.
Rym: You know the old myth that it's hot.
Rym: you can't swim out of Alcatraz like those people who theoretically escaped couldn't have swum it.
Scott: It's not that far.
Scott: Can you see it from the shore?
Rym: It's actually a pretty easy.
Scott: you can see it from the shore.
Scott: You get totally swimming like it's not.
Rym: it depends.
Rym: I mean people deep there.
Scott: listen, there are people who have swum like the English Channel.
Rym: Oh, yeah Distance alone actually is not a big factor in that sort of thing as opposed to you're saying that the waters are Water temperature water roughness and currents actually are the primary issues in trying to do a swim like that.
Scott: Also sharks also sharks, but and octopuses.
Rym: Basically, this is good for anyone who thinks and could I do somehow Alcatraz was impossible or different?
Scott: Jellyfish.
Rym: here's a video of a nine-year-old boy swimming from Alcatraz to San Francisco.
Scott: Hey, it was a nine-year-old boy.
Scott: Was it a nice day?
Rym: I was kind of choppy.
Scott: Is he like prac?
Scott: was he like a?
Scott: his parents trained him to swim from early age So he could be the next Michael.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: He said it was real cold.
Scott: Yeah, when did he do this recently, yeah, why didn't he do?
Scott: in the summer Whatever?
Scott: That's all I got.
Rym: as I got her I didn't want to use just like one of my college humor cute animals.
Scott: So I had different thing in the day, but I think it might have been thinking they before I do.
Rym: There's one guy who swam at seven hundred and thirty seven times.
Scott: So anyway, I know this hasn't been a thing of the day before.
Scott: basically have you ever had to write a program that That speaks to another, you know computer over a serial port rs-232.
Scott: I have have you.
Scott: yeah Well, basically right whenever you do I've done this before as well.
Scott: You you have some community protocol, right?
Scott: This is what the packets are gonna.
Scott: maybe you know, this is what it's gonna look like.
Scott: This is gonna be the control cat, right?
Rym: You got to agree to that.
Scott: all you got to set the baud rate and you got to do both have to agree to it Have some sort of way of negotiating.
Scott: you got to do all this stuff, right and it's not that hard, right?
Scott: I mean, especially on a Unix system.
Scott: It's like you find the file you open the file.
Scott: You're right to it You read from it you buffer the incoming data you buffer the outgoing data.
Scott: Maybe you resend you come up with some protocol and you just do it, right?
Scott: But it has a lot of these things that you have to code every single time that are bullshit.
Scott: Well Somebody has written a programming language called any serial port.
Scott: he's got any serious any serial port?
Scott: calm and it's a serial port programming language and Basically all the things that you do every single time you want to talk over a serial port in your program.
Scott: It basically just provides easy commands to do it.
Scott: So for example, if you want to check if a serial port is open or closed if you want to you know Buffer incoming data.
Scott: if you want to convert a string to an array of bytes, you know All this stuff that you do every single time all the time whenever you're doing any program involving serial ports.
Scott: It just may as easy to do commands to handle all that shit and it makes writing any program that speaks over serial RS to 232 really really 32 to 32.
Scott: It makes it really easy to do.
Rym: It's actually not RS.
Rym: It's an actual standard.
Rym: It's no longer a recommended stand whatever.
Scott: It makes it really easy to do even if you aren't like a hardcore programmer.
Scott: So, you know if you want to like plug some sort of device into your computer on a serial port.
Scott: This will let you talk to it.
Scott: You know, get some Arduino.
Scott: This will work well with that.
Rym: Yeah, I remember when I learned all that stuff worked, you know My original computer my 486 sx2 had Documentation for everything including its 2400 baud modem.
Scott: The only thing with this is it's sort of Microsoft centric, right?
Rym: So yeah, well, I never actually coded anything in Windows.
Rym: I mean whenever I use the serial port in Windows I would basically open hyper terminal and just connect directly and just type direct commands to whatever I was like.
Scott: You look at this feature list.
Scott: It's like yeah You know supports all major Windows platforms redistributable as part of your dotnet application.
Scott: So it's a little you know data export file or any ODBC compatible database MSQL oracle access excel dbase, right?
Scott: So it's like pretty Microsoft centric, but even so It's a pretty good idea Especially if you're a serial port kind of person.
Rym: serial ports are still actually fairly useful just because of the fact that they're really simple And it's really easy to do physical stuff on the other side.
Rym: Yep like it's the the the thresholds of current and voltage for data are real big and The timing is actually really easy to sort out Like coding like making a device that'll just take in USB unless you just buy pre-made stuff.
Rym: Not so easy.
Scott: Actually, this also has an awesome GUI going on.
Scott: So, you know, it's really easy.
Scott: for normal people Like you'll be shocked how easy this is.
Scott: you are compared to writing it and see which is what I usually do But not the most.
Rym: I use my bod 2400 baud modem for though was connecting to BBS's until eventually I upgraded to a 33 6.
Rym: I use the null modem.
Rym: I had a fit to play Doom 2 with my brother.
Scott: I had a 14 4 modem, but then I Eventually got a 56 K external USB modem, which I think I still have somewhere the day or maybe I remember trying to explain to My parents why I needed a null modem And then I finally convinced them.
Rym: we went to Radio Shack.
Rym: We bought it went home and I hooked the two computers up and we played quick and they were actually pretty amazed by that.
Rym: Yeah, because there was no internet back then at least not like we have now.
Rym: there was dial-up Kind of.
Rym: it didn't work that well.
Rym: So we might have done shows about things like this in the past, but Especially now with the peer-to-peer battles really heating up a lot of people don't seem to actually understand what the internet is.
Rym: I'd like It's starting to bother me.
Scott: Well, I got the idea to do this show because people didn't know what internet 2 was.
Scott: So we can we got to start before we even talk about what that is.
Scott: We got to start like with the with the beginning.
Rym: I want well ARPANET.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: So I actually I went to the TLDR version and that too is awesome.
Rym: The internet is capitalized because it's a proper.
Rym: now the internet capitalized is an internet.
Rym: Yeah, the internet is a collection of networks that are themselves Networked.
Scott: Yeah, so a network is just things connected to each other.
Scott: It could be two people It could be it doesn't have to be people could be people computers any things that are connected and communicating is a network, right?
Scott: but an intranet right lowercase I Unintranet is when you have a network that is closed off.
Rym: now Technically, that's just an internal network and intranet usually means that you have multiple networks that are themselves network But they are not connected to anything.
Scott: Yes, but that is Pedantry.
Scott: Yes, that is still a network, right?
Scott: Yes, you can consider, you know, what's the difference between that be?
Scott: You know, okay So I have an office building in New York and have an office building in California and I have an OC 3 going between them.
Scott: That's a land and there's a network.
Scott: I know It's many things at once.
Scott: All right Because on the one hand the network the network in New York is a network and the network in California is a network and they're Connected.
Scott: so that's an intranet.
Scott: the two networks are now intranet worked but at the same time Both of them together are connected.
Scott: So the whole thing is a network.
Rym: now if you want to get into the real Pedantic bullshit details.
Rym: It also matters as to whether or not they share namespaces and IP spaces.
Scott: Yeah, and what if the new and if the New York office is split between like the the sales staff and the tech staff?
Scott: Well, that's an intranet because you've split them into two, you know.
Rym: Or if you've got multiple like a lot of good production IT environments You have multiple completely separate segregated networks Like you have the main interface network that everything connects to.
Rym: that's how you're like SSH into your servers.
Rym: And then you've got the monitoring backplane.
Rym: Maybe you've got even a second backplane that is just for like data transfers or just for backups.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Actually, I didn't bother with that here because now that Scott I don't live in the same place and it's just me and Emily And now that everything's just gigabit doesn't really matter.
Rym: but back in the day I was thinking about making a separate network in the house just for internal data transfers.
Rym: Yeah, not so important now.
Scott: No, not important.
Scott: No, actually I transferred something by gigabit over to my HD PC the other day.
Scott: Yeah, it took five minutes like a whole bunch of gigs.
Rym: Anyway, I gotta make an HD PC.
Rym: I'm that Mac Mac's not holding up anymore.
Rym: No, but anyway, what's real important here?
Rym: I really want people to remember this internet is capitalized because the internet is very very different from an internet.
Scott: Yeah on internet is.
Scott: you know net is?
Scott: Inter-networked networks, right it can form on internet.
Scott: There are can be many internets, you know, but there is only one capital I internet which is the internet.
Rym: However, there is the internet too, which is not itself.
Rym: that name does not specify an Internet so much as it specifies a consortium of people who together have created an alternate high-speed future backbone.
Scott: Yes, but it is on internet.
Scott: in lower the internet too.
Scott: is that network that they have created is on internet?
Scott: Yes, but it is not the internet.
Rym: But what is another?
Rym: it is, however, not Necessarily separate from the real internet.
Rym: In fact, it's a part of the internet.
Rym: It's just your packets aren't routing over it.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Most of the time basically, right?
Scott: So imagine if you know I got.
Scott: you know I'm on.
Scott: I got a cable modem right and rims got cable modem and we're both on the internet right via our cable modems.
Scott: But I toss a cable over to rims house.
Scott: Okay, so now our houses are connected to each other and we're violating numerous local statutes Probably but whatever.
Scott: so I set up my router to say hey router Yeah if anything is you know going to Rym send it over this wire instead of the internet wire and then Rym does the same thing on His end.
Scott: and now that's basically what internet too is like, you know It's you.
Scott: I won't even notice if my packets are going over the you know This the the special Rym wire or the other wire.
Scott: They might actually go over the Rym wire and then be routed over to the internet.
Scott: if you know Who knows what's gonna happen with the routing.
Scott: the point is?
Scott: That's what internet 2 is like it's?
Scott: you don't even notice that you're using internet 2 or using internet 1.
Scott: It's just your packets get routed over the better internet 2 wires if you are on internet 2.
Scott: So if you're at a college that's an internet 2 connection.
Scott: If you visit like say MIT dot edu Your packets are probably going to be going over internet 2 wires.
Rym: is now internet 1 wires the tldr version of that or tldl is that?
Rym: most of what is on that internet is Pornography where's and various copyright violations.
Scott: There is a lot of that going on in internet 2 because someone's sitting in their dorm room at one college as some peer-to-peer Application.
Scott: by the way, I found out what the new hot peer-to-peer application is.
Scott: Yeah The torrent.
Scott: no, it's something else.
Scott: so and then someone else will be seeing a different college and they'll both load up You know, I guess the modern equivalent direct connector.
Scott: if they're still using direct connect that even though Oh my god Or even bit torrent and reconnect flashbacks to RIT and they'll both start a torrent and all those packets like a router.
Scott: No for internet - because they're both on internet - and it'll be really fast.
Scott: That's just how it works.
Scott: But at the same time like if you want to download an ISO of like a Linux distribution I'll take you like two seconds.
Rym: The best part about internet - was just that it was it's kind of a self-selected internet.
Rym: It can be more advanced than the normal internet because smart people are trying out better ways of doing backbone Infrastructure.
Rym: because remember the internet with a capital I is just a bunch of networks that are connected like level 3.
Scott: Yeah Basically, what's cool?
Scott: so what's going on here is you can't like Practice out or do experiments on the real internet because it's the real internet.
Scott: if you mess up your experiment You're gonna disrupt service for a whole bunch of people.
Scott: But if internet to service gets disrupted even the people at the college won't be that my wares.
Rym: I'll have to connect to the local direct connect.
Rym: that only has The collect.
Scott: I can't use internet - I'll have to use the internet and my counter-strike ping to California went up from one Millisecond to two milliseconds.
Scott: Yeah, it's not a bit right.
Rym: So what they do on internet - is actually I think six is about as good as you could.
Scott: possibly the reason it's so fast Is because they're constantly Experimenting on it.
Scott: if you want to do research on you know internet working, you know You do it on internet - at some school and in the in the.
Scott: you know The IT department and you can practice and you can set up new lines.
Rym: and like one example You can try out some IP v6 before the IP 6 v6 rollout.
Rym: I personally applied for and got a Gigantic chunk of the six bone which was like the testing network for IP v6 to do a project for a class that I then dropped.
Rym: eventually that expired.
Scott: The point is is that you know, it's a play internet - is I had a partner I don't know ever happened to his project internet - is a place where you know or magical things happen.
Scott: You can do that sort of thing.
Rym: It doesn't matter with no ping.
Rym: Yeah, all right He had an OC 3 that was for the internet - and then an RC 3 just for the internet and that was back in 2000.
Rym: I can't imagine what they have now.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: Well that I thought we would have a lot more to say on this.
Rym: Well, I do have a lot more to say because the internet.
Rym: this is why I don't want to harp on net neutrality But this is why net neutrality is so important.
Scott: The internet
Rym: was originally designed partly as a military and science application to be a network That was robust that it would route around trouble that everything is kind of connected to everything else and you can send data and it Gets there without having a direct wire to get there.
Scott: Yeah, like, you know, oh this wire broke.
Scott: Well, it's good We got other wires because it's a big web of wires all over the place.
Scott: Yep, as long as it's a path from A to B It doesn't matter what that path is.
Scott: as long as we can find some way to complete it Even if it goes all the way around the world to get there.
Scott: We'll get there.
Rym: But there's actually not that much redundancy in the modern internet.
Scott: Yeah, the biggest problem is that because everyone has ISPs, right?
Scott: There's all these single points of failure for large chunks, right?
Scott: So if your ISP goes down and they say, you know, you're done, right?
Scott: that was you have this one's focal wire that is carrying all the traffic of Cablevision or Time Warner or Comcast.
Scott: so and on top of that right you have another problem, which is okay.
Scott: I have a data center and I know I can't have a single point of failure.
Scott: So I've got ten different wires coming in here, right?
Scott: But at some point, you know some guy out there right if he wants to get to any of those ten wires He's got to find a wire going to your town and all the wires going to your town go through sprint link or whatever.
Scott: some You know huge backbone like that and those backbones luckily are really good at staying up.
Scott: But they've had a major problem in a while.
Rym: I've actually I dealt with a major problem last week.
Rym: I won't name names or anything, but a major provider had a gigantic fire in a tunnel filled with fiber.
Scott: Oh, gee, I can't guess who that would be and it sucked ass.
Scott: But that was a local NYC thing right the big backbone.
Rym: No that actually broke connectivity between an NYC thing and a Virginia thing.
Scott: Wow, it's really big.
Scott: But I'm saying is that it wasn't like a fire between you know, how many times the great old ones fight?
Rym: There will be gods fighting meaning two level.
Rym: two ISPs Will have some sort of bitch fight with each other and then the internet just gets disrupted.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And if there was actually like a major national disaster like if New York City got nuked or something crazy half the internet's just gonna Stop working.
Rym: That's also true and I feel like we need more redundancy.
Rym: We need we need to get to the new, you know People always talked about web 2.0.
Rym: We need to get to web 3.0.
Rym: We need to get to a world or web 10.0 Where every single device is connected to as many other devices as possible wirelessly ad hoc Like you've got to have like 10 layers of redundancy.
Rym: Imagine if we had a world where I've got my wire ISP, right?
Rym: Mm-hmm and independently.
Rym: maybe I've got the power line connection that anyone can just connect to it slow as shit But it's there and the government maintains it or something or you pay a small fee to have access to it And maybe there's municipal Wi-Fi and I'm also connected to that
Scott: and maybe
Rym: I could pay for another Wi-Fi.
Rym: I want to have as many ways of connecting to people as possible such that Everyone is publishing and consuming at about equal rates all the time.
Scott: well, that's another problem.
Scott: right is because they're still in IPv4.
Scott: right publishing is difficult because You need an IP address and there's not so many of them.
Scott: So you have to get a hosting company.
Rym: I would argue.
Rym: it's also difficult because the there is a vested interest in many multimedia conglomerates in preventing Individual people from having publishing parity.
Scott: Well, also every hosting company in the world, right?
Scott: They want you to buy hosting.
Scott: They don't want you to turn on a computer in your house and have that be.
Scott: you know As good as the data with my files.
Rym: I could pretty much host GeekNights here.
Scott: Yeah, there are some people who have good internet connections and they totally do it and that's the way it should be.
Rym: and imagine if Everyone did that.
Scott: Yeah You didn't know one.
Scott: every hosting company went out of business and anyone who wanted a website just turned a computer on in their House or even better and left it on all the time and their website was.
Rym: we've talked about this before.
Rym: Imagine a world where your web browser is also a web server operas doing that.
Rym: Yeah, but it's not There.
Scott: no for obvious reason, but as soon as you got a pv6, right?
Scott: They won't be able to stop you from having a static IP address, right?
Scott: You're gonna.
Scott: so you're gonna.
Scott: you know, the DNS the problem will be solved You know, you'll be able to just have you know Whatever calm point at your house where your computers are and your stuff will be running there and it'll be all good.
Scott: all right, you wanted to pay for hosting.
Scott: all the hosting companies be gone and You know, you'll you'll.
Scott: it'll be totally awesome.
Rym: Well, let's talk a little bit about the World Wide Web because we've done a show on.
Scott: the World Wide Web is not the internet It's not on internet.
Rym: It's not an intranet and it's not internet - it's a Gillette and Michael Godot I know I argued with you about this.
Rym: You guys are still wrong.
Scott: Well, that was a DNS argument.
Rym: Yeah, but then I they I argued with them about Www and they didn't know what it meant.
Rym: and then they they I have the studio World Wide Web is specifically right.
Scott: just pretty much HTTP.
Scott: HTTP is the World Wide Web and what it is.
Scott: people have set up HTTP servers.
Scott: These are servers that speak the hypertext transfer protocol and like, you know Apache is the most popular HTTP server in the world, right and So you if you run an HTTP server that server is not part of the web.
Scott: and basically because every HTTP server can be reached via a URL you can create links and people can click a link while they're looking at a page that is served by one server and they'll then their Browser will request a page from another server.
Scott: So from the user's perspective.
Scott: It looks like there's this connected web of Pages all served by different servers all in different places around the world.
Rym: conceptually I mean the internet physically and conceptually is a web of devices that are all interconnected and there's multiple redundant paths to places.
Rym: You know in theory, yep, the World Wide Web is just a meta structure.
Scott: on top of that It's not even you know on the hardware level.
Scott: The World Wide Web is not even a web.
Scott: It's pretty much just all these individual points that are you know?
Scott: Not connected except for the fact that their content that is served at each of those points Refers to content that is served on other points.
Rym: But the beauty of this is that the World Wide Web is nothing more than a meta construct an abstract a protocol.
Rym: You could have any underlying physical infrastructure It doesn't matter.
Rym: and furthermore because the original World Wide Web was Designed really for making pages where words linked to other pages about things It was also designed right to where anyone could edit any page right.
Scott: your HTTP It's it's plus it's.
Scott: but what put?
Scott: post yeah and delete right.
Scott: those are the four major command.
Rym: You're pretty much getting 99% of the time.
Scott: pretty much everyone gets nobody really ever.
Scott: You know you post when you submit a form right.
Rym: well I think this is just a matter of you.
Scott: don't really delete or put anything.
Rym: Tim Berners-Lee and all the other Geniuses involved in this just were far too forward-thinking.
Rym: Yeah I mean we're way ahead of their time.
Scott: if what their original vision of the World Wide Web had come to be would basically be Every do basically everything would be Wikipedia everything and even probably even better than Wikipedia.
Rym: That would be awesome.
Scott: It would be like everyone edit every page everywhere, and that is what the original vision of the web was.
Scott: But that's not what it turned out to be.
Rym: yep And there are other you know.
Rym: we could go into detail there where we won't but basically The World Wide Web is a meta construct.
Rym: And I think that's important because what was the primary tenant of the World Wide Web?
Rym: even if we ignore the fact that we don't have the editing everywhere that you link directly to relevant information and Just by the course of humans the core create useful neural networks of information.
Scott: yeah, the core of the web really it was the hypertext right that you could have text that links to other text.
Scott: right HTTP.
Scott: and That's what we got.
Scott: we got text that links to other text.
Rym: oh no.
Rym: But now we've got flash that you can't link directly into.
Rym: oh we've got people blocking links.
Rym: You can't hotlink and embed shit.
Scott: Yeah, regardless the web right or the World Wide Web really only refers to web pages.
Scott: It doesn't refer to anything else, so if you think about it, right?
Scott: The internet also includes pretty much everything else right bit torrents IRC I am Email every.
Scott: there are tons and tons of internet applications.
Scott: right things that you do on the internets that are not the web.
Scott: they're not web pages you know and People don't seem to think about those things a lot And I think part of it is because they do a lot of things through a web interface Which is fine, or you know when they're not using the browser.
Scott: They don't realize that they're using the internet.
Scott: Internet is the browser and plus I mean it's called Internet Explorer.
Scott: It's you know but Internet Explorer Actually can sort of you can go on FTP.
Scott: it can do a lot of things that are not HTTP.
Scott: So it is actually sort of an accurate name.
Scott: It is an Internet Explorer.
Rym: Well there was gopher.
Scott: Gopher was also dead now.
Scott: Yeah, you know it was.
Scott: it was similar to HTTP kind of well anyway that.
Rym: but going back to the Web thing because you know we've made all these advances.
Rym: We're doing all these things on the internet other than the web.
Rym: but if we just consider the web we have achieved and realized maybe 1% of the true potential of just text only hypertext like that alone.
Rym: We have achieved so little of what is possible with that.
Rym: all of our laws are not just there interlinked Yep, all of our public policy all the all of our tech.
Rym: well.
Scott: It's just that's just a situation of data, right?
Scott: I mean technologically we've pushed it to the limits.
Scott: It's just data.
Scott: wise you know we haven't gotten all the data up there.
Scott: You know and that's what we built this conceptual.
Scott: a lot of the data That's been up there has been closed off and you know various.
Rym: We built a conceptual lattice and we started putting stuff in it And then we were distracted by shiny stuff.
Rym: And we've got this perfectly good lattice that could change the world and we're gonna change the world.
Scott: But it's only changed the world.
Scott: and the thing is like it can change the world.
Scott: so much right It's like it's only changed the world maybe 10% of what it could.
Scott: but that 10% is gigantic.
Scott: That's like oh, it's 10% of a Jillian.
Scott: so we got 1/10 of a Jillian changes Gigantic ginormous change, I know you hate ginormous.
Rym: I hate that word so much, but We have the word enormous.
Scott: we have the word gigantic.
Scott: We could have a 10 times as much ginormous.
Rym: a change is you know?
Rym: Where does ginormous fit in the scale?
Rym: is it bigger than gargantuan?
Scott: Gigantic enormous is the biggest.
Rym: the biggest bigger than gargantuan.
Rym: yeah bigger than omnipresent.
Scott: Omnipresent is pretty much infinity bigs.
Rym: Yeah, so we can't know.
Scott: so it's not that big.
Rym: okay, so it's not the biggest.
Scott: well No, I mean you can't be you know.
Scott: It's like your infinity is not the biggest.
Rym: well Yeah, it is.
Scott: no that is infinity.
Scott: minus one is the biggest.
Rym: now infinity is the biggest because you could be one more than infinity Minus one, but that's in one more than infinity Which is any.
Scott: but what about what about in one less than infinity is not infinity is infinity minus 10 less than infinity minus 9?
Rym: Yes, by how much one one yep?
Rym: I think we've exhausted this.
Rym: Possibly you know though stay tuned tech people because our next Tuesday show We're actually going to talk about network stuff because in a gaming show yes all you tech people probably Don't realize that the vast majority of games have the like.
Rym: they don't understand How networks work and it's starting to become a problem big problem?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our Website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.