Rym: Hey, it's Monday, November 1st, 2010.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight with resident GeekNights scientist Peter Olson We discuss science education.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know, it's kind of scary that five years and one day ago.
Rym: We started GeekNights for no head.
Scott: We started it five years in like couple weeks ago.
Rym: Well five years and one day ago We published GeekNights to people other than our friends.
Rym: Yeah, and we did it for like three weeks before that when we used to sing the opener.
Rym: remember that.
Rym: That's these stupid human tricks, so I'm pretty sure that those episodes are still up.
Scott: they are in the place.
Scott: I have guaranteed that they are publicly available.
Scott: So nobody can tell me that they are not publicly available.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: They're out there.
Scott: They were linked and the only reason that I do not just straight-up link to them is Because I kind of like having secrets.
Scott: It's like in the old NES days, you know Finding secrets is like oh man.
Rym: But let me tell you finding the original like beta of GeekNights is a lot like finding the pay-me-for-the-door charge.
Rym: You're never gonna get those hours back.
Rym: No We had a microphone on the other side of the room.
Rym: that Logitech stick mic Pointed straight up and we sat like 10 feet away from it hoping that the room would act as a sort of cheap compressor.
Scott: But as anyone out there who's got like old arts or old things that they've made that they're ashamed of Luke crane You should put them out there anyway, you know.
Scott: fact, I'm looking to say look at penny arcade, right?
Scott: You don't see them taking down those original strips.
Scott: In fact, they published a book of those old original strips.
Rym: Emily and I are actually gonna try it.
Rym: I gotta find them.
Rym: we're gonna try to trade all the essays we wrote in like high school.
Scott: Oh I don't think I have mine.
Scott: Yeah, otherwise I would do that.
Rym: I think I got a bunch of hard drives and one of them is crash.
Scott: Maybe we can do is we can just put a Kickstarter and be like look everyone send in So your essays from high school and we'll make a website that people can take those essays and republish them and get a's.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: No, we'll just print out a book, you know, make a book.
Scott: We'll make a book but like a hundred high school essays will call it if it sells We'll make volume two.
Rym: we can call the book terribly inaccurate representations of literature and history.
Scott: We give you like five fag all five paragraphs the book five paragraphs.
Rym: Actually kind of a good idea.
Rym: I would read that.
Scott: So I go read.
Rym: everyone is so boring.
Rym: everyone's gonna start with the global statement and then zero in on their thesis statement.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: So woman, uh Scott warm today.
Rym: No My apartment but my heat was working only in the bedroom not in the studio.
Rym: It is warm in this apartment But my heat was not working in the studio the gig night studio.
Rym: nor was it working in the living room or the kitchen But it was working in the bedroom.
Rym: So I tell the building they're like, okay, we'll fix it.
Rym: Apparently by fix it they might well fix it.
Rym: We'll turn it all the way up and we'll leave it on all.
Rym: goddamn day.
Rym: I got home and it was like 90 degrees is why you just don't ask for anything.
Rym: I wouldn't have had heat in the studio and it's gonna get cold.
Rym: It's gonna.
Scott: it's already cold.
Scott: It's cold today woman.
Rym: I about froze my motherfucking nuts off.
Rym: My love for you at deathless is cold outside you by change that only like.
Scott: I was like trying to decide like You know how much coat I should wear this morning and I took not enough.
Rym: see NASA definitely needs to change its focus, but NASA was right on topic.
Rym: That was actually a long time ago.
Rym: we talked about that on GeekNights here.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, so it is Monday.
Rym: It's a sign.
Rym: stay before we get to our guest.
Rym: Yeah You said you had some news and you didn't want to talk about the holographic universe theory because you much like me Probably have at best a superficial understanding and did not want to be caught generalizing incorrectly.
Scott: Yeah, so I really don't know much about it at all.
Rym: I'm excited about it and I explained it to a bunch of people not on the air poor because I Can explain it poorly but well enough to where it gets the point across but without having a record where someone can prove me wrong in subtle and pedantic ways.
Rym: Anyway, all I'm gonna say is I think it's really cool and I'm kind of excited about the fact that we're getting to the point in the world where we can test for the reliability of things like causality or Locality.
Rym: and you know science always has the boring answer like.
Scott: it's mostly because we invented cool things like lasers that help you do It.
Rym: yeah But it's always like if there's a cool option and a boring option science usually finds the boring option Like are there aliens now now?
Rym: water on that now now now now now is the world just a hologram on a turtle.
Rym: now Now but someday we're gonna find something where they're gonna be like, yeah, you know what we disprove causality.
Rym: Check it out.
Rym: That electron went back in time and killed your mom.
Rym: now what?
Scott: So check that here's some news that might actually affect your life in a meaningful way, right?
Rym: I have a feeling that the breakdown of causality would affect my life in a meaningful way if they broke it down.
Scott: But I'm just saying if they just disproved it It wouldn't be that information wouldn't change.
Rym: disproving of causality would open up the possibility of free will.
Rym: actually anyway That would be exciting.
Scott: It wouldn't be the unit.
Scott: So society would not change as a result?
Rym: No, but I might change.
Scott: I might go all dunyane anyway anyway, so Apparently Google is suing the government which you can only do with the government's permission.
Rym: if I recall correctly I don't know if the government consented to the suit yet.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know either.
Scott: I don't know how that works.
Rym: Neither do I.
Scott: what I do know is that they are suing Because what happened was there was a bid, you know how they do bids for government contracts, right?
Scott: It's like oh the government wants to build a bridge.
Rym: Well, we gotta go with the lowest bidder.
Scott: ten different bridge building companies say I will build the bridge for X dollars And now another company says I will build the bridge for X minus ten dollars.
Rym: Never mind we did an art we did a show we talked about this a long time ago where there's a Problem where there's a whole kind of line of business where you're not good at what you do But what you're good at is navigating the American bureaucracy and restaurants that are like that are like inside of airports.
Rym: Their primary business is filling out paperwork and handling the bureaucracy not making food as you can probably tell.
Scott: Yeah anyway, anyway, so So Google put in a bids to get the some part of the government the Department of the Interior to use Google Apps Instead of Microsoft Office or any you know, whatever else could be used right?
Scott: So they put in this bid and they got rejected boom crack-a-lack.
Scott: and they got rejected again double crack-a-lack.
Scott: and Basically the requirements for this contract were Let me see if the exact words are here somewhere.
Scott: Yeah, I can't find them right now But basically the contract requirements were.
Scott: it has to be Microsoft compatible.
Scott: So basically that's like if I put it a bit and I said our town needs ten cars For compatible they need to be Ford's now.
Scott: Here's manufacturers send in a bid please.
Rym: Here's what I would argue.
Rym: They didn't say Ford's.
Rym: they said Ford compatible.
Rym: I would put forth my Chevy and be like It'll drive on the same road.
Rym: afford will drive on because open office will drive on the same road.
Rym: The world will drive on kind of almost.
Scott: the point is that basically the government sort of was hindering Competition here and sort of giving bullshit.
Rym: Here's the question corrupt bidding system was it or incompetence?
Guest: because Doesn't matter I know it doesn't matter.
Rym: but I still want to know because if it's corruption I expect that and if it's incompetence, it makes me sad, but I Should be angry or sad.
Rym: I Want to know if I should be angry or sad.
Scott: See, I find it strange that you would be angry or sad because like if it's in confidence, I expect that and if it's It's Corruption I expect.
Scott: so it's the same feeling either way.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I get angry when someone like when a fat guy blocks me from the subway I get angry because he screwed me up.
Rym: But if a fat guy just is fat, I'm sad because he's fat.
Rym: I Don't know if the government is fat.
Rym: I'm just sad but if it's also in my way, I'm also angry.
Scott: Thing is whether it's sad or in your way.
Scott: You should push it over.
Scott: It doesn't matter Scott.
Rym: if I push it over I might kill someone.
Scott: well Google's trying to push it over.
Scott: they might kill Microsoft.
Rym: The thing is Microsoft has been doing fine lately.
Scott: I'm using Windows on my desktop because it's better more bad press about Microsoft and like ever before I know people are looking down on them more than ever before.
Rym: It's unjustified like I agree.
Scott: Microsoft thing is.
Scott: you make a fuck ton of money.
Scott: They do not from big business contracts.
Scott: They do government being one of them.
Scott: and if Google can force Microsoft out of the government contract arena That's gonna hurt Microsoft a lot.
Scott: We're like millions millions and millions of dollars.
Rym: another way to go about hurting now This is this is crazy leftist whack job.
Rym: What if Microsoft because up Microsoft really is a business probably needs to move into?
Rym: tablets and mobile stuff and all this kind of modern thing because core OS is No longer, I think a viable business except for proprietary applications.
Scott: But I made it a commodity the brow, you know exactly and then browsers themselves a commodity.
Rym: I feel like operating systems.
Rym: at least.
Rym: there should be a Government branch of Linux that or at least the government should fund open source development in some way and independently.
Rym: Wouldn't it be cool if just the operating system wing of Microsoft and maybe the document stuff too Was bought by the government maintained by the government and just was free?
Scott: That's dangerous for the rest of the world to be incredibly scared and they would not like that at all.
Rym: It's dangerous primarily because how many patches would come out after ten years of government control?
Scott: think about this way, right?
Scott: Okay, so the government the US government might think that's a great idea.
Scott: But imagine if the the Russian government bought the Microsoft Windows.
Scott: very bad news Yeah, so any government buying something like that is very bad.
Rym: Here's what those governments will do.
Rym: they'll hem and haw and then like China remember the dragon processor.
Rym: They're like, yeah Western x86 wick our own processor.
Scott: All right, they could probably do it.
Rym: We have reverse-engineered the 486. we will compete with your penny in billions.
Scott: You're right If you can make a web browser that plays video.
Scott: Video is really the limiter because if you just want to show images and stuff 46 can do pretty well.
Rym: That's actually a fairly lucrative lucrative business.
Rym: a lot of technology a lot of hardware that the military and the government use Have mandates that say they have to be manufactured on US soil by US companies.
Rym: There's a fairly lucrative lucrative business in old technology fabs to make old shit for the government.
Scott: Yeah, but you cut.
Scott: the amount of money it costs to create such a business is incredibly high.
Rym: but at the same time if you already have an old fab rather than tearing it down you just Contract to the government and overcharge them times a billion because I think only game in town funny people are doing that already.
Scott: Yeah, you can't break into that business.
Rym: Yeah, at best you can work for a company that does that like I once did anyway actually twice did.
Scott: But anyway, the point is this is pretty exciting because hopefully we can get some more government technology improvements.
Scott: However slow.
Rym: I think it's part of a bigger trend where for a long time I'd say for like the past four or five years up until just recently We were kind of at a plateau in a lot of kind of our nerdy computer technological stuff.
Rym: like there weren't a lot of revolutions happening and suddenly there has been this spate of lawsuit related chaos where for a long time like the patent stuff where there's a million companies all poised to sue the hell out of Each other and then recently they all just hit nuke and they all sued each other And now Google's suing and all these lawsuits are gonna end at some point and unlike the SEO lawsuit things are gonna change.
Scott: I think what it is is that for a longest time there they were advancing rapidly So they kept coming out with new things.
Scott: So everyone is getting new patents and new patents and making new stuff and making more money.
Scott: and now You know, it's like what has there really been new recently?
Scott: Well, it gets to the point where have been crooks slightly So's like our CPUs now have more than one core.
Rym: gets to the point where it is cheaper to hire the lawyers to engage in The mutually assured destruction crazy lawsuit than it is to pay an R&D team to come up with something.
Scott: What are the new things that are happening?
Scott: We made a social website.
Scott: We made a slightly different social website.
Scott: You know, it's like nobody's really making it But you talk about they're only making things that are crooks slightly.
Rym: So you push it in the same direction that we go with video games a lot.
Rym: I know a lot of you.
Rym: Monday listeners don't bother with the Tuesday night shows.
Rym: a Big problem in the video game industry Is that everyone thinks I want to make a massively multiplayer role-playing game.
Rym: World of Warcraft is the biggest and best.
Rym: I'm going to try to compete with them and do the exact same thing They do and I'll be 1% better and no one's gonna give a shit.
Rym: No and technology a lot of times is the same thing.
Scott: Everything is the same thing Almost everything.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the one thing is that with a traditional sort of business like say a plumber or a carpenter, right?
Scott: It's like you didn't even have to be better than the other carpenter.
Scott: It doesn't be better than the other carpenter in town.
Scott: But when you're in the whole world when you're an international digital business Location don't mean shit except for your taxes, right?
Scott: You just have to be better.
Rym: Don't get me started on taxes.
Scott: It doesn't matter where you are.
Scott: Like if I open up a dry cleaner, I could be a shitty ass dry cleaner But I can open up in a town with no dry cleaners.
Scott: Boom.
Scott: I'm in business, baby.
Rym: I just pictured a dry cleaner who signed.
Rym: they were called shitty ass dry cleaners.
Scott: I would go to that dry cleaner, even if they charge twice as much just because they're awesome.
Scott: name Like what I would.
Scott: here's how you get the marketing right.
Scott: is you would take like a piece of cardboard that looks like a poop.
Scott: I'd be like your business card and you'd put it in the plastic with the clothing.
Scott: It's like you would pick up your shirts and they'd be wrapped in plastic and then under the plastic It would look like there was a piece of cardboard poop like on that.
Rym: So actually this was many months ago when we first moved to the city.
Rym: me and Emily are out somewhere.
Rym: We saw a local billboard like what are those lowdown billboards out in?
Rym: like the Bronx somewhere?
Rym: And it was ass man proctologist and it looked legit and it said butts are our business.
Scott: That's what that is.
Rym: So I know Facebook isn't something we often talk about.
Rym: I mean I don't even have a Facebook account not because I'm a curmudgeon because I graduated before.
Rym: Facebook was available To people who weren't in college.
Scott: just go get you should just get one and then don't use it.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't want it there festering.
Rym: I don't want to make sites that are related to me that don't have anything about me on.
Scott: Well, what you could do is you could forward your tweets to it.
Rym: Yeah, but that because I do.
Scott: I don't go to face.
Scott: but then what's gonna happen?
Rym: is someone's gonna friend me like I'm a Family member and then they're gonna ask me why they didn't friendly.
Rym: It's gonna be that South Park episode.
Scott: You just ignore them.
Scott: Just don't don't click on it.
Rym: Yeah, and that didn't work so well in South Park.
Rym: It's sound clearly.
Rym: South Park is a perfect analog of the real world.
Rym: But anyway, I Think Slashdot is getting Surprisingly conservative.
Rym: and I think this is happening because you're reading too much.
Scott: Slashdot is dead.
Scott: Stop reading it.
Rym: No, it's not eggs.
Scott: Also.
Scott: That's not read that either dig.
Rym: I wouldn't say dig is dead.
Rym: I would say it's pretty dead.
Rym: dig was never quite came to be.
Rym: dig was like it was this little thing and it exploded so fast that like in a in a Not used by anybody enough to matter to used by everybody and therefore meaningless.
Rym: There was basically no period at which it was useful.
Rym: but my trouble is that it's weird that lately I've been reading slashdot comments and I felt that they've been getting more and more conservative.
Rym: slashdot was pretty against the dude who was scanning the barcodes and the selling books and making a profit from used bookstores and They were really mad about my comments in this Facebook article.
Rym: But basically the Facebook article was just about the new feature the stalker tool that lets you Easily see the conversations that happened that were public between two of your friends.
Rym: So say you and Scott Johnson were using Facebook and like talking to each other.
Rym: I could say show me what Scott and Scott talked about and it would just tell me because I could see all that stuff.
Rym: Anyway, it just takes extent information that is publicly available That both of you consented to make available in Facebook and gives it to me in an aggregated form that I can then read.
Rym: People are losing their goddamn shit over this as is expected.
Rym: uh-huh, and I I feel like the core problem because with this whole privacy debate comes down to the fact that people in America have unreasonable expectations of privacy and They have unreasonable expectations about the transitive nature of privacy.
Rym: in fact, one person tried to argue that transitive privacy is not the way to go and Transitive privacy is the only privacy you have.
Rym: anything I ever say.
Rym: if any human being ever hears it I have to implicitly trust them to use that information in a way that I approve or I'm fucked and you know.
Scott: Well, you can leave.
Scott: you can also legally obligate them to keep a secret Ah, but if you don't know it depends though.
Rym: If I tell you something and then I want to make you do a contract after I told you No,
Scott: you have to do the contract before you tell them Yeah,
Rym: and even then one-sided contracts aren't really enforceable in court and there's a yeah,
Scott: they have to sign the contract.
Rym: I guess I don't know.
Rym: I feel like this is an issue where there can't be any argument.
Rym: In fact, I don't want it one step further in this whole privacy brouhaha That's brewing now on the tech world to the point that even non Texas started like even Jon Stewart's making jokes about Facebook.
Rym: Normal people are starting to like get the fact that Facebook invades their privacy.
Rym: but I would argue that all of the arguments on either side of the privacy issue are completely moot and pointless except for the one that I mean.
Rym: because Alright, even if the people who say we don't have any privacy agreed.
Rym: Yes, we should have privacy It's impossible to have yep.
Rym: So Even if I agree with you a hundred percent, there is no way to redress your grievances at all.
Rym: It is absolutely impossible.
Scott: It is as impossible to give you privacy on the internet as much as it is impossible to stop Piracy piracy and privacy both equally unstoppable.
Scott: In fact, they are the same thing They are the transfer and dissemination of information.
Scott: You cannot stop it.
Scott: if you may share if there is something in your brain At least as of now you can keep it a secret but soon Soon, we'll have mind reading devices and know that is not a joke, right?
Scott: Until then though if you think it it's a secret But if you write it down if you tell it to someone and especially if you type it into the Internet's You have effectively shared it with the world.
Scott: That is how the world works.
Scott: You can't stop it unless you destroy all the computers with some sort of apocalypse.
Scott: So that's the way the world works.
Scott: get used to it.
Rym: Here's my point.
Scott: I wrote a blog post about this in like June of '09 and I haven't had to edit it or clarify it.
Scott: It is a word-for-word is exactly the same opinion.
Scott: I still have part of the problem still the perfect rebuttal to every single privacy article that comes up every week And this is my root point.
Rym: this is the news.
Rym: people are freaking out about a feature that shows you information that you can already see and They don't give a shit about fire sheep.
Rym: Which fire sheep?
Scott: because I can't see.
Scott: only nerds see that fire.
Rym: She does what any tech has been able to do for as long as there's been an internet.
Scott: Yeah, I mean since 1999, right?
Scott: There's there's this piece of software called ethereal which is later renamed to wire shark Right.
Scott: and what this does?
Scott: it puts your network card be it wireless or wired into what is known as promiscuous mode.
Scott: And if you know anything about how Ethernet or wireless works, basically when you send packets from your you know Network card and your computer those packets go to every computer on the entire local network.
Scott: The thing is is they're using these Mac addresses So basically the network card.
Scott: if me and remember the same well, you're you're right.
Rym: But I want to jump in because modern networks are actually a bit different from.
Scott: are they any?
Scott: with the point if it's switch It's a little different.
Rym: everything switch.
Scott: basically to keep it short if me and Ram are both browsing the web in the same Starbucks I'm actually seeing everything he's doing and he's seeing everything I'm doing the differences.
Scott: Our network cards are filtering out.
Scott: So we're only getting the packets meant for us like a little.
Scott: yeah You know internet sieve.
Rym: now if you're not using SSL, you don't have the little HTTPS and the little shield.
Scott: HTTPS is a way to encrypt your internet your web connection, you know WWE, right?
Scott: Between your computer and the web server.
Scott: So if you visit say Amazon and you don't have HTTPS then people see everything you're doing.
Scott: But if you have the s there then everything between your computer and the Amazon computer is encrypted and nobody can bust that.
Scott: or it's Incredibly hard to bust that.
Scott: and if you they try to bust it There'll be all these alarms going off in your browser like red lights and pop-ups which people will ignore.
Scott: Anyway, I'll ignore but because they're stupid, right?
Rym: but I guess the part of the thing is that one.
Rym: this actually wasn't a concern for a while before.
Rym: there were ubiquitous hot spots and a lot of people who weren't text had laptops and we're connecting them to wireless networks that other people We're also connected to that weren't for work.
Rym: This hadn't been an issue because we had transitioned from flat land structures to switch infrastructure where no one can see anyone else's packets.
Rym: Yeah short of like an RIT short of attacks like I could attack old Cisco routers and get it to show me everyone's packets by flooding them and Override.
Rym: basically that is actually an attack though Yeah They'd get so flooded that they would start broadcasting everything and then I just sniff like an RIT.
Scott: if I turned on Wireshark or ethereal you wouldn't see shit.
Scott: I would see Rym stuff because you had a hub.
Scott: Yeah, because we couldn't afford a switch back then I wouldn't see anyone else's shit in the whole apartment building.
Scott: right.
Scott: but nowadays, you know If you turn on Iran, you won't see anyone who's doing anything outside of your house.
Scott: And you know if you have a router routers or switches, they're not hubs So you're not even gonna see the other people in your house.
Scott: Well, unless using wireless routers are bridges.
Rym: They're they're.
Rym: they're routers.
Scott: Household routers are usually like four ports.
Rym: Oh, yeah, they'll switch but they're also around.
Scott: there's switch They're.
Scott: you're not gonna see anything unless you're everyone's using.
Scott: Even if you're using wireless if one person's on the two point whatever gigahertz and one person's on the other gigahertz You still won't see anything.
Rym: that's decide.
Rym: but so people are freaking out about fire sheep at least tech people.
Rym: But the tech people should realize that back when I had a cable modem I could see all the traffic of everyone in my neighborhood.
Scott: Yeah, I mean basically all this fire sheep is is it's taking a piece of software a capability of you know Networks that has existed since the 90s and are even older than that and they just put a good user interface on it.
Scott: It's it's basically an old incredibly easy and trivial hack that was as always existed and has always been obvious But they have made it, you know Noticed by the common person who doesn't understand network.
Rym: I think where we're going to see it easy is a new era of script kiddieism.
Rym: But it's almost worse and I'm glad it's happening because we've gone through eras.
Rym: There was an era where the internet was the wild goddamn West where I would put viruses on floppy disks gives them to my friends Then hack into their computers from home and steal all their stuff.
Scott: Yeah And that was you can like format their hard drives and all sorts of nasty shit.
Rym: what I would always do shit that I wish People would do these day What I'd always do is we'd be playing command and conquer and I'd open their CD tray to distract them and then I'd attack them.
Rym: Yeah with back orifice.
Rym: Yeah, and I forget with the one with the.
Rym: I forget what it was called now But it was the one where it had like that torch icon.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: anyway there I it was really easy to hack and it was just a wild west and whoever was smarter would just win on the internet.
Rym: and Then we moved on to where professionals started writing viruses which meant it's all spam and it's all being used to make money.
Scott: I wish that they would make viruses that erase people's hard drives because then people would actually give a shit instead of Breaking just being like oh I have a hundred viruses and I don't even know or care because they're sending spam and they're invisible.
Rym: So we went from a world where people were making merry mischief with the internet to a world where evil professionals are doing evil for profit.
Rym: and Now we're moving to a world where it's not even script kiddies.
Rym: It's browser kiddies.
Scott: It's a fire Fox plug-in That's freely available and has an easy user interface on it with icons and pictures.
Rym: People were demanding that Mozilla somehow block it and Mozilla was like are you kidding?
Rym: Someone?
Rym: on slash I made the best point.
Rym: They said never underestimate the power of scotch tape and a grudge.
Rym: if someone wants something hard enough There is nothing you can do to stop them.
Rym: Yeah, you can't accept fucking encryption.
Scott: You're not no one's gonna be able to Do anything to you fucking encryption?
Rym: How does it work?
Rym: No one?
Rym: No, I mean are we alright?
Rym: So say we want to put up SSL.
Rym: half our listeners aren't gonna understand that and they'll see the warning about the self-signed certificate.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I'll just disable HTTP.
Scott: It'll be HTTPS only.
Rym: Yeah, but do you want to pay?
Rym: Someone for a so-called legit certificate.
Scott: I can get a legit certificate from Gandhi.
Scott: Yeah, pretty cheap actually.
Rym: Yeah, we could get one but it cost money.
Scott: Yeah, it does cost money does cost money as you know, but it depends also what kind of you know.
Scott: That's because SSL is a scam.
Scott: There's a racket, but I don't want to get into that.
Rym: Yeah, I'll put it this way all the fears of it's weird.
Rym: People are most afraid of People who are taking extent information and showing it to you information you are.
Rym: it's like if someone went into your house found your bank account and then told you all With all the information that was in your bank account and didn't even keep it for themselves.
Rym: They're just like hey, here's all this information that you already have.
Scott: yeah,
Rym: but they're not afraid of the fact that I can just go into a Starbucks and steal a hundred myspace accounts and Facebook accounts and RIT Accounts and email accounts and FRC forum accounts and there's nothing you can do about it except never logging into anything That isn't encrypted on any public wireless ever.
Scott: Oh, there is one thing you can do VPNs.
Scott: No, people are actually saying there was a suggestion that people do SSH tunnel, right?
Scott: So I could set up an SSH tunnel for example from Mike and my laptop to say my line Yeah, that's just a poor man's VPN.
Scott: Well, no the problem with that right?
Scott: is the?
Scott: the reason that you a VPN or an SSH tunnel is not gonna cut it Theoretically at least right is let's say I make the SSH tunnel to my line node where they were.
Scott: the website is hosted.
Scott: That would totally work, right?
Scott: No one in the Starbucks would be able to see shit But someone who's on the other side of the line node could see everything anyway.
Scott: But SSL is the only thing.
Rym: I got you from both ends But there are few people remember and that's I'm visiting my own website Which I have both ends after you get past the local network the no one but a professional is going to get your unencrypted data.
Scott: There still could be evil professionals.
Rym: Yeah, but they're a minority.
Rym: I mean, here's the problem.
Rym: The problem is people stealing like my Facebook account and causing trouble for me.
Rym: No one like most ad is not gonna go after me out there me massage.
Rym: Yeah, what's gonna go after me is the dude in the Starbucks who wants to post cockboats on my wall.
Scott: That's true, but there could be and I suspect at least one at one or two places in the world.
Scott: This is happening If not more.
Scott: I'd be very surprised where.
Scott: there's some guy at an ISP somewhere Who's got like a computer set up like one you in Iraq somewhere and he was just like Foraging tons and tons of accounts into like big bundles and then selling them for like the height to the highest bidder in China.
Rym: Pretty trivial to do absolutely trivial to do.
Scott: you go completely undetected.
Scott: No one would know that there was like an extra computer in Iraq with an extra wire.
Scott: They wouldn't know that it'd be completely hidden.
Scott: You could put it in a closet somewhere.
Scott: totally get away with it.
Scott: So you're basically trusting everyone at every ISP everywhere not to be that guy Unless you actually get your encryption going all the way to the other end instead of just part of the way.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me Scott?
Scott: Oh, man, if you have never seen Right, like the awesomest model trains in the world You don't need to see them because here is something that is similar but superior in the eyes of Scott this guy.
Scott: now What some Lionel?
Rym: no Lionel?
Scott: No, this guy in his you know equivalent of model train room has made not a set of model trains but instead of slot cars, however, this set of slot cars is basically a Perfect Formula One track.
Scott: a lot of people with pit crew and such and such and grandstands and everything.
Scott: A lot of people are really down on slot cars because even though even the lighting It's like it looks like a racetrack that is lit up at night for a night race.
Rym: It's pretty hot but a lot of people don't Respect slot cars enough because they look at it and they think I don't have to steer.
Rym: that's stupid.
Rym: I'll just hold it down the whole time.
Rym: They don't realize.
Scott: fly off the track.
Rym: Yeah, it's all about speed control much like real racing.
Rym: Yeah, it's actually a better analog for non race car drivers of race car driving than an actual driving simulator.
Scott: Yeah, I mean basically, you know, if you just hold down the trigger all the way you'd be like Oh whoever has the better slot car will win except on little kid tracks where you can hold it down the whole time exactly.
Scott: but basically when you get to the you know When you get to a turn you have to let go.
Scott: but if you let go all the way the car will just stop And you'll get past.
Scott: but and you also if you know and also there'll be other situations Like you'd be coming to a part where the tracks cross.
Scott: So it's like well, what do you do?
Scott: Do you slow down and let the other guy cross over first?
Scott: Do you try to beat him if you crash?
Scott: you crashed.
Scott: if you're actually taking it seriously, right?
Rym: So there was that big slot car track system in beacon that we are like on the border from beacon and fish kill.
Rym: We never went to.
Scott: yeah was attached to that shady bowling alley.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like we should have gone there at least once.
Rym: Yeah, we talked about.
Scott: it was like a birthday party kind of place.
Scott: It was not like this which is like a man's You know, so this guy is obviously this is number one hobby and you look at this and he is definitely achieved greatness in his Hobby and for that he is a geek nice type of person.
Rym: So, you know, I'm all about the urban exploration.
Rym: I used to do it a lot more and we lived upstate because there was a lot of industrial ruins and I could get away With it around here.
Rym: I feel like if I break into a band in factory, I'm gonna get shot.
Scott: You don't go into a band in factory, but you want to do in New York City's.
Scott: you want to go into underground things?
Rym: Like yeah the things that'll get me shot as a terrorist.
Scott: No, you got like hobo who lives under the street.
Scott: you go to in there's a hobo down there and it's like hey hobo What's going on?
Rym: Nice sewage, but one thing I've always been fascinated with are empty tunnels, especially abandoned tunnels Like I was really, you know when we did that trip you didn't come but we went through the Rochester subway.
Rym: We walked the entire length of the Rochester subway system.
Scott: I mean, it's not a tunnel that gets me that I have any interest in but what I do have interest in is anything Where there used to be stuff.
Rym: well civilized stuff and now one you would have liked not the Rochester subway Because in the Rochester subway among other things all the stations were still there.
Scott: Oh, the thing is that thing is as much as I like it.
Scott: It also makes me sad Yeah, and if I had like powers the saddest are.
Scott: basically what I would do with my powers is make things that are out of Use in use like the saddest part.
Rym: There's like I go to Queens and I'm like world's fair exist again.
Rym: But there's this one spot that was really sad where it looked like the Mines of Moria.
Rym: There was these intricate art deco columns that were gigantic Spanning as far as the eye could see in every direction and it was just an empty abandoned place.
Rym: They're gonna fill in eventually because they want hobos to live there.
Scott: Oh, I just let the hobos live there.
Rym: Why don't they turn into a tourist attraction?
Rym: What stuff down there?
Scott: They just turn at least turn it into a paintball airsoft arena.
Scott: Oh, man, that's what you should do with all large abandoned places is play airsoft until the black paintball laser tag.
Rym: So a year later the police come see a firefight taking place and that's the end of you.
Scott: You set it up as a business with a storefront and everything.
Scott: So it's completely legitimate.
Rym: what I did not know I mean the table don't even know that there was a subway in Rochester, New York.
Rym: of all places But even fewer people know that there's a series of intricate tunnels connecting large portions of Salem, Oregon.
Scott: I've never even heard of Salem, Oregon.
Scott: I've heard of Salem New York and Salem Massachusetts and you've heard of Oregon I assume.
Rym: Yeah, not Oregon.
Rym: I also heard of Missouri But in Oregon, there's actually a hue in Salem at least.
Rym: there's this huge network of tunnels connecting Buildings all over the downtown.
Scott: and why was it made?
Rym: It was made for various reasons that evolved over time and different parts of it arose in different eras Like if you like there's some people who are exploring it.
Rym: Pretty big really.
Rym: It was a boomtown a long time ago a lot of Chinese immigrants and during prohibition.
Rym: but to quote this article there's an antique bank vault with an intact gold drop from the bank upstairs a 1920 stairwell that goes way up to nowhere.
Scott: a gold drop.
Scott: you put gold in it and it falls into the vault.
Scott: Oh, no, no, but I mean gold is fucking heavy.
Scott: If you drop gold, it's gonna get first of all soft gonna get a big old dent in it.
Rym: Well, there was probably a dumbwaiter or something.
Scott: I mean, I'm not but then it's not a gold drop.
Scott: then it's a gold lift.
Rym: It's a gold drop like a mail drop a mail drop.
Scott: Just drops the mail via gravity.
Rym: Not always.
Rym: Sometimes it's just a hole.
Rym: you put the mail in someone's a male elevator goes.
Rym: Sometimes you just put it on anyway, there's a gold drop.
Rym: There's a 20s stairway that goes nowhere an entire 30s grocery store.
Rym: Where did the stairway originally go?
Rym: No one knows.
Rym: some building.
Rym: Okay, kind of like how.
Rym: when they took down the book off in Midtown and when they took away all the like shelves There was this fancy old metal door connecting to the building next door.
Rym: That's just walled off on the other side on 80s disco and just stuff like that.
Rym: There's like this whole underground city a Mall.
Scott: it's an abandoned mall But it happens to be underground making it different from all the other abandoned malls now because it goes all the way back to the 1800.
Rym: Some of these tunnels.
Rym: there's speakeasies down there and bars.
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Scott: Every nerd must move to Salem, Oregon and we'll take it over.
Scott: We're gonna take it over and it'll be nerd town and we will turn all this awesomeness into nerd city.
Rym: So we have our guest Peter Olson resident GeekNights scientist.
Rym: Hi Pete.
Guest: So, my name is Peter Olson.
Guest: I'm a senior food bacteriologist employed by the New York State Department of Agriculture and Markets.
Guest: my job is to test food products from all across the state of New York or The presence of certain food-borne pathogens, I also do Characterization subtyping and lots of other complicated science things.
Guest: So, you know any opinions expressed in this podcast or any writings attached to this podcast That I Express are solely mine and are not necessarily reflective of the stance of the Department of Agriculture and Markets.
Guest: further any mention of any specific product website a Private enterprise of any sort does not constitute endorsement of that thing by the Department of Agriculture and Markets.
Rym: Thank you, and we're hoping you could bring us the thing of the day something We used to ask our guests to do and then we forgot.
Guest: I just might have a thing of the day for you.
Scott: So I I do So.
Guest: anyone who knows me knows that I am not necessarily a huge fan of raw milk But I am.
Guest: I'm also not really a fan of the Colbert rapport either though I'm not equating those two things.
Guest: the Colbert rapport is definitely better for you than raw milk Or less likely to give you serious gastroenteritis.
Scott: So as someone who has experienced severe gastroenteritis and been hospitalized Yeah, as much as people out there probably won't like me saying this I also kind of agree like, you know Colbert obviously has his shtick Yeah, but it's like.
Scott: I personally find it to be only tolerable for like a short amount of yes Colbert just made a movie.
Rym: That was the Colbert rapport.
Rym: would have been like bar at that would have been great.
Scott: But I mean, it's like you have one joke and you do the joke every day.
Rym: It's like well notice how at the rally I went to they Basically had him up there in character and then they killed his characters.
Rym: They could have the serious talk.
Guest: Yeah, he definitely does much better as did much better as Stewart straight, man.
Guest: so anyway Every now and then the Colbert report does a piece or a segment that I do happen to like and and one such segment aired about a month ago now a little less than a month ago earlier in October and The the story that he discussed concerned arrayed by the FDA on an establishment called raw some foods.
Guest: It's expected really well,
Rym: I mean I if they're selling say beef, I mean I eat raw beef
Scott: Technically and he was ironically saying that the government was correct to raid them.
Scott: And since his character is supposed to be the negative he was implying that the government should not have raided them.
Guest: Yes Really not the case.
Guest: Well, it's it's an interesting story.
Guest: The the allegations were that raw some foods was illegally selling raw milk I can tell it by their name and and they did indeed starters pot palace We're talking about you Taking it back aways.
Guest: But yeah no, they found unlicensed raw milk in this establishment and shut them down.
Guest: and there was a video of The feds coming in with guns drawn and oh, yeah, very dramatic.
Scott: But you know, we need that because the hippies will friggin fight back.
Rym: They take this with what like it like in lock stock Exactly.
Guest: Oh There's a clip out there and this segment is interesting for a number of reasons that it features David Atchison of the FDA who is a fantastic speaker very intelligent man.
Guest: He gives a lot of very great information.
Scott: The like the head head head.
Guest: No, no, no, he's not.
Guest: he's not the super head of the FDA But but he's a great communicator.
Guest: He was brought on board relatively recently and he's been great for the agency Like the surgeon general or someone technically the head head of the.
Guest: it's complicated.
Guest: it's really really calm.
Scott: Okay, don't explain it.
Guest: I won't I didn't intend to no intent there.
Guest: So the situation itself is also interesting because raw some foods was selling raw milk illegally.
Guest: but it's legal to sell raw milk in a grocery store in the state of California if you go through the proper licensing procedures, so They didn't even bother to go through the licensing procedure.
Guest: No, it was just laziness.
Guest: But the reason I'm linking to.
Guest: so as a scientist I encounter a lot of bullshit explanations for things in my day-to-day life And of course, they they contribute heavily to my predilection for drinking gin.
Guest: so this one particular Gentlemen that they interviewed from raw some foods Explains why he drinks raw milk.
Scott: and you must understand I've heard I've heard a lot of explanations as to why people legitimate reason I can I can take from someone is they like that it tastes better and it's like?
Scott: is it worth it to Risk death and illness for that better taste?
Scott: and if they say yes, well, that's you know, it's only them drinking it.
Guest: There is another guy.
Guest: there is a guy who who actually says and I'll spoil this little bit of the interview.
Guest: He actually says something I agree with which is that if I if I want to drink raw milk And I know it's going to give me dysentery Then it's my right anyway to proceed as long as I as long as I can agree I can.
Rym: I read an article recently talking about how there's been a rise of tuberculosis in a couple of places.
Rym: There's a rise in the Mexican border because of people taking raw poorly processed milk and cheese.
Guest: It is hypothesized that Tabra mycobacterium tuberculosis human infecting tuberculosis actually evolved from the naturally occurring Mycobacteria that are present in raw milk and they evolved and adapted to human hosts.
Guest: and that's how we got the tuberculosis that we know now it actually came from had been invented and Disseminated earlier.
Scott: there would be no tuberculosis.
Guest: It is it is it is possible.
Guest: We obviously it is hard to go back 300 years and research what happened then.
Guest: exactly disprove the holographic universe You and your holographic universe.
Guest: But anyway, so there's one guy Holographic universe a interview.
Guest: Listen, my mom is a lot of things but I can assure you she is not holographic or pasteurized or Pasteurized that that would be kind of gross.
Guest: But listen, there's one guy Explains why he drinks raw milk and all I can tell you is that it is It's the most outrageous Explanation I've heard in my time as a scientist and I will tell you something.
Guest: I've heard some pretty outrageous stuff.
Guest: I'm gonna link this video and I hope you guys enjoy it.
Rym: and yeah All right, so very briefly the meta moment the GeekNights book club is World War Z by Max Brooks.
Rym: I'm reading it Scott is not.
Scott: I'm gonna read it pretty soon.
Rym: You're not reading it now.
Scott: Not this very second.
Scott: I'm gonna get to it.
Scott: I'm doing a podcast right now.
Scott: Yes, very soon.
Rym: All right Yep, we're gonna be at MAGFest doing.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX East.
Rym: We're gonna be a pack.
Rym: We're gonna be a PAX East.
Rym: We're gonna be a pax prime And we're probably gonna be at anime Boston and I think that's all the matter that matters.
Rym: the e-commerce for GeekNights And our old t-shirt are gonna be up relatively soon.
Rym: snap.
Rym: The last regulatory hurdle is complete.
Rym: We are now legally authorized to sell t-shirts.
Rym: It's just a matter of me turning on the website Right and figuring out what I have to file after we sell to the first person in New York, but that's beside the point.
Rym: So yeah tonight we thought you know before we had Pete on the show This was quite some time ago and we talked about pseudo science.
Rym: You know the Randy bullshit that we're so angry about all the time and pizza scientists, so we thought he'd be extra angry about.
Rym: So now we thought we'd talk about science But we realized science is not.
Rym: there's not a lot to say other than it's science.
Rym: It's right G.
Scott: What a. what a incredibly specific topic that we can you know discuss for 30 minutes science.
Rym: But one thing that we definitely can talk about because it's something very important that I think we all agree needs to be addressed is The state of science education in the world at least in the United States, right?
Scott: I mean I'm pretty sure there are other countries where science education is quite good and other countries where it is perhaps even worse.
Scott: But the United States is the country which we know the most about right?
Guest: So so the state of science education in the US, huh?
Rym: I think how do we like?
Rym: I guess the fundamental question is how do you teach science is like what?
Rym: constitutes a good science education that that's?
Guest: that's a tricky part and a lot of a Lot of how we've taught people science has been.
Guest: it's been a result of how science was 40 or 50 years ago back when Back when the people who were teaching did science and new things and science.
Guest: 40 or 50 year old science isn't isn't really that useful.
Guest: these days science can be invalidated in the span of a year or two or You know, so it's like.
Scott: so you're saying like.
Scott: is it because the science is moving too fast to update the textbooks?
Scott: Or is it because well, it's somehow science is fundamentally different now than it was then?
Guest: it is moving faster than we are Updating it.
Guest: I would I would contend.
Guest: as for science itself Hasn't changed.
Guest: I mean it's everybody throws out the word science the science that I think.
Guest: xkcd addressed this very well in a Fantastic comic with Feynman rising from the dead and smacking people down because they were bitching about myth busters.
Guest: The core of science will never change which is that ideas are tested by an empirical Experimentation.
Guest: that's it.
Guest: It's rooted in the the most fundamental of skeptical philosophy.
Guest: and until Something like their changes then then the root of science is never going to change its investigation.
Guest: Do you think you can I do and we invest easy to teach people?
Rym: Alright, if you don't know how something works try to figure it out.
Rym: come up with an idea and test it and see if you're right.
Guest: Well, the problem was for the longest time our education system was built around teaching people information that we knew because there was a period of time
Rym: like when they taught me there were five kingdoms and they taught me that You flew because the air is moving faster on top because the shape of the airfoil.
Guest: There was a time way back when you could reasonably know Pretty much all there was to know in science.
Guest: you you could be a scientist You could work in the field of science because there was just one.
Guest: you could be mad.
Guest: Yeah, you could be a little crazy.
Guest: and now we live in an era of unprecedented access to information an Unprecedented ability to gather and disseminate information except scientific studies, which are incredibly difficult.
Guest: Well, that's that's part of the issue.
Guest: Talk about that for a while and I might.
Guest: but One of the problems I've seen at least and in in my my day-to-day duties Or The agency for which I work.
Guest: I do have an opportunity to work with students at different grade levels usually college and post-post undergraduate graduate students working in various programs.
Guest: Well, it wasn't that long ago that that was peers and now it's children Yes kids and I can tell you that I get you know The the area in which I'm located in.
Scott: these are people district in New York scientists.
Guest: These are people who are trying to be scientists who come from reasonable backgrounds.
Scott: They didn't just go to public school and take science class.
Scott: They actually went to school for sign They.
Guest: they took microbiology courses and they took physics courses and they took math.
Guest: and they are in Programs and are allegedly because I only have an undergraduate degree the.
Guest: these people pursuing upper upper level degrees should Hypothetically be more knowledgeable in the field than I am and that is unfortunately often not the case.
Guest: I I get to experience a wide range of Knowledge bases from these different students and I say what the heck is going on?
Scott: Some of these kids they went to different schools.
Guest: I haven't established I have not done sufficient experimentation to draw to Draw a correlation but I can tell you that my my course completely unscientific observation is that it doesn't matter It it really.
Guest: It really just seems to vary with the individual level and I'm not quite sure yet what it is that varies from individual to individual.
Guest: that makes one a better candidate for being a scientist than the other but I could tell you that a lot of these kids that I have Taken under my wing started off knowing jackal about science after going through high school in an undergraduate program.
Guest: some of the most basic tenants seem to escape them and I can also tell you that it's not limited to just Undergraduates, it's limb.
Guest: It's it goes to PhDs.
Guest: It goes to people have been in the field for 30 or 40 years.
Guest: Sometimes it seems that people just lose their grip on the the fundamental aspects of science.
Rym: Well, I remember a very poignant moment in my you know, educational curves.
Rym: in 10th grade I was taking like physics in high school and it was like the third week and we're doing experiments and we went outside because it was nice out and We learned all these methods to calculate how far away the Sun was from the earth.
Rym: And we were supposed to figure out how far away the Sun was from the earth using the materials we had available.
Rym: So we did it and you know I was off by like four orders of magnitude because that's what my calculations told me.
Rym: Yeah, and everyone was way way off.
Rym: and Afterward he asked us, you know, all right, we were way off and a lot of people were balking like yeah We were way off like why are even bothering with these experiments?
Rym: and he asked us very simply Alright, so how do we know what the right answer is?
Rym: And Someone said well, it's in the textbook But they were smart.
Rym: They were smart.
Rym: They stopped as soon as they said that and they said oh wait How'd they get the answer in the textbook?
Rym: and the teacher was like by doing exactly what you did only not being?
Guest: And it's it's.
Guest: it's a little.
Guest: it's a little disconcerting that I'm fairly certain those conversations don't happen as often as they need To in science classrooms, obviously, I haven't studied science classrooms extensively.
Guest: it's been a long time since I've been in a high school classroom or even a an undergraduate college classroom.
Guest: But I can tell you that that my experiences and from what I have gathered of other people's experiences from talking to them There's really not so much emphasis on the critical thinking aspects of science.
Guest: Which is really the most critical component of any scientific investigation is how to take these observations and these data that you've gathered and Analyze them and how to break them down into their fundamental components and understand how they interact with each other.
Guest: what do they tell you?
Guest: what what conclusions can you draw?
Guest: and how are your conclusions limited which I find is one of the things that gets lost in the public perceptions of Sciences.
Guest: When whenever a study comes up we see this all the time somebody says science cures Pretty much about everything.
Scott: just read XKCD.
Guest: Randall Monroe was right about a lot of things.
Rym: Yeah That was the other discussion about significant digits.
Scott: anything is beat though It's like you're.
Scott: you're upset because you've got these people who went to school and learned some science But then no it turns out they didn't actually learn the science, right?
Scott: Right, but here's the thing.
Scott: Yeah, look at us computer people.
Scott: They don't even have high school classes and computers and when they do they're not mandatory and when they do It's not taught by anyone who knows any.
Rym: I mean at least I mean you look at the average like freshman computer science or IT Person even at a prestigious tech school.
Rym: They come in and unless they're a nerd who already knows how to code it'd be the equivalent of someone coming to you.
Rym: They've got their bachelors and they're like, I'm ready to do some science and they don't actually know anything more than that.
Guest: They know are a bunch of facts.
Rym: They're like I learned how.
Rym: to you know how to turn my graphing calculator on?
Rym: teach me how to do science with it.
Guest: Yeah, no, I've encountered roughly that that same level of calm.
Scott: That is that's pretty scary.
Guest: I mean consider, you know, not not often not often Usually usually most students I get have memorized factual information and can reproduce it at me.
Guest: when I ask them then I ask them What does that mean?
Guest: How did we arrive at that data?
Guest: How can you apply these data in other situations?
Guest: They go.
Rym: I feel like I had an extraordinary at least science education compared to other high schools because These things were dealt with very well like for example, like with these examples I mean, why did I professor would always like we do a professor the teacher We'd always like do an experiment or something or learn an equation like he said simple ones.
Rym: He said F equals ma force equals mass times acceleration and he put it on the board and he paused Looked at us and he asks, what does that imply?
Rym: and We went for a week on just the implications and the ramifications of that.
Rym: Mm-hmm And I is it just that no one does that.
Rym: I mean, it wasn't hard to have the science education I had.
Scott: I'm not a science genius by any stretch, but it's like I think.
Scott: I think that I know things.
Guest: Yeah, a lot of people think they know things.
Guest: I think we could point to a lot of people who think they know things and this is part of the problem with science education.
Guest: science is all about figuring out how little you actually know and rectifying that problem.
Guest: and We we get into this.
Guest: we tend to get into a situation where people will draw conclusions and say well this conclusion is definite because they sort of misinterpret the some of the fundamental aspects of science about.
Guest: you know How we.
Guest: we have a theory or perhaps some set of conclusions that are valid until something more valid comes along And then people will often Engage in confirmation bias and other such things to Shoot down every single competing Anything that comes along to try to keep clinging to this this principle that they found so many years ago.
Guest: And and this is this is something that I've observed not just in Scientists in general and in science fields at large but but out in the public at large.
Rym: So would you would you agree with this?
Rym: I have this feeling just based on the scientists and the teachers the professors I've met over the years that the ones who were the best were the ones who's like they got more joy from Disproving something then from verifying something like the people who are really driven were the ones who love nothing more than to take some established theory and Absolutely disprove it or even their own theory and disprove it and be like, alright check this out I disprove my theory that I spent 40 years working on.
Rym: how awesome is that?
Guest: It's you?
Guest: well There aren't very many of those people.
Guest: we.
Guest: there's a story in the god delusion.
Guest: I think it was Richard Dawkins Reflected a story about a scientist who had Talked about I forget the exact the exact theorem you.
Rym: I think I remember this anecdote.
Guest: But anyway, you know, he'd been a scientist for 40 years.
Guest: and then he walked up and he congratulated the guy who just proved him Wrong, he said I've espoused this thing 40 years and you just proved me wrong and everybody clapped their hands raw And I got to tell you that doesn't happen Didn't happen that one time.
Scott: Yeah made up story.
Guest: It happened that one time probably.
Guest: I don't know I wasn't there I'm not Richard Dawkins, but it's nice to think that that is what happens.
Guest: but scientists are people people are fallible and The majority case is that a PhD will cling tenaciously to their the research They've been doing for the past 40 years because it's what they've been doing for the past 40 years.
Guest: They depend on that research.
Guest: So It's nice to say that that the principles of science are that we will abandon something as soon as it is disproven.
Guest: But it is not often that somebody will just abandon a Particular theory wholesale, so we're screwed.
Rym: I mean, that's what about the non scientists?
Guest: Yeah No, you guys you guys are pretty much hosed.
Scott: Tell you what to do, but this is sort of a separate problem right?
Scott: the the the problems between Scientists in academia and fighting over getting published and getting you know, all sorts of stuff like that, right?
Scott: It's like that is sort of a separate problem that perhaps is intertwined with the problem of the students not learning anything.
Guest: Oh, yeah, so how does that can?
Scott: how does the one affect the other?
Guest: Well when you have scientists who have to compete very viciously for funding that's coming from many different sources a lot of them will Try as hard as they possibly can to get students to produce as much work as possible.
Guest: You'll often find this in Colleges where a professor has a laboratory and they use their graduate students or undergraduate students as slave labor slave labor To produce as much work as possible to get as much noise out there as they can to make as big a name as possible.
Rym: I wish I could do that.
Rym: I want to get some interns to like migrate machines.
Guest: Again, I get interns every now and then.
Guest: it is pretty awesome to have interns I'm not gonna lie.
Guest: I even get full-fledged employees that I can boss around to.
Guest: it's a lot of fun, but There there are some.
Guest: there are some side effects to this and it is the person who is Willing to make the most noise makes the most noise and they get the most funding whether or not their science is the best or or Perhaps the most used for what should be being done.
Guest: now.
Guest: I don't need to disparage any scientist who is doing a lot of hard work because I know many many very hard-working scientists who publish a lot of really good earth-shattering groundbreaking data.
Rym: Wait, those are the mad scientists shattering the ground breaking the earth.
Guest: Yeah, all scientists at some point, especially when you when you publish very extensively go a little mad.
Guest: so So we have this this Massive problem.
Guest: really it's.
Guest: it's just pervasive.
Guest: everybody kind of misuses the scientific method One of the scientific methods.
Guest: there really is no global method but a lot of people just kind of spin science To suit their own ends and it's it's unfortunate science.
Guest: The the scientific process is easily spun because it's neutral by default It it doesn't care about what you want.
Scott: It just gives you information and then you have How did it get this way?
Scott: Was it ever good before or was it never good?
Guest: No, it was probably never good.
Guest: Well, well, it was never it was never.
Scott: I mean you say it was never good.
Scott: But meanwhile, we still have.
Rym: I would argue that the scientific process is fine.
Rym: The people interpreting the results are.
Guest: it's how it's it's.
Guest: it's.
Guest: the problem we have now is that Science as I said before used to be a thing that you could just know.
Guest: you could grasp all of it.
Guest: There used to be less information.
Guest: We just had less.
Guest: we knew less.
Guest: when we knew less things It was easier to figure out those few things that we knew really easy.
Guest: It's sort of like when there were only four books.
Guest: They were all really good books because they were the only four books we had.
Scott: So it's like we had the specialization and the specialization has you know caused it's the you know And they've all sort of.
Guest: it's not really the specialization the techniques of science Like how we've applied them for the longest time has always been Exploratory in nature finding more information.
Guest: I can give you an example the kind of work that I do.
Guest: Where we test food samples from across the state of New York or various pathogens I Generate a shocking amount of data in a week.
Guest: You could you could take multiple PhDs and give them Graduate projects build entire careers analyzing data that I've generated in a week All right, and it's it's pretty shocking the amount of data that we can actually produce.
Guest: and the problem we have now Is that except for scientists?
Guest: Most people are not very good at processing that amount of information.
Guest: There's literally just too much stuff out there.
Rym: I've been making for a long time and a lot of other computers.
Rym: That's all that.
Rym: knowledge of statistics is probably one of the most important things we could teach now Because a lot of people don't understand the ramifications or the meaningfulness of data.
Guest: Oh, yeah, that is that is pretty much the critical problem with the awesome TED talk I saw.
Scott: basically this guy made a good few minute argument.
Scott: He's basically like look we do all this math in school.
Scott: math in school and we build up to.
Scott: Calculus is like the big thing you're building up to right but calculus almost nobody You know very few people actually need or use calculus on a day-to-day basis.
Scott: You know as fun as it is probability and statistics Everyone needs to use every day even probably before they're gonna learn it in school.
Scott: You need to use it from the time you're like - right yet You don't learn that unless you learn it like in college extra.
Scott: So he said that we should have probably statistics be like the thing now People.
Rym: I think this is where gaming can be used very well because the quickest way to learn statistics is to lose money.
Rym: playing craps All the kids would show up yeah or just D&D I mean every lunch period all through middle school we would play poker for money.
Scott: Well, didn't you see that?
Scott: the guy who was talking about how his kids got really good at doing math by playing Pokemon the card game because they basically How much damage does he do?
Scott: uh, and he was doing math really fast so he could play pokemons better.
Rym: Yep, that's how I learned computing.
Guest: I wanted to play DOS games And this is part of the problem we have with with getting information to people.
Guest: is you have to present it to them in such A way that it makes sense to them that they can that they can reason with it and a lot of a lot of these problems are.
Guest: so you publish a scientific journal article and I'm gonna set aside the fact that 99.99% of you can never access the full text of an article to actually look at the the testing that they do and The greater problem which is that 99.99% of you wouldn't even understand what the hell that means Even if you could read the whole article.
Rym: I asked Lisa.
Rym: I was there's some article.
Rym: I forgot what it was.
Rym: now was like.
Rym: Yeah, I read the abstract.
Rym: It was really awesome.
Rym: And she's like.
Rym: I can get you the real article.
Rym: I'm like, yes now I will understand it.
Guest: No, you won't.
Rym: Oh, it's a lot of words.
Rym: I actually don't recognize and looking them up did not help.
Rym: Nope.
Scott: Yep That's that's often how you look it up.
Scott: The definition consists of more words.
Rym: You don't recognize Yeah, but but the major problem is no it's worse when they consist entirely of words that I recognize and yet combined mean nothing to me.
Scott: I wish that they would just translate them into plain English.
Guest: There's there's no way to we.
Guest: Well, the part of it is there.
Guest: there is of course a problem with the way that journal articles are published.
Guest: You you pay by the word to publish an article.
Guest: that is which is which is why Scientific writing is often incomprehensible.
Guest: We basically condense it to the point where it's barely Recognizable English to get it out there as to get as much information into a small space as possible.
Rym: At the same time Scott you want to change like translate it into like simple English like component.
Rym: No, that's like making but they can assembly like if they didn't people to read they would just write it, you know Normally just what do you mean normally?
Scott: just like, you know, the way that you would say it if you were explaining Roxy zone does the whatchamacallit explaining it to the scientists next to you and you had all the time in the world and you just had to explain the whole Thing you would use Right.
Guest: Well, no, no, we would use scientific lingo because that's what we do.
Scott: Yes, but it would not be nearly as in government.
Rym: Yes, no, no, it actually would be more Scott when I tell you for computing.
Rym: I'm like, yeah We'll set up an SSH tunnel for the people.
Guest: that doesn't mean anything to most people and because it's because scientists are usually Extremely busy people we don't have a lot of time to talk to anyone very extensively about anything.
Guest: So we need to convey the information to you as quickly as possible.
Guest: I hope you're noticing a trend here about how science information is conveyed to people.
Guest: It's as quickly as possible as dense as possible as much information as we can in as small a space as we possibly can or as Little information as we can in the smallest soundbite as we can possibly so Interestingly enough there is.
Guest: I can give you one example of somebody who is doing something right here.
Guest: There is a Project run by a guy in Kansas State University named Doug Powell In conjunction with several other people.
Guest: this guy named Ben Chapman Canada.
Guest: It is called barf blog and this relates specifically.
Guest: This relates very specifically to food safety science.
Guest: I'm a food safety microbiologist.
Guest: This is what I do.
Guest: It's my bread and butter.
Guest: It's it's very public health related Raw butter.
Scott: even look like if y'all like.
Guest: I've seen raw butter before in in the midst during things.
Guest: But no, it's not.
Guest: It's really.
Scott: it's smell Like you don't want to take the raw milk from the cow you put in a butter.
Guest: Do you guys know what a cow smells like you ever smelled?
Guest: Yeah Well, grab the udder and just tug a few times.
Guest: it's a little more complicated than that.
Guest: don't do that you'll get.
Guest: There's a lot of poop around the udder around the cow.
Guest: The milk smells like poop all the time.
Guest: a lot of raw milk products smell very vague.
Rym: I watched a farmer literally squirted into his mouth.
Guest: Yeah, I cannot.
Guest: that is so unsanitary.
Scott: Maybe I have a theory.
Scott: farmers scat.
Scott: It makes sense.
Guest: So anyway barf blog it is a blog and I'm.
Guest: I'm going to tell you that you should read it.
Guest: I don't know if you want to subscribe to it because they post like 40 things a day.
Scott: Whoa, that is so it's.
Guest: it's a hardcore blog.
Guest: These guys are totally dedicated to it.
Guest: And what they do is a really neat.
Guest: They take all of this this crazy food safety information and they make cool infographics.
Guest: they make Plain language articles.
Guest: they summarize information in a way that is accessible to the modern reader to You know Joe whoever in Wichita, Kansas Anybody can read these articles and understand what they have a fifth-grade reading level or does it need at least a reasonable adult reading?
Guest: I would say if you are probably 16 years old you can grasp our blog well enough.
Guest: So they they condense these articles into a plain language that is understandable to modern reader and this is exactly what you want.
Guest: Yes, it's a fantastic movement.
Guest: I think more areas of science need to do things like this.
Guest: It's it's very small.
Guest: It's a very very focused topic, but it's a great start and I tell everyone about it.
Guest: I get a lot of my food safety, you know articles that I spit out to other people about it.
Guest: I say just go read these guys.
Guest: They'll explain it to you because I don't have time to sit here for three hours and explain to you The the full details of why this particular outbreak is significant.
Guest: these guys already did it and they're very good at it.
Scott: So that maybe that maybe that's what we need.
Scott: Maybe we need someone to basically when you if I go to like, you know, PubMed or whatever And there's some scientific paper that I can only see the abstract for right, you know I mean even if I could read the paper we already discussed I won't be able to understand it.
Scott: But maybe we need some guy whose job it is is basically do the bar blog job and write that is normal article Like that for every single paper.
Guest: That's the easiest in the first place to start.
Guest: what I would like to see eventually is and this is one of my pet Projects is full public health and well full public science education reform to shift away from Information gathering to information processing because we can gather information really?
Guest: Well, we need to teach Everyone.
Guest: every individual person needs to be able to understand how to process information How to grasp the limits of a study.
Guest: What is this actually saying?
Guest: and you know, how far does the scope actually apply?
Guest: And that's something that we need to do in the classroom at home in every media to which people are exposed And that that's really what the mission needs to be.
Guest: We we really need to instead of just throwing around pretty charts to spin our points.
Guest: We really need to Break things down and explain them and explain to people how they work and how you draw those conclusions.
Guest: because until we do that Normal people are gonna look at information and just believe it because they don't know how to process it.
Guest: They don't know how to question it.
Guest: They don't know how to think about it critically.
Guest: And that that that problem.
Guest: now we actually have people who interpret and present information.
Guest: This is something that we've found in doing consumer studies people how people respond to package labeling on foods.
Guest: This is how consumers get a lot of their safety information.
Guest: It comes from the people selling them the product.
Guest: the people selling them the product know how to interpret the information to make it Most attractive to the person who is trying to buy.
Guest: it supports the immune system It's like that and that there are all kinds of things wrapped up in that and people are very very very good at Staying within the bounds of the law and allowing people to draw conclusions based on the things they have never actually said.
Guest: But using all of the other details about packaging or presentation Cheerios, I won't have a heart attack and die.
Scott: Yeah, okay It's because there's a picture of a heart on it, right and and and because they've they've thrown some some information at you.
Guest: Wow, that must be good.
Guest: or you know, organic food must be better for you.
Guest: So I'm gonna buy nothing but organic food.
Guest: There are all kinds of examples of these sorts of things and while they often have a degree of scientific merit until we can get people Really able to investigate and ask the right sorts of questions Will will basically have a population that just believes what other people tell them and that is sort of the antithesis of science Everybody kind of needs to turn into a skeptical jackass in order for science to work.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: the one hit is jabbed like crazy.
Rym: So you'd hit that you jab like crazy until you got it in somewhere.
Scott: He's anywhere to get it in.
Rym: Well that there clearly is.
Rym: There's at least one place to get it in Possibly - but poop is coming in Poops coming out of your mouth.
Rym: I Heard you want to do your news first about me.
Rym: do my.
Scott: I got an opening of it.
Rym: Let's do the opener and then we're good.
Scott: or your mom or trap Or street fighting.
Rym: and I got a brief opening.
Rym: you can do your real opening.
Rym: it's Monday November.
Scott: You couldn't even look to make sure Was like.
Rym: I don't know I don't I don't have to look at you.
Rym: I was looking at my beyond began well before you begin.
Scott: Yawning is contagious, you know, and they still know the purpose of yawning.