Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, February 2nd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk a bit about the nerd NYC recess.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I got this brand new computer.
Rym: I can play pretty much any game.
Rym: I would ever wanted to play just perfectly.
Scott: really I have a computer that's like a year old or maybe and it can also play any game ever.
Rym: Yeah, shittily you get like 20 frames a second in Bioshock.
Rym: I watched you.
Scott: Not really.
Rym: Yeah, just fine It was unplayable on your PC.
Rym: I tried it.
Scott: Yeah, you're just crazy.
Rym: Anyway, I've got this awesome PC.
Rym: It's all set.
Rym: What have I been playing for the last?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: three days back man counter-strike.
Scott: It's might as well be pac-man.
Rym: Well, it is counter-strike source to be fair.
Scott: So it's pac-man.
Rym: miss pac-man The thing is I'm kind of happy that I'm doing really well at counter-strike like more so than I used to in the Source in my experience is much harder than regular counter-strike, but I'm doing the.
Rym: I'm doing better than I used to do in these games.
Rym: I don't know if it's the mouse It's the mouse or just the fact that I have a ping like I used to have at RIT.
Scott: again It's the mouse and the ping.
Rym: I think it's the mouse and the ping.
Rym: Yep, cuz I went back, you know at RIT It was like what's my ping?
Rym: I don't know six maybe seven if it's around 11.
Rym: I quit because fuck that.
Scott: Yep That's why my skills at FPS is greatly decreased when I left RIT cuz my pain greatly increased.
Rym: also We don't play every single day like we used to yeah multiple hours every single day.
Rym: Oh my god I remember.
Rym: I'd like come home from our.
Rym: I'd like from class.
Rym: You'd be at home playing tribes.
Rym: I just joined the game like an hour later.
Rym: You'd leave and go to class.
Rym: I'd stay I'd keep playing.
Rym: you'd come home.
Rym: I just you know keep playing.
Rym: then I'd go to class.
Rym: I come back.
Rym: You're still playing.
Rym: Yep Stopped every now and then to like eat but I Eat it while playing.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah, usually I'd make that kitsune ramen and then I'd eat it in my lap.
Scott: But I need some ramen.
Scott: you got me.
Scott: I got a ton.
Rym: I gotta take some but I get it all over my keyboard because I beat it.
Rym: But I'd be hungry, you know, I eat it too fast.
Scott: Just this weekend.
Scott: I dishwashed my keyboard.
Rym: Yeah, I can't really do that with my DOS keyboard.
Scott: It worked real nice.
Scott: It's now.
Scott: it's like super clean.
Scott: I got to do my one for home.
Scott: I did the work one.
Rym: I kind of want to take another DOS keyboard to work, but I think my co-workers would kill me.
Rym: Why click click click.
Scott: Just get the happy hacking keyboard.
Rym: I'm thinking about it.
Scott: We'll see if it's good for VIM.
Scott: cuz the escape key is so close But there's no numpad.
Scott: so you gotta get a numpad.
Rym: Yeah, you can get one of those like external numpad.
Rym: I got external numpads or the company that makes my awesome mouse.
Rym: They also make like dedicated gaming hand pads that I don't like those things that are shaped like a hand.
Rym: I don't know if they're actually shaped like a hand.
Rym: They're just kind of they've got buttons all over them.
Rym: They're like a button pad.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not I'm not a fan.
Rym: I figure hold out like a year and then I'll get an OLED one and I'll be all set forever.
Scott: Basically, I'm not a fan of it.
Scott: You know, I sort of changed my philosophy.
Scott: I'm not a fan of anything that's weird and custom because then when you're in a situation where you don't have it What are you gonna do?
Scott: right, so if you get used to playing like PC games with your weird hand thing and then you go to like some tournaments somewhere and Sure enough.
Scott: They don't have the weird hand thing.
Scott: Well, what are you gonna do with your regular hand?
Rym: The mouse I have at least gets around that the mouse holds all the configs in it.
Rym: Yeah, so no matter where I go no matter what I like that mouse.
Rym: It's so great.
Rym: I took me a long time to like configure it and tweak it and I'm still tweaking it.
Rym: I have a profile for every individual game and it's cool.
Rym: They have all these rules like alright in every game.
Rym: set the mouse sensitivity to zero Unmodified and then make all adjustments in this program.
Rym: set the windows sensitivity to this because this means zero.
Rym: So it's all 100% in the mouse.
Rym: Mmm, of course that leads to some weird problems because Bioshock the mouse because the sensitivity is so low as far as Bioshock sees Basically doesn't work in the menu.
Rym: But once I start playing it's perfect.
Rym: That's because Bioshock's written shittily, I guess.
Scott: Yeah, there's stuff like.
Scott: that is always weird with games like because not every game is programmed the exact same way.
Scott: Like my logitech mouse.
Scott: in the if you go to logitech settings There's a checkbox that says, you know, okay set some sense.
Scott: There's a sensitivity bar and then you can choose do you want to use this one or the windows one?
Scott: Right or both.
Scott: Yeah, and then there's a button that says okay when you start a game What do you want to do?
Scott: Do you want to use this sensitivity the game sensitivity the window sensitivity, right?
Scott: But it the detection of when you're running a game is not the greatest.
Scott: so sometimes it thinks you're playing a game when you're not and sometimes your thinks you're not playing a game when you are and Sometimes they'll get trapped like it'll know you started playing a game, but it won't know you stopped and your sensitivity is black.
Rym: So I remember I had a lot of problems.
Rym: I made a custom thing because no one had a good one to actually Change between the sensitivity for a mouse and the sensitivity for a joystick inside of tribes - yeah tribes - could let you.
Scott: because basically, you know other games the you know the.
Scott: if you opened up the The terminal in the game the command prompt like in quake it was like a quick.
Scott: it's quick language, you know in Tribes, it was basically C++.
Rym: But I couldn't get that to work too.
Rym: Well, so I found an external app that was meant for all games any game that had vehicles and walking But it would pretty much hose my computer every time I stopped playing tribes and I'd have to reboot.
Rym: It says something about the priorities in my life that back then that the obvious solution was.
Rym: well I'll just reboot every time I finish playing a game.
Rym: Yeah, of course those days are back a little bit a little bit cuz.
Rym: I've been playing games like every day when I get home.
Scott: I've been playing Street Fighter 4 a lot.
Scott: Not every day though.
Scott: I haven't played it since last week So I played again probably tomorrow.
Rym: What tier are you?
Rym: Are you top tier yet?
Scott: I'm on the lowest possible tier.
Rym: Can you check out of?
Rym: I don't even know I?
Scott: Well, I can.
Scott: I know that if someone throws me and I throw them at the same time Then it'll say technical and make a little blue swirly.
Rym: So what does that mean?
Rym: What's the gnosis there?
Scott: That means that you did basically you do the same thing as the other guy at the exact same time I hit him in the exact same spot.
Scott: then it basically like cancels.
Scott: It's like So if a guy's trying to throw you right you can't really block because you can throw someone who's blocking you can jump away from Them right, but then you're jumping away from them and maybe they'll like shoot a fireball real quick and you'll land on it And that'll hurt.
Scott: so if you know He's gonna throw You just push throw at the exact same time because you saw the throw coming a mile away and it'll make a blue swirly And then you're right next to him.
Scott: You didn't get thrown and then you can make a move, huh?
Rym: So you got any gaming news because I don't really have any gaming news other than the fact that Pax East is almost sold out.
Rym: There's only 600 tickets as of like four hours before we recorded this.
Scott: You know anime Boston is the week after Pax East, but we're not talking about it nearly enough.
Rym: Now we're going to anime Boston too, but none of you care because this is Tuesday night.
Scott: You know, there's gonna be gaming in anime Boston, too.
Scott: So, you know if you like anime even a little bit you should hang around the town all week.
Rym: Yeah, but me and Scott are gonna be around Boston even more awesome.
Rym: Yeah, anime Boston is gonna be pretty badass.
Rym: Of course, it sells out almost every year, doesn't it?
Scott: I think so.
Rym: Pretty sure it does.
Rym: It has big lines.
Rym: For all I know it's already sold out.
Scott: It deserves its big lines too.
Rym: So it does say one thing about Pax though, and you know, they've got Reed and everything behind the scenes But the Pax Hotel.
Rym: They got much better rates from the local hotels than anime Boston was able to get.
Scott: And they get free internets.
Rym: Yeah, that's the Pax policy.
Rym: If you stay in a Pax Hotel, free internet no matter what.
Scott: Yep And if the Pax Hotel doesn't do free internet, not a Pax Hotel.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, I got a little bit of gaming news Dominion, very popular game lately.
Rym: Yep Of course we had the problem that the game as fun as it was with the basic decks at least boiled down to Just make a money machine and then buy provinces or buy the witch and then make a money machine.
Scott: Basically every time we play Dominion a whole bunch with all sorts of combinations of cards from the regular set and from intrigue And all sorts of different people.
Rym: It wasn't just like a feedback loop like we've often run into.
Scott: Well, not all sorts of different people but enough different people.
Scott: and basically what happened is we determined that in order to win you should only buy like a handful of action cards and Get mostly money and then as soon as you have enough money buy all the provinces or buy duchies if you can't get provinces
Rym: Unless the game has too many attack cards and then you basically had to kind of go in for the long slog and buy duchies.
Scott: Yeah, but it was like a lot of cards were sort of useless.
Scott: Let you know like do you really need like the Chancellor or whatever?
Scott: Maybe not really, you know.
Scott: So whatever.
Scott: so there was a seaside expansion that I knew existed but we hadn't gotten yet and I played it recently at a board game night a couple weeks ago and I played the seaside expansion and I'm playing right and I'm just.
Scott: I'm just like, you know what?
Scott: I looked around the all the ten cards because we played with all seaside cards, right?
Scott: And I looked at all the cards that were on the table and I picked one that I thought looked kind of interesting like the ghost Ship, which is which is sort of nice card.
Scott: So I'm like, okay, I'll get I'll just buy some ghost ships and Silver and gold and I'll be in this business, right?
Scott: So I bought the cars that sort of had obvious uses and You know, I started getting lots of money and I bought a province and the next turn I bought another province and I was like fuck.
Scott: Yes, that's right.
Scott: These morons.
Scott: They were buying action cars like nuts, right?
Scott: And another turn goes by.
Scott: I didn't get a province the next turn I didn't get a province.
Scott: again the turn after that this dude bought a province and a duchy on the same turn.
Rym: See I think what happened there is that it got the game got to the point to where there were enough Combos to where if you you can have this is only seaside cars.
Scott: This isn't have any Dominion or intrigue cards except for coppers and curses and we know whatever.
Rym: but think about it.
Rym: in the basic game It comes down to the fact that if you have eight money You should buy a province because that that's like just the way it works.
Rym: But you can't really build up enough momentum fast enough to do anything crazier.
Rym: There's no like late game because someone will end the game right away.
Scott: Yeah, so in seaside what they added was that some of the cards are orange and if a card is orange That means you play it and then it stays there and it does something next turn also.
Scott: So like the caravan you play it and You get plus one card plus one action.
Scott: So it's basically you know You just play them like crazy because you play one you draw a card you play another caravan you draw a card you play You play all your caravans that are in your hand and then the next turn.
Scott: If you let's say you played five caravans the next turn you start by drawing five cards.
Scott: So your turn begins with you having ten cards in your hand.
Scott: All right And there's a bunch of cards that basically they stick around for one turn and do something on the next turn.
Scott: One card that I thought was the most interesting was the Treasury.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I can't I don't have the specific exact wording of it.
Scott: Basically the way it works is You play it and it gives you some money, right?
Scott: And then if you Don't buy any victory cards right at the end of the then at the end of the turn all the treasuries that you played They don't go in the discard pile.
Scott: They go on top of the deck.
Scott: So basically what happens is if you have like five treasuries, they'll be on top of your deck.
Scott: You draw all five and I think they let you draw a card.
Scott: so then you're drawing five more cards and you basically have this pile of like ones that sits on top of your deck and you Keep redrawing them every single turn because they go right back to the top of the deck every time Until you eventually you buy a victory card, then they all get shuffled back in.
Scott: So it's like you can get six treasuries or even you don't even need six.
Scott: You just need like three treasuries and then draw three gold every turn.
Scott: and you buy gold Three monies and you buy gold.
Scott: you buy gold you buy gold you buy as many gold as you want You buy gold every turn and then eventually when you're satisfied you have enough gold.
Scott: Let the treasuries get shuffled back in by a province by province by province by province.
Rym: Right, well what's interesting is the game kind of had stages and each expansion Gave us more.
Rym: gameplay like the original dominion was fun And then you know our group solved it and then there's more stuff.
Rym: and oh now we got to do different off.
Rym: now We solved it and then there's more saw.
Rym: now we solved it.
Scott: I want to get the seaside because the seaside makes the action cards just a little bit more powerful so that they're actually more Worthwhile than just buying silver and gold but as another dominion expansion that's coming out.
Scott: This is the news called alchemy.
Scott: I suspect it will involve turning things into other things.
Rym: I'm excited.
Rym: Dominion has.
Rym: every time I've started to Peter out and think yeah I'm kind of done with this game and expansion fixes every concern I have and makes the game brand new to me all over.
Scott: Yeah, what's kind of cool is?
Scott: it's like it's not collectible But you use.
Scott: they're still making big money off you because you're buying expansions.
Scott: But that's okay because it's not collectible, right?
Scott: I just buy the expansion and I'm done and I don't care if there's a hundred expansions or not because it's just you know.
Rym: But think of this already.
Rym: there are more Combinations than any human could ever play if they devoted their entire life from birth to death playing Dominion.
Scott: The thing is most of the combinations are the same.
Scott: It's.
Scott: you know, if I play with these nine cards and I switch one out It's depending on which one I switch out probably not making a big difference.
Rym: Well, it'll come down to.
Rym: does this game have the witch or not.
Scott: Yep So yeah, Dominion alchemy is coming.
Scott: Dominion seaside is good, you know.
Scott: Get all four sets mix them up have an awesome time Awesome.
Rym: So I got a couple of quick minor geek bites.
Rym: There's really nothing in the news that I cared that much about though There was that whole.
Rym: the prison won't let the prisoners play D&D anymore because they think it's gang related.
Scott: Whatever Yeah, and there probably is like a D&D prison gang or something.
Rym: That's kind of awesome.
Scott: I know I figure I just let those guys out.
Scott: I'd be like you're good.
Rym: I think I should email or I should just send a regular letter to that prisoner.
Rym: I mean that I found all the info on him.
Scott: Yeah, you can send letters to prison.
Rym: I should be like, hey Burning, can you send them books if I can burning wheel?
Rym: But I've been playing two games, you know I'm not gonna talk about counter-strike and I want to kind of get out my first impressions because they're games that I never actually Played before and I probably should have of course Psychonauts.
Rym: well for sideshow knobs.
Rym: It's like you That's that's one of those games that no one really knew about except the people who were like hardcore about it.
Scott: It's sort of like earthbound.
Scott: it's like there's a whole bunch of people who are like fuck.
Scott: Yeah Fuck.
Scott: Yeah But you know if you actually look around not that many, you know But it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's one of those games of this like a loud internet voice for it and no other voice.
Rym: like no one I get the game that I'd always heard of my whole life, but until Yahtzee talked about it I didn't know anything about it other than there's a game called psychonauts that some of our friends won't shut the fuck up about.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I played it for a few levels, but that was about it.
Scott: I was not really Excited.
Rym: yeah, well the thing is it's one of those games that gets a thousand points for style kind of like Brutal legend, I don't know.
Scott: maybe it gets 500 points for style.
Rym: it gets not as many points as brutal legend.
Rym: brutal legend has the biggest disparity between style and gameplay.
Rym: Yeah, oh my god.
Rym: It pains me that brutal legend is not just a move is completely non brutal.
Scott: It should.
Rym: it should have just been an animated directed DVD movie Oh my god, or even just a live-action movie with Jack Black in it.
Scott: who knows whatever.
Rym: Maybe some Harryhausen eska puppets and claymation sure.
Rym: But anyway, I mean, I don't know the game has just enough dark humor and all that to where I really like the style
Scott: And I
Rym: don't know if it's because I haven't played a 3d platformer in a long time But it's it's filling in an itch that I've had for a long time.
Rym: That was wasn't scratched.
Scott: Yeah, the 3d platform That's the main.
Scott: the reason I never like finished the game is because the 3d platforming this of it is like not The greatest in my opinion, you know compared to say a mario 64 or mario galaxy or something like that.
Rym: That's my conundrum.
Rym: The last 3d platformer.
Rym: I played was mario 64 and then DS and I played halfway through sunshine.
Rym: I was kind of dropped it.
Rym: I never played galaxy.
Rym: I'm kind of behind on 3d platformers.
Rym: So I have a feeling that everything I'm getting out of the sideshow knots I'll get it a thousand times more over.
Rym: if I just play like a Nintendo 3d platformer then I won't care about the game anymore.
Rym: So yeah in the spirit of riding the smaller roller coasters before I ride the bigger ones I'm going to finish precise show knobs first.
Scott: Yeah when I played the site show knots I had already ridden the bigger rollercoaster.
Rym: Of course, we'll see a lot of people say that like once you get later in the game, there's weird and cool stuff.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's a go guy gar situation right there.
Scott: that I am NOT.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: I'm gonna play your game kids and I tell you what.
Rym: if there is nothing surprising in this game I'm going to be very disappointed with every one of you who's?
Scott: I don't think I don't think anyone's lying.
Scott: I think there is something later in the game that's different but at least like the first three or so levels I played It was not there.
Scott: It was later.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is people aren't gonna say, you know that like.
Scott: I don't doubt that the later episodes of go guy Gar good as good as people say, you know, I don't think they're lying.
Scott: I just think that it's you know, I got better things to do.
Scott: then You know go through a whole big show or skip a whole bunch of episodes and be confused.
Rym: Well, it's simple.
Rym: What if would Mario 3 be as good of a game if in order to get to the actual first level of Mario 3 You had to be hide lied No See angry video game.
Scott: nerd did highlight.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I kind of want to play highlight again.
Scott: I want to basically make highlight only not crappy.
Rym: Yeah, but I'd like was by default It's crap.
Scott: All you have to do to make highlight not crappies play The Legend of Zelda?
Scott: Well, no, you just make highlight slower and actually make the sword come out just like Zelda But keep that same map and stuff.
Rym: So just make a Zelda see that has that map exactly.
Scott: But I like the way the highlight looks with the with the screens, you know.
Rym: And then I think you forget what is little mazes what it's like to actually play on that.
Scott: No, that's nuts because the game the controls are all fucked up.
Scott: you move around way too fast You can't tell when you're attacking and defending.
Scott: if you just fix the controls and attack or defend.
Scott: No, you got.
Scott: it actually has to be pressed once to attack once and you know what I'm talking about.
Scott: Yeah, if you change that part it would probably be alright.
Rym: But I feel like I'm gonna play psychonauts now Before I play other games that remind me why it's not the best game in the world.
Rym: But I start to understand why people were so obsessed with it for when it came out The camera was amazing compared to similar games.
Scott: Oh, that is true.
Rym: Is that the camera is great compared to any other game I can think of from any part of that era Mmm also.
Scott: remember though you're playing what I'm like steam, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah a lot of people played this thing.
Scott: I'm like ps2 and such so it's it's a different experience.
Rym: Yeah, I know.
Rym: I mean I got my Xbox controller Screen HD.
Rym: Yeah, I got it right here.
Rym: All right in fact I'm hooking up my computer to my TV because it's on the other side of the room in the living room and I'm gonna use The wireless controller and I'm gonna play all these games on the TV.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I'm excited about this.
Rym: He's got a run an HDMI cable right through that wall.
Rym: We'll see how that goes.
Scott: Good luck with it.
Rym: the other thing I'm playing is all those old total war games that my computer couldn't handle before because my fan of those I'm a fan so far but I feel like Everything that feels like it's strategic is actually just letting me win.
Scott: yeah, I mean I played the demo of like the first one ever when it was new.
Scott: right and Basically, the demo has you do the combat where you're controlling like these big armies and formations.
Scott: You got archers and pikemen and all sorts of stuff right out, but then right I actually watched someone play like for reals.
Rym: They just grab all the troops and send them straight in yet.
Scott: And and basically they never actually went into the combat.
Scott: They just play the game on the map and they just let the combat be like auto because that doesn't matter.
Rym: It gives me that option.
Rym: But I don't know that the whole point of the game is to learn like Formations.
Scott: right but that part doesn't matter because you just win if your army is the right size.
Scott: You just play the map game.
Scott: Yes, I'm playing just that's the reason that I was like.
Rym: well fuck that I'm playing just the actual combat apart.
Rym: I'm playing through all the historical things and the history is okay, and I feel like you can learn some stuff.
Rym: But so far, uh, you learn more from reading the Wikipedia article on infantry tactics than you do play in this game.
Rym: Yeah, so we'll see.
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna give it more of a go but the game is just not nearly as Interesting or strategic or tactical or anything is.
Rym: a lot of people have made it out to be because people can't tell when you Know.
Scott: you just put up the.
Scott: it's like security.
Scott: You just put up the illusion of security and people believe that there's a care where you know Regardless of whether that act whatever that is makes them more secure or not.
Scott: It's the same with strategy.
Scott: You just put something up that looks strategic and people believe you've made it more strategic whether you have or you haven't.
Rym: Yep, like I tried this one scenario a bunch of times and I realized there's guys on the wall.
Rym: So I sent archers in to basically pepper the walls where these other archers are to keep them away while my battering rams and ladders go up.
Rym: and I tried with and without the archers over and over again and I'm pretty sure that the archers had zero effect at all because it just made more goons that got killed on the top And it's kind of just a glorified hard-to-control tower defense game Mmm, or tower offense but not impressed so far.
Rym: Give me another month and I'll say I'm not impressed again.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: what do you got for me?
Scott: I got another funny webcomic I found called Scott meets Family Circus.
Scott: no relation to me.
Scott: This guy's name is Scott Gerdner and basically what he does is he has a little Tumblr blog and he makes a little comic and on the left side of the comic he puts up an actual Family Circus comic which I'm sure is probably illegal, but he's parodying but he's also reproducing, you know He's putting up the original and his parody together as opposed to just the parody.
Scott: So, I don't know if this falls into like a Garfield - Garfield situation or not.
Scott: But anyway on the right side, he puts a parody of that exact same comic.
Scott: so it's a pretty funny take on the Family Circus and I laughed at it and Rym also lulled.
Scott: so it's pretty good.
Scott: Check it out.
Rym: It's no John Hey But it's good.
Rym: Hmm So my thing of the day is not gaming related, but it's just too cool to not talk about it.
Scott: I think it any wasn't gaming related.
Scott: You ever heard of Family Circus?
Scott: video game, of course.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: Anyway, I just I always think back to that Perry Bible Fellowship parody of Family Circus.
Scott: That's the best.
Rym: But Bill Watterson the the reclusive author of Kelvin and Hobbes Which to this day is regarded by most people is one of the greatest if not the greatest newspaper strip in the history of newspaper strips.
Rym: There's an interview with him online which might not seem that crazy until you realize that there really aren't interviews with him ever anywhere.
Rym: He and the thing is it's not like he's a hermit necessarily he just he's just normal guy.
Rym: his neighbors all respect his Anonymity and he just lives in his town and they do reporters ask about him.
Rym: They just say yeah I'm not gonna tell you.
Scott: so basically, you know, he's not like Like Steve Ditko who like won't appear, you know, this guy goes the grocery store and shit.
Scott: He just doesn't want to talk to anybody and it doesn't want to be bothered by fans.
Scott: He just wants to be able to live a normal life without you know Like a Hollywood situation or salesman or business people constantly body just wants to be able to live a normal life.
Rym: But what's really cool is that by and large not like a loner who hides away and doesn't talk to anybody, you know He's such a respected individual that the press and almost everyone involved has respected his Desire to remain mostly private.
Scott: and I haven't respected if people are trying to find him.
Scott: Oh, they just can't.
Rym: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: if you really want in the problem No, but the problem is if you try to if you try to go after him the wrong way You just won't get anywhere.
Scott: He just won't talk to you and it's like well, what did you get?
Scott: You got a picture of him walking down the street.
Scott: big deal Yeah, but there was.
Rym: you didn't get any videos of people like chasing him.
Rym: I'm sure if people try.
Rym: there were two videos of chasing.
Scott: I don't think that's gonna happen because then if you try to do that you could go to like jail.
Rym: now, it's okay.
Rym: It's fine to chase people with a microphone as long as you're not threatening them with the microphone Waving it over your head somehow.
Scott: I think that the local police in that area would have a disagreement regardless of what the law.
Rym: Maybe they just murdered anyone who went anywhere near him and buried the bodies.
Scott: Yeah, right next to cow.
Rym: Anyway, this article.
Rym: It's really cool to finally hear some of his thoughts on why Calvin and Hobbes was popular and what he was thinking in it.
Rym: It's about what you would expect but I'll note.
Rym: the picture of him in the article is a semi stock photo from 1986. they didn't take a picture of him.
Scott: He emailed him.
Scott: He didn't even go see him.
Scott: Yeah, I think so.
Scott: How's he gonna get a picture?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Bob telephoto lens camp out Google Maps.
Scott: the thing that I the most.
Scott: the other the only more recent thing I guess the second most recent thing I've seen in terms of trying to find him was a guy who like Ended up in like a diner in his town and he's pretty sure that he saw him in the back room At a table talking to someone like in the you know the dining room But he couldn't confirm or deny whether it was him or not and the people in the restaurant wouldn't help him out at all.
Scott: So and that was sort of like as far as he got.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I just thought it was cool.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So meta Minute is the off-forgotten meta minute metamucil.
Scott: No Okay, so what meta things do?
Rym: you're the one who reminded me to do it.
Rym: you got nothing to say.
Rym: What's all this?
Rym: What the fuck Scott?
Scott: Well, this Pax East.
Rym: Yeah, Pax East is probably already sold out.
Rym: But if you want to go to Pax you didn't pre-register and you're not going to pre-register right now.
Scott: You're done and there's anime Boston.
Rym: anime Boston might already be sold out.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: you should go pre-register for that, too.
Rym: It's right after Pax.
Scott: There is the mocha the mocha arts festival the weekend after that right after anime Boston.
Scott: Yep Do I was like what the one that's a week after that Nexus.
Rym: some atheist thing.
Rym: it's a ways off.
Scott: It's some skeptic thing.
Scott: I don't think it's an atheist thing.
Rym: Well, I think the two are hand-in-hand.
Scott: No, not necessarily.
Scott: There are a lot of people who believe in the jeebus, but also don't like fake medicine.
Rym: Yeah, but then they're not skeptical enough.
Scott: There Is I'm gonna update the website.
Scott: you're reaching soon with some stuff and Rym is still not doing any e-commerce.
Rym: Yeah, I'm having enough trouble with these new microphones in the new computer.
Scott: You could have done the e-commerce first.
Rym: Yeah, I could have but the old computer as I learned when I tried to boot it to put up a show.
Rym: We recorded and it didn't boot.
Rym: I Changed computers about the right time.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Sure Okay, that's good enough.
Scott: It's supposed to be a moment.
Scott: It's not supposed to be the meta hour Yep, nothing else.
Rym: And then that was there was a little bit.
Scott: I for someone who was so prepared to do the man I just want to start remembering you do it every time.
Scott: Oh, oh the book club selection is still Douglas Adams Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy and you should read that first book only and the next Thursday show.
Scott: That's what it's gonna be.
Rym: Well, you're allowed to read the rest of them, but we're not gonna talk about.
Scott: Yeah, and if Rym doesn't read it by the next Thursday show, we're gonna do it anyway, and it's gonna be lulls Rym sucks, I'll do it from my memory of like 12 years ago.
Scott: Yeah, you should.
Scott: you should read it.
Scott: It only took me one night or two.
Rym: It's not a long book now and you know, you guys should read read.
Rym: Yeah I Get the impression people don't read many of the books we're doing and I'm pretty sure most of the people that were looking point of Doing the book club is to make people read.
Rym: I'm pretty sure almost all of you who are looking forward to the next GeekNights' book club show on the hitchhiker's guide Are only looking forward to it because you already read the book a long time ago.
Scott: Yeah read again.
Scott: Yes, however, or for the first time over the weekend.
Rym: We went to the nerd NYC recess in Brooklyn.
Scott: yeah, I've been had.
Scott: there's a group in New York City if you live in New York City called nerd NYC and They have all sorts of gaming meetups and they do it one They do a board game night at a coffee place once a month that I go that I've been going to like two months in.
Scott: They got some sort of Gotham Gaming Guild RPG meetup kind of thing you can and basically all this stuff is organized.
Scott: They have a PHP BB and all this stuff is organized there.
Scott: So if you're looking for RPGs LARFs board games any kind of thing in New York City, they got it.
Scott: So they have this recess event that I think is you know somewhat, you know, once or maybe twice a year ish and It's not quite a gaming con.
Scott: however, it is not but it's not exactly a board gaming night either I'll put it this way.
Rym: It is not a gaming con, but it is bigger than several gaming cons I have been to.
Scott: yeah There were like a hundred something people there and it's two full days of gaming from like 11 in the morning to 11 at night Ish.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We I will only went for one day and for two days.
Rym: But in general if you guys you know You always want us to do the GeekNights con and we're getting there where you know We got a lot of others probably gonna be pretty similar to that Basically a room full of tables.
Scott: hang out for a day, you know play games Yep.
Rym: But if you want that Desperately and you're not willing to wait for us to get to it and it's not at the top of my queue by any stretch If you go to these things, we're there.
Rym: you can just pretend it's a GeekNights event, even though it's not Yeah, there was a listener there said hi to us.
Rym: Yeah, there were a couple listeners I ran and I'm also you know, I'm starting to.
Scott: you know, like I've been going to these things.
Scott: So I sort of you know, I'm becoming some friendly with some of the repeat attendees, you know, I can recognize them.
Scott: They recognize me.
Scott: I know a few of their names, you know, I know who likes what games, you know There's some guys or it's like.
Scott: we know, you know, we're the sero guys.
Scott: We always played the sero.
Scott: We got things going on.
Scott: So it's it's a good group of people's there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean the only big thing I did was play a paranoia game.
Rym: This is the third paranoia game I've played in my entire life.
Rym: Oh man as much as I love paranoia I'm not one to put forth the effort to run it because I have other things I want to run and Not that many people run it let alone.
Rym: Well, so I mean what.
Rym: we had that LARP at RIT that we were both in like the tabletop paranoia LARP And I played it once halfway.
Scott: I mean, it wasn't a LARP.
Scott: It's just it's sort of a half LARP.
Scott: It's a LARP.
Rym: Well, I usually I call that a tabletop LARP where you're LARPing and that you're all first-person.
Rym: Yeah, and the rules are fast and loose, but you're still all sitting around a table.
Rym: It's just like instead of dice.
Scott: There are some physical elements involved like props.
Scott: It's basically a tabletop RPG with props.
Rym: Yep, but also drop some of the dice and Oftentimes people like in paranoia like zap.
Scott: They'll use the mechanic of if you want to shoot someone you yell like a gun at them and you go your finger guns And you go zap.
Rym: Yep, and then everyone goes zap all at once and if you don't immediately zap at someone you didn't shoot.
Rym: Whoever has the most finger bangs pointed at them dies.
Rym: I like that mechanic a lot.
Scott: It's a little bit of mafia mechanics there.
Scott: It is werewolf for those of you who are heathens.
Rym: the guy around the game was pretty awesome.
Rym: He ran just as well as Luke only without the tabletop LARP element with Morgan.
Rym: Yes, and the cool part is I ran it You know, I played in it and Emily played in it with me and she had never played paranoia before.
Scott: Did you have the soda now?
Scott: We didn't do this.
Scott: What the hell.
Rym: she didn't know anything about paranoia other than it's kind of Logan's runny and weird and Computer the colors nothing.
Scott: She didn't really didn't know about the computer and the colors of being happy communist or anything.
Rym: She pretty much knew all the stuff, you know from us.
Rym: talking about the game She never read the books or played it or anything.
Rym: So so we started as blue.
Scott: We played as like oh shit I played anything but red.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: I gotta tell you I was yeah, you could do fucking crazy show.
Rym: Oh my god, we went into the fucking position equipment.
Rym: We went into R&D and I was like, I want exploding everything.
Rym: and they're like, here you go.
Rym: And here's a nuke.
Rym: Yeah that nuke.
Rym: we had a total party kill.
Rym: In fact, we had two total party kills because not only did the whole party die But because then the nuke went off.
Rym: the computer NPC party that was sent to kill all of us was also killed.
Rym: nice But she had no idea was going on and we're blue.
Rym: So, you know I bust into the R&D department with all these reds and yellows.
Rym: I'm like, give me all your fucking shit.
Rym: and then I killed them all because they were clearly communists.
Rym: Of course It was great.
Rym: I love paranoia so much.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: What game did I play Saturday?
Scott: I'm trying to even remember.
Rym: We played Dune.
Rym: that was it.
Rym: we came in.
Scott: we played Dune the board game.
Rym: Yeah, we played first, you know, I've done a whole show on.
Scott: so should we really discuss it again?
Rym: I got there before Scott got there.
Rym: So me Alex Jess and Emily are all there.
Rym: and you know, I had via plenty.
Rym: So we just played it with some guys.
Rym: All right the via plenty and then those two guys, you know We're talking to him like hey, you want to play Dune and they're like, what's Dune?
Rym: and we did the thing We always do.
Rym: well Dune is an asymmetric, you know all the stuff that makes you go.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: I want to play that game.
Rym: So we all sat down and we played a full-on game of Dune all the way to the end.
Rym: I don't think we've only done that.
Rym: I think once before.
Rym: Yeah We always kind of stopped halfway through Or we don't have a full loadout or whatever.
Scott: trying to remember what I was playing while you were playing Paranoia because I was at the next table.
Scott: Oh, all right.
Scott: I was running my t and e. I ran t and e. That's what I was doing.
Rym: Didn't you also run doom?
Scott: No, they accidentally put my name on that but no But yeah, no, I ran a t and e. I taught some people to play t and e. there was one guy who was German.
Scott: He already started knew how to play so he sort of crushed it.
Scott: one guy was cool, but he didn't really.
Rym: He did not grok the fullness.
Scott: Oh, he slowly he grok'd.
Scott: he grok'd more than that guy at anime Boston, but He didn't catch on until you know sort of halfway through.
Scott: the other guy sort of knew what was up But he was you know, he definitely had the potential but it was his first time playing so you couldn't beat the you know.
Scott: And then there was that guy's the second guy's girlfriend who was sort of like.
Scott: well, you know She just sort of she was like she you know She.
Scott: I think she liked the game But she just sort of got tired of not being able to make progress or figuring out how to make progress and getting crushed By the guy who was good.
Scott: So she was just sort of like whatever.
Scott: Let's just get this over with.
Rym: Yeah, one thing I can say about our Doona game though was that you know Normally you play at a con like this and if your game goes long and people have like another game They should be playing.
Rym: you can tell a lot of games.
Rym: You'll see people sitting around.
Rym: They're all antsy.
Rym: Like I just want this to end.
Rym: I want to go do something else.
Rym: This was not what I was bargaining for.
Rym: This wasn't as good as I thought.
Rym: whatever that is.
Scott: The problem is that I think a lot of gaming cons, right?
Scott: They do this game registration thing Which is where you got a at a certain time.
Scott: They open the registration and you got to sign up and say what game you're gonna play and then you have to start playing That game at that time and then you're in that game until it ends.
Scott: you've committed to it And you know, this is sort of a traditional gaming con thing.
Scott: all gaming cons are like this, you know But I think you just shouldn't do it at all.
Scott: Just have open gaming period.
Scott: don't have any.
Scott: you know If someone might want to schedule a game like say I'm running this at X o'clock, right?
Scott: But don't do registration just so.
Rym: how do you deal with the fact that all right, I'm running paranoia?
Rym: I mean you saw like a hundred everyone lined up way before the afternoon signups.
Rym: The paranoia game was full at me Yep, and everyone behind me was like damn it.
Rym: I wanted to play paranoia.
Rym: So, what do you do when I schedule my paranoia game and there are 60 people standing there who want to play?
Scott: I think that what you do is you just have table and first first to sit down.
Rym: So the fat guy sits down at noon and just waits all day.
Scott: Or better yet, right the guy running the game just chooses who he wants to be in the game.
Scott: Because I think a lot of the times what happens especially with an RPG, right?
Scott: But the signups is that the person who signs up is the person who's you know The crazy guy who's gonna wait in the front of the line.
Scott: It was not necessarily gonna be the best at the game or have the best Resulting game experience in the RPG.
Scott: So you don't really want that guy in your RPG.
Scott: He's gonna make it less fun.
Scott: You want to pick who's gonna make it the most fun.
Scott: So Just pick just be a jerk.
Rym: I think you should have both I think open gaming and sign up.
Rym: gaming have places especially.
Rym: remember these are you know?
Rym: sit down play a German board game for a Couple hours.
Rym: These are four to six hours of like.
Rym: I am dedicated to this and the game only has a certain number of slots And all that.
Scott: That's the other thing is sometimes, you know, like Alex and Jess they signed up for something.
Rym: yeah, it uh Basically, I kept looking over at their table and we're playing paranoia like got one dude on the party is turning into a werewolf.
Rym: So he starts to like howl cuz.
Rym: he can't hold it in and to cover up for that in character.
Rym: he starts singing the bouncy bubble fountain food beverage theme song from the commercials in the game and we all start singing and Everyone at that table kind of looks over at us.
Rym: Like I want to be over there.
Scott: Yeah, I think Alex said that basically he was playing Spirit of the Century which is a game that has a lot of hype and I'm pretty you know, but Apparently someone was right at the game.
Scott: like the default theme in the game is like 20s Indiana Jones pulp adventure which I'm totally all about.
Scott: but it seemed like Alex.
Scott: they were using the system to play A D&D dungeon with.
Scott: you know, kill kill the rats.
Rym: That's like the opposite of the point of our beyond D&D panel.
Scott: So Alex was.
Scott: he was basically like yeah, you know He couldn't really tell if the system was actually good or not.
Scott: and I'm I don't know about that system because it gets a lot of hype but the book is very large and Whatever, but you know He had not a good time in that particular instance of the game because it was just here's the trouble.
Rym: and you have the same Thing at like anime con.
Rym: so you've got a panel right say you walk into the panel expecting whatever and it's totally lame And you're like one of four people sitting in the room.
Rym: You just get up and walk the fuck out.
Rym: Yes, what if you're the only guy in the room?
Scott: Yes, definitely.
Rym: So gaming cons though It's much harder to do that because one, you know, it's like if you walk out of a panel You're not hurting the panel.
Rym: You might hurt the panel's feelings But you're not hurting the panel.
Rym: you walk out of a game that only had six slots.
Rym: You are hurting the game and everyone playing in it and the feelings of the guy running.
Rym: It's like a twofer.
Rym: Yeah, and you committed to six hours of that game.
Rym: What are you gonna do now?
Rym: All the other games are full.
Rym: you can go to open gaming.
Rym: But now, you know, you're not having the same experience.
Rym: What are all the people who are gonna play in that game gonna do?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't know how to get around that except maybe every game should have a 15 minute, you know.
Rym: Let's start and play and then after those 15 minutes Every game in the entire con stops has a 10-minute break and you're allowed to not come back.
Scott: I think one good way to do it his is is a possible solution.
Scott: You're right.
Scott: The thing is is that you know, it takes preparation and efforts to run an RPG, right?
Scott: And the thing is most people want to play in like these particular awesome RPGs But there's only a few people will run them and those people will only run like one and that's it.
Scott: He won't run it like three or four times right like we will because we're nuts.
Scott: But you should do is you should just have it RPG con and you say everyone who's coming to this con must bring prepared RPG right.
Scott: and basically what you do is you get a group of people and one of you starts running your game and At any time, you know, you know, who's gonna play in your game.
Scott: if everyone's running games You don't run them all at the same time.
Scott: You take turns running games and you keep shuffling and mixing it.
Scott: if someone's game sucks cuz you know people's games will suck.
Scott: In fact, most of them will you know everyone, you know, most people don't have the GM skills.
Scott: They know they don't have the GM skills, but they come prepared with a game.
Scott: Anyway, maybe they come prepared with like oh, I'll say my baby at least right and you know You can just stop playing game and start one at any time because as long as you can just get people together Someone's got a game.
Scott: Maybe someone who had a fun game will run their game twice You know if they start with one group and then maybe they'll get you know shift to other people and so that way it.
Scott: you know.
Scott: Basically, people are constantly starting playing or stopping playing RPGs the whole time and everyone's got something prepared So that you know no matter, you know, you won't get in a situation where it's like well There's five people free, but none of us are GM's, you know, everyone's gonna get prepared to GM something.
Rym: Well, if you want to fit it in more with the the way these cons already work I think a compromise.
Rym: take the idea of you know The games all have like a 20-minute introductory period where like everyone sits at the table, you know goes over all the stuff They're gonna do and then you have the break and at the break anyone who wants to leave a game goes over to the games that they want to join and then if you don't leave your game then you just come back to the game that you want to stay in and Then any.
Rym: if you go to a game and there's an open slot you get in.
Rym: if you go to a game and it's full Or whatever then you keep reshuffling, you know You have this whole like 20 minute period Where eventually everyone's in a game they want to be in or they've bailed completely on the games that sucked.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's another thing.
Scott: It's like I was playing T&E, right?
Scott: I was teaching and then running it for people like I didn't even play.
Scott: I just taught it and then sort of watched and helped and there are people who were just looking for games to play.
Scott: but my game was full because it only had four seats and I was like listen just sit and learn how to play.
Scott: you don't need to write, you know Even though you can't play they're like no they don't.
Scott: they didn't want to right Like if I couldn't get into an RPG, I'd be happy like to sit there.
Scott: but it's like nope There's X slots and that's it.
Rym: go out, you know, so I don't know might be a difference in culture.
Rym: I mean we're.
Rym: we spend most of our gamer time at either anime con gaming or like generic on you know Like Dragon Con ConnectiCon style gaming where it's kind of geeks all playing games as opposed to gamer only people playing games.
Rym: The crowd at the recess was definitely the Gen Con crowd and not the dragon con or ConnectiCon or packs or any of that Crowd.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I have a feeling dragon con is also sort of the Gen Con crowd.
Scott: I think so But not as much as much a little bit different because Dragon Con has all these sort of different tracks.
Scott: I think dragon is technology.
Scott: It's got skepticism It's got all sorts of.
Rym: I would guess based on what my friends to go to Dragon Con say that half the gamers There are paxi kind of gamers and half the gamers.
Rym: There are Gen Con kind of game is anyway.
Scott: So is that all you did?
Scott: Saturday?
Scott: was you played the paranoia and that was it.
Rym: pretty much paranoia and dune and hanging out.
Rym: Sadly, you know Saturday night we all you know, the our games all ended We all got together and they had the cool party at this bar down the street.
Rym: So like oh, yeah, let's all go down.
Rym: We have a drink say hi to everyone then go home.
Rym: We go down there and the stupid bar wanted a $5 cover charge and not paying five bucks to walk in say hi and leave.
Rym: Yeah, especially considering that the bar for five bucks.
Scott: I can get like five candy bars.
Rym: Sadly the bar looked like it was general admission and all the other bars around weren't super crowded.
Rym: There was no real reason for that cover charge Except for the fact that they're trying to game five bucks off of all these gamers who wanted to.
Scott: there's no cover charge If we would have gone over earlier when the other people went over.
Rym: so the cover charge started right as the event We were all leaving ended.
Scott: Yeah, that's awesome.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know who's who is responsible for setting that up But not well executed apparently.
Scott: they just weren't that many other places to go like, you know, they didn't choose, you know It's like there was no real choice of place.
Rym: Yeah, I would have been having even on Sunday, right?
Scott: So on Sunday, I went out just looking for a place to eat, you know for lunch and it was surprised How many places were just closed?
Rym: Well that part of Brooklyn is definitely not super happy or sit-down What are you talking about?
Scott: That is like the Happeningist area in Brooklyn.
Scott: That's where all the shit is.
Rym: But right around there no bars.
Rym: No restaurants open on Sunday.
Scott: The restaurants are open there to sit down.
Scott: I'm talking about walk in get food lunch kind of place.
Rym: Oh, whatever.
Rym: I mean there was that muffin place.
Scott: Yeah, that's not really lunch.
Rym: That is dead paninis and all sorts of stuff.
Rym: That place was awesome.
Scott: Anyway, so on Sunday, I went back and in the morning I signed up to play Starfarers of Catan.
Rym: remember we played that that's a good game Except that it's kind of broken once you've played it too many times.
Scott: Yeah with the encounters Yeah, but if you don't know what the encounters do it's real fun I think is we sort of messed up the game.
Scott: We played it a little bit wrong, you know in that We deployed the beginning colonies like incorrectly or whatever.
Scott: But you know in remembering how to play I was like, oh, yeah this game is a good game.
Scott: And now I kind of want to like.
Scott: I think that that's really it, you know I've sort of wanted to play settlers, but then I keep remembering that like yes settlers is kind of broken and bad.
Scott: You know, it's like settlers itself sucks.
Scott: So I definitely I think I want to get back and try to do Star fairs or cities and nights and start playing that because you know to revive the settlers and thisness of it.
Rym: One thing that was interesting I kind of I miscalculated and that I hope to recruit a whole bunch more Pax East enforcers at this con or at this event.
Rym: So, you know, I went around I was talking to people and surprisingly almost everyone I talked to.
Rym: the conversation was along the lines of well What's Pax?
Rym: What's Pax East?
Rym: What do you mean it like e3?
Rym: What's e3?
Rym: Penny arcade like they did I there's a huge.
Scott: the thing is there what the there is.
Scott: I know that you know That's not everybody.
Scott: You didn't get like a goods.
Rym: No, it's not like.
Scott: I asked everyone to the con company when I was at the board game night.
Scott: There was a girl I talked to and she was there and she told me that she made like the first penny arcade website.
Rym: Wow I would pretty much say that I talked.
Rym: I asked about to 10 people 10 or 11 people and Two of them that I talked to.
Rym: you know, my small sample size Knew what was up and the rest of them had never heard any of these things.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: It was just interesting.
Rym: It's kind of like you go to an anime con and everyone at least knows what comics are and you go to like.
Rym: You go to like a bigger gaming con and like I had the trivia remember.
Rym: Oh, yeah The trivia.
Scott: so we do this trivia, right?
Scott: And so we're first we.
Scott: it's it's just front row crew people on a team.
Scott: But then we got some other people on.
Rym: it was great.
Rym: We named a team that had nothing to do with that.
Scott: We couldn't think of a team name.
Scott: So we went with the Ozamanga Diode team name of C cucumber.
Scott: But then they broke our team up because there are too many big teams.
Scott: So suddenly we were back to just FRC people again and some other team was team C cucumber, right?
Scott: But then the people that split up from us were no longer on team C cucumber.
Scott: So actually some people were on team C cucumber and none of them had chosen that name Right and our team ended up being named big fire.
Scott: but I think next time we have to go with experts of just I think experts of justice is a more Profound and awesome sounding name.
Scott: and then there was one guy who we didn't know who was on our team.
Scott: Also, however, he filled out a lot because we did not have the knowledge that he had.
Rym: round one was geek And pretty much every team got all of them, right or almost all of them, right?
Rym: Yep round two We had almost nothing because it went right into nerd.
Rym: We had we were done at that point.
Scott: Yeah, basically, we're like.
Scott: all the questions were like aimed at not us not us at all except the whole time.
Rym: We're like, wow, there's like no anime questions here at all.
Rym: We're pretty much boned unless they ask about like old-school gaming or old-school like anime.
Scott: and then they ask one question Hooked on okay and everyone our whole table is like what and the whole rest of the room is like what the fuck They went back to like.
Scott: what's the name of the do?
Rym: what's the name of this Harry Potter thing?
Rym: or what's the name of this?
Rym: Thing from the dark tower that I've never actually read.
Scott: Yeah, there's all these good.
Scott: There's questions about like wheel of time and stuff.
Scott: I mean Alex could cover some of the fantasy, but even he couldn't cover all of it.
Rym: Yeah, there's the one Silmarillion question, but it was deeper like it was such.
Scott: it was like What was the name of the dog they used to find like I don't fucking remember.
Scott: I read that book And I was yes, why can't the answer be a Luvitar?
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: I know you could have asked a hundred questions about the Silmarillion.
Scott: that would have gotten but they asked like.
Scott: You know one of the thousand questions I would not have gotten but at least that's.
Rym: what makes a good trivia is if they gave every question, you know 95 percent of the answer but only the true nerds know the extra five percent.
Scott: Yeah, it's like one of the asshole.
Scott: they had these asshole questions and one of them was like, you know name all the superheroes That were on this cover of this comic and I was like, uh, it was a defenders comic.
Scott: So I'm like trying to guess and I know some of the defenders.
Scott: I got like doctor strange, you know.
Scott: And the thing is like I probably could have gotten it with enough time, but it was just like duh Like they played a sound from a video game and they're like they didn't ask.
Rym: what video game is this.
Rym: they ask Specifically what action is happening right now?
Scott: Yeah, and the dig dug.
Scott: one like if they played a sound clip from dig dug.
Scott: that didn't sound like dig dug.
Scott: It sounded like you know frickin like space some space shooting game or something.
Scott: Yeah, even Rym didn't know it.
Scott: It was dig dug.
Rym: I know of course Honestly, I played dig does.
Scott: he would have gone like if they would have gone doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Rym: Then I would I had dig dug immediately, but that's the difference between a geek and a nerd question.
Rym: Yeah, and the other one he was burger time and I was like, it's just burger time, duh But I couldn't tell what the action was.
Scott: Yes, like is it?
Scott: is it when he's peppers the bad guy?
Rym: well, I thought it was peppers, but I realized I think what screwed me up there?
Rym: I Only really played burger time on the Intellivision.
Rym: Yeah, not on the arcade.
Scott: I totally bite you totally bite you.
Scott: but yeah We sucked ass at the trivia and we want if we had like some of our other FRC people's there we probably would have done a lot better.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah between like katsu Pete Nury You know cater Adam there.
Scott: They.
Scott: yeah, I mean why is the trivia master?
Rym: There was some old like Warhammer questions.
Scott: Yeah, we got like they were like what planet are the ultramarines from?
Scott: and like the one guy We didn't know when any FRC had any clue right but the random guy the strange guy He was like it was like lotrim are.
Scott: but no was ultramar.
Scott: It was like Pete would have had that in like a second.
Rym: Yeah, Pete in fact would have punched all of us for not knowing it.
Scott: Yeah that the ultramarines are from ultramar.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, we feel stupid.
Rym: But anyway, it was a good time.
Rym: It was really well run.
Rym: the questions were good.
Rym: I like the whole asshole question thing.
Rym: Oops banging into your microphone.
Scott: Yeah, my headphones banged into him.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know what else you have to say.
Rym: I just thought it was a super.
Scott: well I I need to talk about what I did and the reason I went back on Sunday.
Scott: The primary reason was Later on Sunday.
Scott: I basically felt like a complete moron waiting in the front of the registration line, you know But I did wait in that front of registration line.
Scott: I ran out to lunch came back and got in the front of the line.
Scott: Also everyone liked oshi who I played it with oshi was pretty popular because people didn't know it But they loved it when I played it with them.
Scott: but I signed up and played free market for reals with Jared and these three other dudes and I am prepared to to spill all sorts of beans about free market, which which beans would you like to be spilled?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm not sure what I want to know about the game.
Scott: Okay, basically the way free market goes is it's the new RPG from Lucre and Jed.
Scott: Jared Sorenson team up it.
Scott: The pre-orders are gonna be in March.
Scott: There's no dice and it goes something like this so you're on the space station and The space station gives you everything.
Scott: There's a computer on the space station, but it's not like Hal or the paranoia computer.
Scott: It just sort of is brain, you know, it doesn't have any motivation or anything.
Scott: it just sort of provides everyone with food in the basics and That's it.
Scott: So you have to get the idea.
Scott: the game is to get flow.
Scott: you got to get flow and the way you get flow Is by you know doing various things like.
Scott: you can friend people friending people, you know if people become your friends you get flow.
Scott: if you will give you like smiley faces or You know doing various things you can get flow, right?
Scott: so you got to get flow and So you have this character and your character has experiences interface Technology and memories and these things are what you use to get flow right and memories Turn into experience in this whole thing.
Scott: All right, so you basically All the people all the players join a mercy a Merc Z Right, and that is your group and your group has some sort of objective.
Scott: So it can just be whatever the hell you want.
Scott: Like you can just anything.
Scott: All right, so ours was like fucking teeth.
Scott: I think we called it like guts and gums and we're just like yet fucking teeth.
Scott: That's what we care about.
Scott: And I was a. I was like a a cyber athlete of sorts, you know.
Scott: And the other with jouster.
Scott: no, it was like we decide.
Scott: we just came up with shit on the fly.
Scott: so it was like it was called like schnoz ball or whatever and I didn't even make up what the sport actually was until I had to play it and what you know.
Scott: But basically, you know, you were playing this game and we're like, okay, how do we start?
Scott: So he's just like reading various like.
Scott: he starts off by telling us what we have in our like little Mercies area because space is a commodity like physical space is like rare because the space station was designed for 40,000 But there's 80,000 people.
Rym: So there's a movie.
Rym: there were 80,000, right?
Scott: So he's basically telling us like, you know This is the stuff you have right and we're like some and one of the things had to do with pets.
Scott: So suddenly we start the game by going we got to make a pet.
Scott: So we try to make this tooth fairy and The tooth fairy comes out all like nasty and gross and we're like, okay Well, let's let's make a movie with the tooth fairy.
Scott: That'll be like a wicked YouTube type meme and spread over the whole space station and somehow we managed to pull it off where the tooth fairy became wicked popular across the entire station.
Scott: and suddenly people start calling us up like, you know, we created this mean people wanted to get like these pliers and pouches to pull their Teeth out or whatever.
Rym: It all comes back to the Perry Bible Fellowship, right?
Scott: So we're like, oh shit We got to make these pliers and things.
Scott: So Basically, we realized that we all sweet.
Scott: None of us had the printing experience, which means it sucks.
Scott: We suck at making things which is why our tooth fairy came out all nasty.
Scott: So I Called up the guy who makes my sporting equipment, you know, and I'm like we need you to make this thing for us.
Scott: He's like, what are you gonna do for me?
Scott: So basically I had to like.
Scott: My rivals daughter was a fan of me.
Scott: So he wanted, you know, but my rival was also a customer of his and he wanted to make my rival happy.
Scott: So we took a memory out of me modified it and implanted it in my rivals daughter.
Scott: So now she liked her father and not me and then I was in a sporting event with her father and I ripped his fucking Basically blew his teeth.
Scott: I blew his skull in half and blew his teeth all over the crowd as we were Giving them all the pliers that they want.
Scott: So that's that's the kind of game that comes out of at a free market, but basically the way the game works is you have these cards and What the how you use how the challenges work use the cards to resolve the challenges and are really sort of crazy and incredibly difficult to understand way Which is I think a negative.
Scott: but at the same time he said that they did it that way on purpose.
Scott: So it's like they made the challenges intentionally complex.
Scott: but even though the way the challenges worked with these cards and the conflict resolution and how many cards do you draw and what Do they do?
Scott: and how do you figure out who wins?
Scott: Like you need like a reference sheet to learn figure this shit out like big time Even though that was really complicated for some reason.
Scott: the way the game worked the role-playing like came real easy.
Scott: if you couldn't tell you know, huh and Like, you know, basically everyone gets like one of these sort of like attaboy tokens.
Scott: That's sort of like, you know.
Scott: Yeah If someone else does something awesome you throw your token at them and the rule is you only get one token per session to give To someone else.
Scott: when you give it to someone they get flow But one person can only receive one token per session.
Scott: So if you do ten awesome things in this ten players, you can't get nine tokens.
Scott: You can only get one and you know, so Throughout the game like everyone threw their token at me at some point and I was after the first one I had to say like I already have one like three times.
Rym: Well, we're kind of used to the whole burning wheel, you know crazy gaming stuff already.
Scott: A lot of people aren't yeah But I definitely you know, I have the PDF for free market and if I could just get the cards I am totally prepared to run this game.
Scott: I think it is a game.
Scott: I could definitely run with awesomeness.
Rym: I imagine we'll be running a lot of impromptu games at PAX East and anime Boston.
Rym: We're just hanging around.
Scott: I'm definitely planning to run free markets at PAX East because I know that a lot of people like one.
Scott: I want to play it and there are not gonna be enough people running it.
Scott: So I will run free markets there once or twice and I'll definitely run it at Connecticut and such.
Scott: but yeah That's it's free market is what it is.
Scott: There's gonna be pre-orders in March and it's gonna be like a whole box with cards and a whole thing.
Scott: So it's good, you know.
Scott: Make sure you keep an eye out on the websites so that you get a copy when it is available.
Rym: All right on that note.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: Yep This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.