Rym: It's Wednesday July 28th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight, a-durrrrrrrrr.
Scott: We gotta redo that.
Rym: Dur-a-ra.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So, durr, that's durr.
Scott: I guess that's the noise Rym makes most of the time.
Rym: See, I realize the reason that is a bad way to introduce this show is that we could be talking about Rosa Versailles.
Scott: No, that's durr.
Rym: Well, that's if the P is silent.
Scott: Der is just Rym.
Rym: Well there's der, there's derp to der and there's derp to derp to der.
Scott: No, those are all you.
Rym: So we'll get into this.
Rym: You know, Otikons this weekend, we have news from the Comic-Con, but taking a cab home last night, right?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And I was talking to the cabbie and he owns his medallion.
Rym: Really?
Rym: He bought it like 20 years ago.
Scott: Wait, wait, wait.
Scott: So why, how did, how did you get to the point where he was actually telling you about this?
Rym: I was sitting in the front seat with him and he was like, "Hey, I'll drive you, but my credit card machine's not working.
Rym: I cannot take credit cards.
Rym: I will get in serious trouble if you want to pay with a credit card and you
Rym: can't.".
Rym: And we were like, "Well, we got it.
Rym: We got
Rym: cash.".
Rym: And he was totally cool.
Rym: We were talking about the city and then he's telling, you know, he lives in Queens.
Rym: He's like, "I've lived in Queens for like 40 years.
Rym: It's the best place in the world.
Rym: It's cool everywhere else.
Rym: Don't ever live anywhere
Rym: else.".
Rym: And yeah, apparently 20 years ago for like 50 grand, he got a loan.
Rym: He bought a yellow cab medallion.
Scott: So it's worth it, I guess.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: He said, yeah, he lives comfortably.
Scott: How much money can you make in one day with a cab though?
Rym: Well, it took him like 20 minutes to drive us home.
Rym: It was like 20 bucks total.
Rym: So about a dollar a minute.
Scott: Dollar a minute.
Scott: So that's eight hours of driving, assuming you do eight hours, times 60 minutes.
Scott: So $4,800 a day.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: Damn.
Scott: Why the hell am I doing this?
Scott: There's more behind me.
Scott: I don't make $4,800 in a week.
Rym: Because a medallion costs one to $4 million.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So if I pay one to $4 million, how long would it take to pay it off?
Rym: Remember interest, because you have to borrow that money.
Rym: You don't have one to $4 million.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: I had to do some maths.
Scott: Regardless, it's a lot of driving.
Rym: It was pretty cool.
Scott: If he's driving for 40 years, good deal.
Rym: So we realized we haven't done a Monday show and for fuck ever.
Scott: And we're not doing a Monday show right now either.
Scott: It's a Wednesday show.
Rym: We got an epic Monday show coming.
Scott: We haven't done a Wednesday show and forever.
Scott: So we haven't done a Monday show and fuck ever.
Rym: So we're back.
Rym: It's Wednesday.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: There's actually for once news in the animation industry.
Scott: Well, also in the comics and everything else, because everyone saves all their announcements for Comic Con.
Scott: I really, you know, some other people are saying the same thing.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Why do you save your announcement?
Scott: Like, what's the point?
Scott: Like, I don't get it.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: Some industries you want to announce when other people are not announcing unless your announcement is big enough to where people will forget about everybody else.
Scott: I mean, the problem is, right, is Comic Con is mostly movie shit nowadays, right?
Scott: And people are actually saying maybe we should split it into, you know, movie con and Comic Con, you know, because it's getting all over each other.
Scott: But anyway, regardless, if some guy's announcing like, oh, shit, we're going to make a movie about the superhero, that's going to be all over the news.
Scott: And your announcement of my new comic is coming out or, you know, is not going to be heard by anybody is right.
Scott: So you should just announce things.
Scott: as you know, when you have confirmed something like, ah, we have decided we will do this.
Scott: It is a lock.
Scott: We're doing it.
Scott: Announce it right then.
Scott: How about that day?
Scott: The day after the next convenient day?
Scott: You know, hold on to it until Comic Con, you know, and then put it out there.
Scott: And now it's lost in this big sea of people going.
Rym: But it could also be a kind of gentleman's agreement in the industry of we'll all announce our stuff at this event where it is traditional to do so.
Rym: Perhaps people who run conventions like this.
Scott: What is the benefit of choosing Apple in that situation?
Rym: Perhaps.
Rym: Remember, in the real world, unlike in just the prisoner's dilemma, you only really choose Apple when someone is bribing you with several additional apples.
Scott: So where are these additional apples?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe the comic industry.
Rym: I mean, I don't know.
Rym: I just your dismissal of the practice of the industry, while usually warranted, I can force.
Rym: I can see reasons why people might delay announcements or wait or give me a reason.
Rym: All right.
Rym: They want it.
Rym: They know that press will be there paying attention at Comic Con.
Rym: If they announce it another time, no one gives a shit.
Rym: No one even notices.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, if it's if it's a news about something that is not a movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Those press aren't paying attention anyway.
Rym: But at Comic Con, there is press that cares.
Scott: But if it is a comic or anime news, they're not going to pay attention anyway.
Scott: The only people that are going to pay attention are things like Anime News Network or Newsarama or any of the kind of news that you're thinking only of the above the radar fans, the below the radar people.
Rym: They probably barely know that Comic Con exists.
Rym: And then right after Comic Con, there's all this news.
Rym: And they suddenly start like looking at articles and seeing stuff.
Rym: And the rest of the year, they never even look.
Rym: So the news is all at once.
Rym: And then as a result, the nerds find out all at once.
Rym: These people would otherwise never find out.
Scott: Maybe there's a chance.
Scott: there's a chance that the normal under the radar fan could go to the nerdy websites all the reason soon after the comic.
Rym: It doesn't matter either way.
Rym: And you just pick that date because that's a nice date to kind of plan to do all your announcements and it's a nice tradition.
Rym: And you're not under any pressure because you're in an industry with very long cycles.
Rym: Well, of course, there was actually very important news from the Comic Con.
Rym: I mean, that guy got stabbed to death, I heard in Hall H.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: Well, Hall H, you know, H stands for hell.
Rym: Hall H is like the worst.
Rym: It's everything that I would hate about going to the Comic Con condensed into one hall.
Scott: Thing is, people talk about going to Comic Con and waiting in lines and waiting in lines.
Scott: It's like, dude, I mean, if you don't go to the Hall H, are you really waiting in any lines?
Scott: Just don't go to see any of that shit with the famous people and you won't have to wait in a line.
Rym: I'm looking at pictures of the Comic Con and it's just like you think that hallway in the middle of Otakon is bad.
Rym: Imagine that times 10.
Rym: It's like you can walk.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen pictures of the dealer's room and you can't really walk very much at all.
Scott: But even so, it's like, OK, you can't really walk that much in the dealer's room, but you can still, you know, cover it.
Scott: You don't have to wait in a line.
Scott: You can.
Rym: just Hall H is basically the room where, like, oh, shit, the trailer to the new Twilight movie is going to be shown at 141.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And then that's it.
Rym: And little things like that.
Rym: And the hardcore crazy fan just bust their way in.
Rym: Never leave.
Rym: Unless I can have some sort of bodyguard entourage bubble, I don't think I ever want to enter that hall.
Scott: Like what could possibly be in Hall H that would be worth in or in any hall that would be worth waiting in that ridiculous.
Rym: I mean, you're basically about free kisses from Patrick Stewart.
Scott: Big deal.
Scott: So I mean, like angry video game nerd, he was talking and like he went to see Penn and Teller and he had waited in line for that.
Scott: But I don't think it was Hall H. I think it was some other hall.
Scott: You know, the line wasn't that crazy.
Rym: It's a much better idea.
Scott: And he did get in.
Rym: We could have a Dagen H instead.
Scott: Oh, Dagen H. That's such an excellent H. You know what?
Scott: I think Comic-Con needs its own Dagen H.
Rym: As does Otakon.
Rym: Huh?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, imagine if you're waiting in the Otakon line.
Scott: The line to get your reg badge.
Scott: But that's not the line to get the badge.
Scott: That's because the badge was mailed to you.
Scott: Because this is Comic-Con International.
Scott: They mail the badge, right?
Rym: But then you get...
Scott: You have to wait in that line for every panel.
Scott: That's what Comic-Con is.
Scott: You're waiting in the line to get into Otakon.
Scott: You get your badge, but you're doing that multiple times.
Rym: I don't know how people deal with it.
Rym: But look at these pictures.
Rym: Every single person is smiling, except in one picture I'm looking at.
Rym: There's this really fat guy who looks really hot and uncomfortable.
Rym: And someone is trying to, like, shove their way around him.
Rym: And he does not look happy.
Scott: All right, well, let's talk about the stabbing.
Rym: So, basically, here are the details...
Scott: Stabbing.
Rym: So, the details that are relevant are that, one, the nerd media jumped all over this and lost its shit.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: It finally happened.
Rym: You know, violence at a nerd convention.
Rym: Someone got stabbed.
Scott: Yeah, dude, you should check out Akihabara.
Scott: They've got you beat.
Rym: So, here's what actually happened.
Scott: Ow.
Scott: Dang it.
Rym: And it is the tiny details that make this wonderful.
Rym: Like, for example, what panel it was that these two nerds were trying to see and what they were wearing.
Scott: Wasn't it the Resident Evil movie thing?
Rym: Yes, Resident Evil.
Scott: We saw the big cardboard setup for that at the movie theater.
Scott: It looked pretty terrible.
Scott: Had a panel.
Scott: All right, so that was in Hall H, right?
Rym: That was in Hall H.
Scott: Why would you wait in that insane line to see that?
Scott: What person is this?
Rym: They were already in the panel.
Rym: In fact, the panel was almost over.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So, near the end of the...
Scott: But, I mean, why would anyone wait?
Scott: Why was that in Hall H?
Scott: Why are there that many... Hall H, I assume, holds thousands, right?
Rym: Scott, the room was filled for this.
Scott: So, there were thousands of people there to see the Resident Evil movie something?
Rym: Scott, remember when we went to see Inception?
Rym: And there was that crazy line to get into the theater.
Rym: We're like, "Crap, we're not going to get a
Rym: seat.".
Rym: And then the theater's like, "No, that's the line for
Rym: Salt.".
Rym: Walked right in for Inception.
Scott: What the hell was Salt?
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: Angelina Jolie's spy movie.
Rym: It actually looks pretty good.
Scott: But, why would you wait in the line for that?
Rym: Your strangely righteous indignation surprises me.
Rym: I mean, I would wait in that line for free gold.
Scott: Are they giving out free gold?
Scott: I'm waiting in line.
Scott: I'll wait in line the whole con for the free gold.
Rym: Scott, beauty's in the eyes of the beholder.
Rym: And for some people...
Scott: You know what's more beautiful than any Resident Evil movie?
Scott: Free gold.
Scott: And you know what they don't got?
Rym: Free gold.
Rym: For some people, Resident Evil Afterlife, like that is the movie.
Scott: You know what I was waiting that line for to go into Hall H?
Scott: Zombie Will Eisner.
Scott: Or maybe Zombie Tezuka also.
Scott: That I would wait in line for.
Scott: That might be dangerous.
Scott: We have brought them back from the dead for you.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: Yes, you know.
Rym: So anyway, to get back to the news here, because we actually have a show to review.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Rym: So Hall H, Resident Evil Afterlife panel.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It's nearly over.
Rym: And a quote, "Altercation breaks out between two people who both are wearing the same limited edition Comic Con 2010 Harry Potter
Rym: t-shirts.".
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So one of them suggested that his friend, the person next to him, leave his seat because he wasn't into what was being shown.
Rym: So why don't you leave?
Rym: You obviously don't care as much as I care about Resident Evil Afterlife.
Scott: Who cares about Resident Evil Afterlife at all?
Rym: And the guy who was sitting down tried to stab him in the eye with a pen.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Scott: So there was a guy sitting next to him and he said, "Why don't you leave if you don't like
Scott: this?".
Rym: And something happened.
Rym: I don't have any details as to what happened.
Scott: I thought I heard that there was a guy trying to like, you know, who left and then he was saving a seat for a friend and a guy tried to sit in the same seat.
Scott: And that was what made the stabbing.
Rym: This is the most recent news I could find.
Rym: That the two people knew each other were wearing the same t-shirt, the limited edition Harry Potter Comic Con 2010 t-shirt.
Rym: And the best part is he didn't even get him in the eye.
Rym: He missed and just kind of scratched him a little bit.
Rym: The stabby was taken to the hospital and quote, "His injuries were non-life
Rym: threatening."
Rym: Really?
Scott: And the cool thing is- The worst part is you got to go to the hospital.
Scott: Not, you know, that you're hurt.
Scott: You waited all in that whole line for the stupid Comic Con.
Scott: You even got into the horrible Hell Hall H and now you have to leave for hours in the hospital waiting at the emergency room before you can come back.
Rym: He didn't even get to see the end of the Resident Evil panel.
Rym: But apparently all the- What happened to the stab-er?
Scott: Did he go to jail?
Rym: He was taken away by the police and to jail.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: Does he out of jail?
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: That seems like the sort of one night in jail kind of thing.
Scott: Not like a trial, go to court, go to prison kind of thing.
Rym: I don't know if I were the guy who got, you know, stabbed.
Scott: Yeah, but you really you can just press what?
Scott: Like an assault charge?
Scott: I'm not a lawyer.
Rym: No, I'd press like assault and intent to cause grievous injury.
Scott: It's not attempted murder because there's no way you could have murdered him with the pen.
Rym: Pen to the eye could probably kill you.
Scott: I don't know if it'd kill you.
Scott: You'd lose the eye.
Rym: Uh, far enough back.
Rym: Brain, right there.
Scott: Okay, the odds of that are pretty unlikely.
Scott: You know, the most likely scenario in a crowded Hall H is that the ambulance would come and you would lose your eye and you'd have a wicked cool limited edition Harry Potter glass eye for the next Comic Con.
Rym: I think they were selling them at the booth next to Hall H.
Scott: No, they were selling the Resident Evil movie glass eyes.
Rym: Once this nerd slap fight got out of control and after the pen came out, everyone else in the room freaking jumped the guy and held him down till the police got there and took him away.
Scott: That's how it's going to go every time.
Rym: Well, remember way back, this was like Otakon 2003.
Rym: That one guy like went nuts and attacked that girl that we knew.
Rym: What?
Rym: You don't remember that?
Rym: We were at Otakon.
Rym: We were in the back room talking to the staff because we just run like the club summit and we were trying to like join the Otakon staff way back then.
Rym: So we're like walking with a bunch of Otakon staff and talking to them about like our plans and let's do, it was either 2003 or 2004.
Rym: I think it was 2003 and we're like, like we're walking and we're like, yes, we've got it.
Rym: We're eating with the Otakon staff.
Rym: This is awesome.
Rym: And then we look up and I see like Pete and a bunch of our friends standing around a fight that has broken out and then they proceed to enter this fray and break it up.
Scott: I don't remember the details of this.
Rym: Do you remember this at all?
Scott: I remember there was something going on.
Rym: That's all you remember?
Scott: Like there was one dude who's wicked angry and he was related to somebody we knew maybe.
Rym: I'm just not, I'm leaving out the names for privacy reasons, but I'm surprised you don't remember who was involved.
Scott: I remember there was someone we didn't know who was all angry, who was related to someone we knew.
Rym: We knew who he was.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: Having some trouble here?
Scott: Oh, anyway.
Rym: What did you eat for lunch yesterday?
Scott: Yesterday?
Scott: Peanut butter and jelly.
Rym: Four days ago.
Scott: Peanut butter.
Scott: Well, four days ago was Sunday.
Rym: I think you've got Alzheimer's.
Scott: I didn't, I didn't eat lunch Sunday.
Rym: Uh huh.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Regardless, every nerd fight I've ever seen at a con has ended with someone intervening because it's really easy to intervene into nerd slap fights.
Scott: There aren't often fights where there's no intervention.
Scott: Well, these public fights, public fights.
Rym: That is the extent of the fullness of the knowledge of the stabbing in Hall H. Okay.
Scott: So his is a bunch of really tiny news that are more anime manga related, right?
Scott: Cause there were a bunch of comic news that were, you know, not manga, but you know what?
Scott: They all sucked.
Scott: So news number one, Eisner award winners, as is always at the comic con, right?
Scott: Only really important.
Scott: Well, I'm sure there are other important winners, but the most important winner, Yoshihiro Tatsumi's, uh, drifting life.
Scott: It won two, two Eisner awards.
Scott: What does that mean?
Scott: That means you should read it.
Scott: If you haven't read it, you suck.
Scott: Read it now.
Scott: No other manga has won any Eisner awards this year.
Scott: So Yoshihiro Tatsumi's a drifting life.
Scott: Go on Amazon, buy it or else you suck.
Scott: Two Eisner awards.
Scott: That means read it.
Rym: I think much more important.
Rym: I'm sure you're going to talk about this.
Rym: Some, uh, some important shows are released on DVD are going to be released on DVD.
Scott: Well, you know, the, uh, the galaxy express three, nine movie and also the second movie, which is just as awesome, right?
Scott: Have been on VHS and we're on sci-fi channel, but now they're finally going to be on DVD from discotheque media.
Scott: But discotheque is also releasing project ACO.
Rym: Holy crap.
Rym: That was in fact the third anime I ever saw.
Rym: And I think we talked about this like three or four years ago.
Scott: Express movie might've been the third anime I saw that.
Scott: It was that Saturday.
Rym: It was like vampire hunter D, robot carnival, project ACO, galaxy express.
Rym: Earth's answer to.
Scott: They're all old sci-fi channel stuff.
Rym: Kashawn, robot hunter.
Scott: Interestingly enough in the very same, um, announcement, they announced that they're going to release sword fighting.
Scott: Very good on DVD in the U S sort of fighting.
Rym: Very good was a mediocre movie with very good sword fighting.
Scott: And what I didn't know what it says here is that, uh, the princess blade reimagines a historical manga that is written by Kazuo Kami Mora and also Kazuo.
Scott: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Scott: I didn't know there was any connection between Kazuo Koike and sword fighting.
Scott: Very good article.
Rym: Doesn't say what that is though.
Scott: What is that manga?
Scott: Oh, historical manga.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: What is it?
Rym: Why did they not tell us this?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Um, yeah, but yeah, galaxy express movies.
Scott: Like I'm just going to buy them at like full price, whatever on Amazon.
Rym: project ACO too.
Rym: And I, as a kind of a shout out slash plug, you guys should go find, there's an old anime world order show where they reviewed project ACO and the history as to how and why project ACO was made is hilarious and independently.
Rym: project ACO is hilarious and independently, independently, anyone who watches project ACO before they turn like 11 will probably not understand that it is supposed to be a comedy.
Scott: You'll think it's a serious thing.
Rym: I thought it was a straight up like dead serious sci-fi.
Scott: Anyway, also, uh, interesting releases, right?
Scott: Drawn and quarterly.
Scott: Who's been doing some awesome releases of serious old high quality mangas, right?
Scott: Is releasing two mangas written by the creator of, uh, giga no Kitaro.
Rym: Ah, not the good Kitaro.
Rym: I prefer hakaba.
Rym: Anyway, it's the same guy.
Rym: I know, but it's not that gay, gay, gay Kitaro is kind of funny and Kitaro is hilarious or dark, depending on what kind of person is.
Scott: the same guy did both of them.
Scott: So this guy, uh, he did two other mangas that are coming out from drawn and quarterly.
Scott: One of them is called onward towards our noble deaths, which is a war manga, which is like, Oh my God.
Rym: That's a good title.
Scott: And the other one is non non ba, which is about a boy in the thirties.
Scott: Who's introduced to the world of, uh, you know, yokai and such, and he's going to see some awesome shit.
Scott: So apparently that manga won the award for best comic book at the uncle in 07, which if anyone doesn't know on glam is basically the, uh, comic con of Europe.
Scott: So if you that's, you know, if you're in Europe, it's like board games, Essen, comic con on glam.
Rym: Actually, randomly, one of my coworkers sent me an article about S and they were like, how come you don't ever go there every year?
Scott: And I was like, it's in fucking Essen.
Scott: Maybe we should go.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: Next year, Essen wants it.
Rym: Wait, this is dangerous because that's how we wait.
Scott: Maybe Essen is still this year.
Rym: Fuck.
Rym: I can't go this year.
Rym: I got too much planned.
Scott: We'll get, we're going to go to.
Scott: if, if Essen is this year still, and it hasn't happened yet, we're not going, but the Essen of 2011, watch it's on the same weekend as packs.
Scott: Then we won't go.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But if it's just, you know, Essen, we'll go on.
Scott: Let's go to Essen.
Rym: So briefly, but you know what?
Scott: If we go to Essen, let's also go and look at German castles and such and such and such.
Rym: If I'm going to Europe, I'm taking at least a week off work.
Scott: Probably two.
Rym: Thing is if it's in the spring, I'm going to Japan in the spring.
Rym: So we'll, we'll see.
Scott: We'll see when the Essen is, but let's, I don't even know.
Scott: I just, that's all right.
Rym: A tiny bit, but this is worth discussing later, maybe in the forum, maybe on another show.
Rym: But the guy who wrote Cowboy Bebop Daisato Sato said that basically said the anime industry sucks now and it's going to die within a few decades.
Rym: Obvious.
Rym: He has a lot of interesting reasons why, and it's mad props to him for having the balls to speak up.
Rym: But I'll point something out.
Scott: Say everything we already know.
Rym: He said, you know, there are anime now that are still fighting these stagnating trends.
Scott: There, there sure are.
Rym: Eden of the East and Ergo Proxy.
Scott: They're all, they're all in no automata.
Rym: And we started watching both of those.
Rym: Didn't finish them.
Scott: I feel like that block get canceled or not.
Rym: I don't know, but I feel like I'm just going to buy Ergo Proxy.
Rym: We got to watch all of it.
Rym: Start from the beginning.
Scott: I'm watching Eden of the East right now.
Scott: I watched the first episode a long time ago, but now I'm rewatching.
Rym: I rewatched episode one yesterday and I guess episode two today, but I'm not going to talk about the rest of the, like the impetus of his article.
Rym: I want to point out one thing that was unpointed out by many people talking about this.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Eden of the East and Ergo Proxy, the two shows that he says, yes, they're fighting the good fight, have something very important in common.
Scott: that he wrote them.
Rym: He wrote both of them.
Scott: Even so though, he is, he is, uh, you know, he writes, he writes the good animes.
Scott: What can you say?
Rym: So things of the day, what do you got for me, Scott?
Scott: Oh, you want to know what I got?
Scott: Even though mine is vastly superior.
Scott: So one of the greatest anime voice actors of all time, maybe not if the greatest.
Rym: Well, it's either pumpkin head or a door.
Scott: No idea.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So he is awesome.
Scott: Uh, and what I did not realize is I don't know if this is a meme or if he's actually doing this, I cannot tell, right?
Scott: Either way.
Scott: It's a thing of the day.
Scott: That is awesome.
Scott: What do you, what we got here is there are multiple videos on YouTube that are Norio Wakamoto doing the opener to some anime.
Scott: So here's Norio.
Scott: Wakamoto sings, Evangeline opener.
Scott: Well, Rio for good channel opener.
Scott: So, but the one that is my thing of the day is Norio.
Scott: Wakamoto sings lucky star opener.
Scott: That is my thing of the day.
Scott: Oh, snap.
Scott: You got to see this shit and well hear this shit.
Scott: Also this actually some legitimate, uh, documentaries, at least, uh, interviews with Norio Wakamoto on YouTube that you should totally check out and, uh, plenty of other scenes, uh, where you can hear him.
Scott: Doing awesome things like, you know, speaking in English as, uh, as the, the Catholic in Hellsing or being Chiyo's dad or whatever else he's doing.
Rym: So that is pretty awesome.
Scott: It's all about Norio Wakamoto today in Scott's thing of the day.
Rym: I have for you a list of the 10 most famous penises in the land.
Scott: It's got Ruben.
Rym: Maybe Juan Batista dos Santos.
Scott: That was me in a past life.
Rym: You know what his deal was?
Scott: It was so big.
Rym: No, no.
Scott: You wrapped around the world.
Scott: That's why everyone knew it was so famous.
Rym: Daddy to PP.
Rym: Both functional.
Scott: For serious.
Rym: For serious.
Scott: Did the P come out both?
Rym: Uh, actually it talks about that.
Rym: Here's a real picture of the double penis.
Scott: Was it actually two penises or they were separate?
Scott: or was it they had, he had?
Scott: just, they were separate or is just the hose had a Y splitter.
Rym: Now they were separate.
Scott: Really?
Scott: So he could actually, maybe he had to pee on the right and then maybe later.
Rym: actually the story as to who he ended up having a relationship with is quite amazing.
Scott: Oh wow.
Rym: He could probably, he could do the shocker, but, but that's, there's the, uh, the half millimeter penis that caused a children's book from Germany to be banned in America.
Scott: Rym was, Rym was the model for that.
Rym: Dirk Diggler.
Rym: And it goes on from there.
Rym: It's an interesting list.
Rym: The only, there's one disturbing one toward the end too.
Rym: If you count John Wayne Bobbitt and Rasputin's penis is either very large or that is actually some sort of root vegetable.
Scott: I doubt that that is actually Rasputin's penis.
Rym: If it is, they ripped out a sizable portion of that man.
Scott: Well, you know, if you, depending on which tail you believe, I mean, they would have had access to the entire body.
Rym: So, so the meta moment I suppose is in order.
Rym: Otakon is this weekend.
Scott: We won't be there.
Rym: This is the first time in almost a decade that we have not been to eight Otakons in a row.
Scott: This would have been number nine.
Rym: You almost said Otakon.
Scott: Otakon.
Rym: You said Ana.
Rym: No, I get to this day.
Rym: It amazes me when someone will say Otakon.
Scott: Well, it doesn't mean there's that guy in metal gear, right?
Scott: And they always get confused.
Scott: But it's Adam.
Rym: It's our friend Adam who does it.
Scott: He's been to Otakon for- It's Otakon and it's for Otaku, right?
Scott: It is a kon of Otaku.
Scott: So it's Otakon.
Rym: It's for American Otaku.
Rym: Yes, but you know- We have a slightly different definition of the word.
Scott: It's Otaku Otakon.
Rym: Yeah, but Otakon is this weekend, the 31st and 1st.
Rym: You know, we're not doing any panels at it and we'll see what we do next year.
Rym: But one thing I will note for those of you who are going.
Rym: They don't mail the badges.
Rym: The line on Thursday is very long.
Scott: The line on Friday is worse.
Rym: Yes, there is going to be likely a severe thunderstorm in Baltimore Thursday while everyone's going to be in line trying to get their badges.
Scott: Bring your umbrella.
Rym: If there is a thunderstorm, I suggest to you.
Rym: But I also suggest not to listen to me because I'm not liable if you get struck by lightning.
Rym: Do not get out of that line because the Friday line will be a disaster.
Rym: It always is.
Scott: Yeah, it is rain Thursday.
Scott: No matter what.
Scott: If there's rain on Thursday, a lot of people will probably leave the Thursday line.
Scott: This is just, you know, logic, right?
Scott: And they'll go to the Friday line where there won't be rain.
Scott: You do not want to do this.
Scott: The Thursday line, you will succeed in getting your badge.
Scott: But the Friday line, the Friday line is multi hours already.
Rym: Now, imagine if half the people on Thursday and they get like 10 to 14,000 people on Thursday.
Rym: If even a quarter of them get in the Friday line.
Scott: And also a recommendation, you know, shortly towards the middle of the day on Friday, what's going to happen is the lines will pretty much be gone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, the whole registration area sort of opens up and you can walk through there easily.
Scott: As soon as that happens, go get your 18 plus wristband for violent movies, because otherwise you're gonna have to wait.
Scott: If you wait until right before the violent movies, you're probably going to miss some of them waiting in that stupid line to get your wristbands.
Scott: to get your wristband early in the day.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Oh, God.
Rym: We don't have as much other advice we should really give.
Scott: There's going to be a lot of actually there's going to be a lot of awesome stuff at Otakon.
Scott: That's not us.
Scott: None of it's going to be us.
Scott: So you should check it all out.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Like Yoshida Brothers.
Scott: Check that out.
Scott: Artist Allie.
Scott: Violent movies late at night.
Scott: Check that out.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But I will say if you have any feedback about Otakon that you want them to know, like say you wanted them to mail the badges or you want to know why we weren't there or you wanted Daryl Surratt to have panels or you wanted Super Art Fight to do their awesome show.
Rym: instead of Iron Artist's somewhat lame show, you should go to the con feedback because that is like the only time where Otakon really gets feedback.
Scott: And even if you don't want to give feedback at the at the Otakon feedback session, they also show the winners of the AMV contest.
Scott: So don't waste your time at the real AMV contest.
Scott: Yeah, forget that thing.
Scott: Go see the winners at the closing ceremonies and also they will announce the dates of the next Otakon.
Rym: So you can then get the hotel early and ruin it for everybody else like we always do.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: And they will also announce, I think, the attendance figures usually.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And they'll show probably the opening and closing animations for the con again.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: We're not going to get to see him because they always they keep them under lock and key.
Rym: I know I've been I've been trying to find a bootleg copy of any of them.
Scott: And I think it is not going to be this way.
Scott: We've seen them all the first two, but we're not going to see this one.
Rym: Well, from the staff forum, I know a lot about the animation this year.
Rym: Yeah, but it's pretty high quality.
Scott: Probably.
Scott: But we're not going to see it because they don't show it anywhere else.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: I'm pushing to get New York Comic-Con to start having its own animation.
Scott: Dude, you just got to put your freaking opening animation on YouTube because it's a great advertisement for your Japanese.
Rym: People are stupid about that sort of thing.
Scott: So you just smack them upside the head.
Scott: You say, oh, yeah.
Scott: Oh, well, you know, you don't let us show on YouTube.
Scott: We're just not going to show it at all.
Scott: Why did we put all that hard work into it?
Scott: Well, you know, we can't show it on YouTube.
Scott: So what the hell is the point?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: You can find on YouTube.
Scott: Oh, thank you.
Scott: That's a Japanese one.
Rym: All right.
Rym: The book club is done.
Rym: So, you know, the next book club book is the way we have.
Rym: This is a new announcement is going to be a Ray Bradbury collection of short stories.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: We'll do a show on it later, but you should read some Ray Bradbury.
Scott: Which, which book though?
Scott: Should I even really say people are just going to go start buying random ones and they're going to get the wrong one.
Rym: And then red apples of the sun or golden apples of the sun.
Scott: You don't know how to remember.
Scott: That's why you fail.
Scott: I've never heard of it.
Scott: So I've heard of Ray Bradbury, but I've never heard of either.
Rym: Have you read any of Ray Bradbury stuff?
Scott: Fahrenheit 451.
Rym: Any of his short stories?
Rym: Fahrenheit 451 is pretty short.
Rym: He tends to write like four to five page short stories.
Scott: Oh no.
Rym: Most of the ones are like, here's the concept.
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: Maybe you should turn some of them into RPGs.
Rym: Like one of them in this is let's go back in time and kill a fucking dinosaur.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Scott: Also the New York Comic-Con New York anime festival, October 8th, 9th, and 10th.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And we will be there in force doing crazy shit.
Rym: Also that weekend nerd NYC board game night, Friday, October 8th.
Rym: Also that weekend, 8th, 9th, and 10th, 10, 10, 10, the burning wheel convention in Astoria.
Rym: Also in New York city, labor day weekend packs.
Rym: We are doing big shit at packs.
Rym: We cannot announce it yet.
Rym: We've been, there've been a lot of hints.
Scott: We've been talking about the packs.
Scott: It is going to be boom explode.
Scott: Cause there'll be so much awesomeness contained in the small area.
Scott: And that's not even.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: Next year PAX East is, I mean, this is cruise missile.
Scott: We're talking about here, but next year PAX East is going to have to bring the nuke in order to, to, to step up the game.
Scott: It's basically, it's basically like a one upsmanship between the East and the West every year.
Scott: The one is going to be better than the other was in the previous year.
Scott: So the most recent packs will always be the best packs.
Rym: Maybe that's their plan.
Rym: So every year Tycho can say at every con, this is truly the real packs.
Scott: That is correct.
Scott: Except the East is the real packs.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Um, but no, we live in the East.
Rym: We're doing egregiously unrealized potential.
Rym: We're also doing our home or hardcore panel game mechanics and mechanism design.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Are you ready?
Scott: Are you ready for something?
Scott: I got one more new announcement and we're done with the meta moment.
Rym: Is this something I know about?
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: One week after PAX West in New York city is recess on Saturday all day in a, what is it?
Scott: Manhattan something, something they call the same place.
Scott: The same place.
Scott: There's going to be a full day of board and role playing games courtesy of nerd NYC.
Rym: Uh, I'll probably, I might run an RPG.
Scott: I'm debating what to do in the board game by popular request.
Scott: We have to sign up for it with everyone else.
Rym: I will sign up for it.
Scott: It'll be full.
Rym: I mean, if I run a game, I can sign up before everyone else.
Scott: So in the other time slot, I think you sign up for your own game before everyone else.
Rym: I don't think you sign up that one of the perks of running a game is you can sign up for another game before everyone else gets a crack at it.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: You didn't remember that or you didn't do that last time.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Scott: Ah, I don't think that.
Scott: I think that may be a new rule.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: I remember that being the rule last time.
Scott: Oh, we'll see.
Scott: I don't know if that's a rule or not, but anyway, that is the end of the meta moment.
Rym: So there, we often don't talk about newer anime.
Rym: I mean, right now I'm watching Hokuto no Ken and watching all of Leiji Matsumoto's works.
Scott: Uh, I've finished watching space symphony Mitel.
Scott: So now I'm watching Eden of the East and I'm trying to get gun frontier.
Rym: Well, I'm going to get on DVD and I'm going to get ergo proxy.
Rym: We can burn through that and do a show on it, but a new anime that's worth talking about.
Rym: And many of you are watching it now before we review it, we're not going to spoil anything.
Scott: We already did a preview of it, but we didn't really.
Scott: It was basically, we talked about one episode.
Scott: Now we've seen, we've seen the whole show, both of us.
Scott: So now we can do a real show on it.
Rym: And what I'll say is that you shouldn't even need to listen to this.
Rym: You should be watching Dora.
Scott: It is if you haven't watched it already, in which case you should have watched that.
Rym: It is a timeless anime forever because it is too soon.
Rym: I am too close to it.
Rym: We can't put it in anime.
Scott: You should say, I don't think it's, I don't think it's that good.
Rym: No, but we can't put it in anime.
Rym: You should see or anything just because it's too new, but you should watch it.
Rym: Jesus Christ.
Rym: Should you watch it?
Rym: Especially if you're one of those people.
Rym: And this happens to a lot of anime.
Scott: If you're tired of moe shows and you're tired of shounen fighting shows.
Rym: Very specifically, if you watched a lot of anime in the past and you've started to fizzle out as an anime fan, for whatever reason, this show will basically kick you in the nuts right back into anime.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: This is, this is the good kind of show that we're always looking for.
Rym: So Dora is by the same guy, or at least directed by the same guy who did Bakano.
Rym: And there are very similar shows.
Rym: In fact, there's a cameo for Bakano in Dora.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: There's a couple, there's a couple of references to Bakano in Dora.
Scott: But the thing is Dora, Dora, I think it's Dora, Dora, Dora, Dora, Dora, Dora, right.
Scott: And it's not, it's just annoying.
Scott: And you're just making yourself sound retarded.
Scott: Anyway, the reason it's called Dora, Dora, Dora is because that's, it's an onomatopoeia for, you know, a motorcycle.
Scott: And there is a very important character riding motorcycle all around town.
Scott: So it's like, dude, you know, uh, it's based on some visual novels as many animes and mangas are.
Rym: And unlike the usual situation, when something is based on a visual novel or an anime, the anime is moving slow enough to where there's no filler.
Scott: There, it's not like they, well, it's not a matter of moving slowly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I think the visual, from what I understand, I could be wrong, is that the visual novels are all done.
Scott: And there's so many of them that I think maybe five or six ish.
Scott: And the anime basically covers the material of the first two.
Scott: So you have half of the half of the season, like the first 12 or 13 episodes, basically cover volume one and the rest of the show covers volume two.
Scott: And then you don't get volume three, four or five and so on.
Scott: They're not animated.
Scott: So that's that.
Rym: Of course, I get the impression that this was very popular, so we'll see what happens.
Scott: Hopefully, hopefully they will just continue to turn the visual novels into anime because I can't read the visual.
Rym: Tell there's no AV.
Scott: At the very least, maybe I've, you know, quite a few visual novels have been brought out in the U.S.
Scott: Translated.
Scott: Not that many, but you while I would read this one, if they if they try, I haven't bought any of them yet, but if they translated this one, I would buy it if they actually came out with all the volumes, just because I want to know what happens.
Rym: So I look forward also to what things in the future, because Takahiro Omori, the guy who directed Bakano and he's definitely he's going to do another show.
Scott: He's done two successful shows so far.
Rym: Not only that, look at his credits.
Rym: He is one of the old guard people who clearly worked under other people and learn the trade the old way.
Scott: What else did he work on?
Rym: He he did like animation for X driver.
Rym: He was the series director.
Scott: X driver.
Rym: For Fancy Lala.
Rym: All right.
Rym: He did a Lupin.
Scott: If you haven't done a Lupin, you're not an anime.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: The thing that we always look for.
Rym: And this is the secret.
Scott: Even Steve Bennett did Lupin.
Rym: If you find a guy who directed something and you see that he did like the key animation for a bunch of old stuff.
Rym: He's probably one of the protege's.
Rym: He did the key animation for one of the Ursa Yatsura movies.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And he directed a bunch of other stuff and he's all over the place.
Rym: But I think he is that these two are the, you know, Dora and Bakano are the shows where he is finally like, I'm directing and I will continue to direct stuff like this until I die.
Scott: I look forward to his next work, which I hope actually comes to be.
Scott: And I hope he is not fired.
Rym: Go back and watch the end of Fancy Lala.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Scott, he was the series director.
Scott: Oh, I will.
Scott: I will let you go tell me the secret of the dinosaurs.
Rym: He storyboarded the first and last episodes.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: He also directed the first and last episode.
Scott: When you figure out the secret of the dinosaurs, just come tell me.
Rym: You realize once I know the secret of the dinosaurs, I'm going to tell you that I know it and I'm not going to tell you it.
Scott: I'll just stab you with a pen near the eye, but kind of miss.
Scott: While I'm wearing my limited edition.
Rym: Unlike Dora, Bakano, you know, if someone has seen none of it and you're trying to tell them what it's about without spoiling anything or spoiling kind of the big reveals of the show or even the early kind of, oh, that's what the show's like.
Rym: Bakano is very easy.
Rym: It's about, you know, immortal gangsters who are awesome.
Rym: Let's rock.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: Dora is about a bunch of people living in a district of around Tokyo, like an urban area, Ikebukuro.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I just, it's not relevant and interesting things happen.
Scott: Well, more, more in, I think a better explanation is that there are people that live in Ikebukuro and things are pretty interesting because it's a happening kind of place, but there's all these urban legends and they're real, but they're real.
Scott: All of them.
Scott: So it's like people always whispering about the, oh, the, there's a secret gang called the dollars.
Scott: Yeah, there really is.
Scott: Uh, oh man.
Scott: There's a, there's a headless biker.
Scott: Yeah, there really is.
Scott: You know?
Rym: And it's like, or that black Russian guy who sells the sushi.
Rym: He is crazy dangerous.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: He really backstory.
Rym: Shizu Oh, dressed like a bartender.
Rym: Fucking beats people to death.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Right there.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, he does.
Scott: He's crazy.
Scott: Super strong.
Scott: You know, and it's, it's basically, you mix, you take these urban legends, you know, they're not, I don't know if these are real urban legends.
Scott: I've never heard of them before.
Scott: So it's like they made up a bunch of urban legends for the show.
Scott: And then they all have something supernatural in nature and they're all for reals.
Scott: And you have this huge cast of characters like you have in a movie like snatch and they all get mixed up in all sorts of different directions as crazy things happen.
Scott: And you know, there isn't really a quote, main characters.
Scott: Some are more main than others.
Scott: Some have the spotlight more than others argued that seltie is the main care.
Scott: It can also be argued that the main character.
Rym: So, or you could argue that there are two main characters.
Rym: The first is seltie because she is like the overarching plot driver.
Scott: She's also the driver of the time, but some of the time she's barely in it.
Rym: But, but she's still like, her story still ties them together in, in many, many ways.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But the other main character is the, the triumvirate of the three characters.
Scott: Well, there's also right.
Scott: Isiah, who is like the bad guy, but he's like always in everyone's business, you know, it's like, no matter which, no matter which of the plots is going on, he's always into it.
Scott: He's got his hands in there.
Scott: So could it be, you know, really, it's like, he's never way in the front, but that's just cause they don't want to reveal all his secrets, but he's always there.
Scott: It's like the supporting guy who's, you know, if he's there all the time and all these other main people have a greater spotlight, but they come and go, maybe he's equal to them in, you know, mainness.
Rym: But it's a show that moves very quickly sometimes and slowly at other times.
Rym: But the end result is it's not a show that's easily predicted.
Rym: You can predict like certain major plot points, like you can with any show, but the show will kind of just story for a loop.
Rym: or they'll ask a question like, what is the secret of the, Oh, it's this.
Rym: Now what?
Scott: And the other thing is that there's a lot of times where you know something, but different characters don't know it.
Scott: So it's like, Oh, he knows, I know all these things, but he only knows this subset and he only knows this subset.
Scott: And all, if only these characters would all just tell each other what I know, they all know that they know that the other person doesn't know that they know.
Rym: So at the end of the first story arc, there's one big reveal of, Oh, that's not so and so that's so and so I didn't see that one coming.
Rym: I did that when that, when that whole reveal happened, basically it comes down to a bunch of people standing around going, what the fuck?
Scott: There's pretty much really, there was pretty much only one thing and I predicted it way early and the proof is in the forum.
Scott: And did in fact predicted, I predicted it absolutely 100% way early and everything else I didn't predict.
Scott: So I got, I got one, but it was a big one and no one else got it.
Rym: So who should watch the show before?
Rym: we, you know, have a little.
Scott: everybody except except very small children and maybe old people won't like it.
Rym: I think small children would like at least the first season about like two year olds.
Rym: It's pretty and colorful and stuff's going around.
Scott: It's kind of dark stuff's lying around.
Scott: I was like 10 year olds and up from 10 to like, you know, I mean old people should watch it, but they probably won't like it.
Scott: So maybe like 10 to 60 year olds.
Rym: I was eight when I saw vampire hunter D and I loved it.
Rym: My little brother was five, five, I don't know.
Rym: He loved it.
Rym: Vampire hunter D was the best thing ever when he was five years old.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, I don't know.
Scott: He's going to really understand what's going on when he's five.
Rym: Just colorful, just colors running around.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But you can get more colors if you watch Pokemon.
Scott: Or, uh, that's got way too many colors.
Scott: Stick with the Doraemon when you're five.
Scott: In fact, stick with Doraemon until you're like in second, third, second, third grade.
Rym: Just don't watch Doraemon.
Scott: Dude, there's your, there's your mashup.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: He just Doraemon shows up and he takes off her helmet and it's just Doraemon.
Rym: So not to spoil anything, but this helicopter straight up and the way the show goes is, you know, there's the first episode and the second episode are really cool and they set up all this stuff.
Rym: But then the mystery is who is the headless rider?
Rym: What's the deal?
Rym: Is she really headless right away?
Rym: They answer that straight up and she is just a character from that point forward.
Scott: It's like, it's like, Ooh, there's a mysterious headless rider.
Scott: Then like w w like episode four or five.
Scott: It's like the headless rider.
Scott: Hello.
Rym: She's just cool.
Scott: I'm hanging out in my house.
Scott: I'm the headless rider.
Rym: She's scared of aliens.
Rym: She talks to people with an iPhone.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, what's up?
Scott: Someone's like, they don't like, it's not like one of the other characters discovers it.
Scott: It's like this.
Scott: Suddenly there's an episode just focusing on that character and just reveals all at least reveals most.
Rym: And then later someone's like, show me what's under your helmet.
Rym: She was like, okay.
Rym: And he's like, Oh, okay, cool.
Scott: All right, let's go.
Scott: I see what's under that helmet.
Rym: I see what you did there.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So I don't know how the helmet stays on.
Scott: That's my problem.
Rym: Well, she, her clothes, everything else stays on and half of it was formed by her magic.
Scott: That's cause she has a body.
Rym: But she forms her clothes with magic.
Rym: Remember?
Scott: Oh, right.
Rym: She makes all those other helmets.
Scott: No, that's right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: I forgot about that.
Scott: Magic.
Scott: He has a lot of magic in this show.
Rym: Not as much as you'd think, unless you count the internet as being magic.
Scott: The internet is magic.
Rym: It's funny cause you know, some characters like Salty has powers straight up and she's a little of the strong guy.
Rym: Technically.
Rym: It's not so much that he has powers, but she's just kicked so much ass.
Scott: It's so awesome.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: Some awesome people cosplaying issues as well.
Scott: And it's actually cool cosplay.
Scott: Cause instead of carrying around a big stupid sword, you carry on like a signpost or whatever, or like the railroad sign.
Scott: I saw some guys at Connecticut doing that.
Scott: cosplay is pretty good.
Rym: Plus his, I love his backstory and there's a scene where he gets, I can't spoil it, but it's awesome.
Rym: You should watch this show.
Rym: Anyone will like this show.
Rym: It's a cowboy beboppy show.
Rym: We're pretty much, it's not quite as good as not in terms of goodness, but in terms of it's fun, it takes you along for a ride.
Rym: It's both serious and funny.
Rym: Good start.
Rym: Good soundtrack.
Rym: It kind of fades into the background.
Rym: Just accents the point.
Rym: It's no, uh, Yoko Kanno soundtrack, but it's there.
Rym: The openings, the first opener I really, really like.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Second opener.
Scott: The only thing I can say that's negative about the show really is that it pulls the Prince of nothing right away.
Rym: They're like, there's going to be a holy war and the whole series ends.
Rym: And it's basically, we're almost at the holy war.
Scott: Well, I think it's because you're only getting two.
Scott: That was the negative thing is you're only getting two of the light novel.
Scott: So you're not getting the whole story.
Scott: So even though each individual light novel sort of wraps itself up and at the end of series, you get closure.
Scott: You don't get the full closure because you only have two out of X parts, you know?
Scott: So it's like, if you're watching the star wars, any individual star wars movie stands on its own and has an ending to itself.
Scott: But if you only watch episode four and you don't watch five and six, it's like, well, like we don't get any ending here.
Rym: Look at, uh, you know, the Lord of the rings, the first movie, or much more importantly, if the empire strikes back stands on its own, except as a kid watching that, not having seen like all of the first movie and not knowing there was the third movie, that ending is basically what the fuck?
Rym: Really?
Rym: That's how it ends.
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: No one won and they just run away.
Scott: Cause I know that guy's on.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: When my dad was like, there's a third movie, you know, Okay.
Rym: But before we move on to a couple of spoilers, I'll say this, the dirt has a plot in the kind of the first 13 episodes or so that resolves itself in a very satisfying way and answers many, but not all of the questions.
Rym: The second season raises a whole different set of questions and answers most of them.
Scott: The first season, you know, relies a lot on the fact that it's introducing all these characters.
Scott: So it can make most of the plot being revealing the characters.
Scott: Once all the characters are revealed, the rest of the series is about the conflicts between the characters unfolding and switching and whatnot.
Rym: It works because every character in this show is the short guy wearing a white suit in that Simpsons episode with the Chinese and the Yakuza and all the fighting.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Because every character is kind of just there.
Rym: And then they have their moment where you find out how completely crazily bad-ass or scary they are or both bad-ass crazy.
Rym: I think my favorite characters are the van people.
Scott: They're pretty good.
Rym: Like all of them together because they compete with Russian sushi.
Rym: I don't know the tasty, the van people are just like, yeah, let's go.
Scott: But then there's the head guy.
Scott: What's it?
Scott: I forget his name, but he's just, he's just awesome.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then there's the two, the Otaku in the back of the van.
Rym: But they're crazy awesome when they want to be.
Scott: But there's the fourth guy in the van.
Scott: It's like, what?
Scott: He's just sort of there.
Rym: He's the van driver.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, what's, I don't know.
Scott: I don't get his deal.
Rym: He's the, he's the initial D drive and getaway guy.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: The show is great.
Rym: So we're going to spoil some shit about the first season now, just so we can talk about it to make this worthwhile.
Rym: The people who listen to our preview and already watched the show.
Rym: So spoilers, spoilers, spoilers.
Scott: Oh my God, everybody dies.
Scott: And the show resets.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It was all just a fucking dream.
Scott: So anyway, the thing that I predicted correctly, right.
Scott: Was that a Mikado is the head of the dollar.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And that was, it was so obvious because completely normal guy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you have this whole, during the show, there's always this internet typing going on.
Scott: And he comes into town and he's totally boring, but there's this dollars thing.
Scott: And it's like, oh, well, obviously this normal guy, right.
Scott: There has to be something about him.
Scott: That's crazy secret.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: Just like there is for every other character in the show has a secret.
Scott: And he's the only one who doesn't look like he has a secret.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: But the only thing in the show that isn't already attached to somebody is the dollars.
Scott: It's like, well, what's the dollars.
Scott: It's this thing.
Scott: Obviously that secret.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: That's just sort of unattached attaches to the guy without any secret.
Scott: That's, that's just there.
Scott: That's how it goes.
Scott: You know, everyone else has something to go with already.
Scott: That is, you know, already, they're already got their stick.
Scott: He didn't have a stick.
Scott: There's a stick without a person.
Scott: The person with no stick stick with a person.
Scott: Boom.
Scott: Done.
Rym: But also I like how, you know, people all have these kind of powers, whatever they may be.
Rym: And his power is basically.
Rym: Fortune.
Scott: It's a good power to have, especially when it actually works.
Rym: It makes it really interesting the way he used it.
Rym: Like that was the moment when the show went from just being really, really fun to also being like really, really well executed.
Rym: the way he uses the fortune power and the end of that, you know, and then all the reveals happen.
Scott: But then in the second half of the show, he starts to use it a little more frivolously.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: Still to great effect, but not like the first time.
Rym: Well, the first time that moment, just when everyone's looking at their phones and then they all look up and all the people who aren't looking at their phones, they're like, uh.
Rym: It's kind of a, that's the way the world is and is going to be.
Scott: I hope so.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Fortune.
Scott: The other thing I thought was really interesting was the whole psycho thing, right?
Rym: It's like that I did not expect.
Rym: When she got away and I was like, how the fuck did she get away?
Rym: But I didn't think maybe I should try to figure it out.
Rym: I just thought how the fuck.
Rym: And then when they revealed, oh, duh.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the thing that got me is that it's like, okay, someone's possessed by an evil sword, right?
Scott: But it's like, it's not the typical situation when you have that.
Scott: Usually when someone's possessed by an evil thing, it's like the one ring, right?
Scott: This was like, yeah, I got the one ring, but you know what?
Scott: I got it under control.
Scott: It's cool.
Scott: And it totally is cool.
Scott: Like she's, she's got it, but she's not, you know, going crazy or stabbing people.
Scott: You know, it was only someone else who had a problem that became all crazy toward the end.
Rym: She starts using it semi-frivolously too.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But they, they show you the contrast between the slasher and her of like, yeah, this is what usually happens when there's someone possessed by an evil weapon.
Scott: and here's how our person upset possessed by an evil weapon is going to be right.
Scott: You know?
Scott: And it's like, ah, I'd like to think that if I was possessed by an evil weapon, I'll be more like that.
Scott: You know, I wouldn't be all just like crazy, stabbing everybody.
Rym: So I guess the last thing before we end the show, cause we've gone on long enough toward the end when in case someone's still listening, I'm not going to say who, but anyone who knows knows when someone gets fucking shot at the end of an episode, the fact that, and now I'm spoiling in the next episode, they don't address it for a while.
Rym: And then the fucker just kind of wanders into the scene.
Rym: He's like, someone shot me.
Scott: What the hell?
Rym: I walked here.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I thought he was, I thought he was done.
Rym: I thought he was done too.
Scott: And I was, I was upset because I was an awesome character.
Scott: I wanted to stick around.
Scott: But then when he came back, I was also sort of upset that it was not a for real death.
Rym: I was also happy because that was fucking hilarious.
Rym: That was, it was really like, like epic, like crazy scene.
Rym: Like someone got shot.
Rym: Things really got escalated.
Rym: And then he just comes in and he's just so bad ass.
Scott: The thing is guns are always a much bigger deal in Japan.
Scott: Real ones.
Scott: Anyway, then they are in the, you know, in us media.
Scott: It's like when you see a gun coming out and like, you know, an anime that takes place in what's supposedly modern Japan, shit, you know, daughter dies.
Rym: So Sasa in the movie, nobody has a gun.
Scott: And they're all, it's a cop movie.
Rym: I remember the scene where I forget if it was the first movie or maybe it was the rainbow bridge where that crazy person has a gun and none of the police have a gun.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: And then, you know, there's the, the, the big scene and those.
Scott: that is a fricking stabbing, right?
Scott: It's like, Oh shit.
Scott: A knife.
Scott: Ah, Hey.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So it was better than one knife tuna.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: We can wrap this up.
Scott: You should watch the show.
Scott: It's I think it's still free on crunchy roll.
Scott: There's going to be some sort of OAV like epilogue.
Scott: That's going to come out, which is like, Oh really?
Scott: Cause I guess that means that they're not going to do the remaining.
Rym: I think they will.
Rym: I think maybe they'll just do OAVs for a while.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: It's hard to tell.
Rym: I don't know what the sales are like.
Scott: I'm more looking forward to just the guy directing more different animes.
Scott: Cause I can, you know, I can get the light novels for this, right?
Scott: But also find the rest of the story.
Rym: If you haven't watched it, watch Baccano.
Rym: If you like Dora, you'll like Baccano and the other way around.
Scott: But I still didn't finish Baccano.
Scott: I only watched a handful episodes.
Rym: I've seen all, but like the last three episodes.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: I thought you saw it all.
Rym: It's fricking awesome.
Scott: I've only watched like a hand, like three or four and I've got to, I've just got to go forward.
Rym: It is a lot more violent than Dora Rara Rara Rara Rara Rara Rara Rara Rara Rara.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.