Rym: It's Monday, December 13th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight in the year of our Lord 2010 we talked about Abstraction.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So apparently Rym tells me that he is illicitly modifying the shows.
Scott: GeekNights what evidence have you?
Scott: you just said so.
Scott: when prove it a minute ago?
Rym: If I go back to the audio record it appears that a minute ago, there is no audio.
Scott: Well, you know I could just go and get any of the mp3s and I could listen to them until I hear shit.
Rym: The Marantz was not.
Scott: I got to delete that until I hear some illicit edits that you may have made.
Scott: So if anyone you know if you are misjudging you may be misjudging Rym Falsely positively and misjudging me falsely negatively.
Rym: What kind of edit do you think I could have made?
Rym: It's not like I can really do like add words that you said you could cut out.
Scott: Yeah, you know I've said pretty much almost every word in my vocabulary through the course of this show so you could cut and paste them together Making me say pretty much anything.
Rym: That'd be way too much effort.
Scott: I'm just saying you admitted to illicitly adding things to the show one.
Rym: You have no evidence of that.
Rym: and to And to.
Rym: the last time I did that was when you were chewing that just admitted that you're gonna do it.
Rym: But you were chewing that goddamn gum, I edited out like two minutes of you gum smacking.
Rym: Well, come on, I replaced it with me saying Scott was chewing gum for two minutes.
Scott: Yeah, I don't do that.
Rym: Nah, no, nah.
Rym: Anyway, maybe if you learn audition and audio engineering you could take this over.
Scott: It's not I haven't just.
Scott: I just wouldn't care.
Rym: I'll just send you.
Rym: I'll just send you the raw wave and then you can edit it together.
Scott: I'll just turn it into mp3 and upload it.
Rym: Well with like five minutes of us arguing about what the show's gonna be on.
Scott: Yeah Because then people will see the truth, you know, we saw an edited truth.
Rym: we said we were gonna do that a long time ago and we never did.
Rym: if do one special show where we just record the Whole conversation before and after the show and then like we put up that week the show and then the next week We put up the making of.
Scott: yeah, there's not much making of just now there was not really.
Rym: apparently you have all these accusations Wild accusation that you just admitted to.
Scott: you confessed.
Rym: Oh cuz you think I'm not gonna edit that out.
Scott: you confessed to the comfy chair.
Rym: You realize I could edit this whole thing out.
Rym: I could start the show right now.
Scott: Yeah anyway So, you know, I got all kinds of Arduino and electronic stuff and I did never really, you know Like I did a whole bunch of just you know, follow the instructions kind of things to make stuff But I didn't really make anything on my own initiative because they didn't really have an idea.
Rym: It's kind of like when I learned to cut like I had to learn C sharp to do a web service at work.
Rym: So I made kind of half of a program.
Rym: cuz I thought oh, I'll make my own Like I'll make a shitty little ticketing system just to learn.
Rym: and I got I don't know a day into that and I just stopped.
Scott: yeah, so But I actually have something I want to make and I'm gonna make it and the thing that's good about it is it's mostly crafty Right, the actual electronic part is like five minutes almost right?
Scott: So here's what I'm gonna make ready.
Scott: Remember that thing the shocking roulette.
Scott: you put your finger in it and go dig it again.
Rym: We thought about buying that at RIT to decide who goes first in Puerto Rico, well, that's the point of it, right?
Scott: But I got a better idea.
Scott: I'm gonna make pretty much the same thing with an airsoft gun.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Rym: Same thing with rat tracks.
Scott: It's not a bad idea.
Scott: I'm gonna make basically as small as possible the ultimate Boardgame gadget.
Scott: right and what it's gonna do is gonna do many things that you need in board game.
Rym: All I need is a turn taker timer.
Scott: Okay, it's gonna have turn taking timing with chess turn taking timing mode for multiplayer to like a players.
Scott: Oh, it's gonna have a lot of players tons, right?
Scott: It's gonna have Choose a player at random for whatever you might need to do that, you know going first turn, you know all kinds of stuff right.
Scott: it's gonna have Forget the other things.
Scott: I was gonna have not much else apparently.
Scott: Oh, it's gonna have like money counting for games or you don't want to use the stupid paper money.
Scott: You can actually have money for each person, right?
Rym: So and so how?
Rym: so this is just software.
Rym: then what do you need the Arduino for?
Scott: Well, cuz it'll be a nice little.
Scott: it won't be just like a computer program on your you know, laptop.
Rym: I mean what am I gonna put it on the money counter monopolies.
Rym: when I pull a 500 out?
Rym: It says Rym has taken 500 monopoly dollars.
Scott: They'll just be like, you know up and down You know, I mean you could do.
Rym: I mean I used to do that when as a kid I'd always sit there with my calculator and I would do all my money and that's how I would do it Do and then everyone else would accuse me of cheating.
Scott: Yeah, those one other thing I was gonna have.
Scott: turn time taking.
Scott: choose player at random shocking.
Scott: No shocking.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: The shocking is all I wanted.
Rym: I didn't care about the random.
Scott: I could roll a frickin.
Scott: Oh Quizbowl buzzing in like D. Ah, I cuz independently.
Rym: I was actually thinking about just buy.
Rym: I thought about making one and then I saw that they're so cheap.
Scott: Anyway, you could read like the same LEDs that will like one of them will light up to say who you know.
Scott: choose player at Random.
Scott: you could use those same ones for who buzzed first, you know.
Scott: So it's got a lot of reuse going on and they can make it a just nice small little compact thing.
Scott: So you keep it in your bag and we go to play a board game.
Scott: You just put it in the middle of the table and it's just got a little 16x2 LCD screen and a bunch of LEDs and some buttons.
Rym: See I was thinking about making just the quiz bowl thing because I you know I knew how to make them.
Rym: I help people make them for my high school all the time because we couldn't afford to buy the One so we'd make.
Scott: no this will be money-saving right because you don't need any more electronics to add these extra purposes.
Scott: You know, you have the same number of buttons and the same number of LEDs But you just add extra software and you get more functionality out of the same hardware.
Rym: You really need the shocking though.
Scott: The shocking requires extra hardware.
Rym: Yeah, just a monetizer on it spins in a circle and shoots.
Scott: That's all you I'm gonna do.
Scott: LEDs.
Rym: You ever put your finger in that shocking thing.
Scott: It actually kind of hurts.
Scott: I've done the one where you You know you have the the metal twisted wire and you get the hoop and you try to guide the hoop along the wire without touching the Wire with the hoop and you put your finger on a thing and if you mess up it will shock you.
Scott: Well, if your fingers are also on the shocking pad, I've done that.
Rym: I Could see this being useful but the reason I didn't actually make one was that it's Cheaper to buy one.
Rym: if I can't.
Rym: even if it takes me like a half-hour to make it It's cheaper to just buy one by what.
Scott: a quiz bowl buzzer like 40 bucks Arduino and one Arduino is 30 bucks.
Scott: It's pretty close.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, plus it depends I mean.
Scott: But the thing is.
Rym: but can get the fancy quiz bowl ones that have like the different lights for teams multi-team interaction Networking them across room.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna have to go and try to you know.
Scott: The thing is I have to scavenge up like some good buttons that are good for hitting.
Scott: I'm thinking I might get that that thing from staples.
Scott: What's that?
Scott: You know the red easy button?
Rym: Yeah, you can get better buttons.
Scott: I need a good though.
Scott: No, that's good that you can hit hard and frequently.
Rym: I'll show you some places to get buttons.
Rym: You know, I've said this sounds dumb.
Rym: I actually do have good knowledge on buttons specifically.
Rym: I know I remember when I made that hard DDR pad.
Scott: Yeah, well, I need something that you can punch with your fist and has a nice cable on it.
Rym: Yeah, I did a lot of research into switches and buttons And you know ribbon switches are actually what you want.
Rym: if you want to make a DDR pad Just a long ribbon and if you squeeze it anywhere it goes off.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah All right.
Rym: So the news apparently is Gawker which is something I mostly ignore.
Scott: Well, so Gawker if you don't realize this, right?
Scott: There's a whole bunch of blogs out in the world.
Scott: Some of the most popular blogs actually are part of this company called Gawker media and they're actually in New York And the company consists of many blogs such as Gawker Kotaku Gizmodo io 9 And a bunch of other ones that I remember.
Scott: Yeah life hacker life hacker I think apparently flesh bot if let's bust the porn blog.
Scott: Yes, basically just porn.
Scott: It's not even really a blog.
Scott: doesn't have stories about the porn industry Just has hey check out this porn.
Rym: that spin is spawned on the Wikipedia page.
Rym: Jezebel for celebrity sex.
Scott: Yeah, great basically, you know company.
Scott: yeah anyway Pretty much the only Gawker thing.
Scott: I even pay attention to is Kotaku and the only reason I Prefer Kotaku over joystick is because I think joystick is you know, while it's high quality Kotaku Definitely focuses more on like, you know, the Japan stuff because they actually have people in Japan So that that helps them but all the other Gawker blogs that can give shit about.
Scott: but anyway They fucked up right at Gawker.
Rym: now you fucked up.
Scott: They fucked up big time in the security department of computers.
Scott: So what happened was somebody through some probably very easy means Managed to steal everything from Gawker the source code to their blog software, which I'm pretty sure is just regular old blog software That's slightly modified.
Rym: I highly doubt they have anything particularly special.
Scott: It's just probably a CMS Just like you know, it's a WordPress kind of thing or movable type or one of those.
Scott: I don't even know which one they use.
Scott: and then they stole their entire database for all their blogs Including all the use names and passwords for posting comments and such.
Rym: but but of course they were encrypted.
Scott: Yeah, they were.
Scott: they were indeed But they made a very big mistake.
Scott: and this is is that you know?
Scott: I mean you can get all the details of this story elsewhere on the internet but the one thing I really want to focus is on is the storing of the passwords in the database right because Most of the stories you're gonna read on the internet won't discuss this very technical topic in any depth to where you'll actually understand what's going on, but It's a very important topic and all the other parts of this story are discussed everywhere in great depth.
Scott: So anyway, here's the way it works, right?
Scott: I have a website.
Scott: I want you to log into the website.
Scott: It means you need to.
Scott: every time you go to the website You type in a username and a password and you push submit and when you register at the website You also type in the password right to.
Scott: you know to tell me what it is.
Scott: Now I just write down the password in the database But that means anyone who gets the database can see everyone's password and then log in as anyone.
Rym: I have worked at places where I had to change my password into system and it was old and no one could tell me how.
Rym: So breaking into the system and looking at the database I could see everyone's passwords and just do an update statement to set a new password for myself.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you have access to the actual database server You can edit any of the passwords easily but to read the password is a different story Especially since many morons in the world use the same password on every website.
Scott: So if you get their seemingly innocuous blog comment posting password You could probably get into their bank account.
Rym: Yep, cuz oh.
Rym: and then once you get email email is like the gateway to everything.
Rym: It's like the chart at our wag of who is slept with who.
Rym: yeah, you can get to someone's email You can get to every other thing they've got.
Scott: Yeah And this is the thing is that most people use the same password everywhere.
Scott: Right, and when most you hear stories about like oh he hacked to myspace he hacked Facebook.
Scott: usually it's just they had a really shitty password and someone guessed it or Saw it or figured it out.
Rym: cuz passwords and databases are hashed or munched or something, right?
Scott: So the way right?
Scott: so here's the part I want to talk about.
Scott: So we need to fix this.
Scott: You can't just have a password in the database.
Scott: It doesn't work.
Scott: So what the solution is is we encrypt the password, but how can we if we encrypt the password?
Scott: Then we could just decrypt it.
Scott: right if I use a code of like, okay We're gonna take every letter in the password and make it go up by one.
Scott: So if your password is a BBB will change it to B C C C and then right.
Scott: that doesn't work either Cuz as soon as someone knows the code they can reverse the code, but thankfully in maths, there are one-way transformations, right?
Scott: So we have hashes that are one way, you know, you just probably heard of things like MD 5 or sha1 or des.
Scott: Right, so you encrypt something.
Scott: basically, it's a one-way math.
Scott: So if it's one way though, how can we get it back and figure out if it's the right password?
Scott: Well, here's what you do, right?
Scott: Let's say your password is the letter a and I pipe it through MD 5 and outcomes blaga blaga blaga, right?
Scott: So I write blaga blaga blaga in the database.
Scott: so now you come to the website again and you type in a. I Type I take that a and I run it through the same.
Scott: You know gristmill and outcomes blaga blaga blaga and I can check to see if the blaga blagas match.
Scott: and if they match Then I know that you just typed in the right password even though I Don't I didn't know what the right password was because the right password was not in the database and also Because of maths that I'm not going to explain.
Scott: you can't take the blaga blaga.
Rym: I want to tell the listeners because this applies to me as well Anytime we say math that we don't want to explain that is code for math that we don't particularly know.
Scott: I know it By heart, you can't go backwards, right?
Scott: So if I just say here Rym his blaga blaga tell me what the password is Rym will have no fucking clue.
Scott: There's no way for him to know now.
Rym: What I could do is brute-force it.
Scott: yes, and this is actually something that is many many people have done because actually it takes less than a fraction of a second to Doing it to do an MD 5 of anything
Rym: which as an aside is why one of the most important things for security is on your outward facing portals to Slow down to throttle the rate of login attempts as people continue to fail.
Rym: Yep That is one of the surest ways.
Scott: or to lock out accounts after a certain number of false attempts Which means so many work blackberries get locked out because yeah stupid They stay but anyway or to have some physical thing like a Yuba key or RSA secure ID.
Rym: So I went to log on to server fault the other day to ask a question about DRBD and it was like What's your Yuba key?
Rym: And I was like, oh fuck I own a Yuba key.
Scott: Yeah, where is he on the keychain?
Rym: I found it and I plugged it in and it worked.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There you go It only works 32,000 times that I had to give you a new one running out.
Scott: I know right?
Scott: It's very slowly.
Rym: Um, but anyway So I've used my Yuba key more times to show other people how it works than I've used it to actually log into anything.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: I can.
Scott: I can incorporate into anything we've got, you know, we should do it on the website.
Rym: I think I could do that.
Scott: Um, anyway, I have it on one of my WordPress blogs the.
Scott: so we MD 5 is not the greatest idea because Somebody out there and many people have done this is they just get the MD 5 of everything they are.
Scott: What's the MD 5 of a and they write it down?
Scott: What's the MD 5 of B and they write it down?
Scott: What's the MD 5 of C and they write it?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So if I look in your database and I find herp to derp de bar in the password hash And I know that herp to derp de bar is what happens when I put welcome into the text prompt.
Scott: Yeah Basically people have these thing called rainbow tables and they just is basically they've written down.
Scott: you can just download these things Every or the vast majority of the most common passwords.
Scott: You know MD 5 hashed so you can.
Scott: just they can just if they have the MD 5 hash even though it's not reversible math.
Scott: They've done the one-way math for almost every possible password.
Scott: So they just look up what your password is and this big ol list.
Rym: It's kind of like when you do complex integrations where sometimes there is no or like complex factoring where there is no procedure That is guaranteed to work that a human can follow.
Rym: I mean computers can follow, you know PNP.
Rym: they can follow algorithms that will eventually guaranteed find an answer.
Rym: But humans don't have that luxury and a lot of times the way to solve an integral is to look up how to solve it Because someone else already figured out the optimal path.
Scott: Now there are some things that you can do to help this.
Scott: for example Some people use salts and what a salt is is okay.
Scott: instead of just running your password upon its own Through the one-way math We're gonna take your password and also your username and the date that you joined This website and put them all together and then run that through the one-way math and that helps quite a bit right because now Someone, you know can't just sit there getting pat guessing passwords.
Scott: They also have to guess You know The the time you joined and they have to know that that's what the salt is in order to actually get the password.
Scott: It becomes a little bit more difficult.
Rym: Or they have to pull some sort of taiko brahi math where they figure it out indirectly, which is not likely.
Rym: that is solving.
Scott: I mean the thing is in this case It wouldn't have helped because they have access to the database and the source code of the block of the Gawker website.
Scott: So they know what the salt is because they can see the salt right in the source code of the website.
Rym: Oh Snap.
Scott: so with that knowledge and with you know, the thing is Gawker wasn't even using assault.
Scott: They were just using straight-up des, right?
Scott: Oh So you can see the source code and they have the hash password so they can figure out everything.
Scott: You know They just have to go and they they just had to get their tables.
Scott: and they can because des is pretty fast to calculate.
Scott: They can.
Scott: just they don't have a table already.
Scott: They just generate a new table and it's gonna take them a few days.
Rym: They try to cover it up, but it's too late Right.
Rym: I've seen everything.
Scott: So what is the solution to this problem?
Scott: Well, you might be thinking well.
Scott: Rym and Scott are always talking about public key private key.
Scott: Isn't that the right solution?
Scott: No, that actually doesn't work at all.
Scott: Yeah, what are you gonna do?
Scott: Okay, so I'll encrypt my password with my private key and send it to you.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah that fails.
Scott: Okay, so I'll encrypt my password with your Public key and send it and it there's no way to do it.
Rym: You use a public private key system of X key exchange that lets you log into the site, but then isn't you?
Scott: Well, that's s is okay.
Scott: So I like this.
Scott: the login to the site is SSL so nobody can just sniff my password off the network.
Scott: But you still have to store something in your database that you can Decrypt to verify that the password that I have sent to you is the correct pass kind of like a lot of people carry their private Keys around on a USB stick.
Rym: that's well and good unless someone has access to USB stick.
Scott: Yeah, you could do an SSH model.
Scott: We're basically instead of giving you a password I give you my public key and you store that in your database and then I log into the website with a challenge response By by because I have my private key on my computer.
Scott: That's far too difficult.
Scott: No one will ever be able to do that.
Rym: You do that for things like government secrets.
Scott: that Oh WikiLeaks or as you know, your servers with SSH.
Scott: Yeah, all right That's not gonna work for logging into websites just like Yubikey and RSA secure ID aren't really gonna work for logging into websites.
Scott: people Can barely handle, you know Wow and PayPal using physical login mechanisms, you know They're not gonna be able to handle it for every single website in the world.
Scott: So the correct solution at least as of right now is actually a thing called bcrypt.
Scott: Bcrypt isn't really mathematically much different than using you know hashes on assault You know with a one-way math.
Scott: the one thing that bcrypt actually has an advantage of though However, is that it's actually kind of slow, right?
Scott: You can still generate a rainbow table for bcrypt But it'll take you a fucking long as time and you might be saying well So as soon as we wait a couple years bcrypt will be dead because I'll just use a faster computer and that'll be that.
Scott: Right, I can figure out all the bcrypts.
Scott: well bcrypt actually has options where you can tell it how long you want it to take.
Scott: so it can actually as Computers get faster.
Scott: You can just keep changing the number that you're telling bcrypt Right to go slower and slow until basically you can always make it so that it takes like five minutes.
Scott: Did you know to jet?
Scott: even if you make it take two seconds to generate you the password with bcrypt, right?
Scott: And you keep changing it as computers get faster so that it always takes two seconds.
Scott: That's still two seconds times the number of passwords.
Scott: It's gonna take them.
Scott: Centuries do remember.
Rym: it's not a number of passwords until they get yours.
Rym: That's just even to generate the tables.
Rym: Like if you're gonna brute-force it.
Scott: Yeah, they had.
Scott: you know, remember this is one-way math.
Scott: They can't just take it and you know, look up and go backwards from the from the encrypted stuff to get the password.
Scott: They actually have to try every password in the universe until they find a match for You know the what you've got.
Rym: think of it as like a CAPTCHA system for computers.
Rym: We've got a human who wants to connect and say you give them increasingly difficult to solve Mathematical CAPTCHAs as they continue to fail to log on.
Rym: so there's some.
Rym: it takes more Actual real entropy universe destroying efforts to get in to make one more attempt.
Scott: Yep, so if you're worried about your database being taken from your website, right?
Scott: And you actually have you know.
Scott: If you're just using software that someone else wrote like WordPress or something just let it be don't you know?
Scott: worry too much about it.
Scott: Just keep it up to date with the security, you know 2650 users in their database.
Rym: We're using the password either password or QWERTY.
Scott: Yeah, I mean our.
Scott: You know my WordPress blogs.
Scott: I added Yubikey to them because I know WordPress is all frequently has security holes and I'm always updating it to make sure but I Haven't really changed.
Scott: It still uses whatever WordPress uses for encrypting passwords, you know, but if I make my own site Right.
Scott: I'm doing the bcrypt and the salt and the hole, right?
Scott: You got it.
Scott: I'm going full-on to make sure that that shit is working.
Rym: and also maybe Yubikey as an aside salt does it like.
Rym: this is just One very specific application of salt like I don't know if Firefox still does it but back in the day Mozilla to your profile directories would be you know Your username and then a dot and then a bunch of random characters so that worms and things that might try to exploit profiles Couldn't easily figure out what your profile was based on when you logged in or anything.
Scott: They could just go into the profile folder and see that there's only one folder in there And that would be the only folder in there.
Rym: Yeah, it was you.
Rym: I mean it was this.
Rym: this is a primitive mechanism from Yeah, anyway.
Scott: But you see this is.
Scott: this is what how you have to store passwords in Databases to let people log in without giving all the passwords away, right?
Scott: And this is why you should never you know when steam or any of those other people tell you Don't tell anyone your password.
Scott: even the company that you are You know working with.
Scott: don't even tell your password to your bank because the bank doesn't know the password.
Scott: They've just got a database full of gobbledygook, right?
Scott: So there's no reason to ever tell anyone in the universe your password ever because they don't need to know it in their database, right and You no one else needs to know it.
Scott: only you need to know it.
Scott: so don't tell anyone Because of this stuff that we are saying right now.
Rym: So I'll talk about this briefly because we went on for a while about the other thing.
Rym: I want to make sure people understood this very important personal security information, but it looks like good things are on the horizon.
Rym: There's an article on slash out talking about this, but we might slowly see the end of VGA.
Scott: VGA cables.
Scott: Yeah, they're not.
Scott: I mean they're already dead.
Rym: Pretty much every projector in the business and convention world has just a VGA input.
Scott: Well, no, no I mean most of the projectors that I've seen in recent history have all kinds of inputs.
Scott: The thing is people always use VGA Because the least common denominator.
Scott: and even if someone has DVI or HDMI or DisplayPort output it can always be converted to VGA.
Scott: So rather than provide a litany of different cables for different occasions and different laptops They always just give you a VGA and then Completely fail at every convention because they forget to bring their adapters if they even have it.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean you can just go and get.
Scott: they have the adapters they exist.
Scott: So it's it's just the fact that it's the least common denominator, you know, that's the only reason it's still around on the projectors.
Scott: It doesn't really need to be.
Scott: I mean we could probably provide DVI and start giving to the finger to the few people who have Only VGA is their option, but the problem is at the same time laptop I mean my laptops VGA only.
Scott: really mine has a. mine has a VGA output, but it also has some other option.
Rym: What other option does it have?
Scott: Let me take a look.
Rym: I mean, it might have a DisplayPort which is starting to be more common.
Scott: No, I guess doesn't have any.
Scott: I thought I had another option now.
Rym: so uh, we got the V to DVI only projector Not what.
Scott: oh, no, I sorry.
Scott: It does have a different option, but I need the docking.
Scott: I need the docking station.
Rym: You're gonna bring your docking station to do a presentation.
Scott: I don't have a docking station.
Scott: But you know, I've seen plenty of laptops, you know, most of them nowadays the newer ones have DisplayPort or HDMI or Not as many as you think Many of you guys around.
Rym: but VGA is still pretty much the standard on projectors mostly I think I think the biggest reason why we haven't been able to just kind of chuck it as quickly as we have other things Is that VGI day is such a long history and a lot of people are really cheap
Scott: You know, the other thing
Rym: is that they're not replacing.
Scott: The other thing is right.
Scott: take for example, my TV was stolen, right?
Scott: they also stole my HDMI cable said to buy some new ones.
Scott: and But so I when I got I got a new TV before I was able to get new HDMI cable.
Scott: So for a day or two, I plugged in my HD PC to my new TV with a VGA cable.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It was that you know, 1080p full HD on a VGA cable.
Scott: just fine It was.
Scott: I really couldn't tell the difference between the HDMI cable and the VGA cable Other than the fact that the video driver was a little flaky that using different, you know I had to set it differently Yeah, and I had to push like the auto sync button and also it didn't doesn't an audio over the VGA cable.
Scott: But other than that the actual video quality after I you know, got it aligned was identical.
Rym: Yeah, but they're the one.
Rym: it's a little because I was playing around plugging my computer and different things in with.
Rym: you know HDMI versus the VGA and the VGA.
Rym: for summary.
Rym: It's a little fuzzy.
Rym: I didn't know There's an over scan.
Scott: I mean it's LCD.
Scott: you can't really.
Scott: I got I had under scan with the with HDMI But then I fixed it cuz the ATI driver sucked.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: ATI driver you suck.
Rym: But basically Intel is taking the first step and by 2015 They're gonna stop supporting VGA and all of their client processors and chipsets.
Scott: No good idea.
Scott: Yeah I mean this is it doesn't matter though, cuz okay.
Scott: We'll stop supporting VGA.
Scott: So everyone have DVI With adapters.
Scott: Yeah, you know what really needs to happen.
Scott: is we just need to be like, you know You need to.
Scott: when you go to a place right you do the slow transition.
Scott: You know instead of just having a VGA cable be the only thing.
Scott: when you hook up a projector at a conference or in a Conference room have a DVI cable there.
Scott: also have an HDMI cable there.
Scott: Also have these other cables next to the VGA cable.
Rym: So that is why I wanted to bring this article up because if you look at the trend of computing in technology history Very rarely has the non backward compatible kind of long change thing Been the one that failed when there's a race.
Rym: and in this case, I mean look at most projectors now I said they'll have VGA.
Rym: Usually.
Rym: they also have as video and RCA.
Scott: Yeah, it's because they you know, they're not expecting computers.
Scott: Most of them are not meant for computers primarily even though that's what they use for primarily.
Rym: but all the old Computers like old laptops I had at work.
Rym: They'll have as video out some of them.
Rym: Yeah So basically what's gonna happen is it's kind of like we've got this queue and now we're dropping RCA and s video off the end and VGA is gonna be the old ass connector on everything.
Rym: but new things coming out are slowly probably going to have Like DisplayPort and VGA.
Scott: I think really what we need to have is you need to have HDMI because right the HDMI also has audio.
Scott: So as soon as people can realize that and it actually starts to work If you hook up your laptop with HDMI and the audio also works Right and the video on the projector without having to have the separate tiny little wire I agree.
Rym: However, it is annoying to me personally Only because when I you know running conventions and doing things like that if I'm in charge of a room I often want to do very weird and specific splits to different devices.
Scott: I'm not saying remove the headphone hole Right, it's just.
Scott: I know.
Scott: I agree with you.
Rym: in the vast majority of cases in the modern world There's no reason to have these separate audio and video chains because very rarely do you want one and not the.
Scott: you know Plus if it's a fancy room right that HDMI cable is not gonna go directly into the projector sending its audio into the projector Which is really dumb.
Scott: It's gonna send it into some sort of room mixing machine, you know And then it's gonna forward the video to the projector.
Scott: We were spoiled forward the audio to the speaker system by RIT.
Rym: to this day when I give a presentation somewhere Nobody has a setup like RIT did.
Scott: No, not at all.
Scott: every room the wall jacks the podiums Yeah more laptops should have HDMI or mini HDMI and it should come with the appropriate adapters to go to VGA because it's still necessary.
Scott: and then when people if you set up projectors and conference rooms make sure to provide multiple different ways to connect so that people will use you know, the one that is the best and they won't you know I mean if people have see that the HDMI cable fits they're gonna choose that over the VGA Which requires screwing in and it's all kind of funky.
Rym: I actually have a non screwing VGA cable has little clips that go like a kunk Interesting.
Rym: Yeah, so anyway things of the day.
Scott: So check it out.
Scott: It's say it's hockey season So it's about time to do some hockey things today As we want to.
Rym: as I recall we have had multiple hockey fight weeks in the past.
Scott: I think we only had one hockey fight week.
Scott: This is a pretty good stick right this guy.
Scott: I'm not even sure what league this is.
Scott: It's some minor league Not too many spectators league.
Rym: All
Scott: right, but this dude he picks up the puck on his stick something pretty much any hockey player can do When he's behind the net and he pretty much plunks it onto the goalie's head and then it bounces off the back of the goal He said into the goal.
Scott: brilliant.
Scott: This would not work in You know more professional leagues because someone would have hit him.
Scott: if you notice there was a guy standing right there Basically watching him do it in the NHL.
Scott: The guy would have just hit his stick and taken the fuck, right?
Scott: It's only works because it's amateur hour, but it's still pretty awesome, right?
Rym: It's one of those moves You're like, oh snap kind of like the the little league football trick plays exactly or the kids stealing home plate Exactly.
Scott: I love that love this.
Rym: So I don't have a video or anything.
Rym: I'm gonna try to not use College Humor, you know cop-outs for a while, but I Would I wanted to use this on a Tuesday, but I haven't used College Humor in forever.
Scott: This is the first time in a long time,
Rym: but basically this is an opinion piece on the New York Times You know, whatever by David Brooks, but it's called the triumph of hope over self-interest And it's an interesting article that if you boil it down is basically Why do poor people vote to give rich people more money?
Rym: And the statistic is really interesting.
Rym: I actually want to use this.
Scott: the next time we do a game theory panel this statistic Are there studies to back up whatever hypothesis this this this guy is presenting here?
Rym: Oh, there's one study and then a couple of other kind of tentatively linked to study.
Scott: We could actually probably study this psychological phenomena with some sort.
Rym: Yeah Well, he makes sort of game.
Rym: He makes some interesting points that if you notice and this is all just conjecture the people who tend to vote against tax increases For the wealthy even though they're poor tend to live in less affluent areas where they feel like they're richer.
Rym: They feel like they have more money when actually they're you know in the bottom 50% Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the interesting statistic is that and this was from 2000 and apparently it's worse now I'm trying to find the more recent study.
Rym: It's behind a paywall.
Rym: They ask people one if they believe that they are in the top 1% of wage earners 19% of Americans think they are the richest 1%.
Scott: Oh boy.
Rym: I thought it'd be like 5% 6%.
Rym: no 19% of Americans.
Scott: I know the top 1% of America has like 25% of the wealth.
Rym: So so so so a further 20% expect Realistically that in their lifetime.
Rym: They will be in the top 1%.
Scott: Already know you're not you're not in the 1%.
Rym: the odds of you being in the 1% are 1% less than 1% 39% of people think they're rich and as a result think that the rich shouldn't be taxed when in actuality They are some of the poorest.
Scott: Uh-huh, and it's it's an interesting article that so that's that's the actual.
Scott: there was actual study behind those numbers.
Rym: Yeah, those numbers are a sir a post-election survey in 2000.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Well, I'd love to see today's day.
Scott: I would love to see today's date is of course the economy got bad.
Rym: So maybe people be like I'm not rich anymore.
Rym: Yeah, I'd say my house went under so I'm gonna try to find some more data, but it's an interest.
Scott: Yeah, I would be very surprised if there's any homeless people who are not also crazy people who said I'm in the richest one You don't even have a house dude, I mean, ah, but he doesn't have a phone so he's not gonna get pulled.
Rym: But this is an example, you know Monday people can talk about this a lot of game theory.
Rym: game theory perfectly models the behavior of Rational actors.
Scott: That's what I was just gonna say.
Scott: We need to study this with a game.
Scott: Yes, we need to have a game where you know, we make people think There's taxes and you have to vote on the taxes.
Scott: Straight up you vote on the taxes for the next turn.
Scott: Yeah But you you get tax this turn.
Rym: I notice you're not voting for the tax increase.
Rym: anything you tear to share.
Scott: I'm in the top like 20%.
Rym: It's an interesting article.
Rym: I thought I'd do something more erudite than a guy getting hit in the nuts.
Scott: All right Meta moments meta moment.
Rym: We're going to be at MAGFest doing free panels not Simultaneously, that's good.
Rym: What is our panel?
Rym: And then we're also going to sit on two of the mag nine gaming intellectual panels.
Rym: I think it's technical changes in game design and Achievements in metagaming.
Scott: Yeah, I wonder how those are gonna go.
Rym: I think they'll be interesting.
Rym: the people everyone else on the mag nine seems intelligent about games and We were encouraged to disagree.
Rym: I don't know if you read that email.
Rym: They're like.
Rym: I would hope that you will Disagree with each other forthwith in order to make the panels interesting and not just yes, man Uh-huh.
Rym: I plan to disagree with people.
Scott: Yeah, that's gonna go.
Rym: well The book club book is hyperspace Michio Kaku's hyperspace a snap The last book club book was World War Z. You can listen to our show from last week.
Rym: We also have a book club book site.
Rym: I don't think we put it up yet.
Scott: No, I got.
Scott: I gotta work on that.
Rym: Okay, it's almost done.
Rym: I did all the data entry.
Scott: All right, do we add World War Z?
Rym: No, that's your book.
Rym: Okay, gotta add your own books from now on.
Scott: All right, I'll add it.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX East.
Rym: we're gonna be at you know, anime Boston all those other conventions and icon.
Rym: We're not gonna be a Katsucon which only comes up because someone emailed us asking about Katsucon panels.
Rym: We quit that staff like a year and a half many years ago years ago.
Scott: You can buy t-shirts.
Rym: You know GeekNights t-shirts the original series are actually selling out pretty quick.
Rym: We have very few left.
Scott: and then you know, you got to buy them all before you get more.
Scott: So Oh and as we have a counter-strike server, yes, yes dot front row crew calm.
Scott: Did you test if that works?
Rym: Uh, yes, it does.
Rym: Okay, also GeekNights dot dine DNS calm.
Rym: also the IP address in the forums It's currently.
Rym: it might go down tonight because I got to put the computer I built back together.
Rym: Yeah, but we're gonna start hosting.
Rym: this is kind of a test and it seems to be going well.
Rym: I'm gonna try to host a lot more game and file and servers for you people because I got crazy files and Someone in the forum is running a minecraft server.
Scott: It's actually this they're Devon a second go of it.
Rym: Yes There's prior Toria, which they built.
Scott: Well, no, I think they have another one.
Rym: Yeah now it's second this.
Scott: Okay, so, you know if you want to play Minecraft with people join the guides forum join the forum And I guess you know, I guess if you fuck around they'll ban you.
Scott: we have nothing to do with that.
Scott: It's unofficial It's not.
Scott: it's not officially endorsed.
Rym: It is unofficial, but it is endorsed as in.
Rym: I endorse it.
Scott: All right Well, they have one.
Rym: I guess the gist of this is that we have a lot of listeners who you know Kind of shy away from all the community around GeekNights.
Scott: But really I think the community around the front row crew and GeekNights I mean if you're stronger than GeekNights itself if you listen to this show Every day, I mean sir, you don't want to connect with the other people who do the same thing.
Scott: I mean the people.
Scott: there's only very few people out of the seven billion people on earth.
Scott: There's a ridiculously small percentage of people who listen to this show with any frequency.
Scott: So if you're doing that and there are other people who are doing that Those are probably people who are on earth have a great more in common with you than any other people's on earth And you probably would you know want to connect with those people.
Scott: it
Rym: is telling that many people who don't listen to podcasts anymore I mean, I don't really listen to podcasts
Scott: They
Rym: you know, they go to our panels at cons and everything But they hang out in the forums to this day because the forum community is kind of an independent body.
Rym: Yeah, and it's not scary like the penny arcade forums.
Rym: It's legit.
Scott: Yep All right, so Abstraction.
Scott: Yeah, we sort of came up with this idea.
Scott: Who knows how to go.
Rym: I didn't want to talk about home networking.
Scott: No, we already did that.
Rym: We talked about our own home network.
Scott: That's the same thing.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Would you guys want to hear about port forwarding?
Rym: Okay, whatever Listeners back me up.
Scott: Yeah, they want to hear about anything that they'll.
Scott: they'll take any show they can get.
Rym: No, they won't.
Rym: they want a zombie show and a food show.
Rym: Yeah and a port forwarding home networking show.
Scott: Anyway, I wanted to talk about abstraction because it relates to the networking situation.
Scott: It's also widely misunderstood and it's also pretty much what you know, the core concept of pretty much modern Computing.
Scott: for anything, you know beyond a user level right anything deeper than a user level You have to understand what abstraction is and you have to be able to recognize layers of abstraction and the connections between them and You know what abstraction means.
Scott: Right, and we also use this term a lot when talking about board games and RPGs where it means the exact same thing.
Rym: It always amazes me in my professional career.
Rym: I run into people who ostensibly went to computer school.
Rym: They've done learn the computers and it's not that they don't know some particular thing like how to do abstractions or instances or interfaces or whatever in a particular language or the OSI model but they just never like learn coding enough to know the fundamentals of How to write code or how to.
Rym: I've got a fit like I. they don't understand abstraction Which is like the core of modern coding, right?
Scott: So it To give you an idea of what abstraction is, right?
Scott: Let's talk about, you know, the OSI model of networking which is something you should learn also.
Scott: So it's we're gonna give you two birds for one stone.
Rym: If you learn Cisco, you probably think there are five but technically there are seven layers.
Scott: Well, I mean the thing is the top layer is the application layer and the thing nowadays The application layer can have multiple application layers and often does so.
Scott: shit gets crazy.
Scott: But it's really only seven layers, you know in the classical you remember that I could.
Scott: I'm gonna look them up the internet Really?
Rym: I remember most of the physical data link network transport session Presentation application because presentations all the encryption and stuff.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Took me a while.
Rym: See the thing is the OSI model.
Rym: It's funny because it's an abstraction and it's very important.
Rym: and yet TCP IP Which is kind of based on the OCI OSI model is Not seven layers.
Rym: They actually only break down to five layers and most people only know that.
Scott: yep Anyway, but what an abstraction layer is?
Scott: think of it like a cake, right?
Scott: You know, you have a layer cake or each layer rests upon the layer below it.
Scott: so each layer is a layer of abstraction and what it does is basically it allows you to Interact with a technology or a system right while hiding Everything that can be hidden and only you know fulfilling certain functions.
Scott: for example Think about your car that you drive right.
Scott: when you're driving this car You're stepping on a gas pedal and a brake and you're spinning a wheel the gas pedal abstracts a throttle mechanism That is surprisingly complex.
Scott: Yeah, so they're inside the car.
Scott: what happens when you step on the gas pedal?
Scott: is this ludicrously complex system Right.
Rym: Well, well, it depends.
Rym: in in older cars like my car There's a wire that just opens or closes a hole.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much but opens or closes more or less doesn't completely, you know.
Scott: in many cars nowadays They'll actually, you know stepping on the gas pedal will go to a computer which is calibrated to think Okay stepped on it this much.
Scott: So he wants to go this much faster and you know The automatic transmission might change gears and then when he said quickly you stepped on.
Rym: when you step off It'll keep going at full speed until it crashes and you sue somebody.
Scott: Yeah, you know, there's various Various, you know things that go on thrust from stepping on a pedal, right?
Scott: so this simple mechanism of pedal goes up pedal goes down is abstracting this complex system of Pistons spinning and going up and down.
Scott: and you know gas, you know moving around and air intakes opening up.
Rym: We have technical people.
Rym: I mean, let's talk about accessing web page.
Rym: I got Firefox open right now All right, so Firefox is displaying a web page.
Rym: I'm communicating with something.
Rym: say I connect to Scott's server over at his house.
Rym: Firefox doesn't know anything about the voltages on the wire.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: It doesn't even know anything about MAC addresses or data lakes.
Rym: In fact there's stuff at both ends because you kind of have to go down through the layers of abstraction all the way to the bottom and Then all the way back up to the top again.
Rym: So basically, you know We've got all these layers.
Rym: if Firefox at the top is my application layer and I'm connecting to Apache on Scott's server Which is an application in and of itself The application only knows that it's talking to another application.
Scott: Yeah, I mean when you're right.
Scott: if you let's say I was gonna write my own web browser in C Let's say right C knows how to work a computer, right?
Scott: So in C, I would be doing things like moving bits around in memory and flipping Transistors and moving data between RAM and the CPU.
Scott: and you know writing and reading data from input output devices, right?
Rym: But I don't have to write.
Scott: set the voltage on this pin to six volts.
Scott: You never had to write that because that is something that is hidden from you on the layer that you are working on Right.
Scott: So in order to do networking on the internet as the most of the networking that you're gonna do in your life there are actually seven different layers of This kind of extraction going on right.
Rym: the bottom layer, of course being Electricities or electrons or that's the same thing or photons is what I meant to say.
Scott: Oh photons.
Scott: Yes It could be optical you're correct, you know, it's basically the electricity the lights the you know Whatever some sort of physical hardware.
Scott: It could actually be like somebody's hand taking up You know a plastic tube and moving the plastic tube from one shoot to another shoot and then the tube goes flying away, right?
Scott: Whatever the physical thing is that makes the data move is the bottom layer.
Rym: So think a simple example to just have two computers.
Rym: They're on a local network.
Rym: You just want to have them talk to each other directly.
Rym: So the computers at the lowest level that you know layer to the so-called data link layer.
Rym: They know, you know, they have an abstraction of the physical layer.
Rym: They know something like Send data to this address on The network in quotes.
Rym: it knows there is the network.
Rym: I can send stuff to it Yep, and I can get stuff from it.
Rym: That's all it needs to know Yep, and then then you know every layer up only needs to know the layer underneath it Yep, so the network the layer three is like the network layer, right?
Scott: And that's where you start getting the switching and the routing going on, you know, if you just that's IP Yeah, a data link Mac addresses.
Rym: So, you know, I connect out.
Rym: so IP address I have and ports that's transport layer.
Rym: So I connect to port 80 that's the transport layer.
Rym: that says, you know, what am I connecting to?
Rym: How am I connecting TCP UDP all that stuff?
Rym: and then so where am I connecting the next layer down?
Rym: That's like your address the IP address and then once you get through the switches and routers.
Rym: Your Mac address doesn't travel all the way through Mac addresses is just local computers next to each other talking.
Scott: Mm-hmm Actually, I don't think a lot of people understand how Mac addresses work.
Scott: we should we should like all right Let's say we can cover that very quickly.
Rym: Well, what about it?
Rym: I mean, it's actually not a quick thing to cover.
Scott: if you if they don't actually know how it works No, that's what I'm saying is it's it's pretty quick, right?
Scott: It's basically when you plug your computer in with a wire, right?
Scott: On a LAN over the hub, that's not a good, okay.
Scott: Basically, what happens is if you want to send you want to send.
Scott: I want to send a packet from my computer to rims computer Right and there's ten computers on this network and they all just have wires going into a hub.
Scott: So how does my packet get from my computer to rims computer the hub?
Scott: a hub doesn't know anything.
Scott: All a hub does is take every packet going in and send it out to everybody.
Scott: All right, it doesn't it doesn't know shit.
Scott: So everybody sees the exact same thing.
Scott: So how do I talk to just room without talking to anyone else?
Rym: Alright, listen, we can go up a level.
Rym: So, you know my IP address.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Alright, so what does it do?
Scott: Okay, so I'm just curious here how much you know this how much I know this Alright, so I decide that I'm going to send write something to rims IP address.
Scott: So first my computer looks at its network configuration.
Scott: It looks at the subnet mask.
Scott: Alright, and if the IP address is in the subnet mask Then it knows that Rym is on the local network and he is not on a remote network.
Rym: That's a roundabout.
Rym: yeah, that's kind of true that is correct.
Rym: Yes, well it more has to do with whether or not you have a specific route.
Rym: You know at a higher level part of the pro.
Scott: I was about to say if the IP address is not in the subnet mask, then it will look at the default gateway.
Rym: Yeah, but then it still does the same thing.
Rym: because if you connect to the default gateway the router, you know The router that you've got connecting your computers to the internet old listeners you connect to that IP and then that basically makes its own Connection out to whatever you're doing.
Scott: Yep Anyway, so let's say I'm gonna send the packet to Rym.
Scott: He's in the local network, right?
Scott: So he's in within the side.
Rym: that was the first thing that comes out of your computer The very first thing when you're trying to send data to me on the local network and all you know is my IP I believe the ARP.
Scott: Yes, the ARP is the first thing.
Scott: so that stands for I have no clue.
Rym: address resolution protocol Alrighty, it's actually pretty straightforward.
Scott: So the ARP goes out and it says hey, I'm looking for this Address and then rims.
Scott: computer would say hey, that's me I got that address.
Scott: So I go aha.
Scott: I see Rym over there.
Rym: Well, I don't just say I've got that address.
Rym: I say I Own that Mac address which it figures this out on the physical level with a bit mask.
Rym: and then it responds and says Not only do I know is that me here is my Mac address.
Rym: and then Scott's computer says Okay, and caches that and then sends to the IP address of me the actual data.
Rym: He wanted to send but Encapsulated in that.
Rym: you know that that that IP packet that data is itself encapsulated into.
Rym: I Don't want to get into the technical details of frames and windows and everything But it's basically encapsulated in one thing that says deliver me to this Mac address and the thing that delivers it Which is just the wire doesn't know shit about IP addresses.
Rym: All it knows is it takes it and it sends it to you know switch that Mac address or if it's a hub everybody.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So that's that's how that works right.
Scott: you can see others.
Scott: you can see how these layers right.
Scott: so if I'm working with IP Addresses I don't have to think about the Mac addresses because that's just.
Scott: you know I'm one layer above that shit.
Scott: if I'm working with Mac addresses.
Scott: I don't have to think about Electricity right electricity is just taking care of I guess a simple way to explain it the OSI model.
Rym: Abstracting this out is the same as encapsulation.
Rym: The physical layer is like an envelope that holds everything above it and inside of that There's an envelope of the data link and inside of that There's an envelope with the network and you open all the envelopes and seal all the envelopes up and down the chain at both ends.
Scott: Yeah, imagine if like there were there's a post office.
Scott: Well, there is a post office right and they have the address of your house.
Scott: But then the envelope gets to your house and it says, you know apartment 1a in this building.
Scott: But then you open the envelope and it says deliver to the desk.
Scott: So now you've got an address within an address.
Scott: You got to go find that dog.
Rym: I heard you like to dress see.
Scott: so then you bring the envelope to that desk and the guy at the desk opens the envelope And it says this will be delivered to drawer number three in this desk.
Scott: So now he has to put it in.
Rym: drawer number three addresses an envelope like that and then inside I got an envelope that was like your right front pocket, right?
Scott: So then in drawer number three There's a midget and that midget opens up the envelope and it says give it to the third dust mite from the left Any right, so that's that's how this works.
Rym: I apologize that we keep saying the same thing over and over again But I realize every time I've ever taught this I mean, I've actually taught classes on this stuff Mostly to like high school kids back when I was IBM.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I always had diagrams that I pointed at examples Plus even if you explain to people they still don't sort of understand.
Scott: and the thing is this is not just Networking right.
Scott: pretty much everything you do in computing Follows this model, right?
Scott: So I'm a programmer right?
Scott: So I'm programming.
Scott: I don't have to think about the transistors flipping anymore.
Scott: I mean I could I was programming an Altair right, but I'm not.
Scott: so on top of that You've got you know, you've got the machine the assembly language in the CPU.
Rym: But Scott you're writing a program that itself Simulates the physical interactions of transistors and then you use those transistors to build the OSI model again on top of it.
Scott: Well, I could even do some FPGA and then she gets real crazy.
Rym: Oh, man Right.
Scott: So and then on top of that you've got a programming language like C where C, you know abstracts away a lot of the machine Language, but it doesn't abstract away things like memory management, right?
Scott: But then you got a computer programming language like Java or Python or Ruby which abstracts.
Scott: It's even a layer on top of C where it abstracts away the memory management.
Scott: This is the garbage collector and those sorts of things.
Scott: You don't have to think about the RAM anymore You know, all you have to think about is you know, just these concepts of variables and you know Moving data around and you don't even have to really think about the hardware of the computer at all in a way.
Scott: And then on top of that you might be using an application that you know For example something like game maker.
Scott: right game maker is a program that is written in another programming language.
Scott: You can use it to make a game Right with just a GUI by clicking on pictures or flash.
Scott: you can do the same thing, right?
Scott: You know, but and then flash has action script which is then again a layer on top.
Scott: You know
Rym: when I was really young like way young and I was playing with Q basic on the school's computer Yeah, I had this sudden revelation when I realized that the interpreter I was using was written in a language Yeah, that it was like I suddenly was like wait a minute.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: What's at the bottom?
Rym: Yep, and then that started my long road to where I am now.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you want to I mean this is the one thing that confused me for the longest time turtles all the way Down right?
Scott: It is turtles all the way down is how do you translate from?
Scott: you know?
Scott: How do you get to difference between typing in letters down to the electrons?
Scott: It seems like there's some sort of barrier in between.
Scott: How does that shit work?
Scott: That's assembly, right and Pretty much the way it works is.
Scott: you know, this is this assembly language and an assembly language, you know If you look at assembly language the way people type it it looks like, you know move L percent RDB space.
Scott: You know, you know percent our DQ.
Scott: It's basically just binary.
Scott: That's what it looks like when you're typing it in.
Scott: but the fact is that directly translates to something like zero zero one zero one zero Right and that zero one zero zero literally translates to zero.
Scott: turn this trend turn this wire.
Scott: No electricity one.
Scott: this wire has electricity zero.
Scott: This wire does not have electricity Right.
Rym: So now think about that.
Scott: when all those payments on the bottom of your CPU are gonna have electricity going into them or out Or not.
Rym: when you're writing Applications you it is no different than physically controlling machines.
Rym: You're physically controlling real moving things with mass, right?
Scott: So if you have a 64-bit processor, that means that the instructions are 64-bit.
Scott: So imagine you have 64 on and off switches in front of you.
Scott: That's it Yeah and you well and so you turn them on and off.
Scott: and this you know, There's two to the power of 64 different combinations of ways.
Scott: You can turn them on and off which is a lot It's bajillions.
Scott: All right, and that is the number of possible instructions.
Scott: There could be.
Scott: obviously They don't actually have that many instructions because you don't need that many Right, but that's how many instructions there could be and each so multiply might be zero zero zero zero one two one zero Right, whatever, you know 64 ones and zeros.
Scott: one combination of them is multiply.
Scott: So then after that you got to say well, which numbers do you want to multiply?
Scott: So there's two more 64-bit numbers which are in binary.
Scott: and then so if you send all those bits into the CPU Outcomes the other end the multiplied, you know The two numbers.
Scott: another 64-bit number which is the multiplied number is the result.
Rym: That was a pretty good.
Rym: we abstract all that.
Rym: Yeah, we abstract all that because it's boring.
Scott: I don't have to remember right what the bits are to.
Rym: actually, you know Tell an x86 CPU to multiply two numbers by each other to conceptualize it a little more simply like to back up even and abstraction Is like an analogy and note how I used a simile.
Rym: But in that when you abstract something like say I'm trying to program a Scott simulator Okay, I'm going to abstract Scott in a way.
Scott: He's not gonna program like the lungs breathing You know, that's that's not the point of the Scott simulator.
Rym: No, I might make a very detailed Abstraction.
Rym: it might approach a real Scott but much like analogies.
Rym: if your if your analogy never breaks down It is not an analogy.
Rym: It is the thing.
Rym: if I'm able to perfectly emulate Scott Absolutely, actually every single sub, you know sub atomic particle then I have made a Scott.
Rym: Yeah, straight up.
Rym: There's no difference between that Scott and this Scott.
Rym: Mm-hmm except locality, but that's yeah, you get the point.
Rym: So say I want to write a ticketing system.
Rym: I want to track problems.
Rym: I'm abstracting problems.
Rym: a lot of people who just get into programming don't actually abstract enough.
Rym: They think too close like alright I'm making a ticket.
Rym: tickets are like this and they've kind of worked through when really they should back up and say What am I trying to accomplish and then abstract that?
Rym: All right What are the basic components of a problem?
Rym: Well a problem has a person who opened the problem It has a solution and as the steps I took along the way to fix it It has the money it cost the time I spent on it, you know all these things and that is abstraction.
Rym: You're abstracting a problem into something that you can then do something with.
Scott: Yeah, I mean because the reason that works, you know abstraction is progress right is because number one We've solved most of the problems of the world right especially on low levels, right?
Scott: For example, we've solved the problem of HTTP, right?
Scott: I mean there are perfect implementations of HTTP stacks.
Scott: They're perfect effectively perfect implementations of TCP IP stacks.
Scott: You're not gonna write a better TCP IP stack or you're not gonna write a better HTTP client or server.
Scott: It's not likely right.
Scott: what you want to write is a website.
Scott: Technically you could write a website in assembly language, right?
Scott: You would have to write a TCP IP stack.
Scott: You have to write, you know an HTTP client and a server.
Scott: you would have to write all the memory management.
Scott: You would have to write an HTTP, you know all this stuff you would have to write.
Scott: instead You just want to reuse the stuff that's already been written and you only want to worry about the problems that you Care about.
Scott: the things that you care about are what do my website look like and how does my website work?
Scott: and if you actually have to Rewrite or think about the electricity on the wire, which is something that's happening when you're visiting a website While you're making your website, you're never gonna solve any website problems.
Scott: You know, where would Google be if they actually had to worry about the electricity on the wires directly, right?
Rym: Well, they don't because there's a lot of it.
Scott: It costs a lot of money saying if they had to worry about that from the beginning They only wanted to solve the problem of searching.
Scott: if they had to solve the problem of electricity and on a wire Before they could solve the problem of searching they never would have solved the problem of searching.
Scott: Of course
Rym: this gets into even not just abstraction But also, you know standing on the shoulders of giants that every human alive today At least if you live in a society that is free and you are not Disadvantaged due to the fact that we're not as humans that good at this stuff.
Rym: yet You know society and being nice to each other and everything.
Rym: You basically have this huge set of resources that are the consist Consituent knowledge of everyone that came before and most of it's on the internet.
Rym: So you start at this high level and you can pick very high level problems to solve because you're not worried about Instantiating food on a given day.
Scott: It's like all right.
Scott: Think about something that's more accessible to computers, right?
Scott: Let's say you're a chef, right?
Scott: Imagine if you wanted to become a chef you had to reinvent knives and knife sharpening.
Scott: you had to reinvent forging Right, you had to reinvent Mining of metals.
Scott: you had to reinvent, you know the fire.
Scott: you had to reinvent ovens You had to reinvent.
Rym: I like how fire gets a definite article right?
Rym: I know I go too far.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Imagine if you had to reinvent all those things and build your own oven.
Rym: Oh, you mean like a bunch.
Rym: you mean like if a biologist had to reinvent calculus.
Scott: Yeah You know.
Scott: or make your own knives while someone might really like to do that and I say go for it.
Scott: That's awesome.
Scott: Right, it's not gonna cut a tomato, but right if your job is chef You're really want to just think about the recipe and the preparation of the food to make it as good as possible.
Rym: It also to use a less, you know silly example because this is kind of silly to think art.
Rym: I want to be a chef.
Rym: I want to do all this.
Rym: What if you're a chef and you really focus on cutting the tomatoes into?
Rym: Absolute perfect cubes when really that's not the important part That's not the part that you want to get to.
Scott: it might be depending on what you're doing But it's rarely most likely not we.
Rym: actually we use these this a lot in the Tuesday shows and in our lectures on gaming Role-playing games.
Rym: a lot of people who get sick of Dungeons & Dragons get sick of it because it doesn't abstract the boring shit.
Rym: Yeah, and games like burning wheel?
Rym: They instead of saying I have 58 electron pieces and one platinum piece and five rubies you say I have a level four Money, yep, and you abstract all that haggling and buying stuff and keeping track to.
Rym: I roll the dice once.
Rym: Yes, I can afford the sword.
Rym: No I can't afford the sword.
Rym: Yep and you get and you get to skip the boring part of buying the sword and get to the awesome part of using the.
Scott: So if you want some you want to haggle you make it one easier or one point harder to Succeed at that roll of the dice, you know Basically you come up with some system that is not the original system because it was the original.
Scott: if it was actually money It wouldn't be it wouldn't be an analogy.
Scott: It would be the actual thing.
Scott: All right, so you come up with something that is simpler.
Rym: There's a role-playing game.
Rym: Well, it's designed to use real money between the game master and the players.
Scott: What are you role-playing as stock brokers?
Rym: No, I know merchants, but I like we could make some money with this.
Scott: Love tournaments at bags.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'm sure that these stats as a player player versus environment.
Scott: Of course, of course Ah Plus one sword actually a poker based PVP RPG was real money as it now with real money, but it's been done.
Scott: stay with real money.
Scott: Let's take a little luck out of it add a little role-playing to it.
Rym: We should write the rules and just put something online and watch the crazy chaos is gonna ensue.
Scott: Oh, we should make.
Scott: we should make a website where you can play it to avoid all the regulations about online poker because it's not Poker.
Rym: Nah Playing and all we do.
Rym: here's the brilliant part all you do.
Scott: and here's how.
Rym: here's how Scott let's hear me out.
Rym: You keep the books of who has how much money in each local gaming group.
Rym: You keep it on the server for them.
Rym: You're not handling money.
Rym: You're just handling fake money and you tell people you shouldn't use this to determine how much money to give your friends and who owes you how much money and They will.
Scott: anyway I was thinking that everyone would send you a money which should be the monthly fee and then you would give out Prizes.
Rym: now giving out prizes is a thorny ground.
Rym: you give out virtual fucking prizes because fuck that The prize is never abstract prizes.
Scott: Yes, here's a picture of a present.
Rym: here's a picture of a $20 bill.
Scott: Here's a picture of Andrew Jackson.
Scott: It's actually no really is a photo.
Scott: So now there's no numbers next to him.
Rym: If everything we said doesn't make sense just follow the Wikipedia link that I'm gonna put.
Rym: I'm sure the Wikipedia paid it.
Rym: Yes, the Wikipedia page has a picture of the OSI model.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean this this concept of abstraction is pretty much the key and core concept to modern Computing, you know for any you know, whether you're IT whether you're CS what you know, even if you're in you know.
Scott: I mean like think about biologists, you know, think about biology.
Scott: Technically this physics going on way down there.
Rym: You know biology is just abstracted physics, right?
Scott: You know, and then this it's also abstract that You know this, you know, everything is abstraction, right?
Scott: You want to think about a problem on a higher abstraction level right to figure it out?
Scott: Because if you actually had to think about what every freaking Electron and subatomic particle was doing when DNA was restructuring itself now You might need to zoom in.
Scott: You would never get it all.
Rym: You might have a problem where you do have to zoom in way low and Some things can't be that abstracted.
Rym: That is true.
Rym: But that's not where you should start.
Rym: I mean, I realize as we won't talk about inheritance or anything or classes or abstract classes.
Scott: Well, I could write a program in Python and it might have a problem where there's too much memory.
Scott: It's using all the memory on the computer and I might have to look one level lower.
Scott: You know on the abstraction Let you know to see where the problem is.
Scott: if I can't find the problem in the Python code itself that happens pretty often.
Scott: But you don't start, you know, that does not an excuse or a good reason to throw away You know this higher level abstraction and write everything in C because then everything is gonna be a pain in the ass Or even within a simple application.
Rym: say you're simulating, I don't know, fireman.
Rym: So you write like the fireman class and then you inherit down and make very specific implementations of fireman.
Rym: You don't start with the very specific implementations when you're writing code because then when you're trying to work up to the more abstract stuff You're basically Guaranteed to have made a terrible mistake.
Scott: Yeah All right, if you don't get by now and you know, it's just real important.
Scott: So we want to give a lot of examples and we don't have any visuals.
Scott: So we want to give a lot of examples.
Rym: I wanted to say like, how can she something?
Rym: but I got nothing here.
Scott: No I didn't give any opportunities.
Rym: It's not the right time for that.
Rym: I got to save it.
Scott: You are who I thought you were.
Rym: Mmm, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.