Rym: It's Monday December 27th 2010.
Rym: I'm Rym some Scott and this is GeekNights tonight predictions past and future.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, you know what?
Rym: I'm gonna say, right?
Rym: Right about now.
Scott: Well, I mean you would say woman but the thing is it's not actually cold.
Scott: It's just fucking.
Rym: It fucked warm yesterday.
Scott: No, not really quite warm.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I was in Rochester.
Rym: You were here and snowed snowed a lot.
Scott: What's that?
Rym: I wonder if the snow in Rochester is higher or lower than there was basically no snow until we got to about.
Rym: So the Tappan Zee.
Scott: so on the return trip.
Scott: So you don't really know how much snow is in Rochester because you left before the snow arrived.
Rym: I think the snow really got that bad out there.
Rym: Let's really just the city.
Rym: But anyway, you know, we made it through all this crazy snow.
Rym: We are three blocks from the apartment and we get stuck.
Rym: actually we're not stuck.
Rym: We're fine.
Rym: in front of us This livery car is stuck and around it our cabs and other cars all stuck and we couldn't get around him.
Rym: So we parked on the sidewalk and gave up.
Scott: It looks like there was plenty of snow in Rochester according to the weather report Not only yours as much snow as we got here.
Scott: Apparently it's gonna.
Scott: it's still snowing there and it's gonna continue snowing there for a couple days here.
Scott: What's it?
Scott: We're already done.
Rym: Yeah, we got just the drifting.
Rym: Yeah, but much more important Winter classics coming up.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think people really know but there's a new tradition of the NHL.
Scott: Is that on New Year's Day to compete with the bowl games the college footballs?
Rym: Yeah, we have a real men's sport.
Scott: Yeah, they put out and they they have one hockey game.
Scott: That is outside.
Scott: Holy crap outside hockey Real man hockey.
Scott: It's mostly the same as inside hockey, but basically they make a rink.
Scott: So it's.
Scott: it's not like it's on a lake.
Scott: It's not as badass as it could be see.
Rym: the thing is though watching NHL players play outside.
Rym: They're not used to things like glare.
Scott: Well, yeah, the Sun is gonna be out.
Scott: They're not used to the incredible.
Scott: It's gonna.
Scott: you know, it's gonna sell out.
Scott: this thing always sells out.
Scott: It's been going for a few.
Rym: the ice surface is way different in the Sun, too So it's much louder.
Scott: the surface is different even though it is professionally maintained.
Rym: with all the right You got that sunlight.
Rym: it's.
Scott: it's actually surprisingly more slippery and the temperature and the wind also becomes effective.
Scott: Yeah wind so, you know, it's not even though it's not on a pond with no wall around it.
Scott: Like really like, you know badasses.
Scott: It's it's still pretty good.
Rym: I Just don't think a lot of our friends quite appreciate it.
Rym: We're even like none of our friends.
Scott: See, none of our friends really appreciate sports.
Scott: That's why I think that a lot of people listen to this show might get the impression that we care about sports a lot more Than we do, but I think it's really just that we talk about sports on the show More, you know more often than we do in real life in order to sort of get people to realize like hey geekery and sports Are not these mutually exclusive things, you know, you don't need to be hating on sports to be a geek.
Scott: In fact, it's good to like some or all of them.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I always say the guy who's memorized all the lookup tables for hit locations in mech warrior or Battle tech is the same as the guy who memorized all the stats for his football team.
Scott: Yeah, exactly and go look up.
Scott: They got some freakin nerdy ass stats going on these days, right?
Scott: They're like, oh no No, you can't judge by that in especially baseball baseball is the most stats nerdiness of any of any of the sports.
Scott: You know,
Rym: it's funny to me that our crew, you know we're having our annual front row crew New Year's bash in the city this time and We post the thing like who
Scott: wants to
Rym: go do karaoke and who wants to watch the winter classic and I think Gonna be me and Scott and Andrew watching the winter classic and everybody else.
Scott: Nobody appreciates the ice hockey.
Rym: You think they went to RIT, but then again who went to the hockey games with us?
Rym: It was you and me and like two or three other people who were regulars like Emily Yuko would come when she could and Greg would come Stop coming.
Rym: Yeah, Alex went once twice, but now most of the crew didn't actually go to all the RIT hockey game.
Scott: I went to every single one.
Scott: I was able to yep In fact, we've stopped playing Crystal Chronicles to go to the hockey game and then we came back and we still beat it in time.
Rym: Yep So, yeah, you got any news because I kind of want to get right to the main bit of the predictions because I'm kind of.
Rym: You know, it's the holiday season.
Rym: We've been missing shows here and there and I'm kind of hungry and I'm kind of lazy.
Rym: Want to get done with this?
Rym: All right.
Scott: Well One news that I saw today.
Scott: That was pretty interesting, you know, cuz I'm not at work.
Scott: But so, you know, I'm looking at the internet.
Rym: I was at work.
Rym: The thing is, me and two other people made it into the office.
Scott: The thing is oh you don't go to you can go to work.
Scott: Well, you know I have off all week.
Scott: So you think oh I'd be looking at more internets.
Scott: No, I'm actually looking at a lot less internets looking at almost no internets.
Rym: Cuz he's doing stuff.
Scott: Yeah, because looking at internets The only reason I look at it so much is cuz I'm in at work if I'm not working.
Scott: That's the only thing there is to do.
Scott: I can't read a book I can't play a video game, but if I'm home and I don't got nothing to do I can read a book.
Scott: I'm playing video game.
Scott: I can work on my own project.
Scott: that you know.
Scott: I don't want my work to be a work for hire for my company.
Scott: I can you know cook I can clean I can do all sorts of stuff.
Rym: So you play video games all day mostly.
Scott: That's only cuz video game season.
Scott: I mean look at fucking steam with their sales.
Rym: It's been video game season for like a year for me lately.
Scott: I got all my wee downloads back.
Scott: Nintendo finally saved me there.
Rym: Yeah It's just.
Rym: it's weird that I'm not playing as many board games as I want to but I really want to as much as I like Video games.
Rym: I play counter-strike like every day lately.
Scott: I finished building the robot I was working on and I started designing that board game that we were talking about.
Rym: before which one?
Rym: the the garymandering one?
Scott: Yeah, it's not I can't really.
Scott: you know, I got only got so far.
Rym: Well, you know, we got to do.
Rym: We always make the mistake.
Rym: We have to make the POC the simplest dumbass game.
Scott: That's what I did.
Rym: Is it done?
Scott: It's really simple and dumbass.
Rym: But yeah That's not gonna make the.
Rym: well I got to make a Firefox plug-in.
Rym: that basically is the front end for that delicious thing.
Rym: Mm-hmm, our box plugins, by the way for anyone out there who's you know a techie, but you don't make stuff way easy to make.
Scott: I also got to do chrome plugins.
Rym: In fact Chrome extensions 99% of making a Firefox plug-in is actually not plugins.
Scott: extensions different.
Rym: Yeah, designing the UI to look good.
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty much.
Scott: all we need to do is have a button a couple buttons in the toolbar with yeah with icons.
Rym: I'm not even worried about like the integration of getting the bookmarks back or any of that.
Rym: yet I pretty much just want first I want to make the make a bookmark cuz that's I use that more than they look at my bookmarks
Scott: exactly anyway, so In this news the only one of the only interesting internet tech news I saw today Is that Putin the president?
Scott: Well the Prime Minister of Russia the king of Russia Scott is he who's?
Rym: You know Mevdev is right?
Rym: Yeah, he's.
Scott: technically he's the president.
Scott: It's one of those countries where they have the you know president and prime minister and it's like well who's really in charge?
Scott: You're what?
Rym: well, you know, we'll use the authoritative source.
Rym: according to WikiLeaks.
Rym: Putin is in charge of everything.
Scott: exactly what I was saying.
Scott: So he gave an order right?
Scott: I think the shows he's in charge of everything.
Scott: He ordered a Russian move to Linux, right?
Scott: So, I mean Germany sort of did this and it failed.
Scott: All right, if I remember correctly or was it one city in Germany?
Scott: I don't remember exactly but wasn't it Munich?
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: There was you know, there's some sort of thing like all right, we're gonna do it and then it was not going it.
Scott: So well, but apparently he you know, this is tried to happen in many times in Russia before to limited success.
Scott: But now what?
Scott: because you know, the king gave the order The odds are is that it's actually gonna go through and they're actually gonna you know Start moving their butts.
Scott: and there's a whole plan, you know a five-year plan to get this done between the years of 2011 and 2015 20 forever.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know, this is gonna be pretty interesting to see.
Scott: you know a do they actually do it?
Scott: B What comes of it?
Scott: see how long it takes because what it could be?
Rym: It's a situation that America cannot have with our current government of the dog and ho the.
Rym: let's do the right thing Technologically and force it down everyone's throats whether they like it or not.
Rym: Yep I don't know if it'll work though because Russia does not have a stellar history of technological prowess.
Scott: Well, no, actually the problem is I think it's sort of it's hard to figure out like what the reason for this is like.
Scott: Okay, obviously saving money in the government, you know, good idea, right?
Scott: Always a good to be openness.
Scott: You know for the people it's still a good idea right not being dependent upon a u.s.
Rym: Centric OS company.
Scott: Yeah, very good idea, right?
Scott: Russia is where all the hackers are at.
Scott: So you want to secure up against them, right and Maybe they'll come work for you.
Scott: If you're all cool.
Rym: Also think of this a move like this will basically trickle down through the education system and certifications and Right now we have the situation where if you want a shitty Windows administrator You can pay him like 12 bucks an hour.
Rym: They're a dime a dozen.
Rym: even if you want a shitty Linux administrator They're scarily hard to come by.
Scott: Yep, very hard, you know and a good one.
Scott: What you're gonna do is you're gonna get a Windows guy who's gonna search Google and copy and paste which up or you're gonna get One of those.
Rym: I have a Red Hat certification and then he sits down he types service HTTPd start and it doesn't work and he doesn't know what to do.
Rym: Like you ever seen the Etsy?
Rym: do you even know what's in Etsy?
Scott: do you even know Even know what I what I mean when I say Etsy.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's like they sell crafts.
Rym: Do you install everything in user local?
Scott: maybe opt like you install things in places.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: That was the question.
Rym: an unnamed person at an unnamed former company I worked for asked me when I was trying to like get him to administer some stuff so I could work in other things.
Rym: and He asked me and I quote so Where did you install Apache?
Scott: Yeah, I mean this is that that's the kind of question.
Rym: The answer would have been you're fired.
Scott: Yeah, I mean when someone asked that question, right?
Scott: It's obvious that they come from Windows background.
Scott: because you install anything on Windows.
Scott: The number one thing is the location in the file system where you are installing it, right?
Rym: No, they've gone down a road of things are still monolithic, but at least they're all in.
Rym: you know.
Scott: program files Yeah, but in you know in the Unix Linux world, it doesn't.
Rym: that's not how well It is.
Rym: for a lot of enterprise stuff to a lot of things are just and a lot of stuff I install ends up because of the bullshit enterprise proprietary stuff.
Rym: It's got a user local install with its own like Sun Java Jerry that only it uses because it wants some busted ass old version And it wants its own busted ass libraries for everything.
Rym: I don't know why people fucking do that shit because they don't know better.
Scott: I wouldn't I wouldn't use something if they were so shitty.
Rym: Yeah, I wish I had that option.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, I'm getting there though.
Rym: No, I'm working on secret projects, you know all my complaints about enterprise software and how shitty it is.
Scott: He's gonna replace it all.
Rym: I got one enterprise vendor where I was like look You were one of a small number of people who make this product.
Rym: Here's the list of what I want.
Rym: you don't do it and neither does anyone else.
Rym: and Instead of saying price discount, which is basically what I was going for from all these people I expected to pay less for the same shit.
Rym: These guys were like, well write it.
Rym: You're right Your design is better than a. well, let's do it.
Scott: Coming along so far so good really that did they actually show you something that was made.
Rym: they gay.
Rym: I have a debt of her they get.
Rym: I have a beta version of the product that Implemented a lot of what I wanted pretty quick and the guys actually like I'm working with their developers like directly.
Scott: They're not stupid.
Rym: No, they're not stupid.
Scott: Oh my god is amazing.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: This is a public company odd now.
Rym: Ticketing systems.
Rym: Suffice it to say.
Rym: I'm not anywhere yet, but I'm working on it.
Scott: Anyway, yeah No, this is this is gonna be interesting and I am going to be very curious to see how this goes.
Rym: Well one well now I don't want to get into my political views, but I feel like this sort of thing with technology is impossible to do in the US but it could Revolutionize American government more so than just about anything else just forcing technology to be updated.
Rym: Yeah, even if we update it to crappy stuff it'll at least put it on everyone's radar.
Scott: I just want to refer to my extremely old thing of the day which shows dog and home.
Scott: No, Hillary Clinton being asked about firefight.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: But the thing is.
Rym: what was beautiful about that video was heard the expression on her face She smiled.
Rym: that smile of I don't know what you just said and I'm going to stall until someone fixes this for me.
Scott: Well, the only thing that was reassuring about the video was just how many people in the audience were like, yeah Even normal people who know nothing about computers.
Rym: Remember that their nephew said something about using that firebird thing because the IE thing with the blue thing is bad.
Rym: Yeah, I know that much.
Scott: I think it's definitely right a Situation where we're getting to the point where it's like think about the olden days, right?
Scott: You would go into a factory and the people who worked on the factory floor They had to do this repetitive task over and over so they mastered it, right?
Scott: But then the big guys on top would come down and say oh do it this way We know better.
Rym: look at the old trope.
Rym: when they don't know of the factory worker or the engineer who you know The big boss says do it this way He says okay, and then he hacked something together on his own because he knows better and the foreman knows he knows better He doesn't say anything.
Scott: So I think you know, if you look at offices even though most people have no idea of anything about computers, right?
Scott: They still you know, they maybe they try out Chrome and it's so fast.
Scott: So they you know, that's they can tell that right away or outlook crashes and their Gmail always works, right?
Scott: And they know that even though they're not computer experts.
Scott: They know, you know something, you know, they have that intuition.
Scott: They know that something's better or they like something better and they have a preference whereas the people on top are you know?
Scott: Executive types who are using.
Scott: they use a blackberry because all they do is email all day and outlook So they never use anything else so that you know That's all they want in the whole world and that so that result is that everyone below them has to use the same Stuff, even though it's worse for them.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: We have a weird.
Rym: it's a two-way situation.
Rym: I'd say half the workers.
Rym: I'm it's not actually half but there's two classes of the kind of the factory workers of the IT white-collar world.
Rym: half of them Don't know shit and they want to do things an old busted way.
Scott: and if people above them try to make them change they just Well, I don't say what the IT work is now at the regular office workers.
Rym: Oh, even the regular office workers half of them.
Rym: You just can't change anything Or they just they can't deal with it, but the other half know better but the people above them won't let them change.
Rym: Mm-hmm, you know like.
Rym: imagine the kid who gets a job like over the summer.
Rym: We're as a clerk somewhere and his boss is like I need you to do the time sheets.
Rym: Here's the Excel macro That connects to our excess database And you know better.
Rym: There is no way you will be able to convince your boss that the MySQL thing you wrote in ten minutes is better I'll write it into.
Scott: actually just do it.
Scott: I'll write it in ten minutes.
Scott: I'll just use it and that'll be that.
Rym: Yeah, but then what's coming out of that?
Rym: the Excel spreadsheet that the boss wants.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so well that seat the thing is.
Rym: that's the brilliant part.
Rym: the really good people Ignore the incompetent bosses work around it with technology and have infinite free time at work.
Rym: Mm-hmm That's why we sit looking at the internet all the time Yep, so I want to talk about this really briefly because you know Russia and everything.
Rym: It's interesting that Stuxnet that virus that was may or may not have been written by the Israelis Supposedly seems to have actually taken out physical hardware in Iran's nuclear program.
Scott: I thought that.
Scott: you know, I didn't think that was news.
Rym: It's new.
Rym: basically It's.
Rym: it wasn't sure.
Rym: it was all speculation and the speculation has become much more firm.
Scott: Well, I mean there wasn't.
Scott: I did you know it.
Scott: there was speculation.
Scott: I mean who would be speculating?
Scott: It's like oh we think this thing did this but you know if nothing happened.
Scott: Well, it's like well, how do you?
Rym: Well, there there is a lot of precedent for this I mean remember the u.s.
Rym: Sabotage that Russian gas pipeline back in the Soviet era.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: You know about that, right?
Rym: Kinda, basically we knew the Russians were trying to steal control software for this big gas pipeline.
Scott: Wow Why couldn't you just tell me how complicated could that be?
Rym: This is a long time ago Soviet Union All right.
Rym: So we the u.s.
Rym: Planted bad Evil software that we knew they would find and steal.
Rym: they did steal it.
Rym: They used it not long that long later.
Rym: It caused one of the biggest non-nuclear explosions in the history of the world uh-huh, and That was considered a successful intelligence operation and Stuxnet is basically a similar thing.
Rym: Supposedly it took out about a thousand IR one centrifuges that Iran was using to enrich uranium.
Rym: All right My what's it?
Rym: Well, we'll talk about this again in the main show because you know We're talking about predictions and I think Scott has a prediction along these lines, but I posit a theory.
Rym: I do not believe that Israel actually wrote this and deployed it because I don't think Iran is that technologically incompetent and I don't think it would be that easy to get a Virus on the computer on the computers that control the centrifuges that would do it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean little.
Scott: yeah I mean, how would you specifically get a specific virus under us?
Scott: I mean, it's one thing to put a virus on the internet in general and then it's gonna get a bunch of Windows PCs But you don't know which ones.
Scott: but to target specific computers of the specific virus You need to have a specific person who's gonna eat it.
Scott: You need to target it somehow.
Scott: you need to either put it on a website that you know a Particular person goes time, but then you have an inside person it physically install again.
Rym: You know to play my own devil's advocate you could do this with old-school intelligence.
Rym: You know leaving USB sticks at the factory around things like that having agent Yeah, but you have to have someone in there Yeah, which is you know, I'm pretty sure Israel would be able to arrange something like that anyway.
Rym: But my speculation is much simpler because the way these documents are leaking and the things Iran has said.
Rym: I would wager That Iran's government needs an excuse to not have made the bomb Because if they actually have Workwhile working nuclear weapons The people that they are pacifying with their nuclear program will be angry that they are not threatening to use them or actually using them Mm-hmm, and the government Ahmadinejad is not a stupid man.
Rym: And I I. this is why you should.
Rym: he's pretty crazy Yeah, but this is wild speculation.
Rym: I would speculate that even if this was an Israeli thing or whatever, you know If there's just a targeted attack from the outside Even if it failed it is in Iran's vested interest to act as though it succeeded and blame enemies of the state for delaying their nuclear program thus giving them an excuse to not actually have a working nuclear program and yet Simultaneously get all the benefits of saying that you have one
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: That's all.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I can tell you don't care at all about world politics.
Rym: So anyway things of the day you got a thing of the day.
Scott: I do.
Scott: so check this out.
Scott: this guy This video was on the internet and then it got taken down, but I found it again.
Scott: So take that internet.
Scott: Basically, this guy pulls a funny prank that I think is actually a dangerous prank that I would not have pulled.
Rym: I'm surprised he did not get shot.
Scott: Yeah, he basically puts was stocking over his head like a like a bird like a Mug, you know like he's gonna rob the store.
Scott: and then he just goes legitimately shopping at a bunch of stores freaking out the the store clerk.
Rym: My favorite guy is the guy who obviously is ready for this because he runs back locks himself in a cage and just says I call Police you go away.
Scott: Yeah But the thing is is like he did this.
Scott: It looks like he's doing it in the UK, which is much safer.
Rym: Actually, there aren't that many guns.
Scott: Yeah but I mean I think the only country that I would will be willing to risk such a prank is Japan because it had the nation where there's apparently zero Danger of doing even deadly pranks on average unsuspecting.
Scott: Yeah, you can just you know open up porta potties.
Scott: You can send people out of you know, hot tubs careening down mountains the sniper prank.
Scott: Yeah, you can do whatever the hell you want.
Scott: in terms of pranks in Japan It's like if you're a prank you can break.
Scott: if you're pranking you can break no law Especially if you have a camera.
Rym: actually one underrated one is the one where they just had a floor in an office building That would just collapse into a pool of water.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so I mean in Japan it's pretty safe.
Scott: the worst it's like some guy might come at you with a sword.
Scott: You just run away first.
Rym: Remember this might have been done for TV.
Rym: So there's a there's a not zero chance true that they went in and primed the people like look we're gonna do a prank.
Rym: So just freak out for the cam.
Scott: that is true.
Scott: is that there is a camera in there, right?
Scott: So these people they're running and hiding.
Scott: but and there's you think oh, they're just seeing this robber.
Scott: But actually they're also seeing a guy videotaping.
Rym: the guy might have a hidden camera, but I note the camera is a little too Steady.
Scott: Yeah, there's someone follow a given watching him.
Scott: So yeah, I bet they tried this at a bunch of places until they actually found someone who wasn't looking at the camera.
Scott: But you know anyway, it's so funny.
Scott: So even though it might be fake
Rym: It's Monday and it's just a college humor, but it's actually a very important message, especially if you Monday listeners I know you like me and like many of us will be ready for bed be tired and Have a computer connected to the internet and you'll sit there drawing squares on your desktop and watching YouTube videos.
Rym: You've already seen Long into the night when you could sleep like this.
Rym: There's this desire for entertainment that is stronger than the desire to have a good night's sleep.
Rym: This video is for you.
Rym: it is actually Surprisingly apt.
Scott: it is Scarily accurate.
Rym: is that part where he's like you're just sitting there drawing squares on your desktop and I'm like, I've done that.
Rym: I've done that many nights.
Scott: I Usually don't have you know, I don't have much problem falling asleep because I you know, I don't have trouble falling asleep But I will delay sleep.
Scott: I know good reason I don't really delay sleep but I'll you know because I can always if I go reach for a DS or for a book or for a comic book and I just go at it and don't you know?
Scott: switch to anything else and I just keep going at it.
Scott: Eventually, I will just be sleep.
Rym: There's some Final Fantasy.
Rym: That'll get you.
Scott: Oh good.
Scott: Hey Works every time.
Scott: Dragon Quest 9 was doing that pretty well until my DS got stolen.
Scott: So then I lost the save game So I not playing that game again.
Rym: Actually, I don't do it as much as I used to RIT.
Rym: I was really bad about that.
Rym: Sometimes I just sit there at night watching AMVs.
Rym: if I had class at like 8 a.m.
Rym: The next day.
Scott: I didn't do that.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: So metamoment metamoment we're gonna be at MAGFest.
Scott: Oh shit this real soon, isn't it?
Rym: Yeah, that's real soon.
Rym: Oh crap, we're doing.
Rym: losing should be fun and a bunch of other panels.
Rym: It's an updated version of losing should be fun.
Scott: They needed an updated version.
Rym: It didn't need an updated version.
Scott: We've learned a lot since then so I don't get it's like we did that other panel at PAX, right?
Scott: We did two panels there basically right not counting the crap late show.
Scott: Which yeah guys game mechanics mechanism is done and losing should be fun.
Rym: and give me guys losing should be fun.
Rym: We did a graciously unrealized potential.
Rym: All right, we did on Sunday.
Rym: I was tired as balls, right?
Scott: But it's like clearly right.
Scott: the game mechanism design.
Rym: That's like our best panels like the best.
Scott: So why are the people not asking us to do the best one?
Rym: Yeah, I should forward you.
Rym: Did you tell them?
Scott: Hey, this is our best one.
Rym: I should forward you.
Rym: the conversations I have with all conventions because usually it's along the lines of Here are like the three panels that we want to do and this one is fucking awesome.
Rym: And I get an email back like I heard you guys did something called beyond Dungeons & Dragons.
Rym: That was really good.
Rym: Could you run that?
Scott: I'd be like look.
Rym: I was like.
Rym: usually I'm like no I'd be like.
Scott: you should just tell only offer the ones that are the best ones.
Scott: don't offer the other ones.
Scott: Just be like look we've got a new panel game.
Scott: I can get game mechanics mechanism design.
Rym: you wants to do it thing is at least it's not like it's packs.
Rym: We're gonna do the same panel again, and I don't want to do the same time.
Scott: if it's West East, you know.
Rym: But even that it we did beyond the India two PAX West's, all right, it's a new.
Rym: it's a panel for an audience.
Rym: We've never done and I think actually it was a really good panel and we didn't run.
Scott: not bad But it's not the best.
Scott: so we want to go out with the best.
Rym: Well, we didn't run it as many times as we should have and could have.
Scott: Anyway, it's met a moment here.
Scott: Let's let's see.
Rym: So magfest will be there.
Rym: We'll be chilling with John St.
Rym: John and James Rolfe and all the cool people.
Scott: Yep, and I know it's holidays.
Rym: So the book club book is Michio Kaku's hyperspace.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Are you reading it Scott?
Scott: No, that's gonna be for a while.
Scott: Really?
Rym: It's it's a quick book to read.
Scott: I don't even have a copy.
Rym: really You need a copy.
Rym: I got a couple Next year also coming up in the near future.
Rym: you can google the details but no pants day is coming.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: January is in the winner.
Rym: It's early in January.
Rym: We'll be there doing our no pants thing and I recommend if you live in a city that is doing it Do it.
Rym: if you live in a city that is not doing it go to the website and volunteer to do it.
Rym: Yep Anyway doesn't quite have the same impact on cities without mass transit though.
Scott: No, what are you doing?
Scott: a city with no mass transit?
Rym: Uh walk to work in your boxers or just go to work in your boxers, but you just you're driving in a car Yeah, and then you get out in the parking lot and walk go to Walmart I guess and they'll just kick your ass out.
Rym: What rule you're breaking?
Scott: I have pants on pants on you out of the store for any reason.
Rym: Yeah, if they got it, what are they gonna say except for being black?
Scott: They can't Being a Jew right, but they can kick you out of the store for not having pants.
Scott: that's perfectly legal.
Rym: Well, you make a scene and you film it All right, so it's the end of the year.
Scott: There's really when it comes to the end of the decade It's true.
Scott: So it's millennia.
Scott: Just kidding.
Scott: Uh So there's really not really much news ever except there's tons of news.
Rym: There's like ten.
Rym: tech news is That I could have talked about like right now.
Rym: I had trouble picking.
Rym: I did the succinate things.
Rym: there was something I could just kind of mention as a blurb.
Rym: I didn't want to go long.
Scott: Well, the thing is right.
Scott: We don't want to do a news show anyway, right and at the same time We're sort of running out of tech, you know non news topics.
Rym: I'm not Okay.
Scott: How come you couldn't come up with any.
Rym: I came up with like ten.
Scott: you just didn't Grab people and you know it.
Scott: I think they were good.
Scott: No, whatever.
Rym: So I want to talk about link rot.
Scott: That is a good idea.
Scott: We should put that on the list.
Rym: It's been on the list for like a month.
Scott: You didn't mention it earlier.
Scott: I was saying hey, what should we do the show on?
Scott: Anyway, yeah, so I came up with a good idea earlier, which is hey, let's start a thing where every year We will talk about the biggest stuff that happened in the past year, I know this is a cliche.
Scott: everyone does this But you know what?
Scott: I think we're gonna do it better than everyone else because we're smarter than everyone else and we will also predict for the next year.
Scott: and then it'll be even more interesting next year because you can look back at the previous predictions and see if we are geniuses or morons and That will be the.
Scott: so this show might not be the greatest but it'll be awesome next year when we do the second show And forever there, you know, so we're laying some groundwork.
Rym: I feel like I don't.
Rym: I originally I wanted to talk a lot about the previous Year, and then I realized just now because it's the end of the decade, you know decades ago at least in America They're kind of seen as like the boundaries of things like the 90s was the age of the Internet and then the 2000s were this Kind of whole different world and now we're in the 2010s and everything's way different again.
Rym: Yep, but at the same time I don't know if I want to go back and talk about all you know What happened in the last decade because every tech site in the world is gonna do that.
Rym: I kind of really just want I mean you want to talk about the last decade here.
Scott: I'll take you through it ready.
Rym: Look at the last a year.
Scott: in the year 2000 They were worried about right y2k and it was a legitimate worry.
Rym: you assholes us tech guys fixed it for you and Napster was still rocking.
Scott: and then in 2010 Facebook in Farmville, there you go.
Scott: That's that's the little decade.
Scott: That's how far we've come.
Rym: The stock market in 2000 pretty good.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: There were.
Rym: there were no tablets back then Smartphones.
Rym: people didn't have smartphones hell in 2000.
Rym: I didn't have a cell phone.
Scott: Nope, not me.
Scott: I mean they my family had them.
Scott: I didn't have.
Rym: yeah, I had one in like 1998 But that was the family's like brick phone.
Scott: Anyway, let's talk about 2010 in no particular order, right?
Scott: The biggest I guess tech thing that any tech site is gonna report on is the iPad.
Scott: just because they always Talk about Apple more than anyone else because well Apple gets you know, the lot most attention.
Rym: Apple very brilliantly created a third like a third and viable market for tablets because the market of Doctors and workers never really panned out and the market of artists never really panned out.
Scott: Yeah Well, you know, I think they definitely you know, pretty much anything Apple makes people buy I think Alma, you know, I mean even the new Apple TV, which I think is pretty terrible, you know It's just really small which makes it it's better than the previous Apple TV, but it's still not good especially if you compare it to the Mac Mini, but Apparently they sold a million of those.
Scott: So You know, what do I know?
Scott: The only thing that disappoints me about the iPad still is that while you know It is saw it is made the idea of a tablet device useful to apparently many people.
Scott: It is still not a tablet device for the artists, which is what is needed.
Rym: Yes, but you know, we've talked about this so we won't talk about it further.
Rym: But that's all I have to say.
Rym: it's an ish market that might not be served in the next year.
Scott: No WikiLeaks was gigantic in 2010. surprisingly recent - yeah I mean I was given money to WikiLeaks like a long time ago But it took this long people to actually lose their shit about it.
Scott: The Kinect came out just recently.
Scott: I'm still not exactly how sure how well that's gonna pan out in terms of will this be popular?
Rym: You know, let's just start throwing right into predictions Next year.
Rym: I don't think the Kinect is going to be a major player.
Scott: I think the Kinect is basically like the Wiimote.
Scott: right.
Scott: and the thing is, you know The Wiimote had plenty of you know hacks to people like oh look what I was able to do with the Wiimote.
Rym: You can do the same thing with a webcam.
Rym: Just give it time.
Scott: Yeah well, no, there are things that Kinect can do kind of webcam can't do now, but The Kinect is you know, it's people are hacking it.
Scott: They're having fun with it You know, but you know some people are having fun with the games.
Scott: but but industry was.
Rym: we know what's gonna happen.
Scott: It's gonna be the same as the Wiimote.
Rym: They're going to be a whole bunch of games that use it in a gimmicky fashion.
Rym: a few games We'll use it.
Rym: Well, and then they'll just be a component in a lot of games Basically not know worthy.
Scott: I actually read this interesting thing is a story.
Scott: It's just anecdotal story.
Scott: So whatever it's not evidence of anything, but some family like, you know an old lady and her husband, right?
Scott: They bought the the Wii and the Wii fit and whatever right and they were like, yay So they went back to the store Right, and they were like, oh let's get some more.
Scott: we say look around and there was nothing for them because there's only one We fit and that's it.
Scott: And it's Yeah, but I mean it's like it comes with Wii Sports.
Scott: So it's like you turn around from the other side.
Scott: It's like okay I go to the store and I buy a Wii and I get Mario and then I go back to the store and I've bought the four Mario games.
Scott: then I go back to the store and There's nothing.
Rym: well, one of the best multiplayer games on the Wii to this day is the GameCube version of Wario.
Scott: where?
Scott: Right, so I think the Wii is is it's you know.
Scott: at this point, you know, some people like oh It doesn't everything for the hardcore gamer.
Scott: and but the you know, you think I was just for the casual nobody gamer.
Scott: But really those people go to the Wii and they say oh, there's nothing for me here either.
Scott: It's all this in-between Stuff it's stuff.
Scott: That's too, you know, non hardcore People don't want it.
Scott: But I mean a person who buys Wii fit to do some jumping up and down is not even gonna buy You know the most casual shovelware, so the Wii won in the sense that it made a new market for gamers.
Rym: It made gamers who previously weren't gamers in that in that market segment and then sold a product to all of them.
Scott: Yeah, it made a lot of money But I think the Farmville is is ten times in the same department as the Wii maybe a hundred times.
Rym: Yeah, I would argue the Farmville isn't a game but that we did.
Rym: I digress.
Scott: It doesn't matter if it's not a game All together.
Rym: yeah, in fact, it's a different industry.
Scott: the people who bought a weed to do we fit and that's it.
Scott: Are the same people who play in Farmville?
Rym: Technologically though notice how the ps3 was supposed to be the ten-year console and it kind of is gonna be the ten-year console But it really doesn't have any.
Scott: ps3 is doing the same thing.
Scott: The PSP did.
Scott: it's sticking around.
Scott: There's still a bunch of people who doesn't have anything on the Xbox.
Rym: the extra power It has is not being utilized and by the time there's something that will utilize it.
Rym: It won't matter.
Rym: No anyway, so Processors those didn't get used in a million things.
Rym: Did they know?
Scott: Netflix definitely busted out in 2010. at the beginning of the year you could do Netflix on like almost you know What your Roku maybe?
Rym: Yeah, I bought a Roku even exist And did I come into existence in 2010 or it might have been before then.
Rym: we had the Roku for a while.
Rym: Yeah, I did it in beacon.
Scott: Yeah, but was it before last new year?
Rym: I think so.
Scott: But anyway, you couldn't really get Netflix on.
Scott: you know streaming on many devices also.
Scott: the selection was pretty small But by the end of 2010 you could stream Netflix on every motherfucker that had a screen.
Scott: So Netflix definitely busted out big time.
Scott: Net neutrality in 2010.
Scott: We don't have it getting some setbacks.
Scott: They passed.
Scott: the FCC said something This is only recent useless.
Scott: It's it's not good.
Rym: I'm not I'm worried.
Rym: I'm actually worried.
Scott: Android in 2010 actually succeeded beyond what I expected.
Rym: Well, this is the problem.
Rym: Android sucks, but it it's the only thing exactly.
Scott: Um, I predict that in 2011 what you're gonna see is the iPhone will despite, you know This rumors been going on forever iPhones gonna be on something's not AT&T.
Scott: Oh, it's gonna be us.
Rym: I don't think we're gonna see it in the next year.
Scott: I think we are.
Scott: I think this is the year it's actually gonna be true.
Scott: You are gonna see the iPhone on Verizon for reals this time.
Scott: This is the real time Because with the 4g and the LTE and all that stuff right LTE is actually going to be big in 2011. going into 2012 is when you're gonna see LTE actually started to become.
Rym: you know, well, here we go.
Rym: This is the first proper prediction because a lot of tech news people make softball predictions Like if I wanted to say Android is gonna be 75% of the smartphone market.
Rym: That's a stupid prediction It's obvious.
Scott: I think what's gonna happen is LTE is gonna get big.
Scott: The iPhone is gonna finally come out on non AT&T.
Scott: all those people on that carrier probably Verizon are going to as their contracts run out or maybe even earlier than that are gonna Bail to get iPhones and Verizon AT&T people with iPhones are gonna bail to go to Verizon to get iPhones and It's gonna take about a two years because that's what how.
Scott: it'll long It'll take for the iPhone contracts to expire and such and you know what?
Scott: I think I you know and I think you're gonna see.
Scott: Android is gonna take a big hit as people are able to stay with The carrier they like and get get an iPhone.
Rym: Ah, see I don't think Android is gonna take a big Not big hit.
Rym: So here's here's why I disagree one.
Rym: I don't think the iPhone is going to be on Verizon in 2011.
Scott: I think it will definitely be.
Scott: this is the real.
Rym: here's the question.
Rym: what it all comes down to is why?
Rym: Specifically what is the exact reason?
Rym: it's on AT&T only who paid whom how much and are they going to continue to pay?
Scott: it's because AT&T pay gives Apple a huge deal right and Because AT&T were the only people who would let Apple run the show right.
Scott: Verizon wanted to be like.
Scott: Oh we got to put a Verizon logo on it and we're gonna gotta pull up rise and apps on there.
Scott: and Apple was like.
Scott: And now that the iPhone succeeded on AT&T Verizon has learned the error of their ways.
Scott: they like shit.
Scott: we have to let Apple on and we have to let them have it their way.
Scott: and You know fine and you're they have you know, they're finally gonna cave in and give Apple the you know The money they want they do.
Rym: Verizon doesn't need the iPhone because if they stay if the iPhone stays at AT&T because it's not gonna go to Sprint or anything They might know.
Rym: it's a space You know probably not like right the company that goes out of its way to have the shittiest phones of every generation of phones.
Scott: They're not doing too bad lately.
Rym: Oh, they're doing fine because they're cheap.
Rym: They're cheap and they have great coverage Verizon is expensive and as great coverage the mobile is actually coming up from behind because they're putting the LTE up before everyone else.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't trust t-mobile because I occasionally leave the city.
Scott: Yeah Listen, you know t-mobile does have less coverage than all the others, but it's not bad.
Rym: It works You know, it's the thing is if I'm going t-mobile, I'm going like Metro PCS.
Scott: Well, I mean the thing is I would go Metro PCS if you can get a good phone and they actually do have a smartphone Now, but it's really terrible.
Scott: It's like the shittiest smartphone you can get.
Rym: but basically if say the word the iPhone stays on AT&T and they don't make a deal with Verizon and they don't go to Sprint The only people that Verizon loses are the people who really really want the iPhone, which is a lot of people.
Rym: But they're not the majority.
Rym: They're like, I think a quarter of the expanded market.
Rym: So AT&T but Verizon then will always get the people who have the belief either mistaken or not that Verizon is reliable and fast and better.
Scott: you're thinking about it the wrong way right?
Scott: Verizon basically didn't lose anybody except for the people who really really wanted the iPhone and Pretty much you look around and all these people who are on Verizon.
Scott: They will never leave Verizon.
Scott: They're loyal to Verizon first, right?
Scott: They must have a rise and they have no choice.
Scott: It's like that.
Scott: You know, all they choose is their phone.
Rym: Think that those people actually flip-flop between Sprint and Verizon.
Scott: I don't know that everyone.
Rym: I've seen polls where people basically believe that both of them have equal coverage.
Rym: the only Carrier that I see having significant negative press is AT&T even though the negative press is actually less warranted recently.
Scott: Yeah, AT&T has improved its network at least in New York City.
Scott: But anyway, there are people who absolutely must stick with Verizon.
Scott: They will not leave it no matter what right.
Scott: and these people they want an iPhone but they will not leave.
Scott: so they get an Android phone because that's the smartphone that Verizon has.
Scott: see IV iPhone comes out on Verizon.
Scott: they they will go and get that iPhone immediately.
Scott: They are dying for it, but they will not leave to go get.
Scott: I don't
Rym: think they are as many people as the much more Viable cash cow which is the currently non Smartphone to people who want a smartphone or would like a smartphone or don't even know they want a smartphone But the commodity Android, you know $50 phone that they get from Verizon or even Sprint is a smartphone.
Rym: but oh they need a data plan now.
Rym: And the data plan being sold to the person who never had a smartphone before is worth way more money Than the guy who wants the I.
Scott: you're also not thinking about right the fact that if the iPhone came out on Verizon There are so many dissatisfied AT&T iPhone users they will all bail immediately.
Scott: No, they won't.
Rym: they will bail the contract ends.
Rym: name you way Overestimate how much people actually will break a contract.
Scott: No These people are dying to get the hell away from AT&T and if the iPhone is the only they're more loyal to the iPhone than they are to the carrier.
Scott: So as soon as that iPhone as soon as they have a choice of carrier, they will choose anything by one.
Rym: I disagree but to suppose that's true AT&T is gonna keep a death grip on that.
Rym: They'll pay whatever they need to pay.
Scott: No, also Verizon.
Rym: I don't think I mean.
Rym: if it's a matter of AT&T paying to keep it exclusive AT&T will pay and the only reason they lose it is if Apple says look you've got to pay us, you know infinity dollars.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing is that they won't do that because Verizon probably is taking the opposite tack.
Rym: They're saying if we get the iPhone Apple you have to do X Y and Z for us and Apple's gonna say no They've already learned that they have to cave to Apple.
Scott: They've learned this lesson.
Rym: I don't think they've learned that lesson because I don't think it's true.
Scott: No, you're gonna.
Scott: you're gonna be wrong and we will see in a year from now.
Rym: Let's see.
Scott: It is on record The iPhones gonna come out in Verizon.
Scott: people are gonna bail From AT&T as soon as they can.
Rym: that's your prediction.
Rym: My prediction is no.
Scott: Android is gonna take a hit as a result.
Rym: I think we're gonna see no iPhone on the on Verizon in the next year 2011 and two.
Rym: I don't think there will be any sort of hit to Android because for every one person The people are buying iPhones are gonna be dwarfed by the non smartphone people who buy a commodity Android smartphone.
Scott: No, cuz they're gonna buy right when the eye is.
Scott: this isn't even a prediction.
Scott: We know it's gonna happen right.
Scott: the iPhone four and a half is gonna come out.
Rym: It's gonna be an incremental improvement.
Scott: It's gonna be like the iPhone 3DS.
Scott: I think what's gonna happen Though obviously is the same thing that's happened before right is that iPhone 4.5 is gonna come out.
Scott: Right, that's gonna be on Verizon.
Scott: the people are gonna switch to it and the iPhone 4 gets the price dropped Just like the I. you can get a 3G now or 3GS for way cheap, right?
Scott: They make it way cheap.
Scott: So the commodity smartphone is gonna be the old iPhone.
Scott: It's not gonna be so not going to happen.
Rym: The commodity smartphone is gonna be like some HTC piece of crap that they get for like 50 bucks.
Rym: with their two-year plan You could get the old iPhone for $99.
Rym: If you look at the way plans are right now Sprint especially and Verizon to a lesser degree.
Rym: They're really Pushing the two-year contract.
Scott: everyone everyone just gets to your contract.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So how many people have to your contract?
Scott: I highly doubt everyone with an iPhone 3GS.
Scott: their contract runs out in the summer.
Scott: It's always the summer cuz that's when the new iPhone comes out.
Scott: So, you know in 2012 the iPhone 4 contract Yeah.
Rym: So there's gonna be one more cycle of it being AT&T exclusive and I think 2012 is the year of the iPhone on another 2011 2012 anyway anyway, so let's get away from the phones for a minute.
Rym: So talk about Yahoo.
Rym: Yeah I With the delicious thing and the leaked documents and everything.
Rym: Yahoo is basically, you know, oh my wah mo shindeiru They're all they're dead.
Rym: The company is dead, but the corpse is still moving.
Rym: It doesn't realize it's dead or me?
Rym: Oh, I think more importantly it realizes it's dead and it's trying to pretend that it doesn't know it's dead.
Rym: So it doesn't lose value as they divest themselves of profitable enterprises and then eventually disappear.
Scott: Well, you know to get there is a possibility.
Rym: That's definitely what's going on because Yahoo has like, you know a handful of good products that are profitable I assume or at least could be profitable.
Scott: their content business is actually their best stuff.
Scott: right?
Scott: Yahoo Finance Yahoo News Crap compared to Google the Yahoo the Yahoo like celebrity news is like one of the most popular sites on the entire Internet.
Scott: It's huge.
Rym: So I think my prediction for the next year is that Yahoo is going to sell off Small numbers like two maybe three of their things that are big that don't have Yahoo brand name.
Scott: No I think I think it's gonna be the opposite.
Scott: Yahoo is gonna sell off everything that doesn't make money and they're gonna keep only the Really big parts that are like the core of Yahoo the Yahoo Mail the Yahoo search.
Rym: See no, you're thinking Too much on money.
Rym: It's all about brand.
Rym: what they're gonna do I think is they're going to sell off anything that is not strongly branded with the Yahoo name To get whatever money they can for it.
Rym: things like delicious and flicker they can sell off and Those are worth a lot of money to someone who's actually going to use them.
Rym: I mean Facebook.
Rym: if they bought flicker, that would be a huge and I think excellent deal for them.
Scott: Well, they were.
Scott: just the thing is anyone who buys flicker who already has a photo service.
Scott: It's just gonna try to integrate it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, if I were Facebook, I would buy play.
Scott: The thing is Yahoo tried to integrate flicker into the Yahoo photos and they just technologically failed at that.
Scott: Yahoo failed at a lot of things for the thing is if you do that though is the problem?
Scott: if you try to integrate it All the flicker users will hate you and bail.
Rym: Oh, they're not actually gonna bail.
Scott: They will.
Scott: No, they won't if you turn if you just like say alright flicker is now Facebook photos.
Scott: Just use the photos in Facebook.
Rym: No, that's not what they do.
Rym: They'd leave flicker up as its own but they they'd over time.
Rym: keep adding things like alright So all you Facebook users You can just import all your flicker photos with all the metadata and then we'll run the facial recognition And go retro tag everything and then they'll go to the flicker people and say hey Have a Facebook account you want a Facebook account.
Rym: you can keep using flicker just fine.
Rym: But if you want to use the awesome Facebook face recognition and tag all your friends roll them all into Facebook.
Rym: But you'll keep.
Rym: your flicker will integrate the two.
Scott: Yeah, there's definitely gonna be some shakiness with all things.
Rym: Yahoo I think they're gonna.
Rym: they're gonna decommission any non Yahoo brand that they can't sell.
Rym: They're gonna sell any non Yahoo brand they can sell and then everything that's left is just gonna be stuff That's too like directly intimately tied to the Yahoo brand even if it's not tied to Yahoo technologically.
Rym: The Yahoo company will then be sold in a block and is going to be bought by either Yahoo by Yahoo by either Facebook Straight up or Google straight up.
Rym: Yeah, we'll say that's my prediction for the next three years.
Rym: But the next year they're gonna sell off all the non Yahoo branded shit.
Scott: Yahoo's definitely gonna have some collapsing in in the year to come.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yahoo is fucked.
Rym: That's really the long and short of it.
Scott: Yeah e-readers were actually.
Scott: you know people have been trying to get the e-readers going for years now with no success.
Scott: until 2010 that you readers actually started making big moves.
Rym: the kid sold Raisley this holiday season.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So did the nook.
Rym: Yeah all the One even is doing pretty well.
Rym: I saw yeah, not bad.
Scott: So the e-readers are doing really well.
Scott: I think that in 2012, it's pretty much gonna be more the same but I think there is gonna be a level off right because what's gonna happen is people are gonna start to realize that Look, this e-reader is just an e-reader, but you could get you know iPad 2 which is also all these other things.
Scott: Some of the Android readers like some of the Android tablets like they got the new the Samsung whatever the hell it is I forget the name of it Galaxy tab.
Rym: at the same time the people who want e-readers they kind of have this movement of not wanting a tablet.
Rym: They don't want all that bullshit.
Rym: They want to read books.
Rym: They see themselves as more erudite.
Rym: and the display technology?
Rym: They actually probably want that low energy awesome display for reading.
Scott: Yeah, but the you know, the LCD is clearly shown, you know, you can make a display.
Scott: That's not a stupid e-reader display that actually works properly doesn't work that well.
Scott: It works pretty work surprisingly.
Scott: Well I can read with the iBooks on my iPhone.
Scott: I can read whatever.
Scott: so same thing with an iPad.
Scott: It's only got to be better than that.
Rym: See, I don't have any strong predictions though in the market because the neck the revolution is going to be the tablet that has a Quote-unquote e-reader like e-paper display and a real display.
Scott: I don't think I think that's something like that is to.
Scott: just the technological Aspects of it are gonna make it too flaky.
Scott: It's not really gonna work not in the short run.
Rym: I'm talking like five ten years.
Scott: You'll just more likely.
Scott: you'll just see what.
Scott: a better display period that you know of some sort as opposed to some sort of weird.
Rym: Oh, yeah It would be some sort of fusion because the one thing that LCD displays like they're treated like the iPad can't do is the passive Display of.
Rym: it is just colors and then light reflecting off of it is the image Anyway, like a book.
Rym: But anyway, there's not much.
Rym: I mean e-readers for sale rights.
Rym: No one really cares about that.
Rym: I think with streaming in Netflix I have bigger predictions because notice how Netflix did the obvious thing toward the end of the year and they now offer a streaming only plan Which is what I think they've realized this.
Rym: I think the the moment of realization for Netflix.
Rym: remember when they got rid of profiles and Everyone lost their shit including me because I needed those profiles because I had my three DVD cues.
Rym: yep, as Soon as they did that everyone bitched and dropped to one cue because they wanted to keep the streaming and without the cues You know multiple DVDs were worthless.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And then when they brought the cues back, I don't think anyone went back.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't go back.
Rym: and at that moment They probably had a meeting and realized streaming is the only thing anyone cares about anymore.
Scott: actually read something Recently about how Netflix actually has like this huge turnover like this, you know The sort of problems in the workplace is like the opposite of Zappos, right?
Scott: I mean even though they somehow managed to turn out.
Scott: You know stuff and you can sort of see that.
Scott: maybe this is true.
Scott: looking at the way that the Netflix Software is different and every single platform that this could this is very likely that they're.
Scott: they're sort of, you know, a little dysfunctional.
Scott: You know, it's not like they turn out the same exact thing with clean updates to every platform all at the same time.
Scott: I think you're gonna see it go like one of two ways, right?
Scott: Netflix might actually start to level off because everyone's just streaming and it's already on every device and that's it.
Scott: And but they are moving to HTML 5 which is not really gonna change their business.
Scott: really Yeah, but I think you can actually see.
Scott: another thing is if they don't figure out like another move Right, if that's all they have is we stream on every platform.
Scott: end of story.
Scott: You're gonna see them start to decline.
Rym: See, I don't see a decline because there are a steady hold.
Scott: You're not gonna see this continued rapid growth of Netflix.
Rym: Oh, no, you're not gonna see.
Scott: they need a second.
Scott: You know, it's a third act.
Scott: right act one was discs act two is streaming.
Scott: They need a third act.
Scott: if they don't have a third act which could happen, right?
Scott: I'm 50/50.
Scott: They're either gonna have a third act or they're gonna level off now.
Rym: See I will forget about.
Rym: I mean I'm not gonna growth.
Rym: growth of the company, but I don't think they need a third act.
Rym: I think what's going to happen.
Rym: my straight prediction for you know, visual media in the next year in 2011 is that Netflix is going to slowly transition to becoming a streaming only company and the DVD part is going to drop off and be a kind of an add-on that you Can pay for if you want DVDs?
Scott: Yeah, that's already sort of happened.
Rym: Oh, I think what they're going to add is a function.
Rym: this is just total speculation.
Rym: Instead of having a. you know, you keep getting DVDs.
Rym: You have the streaming only and if there's something that isn't streaming You can from your viewer whatever it is say send me the DVD and they charge you like a dollar.
Rym: Maybe I think they'll do that because they have to leverage the DVD not a bad Inventory that they have but they don't like.
Rym: no one wants the DVDs.
Rym: They only want the DVDs because they can't get anything like.
Rym: they can't get the stuff that's on DVD.
Scott: Here's what I understand, right?
Scott: It's like care about extras by and large if they have it the basically Netflix effectively has you know infinity DVDs.
Scott: Right if you ask for a video, you know, and you want to watch it.
Scott: They have a disc.
Scott: Yeah, you know it's never a situation where it's like, oh we don't have another copy of it.
Scott: You're right So why can't legally?
Scott: I know Lee it is obviously illegal, right?
Scott: But you know in terms of right and wrong, they should be able to stream anything.
Scott: They have a disc for right?
Scott: It's really in effect no different.
Scott: they've paid for.
Rym: no It would only be no different if it was set up such that only one streamer could stream per DVD They owned in their vault.
Scott: All right fine, which is fine.
Rym: So they yes got copyright law.
Scott: Yeah, but I just say you know So that.
Rym: but anyway, that's my prediction for Netflix.
Rym: but to with the whole streaming in general I think we're gonna see huge balkanization.
Rym: I think Hulu is going to fail.
Scott: really.
Rym: in 2011 Hulu might not disappear But Hulu is rapidly be getting fucked by all those interests of the different studios that make shows and as you know Like NBC there's all these mergers being talked about.
Rym: the industry TV industry is not doing that well and I think what's going to happen is that Hulu is going to kind of collapse under this balkanization where Every studio will allow like one or two episodes of their show to be on Hulu But they'll hope they'll have links back to their personal streaming site a la Comedy Central and I think bit by bit every every peep.
Rym: every network and every person that makes shows is Going to try to bring people to their own site and try to keep people away from the centralized things like Hulu.
Scott: That's not a prediction for the future.
Scott: That's that's a seeing.
Scott: what is you know, that is the past.
Scott: That is what has already happened.
Rym: It hasn't happened yet because all those sites all the balkanized sites suck and people do just go to Hulu and if Hulu doesn't Have it they go to BitTorrent.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: I think what's gonna happen?
Rym: That's why Netflix is doing so well because Netflix no one cares.
Rym: very few people care about seeing stuff right now and the people that Do just pirate it.
Rym: Netflix is gonna be the only Centralized streaming site that survives the balkanization.
Scott: I think that things like the Google TV It's actually surprisingly right, especially since you just saw a million Apple TVs sold the new ones, right?
Scott: I think the Google TV is actually gonna do well and I think I thought it was going to.
Rym: did you read the recent articles?
Rym: About how?
Rym: yeah, Google is basically Slowing it the fuck down and they're they've.
Rym: they're downplaying the press releases now.
Rym: There are commercials for it on TV Yeah And now they're pulling back and a lot of the devices that were Scheduled to be shown at CES are not going to be there.
Rym: I saw one at pecs Yeah, and there's this pullback and I don't think Google TV is gonna be viable in 2011 I think cause this balkanization is going to fuck them.
Rym: Google TV Relies upon there being places like who I think Hulu is.
Rym: now.
Scott: they can just write a plug-in for every single new place It's not a problem and then the new places will block those plugins.
Rym: It doesn't matter They're going to do it and Google won't do there.
Rym: You know, you know Google They're not going to play the game of.
Rym: you're blocking our agent string.
Rym: So we're gonna change the agent string.
Rym: They're just gonna give up.
Scott: No, I think the Google TV, you know, the boxy box clearly I don't think did you know as well mostly because you know boxy.
Scott: anyone who want knew about or wanted run boxy already had.
Scott: You know just ran boxy on a computer, you know, the boxy boxes is not didn't have this wide market But I think the Google TV and the Apple TV, you know, which seem to be getting more I think in 2010 you're gonna see.
Scott: you know, the cable companies are gonna start to hurt as more and more people It's gonna accelerate.
Scott: Oh, yeah The rate of people dropping cable and satellite will accelerate.
Rym: my three-year prediction is that within three years?
Rym: It will not be a viable business.
Scott: in 2012 You're gonna see the breaking but in 2011 is gonna be a big lead-up to more and more people.
Scott: Just you're gonna be dropping cable.
Rym: I agree, but I think what they're going to go to Google
Scott: TV
Rym: The way it's supposed to work the way they demoed it really only functions well when there are places like Hulu that are viable and as a result the people are gonna adopt Hulu TV or Hulu TV.
Rym: Google TV in 2011 are going to the people who have large collections of pirated video and people who will use it to stream their Netflix and People who use it to stream the few things that the people who produce content will allow to be streamed on Google TV.
Rym: I think most other people are going to block it and are going to basically extort Google and say pay us or we'll block Google TV.
Scott: You know, normally you'd think that would be true But here's the one difference between boxy and Google.
Scott: right is basically you don't extort.
Scott: You can extort the boxy people.
Scott: you may boxy.
Scott: We're shutting you down.
Scott: You can't shut Google down.
Scott: all these people are sucking at the teat of Google.
Scott: They will not go and fight with them.
Scott: They want Google's love.
Scott: They're like Google.
Scott: send people to my website But they hate Google because they realize that They hate it because they can't get away from it.
Scott: Oh, they had.
Scott: they pay Google a zillion dollars every year for ads.
Scott: this Bring in more money than you know, then they pay for that and this is the trouble.
Rym: This is the net neutrality thing.
Rym: I think all the content producers are going to try to collude to keep Google out.
Scott: No, you can't.
Rym: Oh, it won't work in the long run, but I think it's going to hold Google TV from being mass-market successful Until after 2011.
Rym: Google TV is not going to be a major player in 2011.
Rym: It'll be alright.
Rym: You heard it here first.
Rym: It's got so wrong.
Rym: It'll be good.
Rym: There's no way I'm so.
Scott: they already have the devices.
Scott: They're putting commercials on TV.
Scott: Yeah people, you know, I think that people people go for it.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think people are gonna go forward enough.
Rym: it's not gonna be a major player because People who use Google TV are just gonna use it for the same thing.
Rym: They use everything else for the stream Netflix because that's gonna be one of the few things that's reliable on it?
Scott: No, it's gonna be I think.
Scott: I think you know, you underestimate the the ability of Google TV to to get content.
Rym: There's too much too much movement among the content producers to try.
Scott: That's what Google does best.
Scott: is they search the web to collect content, right?
Scott: That's that's their thing.
Scott: They can't.
Scott: they're not gonna get it wrong.
Rym: Well, here's the thing Google TV will succeed in.
Rym: this kind of.
Rym: between the two Google TV is going to allow YouTube TV aka watching stupid dumbass videos on YouTube and college humor and things like that to displace Traditional content production entirely.
Rym: No, Google TV is gonna kick it now It's only gonna take.
Rym: kick it for alternative stuff and for Netflix.
Rym: It's not gonna kick it for broadcast TV because broadcast TV is going to fight to the bitter end.
Scott: It's gonna kick it.
Rym: Anyway, I think we've heard you have any one leg.
Rym: We're done here.
Rym: Do you have?
Rym: we should each make one?
Scott: Oh, there's a lot of other things.
Scott: I want to talk about talking for an hour.
Scott: Well, I wanted to talk about how open source is gonna be hurting big time about that's.
Rym: I think that's obvious though It's just at web app.
Scott: ever since Oracle bought Sun, right?
Scott: That's was a huge hit.
Scott: and then on top of that all the developers are basically just making websites It's not?
Scott: you know, I talked about you know The other week how people main was having trouble getting developers, right?
Rym: Oh, yeah Well, I'm gonna extend this because I want to make a crazy prediction more people are using Apple products as opposed to.
Rym: I think what's Gonna happen is X windows is gonna really drop off in support and updates.
Rym: Oh, that's definitely true in 2011 because one Ubuntu which probably has one of the bigger pools of developers is Dropping X.
Scott: Yeah, and to that Linux on the desktop is dead Yeah, so I mean it's gonna be a bad times for the open source world, right?
Scott: you know open source for in terms of its ability to serve websites and its ability to scale and all that stuff and You know run in the cloud and all.
Scott: that's where all the attention is right now.
Rym: databases Scaling website something about what we use the internet for the content itself is actually the only thing that matters.
Rym: Yeah, and all in all the other departments Open source is gonna do poorly in 2011 because people are much They want their content and they don't care about what's going on behind the scenes.
Scott: Yeah I think that 3d is gonna be.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think that you will definitely see.
Scott: as you know, there's gonna be definitely more 3d movies in the theaters if you know.
Rym: If there could be more here's a prediction.
Rym: I think that you want Netflix's next big thing.
Rym: You want them to have a third pillar like a new move.
Rym: it'll be when they have both subtitle support and That's not a very.
Scott: that's not a third pillar a third pillar.
Rym: No, cuz that that will.
Scott: that's just features.
Scott: That's not a whole new business.
Scott: streaming is a whole new business Scott.
Rym: That was just a problem.
Rym: That's just like one huge feature.
Rym: But the real one will be when they have 3d movies.
Scott: That's not a new business model.
Rym: Well, they'll never have a new business.
Scott: They did they had discs and then they had streaming.
Scott: they could I'd be need a third thing Happen.
Rym: what would that in the next year?
Rym: It could happen.
Scott: what they're gonna need something cuz streaming isn't gonna last forever.
Rym: That's how you get content.
Rym: They'll be the content provider.
Scott: There's gonna be a streaming is only gonna hold out for so long.
Scott: 2011 is not going to see the decline of streaming Scott No But I think what's gonna happen is that everyone will already be signed up for it and then what?
Rym: and then you continue to make Money forever.
Scott: No, you need to.
Scott: you need to keep.
Scott: you need to keep doing something.
Scott: You need another another move.
Rym: No, that's actually a stupid thing to say because that's pretty much what drives most businesses into the ground.
Scott: people would have said this You just did the same thing about DVDs and you know the 90 in 2000.
Rym: no because here's the thing.
Rym: when you're when you're in an industry where you have a cash cow your work on something.
Rym: Yes, but that's kind of an irrelevant discussion.
Rym: That's just obvious You weren't?
Rym: you know your shareholders?
Rym: you work on some other thing and then you have a sunset plan for your business.
Rym: Streaming is not going to sunset in the next decade.
Scott: Yeah Sunset a lot sooner than you think.
Rym: All right, so what's gonna replace it in terms of getting media?
Scott: How long did Netflix's DVD thing last is?
Scott: pretty much, you know, it's going downhill now.
Rym: Well because we went from you know, non streaming to streaming.
Scott: Yeah, that's gonna be streaming to something else.
Scott: What else?
Scott: just as quickly as a DVD mailing went out streaming is gonna go out.
Rym: Alright Scott.
Rym: I want to watch a video.
Scott: if I knew what the what else was No.
Rym: Saying streaming is gonna go out is like saying that Moving between places is going.
Scott: you would have said the same thing if I would have said DVDs were gonna go out.
Rym: No, I would have said ten years ago.
Rym: I would said yes someday.
Rym: We'll just download all this on the Internet Uh-huh.
Scott: So you can't even imagine anything beyond the Internet's.
Rym: Yes, I can but they're not relevant to the discussion of getting media.
Scott: got no imaginations over there.
Rym: It's got.
Rym: streaming is just a concept of.
Rym: there is audio visual media of some kind or maybe you know feel ease It doesn't matter.
Rym: There is content that is made feelings.
Scott: That would be that would be a whole new thing.
Rym: Yeah, but you're just streaming the feelings.
Rym: Anyway, I think it's a silly argument to say that Netflix needs to worry about the end of streaming and make a new business model.
Scott: They do Know that.
Scott: I guarantee that they are.
Scott: they already have something.
Scott: Uh, what they doubt, you know, they Netflix, you know.
Scott: They purposefully called the business Netflix, you know as opposed to they were gonna call it like DVDs by mail But they called it Netflix because right they didn't what they already knew that they weren't being limited to this one thing.
Rym: Yes Because everyone's known since the beginning that someday we download videos over the Internet.
Scott: They know that they're going to be about delivering movies or whatever in whatever form and whatever.
Scott: You know means that that may be and it will not be streaming.
Scott: It's got streaming over Internet.
Rym: It's not a technology It's a concept.
Scott: It will not be streaming over internets or street.
Scott: It will be something else.
Scott: They have another move.
Rym: What I get the content over some sort of wireless network.
Scott: if you listen you're thinking much too.
Rym: You're thinking stupidly abstractly and not saying any.
Scott: and when Netflix makes a move you're gonna be like, ah shit I'm gonna be like I was right.
Rym: Yes when they stop giving content to people because that's what streaming is.
Scott: Anyway, anyway Netflix is gonna have a third there.
Scott: if they're they're either gonna go out completely or they're gonna have a third move.
Rym: They have a third move, you know, what is gonna be actually making content or funding people to like studios.
Rym: But then you know what they're gonna do.
Rym: They're gonna distribute it.
Rym: You know how they can distribute it over the internet.
Scott: now streaming I can have something new new move.
Rym: That's stupid thing to say.
Rym: not this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.