Rym: It's Wednesday November 7th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I am the sky and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Area 88 the blue skies of betrayal.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: The original not that great OAV not the even worse boring recent anime.
Rym: Relatively reason.
Rym: I think it's like five or six years old at this point.
Rym: Maybe more so.
Rym: uh Yesterday I Went to Starbucks, and I bought a peppermint mocha.
Rym: Okay I also because I did not get breakfast bought a banana And I put the banana in my pocket.
Scott: because how much do they sell a banana for at Starbucks?
Rym: like a dollar.
Scott: Why don't you buy one from the street guy?
Scott: Who's like 50 cent or 25 cent?
Rym: There's no street guy open when I get to my office anywhere near my office.
Scott: You can get fruits all near my office.
Rym: Also, I don't have to walk anywhere.
Rym: this subway stops like right there, but anyway.
Rym: I bought a banana.
Scott: Okay Overpriced Starbucks banana.
Rym: my hands are full so I put it in my pocket of my leather jacket.
Rym: I went into work, and I forgot I had the banana.
Rym: I Realized today, I'm sitting at work, and I'm like wait a minute didn't I buy a banana?
Rym: And I reach in my pocket.
Rym: It's not there.
Scott: Are you sure you didn't drop the banana out the pocket.
Rym: if you look at those pockets?
Rym: There's a flap and they're really deep there's and there was also a moleskine and my wallet in the same pocket.
Scott: I start you sure you didn't eat the banana and forgot you ate the banana.
Rym: I'm Food is very important to me in my life.
Rym: the odds of me forgetting that I ate anything pretty low Are you sure?
Scott: that you were like?
Scott: you know you Like did you look when you put the banana in the pocket or just sort of feel you put the banana pot because you might Have felt like you put the bit in the pocket back?
Scott: She's dropping it on the ground.
Rym: so I've done that before With other things.
Rym: in fact I had a pair of jeans where the left pocket if you put anything in it immediately fell into my pant.
Rym: So uh no I am sure because not only did I lift the flap and like put it in and then think uh-oh What if I crushed this banana against my moleskine?
Rym: Oh, don't worry.
Rym: I won't forget the bananas there.
Scott: Are you sure you didn't do some sort of you know?
Scott: Move to avert that situation and forgot the move you made.
Rym: There's only so many pockets in the and I went back to.
Rym: so basically I had this moment of There is a banana on the loose.
Rym: That is a dangerous situation.
Rym: So I checked every pocket no banana.
Rym: I looked around my desk at work.
Rym: No banana.
Rym: I Went into the closet at work and looked around no banana.
Rym: I didn't see a banana at any point.
Scott: So now you're a pickpocket of the banana.
Rym: I thought about that, but my wallet was in the same pocket And I still really shitty pickpocket or really hungry, so there's a banana on the loose.
Rym: So I implore you GeekNights listeners if any of you find my banana I would like you to let me
Scott: know it's in your pants
Rym: because if you find my banana It means that you are a goddamn stalker, and I really need to know your name, so I can tell the police
Scott: also.
Scott: You can find the banana easily.
Scott: just look for the fruit flies.
Rym: Also, that's what I want to avoid.
Rym: I don't want to find fruit flies because then I will find the banana also bit too late.
Rym: banana banana banana God dang I don't think anyone who listens to the show will understand what you were referred to.
Scott: fine I think everyone was banana waiting in fact.
Rym: Then until this second at least one listener thought you were very poorly referencing that.
Rym: Nope so it's Wednesday now.
Rym: What do you got for me?
Scott: so?
Scott: The other day we were discussing what to do the show on about.
Scott: today now It's a Monday night.
Scott: after the Monday show we're like what should we do on the Wednesday?
Rym: And I was like well Scott you had me reread Gotham Central, so let's do the show on.
Scott: well you I had you read it.
Scott: I was supposed to reread it.
Rym: I had read the first one before but I didn't read the rest.
Scott: for some I have not Reread it so we cannot do a show.
Rym: I can't in any way blame you because I've been the person causing the.
Rym: oh, I didn't read it yet it more times.
Scott: Also, I'm playing ns2 you can't you know?
Rym: yeah, so we were like alright, let's do what we did before.
Rym: Let's get some anime and watch it and rather than rely Just like we did on the last Wednesday episode about one piece rather than rely on the you know Bit torrent or wait a minute.
Rym: Are you sure this thing's only an hour long?
Rym: We I have a bunch of DVDs like a nice high kick silent service great elf princess rain.
Scott: So new Rym suggests some tenchi muyo av.
Scott: so I don't know.
Rym: no no I suggested the tenchi muyo movies.
Rym: now the problem is Tenchi muyo movie number one actually really good.
Rym: Not an hour long Tenchi movie - actually an hour long involves incest.
Rym: Okay, so we had to pick something else.
Rym: so we talked about tension el hazard situation.
Scott: But isn't that the same guy so Scott suggested?
Scott: Maybe jokingly because he was already suggesting all these tenchi things.
Scott: I jokingly suggested tenchi muyo gxp Which if you don't know if we have talked about it in the distant past terrible.
Scott: It's awful.
Scott: We watched this in anime club when it was brand fucking new.
Scott: we watched like four episodes.
Scott: I think I only watch one.
Rym: I walked out after the first episode because I was.
Scott: That point is the worst show with the best opening song of any show ever like that.
Scott: I'm not saying it has the best opening song of any way ever.
Scott: I'm saying The goodness of the opening song compared to the shittiness of the show is the largest gap.
Rym: now to put that into perspective Dot hack sign and noir have really good opening songs.
Rym: They do pretty bad shows.
Rym: the disparity here is greater.
Rym: Yeah, basically because the primarily because of how bad you know the opening song bow time.
Scott: It's like the opening song is pretty good.
Rym: like I Love that song so much.
Scott: It's a good song, but the show is so Shitty.
Scott: seriously, I'm talking worse Photon bad definitely ready how to smack your mama.
Rym: so here's the deal.
Rym: It's bad right, but it's bad in like this extra way.
Rym: So if you haven't seen any other tenchi muyo, and you watch this It's just this terrible fucking anime if you have seen tenchi muyo.
Rym: It's even worse because you're watching thinking alright It's tenchi, so it must take place in the tenchi universe.
Rym: I think once like one of the real tenchi characters flies by in the background And you're like.
Rym: that is literally the best thing that's happened in this show.
Rym: so My surprise god is this better or worse than photon in your?
Scott: I didn't see photon So I went to.
Scott: I've only seen photon on the TV.
Rym: What is worse watch an episode of photon and an episode of tenchi muyo.
Scott: Even have episodes isn't it just one disc.
Scott: I've only ever seen one disc.
Rym: I've only ever seen the trailer and I knew better.
Scott: I saw an immediate plate.
Scott: was one disc photons below that line.
Rym: like I always say the second worst movie ever made is Well the worst movie ever made is Clifford with Martin short playing a ten-year-old boy Because below that there are worse movies that I knew better than to watch.
Rym: I knew better than to watch.
Scott: so tenchi muyo Gxp imagine my surprise.
Scott: I go to look for news for this show You know in this morning, and I noticed that on November 3rd this year only four days before this recording Cartoon Network has announced they're gonna have tenchi muyo Gxp added to their adult swim lineup.
Rym: What really?
Scott: here's the schedule.
Rym: we cause that through some sort of like reverse synchronicity.
Scott: Here's the adult swim schedule midnight.
Scott: bleach.
Scott: midnight and a half.
Scott: tenchi muyo Gxp 1 a.m Samurai 7.
Scott: Thundercats at 130.
Scott: Symbionic Titan at 2.
Scott: Eureka 7 to 30.
Scott: Fullmetal Alchemist Brotherhood at 3 and 3 30.
Scott: Cowboy Bebop at 4 and 4 30. so Inu Yasha at 5 and 5 30.
Rym: here's the problem with Why anime is not doing so well in the mainstream?
Scott: Because that's the fucking lineup and the only shows in there that are halfway good or being 26 episodes and they're rotating through them a hundred times because that lineup isn't right after school.
Scott: That's also true.
Scott: It's a fucking midnight.
Rym: Yeah, who why is there even TV on at that time anymore?
Rym: Anyone who's up that late nowadays?
Rym: Knows how to use the internet.
Scott: That's the adult swim to Nami block at midnight is showing tenchi muyo Gxp as the second show.
Scott: No one's like.
Scott: no one's gonna.
Scott: if some new anime fan happens to have insomnia and can't go to sleep and ends up by the Cartoon Network, they're not gonna make it to cowboy bebop guys.
Rym: Yeah 4 a.m You're.
Rym: if you are awake at 4 a.m Something has gone horribly wrong in your life.
Scott: Or maybe you're just most people with a really early job and you watch it like in the morning when you wake up.
Rym: Yeah, but if you're up and awake and have a half hour to kill watching an entire episode of anime Something's going.
Scott: maybe you wake up and eat your breakfast like at 4 30 with the second coffee above episode.
Rym: I'll be not bad Time to go to watching cowboy bebop again, that wouldn't be so bad.
Rym: So if you're up at 3 in the morning and you're watching Fullmetal Alchemist brotherhood, it's an up all night party.
Rym: I actually haven't seen Eureka seven and Thundercats is shit.
Scott: I find it funny.
Scott: They have samurai seven.
Scott: Wait a minute Thundercats.
Scott: Well, wait, is this the new Thundercats?
Rym: or do you really think it's the old Thundercats?
Scott: Do you really think that I thought it was the old one?
Rym: Okay, the new Thundercats looks great.
Rym: If you watch the new Thundercats with no sound and no sub the titles.
Rym: It's pretty great.
Scott: But anyway, they have samurai seven and Eureka seven.
Scott: They need to add in blue sub.
Scott: Anyway Do you have any sort of news?
Rym: So since we brought up tenchi muyo, you know tenchi muyo It's interesting how when I was like are like a huge fan of anime.
Rym: I mean, I've been a fan of anime since in the 90s since I was in fourth grade in the 90s.
Scott: Yeah, when I'm she muyo was a big deal in the u.s.
Scott: I don't know how big a deal it was in Japan.
Scott: I assume it was at least a moderate deal when I.
Rym: but that's based on when I was nothing when I was in fourth grade And I saw a vampire hundred because my mom forced me to I became a huge fan of anime.
Rym: But when I got involved in anime culture Which did not happen until long after that because they're really I saw anime before I had access to the internet.
Rym: So when I finally got on the internet and discovered there was this whole anime culture and like anime conventions and all this bullshit Tenchi muyo among anime fans was the biggest goddamn thing ever.
Scott: Well, I mean, here's how it went, right?
Scott: So you could watch Sailor Moon and stuff like that and syndicated local TV.
Scott: But once you got Cartoon Network, you could drop.
Rym: now that out.
Rym: you could drop 40 bucks to get one.
Rym: I was subtitled VHS tape.
Scott: I was attention with two episodes Whose video went to the local comic shop and they had the tiny shelf that had like 20 VHS tapes on it.
Scott: 18 of them were on my half and two of them were tension.
Scott: We know no no No, there was also.
Scott: three of them were Dragon Ball Z.
Rym: Now if you were a little little more connected you go to Suncoast video and they had slayers.
Scott: We didn't have one of those they had.
Rym: so they had subtitled anime, which you guys might not remember back then.
Rym: Subtitled anime cost an extra ten to fifteen dollars.
Scott: But anyway, those are the three shows tension.
Scott: It was one of them.
Scott: So of course it was big at the time.
Scott: In fact, you know how it's pretty much disappeared.
Scott: Can you even remember seeing a tenchi cosplayer at any convention recently?
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: No, but yet I remember no to con 2002.
Rym: I Saw a girl who was dressed up as Ryoko and I thought she was super cute and I didn't flirt with her and I don't remember Why.
Rym: okay, and back then they were all my age.
Rym: It wasn't like now.
Scott: so continue with your news.
Rym: Oh, my news is a geek bite.
Scott: Oh, it's not a news.
Rym: You are a no more recent fan of anime and you'd like there's harem shows.
Rym: Actually, I don't think anyone even really remembers love Hina anymore.
Scott: I remember it existed.
Scott: I watched the whole thing.
Rym: I know I didn't cuz I knew better.
Scott: cute turtles is the only good part.
Rym: Yeah, everybody gets one harem show.
Scott: if you're gonna watch it You know why I watch that show.
Scott: because I was home from RIT.
Scott: My internet was 56k dial-up modem got everybody already downloaded all of it.
Scott: while I was at RIT I already watched everything that I had already downloaded and I'm sitting at home in the summer sort of in between.
Rym: So when it comes to anime everybody doesn't just get one of a different genre.
Rym: You have a Yahtzee sheet.
Rym: You've got like harem show But independently of that you've got the show you watch when you don't have internet Which I guess can't happen anymore and all you've got is something on a hard drive.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: My show like that was read or die TV.
Rym: I watched all of read or die TV Living in the woods.
Rym: I didn't have internet.
Rym: I was living on the mountain.
Scott: So you did read or die TV.
Scott: I did love Hina TV.
Rym: So love Hina fills for you either your harem show or your.
Rym: there is nothing else to do show.
Scott: I think I've seen some other harem shows So I'll put that is our thing else to do.
Rym: so his art.
Scott: does that count as a harem show?
Rym: All right, but it's also a robot show kind of.
Scott: well, how about Maha to kaita?
Scott: Is that a harem show?
Rym: No That is a. that is a wacky anime 90s comedy in my opinion.
Rym: Anyway, so if you're gonna watch a harem show You should watch tenchi muyo, but it's hard to watch tenchi muyo because there's no AV.
Rym: That's actually really good.
Rym: There's another OAV.
Rym: That's a sequel to that not as good.
Rym: That's garbage.
Rym: There's a TV show.
Rym: That's garbage a TV show.
Rym: There's more garbage TV show.
Rym: That's even more garbage a TV show.
Rym: You shouldn't watch and then tension.
Scott: wait So they use this.
Scott: that there were four TV series is each one was more garbage than the last.
Rym: Everyone is worse, but so hey, but only the fourth one.
Scott: you shouldn't watch.
Scott: so you should watch the first three garbage ones.
Rym: It's kind of like how if you like initial D, okay watch season one You're done.
Rym: If you're a goddamn maniac you watch the rest of it.
Rym: if you watch the tension if you get into tension You're gonna watch it all.
Rym: I'm gonna give you all some advice stop before tenchi in Tokyo.
Rym: You might think the Rym.
Rym: I really like it.
Rym: should know no Do not watch tenchi in Tokyo if you like, but they like those three which were garbage.
Scott: They like garbage shouldn't they like?
Rym: in my opinion that tenchi consists of the first movie and the first OAV and everything else is Literally just trying to reclaim nostalgia for those first two things.
Rym: So if you haven't seen a harem show haven't seen these kind of 90s II anime And you don't know where to start you want to know something about tenchi which which was Somewhat moderately important during a time period in American anime history.
Rym: in fact I would say that this is one of those anime You should see if you call yourself an anime fan.
Rym: You should watch the tenchi muyo movie tenchi in love.
Rym: It is the first movie just 90 minutes long well animated big budget.
Rym: It's a good movie.
Rym: there aren't that many anime movies Especially ones that break the formula.
Rym: This is a movie for a show that has its own continuity affects the plot kills people.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: So watch that that is my geek bite.
Rym: I don't want to say anything else.
Rym: you don't need to know anything about tenchi because I Watched the tenchi movie on the sci-fi channel and all I could think was why the hell can that one girl fly?
Rym: Does she have a tail?
Rym: and I couldn't quite tell if she had a tail or not.
Rym: I was really fascinated by this.
Scott: I Don't need to say anything to that Time.
Rym: you understand 1992 or 93 but anyway things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me Scott?
Scott: I went through my youtube likes and I found the first thing that I thought would be okay.
Scott: And it's been a little dry recently.
Scott: so here we go.
Scott: Girl football player is fast and fun to watch.
Scott: it is some girl.
Scott: she looks like she's in elementary middle school age, maybe late elementary early middle and she plays peewee football in whatever her town is and She totally kicks ass and gets like 35 fucking touchdowns and the video is like all fast forwarded.
Scott: So it looks like everyone's running really fast.
Scott: They're obviously running slower than that, but She's fast anyway because no one can fucking catch her right.
Scott: she gets the ball She runs all the way down the field like a pro, and it's pretty awesome.
Scott: You know I mean I've never seen peewee football.
Scott: anyone this good At peewee football.
Scott: usually peewee football is like a bunch of kids Move a ball and then fall on each other in a big heap and then someone like you know peels them off each other.
Scott: and It's just like there.
Scott: it might as well be vibrating table football right whereas You know this because this girl is in play and she seems to actually know what the fuck is going on and B She's able to run really fast.
Scott: It actually turns into something resembling real football, and it's cool.
Rym: So we talked about we didn't go to the New York comic-con because there's basically nothing to see there.
Scott: Anymore no no reason to physically go especially to spend money and time to go there.
Rym: the last thing that most people have you know If you discount all the things that aren't there anymore it comes like this the one thing you can go there for is to see Stuff that no one else has seen before.
Rym: that's being announced and is brand new like if you're waiting for a new show to come Out you'll see like the highlights review preview.
Scott: Yeah, they do this at San Diego comic-con and also at New York comic-con like oh my god.
Rym: Here's six minutes of the new My Little Pony episode.
Scott: Pretty much the only two places.
Scott: They do it is they'll be like all right.
Scott: We've got a new movie coming out.
Scott: You're the first people in the whole world to see this ten minute clip from this movie That's coming out or this trailer for this movie.
Scott: We literally just announced 30 seconds ago You're the first people in the world this.
Rym: so yeah, guess what if you wait like an hour?
Rym: Someone on YouTube?
Scott: someone had a fan cam and put it on YouTube.
Rym: so I'm a fan of venture brothers, and I become more and more of a fan as time has gone on.
Rym: It's a great show.
Rym: It's actually one of my favorite cartoon TV shows There's been in recent memory if you were a fan of it.
Rym: You're waiting for season 5. not only is it coming which we've known for a while.
Rym: There is a sizzle reel from New York comic-con 2012 five minutes and 17 seconds of spoilers.
Scott: Something I've learned from sizzle reels is that when you see them You don't need to see the show because it's pretty much all the good parts right and it comes.
Rym: ah But a properly done sizzle reel and this one does it well.
Rym: if you watch this and you've never seen venture brothers.
Rym: It makes no goddamn sense.
Rym: Pay attention to certain things happen and people react to them very differently like a dude Shows up in a butterfly costume and people are like yeah, and then some other dude shows up in a similar costume And the crowds like oh my god.
Rym: But this one does a very good job of.
Rym: if you've seen venture brothers It's just everything you see is a really oh my god.
Rym: I got to know what that's all about.
Rym: moment mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, usually what happens is it's like the guys who make trailers.
Scott: They're always torn right.
Scott: It's like they don't want to put give everything away in the trailer.
Scott: They know that but the problem is okay, so we won't put the best good stuff in the trailer We'll put the medium stuff.
Scott: so now the trailer isn't so good because you want like especially if it's a comedy, right?
Scott: It's like what do you want me to do?
Scott: put the unfunny jokes in the trailer?
Scott: No, you get about the funny jokes in there so that people think the movies gonna be funny.
Scott: And then of course they see the trailer they hear all the funny jokes They watch the movie and the only times they laugh are the same jokes that were in the trailer They've already heard.
Scott: and then the movies.
Scott: not funny because those are the only funny.
Rym: So the proper way to do a sizzle reel is to show things that are tantalizing Especially in this case.
Rym: you know it's a show that already had four seasons.
Rym: the only people watching this sizzle reel are people who have seen them.
Rym: show them just enough stuff to hint at the kinds of things that will happen.
Rym: and The crazy plot points like oh my god so and so is still alive and some bullshit's gonna happen.
Rym: or why is that guy a centaur now?
Rym: and And Don't actually give enough context to figure out what actually happened?
Rym: don't show an entire scene Mmm-hmm.
Rym: so just show the basically fanboy fodder.
Scott: all right That's things of the day.
Scott: meta moment time.
Rym: the book club book is the name of the wind by Patrick Roth.
Rym: You know what pretty good book?
Rym: uh Read it.
Scott: It's a book club.
Rym: I'm gonna lock.
Rym: glamour is better, but you should read it because I read it and I started reading the second book Which is the already yeah?
Rym: But I haven't started reading.
Rym: I was on the subway for like an hour.
Rym: I had to do something.
Rym: okay I already listen to Dave and Joel.
Scott: what other meta moments.
Scott: Do we have?
Scott: you should.
Rym: we're gonna be at magfest.
Rym: It's coming up in a few months actually right after New Year's January.
Rym: We're going to be doing beyond the Candyland.
Rym: I guess reborn this isn't necessary.
Rym: It's so far away And we're gonna be on probably two gaming intellectuals panels that I cannot announce yet.
Scott: All you need to know is that if you don't go to magfest and you're anywhere even remotely Geographically close to magfest and you're listening to this podcast right now.
Scott: What the fuck is wrong with you I'm a warming up my raw.
Scott: Yeah, seriously, okay?
Scott: Also, we are all over the internets.
Scott: I swear you haven't you?
Scott: you have internet connection because you're listening to this.
Scott: you have to have.
Scott: You should use that internet connection to interact with us via many different internet protocols such as email newsletter web Twitter IRC Facebook etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: Whatever the thing it is that you use in the internet iTunes RSS You should connect to us in the way of your choosing.
Rym: You should also follow me at Shazar on Twitter for reasons that you can find out by asking other GeekNights listeners.
Rym: Okay, I will win that That thing.
Rym: you could follow me And then they will see the thing that I promise they can see if I if a certain condition is met by the end of the year boats.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: show about Area 88 the blue skies.
Rym: You stopped.
Scott: that's all we needed up the trail.
Scott: So did you know that there's a Super Nintendo game based on this called UN squadron?
Rym: Actually, I heard there's a Super Nintendo game based on this called UN squad.
Scott: really did you know the Super Nintendo game based on this?
Scott: Anime and manga called UN squadron.
Rym: So more importantly there's this movie called snatch.
Rym: I don't know if you've ever seen it, but it's an inside joke.
Rym: Oh So here's some context.
Scott: back in the day, you know back in the day Monday We needed to figure out what to do a show on.
Scott: we couldn't come up with anything.
Scott: today We're like we need to watch an anime real quick.
Scott: The only DVD we had that had an anime that was only an hour long.
Scott: is it this way two hours?
Scott: I was was area 88 so we watched it and now we're doing a show on it.
Rym: I want to do a little more context cuz I have seen this before whoa.
Rym: So when I knew of it before when I was eight and a half years old And my little brother was Six years old.
Rym: Okay, my parents forced me and my little brother to watch vampire hunter D Eyeball it mouth.
Rym: I was born in 1982 so you can figure out when that was so.
Rym: Not too long after that as in about five minutes after that I was a hardcore anime fan and I went to blockbuster video which existed back then wasn't full of ghosts And I proceeded to rent every single anime that was on the shelf there Except for neon Genesis Evangelion because as a little kid, I thought it was some Christian anime.
Rym: I didn't want to see anything like that.
Rym: Good job an atheist.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: Only I'd known.
Scott: good job.
Rym: I swear to God.
Scott: So when I went to the RIT anime club I looked at the VHS tapes they had there and even jelly was the one that had the nicest boxes and had a name and Felt like it was.
Scott: I just saw these crosses.
Rym: It was called Evangelion.
Rym: That was the first one I went for of a wimpy kid like sitting in a chair crying and someone's talking to him.
Rym: I knew what that was gonna be about.
Scott: sure you did.
Rym: So after I'd already watched like Armageddon and I don't know wind of amnesia and we named me not even demon demon city There project a co all that business wicked sitting.
Rym: I hadn't seen wicked city.
Rym: yet I saw a wicked city later, but still probably Dragon pink and dragon half.
Rym: some point in that sojourn I rented a VHS tape that simply said area 88 the blue skies of betrayal.
Rym: and when I looked at that box I remember thinking wait a minute.
Rym: That looks a lot like UN squadron.
Rym: This is UN squadron, why the fuck is this called area?
Scott: I don't know if we can emphasize enough.
Scott: This thing is fucking UN squadron.
Rym: Yeah, I was a big fan of UN squadron.
Scott: It's actually a fucking good game, but fuck it.
Rym: It's a really good shmup But it's hard as ball like the weather outside.
Rym: I get like the wind rimer that it is.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So as it fucks.
Rym: I watched this this one episode and I was obsessed with it Because it does all the things that initial D does except it's not like initial D. It's more like one of those more like I don't know one piece.
Scott: Yeah bleach if I was still high school middle school kid, this would have been the best anime.
Rym: I'm against initial D of fighter jets sort of but you've got to earn money.
Rym: The dude has to earn money just like Million, I guess dollars.
Rym: Maybe it was yen.
Scott: It was something 1.5
Rym: million something's by piloting fighter jets and being paid to shoot down other fighter jets in what apparently is an endless war with unlimited fighter jets in a place that is vaguely Arabic but not in Africa
Scott: with a war that has no Context a war
Rym: where there's just bunch of tanks in the desert a bunch of fighter jets destroy them.
Rym: They get paid like 500 bucks a tank.
Scott: Yep, and there's just like in the video game You shoot things and money pops out just like in Raiden.
Scott: or you know any of those shmups?
Rym: and I was a little kid I thought this was the best thing ever and it didn't go anywhere.
Scott: Well, here's the thing is this is only episode fucking one.
Scott: there's three episodes in this OAV.
Scott: We've only seen the first time.
Rym: there is another area.
Rym: eight is a terrible recent TV show.
Scott: Okay, so according to Wikipedia is a long ass manga.
Scott: this 20-something volume never read.
Scott: It is a three episode OAV of which we are only discussing episode one.
Rym: I've only seen one episode if I saw more episodes and their tiny brain does not remember and there is a TV series that is Actually relatively more recent.
Rym: I watched one episode of it and it was I watched it.
Rym: All I could think was this feels way bad compared to the original OAV.
Scott: So here's something interesting and the reason.
Scott: we only saw the first episodes OAV.
Rym: Yeah, we had a DVD of it.
Scott: We have okay.
Scott: So first CPM put it out on VHS.
Scott: the whole fucking thing, right.
Scott: then CPM put out only the very first episode on DVD, which is what we have.
Scott: Then a DV put out the whole thing on DVD, which we do not have.
Scott: What I have is a u.s.
Rym: Manga core complete with their mecha spokesman Mandy guys most dangerous.
Rym: and if I open this up, this is the DVD.
Rym: We actually just watched.
Rym: I don't know when I bought this or how I own it still has a CPM survey card.
Rym: It has the CPM survey card.
Rym: So I'm gonna share this.
Scott: I'm pretty sure we got this at the first New York anime festival in the CPM going out of business.
Scott: Ultra discount fire sale being ahem.
Rym: What is their annual household income?
Rym: and the highest I can say is over 50k.
Rym: Okay, how many pre-recorded video cassettes do you own?
Rym: What equipment do you have?
Rym: There are six options VHS.
Rym: Yes, eight millimeter.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: video disc Yes, satellite dish.
Scott: No.
Rym: Compact disc.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: projection TV.
Rym: No.
Rym: Where do you purchase or rent your video cassettes?
Rym: mail order catalog?
Scott: No drugstore?
Rym: No Department store.
Rym: No record store.
Rym: No video store.
Rym: No toy store.
Scott: No There's no internet option.
Rym: The last one the last one here what factors were important to you and you decided to buy this video cassette?
Scott: price Yes, no featured actor or actress.
Rym: no type of program or genre Yes brand and or reputation.
Scott: Yes other yes.
Rym: So, yeah, I want to mail this in but I know that if I mail this to 250 West 57th, they're not there.
Rym: 317 they are not there.
Rym: No, but no postage necessary.
Rym: So it will get there.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: All right, so Let's talk about this actual fucking show.
Scott: So the first episode here you and squadron, here's the deal.
Scott: There's a guy.
Scott: he's a badass fighter.
Scott: Shin Kazuma.
Scott: He's piloting this meaningless fighter pilot in this meaningless war in the desert.
Rym: He's pretty he's got side hair and he bears his chest On the cover.
Scott: He's at area 88 which is this Airport, basically with all the fighter jets take off.
Rym: There's a gas station in initial D.
Scott: Yeah, there are other characters there who are also fighter pilots of various sorts.
Rym: the bearded guy who's like my planes on fire.
Rym: Fuck it.
Rym: Let's keep going.
Scott: Most of those other characters don't really matter.
Scott: There's a photographer who's sort of you know, they're witnessing what's going on, but he doesn't really matter either isn't doing anything.
Rym: He's no speedgrapher.
Scott: Yeah, nothing.
Scott: He does means anything.
Scott: He's just sort of there.
Rym: as far as I can tell the area 88 TV show focuses mostly on him.
Scott: Oh interesting Yeah, cuz I mean if you did that it would be sort of like a Marvel situation where you have this sort of you know Neutral character sort of giving you the viewpoint of the viewer of the show, you know watching things from the outside Perspective.
Rym: but no this one clearly actually just follows.
Scott: Yeah, all the guy with the camera all he does is bother people.
Scott: There's some other characters.
Scott: We barely see them in this first episode except for you know, the impetus of why?
Scott: shin cosmo piloting You know planes in this meaningless war.
Rym: So when I was a kid, I thought that the plot of why he's doing This was amazing.
Rym: It was the best thing ever.
Rym: I couldn't oh my god fighter jets.
Rym: So watching it now His friend wants to shtink his girlfriend, yep, so he gets him drunk Yep, and then holds a piece of paper in front of him to sign this.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: He signs it That's it.
Scott: That is a con actually a contract to have the guy signed up to go and do the killing fight in the Osron Royal Mercenary Air Force, right?
Rym: He has to either fight for three years Be earn 1.5 million dollars or dessert which I assume they kill you if you dessert Yeah, well if they catch you deserting, yeah, and in the desert you're not gonna make it now.
Rym: uh What's interesting is that he signs this contract and then these dudes with guns come and they're like We're gonna shoot you if you don't come.
Rym: I feel like the contract is unnecessary.
Rym: I feel like they could have just kidnapped him and it's kind of stupid.
Rym: up bonus points the guy who shanghaied him Basically did it to marry the daughter and the daughter.
Rym: the daughter of this rich guy and the daughter who loves shin is like I'm not gonna marry you.
Rym: I still love shin cuz she's actually kind of cool dude.
Scott: You could marry fucking any girl.
Scott: Why do you need to shanghaied dude to marry that girl also in the preview of the next episode?
Rym: He's like she won't marry me because she thinks shins still alive, but doesn't know.
Rym: So he tries to hire a hitman to kill shin while he's still in area 88.
Scott: Why don't you just falsify some evidence that he's dead?
Rym: Yeah, or just say How does she even know he's alive?
Rym: How is killing him going to matter?
Rym: Why didn't you just kill him in the first place?
Scott: None of this shit makes fucking any sense at all.
Scott: It's so contrived.
Rym: Maybe the manga tells you more.
Rym: Yeah, there's something I want to say.
Rym: We when we talked about the baron omatsuri the sixth one-piece movie We were inspired to do a lecture which we're gonna do an anime Boston about how every anime Is the same?
Scott: Well, no every anime movie is the same but These are not the same only these movies.
Rym: Well, the slayers motion picture is arguably an OAV.
Scott: Was it never in theaters?
Rym: Oh, so if you watch the slayers OAVs, they actually have the same anyway, that's true Those are so.
Rym: there are two classes of those standalone anime things.
Rym: That's one is the baron omatsuri that we're gonna talk about a lot.
Rym: The other is area 88, but the best example of this is the god-awful sanctuary OAV.
Rym: There was an era where there were a ton of OAVs and all they are is let's get all the proper nouns from some really popular manga and Show just enough of it to where everyone who has read that manga is gonna buy this VHS tape or DVD and watch it and go.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: There's the character.
Rym: I like from the manga.
Rym: Oh my god There's some foreshadowing for something that will never happen in this OAV exactly.
Scott: Well think about it, right?
Scott: It's like, you know nowadays you get an anime series like say Death Note, right?
Scott: Take the whole manga copy the whole damn thing translate the whole show to anime right and put it out on TV.
Scott: That's what they did there.
Scott: this it's back in the day.
Scott: They had a lot more money in the anime industry.
Scott: and it's like well Here's this somewhat more obscure not as popular as Dragon Ball Z thing, you know Which is gonna get you know, completely translated into an anime.
Scott: We don't want to make a whole TV series for area 88 so let's sort of squish it down and make an OAV and super fans will buy it and pay a lot of money for it.
Scott: and You know, we only had to produce like three episodes.
Scott: Let's just you know copy as much of the plot as we can and squish it in here like the sanctuary.
Scott: one was like episode.
Scott: it's basically volumes one and two of sanctuary animated poorly and That's it.
Scott: and they just don't bother continue with the rest of the manga and it's pretty much like hey super fans We animated some of your obscure thing.
Scott: Isn't that cool?
Scott: Yeah So, I mean granted we've only seen OAV one.
Scott: but I mean you're not gonna convince me that if I watch episodes two and three of the OAV that that is going to contain everything that happened in 25 volumes of manga.
Rym: this OAV is notable one because of UN squadron.
Rym: Yes, the video game - it has some pretty dangerous music.
Rym: Good God three.
Rym: the characters Have these this ridiculous Foley like when he takes off his helmet.
Rym: There's like this shook noise.
Rym: It's almost as ridiculous as an escaflowne when every sword apparently it consists of nothing but a million raddly pieces of metal.
Rym: Everything they do has these like ridiculous noises to the point that I couldn't stop laughing the entire time.
Scott: and how many people can crash land fighter jets on the runway without getting hurt at all?
Rym: This is basically someone crash lands a fighter jet behind you the movie.
Scott: Nothing is realistic or making sense or they're not even trying.
Rym: So this was directed by a man named Hisayuki Toriyomi.
Scott: Okay, never heard of him.
Rym: I'd never heard of him.
Rym: So I did a little bit of research meaning I looked at anime news network.
Rym: Okay, and The only thing he is directed that I have ever even heard of.
Scott: besides area 88 is Fucking Lily cat.
Scott: I never heard of Lily.
Scott: Really?
Rym: You've never seen Lily cat.
Scott: What is it like it?
Rym: It's a terrible anime No kidding.
Scott: What's what's it about?
Rym: a Genetic?
Rym: I don't even know, okay.
Rym: Oh Wait, here's a plot summary.
Rym: Okay So this plot summary doesn't jive with anything.
Rym: I remember other than that There's a gene.
Rym: Okay So a crew travels across the universe in a ship that can travel for 20 years with the crew that will only age one year.
Rym: Suddenly some of the crew members come down with some sort of virus with no help from the outside world.
Rym: They survive the viral attack for a year.
Rym: Okay, basically an alien knock-off Or an alien knock-off with the cat girl at it.
Rym: There's no cat girl.
Scott: Then why is it called Lily cat?
Rym: Oh cat is an acronym.
Scott: What does it stand for?
Rym: Fuck if I remember cryogenic something time.
Rym: It's pretty bad Pretty bad really bad.
Rym: It's got one of those Carl Masek dubs, but crappy anime TV show cat He's the.
Rym: Yuki Toriyomi not only directed it, but apparently wrote the story.
Rym: Whoa, okay Yeah, whoa Nelly there way to go dude not the script But he wrote the screenplay or the original story and then he directed it, but the script is written by some other guy.
Scott: So, uh, I don't know how long you want to go with this.
Rym: This has got that really good sort of like 90s animation of tanks rotating like machines Rotating in three dimensions that takes a long time to do and sell it.
Scott: Yeah, it has.
Scott: it has a certain nostalgic feel to it from anime from that.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: It feels so late 80s.
Scott: Oh my god, but It's really I would not go.
Scott: I'm not looking for episodes two and three.
Rym: You only watch this if you're a hardcore anime fan and you want to see something that is very Typical of an era and that era is between 1985 and 1992.
Scott: Yeah, so You know don't watch this really.
Rym: So Scott, how far is it to paradise?
Scott: That's a good question.
Scott: But yeah, it's just as far as your SNES controller where you can play a game worth.
Rym: Oh This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and brand Okay for the logos Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.