Rym: It's Tuesday, August 7th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, tournaments.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I am back from Brazil.
Scott: Brazil.
Rym: I'll do a show later like on some Thursday about being in Brazil, but it was pretty fun.
Rym: I would go again.
Scott: Yeah, Brazil is a weird place because it has good things and bad things in great combination.
Rym: The city, Sao Paulo, super modern, super chill.
Scott: Wouldn't it be modern?
Rym: We wandered around like the equivalent of Fifth Avenue and had nice dinners and it was crazy.
Rym: But at the same time, you notice that half the cars on the street are armored as in an inch of bulletproof glass and bomb proofing.
Rym: And yeah, the one thing that I can say is that I did some research.
Rym: Brazil recently fell off of the top 10 list of most violent countries.
Rym: So they're getting better.
Rym: A lot of violent crime and kidnapping, though.
Rym: Yeah, but no, I hope but also lots of good stuff.
Rym: I get to go back soon.
Scott: It's weird that a lot of countries, you know, it's like you look around the world and it's like, ah, you know, you live in the U.S.
Scott: and you look around and you say, look at that country.
Scott: They have something awesome that we don't have like Portugal.
Scott: You can just you know, the drug policy there is great.
Scott: What problems do they have?
Scott: The economy not so great.
Rym: They speak Portuguese on Brazil.
Scott: They do.
Rym: Let me tell you, Portuguese, Spanish people who speak Portuguese can understand Spanish just fine.
Rym: But people who speak Spanish can't understand shit of what Portuguese people say.
Rym: And that was and the weirdest part of that is I could read the menus at restaurants better than the Spanish speaking, learning Portuguese guy I was with because a lot of it was in Japanese.
Scott: Really?
Rym: A lot of Asians there.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Rym: So I'd be like, yeah, she made you whatever different names of fish.
Rym: I got this.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Fish is pretty good down there.
Rym: Fish was pretty good down there.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, yeah, I'm back.
Rym: Regular schedule until PAX and then fuck.
Rym: There's going to be.
Rym: I don't know what's going to happen.
Rym: We're going to be gone collectively for like three weeks.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So remember, I talked a whole lot about my new computer and your tiny God.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Let me tell you, I don't want to go on for a hundred years about it, but I've never bought a computer before in my life that was so powerful relative to what is available on the market.
Rym: Scott, when I bought this computer, it was that.
Rym: So I know exactly how you feel.
Scott: It is like I can do anything and it's like I bought this stupid Adobe Creative Cloud.
Scott: So now I can do.
Scott: I feel like I can make any things that I can imagine I can make it.
Rym: It is a powerful moment when you drag an hour long, like 1080p 60 video into Premiere and it's like, boop.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's even crazier.
Scott: So it's like I'll have everything open that I usually have open and I'll have like Premiere rendering a video and I'll have like Lightroom organizing photo and iTunes importing all these MP3s and full screen 3D game Mac settings.
Scott: And there's no slow down.
Scott: The fans don't even get.
Rym: My how times have changed because I remember at RIT, because remember when we first all met, you know, there's the cycle of who has the baddest as computer at any given time among a group of the E.P.
Scott: competition.
Rym: When we all got to RIT, that was me because I spent every bond.
Rym: my grandparents had bought me for 19 years on a computer right before I went to RIT.
Scott: Mine was a Pentium 3450.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Mine was an AMD like K7.
Scott: All right.
Scott: We switched to AMD and they kept breaking.
Scott: We kept upgrading and breaking and upgrading.
Scott: Yeah, because then I upgraded to the Thunderbird gigahertz.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's another thing I want to say, right, is, you know, there are still people out there I realize that are all AMD ish.
Scott: And, you know, I looked at AMD and it's like, yeah, you can get like a six core AMD for 100 bucks.
Scott: It's like, whoa.
Rym: At the really low end or not the really low end, but at the at the not like plateau of performance, AMD is still way cheaper.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the thing is, you know, I first had it in Pentium three.
Scott: It was my first computer I built.
Scott: And that computer never had a problem ever.
Rym: Simpler anecdote.
Rym: Every Intel computer I've ever built booted on the first try.
Rym: No AMD computer I've ever built booted on the first try.
Rym: We built AMD computers from like all through the Pentium four years up until the core two, which was always like me, Scott and a bunch of the other crew standing around a computer being like, why won't it boot?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I guess we have many like AMD CPUs.
Scott: Did we have lying around extra motherboards?
Rym: I still have all those AMD CPUs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We had all this stuff lying around.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Because the shit kept breaking.
Scott: So now I'm sure AMD might be just fine now.
Rym: And Intel, to be fair, the shit that broke wasn't the CPUs.
Rym: It was always the.
Scott: I had a bad CPU.
Rym: I never, never.
Rym: But anyway, the point is that it was always those jank ass a bit motherboards.
Scott: Well, the general the first the Pentium motherboard, the first one ahead was a bit.
Scott: It was perfect.
Rym: The thing is around that era is when I was getting like, let's overclock it a bit like super mother.
Scott: I didn't even overclock.
Scott: But all those AMD years shit broke.
Scott: The whole AMD ecosystem of hardware was not reliable in those years for us.
Scott: And every Intel computer I've had has been 100 percent stable.
Scott: My first one, Pentium three was stable.
Scott: The core two duo that I just replaced is still in great condition.
Scott: If you want it, contact me.
Rym: I also have a core two duo that you can have.
Scott: However, and the new one I just bought booted on the first try.
Scott: Perfect.
Scott: Everything amazing.
Rym: There's something wrong with that motherboard because USB will occasionally cause it to voltage drop and hard crash.
Scott: Anyway, anyway.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: And having two of the Dell ultra sharp monitors to on arms is pretty sick.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So if you want my old monitors this past weekend, you may know that we know many people who work at MUSE games.
Rym: like a whole bunch of our friends work there and they're working on a new game is Guns of Icarus online.
Rym: There's been a beta for a while and I was in it, but I played it for real over the weekend because it's getting to the point of like being good.
Rym: You can actually play it.
Rym: And it was actually really fun.
Rym: Emily was like, come on, play my game, try it out.
Rym: I'm like, OK, I'll stop playing Counter-Strike and play this new game.
Rym: And it's no slight to Guns of Icarus because it is hard to give it to me to play any game that is in Counter-Strike.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I start to play and then I just kind of kept playing for some hours because it was actually really fun.
Scott: There are people playing in.
Rym: Yeah, there were.
Scott: So we were doing like and the network part worked as the most important thing is that, you know, all these indie games, the network shit doesn't work.
Rym: The network should actually work perfectly.
Rym: There was glitchy stuff in the game, but it was the kind of like game balance, game mechanic glitchiness that you expect from a beta.
Scott: Not like, oops, I walked through the wall.
Scott: Oops, I fell off the well.
Rym: At one point I fell off a ship and instead of dying, I just kept falling forever.
Scott: Nice.
Rym: But mostly it worked.
Rym: And the game is actually super fun.
Rym: And me and Adam ended up being on a ship at one point.
Rym: And here's why this game is actually fun.
Rym: Like the whole gist of it is that you'll have multiple ships, like two ships per team, and each ship has like four or five, a bunch of people on it.
Rym: And you run around FPS style on the ship, repairing stuff, Team Fortress 2 style and like manning guns and someone's and someone's the captain and they're steering it.
Rym: And the steering feels like this kind of like steampunk thing.
Rym: The steering and the logistics and the teamwork and all that stuff actually matters a lot.
Rym: Like at one point, Adam was the captain on my ship.
Rym: And, you know, it's like when we play Counter-Strike, if two people who know what the fuck they're doing in games are on the same team in a game, shit goes down.
Rym: And yeah, shit went down.
Rym: Adam was like, they're coming up on the left and he's pulling maneuvers through the smoke.
Rym: We'd like get into the smoke and then reappear behind someone suddenly and just open up a broadside.
Rym: It was the game was surprisingly fun for a still beta game.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Rym: So that's my initial geek bite.
Rym: And I'm going to do a more thorough geek bite once I play the game a little more and possibly play it against strangers instead of with someone I know.
Rym: Adam, you're a good captain, but don't use that.
Rym: There's this thing.
Rym: you can use that like speeds up your ship, but it also ruins your engines.
Rym: And I think he turned it on and forgot to turn it off.
Scott: So it's not like.
Scott: it's not like a one time burst.
Scott: It's like a lever that you put in one of two.
Rym: It's basically like poor moonshine into the engine and you get like 300 percent speed, but then the engine takes damage.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But you just kept the moonshine was just flowing like water.
Rym: OK, I guess like you didn't run out of it.
Scott: I mean, it takes a while.
Rym: Well, the engines all exploded.
Scott: How many X was it?
Rym: Three X's on the bottle.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, we learned the X is on the moonshine bottle.
Scott: That's how many times it's been through the still.
Scott: Every time you put it through the still, you put another X. That's when.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, there you go.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Or, you know, so let's just do some news here.
Scott: Let's not blow our whole load that we have plenty to talk about in future episodes.
Rym: So I'm always conflicted when a company I hate sues another company I hate.
Scott: And well, the thing is, usually when that happens and this hasn't been happening lately, but whenever anyone sues anyone, I mostly just want the court to set the precedent the way that I want, because I want what I want.
Rym: Well, well, there's two things or I or if it's people I hate, I want them to do as much damage to each other as possible.
Scott: That's also true.
Scott: But so when it's two people, you hate you anyway.
Scott: So what's what's going on?
Rym: EA has sued Zynga.
Scott: Well, Zynga.
Scott: I mean, I hate EA, but Zynga is worse.
Rym: Well, EA is just kind of, you know, exploiting their workers, making generic.
Scott: Well, they already got sued for exploiting their workers and they supposedly fix that, I guess.
Rym: The video game industry is fucked when it comes to worker treatment.
Rym: That's a separate union.
Rym: But EA, you know, they're like the Microsoft of the gaming world.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Microsoft in the 90s to nerds.
Rym: Anyway, Zynga.
Rym: Well, no, they're not a game company.
Rym: Zynga doesn't make games.
Rym: I've said that on lectures.
Rym: I've said that at PAX.
Rym: I've said it on the shelves later.
Rym: Zynga does not make anything that competes with what I would call a game.
Rym: They make games in the same way that patty cake is a game, but in replace patty cake with patty.
Rym: And then you got to put a quarter in to get the cakes.
Rym: So EA is suing Zynga over copyright infringement.
Rym: And this is where things get weird, because if you don't know game mechanics, game rules, things like that, not copyrightable at all.
Rym: You can.
Rym: There is so much precedent for you not being able to copyright the rules of a game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You don't copyright rules of a game.
Scott: You copyright, you know, art work or music.
Rym: A specific, like, for example, a drawing, a music, a background.
Scott: Yeah, that's artworks are copyrighted.
Scott: You know, something like game mechanics would be an invention.
Scott: They'd be patented.
Scott: And even then it's very your logo of your company or the logo and name of your game trademark.
Rym: So you can't sue someone and win by all the legal precedent we who are not lawyers know of.
Rym: And I read like 10 articles.
Rym: Well, you could.
Scott: What if I made an FPS that used like all the sprites from Doom, but you didn't let me finish based on game mechanics.
Scott: Of course not.
Rym: And every time there's been a lawsuit that worked about someone stealing a game, it's always been like, yeah, they stole all the backgrounds from Morrowind or something like that.
Rym: But in this case, no, EA is suing over a game because it's mechanically and stylistically similar to their game.
Scott: Well, did their lawyers be smart?
Scott: I don't know what's going on because I mean, like, how could we know more than people who are lawyers 24/7?
Rym: So what's interesting is that the mainstream media, like Wall Street Journal type news organizations are saying the same thing.
Rym: we're saying.
Rym: They're like, what the fuck is EA doing?
Rym: You can't sue for that.
Rym: That's not even covered by the law.
Rym: That's crazy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, look at around the world.
Scott: This is why you can see a lot of like Monopoly clones out there, but you just can't call it something like Opoly because you'll get trademark sued.
Scott: But if you just call it like the Scott game, but it looks just like Monopoly and it plays like Monopoly, how many people.
Scott: it doesn't have Monopoly man on it and doesn't use like Baltic, you know, those names as different names and different colors.
Rym: How many people have taken that old mafia slash werewolf game and remade it?
Rym: I'm doing it even.
Rym: Yeah, it's not you can't copyright that.
Rym: But so every article I've read has had a quote from a lawyer or an analyst or someone who basically said, what the fuck is EA doing?
Rym: This is a ludicrous lawsuit.
Rym: Yeah, but they've always qualified it by saying not that Zynga is a good company.
Scott: Well, because I mean, you got to think Zynga basically does just clone all the games.
Scott: They see someone else, a successful game.
Scott: They make the same exact game thing as a team in the mighty.
Rym: Then they're not breaking the rules, but they're still.
Scott: they take.
Scott: They see a game that's successful.
Scott: They directly copy it and Zynga if I and tweak it slightly.
Scott: So they make it time to make it to make do.
Rym: every time I click, it's nine ninety five to you.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And then they stick it on Facebook and iPhone and whatnot.
Scott: And that's that.
Scott: So, yeah, they're not exactly, you know, the bestest.
Scott: I mean, imagine if we just made a game that was the same game as Puerto Rico, but we called it GeekNights, Rico, and we changed all the artworks and all the things legally.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Morally gray area.
Scott: But if we put that out, you know, we would be punished in the marketplace because anyone in that marketplace would know, hey, this is a Puerto Rico clone and no one would buy it up unless we made it online and easy to play.
Scott: Well, actually, I was thinking, right, what if we did that evilly?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And what we did is we basically just made the board game versions, the physical versions with very low production values, but still playable.
Scott: And we made them way cheaper.
Scott: So it's like Puerto Rico, 10 bucks because it's a cheap ass version.
Scott: But it's not called Puerto Rico.
Scott: It's GeekNights, whatnot.
Rym: That'd be on the morally gray, shitty business practice level of the stuff Zinga does.
Scott: But legal.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: In my opinion, not a lawyer.
Rym: Everything Zinga is doing here is pretty legal.
Scott: There's nothing.
Scott: The thing is, right, is lawsuit is groundless.
Scott: They is currently legal.
Scott: But I'm actually I'm not sure my opinion.
Rym: Scott, if you're OK with copywriting game mechanics and you're OK with a much deeper copyright ability of things like I am considering making my opinion.
Scott: I'm not saying this is my current.
Rym: All right.
Rym: You realize my hackles are up.
Scott: I'm ready to argue here that Zinga like games are so basically they're gambling and should be regulated as such, even though.
Scott: because imagine if I made a slot machine, but the slot machine had a guaranteed payout of zero, but you had to pay a quarter.
Scott: You pulled the lever.
Rym: I'm just going to.
Rym: I'll play the devil's advocate because we should do a separate show on this.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: We're going to be talking about this at both Pax Prime and Pax Dev on two different.
Scott: I'm feeling like, you know, that's like even, you know, solitaire blitz is kind of fun from PopCap, but I'm feeling like it's just an evil slot machine and sort of shouldn't maybe shouldn't be.
Rym: I'm not sure.
Scott: I'm considering changing my opinion that it shouldn't be an argument to be considered or at least should be regulated.
Rym: That's we.
Rym: free speech is number one.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: I know.
Scott: That's why I'm only considering.
Rym: because are we going to say that a game is no longer free?
Rym: speech is speech when movies, books, pictographs, drawings, music, everything else is free speech.
Scott: But a game is can also because of what it is, right, because it is a thing that you do and not just the thing you experience gambling be regulated.
Scott: That is a good question.
Scott: And also sort of why does it?
Rym: why does gambling matter if there's no payout?
Rym: The only reason you regulate gambling is to make sure that at least the people who do gamble don't get fucked by an unregulated, but it's also to make sure, but it's also to make sure that the casino doesn't cheat the people.
Rym: That's what I'm saying, to make sure that that there's not some unregulated market where the consumers don't know what they're buying.
Rym: But games like this, like these crappy social league games, I feel like social game is code for a shit game at this point.
Rym: Well, yeah, but I do those games not tell you exactly what they're doing, not 100 percent of the time.
Scott: They don't necessarily tell you, like all the mechanics of the game, like, yeah, this thing gives you 100 percent chance of this happening within five hours.
Rym: So, Scott, if we regulate those games, what's the line?
Rym: Does Half-Life have to tell you how many points of damage the new gun does?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: That's why I'm only considering.
Scott: Yeah, but there's still some.
Scott: I mean, it is sort of a man trap, right?
Scott: It's like certain kinds of advertising are illegal.
Rym: Only only advertising that is actually directly false or because of weird regulations, cigarette ads.
Scott: Well, yeah, but I mean, like, you know, subliminal advertising, even though it doesn't work, is illegal.
Rym: But that was made illegal under a very shady, it was and would probably not stand up in court if it was challenged.
Scott: But it doesn't work.
Rym: But imagine that because it now I'm saying one, because it doesn't work, it wouldn't stand up in court.
Rym: I don't believe.
Rym: And two, OK, even if it did work, would it be?
Rym: would it really be fair to regulate it?
Rym: Because what if I wrote a novel that's subliminal?
Scott: Let's not waste the whole episode on this, but I'm going to ask one question and then we will not answer it and then we'll move on.
Rym: OK, and then I'll ask another question.
Scott: No, no, no question is like my question.
Scott: If I invented a mind control device, would should it be legal?
Scott: That's the question.
Scott: Don't answer it.
Scott: Let's just move on.
Rym: So my question is, do we care if Zynga gets fucked or not?
Scott: No.
Rym: So here's here's my personal read on this.
Rym: I think what EA is trying to do here is get a precedent set to change the way these things work in the courts.
Rym: I think EA is going to try to use its muscle to get the court to argue or to agree that certain aspects of game mechanics are copyrightable.
Rym: And regardless of whether or not you think this lawsuit has merit, because again, Zynga basically steals stuff for all intents and purposes.
Rym: If EA wins this lawsuit, the the ramifications for game design and gameplay are staggering and almost universally bad.
Rym: Well, the thing that we're not want to win this this is like someone sues Hitler.
Rym: We don't want Hitler to win.
Rym: But if the lawsuit passes, then video games get banned.
Scott: Well, here's the thing, right, is that a lot of these cases lately, the people have been pushing jury trials, you know, juries to decide.
Rym: That's bad news.
Scott: And if a jury looks at pictures of EA's games, sees evidence that those games were released on the market first and then sees pictures of Zynga's games, which look basically identical, 99 percent identical, it's not going to.
Scott: it's going to be hard to convince the jury that Zynga wasn't just ripping them off.
Scott: But at the same time, the jury is not going to want to decide in Zynga's favor.
Rym: But at the same time, then the appeals would look more.
Scott: It's up to the judge to give the jury the correct instructions.
Rym: No, I'm saying even if a jury trial happened on appeal, it would probably end up getting into a precedent's argument and that sort of stuff.
Scott: That'd be good because.
Rym: Yeah, but that's the news there.
Rym: I don't want to get a win, but I don't want to win either.
Rym: So I'm hoping that Zynga exhausts money defending against this wins, but then goes out of business.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day, there's been a sort of hobby on the Internet for a while now, and it's kind of gained some steam recently because more people were doing it.
Rym: We linked to things about this a while ago, but trying to play modern games with really low settings just to see what they look like and do this.
Rym: Yeah, you did.
Rym: So this one goes a step further.
Rym: This is a dude who didn't just set the kind of like in the menu settings down on Half-Life 2.
Rym: He went and changed all the variables to make Half-Life 2 be as minimal as goddamn possible.
Rym: And let me tell you, this looks a lot like Quake one, and it's actually kind of amazing to see how the game is still pretty playable and things are still pretty recognizable.
Scott: Only because you played it before.
Rym: Even then, I could play this because it's yeah.
Scott: No, you forget on paper is playing Scott.
Rym: When was the last time you played Doom?
Rym: and it was not one of these Doom remakes with a higher resolution?
Scott: I played the Doom remake with a higher resolution, but I didn't enable the higher resolution.
Scott: So it still looked like Doomdoom looked like.
Rym: I can't even comprehend Doomdoom anymore.
Scott: I can.
Rym: My brain is like, what the fuck is that?
Rym: And I turn the resolution up.
Rym: But anyway, this is actually pretty entertaining to watch.
Rym: Also, you should totally comment on the guy's video and tell him how amazing it is that it looks just like Minecraft, just like everyone does.
Rym: Yeah, he has an annotation.
Rym: He's like, guys, stop telling me it looks like Minecraft.
Rym: I get an email for every comment.
Rym: I don't care.
Scott: So you could turn that off if you wanted to.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, so, you know, I just bought a new computer and it has a sound card in it, but the sound card is part of the motherboard.
Scott: And pretty much every sound card these days pretty much just plays digital audio perfectly, as many digital audios as you want just to speakers, just like your iPhone or whatever, like a stereo.
Scott: It's they're pretty much perfect.
Scott: They're all the same.
Scott: They don't really matter.
Scott: They all follow the same Intel AC 97 standard thing.
Scott: They all you know, there's no friggin difference.
Scott: You don't even think about it.
Scott: You just your computer can play any sound.
Scott: There is.
Scott: no.
Rym: I remember a day.
Scott: I remember a day back in the day, computers couldn't play any sound.
Scott: There was they didn't.
Scott: you didn't have enough memory and processing power to actually play digital audio.
Rym: Most games had MIDI soundtracks or some equivalent.
Rym: And even then, it sounded way different.
Rym: If you had an all 32, it sounded way different than if you had like a regular sound blaster.
Scott: or basically, you know, computers today have digital audio.
Scott: You have the audio in a file like an MP3 or an AUG.
Scott: that is just the waveform.
Scott: And then the computer plays it back by converting that digital data into an analog audio signal and sending it to a speaker.
Scott: In the olden days, you couldn't store that or process that digital thing and convert it to analog quickly enough or have enough memory to hold on to it.
Scott: So you couldn't do it that way.
Scott: You could have analog audio like a vinyl record or cassette tape and just play it back with a player.
Scott: But you would have to somehow control the cassette player, have the computer control the play and pause buttons, the cassette player and rewind.
Scott: And I don't think anyone ever even did that.
Rym: Remember, even like not that long ago, PlayStation one games, Redbook audio.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the very first computers for audio, all they had was a PC speaker that basically went beep boop and it had.
Scott: basically it was like a buzzer and you like a doorbell and you could friggin ring it.
Scott: And that was pretty much it.
Rym: I remember installing old games.
Rym: One of the things you had to do is set the IRQ and DMA stuff for your sound card and you had to pick like, do you have an ad lib or the Roland, whatever.
Scott: So over the years, what you know, they had sound cards and what sound cards were.
Scott: And your computer still has one of these in it somewhere, even though it's not used.
Rym: It's just on the motherboard.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's basically a synthesizer.
Scott: So it was like you have an instrument, a keyboard, like a Casio keyboard synthesizer built into the computer.
Scott: And the computer, the game basically has, you know, a musical track and then plays the sound card like it's a keyboard.
Scott: And that's how your computer would make music with a sound card.
Scott: And because of that, you know, different synthesizers sound different.
Scott: So different computers sounded different and had different capabilities and could play more noises at once.
Scott: And this is how the NES made music and how the SNES made music even.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was all these old computers had synthesizers in them that the games, the software played.
Scott: So the software is playing a digital instrument.
Scott: So this guy wrote this amazing article here that is called The History of Sound Cards in Computer Game Music, and he covers the PC speaker, the IBM PC, Jr.
Scott: and Tandy, the Adlib, the Roland, the Creative Game Blaster, the Sound Blaster, the I had.
Rym: my first sound card was this like integrated way.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: Roland sound canvas, Gravis ultrasound, Creative Lab, Sound Blaster 16, R32 and then modern sound cards.
Scott: And he has audio samples from all of these.
Scott: And the best part was that he got audio samples from this game, Silpheed, which is really old shooter, but he has like Silpheed.
Scott: He has samples from it, from PC speaker, PC, Jr.
Scott: Adlib.
Scott: He's got Silpheed running on like six or seven different cards here, or maybe five or six with the same exact music.
Scott: And it's like, whoa, you can totally hear, you know, what's going on.
Scott: The other thing is he kind of left out like he has the music from Descent and Descent 2.
Scott: But what he left out was the fact that the Descent and Descent 2 were on CD-ROMs and had Redbook audio.
Scott: So what those would do is even that was you would put Descent in and you start playing it.
Scott: And if you had a modern sound card with the CD-ROM had a little cable that ran from the CD-ROM to the sound card and basically play the music straight off the CD like a CD player.
Scott: So you had a real music with those games.
Scott: But he's not giving you that music.
Scott: He's giving you the synthesized music from Descent and Descent 2 for people who didn't have CD-ROMs or CD-ROMs hooked up properly.
Rym: I remember the one when I finally give us my dad to buy me a Sound Blaster AWE 32, the AWE 32.
Scott: He's also got a lot of Quest for Glory clips here for Rym.
Rym: Quest for Glory had some great sound.
Scott: Also, let me tell you, the Roland sound canvas friggin sounds like amazing.
Scott: It's like this unbelievable synthesizer.
Scott: It's pretty sweet.
Rym: So when I installed it, suddenly I heard the Star Wars theme in TIE Fighter.
Rym: In AWE 32.
Scott: Oh, and you had never heard sound before.
Rym: I'd heard it before, but it was on this shit MIDI card.
Rym: So the samples were ass.
Rym: The AWE 32 had really good samples built into it, and it sounded to my young ear like the best music I'd ever heard come out of a computer.
Rym: Yeah, because that was before MP3s.
Rym: So in the meta moment, you realize, guys, that we're going to be at PAX Prime and PAX Dev.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Rym: Yeah, PAX Prime, Friday, 3.30 p.m.
Rym: in the Wolfman Theater, short subjects in gaming.
Rym: One of the panel, one of the many panels within that that we're doing is called On the Ethics of Mind Control.
Rym: And we're basically going to have the discussion that Scott and I almost had just now.
Rym: And at PAX Dev, if any of you were going, Scott, myself, Luke Crane, Jared Sorenson, Avery Alex and Conrad Kraling will be doing Academia versus Reality, Psychology Game Theory in Games in the Grand 2 Ballroom, Wednesday, 2.30 p.m All right.
Rym: Asha, son, it's on big time.
Rym: Magfest is a ways out, but we'll be there.
Rym: I'll be there.
Scott: Other meta, I just want to say, you know, we I started this GeekNights newsletter and I've actually been mailing it about once every two weeks.
Scott: So and in that newsletter, I actually put some moderate amount of work into rewriting it every time.
Scott: I don't know if anyone's actually reading it, but I can sort of see numbers.
Scott: So subscriptions that people keep subscribing to it.
Scott: And there are people who are reading it and people who are clicking on the links in it.
Rym: Remember, there is a unique content exclusive.
Scott: There is a small amount of exclusive content in this newsletter.
Rym: There's a newsletter thing of the day that you'll never get on the regular website.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And there is also a newsletter fan art.
Scott: So if you want to submit fan art, you want to submit questions for us to answer in the newsletter, you know, stuff like that.
Scott: We're just trying to increase our listener engagement.
Scott: So newsletter is not a bad place to do that.
Scott: Why not subscribe or whatever?
Scott: And then if it sucks, unsubscribe, but at least tell us so that we know how to make it better or whatever.
Rym: OK, so tournaments, obviously the real.
Scott: what is a tournament?
Rym: You want to look up the dictionary definition?
Rym: Because, I mean, a tournament is a thing at a convention that takes way too much time.
Rym: I never do it, even though I know I could win some of these things.
Scott: Well, I mean, to me, what a tournament is, is you want to?
Scott: you want to determine somehow who is the best at a at a particular thing.
Rym: From a limited field of contenders.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And simultaneously, I think, equally important to most tournaments is to provide an entertaining spectacle for the people who are sometimes.
Scott: Yes, that's what I'm saying for me.
Rym: Yeah, that is an equally important thing.
Scott: I think the purpose of a tournament is that you have some sort of competition and you want to determine who's the best.
Scott: So let's say you wanted to have, you know, a race, you know.
Scott: So, for example, you know, you could say, OK, everyone ready, set, go.
Scott: And then you have one race and whoever gets to the end wins.
Scott: Now, for just a race, that probably is the best way to do it.
Scott: That might work.
Scott: But the problem is, is what if the competition is such that only a small number of people can participate or you can't really figure out who's the best in the world with only one iteration of the contest.
Scott: So who's the best at Puerto Rico?
Scott: Well, we got five guys playing.
Scott: A guy wins.
Scott: Is he the best in the world?
Scott: No, only five people played.
Scott: Well, 100 people can't play one game of Puerto Rico.
Scott: Of course not.
Scott: That's why you need.
Scott: A tournament, you play multiple iterations of the thing in some structure.
Scott: that will determine a grand champion of the thing.
Scott: And that is what a tournament is for.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: According to Wikipedia, a tournament is a competition involving a relatively large number of competitors all participating in a sport or game.
Rym: More specifically, the term may be used in either of two overlapping anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So the reason we're talking about this, which you should know unless you live under a rock, is that teams in the Olympics were disqualified for trying to win the medal.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That is pretty much the most succinct way I can put it.
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: So they're playing badminton, right?
Scott: Which is actually like bad.
Rym: It's a super fun sport.
Scott: I'm a big fan.
Scott: So the way the tournament was structured was it was a round robin tournament, which means you actually was more like the World Cup where you play in a group.
Scott: So the group like four teams together and those four teams will each play each other.
Scott: And the two, you know, you win or lose against the other three teams in your group.
Scott: So you play three matches, basically.
Scott: And if you win more than the other teams in the group, the top two teams in each group move on and the bottom two teams in each group don't move on.
Scott: So basically you cut the field in half.
Scott: Everyone plays three games.
Scott: Now, this is sort of a good format because, you know, it's like your first game is flukey.
Scott: It gives you some chances to win, even though you lost a game or two.
Scott: If you are actually better, it can also depending on.
Rym: I mean, there's different algorithms for sorting around robin tournaments or deciding who plays who and when.
Rym: You can have round robins where you play multiple games against people.
Rym: You can have round robins where you don't actually play against every person if they're very large.
Scott: So it allows you to have a very large field of competitors without having to, you know, really and filter them down quickly down to, you know, so you can get a single elimination tournament afterwards.
Scott: So it's not.
Scott: it's not really bad structure at all.
Rym: Now, the problem lied in that the round robin format format for the Olympics for Bedman was basically to to decide who qualifies for the single elimination real tournament.
Rym: And as a result, because of the way it shook down, as you know, in a single elimination tournament, having a higher or lower seed determines who you play.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And in single elimination, that means, you know, round one.
Rym: Me and Scott play.
Rym: whoever loses is out of the tournament.
Rym: So we Scott and I way back, you know, we ran an outlaw tournament like Atari twenty six hundred in our apartment and we did a single elimination tournament.
Rym: Now, had Scott and I played against each other in the first round, that would have been BS because we're we were basically the two best players.
Rym: Right.
Rym: But one of the best players would have been eliminated immediately.
Scott: So it would have looked as if I sucked because I lost in the first round.
Scott: But in reality, I was the second or first best player.
Scott: You just don't realize that because I played against the other best player in round one.
Scott: So the tournament results.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I would have won the silver medal if the seating would have been different.
Scott: But instead I win dick and bupkis because I played against the gold medal guy in the first match instead of in the finals.
Scott: And that's why you have seating in a in a single elimination tournament so that the final rankings are accurate.
Scott: So, you know, imagine if you played a single elimination tournament, you lost in the first round.
Scott: But you could, you know, if you played against the silver medal guy, you would have destroyed him because you're way better than him.
Scott: Well, that's just wrong.
Scott: So there's seating going on after you play in these group matches.
Scott: They arrange everyone in the single elimination tournament, according to seeds.
Scott: Now they're the best guy plays the worst guy and so forth.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Same way the NCAA basketball.
Rym: Part of the reason you might do this, forget the math of it or like, you know, tournament theory.
Rym: You guys realize tournament theory is a for real, like serious field of stuff.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But one reason you would do this is basically to reward people who in the qualifications of a tournament, for example, did exceptionally well by giving them easier matches or even buys.
Scott: So if you don't have to play in the first year, you did really well during the regular season of football.
Scott: So now in the playoffs, which are a tournament, you get to skip the first round and you get home field advantage.
Scott: And, you know, this means that you're more likely to go.
Scott: It's going to be easier for you to go farther in the tournament, but the best team is still going to win.
Scott: And if you look at, you know, the playoffs, it's still it's analogous to like in Formula One.
Rym: You have the qualifying lab and then, you know, pole position.
Rym: Everything is determined by that.
Rym: If you spend more effort in that, you've kind of spent resources of your car to get ahead.
Rym: So you're rewarded for that.
Rym: It makes sure that players, even in, you know, pre tournament play or pre like final round play, have an incentive to try really hard to make the game entertaining and to do well, where if there wasn't a reward for doing better in the regular season, once you're qualified, there's literally no reason to even show up.
Scott: What it is, is you want to have a single elimination style of tournament because it's pretty much like everyone.
Scott: you play, you beat someone.
Scott: That means you're better than them.
Scott: You play against someone else who beat someone.
Scott: And in the end, the winner is the best in a single elimination tournament, right?
Scott: Pretty much.
Scott: But the single elimination tournament has a flaw in that there is a lot of room for flukeiness.
Scott: What if I'm the best, but in one fluke match, there was wind because it was golf or something.
Scott: And I lost because of that.
Rym: There's a reason the Stanley Cup is seven games.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You want to remove flukeiness so you can determine more accurately the true champion.
Scott: And that's why prior to the single elimination tournament, you have this multi round thing to remove elements of luck and chance and, you know, to to really know rigorously that a gold medal winner is the winner.
Scott: So that's, you know, that's why you combine things like, you know, you have a qualifying to test rigorously who is the best.
Rym: Now, again, we're still assuming that the primary goal of a tournament is to figure out who is, in fact, the best right now.
Rym: Obviously, you can try to game the structure of a tournament, much like if you look at voting.
Scott: Yeah, the tournament is a game.
Scott: The games themselves are a game within the larger game.
Scott: The tournament is the game you want to win.
Rym: I'm saying look at like first pass the post versus run off all these different ways of voting.
Rym: You have the situation where you might want to act in a way that is conducive to winning this particular tournament.
Rym: I did this myself in high school.
Rym: I was in Quizball.
Rym: Our school was pretty renowned.
Rym: We had good people and we would often lose a match on purpose to get our own utility, which might be.
Rym: we know who we'd be up against if we were seeded at X. So maybe we would lose the game to make sure our seed was different to play someone else in the first round of the next tournament.
Scott: There are also other situations like, you know, who's the best?
Scott: rock, paper, scissors?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, you know, if you're rock, you're going to want to play scissors in round one so you can make it to round two.
Scott: Now I'm playing against, you know, I don't know, would I just make it up other guys?
Scott: It's rock.
Scott: I'm playing against peace.
Scott: So rocks plant rocks playing against wood.
Scott: Rock is already won enough matches because he's fucking rock, right?
Scott: He's already going to be in the tournament.
Scott: If he loses to wood, he gets to play scissors in round one.
Scott: If he beats wood, which he might be able to do, he's going to play against paper in round one.
Rym: Forget that.
Rym: Look at personal stuff.
Rym: You know, in board games, we talk about how one of the worst things that can happen is when someone who cannot win the game has the power to determine the winner of the game.
Rym: It's generally a sign of poor game design.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: And in tournaments, it's the same way.
Rym: If you have a you could have a situation where I'm still playing around, I'm not eliminated from the tournament.
Rym: I still have to play around, but I cannot qualify for the next round.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So like we're doing the round robin thing.
Scott: I've lost two matches, but I have to play a third match in my group.
Rym: But now I'm playing against.
Scott: it's impossible for me to move on to the real tournament.
Scott: But I'm playing against this guy, you know, it's like, well, I can do some dick things to really screw this guy over or I could lose on purpose to him to make sure he gets into the qualifier instead of.
Scott: maybe the other guy is a neighboring country that I'm friendly with.
Scott: And if he wins, my rival is now not going to be in the tournament, you know, where as if I had played to win, maybe I could have beaten this guy because he's the scissors to my rock.
Scott: And then my rival would have also entered the tournament, though I would not have.
Rym: So what happened in the Olympics?
Rym: Basically, there were teams where in the round robin, very, very good teams.
Rym: They were in a situation where both teams had no more reason to play and actually, in fact, had a vested interest in losing.
Rym: Yes, even though you've seen three stooges is where two people are trying to throw a boxing match at the same time.
Rym: Not fun to watch.
Scott: Oh, so this caused big problems.
Scott: Number one, there is a rule in the books that they have, which is sort of a B.S.
Scott: rule, but it is a rule.
Rym: It's the shadows over Camelot rule.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That says you have to try to win every match.
Scott: So they broke that rule and were disqualified.
Scott: So I would argue that's all there is to it.
Scott: I would argue that that rule, because it very heavily rule says you had to try to win the match.
Scott: It did not say you had to win the tournament.
Rym: What I'm saying is that that rule is broken in the sense that it relies upon intense.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So then the skill becomes, can I throw the match without it appearing that I'm doing so?
Rym: What right does the referee have to say you are trying to throw the match?
Scott: But in this case, just sucking.
Scott: in this case, it is two people trying to throw the boxing match.
Scott: There was no question that they were trying to throw the match at all.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: You know, now this situation is.
Rym: there have been soccer games that came down to two teams trying to score into their own nets.
Scott: There have.
Scott: I've seen them.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So this happens in a lot of sports, and every time it is because of poor game design, if there is ever a situation where a player
Scott: who cannot
Rym: win the game can decide who does win the game
Scott: or somebody who could win is trying to lose a part of a tournament on purpose to gain an advantage.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They are not putting forth the full effort, as you know, you would intend.
Scott: That is because the game is broken.
Scott: The blame lies with the game.
Scott: Not the player.
Rym: The people who wrote the rules for this tournament in the Olympics are fucked up.
Rym: They would they they Hunger Games did.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it caused them a lot of problems because now you have people who bought tickets to watch this and now they're watching two teams trying to lose the second part.
Rym: We care in the Olympics nominally about who is the best at something in the world, but we also care about whether or not it is entertaining to watch.
Rym: And if we just care about who is best, the rules of this game basically said that one of the skills of being best is being able to lose on purpose while appearing that you're not doing so.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: So thus, it's not fun to watch those matches.
Rym: I think the punishment against these players is ridiculous.
Rym: I think whoever.
Scott: Well, I mean, I think it's it's.
Scott: you can't really argue with it too much because they did have the bullshit rule of you must try to win the match, but they didn't even try to look like they were trying to win the match.
Rym: True.
Rym: But at the same time, I feel like that rule is that's like if we play a game in Puerto Rico and I'm going to win and you can't win, but there's a way for you to guarantee that.
Scott: But there's no rule in Puerto Rico that says you must at all times attempt to get as many victory points as you can.
Scott: And I choose like craftsmen, even though I've got a better example.
Rym: Look at power grid.
Rym: Very often players will fuck up or pull back on purpose, use the rubber band.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Or look at look at the stadium bicycle racing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, they were all.
Scott: they were.
Rym: people stop or go slow on purpose to start from behind.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The fact is, anytime suddenly that something like that happens, it means that whoever designed the game made a mistake.
Rym: The game is poorly designed.
Rym: Don't patch it.
Rym: Any time you have a soft rule, like you can kind of say what kind of cards you got in your hand or the player has to try their best.
Rym: That's bullshit.
Scott: So so, yeah, the tournament was broken, even though there's nothing fucked up.
Scott: So let's talk about, you know, different kinds of tournaments and their pros and cons.
Rym: I am a big fan when I am in tournaments of double elimination.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Even though it's a giant pain in the ass to organize.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's the most fun.
Rym: It reduces flukeiness to a good degree.
Rym: And I just really like brackets.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The more you try to reduce flukeiness, you're going to run into, you know, problems of people trying to lose on purpose, you know, to get seating.
Scott: So, you know, the double elimination allows you to screw up one time.
Rym: You can eliminate the problem of people trying to lose on purpose by one, making sure that it is pretty much always to the player's advantage to have a better seed and two, by setting up to where.
Rym: if there could be a situation where a player would be playing against someone who wanted to lose, that that match does not happen and there's a buy in the problem with advantage of better seed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is that the the rock, paper, scissors problem, right?
Scott: It's like, well, theoretically, any tournament have that problem.
Scott: Well, for example, Street Fighter might have that problem, right?
Scott: Where, OK, if I try hard to get the highest seed possible, they're going to put me against a guy who's worse.
Scott: Oh, but that guy plays this character in this style, which is really bad for me, even though everyone else is pretty good at beating it.
Scott: But I'm way better than that guy at the same time when I'm going to get seated against him.
Scott: If I lose, I'll get seated against a guy who's a little better than him, but plays with a style and a character that I'm really good against.
Rym: So I don't know two ways around that, because even while people try to use logic like that, one, a lot of times the skills aren't nearly I guess they're more fungible than you'd expect.
Rym: Players can play different characters.
Rym: It's like the sideboard and magic tournaments.
Rym: Magic tournaments, by the way, have a fucked up magic.
Scott: Tournaments are really fucked up there and they don't even care.
Rym: They're just like whatever the incentivization of magic, of like sanctioned magic tournaments.
Rym: A game theorist would shoot himself if he read.
Scott: Let's talk about this.
Scott: The reason magic tournaments are designed the way they are.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I don't know too many details, but basically what they read, like four articles on this reason.
Scott: OK, one of the things that they optimize for, which is pretty interesting, is, you know, you got a poker tournaments have sort of a similar thing, kind of which is the player.
Scott: Right.
Scott: A single elimination tournament.
Scott: You enter, you lose immediately.
Scott: You're out.
Scott: It's like, well, that sucks.
Scott: They're trying to give the player more enjoyment, even if they lose, so that you can play more games.
Rym: You can have more fun as the people who play magic tend to go to a magic event and only play magic the whole time.
Scott: So like I went to a magic tournament once and I did single elimination.
Scott: I entered.
Scott: I got my ass kicked and then I sat around and did nothing till another tournament started that I could actually cry in a magic tournament once.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Because I played with a 400 card deck and I beat him anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So but it's like if you were to so they make a magic tournament to where you play a bunch of games no matter what.
Scott: So you're not.
Scott: you enter and you have a lot of fun playing a lot of magic, even if you keep getting your ass kicked.
Scott: And so they want to optimize for that to make more people have fun at the tournaments, keep coming, keep paying to play.
Scott: It's a pay to entry.
Scott: You want to get your money's worth, play a lot of games.
Scott: But the result is the badminton problem times a million.
Rym: Now, most people are familiar with single elimination because any convention, any nerdy thing you go to.
Rym: Speaking of someone who helps run big conventions, it's a pain in the ass to run a tournament and they take forever.
Rym: Single elimination is really the only format that is even reasonably feasible to run unlimited resources.
Scott: You know what my favorite kind of tournament is the everyone come up right and gets X number of tries at a thing and then you get something with a score.
Rym: Those are boring because the kinds of tournaments I like are direct competition tournaments.
Scott: I do like direct competition, but, you know, it's like that tournament, though, works the best mechanically, even though it's not entertaining, you know, to really watch or be in it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But like imagine if everyone played Dig Dug, you get three games, three game overs.
Scott: Your highest score counts.
Scott: That removes flukiness.
Scott: And we just post the scores highest score at the end of the day as the winner.
Rym: But much more everyone can, you know, it's much more fun is two player Dig Dug players eliminated.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that's much more entertaining to everyone involved, of course.
Scott: But if you want to determine who's the best Dig Dug, that's a great format.
Scott: It doesn't take a lot of time.
Scott: It doesn't have any, you know, bullshit trying to lose.
Scott: You just try to get the fucking highest score you can each time.
Rym: The thing is, in well-designed tournaments, very rarely is there actually a real incentive to lose it only when they are poorly designed as this come into play.
Rym: This badminton tournament could have been fairly easily reworked to where no one would ever have actually wanted to lose a round match.
Scott: But I mean, there's all these factors, right?
Scott: Entertainment for spectator, entertainment for player, you know, does it actually determine the true winner?
Scott: There are tournaments you could set up where they're so flawed that you might win the tournament, but might not actually be the best player there because the tournament was broken.
Scott: Making sure no one tries to lose all these different things.
Scott: You can't have all of them.
Scott: You need to choose some of them above others, right?
Scott: There is no tournament structure I've ever seen that allows for all of those things to be maximized to perfection.
Scott: It does not exist.
Scott: There's probably some mathematical law that it can't exist.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know if it was this year or not, but apparently it won Olympics.
Rym: The Japanese women's soccer team played a game to a draw on purpose because it meant that in the tournament season, they wouldn't have to travel far to the next round.
Scott: Oh, see, more factors coming into play.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Oh, I found a whole list of Olympic things that are almost identical to what the badminton players did.
Rym: that was totally OK.
Rym: Like in cycling with like getting into a peloton and slowing it down on purpose to let your teammate get ahead, stuff like that.
Rym: So really what it comes down to is if you are making a tournament from a game theorist's perspective to determine the best player, there's math.
Rym: Use the math and come up with the best tournament.
Rym: If you're making a tournament in the real world, use the tournament that causes the most entertainment to happen for all involved.
Scott: I thought of another example, right?
Scott: Let's say it's a. you're having a tournament of a sport where you could actually become exhausted.
Scott: You might want to get a seed to where you're going to play your next game later in the day to have more resting time, whereas you might see it against something you might if you win.
Rym: You know how Quiz Bowl got around?
Scott: If you win, you might see it against someone who's really bad and you're guaranteed to beat them, maybe, but you're going to have to play them pretty much right now.
Rym: Quiz Bowl got around that by not telling you when the matches would be or where they would be.
Scott: concealing, concealing information from the players is very good, because as soon as it's uncertain, your decision is arbitrary.
Rym: But I don't feel we could do a whole separate show, I think, on specifically tournaments and conventions.
Scott: Well, I mean, as I realize we can do tournaments and conventions.
Rym: So I played in my entire life.
Rym: I played in a magic tournament.
Rym: I played in a Dungeons and Dragons tournament.
Rym: Yeah, Michicon, like one of those hardcore like points from a settlement tournament.
Rym: I played in the in a like sanctioned Settlers tournament.
Rym: And until recently, I hadn't really played in any other tournaments.
Rym: because when I go to a con, a tournament like I'll look at a tournament like Puerto Rico tournament, I'll be like, I guarantee I could win that show.
Scott: I could come close.
Scott: Guaranteed.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You know, defense is playing.
Rym: Yeah, I remember there's the guy's got Carcassonne tournament.
Scott: Yeah, you can win that.
Scott: But I mean, remember, there's that guy at the PAX tournaments who has like the frickin armor of medals because he just frickin plays all of them and wins everything to me.
Rym: But then I look and I'm like, all right.
Rym: Dominion Tournament, four and a half hours.
Rym: And then I look in that four and a half hours.
Rym: I can go get a beer and a steak, see a panel, play like two board games or different board games, not the same one times and be in a tournament that takes forever.
Scott: And the thing is, you're not going to necessarily when you join a tournament, you're not necessarily going to be playing at the entire time, but you sort of have to hang around for when your next matches or maybe they'll tell you the time and you to come back.
Scott: And basically you always fall behind that you're leaving and coming back constantly to play a game, play a game, leave, you know, you're playing the same game over and over.
Scott: And it's kind of cool to try to win the tournament, especially if there's good prizes for the variety of the experience, not for the one tournament that takes half my day.
Scott: Yeah, it's much better for these sorts of tournaments, you know, to be standalone.
Scott: If there's a tournament in packs, it's like, well, I'm not going to do that when I get packs.
Scott: But if there's just a Dominion tournament in New York City, oh, my God, that's all it is.
Scott: It's like, of course, I'm going to show up.
Scott: It's not like it's competing with anything, especially if it's in the winter or something.
Rym: So crewmate row let us in on the secret, because, you know, packs one of the things they do, if you win a tournament, you get a medal, you get this huge, solid medal.
Scott: Yeah, I don't want it.
Scott: It's not actually that huge, but I have ones and you don't.
Scott: So, yeah, it's fucking gigantic.
Rym: So what she told us was to play pick a tournament that won't take long on like Sunday morning.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: When no one will show up, especially, you know, one of those tournaments for a less popular game where not too many people are going to enter.
Scott: So they'll only be like maybe one or two rounds.
Rym: So Scott and I show up for this zero tournament.
Rym: We're like, all right, that's a short game, too.
Scott: It's not a game that takes a long time.
Rym: We're like, look, no one will show up.
Rym: It's going to be a 50/50 chance.
Rym: one of us is getting that medal and then we can say we want a medal.
Rym: Then we show up and there were a bunch of people that were actually seven people total, which is the maximum for one game of zero.
Scott: So it actually we only had to play in the one zero and the company that publishes it was there.
Rym: And they were like, look, we're using some rules that make the game not 100 percent random.
Rym: They were really good rules.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And we played a few games and it's like you got.
Scott: it was sort of like an F1 ish system where, you know, the way F1 works is you have a grand prix and you win the grand prix, which you always want to do, because why wouldn't you want to win the grand prix?
Scott: No one tries to lose.
Scott: If you come in first place, you get 10 points.
Scott: If you come in second place, you get seven points.
Scott: Whatever the points are going down to like eventually, I think, like eighth place gets one point and less than eighth place is zero points.
Scott: And then you add up the points you get from all the different races.
Scott: Never has the most points at the end of all the races wins.
Scott: So it was a similar system like that.
Scott: You know, a first place gets you this many points.
Scott: So and that makes you always want to win everything.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So it went really well.
Rym: Now, Scott and I, you know, often talk about how bad ass we are at board games and we're very kind of full of ourselves and people who go to Nerd NYC often look at us like, uh, but then we win.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So they can't really say much.
Rym: So we show up to this thing.
Rym: Scott wins the first round, like ridiculously.
Rym: I win the next round ridiculously.
Rym: We pretty much tie in the third round and it was a perfect draw between me and Scott.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So in sudden death, Me and Rym had a tiebreaker and I won.
Rym: The tiebreaker came down to one card.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I won.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Scott won one by the flaw.
Scott: And this this see this kind of tournament, the F1 style is great because number one, great entertainment for the participant.
Scott: You get to play a lot because you can just keep playing to add up more points.
Scott: You know, suddenly halfway through the the games, the other the guy in first could start losing and you could start winning and you can come back.
Scott: It's also great for the spectator because every match is most of them are really interesting.
Scott: The problem it has is that problem of losing guy can screw things up for winning guy.
Scott: You could be like, you know, for example, maybe the last ground free of the season doesn't matter because the guy already has so many points, even if he disqualifies himself.
Scott: And there's a great place.
Scott: guy wins.
Scott: He still wins the holes.
Rym: There is a great video from some race.
Rym: It was on College Humor a while ago.
Rym: It was something like it wasn't ground free.
Rym: It was like some minor circuit racing.
Rym: Like and basically a guy got passed and he wasn't going to win.
Rym: So he cut across the grass and rammed his rival.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: You know, let's say Rym is in first place and he's going to win the championship as well as the Grand Prix.
Scott: But if he comes in second place or less, he will not win the championship.
Scott: So, you know, he's coming up to to pass me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I'm lapped.
Scott: I'm losing.
Scott: I'm so many points away.
Scott: Even if I won the race and everyone else crashed, I would not win the championship going backwards.
Scott: So, yeah, I'll just freaking get in front of Rym and not let him pass me until the second place guy can catch up to him or crash into Rym or do whatever I can to make Rym not first place.
Scott: And then I someone who is lost can have an influence, has no chance of winning, can have a huge influence on who wins the championship, you know, because I can throw a monkey wrench in there because I'm still participating, even though my chances of winning the whole thing, well-designed
Rym: games and well-designed tournaments minimize the possibility.
Scott: You know what they do in F1.
Scott: Actually, F1 has a very clever in-game solution, the blue flag, which is you're getting lapped like the first place guy comes around you.
Scott: They wave the blue flag at you.
Scott: You have to let him go or else you're fucked.
Scott: So that's not the worst solution in the world.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like in Suro, it could have been a problem because people who aren't winning around could trivially just attack and kill someone who's doing well.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And I think the only reason that didn't happen was that basically Scott and I were trash talking each other the entire time to such an epic degree that everyone else was kind of just sitting back watching us.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You know, that's another thing.
Scott: is you have to consider the game itself, right, is not, you know, is for different, even though you have the same exact tournament structure, which will have the same flaws.
Scott: no matter what the game is, certain games like it might be impossible to try to lose on purpose.
Scott: You know, it's like there's no way in this game for me to lose on purpose or there is no way in this game for me to attack another player.
Scott: I can't bring anyone down.
Scott: So even though if I could do that, it would mess the tournament up.
Scott: There's no way in game to do it.
Scott: So it doesn't matter.
Scott: And you want to match up the tournament to the kind of game it is to take advantages of those characteristics, you know, to match them up with the flaws of the tournament so you can get a better result.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Anything else to say about the tournament?
Rym: Not really.
Rym: Yeah, I should get the video.
Rym: I have all the video from that outlaw tournament, which, as I recall, I won.
Scott: OK, but yeah, tournaments are awesome.
Scott: They're a game in and of themselves.
Rym: Sheriff in town.
Scott: Yeah, I suggest you, you know, try to experiment with different kinds of tournaments, you know, or just study tournament theory and read a book.
Scott: And yeah, there are.
Scott: But I mean, there are lots of weird ones out there.
Scott: It's like find a short game to play with your friends, like spot it or even rock, paper, scissors or tic tac toe or something that tic tac toe and, you know, play a tournament with your friends and, you know, make the game the tournament and not the game itself.
Scott: And you could actually have quite a bit of fun.
Scott: And when you win the whole thing, you feel way more like a champion than if you just win one game or like, for example, but you know what?
Rym: My favorite actual form of tournament is, even though we don't really do anything with it, challenges.
Rym: I challenge you for the title.
Rym: I challenge you for the rank per wrestling time.
Rym: Yeah, we should do that with board games.
Scott: Someone holds on to the championship.
Scott: They're the champion.
Scott: Why don't we determine some by the first game and then you have to beat the champion to take the belt away from the champion.
Rym: I feel like we should do that in our own group just for like Tigger's and Euphrates.
Scott: The best thing about that method is that you don't need any seating because the basically just have two people playing.
Scott: whoever wins is the champion.
Scott: And then if you could beat the champion, now you're the new champion.
Rym: The problem is, is that the person in the order of multiple challenges or that too often do I just challenge Scott every day until he gets pissed off and rises just like that.
Scott: The chair, whoever is the current champion, ends up getting worn out and might lose to someone who challenges later.
Scott: Like I just got the championship.
Scott: You challenge.
Rym: That's why you make a laddered structure of challenges where you can't challenge Mike Tyson in round one of punch out.
Rym: You get to beat all these other MOOCs first.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Like in boxing, it'll be like, OK, you want to challenge the champ, right?
Scott: Well, you actually have to win this other tournament.
Scott: And by winning that other tournament against a bunch of MOOCs, you earn the prize in that tournament is the right to challenge the champ.
Scott: So it's like whoever wins this whole thing, the best of these guys with a regular single elimination tournament, then gets to play the champ to be the champ.
Scott: That is good to be the champ because the champ doesn't have to play in the tournament.
Scott: So he's super not tired.
Scott: And now the reverse problem of dude just fought like six fights in a tournament.
Scott: Now he's going to fight the champ.
Scott: It's like, yeah, champs got a big advantage.
Rym: It's a nice that I'm in the sheriff.
Scott: Sheriff of what?
Scott: Sheriff of Foxton?
Rym: A sheriff.
Rym: Sheriff of nothing.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.