Rym: It's Wednesday January 18th 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: I can't believe we never did a show on Yotsuba, so Let's do this.
Rym: I Think I'm gonna run Run.
Rym: what I mean carousel is obviously a scam.
Rym: so fuck that.
Scott: that kind of running that kind of running.
Scott: Yep Tell me how it goes.
Scott: send me an email from beyond you mean from sanctuary Yeah, and then four months from now or so I will have a better strategy, and I will do a lot.
Scott: I won't make the same mistakes.
Scott: You made.
Rym: it amazes me that when I was a little kid like I remember watching Logan's run and not Like.
Rym: I took it completely seriously like kids take everything.
Scott: I took it seriously that I like shit like that.
Scott: You know you know sort of eerie and quiet and long and a lot sort of like.
Rym: you know get that atmosphere of ooh It's all weird sci-fi and this crazy shit out there, but I mean like I would take like project a co seriously At that same time in my life.
Scott: Yeah, maybe but I remember thankfully seriously.
Rym: I remember Wanting to know what the deal was with Logan's run, but being too young to like really grasp it.
Rym: So I watched it again in like the last five or six years And it's a pretty shit movie.
Rym: I like it all things considered.
Scott: I still like it.
Rym: the thing is movies like that.
Scott: I'm not saying it's a great epic film of all greatness But I like a lot of the aspects.
Rym: it just has the problem that a lot of those kinds of movies have where it's really Long, but independently the majority of the scenes don't actually move the plot in any meaningful way.
Rym: well Yeah, and they really take a lot of like.
Rym: it's like.
Rym: it's like bad cinema 101 like hey Let's take a gigantic detour to explore this part of the world.
Rym: no one cares about That's.
Rym: I like zoom in on the doctor getting cut up because you all wanted to see that.
Rym: yep But yeah, I'm gonna run because Yeah, my otaku expiration date.
Scott: I don't understand right.
Scott: It's like You can carousel or you can run.
Scott: what happens?
Scott: if you run?
Scott: they shoot you.
Scott: Well, you're dying either way, so you might as least have a chance.
Rym: Scott you forget that carousel promises renewal.
Rym: if you make it if you survive you are renewed.
Rym: But if you run just like how in the running man if you get away you get that money And you're set for life.
Scott: No one gets away in the running.
Rym: Those two people got away Arnold.
Rym: That's the only guy Arnold I really want to.
Rym: I don't have the time or the energy to do it now But after we watch commando over the front row crew epic New Year's party I and Conan I Kind of want to take every Arnold movie and mash him up into another movie.
Scott: a lot of people have done that already.
Rym: I have not seen even one person who made a feature-length movie.
Rym: That was nothing more than mashups of scenes from all.
Rym: this is internet.
Scott: it exists.
Rym: I'm doubtful After the show.
Scott: so today, I went.
Scott: there was a SOPA.
Scott: I mean sure.
Scott: I'm sure everyone saw SOPA blackout protests on the Internet's.
Scott: I went to the physical SOPA protests near the senator's office in 49th and 3rd, which I'm on 49th and 7th.
Scott: So I just had to walk.
Rym: I would have gone however one all the people protesting SOPA have jobs.
Scott: well Yes, I just went.
Scott: I didn't want to go there to protest.
Scott: I just want to go there to see how it was going and There are a few things going on there.
Scott: number one I buy.
Scott: that's an area I bike past on the way to work often so I knew the area They basically had.
Scott: there's an area with a wide sidewalk.
Scott: they chopped half of it off and they took away the.
Scott: you know the show the The parking spots in the street and that was the.
Scott: and they fenced it off with little metal brackets that the cops use.
Scott: The cops are standing around lazily going yep.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yep, because all the protesters are just sort of quiet holding up Their signs because they're just normal people.
Scott: They're not a crazy hippies.
Scott: And They had was most interesting is you know, it's filled in like there were hundreds of people there packing into that thing.
Scott: I was quite impressed.
Rym: Yeah, well, you know the moral.
Rym: don't fuck with the internet.
Scott: a lot of people taking photos and such but the cops pretty much what?
Scott: The cops did is they were like you either got to go in the fence or move along.
Scott: You're not allowed to.
Scott: they didn't let people loiter outside the fence, you know.
Scott: So I was like we loitered for about 10 minutes outside the fence took some pictures walked around on my flicker and Then left and got lunch.
Scott: because not going in the fence because that means you can't get out of the fence easily and what if you?
Scott: Had to pee.
Scott: Yeah, and I have to go back to work and it's cold and I want to eat lunch.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like the internet protest is the real force, right?
Scott: But one thing was at the very.
Scott: it was basically sort of this long rectangle right at the very end.
Scott: They had they had some guest speakers and and you know, whatever They had a microphone and a sound system and they got on the news crews to show up and I was like, whoa They got a sound system.
Scott: That's impressive.
Scott: So it's telling but I was looking at the sound system.
Scott: It's like two speakers on tripods and a microphone and you know a box of equipment and I'm like There's no way anyone is gonna hear that.
Scott: as soon as a truck comes by You're not gonna hear shit.
Scott: and the traffic was relatively heavy.
Scott: You know a constant like.
Scott: you couldn't take a picture of it from across the street because there are so many cars.
Scott: Yeah, and When they actually started talking you could fucking hear it was loud and clear.
Scott: I was like, whoa, you know it's impressive.
Rym: I've looked into those systems because there was a time when we would go to conventions that did not necessarily provide.
Scott: So this is like.
Scott: this was so good like New York City Street in the air with cars and trucks driving by Only two speakers and you could hear it loud and clear like one or two blocks away.
Scott: That is a good system set up.
Rym: Well interesting how this one-time kind of ad hoc not planned that far in advance protest was able to be so well organized.
Scott: Well, they were like, you know, it was a meetup and it was the New York Tech meetup Which I don't want to talk about them now.
Scott: Specific message and like the meetup people were there wearing little meetup aprons because they were so proud that meetup was used to get it Together and all kinds of.
Rym: yeah I used to be a member of meetup and then I Dropped because I got all these kind of pointless.
Scott: Well, pretty much any time you join a meetup they start emailing you see it to unsubscribe from each and every meetup and it's you Whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I sort of managed it by unsubscribing from everything.
Scott: But yeah, I was impressed that that many people actually showed up.
Scott: and you know If you look right, you know people have these short memories.
Scott: It seems like everyone but us is a short memory.
Scott: It's like we remember when he fought and lost against the DMCA and like that remember the CBD tPA, right?
Scott: And then we fought and won against that and we fought in one against coaca and I think there were a couple others in there Too right.
Scott: and it feels like every year every other year we had to fight off one of these things and won but we barely fought and won and shut down most of these things.
Scott: and Now this one right it's just basically it's like people like oh watch out for a PIPA - or SOPA - it's like What do you mean, you know PIPA is just coaca CBD tPA for it's not right It's nice.
Rym: over one CBD tPA was pretty much the worst one.
Rym: Yeah, luckily We've never.
Rym: that never got revisited because if it did You got nothing on these protests, but the point is is we got you know We're.
Scott: it's going the other way that we're getting angrier and more people every time.
Scott: the next time they try this.
Scott: I got mad.
Scott: the next time they try this shit like a year or two from now You're gonna see if there were a five hundred to a thousand people this time.
Scott: This is gonna be two thousand next time.
Rym: well, look at Next time.
Rym: the opposite talking points now are basically things like oh so Obama and all these people are clearly just you know in the pocket of Silicon Valley and these big corporations.
Scott: That's awesome.
Scott: if they were in the pocket of Silicon Valley I would vote for them because you know what better at least.
Scott: they'll be corrupt on my side as opposed to being corrupt on the other side.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: This is crazy.
Scott: next.
Scott: well coming up soon.
Scott: I don't know exactly when is mega con which is a February sometime in February.
Scott: mega con is in Orlando sort of everything con with comics and anime But it's mostly one of those cons where it's just buy shit, right?
Rym: Yep Never been to it not really planning on going to it.
Scott: There is a comic store.
Scott: it named the name of this comic store is quote a comic shop.
Scott: Not bad Okay, it's www.comic shop.com.
Scott: They're gonna be at mega con.
Scott: probably I imagine they'll have a booth there.
Scott: They are in Winter Park, Florida Which is pretty close to mega con right and they have a flyer that they're going to distribute.
Scott: You know an advertisement on a piece of paper that you know.
Scott: It's usually what you do to advertise your shit rise.
Scott: you give out a piece of paper with an ad on it.
Scott: This ad was 75% paid for by DC Comics Which is why it's covered in DC Comics characters and logos and does not contain any Marvel Comics characters logos on it.
Scott: Okay But it's mostly an ad for this shop and this is what the ad looks like.
Scott: The ad says DC Comics 52 Justice League.
Scott: Robama wants you to buy American.
Scott: and then at the bottom it says trade in any Manga volume number one.
Scott: get any DC new 52 number one for free.
Scott: So if you go to this a comic shop You can take any manga volume you have.
Scott: that's number one trade it in and they'll give you one flimsy ass comic book for free.
Rym: So is this just not an extension of the long-standing?
Rym: Comic shop owners like weird anger and hatred over manga being popular.
Scott: This is created a giant internet flame wars of awesome cars.
Scott: and you know, there's so many aspects, right?
Scott: It's basically there's the aspect of oh these people recognize that manga makes money, but they don't understand it.
Scott: So they're right and they just want to make money off the shit.
Rym: No, they just want to get a bunch of manga for cheap that they can then sell to make money.
Scott: Well that too, you know, there's.
Scott: there's so many aspects of this.
Scott: you can't even you could spend all day going over them.
Scott: But it's just like, you know, wow These comic shops they still don't get.
Scott: they really don't get it and it's like doing something like this.
Scott: It's like just you might as well just taking a giant roll of paper like in the olden days when you'd print a banner on your Apple - with two cakes at the end and Just right.
Scott: We don't get it and hang it right up above your store But at the same time they might get it.
Rym: if you look at this from this like if you assume that they're savvy Like if you try to pretend alright, these guys clearly have an angle and are intelligent.
Rym: What could it be?
Rym: which?
Rym: funnily enough if you take that approach to a stupid person's, you know attempts at getting something they want You'll usually come up with pretty crazy motivations.
Rym: that's the only way to make it sense, but with these people you could argue that they Don't care about.
Rym: the people who read manga and the people have diverse interests.
Rym: and the people who are interested in, you know visual media.
Rym: They're catering to their base and their base is probably if comic shops I've been to in the last few years with the exceptions of cool ones like Bergen Street are to be any indication.
Rym: Their base is a combination of people who buy every spider-man people who buy airsoft guns.
Scott: You buy everything with Wolverine on the cover.
Rym: Yeah, but I think the airsoft guns are actually the majority of the market there.
Scott: Alright, but it's sort of like on the one hand.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: Are you trying to convert manga people to reading DC Comics?
Rym: That's not gonna work.
Scott: Are they gonna really come in and dump all their shitty manga?
Scott: They never want to read again.
Scott: Not likely right.
Scott: number two Maybe there's all the regular comics guys.
Scott: all of them have like a spare of manga volume around that they don't want You know, but it's like we have all the DC 52 number one issues and I wouldn't trade a manga volume for any of them.
Scott: You should trade you if you know.
Scott: if you did trade a manga volume one for a DC 52 trade number one volume That would be a fair trade and then this would be cool and no one would complain.
Rym: I guess what's always fascinated me.
Rym: Is this weird?
Scott: if I had a comic shop, I would do trade any trade For I would do used for used one one-to-one trades because I would sell you stuff Straight up like GameStop did like a used bookstore does and I would say bring in a used book take a used book.
Rym: I guess I've just never understood the like the weird comic shop or a comic book fan like narrow nerd focus anger at A similar thing being popular among a different demographic.
Scott: Yeah I mean why don't you know?
Scott: it's always cool to see like there are comic shops that sort of get like you like Comicopia in Boston.
Scott: It's like they load.
Scott: They got some ladies there that understand the mangas.
Scott: I mean not to say they load up on the mangas and the regular kind a little bit everything.
Rym: not to say that the American Manga industry understood anything and you can see what they did.
Rym: well, Tokyo pop Yeah, okay, but I just it amazes me that this sort of sentiment can still exist in the modern era.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: how do how come?
Scott: no it seems like people who run companies.
Rym: I mean do they think that people like us started reading manga?
Rym: Because like we were bamboozled by some marketing And that they just have to trick us back in to remind us how much we love Green Lantern and all of his bullshit?
Rym: Stop reading things like Green Lantern because I've always kind of hated stuff like that.
Scott: It's just in general across all business in society, right?
Scott: Especially nerd businesses.
Scott: Why is it that people who work for these companies their job 24/7 is to do this thing comics or comic shop right or whatever it is that they're doing movies.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: They never get it.
Scott: None of them.
Scott: There isn't there hardly any of them that get it.
Scott: it's like who only people get it are like the hot city Miku people and Valve right and it's like who else no one else gets it.
Scott: But meanwhile, there's millions of nerds across the world and all of them get it.
Scott: But no one who actually works for a company who has a job of doing it gets it.
Scott: but people do it Just like in their spare time totally get it.
Scott: Yeah, I look like look at the end or so anyone who gets it running.
Rym: look at the enforcers at PAX who run like different Departments and everything.
Rym: It's not like they're spending 40 hours a week planning that and yet go to a professionally run like real convention and It's you know, it's a different venue a different kind of event.
Rym: I'm not gonna say that like the Board of Trade is gonna have an awesome convention with drinking and partying all night But they fail at the simple stuff like chairs showing up in time or speakers or microphones.
Scott: I just don't know why but it's people whose job it is to do something?
Scott: There's almost no.
Scott: you could list on like a few hands Maybe even just one hand the companies that get it right and pretty much every other company gets it wrong.
Scott: But if you go on the internet and just go to forums and stuff, we're just people doing shit for free.
Scott: Everyone gets it right almost always.
Rym: Comics thing there's there - there's a big Venn diagram.
Rym: There's two demographics that are really involved here.
Rym: There's the hardcore American superhero comic nerds not American comics.
Rym: American superhero comics.
Rym: They're the only demographic this ad is aimed at.
Rym: the other demographic is the equal Pretty much identical mirror image of this.
Rym: That is the.
Rym: I am a fan of manga Because I like manga and the things that I perceive manga to be.
Rym: I therefore hate American comics Which I perceive as being nothing but superhero comics.
Rym: Those are the only two demographics involved in this entire internet flame war.
Rym: Anyway, nobody else is involved or cares.
Scott: it's still.
Scott: it's sort of jingoistic and Ignorant.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't reflect good on telling or DC.
Rym: We bought all 52 of the new 52 Research purposes.
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna review them on the show and well we you and we should have done it already.
Scott: They're already coming out with like number sixes.
Rym: I think I gotta tell you I Expected a slog but I went in with an open mind and you know what some of them remember.
Rym: our reviews were pretty good In fact, I liked a lot of them more than Scott did but at the same time It was such a slog to read them all and you know what?
Scott: I was if you buy comics the other day, there are people who buy all.
Scott: think about their people who buy that stack monthly.
Scott: Those are monthly comics every month.
Scott: They get this day.
Rym: I was at Bergen Street comics the other day for the Johnny Wander like book thing, which was packed like Crazy small store, right?
Scott: So even like a hundred people would pack it.
Rym: Yeah, but it was like.
Rym: but yeah Of course, so I was there and there were a bunch of the 52 thing.
Rym: issue four or five was up on the shelf.
Rym: yeah, so I pick a couple up and The few comics I'd liked have devolved into the bullshit.
Rym: That is exactly why I don't read that kind of comic.
Rym: It was all.
Rym: see issue 45 or see issue whatever of this where the blah blah blah disease was blah blah blah See.
Scott: here's the thing right with those that produce.
Scott: editor notes in particular are a topic of great debate Because if you put them in right then it's like well now if I want to know I know where to go.
Scott: I don't have to go like hunt on the internet to figure out what the hell is going on because imagine that note isn't there.
Scott: Something happens.
Scott: You're like what the fuck just happened.
Rym: at the same time A lot element that comes out of nowhere in a narrative that requires this meta External.
Rym: it's like a deus ex machina to explain the story because the storyteller didn't do it elegantly enough.
Rym: Yeah, then there's a more fundamental flaw.
Scott: Well, yeah, that's the thing.
Scott: but it's like if you're gonna cross over like that Should you put the note there or should you not put the note there and just let it go unspoken?
Rym: I don't like to see the notes.
Scott: I You'd rather have there be no no and then you read and a guy says oh and then you know remember that bitch Sharon is I'm gonna do a different way.
Rym: if there is a note I'm annoyed because now it's telling me hey you have to read this other comic series to to know what's going on.
Scott: sometimes you do and sometimes you know like sometimes the relation to that of the comic will be so slight and sometimes Bother even crossing it over.
Scott: but then sometimes the relation will be very strong.
Rym: But if it's strong then you've got to read both or it's not gonna make sense Even if the notes there you have to go read the other one or it still doesn't make any sense.
Scott: Yep, but at least you know which one to read whereas before without the note You don't even know what the fuck.
Rym: so all the note does is warn me.
Rym: Hey, this is one of those comics And if the note isn't there then it's just a plot element out of nowhere Which you know what happens all the time.
Rym: anyway in a lot of these 52 Didn't some of them already get cancelled?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah But anyway, so I picked out, you know I picked these up and I read through them and they they'd all like they'd all gotten way worse and kind of all blended together.
Rym: And I don't want to ever read any more of these except maybe action comics.
Scott: I'm gonna get the trade of action comics number.
Rym: I'll read that when it shows up, but anyway things of the day.
Rym: so Friend cat pointed this out to us and this kind of amazing.
Rym: I'm not really gonna explain much about it You should just watch the video and kind of skip around you'll figure it out pretty pretty quickly.
Rym: But it's a dating game called hot to fool boyfriend.
Scott: Alright, is it one where you're a girl trying to date guys or we're a guy trying to date girls?
Rym: So you're a girl human girl.
Rym: Okay, and no warning bell number one.
Rym: I had to specify human.
Scott: or is it a gay one?
Rym: It's not a pony thing or anything because that's the other thing I assume everyone was I'm sure those.
Scott: those exist all over the I'm sure as well times a billion.
Rym: So, uh, you're a girl human girl.
Rym: you go to a school for pigeons and you Like the bird tweet try to date or not day like the rats of the sidewalk the pigeons Yes, now some of them that.
Rym: basically you've got to see this to believe it, but you know It's all the typical dating game stuff.
Scott: Well, there's that other one with the disabled people, right?
Rym: But then you meet the pigeon and it's not even like a drawing of a pigeon It's not even like a stylist.
Rym: It is just a picture of a pigeon a photograph and It's pretty great.
Rym: Okay, this is this is kind of amazing.
Scott: There's another reason one that's been getting a lot of attention because you date disabled people like a school for disabled people.
Scott: So it's like all these people like girl in a wheelchair girl with a missing leg, you know that kind of stuff.
Rym: This one is pretty awesome though, and you should play it All right.
Scott: So, you know Sometimes you're in a forum on the internets or you're tweeting or something and you need a JPEG and you want to use your courage wolf.
Scott: Or maybe you want to use that little baby who's making the fist, right?
Rym: You know what he's called.
Scott: No, what's he called?
Scott: I have no idea but I like that guy or the Raptor who's scratching his chin or the guy who's like why you know or You know fry with the squinty eyes.
Rym: So I googled baby fist and I can't find anything right anyway.
Scott: And you know, there's a whole bunch of meme generators out there to put you know, your impact font text on Oh, he is called baby success.
Scott: Okay, let me all right.
Scott: So let me try this and you know, you know, you you want to make the JPEG with the impact font But you don't have you're not you don't have Photoshop.
Scott: You're not any good at it You know.
Scott: and it's like you try to find generators for that stuff and none of them are really quite that good.
Scott: Well, here you go m3 m3 Us slash meme.
Scott: you go to this website and it's the simplest generator in the universe.
Scott: It's three text boxes and a button.
Scott: you type into the second text box, right?
Scott: You got to type in the top text in the bottom text for impact font, obviously And then you just type in the name of the generator.
Scott: So what do you say?
Scott: Was it baby success any success?
Scott: So I'll type in baby success and then I'll type in Rym Sucks and I'll click do this thing.
Scott: and here we have it.
Scott: Oh, it said search fail.
Scott: It's not actually called baby success.
Rym: Well, that's what the internet called it in my brief brief.
Scott: The only problem with this is you have to know the name of the thing.
Scott: Like.
Scott: I know that one guy is named why you know, so I type in why you know And then I type in you know Rym why you know.
Scott: good and Then I've generated a while, you know, there it is Rym why you know.
Rym: good That could be useful.
Rym: now doesn't host the image or I have to save a timger.
Scott: Let me try and see.
Scott: it gives you a URL for your image.
Rym: That could be dangerous.
Rym: Like I should make a site like that and then like one year after it goes live all goat.
Scott: see it gives you a URL And then you can use that URL and send it to him girl if you want.
Scott: That's what I would do but the URL format is actually really straightforward.
Scott: So if you look at that URL format, you can just type the URL directly instead of filling out the form, huh?
Rym: So it's dynamic.
Scott: Yeah, it's very dynamic.
Scott: All right, interesting best meme generator I found.
Scott: I'm gonna use a lot.
Rym: very briefly the meta Moment.
Rym: the book club books are not one but two books The Little Prince and Wind, Sand and Stars by Antoine de Salle Jupyteri.
Rym: I finished Wind, Sand and Stars.
Scott: I'm almost done.
Rym: It's uh, it's pretty good.
Scott: It's pretty great.
Scott: I don't pick shit books like Rym.
Rym: We'll do a show on it soon and then I'm gonna pick a book.
Rym: great You're gonna love.
Scott: hopefully the book clubs will be more frequent.
Scott: We were at Magfest.
Rym: we our panel.
Rym: well our lecture beyond Dungeons & Dragons is on the internet.
Rym: The two panels we were on.
Rym: one of them the videos kind of crap.
Rym: So I'm not gonna bother putting it online.
Rym: The other one was me Scott and dr.
Rym: Hazard and it was pretty good.
Rym: So I'm putting that one online.
Scott: All right Anything else.
Scott: The tickets are already sold out.
Scott: Well, I guess the three-day ones are right.
Scott: Yep If you don't have a hotel and take it already, you're fucked.
Scott: We told you to get one the day that came out.
Scott: You failed.
Scott: that's tough.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You don't deserve to go.
Scott: That's about it.
Rym: Pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, I can't believe we never did a show on this.
Scott: It's like we go through and we're like man.
Scott: We haven't done we haven't.
Scott: there isn't anything recent that we've both seen read watched whatever to do a show on and usually There must be something old.
Scott: We know we've all seen or read.
Scott: Yeah that we've done it.
Rym: But then Scott will be like slayers.
Rym: and then I look and I'm like, wow So we reviewed both the slayers movie and the slayers TV show and it's like I can't believe years ago.
Scott: I gamble and there's so many shows.
Scott: It's like anything we come up with.
Rym: we've already done the show on but recently for people who weren't paying attention All the jubilees were basically at the IFC in New York, so we're even going to see him.
Rym: and I just saw I'm poco again.
Scott: I didn't see any pom poco.
Scott: I mean, I've seen a lot of it is a pretty great movie.
Scott: I didn't see any of the.
Rym: I saw it in the theater at least once as opposed to having only seen it on the tiny crappy TV we had in Beacon.
Scott: Anyway, so we came.
Scott: we're looking for show ideas because I felt like we had a zillion Wednesday show ideas, but we didn't.
Scott: and Lo and behold we came across something we never did a show on.
Scott: I can't believe we haven't done a show on it.
Scott: if we Have it's possible and someone will tell us that we suck.
Scott: But as far as I got because he is the one who said and I quote as far as I can check as far as I Can tell using my intensive extensive high quality better than anyone else.
Scott: I know Google search skills.
Scott: We have never done a show on yotsubato.
Rym: Yotsubato is written by a guy you may know because he also did Azumanga Daioh.
Rym: Kiyohiko Azuma.
Scott: Yep Azumanga Daioh was his four panel comic strip that was also turned into a great anime series.
Scott: It's called Azumanga Daioh because his name is Azuma and it's a manga.
Scott: I was a manga that he did and it was published in a magazine called Denkeki Daioh, which is mostly Sort of perverted.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it's the thing that we often talk.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: This is the kind of stuff that full of panty shots and cleavage we talk about at every convention But we don't really talk about on GeekNights anymore because we've talked about a lot of these topics.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: in 2005 Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, Yotsuba is the comic is working on now that he's still working on new volumes keep coming out No
Rym: But the reason that Yotsuba or Azumanga Daioh things like this often Appeared next to the weird or perverted or kind of sexy stuff is that it tend Sainen not Shonen.
Rym: but Sainen seems to have two kind of distinct branches really cute stuff and really violent and/or sexy stuff because it's aimed at You know young adults mostly men, but also women to a degree at least here.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So Yotsuba and Azumanga Daioh are kind of more Sainen than they are anything else even though well It's weird right you look at these things and they look just really cute in my way and you're like, oh god it's gonna be right.
Scott: and there are I guess Azumanga Daioh has a panty shot and A couple boob shots somewhere in it, but Yotsuba has zero.
Scott: But the point is is it's like You read these things and you look at them and at first glance they're so cute They must be for little girls or kids and they sort of are.
Scott: they work for that.
Scott: But then it's like no actually it's sort of like ponies, but it was.
Scott: it's like ponies on purpose, right?
Scott: It's like ponies Accidentally appealed to the older male audience.
Scott: Yotsuba Intentionally appealed to the older male audience but using the same technique.
Rym: It's like, you know, this is something important.
Rym: This tells me something about marketing.
Rym: in America people who advertise things to demographics in America have no goddamn idea what Demographics actually want.
Rym: or I think there's a more subtle problem.
Scott: I there are things demo.
Scott: there are things that demographics want that nobody makes so nobody is serving That particular.
Scott: there's like a demographic has more than one to me.
Rym: I'm gonna take the secret separate track.
Rym: the things that would be popular for a demographic are not useful Because you cannot use those to sell things to that demographic that they don't care about.
Rym: Mmm, so the most coveted demographic is like the 20 to 29 year old like white male demographic Like.
Rym: that's what a lot of people really go after.
Scott: is they got money and they're gonna spend it.
Rym: but the kind of stuff Are trying to sell to those people It's not gonna work because those people are actually the prime demographic stuff like ponies and Yotsuba.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you'll look at me.
Scott: For example, right you can make ponies and I'll watch that shit But you can't sell me pony shit.
Scott: The only pony shit you could sell me you ain't making Yeah, and you know, you can't profit if you made the good pony shit.
Scott: What are you gonna make?
Scott: $100 statue?
Scott: I'm probably not gonna buy that either.
Scott: you have to make a fish.
Scott: They got to do.
Rym: they got to make bus.
Scott: I Wouldn't even I wouldn't buy a pony bus.
Scott: I hate bus.
Scott: I only like a statue.
Rym: what I would buy though that the statue of the horse head.
Rym: that's in Twilight's apartment.
Scott: That's a good one.
Rym: I would I would buy that.
Scott: Yeah, very subtle.
Scott: Good.
Rym: My grandpa can make that for me.
Rym: He's anyway, anyway, this is the pony show.
Rym: if we're gonna review Yotsuba I want to say one thing.
Rym: if you have not read Yotsuba What the fuck?
Rym: or you haven't watched or read Ozumanga dial the fuck.
Rym: don't even listen to this.
Rym: Just go read him and watch him because Yotsuba is One of the most charming things I've ever read in my life.
Scott: So Yotsuba is a manga.
Scott: It's actually a normal manga, but it's you know, it's not you know.
Scott: Just four panels like Ozumanga.
Scott: die was and it's separated in each chapter stands alone.
Scott: It's very episodic, but there is a little bit of tie-in, right?
Scott: So it's like in one chapter They'll be in the hot air balloon and the second the chapter after.
Scott: that might be about something else.
Scott: I forget the order.
Scott: It might be about the farm or something.
Scott: But they'll be like, yeah They'll mention the hot air balloon when they're on the farm or they'll introduce a character in One chapter and that character will still be around.
Scott: so you're expected to sort of know who they are.
Scott: But other than that, there's no continuity whatsoever.
Rym: It's really like jumbo and yanda are some of the most important ones to know.
Scott: Yeah, it's like as long as you sort of know the characters you're gonna be set and you can figure out who they are at Any time.
Scott: so basically here's how it goes.
Scott: There's a Japanese town.
Scott: It's pretty normal suburbia, right?
Scott: There is a dude and he has a daughter named Yotsuba and they come from a faraway tropical island, but they speak Japanese.
Scott: and Yotsubas like what?
Scott: three four.
Scott: She's real small not even in kindergarten.
Scott: She's like not even nursery school I don't think like barely almost nursery school.
Rym: She's smarter than most people.
Rym: I know and she's five right?
Scott: Okay, so and he brings her to this town and he works from home, but he's busy mostly and some and The Yotsuba just sort of hangs around the house and hangs out with the neighbors and makes mention
Rym: the trouble
Scott: and she does cute things And such cute every doesn't
Rym: do justice.
Rym: What is going?
Scott: well I mean, you know it's called Yotsuba toe like there's an ampersand at the end of the title and then exclamation point because each chapter is Yotsuba and something like Yotsuba.
Scott: and Cardboard card bow Yotsuba and Candy.
Scott: Yotsuba and water guns.
Scott: It's a band something and each chapter She encounters a thing like bicycles or flowers or who knows what and then it's all about that thing.
Scott: So he's basically if you've got an idea like that Cranking out chapters must be just the easiest fucking thing in the world.
Scott: because you just look around your house or outside on the street You see something you're like, oh the bookstore Bookstore episode.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: What would you do if you encountered my favorite thing a bird scare balloon?
Scott: Yeah, it's like you just walk around you look at things and you just come up.
Scott: There's a bridge Yotsuba and the bridge Yotsuba and the cable car Yotsuba and the train Yotsuba and the car, you know, it's just transportation related I mean because I'm looking out the window in New York City, right?
Scott: So that's what I'm thinking of.
Scott: but you know, it's like Yotsuba and the office building elevator.
Scott: It's about and You know kindergarten if kindergarten ever starts.
Rym: now the real like the drive.
Rym: why this bong is great Is that it's so light-hearted and so just charming and Yotsuba is so Perplexed by the things around her but yet at the same time has a certain level of insight into these things.
Scott: Well, yeah, I mean it's typically what it does.
Scott: is it takes.
Scott: you know that aspect of childhood in that, you know Kids, they're cute.
Scott: They react to things In interesting and unexpected ways because they don't understand them.
Rym: yet children tend to ask the obvious question.
Scott: They also have an incredible insight and it takes those Aspects of childhood puts them in Yotsuba and amplifies them times a hundred and gets rid of all the other aspects.
Rym: but at the same time there's a very strong.
Rym: it's kind of like Yotsuba is there and then there's the straight man cast of Everyone else in the world around her.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, not everyone else is a total straight man, but they're pretty much relative to Yotsuba.
Rym: They are yeah, they're normal people But they had.
Rym: they all will have like a little bit of Yotsuba style reactions to certain kinds of things and they do.
Scott: each Character actually has a personality.
Scott: It's not just like a whole right.
Scott: It's like, you know jumbo.
Scott: He's just sort of like this chill cool dude, but he's gigantic and he's a little shy and weird.
Scott: with the ladies.
Scott: I really like Asagi the the oldest sister the oldest sister who's you don't get too much of her early on so Sarcastic.
Scott: Yeah, but she's she's like sort of like cynical and slightly badass.
Scott: and then you've got you know The the neighbor mom is just sort of like a cool totally awesome mom who's all responsible and shit.
Scott: and then You know, basically it's mostly the neighbors of the heaviest used characters right?
Rym: I was a thousand feet tall and yonder is no good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah I love how yonder like.
Scott: oh that guy's no good and they keep talking about him But you don't see him and then eventually he shows up spoilers and he's actually no good.
Scott: He's pretty no good.
Scott: He's like.
Scott: then does it?
Scott: you know the guy in the Baltimore Ravens?
Scott: His name is yonder.
Scott: No good.
Rym: He's no good you know, it's telling.
Rym: you know, we were reading this way back and Yonda became kind of our term for no good.
Scott: Yeah, we're like, man, that's so yonder and that meant it was no good.
Scott: Yep So the arts in it is obviously, you know The typical Azuma art style the same as I was among Adele, but the backgrounds he loads up on the backgrounds I was among Adele didn't really have background so much.
Scott: Yeah Yotsuba.
Scott: He lays it out.
Scott: I'm sure his assistant does that shit or something, but I mean the backgrounds are pretty great.
Scott: They're almost as good as Death Note backgrounds.
Scott: They're crazy.
Scott: And that's really important because it's all about like what Yotsuba is doing.
Scott: is she in her house?
Scott: Is she in the neighbor's house?
Scott: Is she?
Scott: you know, she's riding a hot-air balloon.
Scott: She's driving in a car.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: So all that stuff becomes really she in the playground of the bear that she took in the hot-air balloon like Jarleman.
Rym: Yeah, something like that like the bear just falls out of the balloon and of course Yotsuba is devastated by this and it just lands in this field like kind of Standing like straight up and I think Asagi or someone's over there and she just has this reaction.
Rym: That is priceless.
Scott: Yeah, it's always like the facial expression is what it's all about Cuz.
Rym: he you know, you'll see like crazy eyes or dot eyes or wiggly mouth But it's not a pause of you know, multiple panels of the face slightly changing like building up to the reaction aka the explosion.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like he won't do the cheap cop-out like a lot of old Mangas and animes to do the super deform like, you know slayers even does that where it's like, you know.
Scott: But this you'll keep the character on model and then just make the crazy extreme deform facial expression But he won't deform the whole thing and make it crazy chibi with like triangle arms.
Scott: suddenly, you know and It'll do the same thing that you just said.
Scott: where it's like you'll see Yotsuba and it'll be the same frame three times Right of her like her head is down and in the fourth frame her head is up and her eyes are like wiggle.
Rym: wiggle I got Yotsuba angry is one of my favorite things which is funny.
Rym: cuz with the pet right or a little kid You like them when they're happy, but you also like like it is enjoyable to watch a like a pet animal.
Rym: It's like who is annoyed and perplexed by something not harming them But is simultaneously like a dog who can't figure something out like.
Scott: it doesn't matter what their emotion is It just matters the form their emotion takes.
Scott: like you can laugh at a baby crying or you can laugh at a baby laugh Standing next to a baby just laughing.
Scott: It's like you can laugh at almost any reaction it's having if it's having an extreme crazy.
Rym: Well, like for example, one of our bunnies moogie is a little temperamental like he's.
Rym: he's a worried rabbit so sometimes we'll be sitting there and he'll just be like This is no good and he'll like walk over to the corner.
Rym: Look at us and thump and just kind of be like And I want to go pet him, but I'm also just kind of I can't help but laugh at him being so moody.
Rym: Exactly So, you know what?
Rym: I realize there's a three-way recommendation.
Rym: if you like My Little Pony Azumanga die Oh or Yotsuba any one of the three you will like the other two Probably pretty much straight up and it's weird like Yotsuba has started.
Scott: if you don't notice.
Scott: like Yotsuba You know her name means four leaf clover and she has four pigtails.
Scott: Her hair is green and she has four big tail.
Rym: Unofficial mascot of fortune.
Rym: not not by any action on Osmo's part.
Rym: That's just fortune being fortune.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, you know It's you'll see her around the Internet's and it's like.
Scott: don't think that because fortune is fortunes unofficial mascot There's something going on there.
Scott: That's wrong.
Scott: It's like, you know, the comic is the comic.
Scott: It's a good comic on its own Regardless of what people may do with it or use it for or what comics other fans may draw with Yotsuba in them.
Rym: And such it was a pretty scary disclaimer.
Scott: ignore that.
Scott: I mean, it's you know rule 34 is in effect is basically what I'm saying.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Scott: It's always in effect.
Scott: If you didn't really.
Scott: it's like, you know Stu Leonard has the three rules and is in the front of his store.
Scott: He's like.
Scott: the customer is always right if you if the customer is wrong re re rule number one It's like well rule 34 if this you know, and then rule number 35 is like well, if not rule 34 re re rule 34.
Rym: So there is no anime of Yotsuba and I don't know if there ever will be.
Rym: we.
Scott: there was a news.
Scott: I what I did.
Scott: I see.
Rym: I could see economic pressure like causing it to happen But I don't think anyone involved would want it.
Scott: I did a new I look when I was searching to see if we did an episode on this.
Scott: I found a news where we talked about.
Scott: there was a link that Ozzie where Ozzie Doesn't think it would why why he would never do an anime for Yotsuba.
Scott: So I don't think he's gonna.
Rym: However, I don't think it's a Calvin and Hobbes situation.
Rym: I think someone could go to him with a sack of money and it might happen.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Who knows what his personality is?
Rym: the only person in the world I know of but he actually turned down the sack of money.
Scott: The thing is he keeps doing Yotsuba.
Scott: volumes keep coming out regularly.
Scott: There aren't like huge delays.
Scott: It was published in the US by a DV which failed obviously.
Rym: Yeah, and then It's now published by I think yen press if I'm not mistaken, which is sadly, you know not to harp on translations But at least initially like the first few yen presses I read the translation was kind of shit compared to the original Translate.
Scott: Well, I think the biggest difference in that fan people care about it so much is you know The new one the yen press one or with the new one.
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's yeah.
Scott: It was less like new on it does a lot of the you know, keeping in honorifics and stuff like that.
Rym: Yeah and it's kind of translation like a lot of the sentence is just Really don't sound natural.
Rym: and the ADV one by comparison read really naturally and actually yeah a little bit of the charm is lost.
Scott: The thing is I don't even really notice that much.
Scott: I just read it and the thing is it's great.
Rym: I've read entire volumes of Yotsuba in Japanese and I can't read really any Japanese.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know They're may wait There are a lot of Japanese volumes are that are out in the America.
Scott: the English ones aren't out.
Scott: yet If you can get the Japanese ones It's really even if you don't know Japanese and you'll never be able to read it.
Scott: You can get like 50% of the jokes just looking at it.
Scott: You don't really need to read the words so much.
Scott: once you know, the character is just looking at what they're doing.
Scott: That's usually enough You know, there's fact is like even though the dialogue is it's not like if you're a beginning Japanese reader You probably wouldn't be able to read it because it is real Japanese language and such.
Rym: but it's pretty simple.
Scott: The quantity of dialogue is low.
Scott: There isn't a lot of words.
Scott: It's not like incredibly wordy with lots of sci-fi words going on all over the place.
Scott: It's like they don't say much.
Scott: they say about as much as normal people say and it's a lot of just you know Panels without even talking.
Scott: or you know people looking at something Or a person says one thing and then the rest of the page is them doing the thing.
Scott: So you don't really need to read so much at all to understand what's going on.
Scott: You can tell just by the panels and it's it's just that good.
Scott: Well a well-produced comic that you you can follow it sequentially, you know, so many comics are you know?
Scott: If you took the words out of like a Marvel comic it wouldn't mean dick.
Scott: It would just be like there's a panel with spider-man in it and there's a panel But how will I know whether or not he's actually punching that little guy?
Scott: And it's like every panel has a different guy in it in different plays doing something different.
Scott: It would make no sense, but yotsuba makes total sense even without words And you should read it and buy all the volumes.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: I can't believe.
Rym: there people haven't read this yet now I don't know if we've actually done a show on awesome.
Rym: We got dial either.
Rym: So rather than talk about it I'm just gonna let it be for a night like this when it's a late.
Scott: same shit in high school.
Rym: Yeah, same guy same shit little little different feeling a little more sarcastic at time.
Scott: This is primarily humorous though, which is great because there really aren't that many.
Scott: You know comics that are good and funny and awesome and you know Except this this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.