Scott:
Rym: It's Wednesday June 20th 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott.
Rym: It's a long warm day and tonight on GeekNights.
Rym: We're talking about polar bear cafe kids on the slope and folk tales from Japan.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: I Felt like I had to do the opener a little different because I realized last time we did a Wednesday show was early May.
Rym: It's late June and that show we basically just talked about anime everyone forgot about and kind of a ad-hoc crab people fashion.
Scott: Well, I think we're gonna.
Scott: I think we're getting some show ideas.
Scott: So we're gonna have a period of time here where the the getting is good.
Rym: Getting is getting better before this.
Scott: I'm sure there'll be a doldrums after it, but for now It's goodening.
Scott: We came up with a Monday show.
Rym: I did and actually we got a lot of Wednesday stuff to do.
Rym: Just we have to you have to watch a bunch of stuff.
Scott: Yeah, whatever You could also if you watch I've already what previously watched a bunch of stuff.
Scott: if you watched any of it.
Rym: Ah, but all the things you watched are fucking ass long show.
Scott: You don't have to watch them all you just watch.
Scott: enough to do a show.
Rym: I could do a show on fist of the North.
Scott: Yeah, we actually have never done a fist of the North Star show ever.
Rym: I feel like we could do it.
Rym: It might be time to do it.
Scott: It's always time.
Rym: What?
Rym: But yeah, it's.
Rym: uh You know a lot of people are complaining not that you guys will care since no one listens to the show right as it comes Out.
Rym: but it's warm today.
Scott: It is it was not warm yesterday But it is warm today.
Scott: weather underground if you don't know about this website.
Scott: It has nothing to do with the hippies who bomb shit underground.
Scott: calm.
Scott: They basically take data from civilian, and I don't know if they take data from other weather stations.
Scott: Take data from weather stations, and it's like a open-source weather website.
Scott: According to this the weather where we are right now.
Scott: It is currently 97.3 degrees Fahrenheit, and it says it feels like 105 in Celsius for you foreign peoples.
Scott: I'm clicking the Celsius which right because you can't do it in your head Can you?
Scott: that's right.
Scott: it is 36.3 and feels like 40. it is so awesome.
Rym: I would like it to be a little warmer.
Scott: Well I mean the thing is right.
Scott: when I'm biking This is the tiniest bit of chilliness.
Scott: if I'm if you're moving fast, but other than that It's warm.
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty much taking this granted.
Rym: to be fair the only time in my life I've ever not had air conditioning in my primary residence was when we were at RIT in Rochester.
Scott: Didn't really matter her air conditioning.
Scott: No we didn't.
Scott: I guess not how well.
Rym: Why would you think that we had air conditioning?
Rym: trying to remember we schemed about having air conditioning in the winter?
Rym: Because it got dank we left the window open all the time.
Scott: anyway there is Is something.
Rym: you got something to say.
Rym: you got nothing I forgot.
Scott: so oh, I just gonna say the thing.
Scott: I've been the comment.
Scott: I've been making all day repeatedly, which I won't make after today.
Scott: cuz No, cuz I'm not Rym.
Scott: It's a long day.
Scott: I like how when you open the door to the outside and you if you closed your you already told me that yeah But I didn't tell you on the show.
Rym: Uh you've already said that anecdote though I know you can't tell it to another.
Scott: I'm not gonna say it ever again But you've you already said it twice, but when you open the door to the outside.
Scott: It feels like How's it feel I kind of want to bring some pizza outside just to kind of let it cook And then we could go cook an egg on the asphalt.
Rym: I've done that before.
Scott: you need a magnifying glass.
Scott: No, you don't need no.
Rym: just cracking egg on the asphalt was hot enough.
Rym: It just cooks.
Scott: I don't think it's hot enough right now.
Scott: also the egg would be mad dirty.
Rym: Yeah, but now you don't eat it You just cook it.
Scott: then you leave it there for someone to find me like what the thing is if you put on someone if you Clean a windshield off and use that then you'll be able to eat that.
Rym: True a windshield or a hood of a car?
Scott: Yeah, hood of a car.
Rym: cuz I was gonna say windshield probably not the hottest thing in the world It'd be pretty hot not as hot as the hood of the car anyway.
Rym: anyway Let's send this fascinating conversation.
Scott: so car black car.
Rym: I went to see a cat in Paris with Emily at the Angelica.
Scott: I went all the way to Paris.
Rym: Yeah, there were commas in that sentence.
Scott: how many.
Scott: I didn't mean there must be a lot of cats in Paris.
Rym: There's just one apparently okay, and there were some some other cats in the opening bit, but no it's a French animation.
Rym: What was interesting?
Rym: I saw the dub, and it was dubbed by none other than our friend Sinter Nicklaus Okay, and the main character was played by none other than mr.. Bloom.
Rym: Uh-huh Spike Spiegel.
Rym: all right the dub was fine.
Rym: I don't know how it compares to the sub though because I've never seen the sub, but yeah to geek bite it It is a fantastic movie.
Rym: You should just go see it however you can.
Scott: apparently it has the opposite of the Wonder Woman problem.
Scott: I haven't seen it, but Rym says it has the opposite of the Wonder Woman.
Rym: Yes, we look at a movie post like the movie poster.
Rym: It looks like some amazing like different kind of animation with particular style.
Rym: It looks exactly like that poster the whole time.
Scott: That's amazing.
Rym: It's all like Super flat not super flat, but it's just really flat.
Rym: There's like no depth Perspective.
Scott: that really that you know.
Scott: looking at the poster and knowing that it looks like the poster makes me want to see it.
Rym: It's pretty good, and I don't really want to say anything else about it.
Rym: So consider this geek bite to be.
Rym: go see this movie or get it however you can.
Scott: Is it an anime or is it French?
Rym: it's a French animated movie?
Scott: What's it about?
Scott: at least about a cat in Paris and a plot summer?
Rym: I don't want to summarize it because I went into it not knowing what it was about and it starts out You're like all right.
Rym: There's the cat.
Rym: All right cats pretty cool, and then that's what is the central conflict.
Rym: revolve around I hope Jewel thieves and a crazy guy and a murderer and some cops and the.
Scott: So now we have a better idea, that's good.
Rym: It's better going into it not really knowing.
Rym: All I got to say is when you see the gigantic Giants penis You'll know that you're in fact in the right movie.
Rym: There is a villain the villains described early on as a raving lunatic.
Rym: Yes, and when you meet him he is a raving lunatic like to a degree it was Chekhov's lunatism.
Rym: All right, so we would have reviewed it, but Scott couldn't even pirate it.
Rym: so we got there.
Scott: It was very is possible theoretically But yet difficult to get a subtitled or version because like people are like oh download the French version here and get the subtitle file And I'm like yeah fuck that noise.
Scott: It's like yo 1997 digital fan subs call yeah, so if somebody out there wants to go through this trouble and go through all these sketchy websites one Website I went to was like here download the whole thing, and I'm like okay Don't move dot exe.
Scott: right it was like blah blah blah dot exe, and I'm like I'm not stupid.
Scott: So if anyone else wants to get viruses and somehow put together a non virus File with some English subtitles built in that are properly synced and such Put that on the Pirate Bay, but if not I'll just wait to watch this somehow.
Rym: otherwise Yeah, it was a good movie.
Rym: That was it was refreshing because for me This was pretty good, but I went out of the theater like all right.
Rym: I went out of the theater here like oh, yeah So there's not really much news in the anime.
Scott: I mean, I guess Otakon coming up Whatever, so um I haven't done Scott's box in forever.
Scott: Just cuz I sort of stopped doing that.
Scott: I'm gonna maybe bring it back with increased production But who knows what?
Scott: but so I figure hey is a way to cop out of a news.
Scott: I'll just quickly go down the list not of what I've received But what I just ordered today because I sent in my order form today all right now from DCVs.
Scott: Yeah, so now you will know what to order, but in particular one of these items is going to be my news.
Scott: So I'm gonna hold that one for the last item ready.
Scott: see is the.
Scott: is the order real quick, and I'm ready.
Scott: atomic robo flying she-devils Pacific number three.
Scott: ah Bakuman volume 14 again.
Scott: We was 14 volumes already.
Scott: Manoka Magica the manga volume 2.
Rym: now that manga is written from the anime writer vice has no idea.
Scott: That's why I'm ordering it to find out.
Rym: I can probably find out anyway.
Scott: go on I'm gonna check it out anyway.
Scott: worst case.
Scott: I sell to book off.
Rym: Yeah, you might say worst case.
Rym: I read a volume of the escaflowne manga.
Scott: How can you spell it?
Rym: I also read the first volume of the brave story manga.
Scott: I can sell bad things anyway.
Scott: Essential warlock volume 1.
Scott: I've been waiting for this.
Scott: if you don't know right when you buy Marvel comics They they have lots of different kinds of trades, but pretty much this regular trades, which is a recent comic.
Scott: We bundled six issues into one volume.
Scott: Yeah They have Marvel masterwork Which is you buy a trade or hardcover of some incredibly old comic all?
Scott: Collected in order nice like.
Scott: so you can buy like essential x-men or not essential like Marvel masterworks.
Scott: x-men volume 1 and that has the beginning Of x-men.
Scott: so many issues all in full color beautiful paper fanciness very expensive.
Scott: or you can buy essential Essential is pretty much the same thing as masterwork only on fucking cheap ass.
Scott: newsprint black and white.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so it's like you want to read the old ass fantastic four for like ten bucks.
Scott: Maybe even eight bucks, right?
Scott: Here's like a whole bunch of the issues all in order from the beginning in a big-ass volume.
Scott: Way cheap black and white.
Rym: so a manga adaptation of the series and two spin-off manga series.
Rym: nice All right, so all based on the anime.
Scott: We'll find out later.
Scott: essential warlock volume 1.
Scott: I mean Adam warlock.
Scott: That's my guy, so I gotta check that out.
Scott: You probably shouldn't.
Scott: Starman omnibus volume 2. so the deal with this is there's this DC comic that people can't shut up about.
Scott: that's kind of old and It's sort of famous.
Rym: wait a minute.
Rym: the last time that happened.
Rym: I read that god-awful Green Lantern thing.
Scott: yeah But anyway, this isn't something that really ties in so much right.
Scott: this is more like somewhere between Sandman and Green Lantern like sort of a halfway point at least this.
Rym: are there Green Lanterns in it?
Scott: I don't know, but this it's about Starman primarily right, so I don't know who that is.
Scott: yeah That's why I'm checking it out because it's uber famous.
Scott: people can't shut up about it, and if it sucks I'll sell that.
Scott: yeah, so here we go ready.
Scott: Pokemon adventures box set volume 2.
Scott: This is like seven a bunch of volumes of Pokemon adventures for $33.
Rym: you gonna buy up through yellow.
Scott: I'm pretty.
Scott: no I'm pretty much Box one and box two and that's it.
Scott: not gonna buy box three.
Rym: why cuz?
Scott: box three is all like diamond pearl.
Scott: Who knows what the fuck?
Rym: what if it keeps up with the goodness?
Scott: You know how can it possibly be good after yellow caviar?
Rym: Oh, I actually kind of lost interest.
Rym: even by the time yellow came I was like I just want more red.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: The only reason the yellow and such is good is because it's like.
Scott: red is still like you know sort of like this legend that You can you know the legend of red still goes the legend of the first kid who actually paid attention to what Pokemon are strong And was still better than his friend who also paid attention.
Scott: Also, this is awesome right There's a. there's a Tezuka manga called a message to Adolf, and it was in print a long time ago in English But it's been out of print and difficult to purchase forever.
Scott: Yeah, it is now going to be in English and easily available again.
Scott: So buy it while you can before it again becomes difficult to get an out of print and such not bad.
Scott: So a very important famous Tezuka manga about Hitler and The most important thing Amazon link on our website.
Scott: go and click it.
Scott: This is mandatory purchase for all GeekNights listeners Right mandatory purchase.
Scott: if you do not buy this Just stop listening to GeekNights And also kill yourself and also kill yourself alright underwater.
Scott: welder by Jeff Lemire $10 and 39 cents.
Scott: if you don't pre-order this you are subhuman.
Scott: it is mandatory purchase.
Scott: again That shipment gonna arrive at your apartment Two months from now July September.
Scott: all right all right pre-order price guarantee from Amazon.
Scott: Amazon does Amazon actually and the Amazon date is September 11th 2012. all right Mandatory purchase this book but anyway things of the day.
Rym: So uh I found this video kind of randomly.
Rym: I want to use it because I feel like this kid if he keeps up this level of video is going to go in the same direction as the angry video game Nerd.
Rym: and like mmm.
Rym: There's a video about the mystery of lavender town.
Rym: since we're talking about Pokemon you may remember lavender town was the creepy town with the Pokemon Tower Aka all the dead Pokemon
Scott: in other words the good part of Pokemon where Cubone's mom is in there But she's a ghost and you get the Cubone and this Gastly's and it's good times Isn't it?
Scott: the more you also know you'd use the poke flute to wake the Snorlax.
Rym: He basically he explores.
Rym: You know the music was creepy and everyone like he points out like Everyone thought the music in that town was really creepy.
Scott: it is creep And he's like.
Rym: you want proof.
Rym: look at YouTube.
Rym: the video of the that song has way more views than any other video of songs In Pokemon ever.
Rym: it's true and all the comments are like man that music scared the shit out of me when I was a kid.
Scott: I Was a little older so didn't scare me, but it was creepy.
Rym: Yeah It's weird.
Rym: I know I don't know as a kid.
Rym: I didn't know when Pokemon appeared.
Rym: I just like when I first learned about Pokemon.
Rym: I felt like it had always existed.
Scott: No I see.
Scott: the thing is I actually saw Pokemon appear in like my game pro because I'm a game pro And I saw this and I'm like oh Nintendo's coming out with some kitty game whatever.
Scott: and then You know when it actually came out.
Scott: my brother got it, and I was like yeah That's the thing for kids whatever because I was a kid too, but you know yeah I was older right.
Scott: so he had a Game Boy Pocket with Pokemon blue and Then I had my own money, and I bought a Game Boy Color and got Pokemon red, and that was that All right, so what this video is pretty good.
Rym: It talks about Blues radicate and whether or not it died and all sorts of interesting stuff.
Rym: And I was making Scott watch it and the whole time He's like ah the kids wrong and then the kid would be like no you might be thinking yeah.
Scott: Well it turns out yeah the kid knew everything that I knew about Pokemon lore and more.
Scott: so Mad points that he answered the exact things that I have questions.
Rym: so kid props to you.
Rym: I like this video.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: so check this out checkin, so there's a book you probably don't know about it called.
Scott: Oh hot move.
Scott: It's the official handbook of the Marvel Universe And it has been published like all superhero comics in many different forms and formats and things all over the years.
Scott: So it's it's.
Scott: it's not like you can just buy the whole thing from beginning to end.
Scott: It's like oh well we put a bunch of big volumes, then we put a bunch of individual issues.
Scott: It's got a term Oh hot mu like PHB or DM official handbook of the Marvel Universe and basically they publish parts of this at times and the way it works is it's most.
Scott: most of It is just one page one character.
Scott: It's a lot like a monster manual of Marvel superheroes, right?
Scott: It'll give you their name their relevant information their origin story and a picture of them and all that stuff right?
Scott: so this blog Oh hot mu redux dot blog spot calm Basically has.
Scott: every entry in this blog is a scan of a page from Oh hot mu Accompanied by some indie artists rendition of that character usually in that same pose, but in a new style.
Scott: And a lot of them are way awesome, especially the ones by patricio oliver are the awesomest.
Scott: oh my god I want their patricio oliver to just draw a whole comic book.
Scott: I would buy them all.
Scott: there's also a rocket raccoon by David Peterson.
Scott: oh yeah You should come to this blog just to see that and that alone.
Scott: also.
Scott: the blog updates very frequently.
Scott: It's pretty much.
Scott: Just awesome.
Scott: It's an awesome blog with awesome superhero arts.
Scott: Oh my gosh awesome.
Scott: So uh met a moment.
Rym: Yeah, I'm at a moment Connecticut coming up real soon.
Scott: you should go July.
Rym: what 13 14 15 something like that I think.
Rym: the Hartford Convention Center.
Rym: we run the panel's department.
Rym: There's a bunch of stuff there a lot of guests team four-star john st.
Rym: John.
Rym: We tried to get the pony guests.
Rym: It's actually kind of hard now because ponies is really popular.
Rym: But we tried and we're gonna go for it next year even harder mm-hmm, and the thing is it was funny.
Rym: We were not the ones who were like guys get poke or get to.
Rym: I almost said Pokemon get ponies And they're like.
Rym: no I was like guys get ponies.
Rym: They're like.
Rym: are you kidding?
Rym: We've been trying all year to get ponies.
Rym: They're like.
Rym: can you get us ponies?
Rym: Do you know these people?
Scott: yeah?
Rym: Well, they actually thought we did because we do all the anime voice actors.
Rym: They're like.
Rym: you know any other voice actors.
Rym: I'm like.
Rym: no You know John st.
Rym: John and like 90s anime voice actors, and that's it.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: But yeah, that's coming up.
Rym: pecs prime is coming out every day.
Rym: That's not that far away.
Rym: We gotta write this new goddamn panel.
Rym: I guess the new triple threat Seattle Seattle Not walla walla Seattle.
Rym: Summer shows are a little sporadic.
Rym: We're gonna be in Wildwood this weekend.
Rym: if anyone's in Wildwood great tweet at us.
Rym: We'll meet you on the beach, but We're pretty much gonna be laying on the beach.
Scott: So in other news is right.
Scott: first of all you know we've.
Scott: you know I've updated the website recently.
Scott: But in addition to I think you go to the website not that you go there.
Scott: But I just added because now that the websites updated I can update it a lot in small increments I added the video section of the website And you're probably thinking why don't you go the website?
Scott: video section of the website.
Scott: I can just go to the YouTube.
Scott: You're absolutely correct.
Scott: You can't just go to the you.
Rym: yes But the videos on the website have collected for now a bunch of videos from other YouTube accounts You might not have known about.
Scott: yeah And basically you can just come to the website and you'll find all of our relevant GeekNights related YouTube videos.
Scott: also I'm gonna add some RSS to those videos which that doesn't have them right now.
Scott: So that'll make it even easier to say subscribe to our video.
Rym: It might also let you realize you know a lot of people don't seem to real that a lot of our panels and things are On YouTube.
Rym: yep like if you want to see that famous beyond Dungeons & Dragons Panel or the one where we said World of Warcraft sucks for half hour.
Rym: They're all up there.
Rym: You can just watch the entire thing in glorious HD.
Scott: also now when we post a new video to the website It'll automatically get tweeted Facebook Etc the same way as everything else and you might have noticed we're doing a Google+ hangout of every episode too.
Rym: So there's video of us actually like on the site, and you get to see like you know we do the show But you get to see what happens before the show.
Rym: after the show what we say about.
Scott: you're giving people the finger on the web.
Rym: I'm not giving anyone the finger, okay?
Scott: Also, I want to remind people the new website since it was upgraded right has added a very powerful feature that people do not know About which is wiki show notes.
Scott: you can write show notes for GeekNights episodes if you want.
Scott: the way it works Is this I could have done a standard wiki, but the problem with standard wikis is spam spam.
Scott: So here's how it works on my github account.
Scott: There is an FRC show notes public repository.
Scott: if you fork that You can then in you create.
Scott: there's a text file per episode.
Scott: You just have to create a text file in the correct folder with the correct name and in that text file you put the show Notes and you can put any text you want in there And then you send me a pull request and if I accept that pull request your show notes will then immediately Appear on front row.
Scott: crew comm on the page for that episode.
Scott: It's a pretty crazy system where all the show notes are on github But it totally works because I can do stuff like that now.
Rym: if we started this before we had like a thousand existing episodes I know, but we didn't.
Scott: github didn't exist and I wasn't smart enough to think of that clever idea.
Scott: But now it does and you can learn get you know, and it really isn't that hard.
Scott: You can actually do the whole thing from github.com.
Scott: You don't need to okay.
Rym: We don't have a thousand episodes.
Rym: We have 830 episodes.
Scott: good job.
Scott: Some of the episodes because somebody went there was a guy who was writing show notes and putting them in our forum.
Scott: Somebody went through and copy pasted all those show notes to github.
Scott: So good job on that guy.
Scott: Whoever did that and so there's already some episodes of show notes.
Scott: So you should go and help out on this if you are interested or not.
Scott: Why do you work for free?
Rym: Yeah, but you know one one request we've gotten.
Rym: I mean, you know, we never really read emails on the show.
Rym: In fact, we tried to always avoid even talking about the meta of the show Until we made this like one meta moment like this specific place where we talk about that crap.
Rym: Yep, so The biggest request we pretty much get other than hey Will you come to my tiny?
Rym: Convention is people who are for whatever reason fans of this and they want to get more involved in the GeekNights community.
Rym: And you know what little there is.
Rym: there's actually a lot.
Rym: It's just all in the front recruit forum, right?
Rym: So you can get more ways to get involved.
Rym: You don't want to go into that scary forum where everyone yells at you about grammar, right?
Scott: You can contribute to the show notes by going to github.
Rym: If you have it some sort of like vested political angle, you can get your angle into those show notes.
Rym: We're not really gonna like curate them too.
Scott: Well, I mean they have to be accepted by me as a pull request.
Scott: So it's basically it's pretty much gonna be a thumbs up or thumbs down situation.
Rym: Yeah, but if you're.
Rym: if you're like Scott was wrong or Rym sucked in this episode, we're gonna let that in.
Rym: we're really.
Rym: I Think we're gonna Scott's gonna disprove if it's like the word penis eight hundred times in a row with no other content.
Scott: Notice I said with no other as long as it's actually show notes and not just you know links to Viagra Right.
Rym: Anyway, anyway Otherwise, you know, like I said for the other thing the other of course we get is convention.
Rym: so seriously, if you want us to come to a convention if You are not the person who runs that convention Don't tell us to go to the convention at least like the panels or the guest department.
Rym: We're not gonna go to the convention to say hey, can we come?
Rym: it's got it.
Rym: It's the other way around.
Scott: you have to tell the convention to ask us to come right?
Scott: You're just a convention goer.
Scott: Don't ask us to go to the con.
Scott: ask the con to bring us there.
Rym: cuz I've had like three Situations recently where someone emailed me like hey would you like to come to ex-con?
Rym: and I always send my standard response of yeah You know, it's far away.
Rym: So we need you know X Y & Z and then yeah, we'll come.
Rym: What do you want us to do?
Rym: and then they're like, oh, I just wanted you to submit a panel.
Rym: Yeah to this con.
Rym: I go to right like.
Scott: no the con has to call us.
Rym: Well, the con has to call us if it's not on our list of cars.
Rym: We already go to like packs.
Scott: exactly.
Rym: There's a very we have a short list of cons that we will go to even if we aren't doing any GeekNights crap at them.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: packs and packs and mag fest.
Scott: If you want to bring me to Essen I'll go.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, uh, we've actually Despite not doing a lot of anime shows.
Rym: We've been watching a lot of anime lately.
Scott: I haven't been watching a lot, but there are three shows.
Scott: We watched quite a few episodes of The new Lupin but of course, but I haven't watched that in a while and we can't really.
Scott: I've watched like seven or eight episodes.
Scott: I just yeah, then I haven't.
Rym: we can't review it until we finish it because for all we know it sucks.
Scott: after the last episode We already did a show on it.
Rym:  yeah, well, we'll do a real review once it's done.
Rym: of course I've been watching polar bears cafe.
Rym: Yeah, because my tool told me to watch one episode.
Rym: Yeah, I saw one tweet about it and he and he and I was like what polar bear cafe I wonder if that's literally.
Rym: and then the next tweet from him was like, yeah, it's really just a polar bear and Kids on the slope, which uh, pretty good.
Scott: I watched seven or eight episodes And folk tales from Japan, which is two episodes.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Oh my god Why don't we talk about that first?
Scott: cuz I'm again?
Rym: Okay, so folk tales from Japan is one of those short shows But instead of being short episodes, it's a full-length episode that has three short parts.
Rym: Yeah, but otherwise like I think I'm adding it to our bite-sized anime panel.
Scott: First of all, this show right is so cute with its drawing and the drawing style is pretty different depending on the legend being told Right.
Scott: So I mean it's like It's just I don't know.
Scott: It's just so cute and the animation is so cute and it's it's really simple like they're saving money.
Scott: It's obviously not a big-budget.
Scott: It's got two narrators who basically tell you the story the kind of thing like when you were a kid you would have to see On PBS or maybe not even PBS.
Scott: maybe like you could see it like at the library, you know.
Scott: But you could never.
Scott: you know, it doesn't seem like it's a real TV show But it is.
Rym: it's the kind of thing that you'd like when you had a substitute teacher in elementary school.
Rym: They'd show you something like that.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm like old fairy tale and as a narrator and You know the characters.
Scott: the characters don't really talk that much and everything's very simple.
Scott: But despite all that it's like, you know, then the budget being low The production is not low as you know.
Scott: to go with the budget being low Even though it's simple and cute and there isn't a lot of animation going on You don't need that much to tell these stories and what they do.
Scott: everything they put into it is so great.
Scott: It's like every animal is cute.
Scott: they move, you know.
Scott: enough to be awesome is a cute.
Rym: Well, I think really the strength of it is that you know being not Japanese Like.
Rym: I know the kind of like really big Japanese folk tales kind of like how people around the world know a lot of the big American folk tales.
Rym: There's like a a collected set of folk tales and legends that most people know about but I don't really expect someone in Japan to Know about Johnny Appleseed or Paul Bunyan?
Rym: necessarily exactly granted Paul Bunyan might be more well-known now.
Rym: Thanks.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: McNinja.
Scott: I don't think Dr.
Scott: McNinja is that popular in Japan, although he should be.
Rym: But you know beyond like Momotaro and a certain like set of Japanese folk tales.
Rym: I don't know most of these stories.
Scott: No kidding Cuz he didn't grow up as elementary school kids in Japan.
Rym: And Japanese folk tales have a pretty different lilt from the folk tales I'm used to from when I was a kid.
Scott: So pretty much all of them are the same, right?
Rym: There's someone who does something good.
Scott: Okay, wait, here are the common trends in all of these folk tales from.
Scott: I've watched two episodes so far.
Rym: Should we tell them the trends?
Rym: Let's just tell them the lessons you should learn.
Scott: I hear the trends, ready?
Scott: Number one, the honest person always gets gold as like a rewards and the nosy neighbor gets fucked.
Scott: The lying, cheating, stealing, evil person gets some horrible punishment like poop in the face But it's always pretty specific.
Rym: It's something good happens to someone because they're a good person.
Rym: then a neighbor comes into the house and says oh my god where'd you get all that gold?
Rym: and then they hear the story and they go try to do the exact same thing all evil like and Get horse poop in the face or killed or something, right?
Scott: So if your friend got rich playing the stock market do not play the stock market.
Scott: That is the lesson.
Scott: No, I think your friends got rich betting on horses.
Scott: Don't bet on horses.
Rym: Don't be a noisy neighbor or a nosy neighbor.
Scott: Yeah, don't be a greedy.
Rym: right neighbors alone, you know?
Rym: Oh more importantly if there's a magical artifact and someone tells you not to do something Do not fucking do it.
Scott: Any magical instructions from any supernatural source.
Scott: if a Buddha or an animal or a Goddess or a princess tells you to do something Follow those instructions.
Scott: and also the bad people are going to specifically not follow those instructions and they'll be punished for it.
Scott: And if you follow the instructions, you'll be rewarded for it.
Rym: Unless the instructions come from someone who is obviously bad Then you're rewarded for not doing it.
Scott: Yes, it's obvious to be able to tell what the good instructions are and what the bad instructions are.
Rym: I think my favorite ones are.
Rym: I really like the one about the man the old men with the bumps.
Rym: You didn't see that one.
Rym: No, there's one guy with.
Scott: There's any animals.
Scott: just be nice to all animals and you'll be rewarded.
Rym: Yep turtles Doggies boxes.
Rym: Well, there's the trickster Fox, but he got his.
Scott: yeah fishies anything.
Scott: That's nice.
Scott: You should be nice to it and you will be rewarded for being nice to animals.
Scott: All right You get to hang out with hot Mermaid princess in her palace under the sea for all eternity or you're a dumbass and you leave to go back to the real Stupid world.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that's another lesson.
Scott: if you got it good if you're in paradise, don't leave That's right.
Rym: If you got the reward if you think I should really go out and see my family now That's.
Scott: that is one thing I noticed right in an American folktale, right?
Scott: You would or a fairy tale you would often see a situation where someone get a reward and say no I don't need the reward because I'm such a good person.
Scott: Yep, and this it's like I got rewarded with gold.
Scott: Enjoy the gold.
Scott: like there's one greedy looking for more gold, right?
Scott: You got the gold in or reward usually gold because you were sometimes fancy cloth, right?
Scott: Because you were genuinely nice and honest and you got rewarded for it.
Scott: Don't go greedy looking for more rewards because that make turns you to the bad person.
Scott: You'll lose the reward but and don't go just trying to be honest or you know on purpose to get rewards.
Rym: But if you got a reward those monkeys carry that guy away and gave him gold.
Scott: If you got an honest reward, just enjoy that reward.
Scott: All right, don't go giving it up or anything like that.
Scott: Just enjoy it because otherwise no good.
Rym: but also like what?
Rym: like?
Rym: I think the most interesting one for that because I didn't expect the outcome that happened was the guy had The dream about the treasure.
Rym: the other guys like let me buy your dream from you.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and then he goes to try to find that treasure and I thought the moral was gonna be the guy who sold him The dream was just smart and basically got some free money out of him because the other guy was an idiot.
Rym: But then there was really gold.
Scott: Yeah, so He was honest for buying the dream and then the guy who owned the land that had the treasure split it within 50/50 Which is sort of like.
Rym: But seriously if you're evil or a bad neighbor or a nosy neighbor and you think you're gonna get a bunch of gold Because you're gonna do this plot don't burn all your clothes before your husband comes back with the gold.
Rym: Yeah, he's not coming back with the gold.
Scott: This really makes me wonder like how Japanese culture like neighbors are viewed.
Scott: right because the only Japanese like I mean I only really know every neighbor in these is a day The only anime or manga I can think of where there's neighbors that are like, you know Good and friendly is Yotsuba right?
Scott: Yotsuba has awesome neighbors.
Rym: Oh Here's Greenwood.
Rym: The neighbors are awesome, but they're not good neighbors.
Rym: What neighbors are there in the other rooms in the dog?
Scott: Oh, that's dorm mates.
Scott: That's not the same as not the same I'm talking about.
Scott: you're in a house and the people who live in the neighboring house the house next to it.
Rym: Usually those people don't exist in anime.
Scott: That's what I'm talking about.
Scott: Right, but in a lot of u.s.
Scott: Culture right neighbors happen a lot Dennis the Menace neighbors And it's always bad.
Scott: So Steve Urkel man, right, but that's what I'm saying.
Rym: Is that wait in both Japan in the u.s.
Rym: If there's a neighbor in a story they are bad mr.
Rym: Rogers He was his neighborhood though.
Scott: Maybe all his Sesame Street And you know, we have good and bad neighbors in a lot, right?
Scott: It seems that neighbors at least in animes among us I have read one show that we're following that out, right the animes and mangas that I have read are rare and in my exposure To their folk tales their neighbors are frequent but always evil Really evil.
Rym: one of them was evil greedy one guy who's a dog greedy and mischievous and annoying.
Rym: They're greedy and usually kind of dumb and nosy.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah, and if you're ever in the mouse paradise don't pretend to be a cat That's right.
Scott: So anyway This folktale show is totally awesome and you can learn.
Scott: not only you can not only laugh at these awesome folk tales and enjoy them But learn about folk tales from a foreign culture.
Scott: I really want to see this show from other countries.
Scott: I want the Russian cute folktale show the Indian cute folktale show the African cute.
Scott: I want to see all the folk tales in the whole world like this.
Rym: They're probably our shows.
Scott: from all those Australian folktale show French folktale show hook me up.
Scott: Yo, hook me up Give me a ball and it's on crunchyroll.
Scott: You can just watch all the episodes at least as they're coming.
Rym: and if you watch it with Scott In the opening credit when it says what I'm always gonna point out the snake one of the animals moves.
Rym: It's gotta be like it was the snake.
Scott: It's pretty funny.
Scott: Every episode is the same.
Scott: It's always snake then chicken then bunny.
Scott: as the third one the snake chicken bunny snake is the best.
Rym: Scott pays a lot of attention To this snake is the greatest.
Rym: It's a pretty good show.
Scott: It's a really good snake.
Rym: So Before I knew what kids on the slope was about I knew it was about jazz.
Scott: I knew is by Watanabe with you.
Scott: so that's the thing.
Rym: All I heard was someone said there's a new Watanabe show coming out and yoko kano is doing the music and my brain said cowboy bebop.
Scott: It's gonna be cowboy bebop or something like.
Scott: I know it's gonna be heavily musical just like samurai champloo.
Scott: and also the show.
Rym: It's pretty good show.
Rym: It's not like how we bebop though.
Scott: No, so I watched probably more episodes than Rym has right.
Rym: I think I've seen like four and I fell asleep during one because I just got back from a trip.
Scott: So what I actually like about this show so far is number one.
Scott: It's it's about jazz, right?
Scott: But and it sort of leads you in this direction thinking it's gonna be typical anime tropes, right?
Scott: Transfer student is sort of the main focus.
Scott: character moves into town goes to school There's some bullies and some a girl and it's like I know where this goes same old same old.
Scott: Oh, well the jazz music aspect.
Rym: I thought it was gonna do the the twist of.
Rym: it's the same old show But it has the kind of like getting you into it.
Rym: anime about jazz, right?
Scott: So I thought it was gonna do that but it actually so far Hasn't done that.
Scott: it's like the jazz is there but it's not doing a Hajime no Ippo Shonen jump sort of bakuman teach you everything But it does name drops You
Rym: know You should
Scott: know right and all it does is jazz is just the thing that is bringing these characters together and it's mostly about the characters, you know And you know their dramas and jazz just happens to be this thing in their lives.
Scott: That is like, you know the good awesome thing.
Scott: That is awesome.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I like the show a lot.
Scott: The reason I like it is because after you watch a few episodes, you can see that these characters Do not behave the way the anime character should behave.
Scott: for example What is the typical anime character do when there's a girl avoid talking to her?
Scott: never right in this show?
Scott: It's like hey What's up, right?
Scott: totally opposite of what anime characters do.
Rym: there's a little anime is gonna hang over everyone's heads forever and Escalate and escalate and then be like a plot point here.
Scott: They fight the bullies right away and then they're only there occasionally if at all, right.
Scott: And it really sort of gets into like, you know this sort of and the plot moves, right?
Scott: It starts off for the school is a larger factor in the opening episodes because they're introducing the characters You know and it's like oh the bad guy sits in the back of class later episodes.
Scott: You're not even seeing the classroom It's just not even there, you know, it's all this stuff outside the classroom and they keep bringing in, you know It's like they bring you up stuff that you think is gonna show up like at the end of the show Like oh his dad isn't around his dad is traveling military something like that You know, his mom is who knows where you know, it's like and you're like, oh, we'll learn the mystery of his family like Episode 26.
Scott: It's like no, you don't learn the episode that his family's gonna show up right away.
Scott: No mystery at all.
Scott: And it's like oh we know where mom is.
Scott: Let's go see her.
Scott: Okay, you know and I really like that moving right along not cutting corners, you know progressing.
Scott: But even as they progress and resolve these plots, they don't completely resolve them, right?
Scott: They move them and then the goalposts go farther out.
Rym: So, you know what another show that did that was Nana Exactly.
Rym: Nana was like alright here like I expect the plot to be the the thing about like meeting that guy again And then they get there right?
Rym: They meet him again.
Scott: It's almost just like Nana.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I really like Nana.
Scott: It's a little less so poppery.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Now what is both the strength and like?
Rym: the worst thing I can say about the show is that it doesn't need to be Animated.
Rym: I like it and I'm you know, I have no problem with it at all But it doesn't scratch that like crazy anime.
Rym: It should just scratch.
Rym: Well, I think it's a good show to watch it.
Scott: Yeah I think this would be like.
Scott: you might as well be a manga anime wise because it's mostly people talking and not a lot of Action with the music, but you need the music.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's about jazz.
Scott: How do you know?
Rym: it's the same reason why Nodabe Cantabile like the manga.
Scott: it is a manga.
Rym: But I didn't.
Rym: I couldn't read that manga just was actually pretty boring.
Rym: but then watching the show I loved every second of it.
Scott: Is there anything else to say about it?
Rym: Not really.
Rym: I mean, I don't want to spoil anything.
Rym: We're just saying it's a show you should watch.
Scott: Yeah Negative thing about it.
Scott: I would say that none of the characters are like super awesome, right?
Scott: Usually there's someone in a show that's like that's the awesomest dude.
Rym: There's like one bunta.
Scott: yeah, a bunta or You know Who's the guy in full metal alchemist who got killed?
Scott: Yeah, there's.
Scott: no there is no one in the show who is like super awesome.
Scott: The main character is like he's got good parts and bad parts and he reminds me, you know, he reminds me It's almost too realistic and that every character has awesome parts and not awesome parts so that there's nobody you can really say like that's Some guy.
Scott: I'm rooting for him all.
Rym: the main character reminds me a little bit of aspects of both main characters from karikano Just a little bit like I thought he's got a blue.
Scott: He's got some jerkiness going on.
Scott: That's not in karikano.
Rym: I just I found it interesting that watching the first few episodes.
Rym: I thought of karikano a couple of times Just when characters did certain things.
Rym: Yeah, that's the show ever forgot about.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, there's no awesome people but it I guess maybe the dad who owns the jazz shop is awesome But you don't see him at all.
Scott: Right other than that he like he's barely in the frame and he says like maybe two lines He's very strict.
Rym: we get that.
Rym: that's especially about the jazz, right?
Scott: You're not allowed to go in the basement unless you're jazzing.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Not jazz hands and he plays the bass.
Rym: So polar bears cafe.
Scott: I only saw one episode.
Rym: I only saw one episode.
Scott: Okay, it is a review of one episode.
Rym: You know what it is.
Rym: This is a show about a polar bear runs a cafe.
Scott: Well, that's the thing right.
Scott: the show is called polar bear cafe and there is a literal cafe run by a polar bear Who's pretty cool, but the first episode focused entirely on this panda who was trying to get a job there.
Scott: Well, he's trying to get a job.
Scott: Well, you wouldn't want to get a job.
Scott: His mom was making him get a job with a vacuum cleaner, right?
Scott: But anyway And that is the polar bear cafe was almost secondary and it focused mostly on this lazy-ass panda Who wasn't getting a job and was laying around his mom's house all day doing nothing and wanted to do nothing.
Scott: It was super lazy because he's a panda.
Scott: He just wanted to eat bamboo Because that's a panda's do.
Scott: And I wonder if in the later episodes the focus goes off the panda to these other characters.
Rym: I'm pretty sure it does.
Rym: It's not the panda bears cafe.
Scott: Yeah But I'd really I'd want to find out about the polar bear and his cafe.
Scott: I don't really care that much about any learning anything more about the panda, but I like it.
Rym: So it's one of those odd shows is very atmospheric.
Scott: It's very punny Like the Bear is a pretty serious dude except for when he always does a million puns whenever he can, you know, and that's like his deal.
Rym: But here's what I know.
Rym: the first I like the voice actor like of the polar bear.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: You know that is It's a Takahiro Sakurai and you probably remember him.
Rym: don't know who that is the main character in gatekeepers.
Scott: Okay, you know shouldn't?
Scott: yeah gatekeepers That was the biggest show for a little while for five and RIT cuz it was the only digitally fan sub show.
Rym: Yep Then gatekeepers 21, which I never even watched.
Rym: I watched like one episode Yeah, but for some reason that show for us at that time was the best show ever for like five minutes.
Scott: Yeah Well, it's all good.
Scott: Let's do a show on game.
Rym: You can open the gate.
Rym: We gotta watch it everyone.
Scott: Have we done?
Rym: There's no way on it.
Rym: I'll search anyway, but anyway Something else I found out.
Rym: this is directed by the same person who directed cheese sweet home.
Rym: It's got almost the exact same kind of pacing like a character will say something And they're a manga for polar bear cafe cuz he's sweet home as a manga.
Rym: This is why we're not anime world order.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, it does that thing.
Rym: We're like a scene will start and the characters are kind of just sitting there For a while and then someone says something and then the camera Stays there for a little while after it's very short on dialogue.
Scott: They don't say any words.
Scott: They don't have to say mitsuyuki masahara.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I did not know who that was until now.
Rym: Okay, but cheese sweet home.
Rym: I can see I'd also learned there's a sequel to cheese sweet home that I didn't know about.
Rym: cool I feel like I gotta get back into the anime loop.
Rym: nice a little bit.
Scott: So The other thing is the way the show works, right?
Scott: He's like, well the polar bear runs the cafe though It's some world that looks like modern-day Japan except there are normal people who are humans 100% just humans.
Scott: and there are animals.
Scott: and the animals aren't like furry animals where they like cat people.
Scott: They're just people.
Scott: It's just up.
Scott: It is a polar bear.
Scott: It wears clothes, but it is a polar bear.
Rym: I love the polar.
Scott: Is a panda.
Rym: love out at the zoo the interviews for a job.
Rym: That's like be a panda at right zoo.
Scott: But they these animals interact with society as if they are persons, right?
Scott: So even though it's you know Biologically a panda it talks it has I guess the equivalent of a social security card.
Scott: It has jobs and a house and money and you know, he doesn't have a job, right?
Scott: Well, I mean, but I mean it might as well be a person that is just biologically a panda with a human brain Capabilities.
Rym: so maybe we were talking about this when we watch the show.
Rym: Maybe it's all just people and these characters are being represented.
Scott: That's what I'm thinking.
Rym: is their spirit animal?
Scott: It's all.
Scott: it's actually all people literally.
Scott: but Instead of drawing the panda who as a person who has the spirit of a panda and acts like a panda?
Scott: So they draw him as a panda and call him panda, but it's really a person but it doesn't matter.
Scott: That's really a person.
Rym: that reality will be ruined in like episode 3 when the pole I'm sure someone randomly and then the show goes back to right.
Scott: so it's kind of funny.
Scott: He gets a job at the zoo Right, which and he has to like perform for the nursery school, but that other pan is a full-time panda.
Scott: Yeah, he was just a part-time zoo panda time panda.
Scott: Yeah, but it was funny.
Scott: was the nursery?
Scott: What the nursery school?
Scott: kids all seem to be human, right?
Scott: Did you didn't see any animals in nursery schools?
Rym: Don't go to school I don't know.
Scott: I was under the impression.
Scott: The panda was in school, but graduated and didn't want to work.
Scott: I don't know whatever.
Scott: Yes, it's cool.
Scott: how the animals the you know, it's sort of like Damaka dobutsu in which the animals express their nature.
Scott: The panda acts like a panda.
Scott: he's lazy and he wants to eat bamboo and that's it.
Rym: Yeah, but it's not like the polar bear because polar bears aren't necessarily known for their puns and cafes.
Scott: Maybe they are in Japan I don't know But I don't think I. the thing of the difference from Damaka dobutsu is Damaka dobutsu.
Scott: the animals are the opposite of their nature Right.
Scott: So the wolf was all you know, sappy or whatever right in this.
Scott: the animals match their nature, right?
Scott: So if there was a wolf in this you would be all eating people like a hey He's not there isn't?
Scott: I don't think.
Scott: what were the other animals?
Scott: it was a sloth, right?
Scott: Yep, and the polar bear.
Scott: and who was the guy who's always at the counter?
Scott: the I don't remember.
Scott: I don't remember just watched it.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Anyway, the animals the animals are like the best characters.
Rym: It's a cute show.
Scott: Yeah, very good.
Scott: Oh, right There's the whole part where he's interviewing animals for than everybody said all the animals match their nature so none of them were good for working at the Cafe.
Rym: so then he's like I've decided to hire this girl.
Scott: the human girl is the best worker for the cafe, of course But it's a cute show.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I like all three of these shows.
Scott: I'm kind of what eventually watch all these shows.
Scott: Yep, I'm gonna finish Lupin first and definitely that's a higher priority show.
Scott: But yeah, there's a lot suddenly right?
Scott: There's no big-name new awesome animes like Madoka unless there's one I don't notice happening right now.
Rym: I think we'd notice.
Rym: I mean remember when Madoka didn't notice.
Scott: Madoka tells 100% done.
Rym: Yeah, but we noticed.
Scott: I knew it was a giant thread in our forum.
Rym: I just didn't watch it, but I knew about it.
Rym: I knew that's the big anime that everyone's talking about, right?
Scott: So there doesn't seem to be a big anime right now a Madoka style that we want.
Scott: But there are plenty of good animes happening right now.
Scott: suddenly that are really smaller under-the-radar Animes that are good for people like us, but maybe not good for the anime community at large.
Scott: You're not gonna see polar bear cafe cosplay if I do.
Rym: Oh my gosh I think there will be but it'll be in the city.
Rym: It'll be like our crowd or Mike tools crowd Darryl's crowd.
Rym: Those people will dress up in a duffel.
Scott: Hey, you're not gonna see Japanese folktale cosplay.
Scott: Oh, you know dominating the conventions ahead of say the bleach cosplay, but I bleach.
Rym: I think you mean homestuck, right?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But anyway, there are these good under-the-radar small-time shows that are kind of awesome.
Scott: And if you really need an anime to watch and you really don't guess what they're all there's nothing.
Rym: you're all.
Scott: you can watch them Legally, yeah, you can watch all these things legally.
Scott: I think they're all on crunchy real kids in the slopus Crunchy roll Lupin is funimation.
Scott: All these all the rest of those are all crunchy roll.
Scott: Yeah free.
Rym: so If you really need it to anime, you know, it's an aside, but you know Like we talked about in the churn something that's happened.
Rym: Is that for?
Rym: Internet types.
Rym: anime has gotten pretty mainstream and that it a lot of people watch these shows.
Rym: a lot of people like anime.
Scott: Yeah people have enough.
Scott: people are watching these folk tales to where it's worth for a while for crunchy roll to pay to get the Rights to put it on crunchy roll and to sell ads on it.
Rym: But I think what what happened?
Rym: we talked about in the last show too, but specifically Most of the people are watching anime nowadays.
Rym: I don't think are engaged in anime fan culture.
Scott: Yeah I think there's people who go to crunchy roll who are watching these shows who are not going to cons not going on message boards Not reading anime news network not doing anything like that.
Scott: They're just going to crunchy roll and watching these shows.
Rym: I think there's a. I think there's three categories.
Rym: There's what you said and then there's the people who do those things and go to anime cons.
Rym: So they seem to be the minority at the anime cons now, but there's a third part.
Rym: I think there are people who do read anime news network and they engage in a lot of the online Stuff like.
Rym: they'll research anime.
Rym: They'll be into that stuff.
Rym: They'll post on the anime news network.
Rym: They just don't go to cons at all Because the cons have a lot less anime stuff than the internet does.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Homestuck is the best anime, right?
Rym: Yeah, yeah, well the most popular anime sure that in My Little Pony, yeah Okay, we're done.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.