Rym: Hey, it's Thursday December 13th 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight off the radar.
Rym: geeks and normal people.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I'm sitting in my office doing my thing.
Rym: I got balls.
Rym: I'll meek open and I'm like fucking around with an interface.
Rym: I'm working on for a thing that we're gonna do and One of my co-workers is like what the fuck is that smell?
Rym: and he starts walking around like you smell something really bad.
Scott: the bamboo No bamboo in your office.
Scott: There's are you sure?
Rym: I am so sure.
Scott: This is sounding like there's a bamboo in the future.
Scott: So feeling it about 30 seconds.
Scott: You're gonna say there was a bamboo.
Rym: So I ignore it.
Rym: cuz I'm working on stuff and I put my headphones back on.
Rym: Did you smell something?
Rym: I did not but I did not go to investigate People.
Rym: I go out to get lunch and I come back and as I walk into the office I'm like man.
Rym: our office smells like shit.
Scott: Well, you didn't smell the smell when you were leaving for lunch.
Rym: only when you came back I guess I had been.
Rym: either I had been immured in it and used to it or it did not exist in quantity yet.
Scott: So maybe someone pulled it out like someone spilled the bamboo.
Rym: so I can't.
Rym: there's no bamboo.
Rym: so I came back in the.
Rym: basically this escalates over time one by one.
Rym: people in the office now even like a bunch of People in a room and it's like three people have a conversation and then 20 minutes later Some guy says something related to
Scott: that someone with do and when you left for lunch They weren't there, but when you came back for lunch, they were there.
Rym: Nah, nothing like that.
Rym: So the smell is Pretty bad at this point.
Rym: So I'm like, alright I'm gonna find this because I it's starting to remind me of the smell of a mouse that has died in a wall.
Rym: So I start going around trying to narrow it down.
Scott: Did it smell like a bamboo?
Rym: It's not in the server room where I had just fucked with the HVAC system.
Rym: I wonder if maybe I'd end up killing a mouse in the ceiling with that, but no that was all fine.
Scott: You sure?
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure.
Rym: yeah, I'm you know, I already know the outcome of the story.
Rym: I Already that the fullness of this happened today.
Rym: I got my answer.
Rym: there was it was a. there is a time of worry Followed by a time of discovery and then a sign a time of gnosis.
Rym: So I'm walking around like the fuck.
Rym: I couldn't find it.
Rym: It seems stronger near the closet.
Rym: I'm like, aha, but then I opened the closet.
Rym: It's not that strong in there.
Rym: So I kind of back off and you know I got work to do.
Rym: since I see people I am in me.
Rym: So I go back to my desk and work a little bit and another co-worker comes back from lunch.
Rym: She's like what the fuck is that smell?
Rym: So he starts going around looking for it.
Rym: We can't find it.
Scott: So called a building guy.
Rym: yeah, the problem is I would suspect that it was something that was like we could find it in our office and the building wouldn't be happy if we're Like what the fuck is this smell.
Rym: and then the building guy comes.
Rym: he's like it's this garbage in your garbage can.
Rym: so Finally well one of my co-workers pulls out this cheese and He gots it to like eat it or something and suddenly the smell gets a thousand times work.
Scott: What was he doing with the cheese?
Scott: So we're gonna pull it out from a drawer.
Rym: So we're like How long have you had that cheese in the office?
Rym: and he's like.
Rym: I don't think this cheese is the source of the dead mouse smell and further Investigation turned out that it was in fact the source of the dead mouse.
Scott: What the fuck was he doing with this cheese?
Scott: And why did he not smell it?
Rym: It is a cheese that smells as far as I can tell like dead mouse by design.
Scott: Why was it not in the refrigerator or something?
Rym: Well, it was.
Rym: he was being transported like it was in a bag and like a cool pack or something.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It smelled like a fucking dead mouse and he's like, alright guys, we'll take it home with me.
Scott: So it won't bother you anymore now with that cheese and don't bring any more here again.
Rym: So then he's like, yeah, I'm taking the train to Connecticut.
Rym: Maybe I shouldn't bring this with me.
Rym: No, really.
Rym: So, I'm glad that I do not engage in the social contract of the kitchen of my office.
Rym: I do not use kitchen.
Rym: I do not use the fridge the cooking implements.
Scott: I fought to get a separate mini fridge just for the tech people and we have one now and I fought for that for years At my old company and they wouldn't give it to.
Scott: so now we don't have to deal with the fucking Disgusting fridge all these other people use.
Rym: why is every fridge like that?
Rym: So disgusting.
Rym: at one point I went in there like a month ago.
Scott: cuz you will get a food They put it at the leftover in there and they fucking leave it in there.
Scott: They never get it.
Rym: There was?
Scott: they buy a bamboo cheese.
Rym: There's the frozen spinach in the freezer that was there since before I got to the company.
Scott: It's still there.
Rym: Yeah, it's still there.
Scott: bought it when and why?
Rym: so I pulled it out one day.
Rym: I was like who the fuck bought this spinach and nobody in the entire company knows nobody would own up to it.
Scott: The someone did either.
Rym: It's someone who no longer works for throw it out the fucking window.
Rym: So I'm thinking about and then see who goes.
Scott: no my spinach that I got ya.
Rym: So I'm thinking I gotta do something with the spice bomb because it would be great if that spinach was like some other Companies thing.
Rym: like some guy in an office next door found this spinach.
Rym: He's like what the fuck and he just put it in our office.
Rym: I want to take the spice bomb and like put it in someone's freezer.
Rym: It has to be someone who doesn't listen to GeekNights.
Scott: You do whatever you want with this.
Scott: still gotta do something with the spice bomb Put it on someone's porch and set it on fire.
Rym: if I had I was gonna leave it as Scott Johnson's house after the party.
Rym: cuz then you brought it there.
Rym: No But I'd imagine that you know, he has this huge party.
Rym: It ends these cleaning up and he's like it really smells like spice.
Rym: and then he finds the spice bomb.
Scott: You should move out of here and just leave it behind.
Rym: What would you think if you were like cleaning up your apartment one day?
Rym: And like I don't know in your comics like at the bottom of your comic shelf like behind some comics There was just a spice bomb.
Scott: There was an EGM.
Rym: I Have not found an EGM in this apartment yet.
Scott: Oh, it's interesting.
Rym: Just saying that's interest just saying Okay enough inside jokes yummy news.
Rym: Thursday after all it's.
Scott: The Google Maps for iPhone came out today.
Rym: So iPhones actually have a real mapping application.
Scott: Actually, you know there were a whole bunch of them and they were all adequate.
Scott: But now the new Google Master iPhone is if you were curious Better than every other map on any mobile device ever used ever except no biking direction.
Rym: See the thing is that is only one flaw.
Rym: I suspect that is partly driven by the fact that you had a pretty slow crappy GPS on your previous phone.
Rym: because I remember one time we were out and we both opened up our phones and I realized that your phone takes like a full minute to find his GPS.
Scott: No, it's apparently that's entirely software based because some programs the GPS goes like and the new Google Maps the GPS goes like BAM.
Scott: So it's not anything to do with the hardware.
Scott: It's the software is shitty.
Scott: Yeah I'm saying the old my old Google Maps is BAM always has been well the one I have now is BAM And the only problem is no biking directions BAM, which is the only flaw which is something that most people don't give a shit about But I do.
Rym: it actually matters a lot.
Scott: But in all other ways it is a perfect map thingy.
Rym: Sometimes slashdot was like Google really should have waited on this because this was actually one thing that an Android phone did way better Aside from not being extra proprietary.
Rym: Mmm, and now there's no longer that advantage.
Rym: I think there were at least one or two people Not that that matters, you know one or two out of how many millions who were like You know what?
Rym: I care about maps more than I care about iPhone.
Scott: Well, I saw really interesting that if you do that you buy a GPS or thing, right?
Scott: They still make those those things suck You get none of you buy this ultra high-end one.
Rym: No, they still suck ass.
Rym: You know why those things are not useful for for the kinds of things?
Rym: I use my phone GPS for like.
Rym: I'm in a random neighborhood in the city and I want to figure out what restaurants nearby Or get a biking direction from like the Bowery to a weird place in Brooklyn or Jersey.
Scott: We should make a bike specific thing.
Rym: Yes, we should because I want nothing more than Actually, I was looking.
Rym: I'm thinking about getting a mount so I can mount my phone like a little - on my bike.
Scott: I've seen those.
Rym: The reason I want it is that one.
Rym: I'm playing ingress more and more and I have to be able to look at the screen While I'm biking to find the portals and fuck people's shit up
Scott: and
Rym:  When I bike a very long distance like way outside of New York City, I kind of need the navigation Mmm, and I have more than once dropped my phone if I'm trying to hold it in my hand while I'm biking at speed.
Scott: I have never done that.
Scott: Never dropped the phone.
Rym: Nah, anyway anyway, so In the news, I guess the lounge I wanted to link to this thing.
Rym: It's a bunch of pictures from the subway and when I say the subway, I mean The new line they're making in the seven.
Scott: Why don't you just already become like the full trainer to go hang out with those train guys?
Rym: See, here's the thing.
Rym: I'm super.
Rym: I mean you remember in Beacon like I did all that research and learned all about that abandoned Why don't you just go full on?
Rym: In fact, I remember one time you were trying to argue with me that that line that that third Track and next to the train station with that abandoned platform did not in fact connect to the old line that goes to Danbury.
Rym: And I did a lot of research to prove you wrong.
Rym: I for some reason just got really into that.
Rym: I found all those old stations.
Rym: I Can't go full trainer now because as much as I like the tracks and as much as I like the routes I don't give a shit about the actual trains.
Rym: I just don't care and I would be a pariah in that community.
Rym: But this is great.
Rym: This is pictures of the subway and It's pictures of the subway that they're making now.
Rym: So it looks the same as the normal subways like it's the inside of a subway tunnel But it's before they turned on the piss sprayers and the rat generators.
Rym: There's no grime.
Rym: It's so weird to see what the New York City subway would look like if it had no grime That I'm almost dumbfounded by these pictures.
Rym: Okay So hopefully by summer of 2014 now that we don't go to the New York Comic Con anymore We'll be able to take the seven train to the Javits.
Rym: that will probably never enter again for the rest of our lives Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway in the lounge, it's things of the day and the GeekNights lounge on Thursday.
Scott: so You know, there's a lot of old DOS games out in the world, right?
Scott: And the thing with old DOS games is that pretty much you can't get an old DOS computer.
Scott: DOSBox Yeah, but DOSBox while good while very good is not perfect.
Rym: Most of the problems I found with DOSBox come from the fact that very few people left on earth Know how DOS works.
Rym: true I mean I know how to get the drivership Sorted out if I get a weird game like even if I install free DOS and I somehow find of working 486.
Scott: Get you know, it's not easy to get a game running on there.
Scott: So what do you do?
Scott: Well, someone wrote this thing that is actually Somewhat of a better solution than anything I've seen.
Scott: and what this is?
Scott: it's called M script in, right?
Scott: You might know that JavaScript is a subset Of EN script.
Scott: is the or ECMA script or whatever.
Scott: It's called, right?
Scott: So what this thing does is it takes what is known as LLVM bitcode and converts it to?
Scott: JavaScript.
Scott: so if you have any if you have a program written in C or C plus plus you can compile it using LLVM GCC or clang which will output a binary which runs in the LLVM.
Scott: If you don't know what that is, don't worry about it.
Scott: All you have to know all you have to know.
Scott: if you know what that means You're gonna be like, oh, if you don't know what that means You're gonna be like, oh, all it means is if you have the C code for anything you can compile it Get a file run that file through this em script in thing and it will output a JavaScript and then you can get that program To run in a box on a web page.
Scott: So here is an example.
Scott: If you go to play - dune.com slash Harkonnen It's dune - in a box on a web page exactly as it was on MS-DOS 100% identical with everything working audio works graphics work.
Scott: every did might as well be Fucking DOS there.
Scott: it is The first RTS that there ever was as far as most people know.
Scott: Sort of the same way the astro was the first anime.
Scott: This is the first RTS.
Scott: So for historical reasons check it out And if you have this C code to any old-ass programs that no one can fucking run you should try to compile that shit with a modern compiler
Rym: and
Scott: Then try to run it through the em script it and make a little web page so people can use it because I'll be awesome.
Scott: Not too shabby not shabby at all.
Rym: So In the spirit of linking to YouTube channels that are hilarious.
Rym: There is a new YouTube channel.
Rym: This is my thing of the day.
Rym: Great.
Rym: It is meeper fish and the headlining video is this little thing of Pikachu versus Trubbish?
Scott: I don't know if Trubbish is a real Pokemon.
Rym: I don't know if Trubbish is a real Pokemon or not.
Rym: cuz I'm looking it up.
Rym: I really only know the OG.
Scott: I'm looking it up.
Rym: Really don't care about Pokemon beyond that except Bidoof.
Scott: I'm loading up the Bulbapedia and and the CeraVe.
Scott: Bibarel mostly Bidoof Trubbish real Pokemon.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Okay Is the truth?
Scott: number 568 poison types has abilities hem Stench.
Scott: if the Pokemon makes physical contact with the opponent.
Scott: There's a chance the opponent flinches.
Scott: Nah, sticky hold the Pokemon's item cannot be taken.
Scott: Hidden ability available.
Scott: aftermath the foe that dealt the final hit loses a quarter of its maximum HP if the move made.
Scott: physical contact.
Scott: classification trash bag Pokemon.
Rym: Wow Okay Yeah, so this channel is pretty funny.
Rym: It evolves.
Rym: She has a series.
Rym: What's it?
Rym: evolve into?
Rym: Garbodor Are you sure this isn't a joke?
Scott: I'm sure.
Scott: stench weak armor aftermath.
Scott: It's a trash heap Pokemon.
Scott: Oh my god Look at this motherfucker Garbodor.
Rym: ha I Guess it's a modern sort of coughing wheezing 569.
Scott: No, these are poison types.
Scott: I guess those I guess those are poison types - I don't fucking know.
Rym: But anyway, she has a series called adventures and food service and another series called adventures in retail and they're just cute somewhat full of truth and somewhat hilarious.
Scott: Garbodor Trubbish good God if anyone seeks Trubbish you're gonna lose.
Rym: I can't win.
Scott: I'll just set your fucking Trubbish on fire.
Rym: And in the meta moment the GeekNights book club book is The Great Gatsby.
Rym: Yep, you should read it Probably not gonna do show on it till sometime early next year because we're busy with stuff.
Rym: We launched a new show GeekNights presents.
Rym: you can see that in the YouTube channel.
Rym: We're talking about shoujo kakamei.
Rym: You can see me like it.
Rym: I don't know fucking why people like it But you guys spread the word around.
Rym: cuz I'm gonna say this we're gonna keep doing it But we're not gonna speed up.
Rym: how often we do it unless it starts getting a lot of views.
Rym: Cuz I like doing it but I don't like doing it enough to not go skiing every weekend.
Rym: But if if you get these videos into the tens of thousands of views Yeah We're looking at only some hundreds of views you get them into the tens of thousands We will knock this shit out faster than you can imagine.
Scott: It's only a few hundred views each.
Scott: That's not really So.
Rym: if you are a fan of GeekNights presents and want us to keep doing content like that It is your duty to get other people to watch it.
Rym: if they do not watch it and the view counts do not go up We'll keep doing it just like we keep doing GeekNights, but we're not gonna.
Rym: we're not gonna go full-on.
Rym: I could go all out and we got some other projects in the hopper that are ready to go, but Not working on them unless GeekNights presents takes off.
Scott: you should also go to all the places we are on the internet like YouTube and Facebook and Twitter and follow us and join us and Subscribe us and all those things.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: G+ and You should also go to MAGFest.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: mag fest is coming up right after the new year at the Gaylord in DC.
Rym: Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday, we'll be there all four days.
Rym: We're doing three events.
Rym: We're on two panels.
Rym: We're moderating a video game ethics.
Rym: We are panelists on I believe video game genres and we are presenting beyond.
Rym: candy land should work.
Scott: I'll work on that during the week where I don't have any work between Christmas and New Year's.
Rym: Right share that document and I will also work.
Rym: Yeah, see we're planning stuff right here.
Rym: live on the air.
Rym: That's how we do this.
Rym: write our panel a few weeks before the con One week granted.
Rym: we already wrote this panel.
Rym: We're basically just rewriting it because when we wrote this panel, you might have seen a lot of new games out there.
Rym: More importantly you might have seen beyond candy land.
Rym: We've come a long way in the last like, I don't know.
Rym: five years They're doing lectures.
Scott: So yeah At the very least make the slides look better and very important.
Rym: Connecticut me and Scott along with a new member of our directorial board Kristen run the panels and workshops and special events department for Connecticut a Surprisingly large as in much larger than you'd expect it to be Massively multi-genre convention in Hartford, Connecticut next year is gonna be July 12 13th and 14th
Scott: the week before PAX OS.
Rym: Yes, and we're going to pack sauce.
Rym: So awesome.
Rym: But you might think but Rym why are you talking about a convention in July?
Scott: It's December You were talking about like pecs prime 2013.
Rym: Well listener, I'm talking about it because panel and workshop and lecture submissions are now live.
Scott: Are they actually working properly with a form that doesn't suck?
Rym: they appear to be.
Rym: I'm going to.
Rym: If the email that it's supposed to send out when you submit one that tells you we got it
Scott: Send in a test submission
Rym: I'm going to put in a real submission because we also do panels and it's much easier for me to schedule them if I put them in through the same interface as All the people do.
Rym: good idea.
Scott: I should submit some.
Rym: I'll schedule you at like midnight in the annex on Monday.
Rym: Anyway, so if you would like to do a panel workshop lecture special event anything at Connecticut Which is a pretty fucking awesome con we had 230 something panels last year.
Scott: We're gonna have more this year.
Rym: We're gonna have less because I'm gonna get rid of one of the rooms and have more bigger fewer rooms some of which are.
Scott: Hopefully we'll see how that plan goes.
Scott: The layout is not set in stone yet.
Scott: We are fighting.
Rym: The reason I bring this up now is that we are going to be so far ahead of schedule this year that we're going to Start scheduling panels and workshops after magfest at the end of January Meaning you can keep submitting up and through like April or something.
Rym: I forget what the deadline is, but we're gonna start scheduling stuff.
Rym: So if you submit an awesome panel and you submit it in, you know, March I might have already scheduled all the good slots.
Rym: I'm not gonna bump something.
Rym: I already scheduled for you.
Rym: No matter how good you are Let's see the guest which you're not and we're also gonna make the schedule public.
Rym: once we start scheduling things You're gonna see panels like.
Scott: you're gonna see it constantly changing all the time.
Scott: Yeah, things moving around jumping around.
Rym: It's gonna be awesome.
Rym: We're a ConnectiCon.
Rym: if you went to get out of con last year We uh, there was a huge up stepping of the game We had so many was ridiculous.
Rym: the difference between ConnectiCon 2011 and 2012?
Rym: It was ridiculous.
Rym: the difference between ConnectiCon 2010 and 2011 2013 is going to be just as different from 2012 as 2012 was from 2011.
Scott: Yeah, the convention that improves doesn't just do the same thing over and over again.
Rym: I would've can't hit out a cat out a cat every other kind except packs every other kid.
Rym: It's the lounge.
Rym: we can talk about whatever we want here.
Rym: Why do you hate the lounge so much?
Scott: Why do you love the lounge so much?
Scott: I Feeling this is a male strip lounge.
Scott: That's why you love it.
Rym: So I would like to make Thursday episodes much more freeform and kind of just go for it Rather than having to like force myself to do a news.
Rym: Just be like, hey, it's Thursday.
Scott: What are you gonna talk about?
Rym: same kind of stuff?
Rym: We're talking about right now.
Scott: Okay, whatever.
Rym: So I I've run into this sort of.
Rym: I can't necessarily say it's a problem because it doesn't affect me and in fact in some ways it's good for me, but I interact especially now that we live in New York with a lot of nerds of various different stripes and a lot of normal and a
Scott: conventions as well
Rym: at conventions at places at meetups at events and It amazes me how many people I run into who are one?
Rym: Not old or like having some sort of like obvious reason why they would not be connected to things.
Rym: Two are really into something pretty specific Like video games.
Scott: what are more specific things that are nerdy?
Rym: three?
Rym: Seem to have no idea that any information about said thing exists on the internet or that anyone else in the world likes those guys Or for has any concept of the fact that there are other people in this thing or in any way related to this thing.
Rym: And it happened so often that I all I I kind of want to talk about it and think about all the people who are The same situation.
Scott: we just haven't met them or there did.
Scott: they don't go to conventions They don't go to meetups or go on there.
Rym: They're like under under the radar, right?
Rym: So it's like a good example is nerd NYC.
Rym: We hang out with them.
Rym: We go to their board game nights.
Rym: I go to the recesses occasionally, but when I first go like new people would show up.
Rym: They're like, hey, let's play some board games But they're super into board games and already there's a hint of desperation.
Scott: Right, but it's clear.
Scott: There's somewhat connected because they found nerd NYC on the internet.
Scott: They showed up to it.
Scott: They know about board games.
Scott: They're here to play them.
Scott: They maybe even know some of the other people there Right and they live in New York.
Scott: Yep So not completely disconnected, but they shelter NYC and they just don't know of anything else that exists in the board game world.
Scott: Maybe they never gone to board game geek.
Scott: Maybe they never heard of packs.
Scott: Maybe they never know any conventions at all.
Rym: It's never.
Rym: just one thing.
Rym: It's that I'll be talking to some random person, you know They're really into board games and they'll sell.
Rym: they'll tell me some ridiculous rumor Like.
Rym: I heard there's a sequel to settlers coming out called and they make something up Like I'm trying to.
Rym: the Star Trek settlers is coming out so I can't use that.
Scott: Is that really?
Scott: Yeah I'm looking that up right now.
Rym: So Star Wars settlers.
Rym: I heard it's coming and that's not coming.
Rym: That doesn't exist.
Scott: Are you fucking kidding me?
Scott: Star Trek Catan?
Scott: What the fuck.
Rym: but these like they'll bring up a piece of social currency like hey have you heard about X?
Scott: I think it's out out not coming out.
Rym: Yeah, I saw some pictures of people playing.
Rym: so settlers is going to be the monopoly of our generation in terms of being matched up with everything in a Superficial manner.
Scott: you just go get settlers of Canaan and play that and never play any others.
Rym: Yeah Settlers of your mom.
Rym: Yeah But so they'll They'll.
Rym: I don't know if they make it up or what but the kinds of news that I get out of these disconnected nerds is identical to the kind of news I would get out of kids in the days before the internet who would literally just make shit up about video games.
Scott: And the thing I first time I ever recognized this problem was at that anime next to and to the only anime next.
Scott: you went To and our friend Ian levenstein did a Nintendo panel and it was a filled up room because the Wii was about to come out.
Scott: it was just before the Wii was coming out and People are you know.
Scott: he talked about all this stuff and basically everything He said was something that I had read on Kotaku or joystick or some in gadget or some gaming site.
Scott: You know he didn't have any more information than we do.
Scott: he doesn't work for Nintendo or anything.
Scott: I think his girlfriend works for Pokemon, but it's not like she knew anything either.
Scott: right, so You know I don't remember if she was there.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: what does the matter?
Scott: the point is most of the we've talked about this on the show before probably in the anime next episode Where the people in the audience didn't know this stuff, and they asked him questions.
Scott: I guess thinking he knew something or was somehow a Nintendo employee or had special information All he had was the same information I had reading on the internet me and him Where I could have done that panel because I knew the same things he did.
Rym: because I read websites now before you say oh Isolated phenomena you know it's anecdotal evidence.
Rym: It's an anime account.
Rym: well Yeah We we've been at other conventions doing panels and the same thing happens to us like remember that we did that panel On Advance Wars as those kids are like.
Rym: so when's the next Advance Wars coming out?
Rym: We're like.
Rym: We don't know.
Rym: we don't work for Nintendo.
Rym: They're like how is this part design.
Rym: We don't know.
Rym: we don't work for Nintendo.
Scott: Yeah, we didn't.
Scott: what do you think this is?
Rym: and they kept asking questions like that after our answer continued to buy.
Scott: But see those questions are the problem of not knowing who's on stage.
Scott: the other questions like you know how many?
Scott: Controllers are the we come with?
Scott: it's like that.
Scott: you could just read that fucking shit on Wikipedia Or in gadget or if you've been following the news at all you would know exactly what comes with it And what the software is gonna look like.
Scott: and all this stuff would not be a mystery or a secret whatsoever.
Rym: But it goes deeper than that.
Rym: like a lot of the gamer people I meet have it's very even video game people who like play Xbox games online And listen to like fast karate like they're like video games are my thing.
Rym: and yet They've never heard of packs or penny arcade Ever never heard.
Rym: I've met people at gaming cons who have never heard of the concept of a webcomic.
Rym: I Was talking to a dude about packs.
Rym: he's like packs.
Rym: I'm again the penny arcade expose this giant video game convention, and he's like video game conventions.
Rym: What what goes on at those?
Rym: and I was like Play video games.
Rym: Do you other people have you ever had penny arcades like what's penny arcade?
Rym: Do you like?
Rym: it's a webcomic?
Rym: Do you even read and he's like webcomic what you mean like a comic on the internet, and I'm like Yeah.
Rym: But the fact that you asked that leads me to worry about the direction and future of this conversation.
Rym: But yet that dude was the biggest fan of that guy with the glasses in the world Mmm, so I think what's happening here is We're not talking about the people who don't know anything and are connected to anything.
Scott: well I mean because the fact is those people probably do exist in probably a large number.
Scott: some guy really fucking loves video games But just isn't connected, but we don't know that guy.
Scott: we can't find him, but these are people who have access to Everything right.
Scott: there's really like they're slightly connected.
Scott: It's like they've hooked in to one or maybe two communities, but they do not branch for those communities at all.
Scott: It's like this is whole internet out there.
Scott: But they went on the internet the first day and they found I guess that guy with the glasses right and they put their hooks In and all they do now is go to that guy with the glasses, and that's it.
Scott: They don't go anywhere else.
Rym: people go to our forum.
Scott: They don't know anything else exists, right?
Scott: They don't you know, but the people on our forum.
Scott: It's clear that they go elsewhere because they're constantly posting links to other things all over the internet.
Scott: So they're finding and digging from all their other communities right some people in our farm.
Scott: That's true, but you know who you are me You know I go to lots of.
Scott: I go to everywhere in the Internet's right so it's like.
Scott: But there's other people's like.
Scott: they just pick one thing and they stay there And they don't even think of look at anywhere else or learning and they don't search for things They don't read things and it's like.
Rym: so think about this.
Rym: It's interesting.
Scott: You're really interested in tabletop RPGs.
Scott: Why aren't you going out and looking at every major?
Scott: Tabletop RPG site every day of your life?
Scott: if that is your thing that is your jam.
Scott: Why are you not eating your jam now?
Rym: I think what they're doing is they go to they find a site and they've net like.
Rym: remember the first time we saw The ninja the guy who did the ninja advice.
Rym: ask a ninja ask a ninja.
Rym: That was the most hilarious shit ever for a few episodes, but even then we recognized immediately Oh, this is basically the same shtick as strong bad and homestar runner.
Scott: Yeah, only the you know.
Rym: so we enjoyed a little bit.
Rym: But we'd been zebra storyteller when we originally found the source of this to remove the zebra storyteller situation Where the first time we saw a strong bad email.
Rym: it was the funniest thing in the world.
Rym: It would be like if when we encounter one of those peak internet or media experiences we decided that that was the end.
Rym: Imagine if today's God we just followed the homestar runner run all I guess when nothing else And the only internet things we knew about were things that people in the homestar on all community linked to.
Rym: So how is this happening in an age where you have access to everything?
Rym: I mean we live through the era when porn would just appear whether you wanted to see it or not on a computer.
Rym: We live through the era of pop-up ads coming and going.
Rym: I mean I know what an x10 camera is.
Rym: With all this information.
Rym: How are there people who will sort of?
Rym: advocate all media filtration to one entity, but they don't even relegate it to like an Aggregator like it's not.
Rym: these people aren't like.
Rym: I just go to FARC and that's all my news.
Rym: They at relegate it to the community around something like that Like they'll really like the only learn about internet things from the forum about that guy with the glasses.
Rym: How do you get to be that person?
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I think maybe you know on one hand, right?
Scott: We sort of have a problem where we Internet so much that we need more novelty and the.
Scott: what is it?
Scott: The serotonin?
Scott: is it dopamine or serotonin?
Scott: I think it's serotonin there the brain chemicals that make you feel good.
Scott: We need all those right and we are pretty much dulled on those because we've been pounding our brains with them.
Scott: for you know Forever we go.
Rym: we get the shakes if we don't have our fix of novelty exactly.
Scott: So if I go to one internet community, you know, I freaking drain that motherfucker The same way that like, you know a frat guy empties the keg all on his own.
Scott: He's like where he's not even drunk.
Scott: He's like, where's the more now?
Rym: I'm better than I was in our IT when I had jobs or I didn't do anything.
Scott: yeah, I'm much of it.
Rym: but the point is sit there reading FARC and I considered paying for total FARC or Or going through the initiation to join ultra FARC just to get more novelty.
Scott: The point is I go to Reddit and it's up all purple links.
Scott: So I go to our forum and there's nothing that no new posts.
Scott: So I'll go to Twitter and there's no new posts and I'll go right.
Scott: so I keep going, you know I'm like, I've read everything and all the things.
Scott: I'm gonna go check out Y Combinator.
Scott: I'm gonna go check out Google News.
Scott: I'm gonna go and I eventually I Circle around and I got a lot of play go to Boing Boing and I'll go.
Scott: I just eat going to places More and more places to find more and more new things.
Scott: and it takes a while before I can circle around to the beginning.
Rym: I think of this.
Rym: take the big aggregators.
Rym: if you follow even one of those You'll get like 80% of this stuff.
Rym: Like if you follow like Kotaku, you'll know the penny arcade expo exists.
Scott: The other thing that I do is when I get one of these places, right?
Scott: I fucking branch, you know It's like if I hit.
Scott: you know Boing Boing and there's like a one post and it's about something I can probably find like three related YouTube videos and two Wikipedia articles and something and two other things to that link from that.
Scott: so I can fully absorb all the information related to that post to Get it in its fullness.
Scott: Right, and that's where things of the day and news has come from but even some people in our forum are talking about how?
Rym: Like on reddit people will repost content into reddit Because they know that the people in reddit won't even bother clicking on the link to go read something somewhere else.
Scott: in many cases I don't get it.
Rym: or if they follow a link It seems like the people who are disconnected will literally do the opposite of what you said.
Rym: They'll follow a link to a pay an endpoint a page.
Rym: Whatever that page is is as far as they will ever go in following further links.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I'm desperate to find new shit.
Scott: So I'll follow links to like, you know Dead end of some interesting sort of things.
Rym: like if you go to any random internet forum community You'll see the same set of like 15 threads of people asking these kind of Basic life questions and getting different answers depending on whatever.
Rym: can that?
Scott: yeah, that's the one thing I notice all the time.
Scott: right is like, you know, let's say you have I don't know.
Scott: Let's try mine.
Rym: Here's the example.
Scott: So you go to the Minecraft forums right like?
Scott: not, you know Because it's like every friggin forum in the world has a Minecraft thread, right?
Scott: But there's only one minecraft communities.
Scott: you go to the minecraft community and what thread are you gonna see?
Scott: There's some guy saying hey guys, you know let's talk about tabletop RPGs and all the people who are playing minecraft in the minecraft community or hardcore minecraft people who also like tabletop RPGs will post in that thread as opposed to You know in an off-topic area as opposed to also opening up in a new tab some sort of tabletop RPG community.
Scott: it's like they can only be in one community for some reason and They're gonna anything that they care about in their lives because most people I hope care about more than one thing and not just Silver Age spider-man.
Scott: Well, but they don't want to be in more than one community.
Scott: So anything else they care about in their lives They will post about in that forum that they're in now.
Scott: This is a prize opposed to getting more forums.
Rym: This is a problem for a separate reason that I've found that people who are in those communities are also extremely xenophobic when it comes to Information coming in.
Rym: that is not from one of them.
Rym: Mmm like I don't really post on reddit that much but once I Posted a link to a relevant video on this particular subreddit.
Rym: That was about like mechanism design and RPGs Like there's people talking about like how role-playing games can guide players.
Rym: So I posted a link to our video on the lecture about just that.
Rym: Downvoted to all.
Rym: fuck.
Rym: not because it was self-promotion because I posted it there but had not engaged sufficiently with the conversation In the community outside of that thread.
Scott: Beforehand, I noticed that that sort of thing happens when there's a. it's like depends the size of the community for that kind of behavior.
Scott: Right because if you it's it and it also the right because you look at say a big community.
Scott: There was a thing going down in the red the hockey reddit yesterday where people were voting up these sort of like pictures of ice girls because there's nothing else to Post and I was down voting all of them, right?
Scott: Cuz it's like I don't want.
Scott: you know, not that they're not hot but that's not appropriate for it.
Scott: It's supposed to be about hockey.
Scott: put that in the you know, the hot girls subreddit or something You know.
Scott: take that out of here And like there was you know, if you look vote wise There are a lot of people out there who vote and never comment.
Scott: there was so that there's a lot of people in that subreddit.
Scott: So this thing had a lot of up votes and it was up there, but he looked at the comments.
Scott: There were some people who were like, hey, this is good.
Scott: You guys should keep it up.
Scott: But most of the comments were like, yeah, let's get this stuff out of here.
Scott: The people who are more does, you know, depending on their level of involvement.
Rym: based on statistics from our own forum It appears that the vast majority people who go to our forum lurk never post but read it religiously.
Scott: Yeah, don't do that.
Scott: You should be if you want to be a modern connected person.
Scott: Who's awesome.
Scott: You need to post and create and get involved in all the places.
Rym: so what I was gonna get out here is that I Only engage in one forum community nerd NYC.
Rym: I post like once a month to say I will or will not attend this event.
Scott: I don't even do that.
Rym: I otherwise don't post and every time I log in there's like a million p.m.
Rym: Is for me.
Rym: I'm like really?
Rym: You can't find me on the rest of the internet.
Rym: I don't post content anywhere into into any forum or community Except my own GeekNights.
Rym: Come here.
Scott: I mean, no, you mean you're making.
Rym: you don't post content, right but your comments or anything, but The majority of my stuff like that.
Rym: I post publicly to things like Twitter Mm-hmm, and that's where all my sort of comments are and all my things like that are.
Rym: Then the point is you post in on a regular basis.
Scott: The point is you're still involved in posting things on the internet and communicating with people and getting together with people You know and at least some places It's weird if you just read things on the internet You'd never create anything or share anything or say anything or you know, it's like come on.
Scott: But I was saying about the sizes of the community.
Scott: right when a community is a smaller right though You know it that vocal group, you know the group that's really into it is mostly going to control things Especially if there's some sort of voting mechanism, right?
Scott: So in your example of posting the our video it was downvoted and probably a smaller Subreddit where those people who had those sort of community ideas of who are you here will vote you down.
Scott: if you had been in a larger Subreddit face mob the faceless mob would ten.
Scott: who doesn't you know care about or even know about those things because they're not In the community really?
Scott: they're just like reading and content would vote things up or down based on whether they liked it or not.
Scott: So in those cases you get like a fistful of downvotes from the people who are way into it and a mountain of upvotes Just because it's content that they like.
Scott: they see it.
Scott: They see a JPEG they go, haha And they click up right.
Scott: and all those people who are you know?
Scott: Who are into it are the only people who are gonna bother to look at who posted the JPEG who they are and think about Other reasons into their voting as opposed to just quickly voting, you know an example
Rym: of all this stuff that I ran into recently work Right.
Rym: I'm trying to fix the AC in this like kind of isolated server room.
Rym: So at one point just to make sure that what I decided to do was correct.
Rym: I googled for something.
Rym: I'll google for it right now and hopefully the same thing will happen.
Scott: I'd yet a lot of you'll just don't fucking Google.
Rym: so I need to know a thing.
Rym: So I let's see air-conditioned sealed room.
Rym: Sealed room All right.
Rym: link number one THC forum community for growing in marijuana.
Rym: Okay link number two a separate Marijuana growing community.
Rym: I guess three a third completely independent marijuana girl there.
Rym: every link on the front page I guess people they say isn't?
Rym: we'd probably need air-conditioned sealed rooms, but No, I'm not really amazed at the fact that that is every link.
Rym: It's when I search for this thing.
Rym: I'm amazed that every one of these links goes to a completely separate marijuana community.
Scott: now I'm not saying right I agree.
Scott: I see where you're going, but there shouldn't be just one weed community.
Rym: What I'm saying is I see this on the internet everywhere that like RPGs.
Rym: There's like 10 or 15 forums Let's say they're all about indie tabletop RPGs and every one of them has the same 11 threads And every one of them is the same shit.
Rym: answers in those to 11 threads all from different people.
Scott: Yeah and if you none of those people had bothered to Google their question to find the thread on one of the other forums before I Therefore into a lot of these forums.
Rym: the answers are straight-up wrong.
Rym: None of the people in these communities know anything about air conditioning.
Rym: Yet they all give these answers and ask these crazy Ridiculous questions that it's like they don't understand basic physics.
Rym: one guy's like yeah You could just put a. get one of those portable air conditioners disconnect the hoses You know the tubes that vent the air out to the exhaust and just put it in the room.
Scott: No, you can't.
Rym: no that'll hit the room up you pig fucker.
Scott: But anyway But this is this is a problem that stack overflow and stack exchange has tried to solve with the question answer thing specifically.
Rym: But the people who have this problem the most never go to those sites exactly.
Scott: So they those sites are really good because number one if you go to them You're good, right and they have communities that form around them as well.
Scott: Oh my god, but they've done a very clever thing and that every stack exchange site has a meta.
Scott: So all of that community bullshit is separated out from the actual question-answer part that everyone sees Into a backlot that where you have to specifically engage there.
Scott: So it's sort of like a little segregation and it works really well.
Scott: the main problem with that is if you're a googler you someone who has the reflex to Google something and you Google a question and It exists on a stack exchange site.
Scott: You will find it as in a top Google result, which is really good.
Rym: Also, but these people's first instinct seems to be go to it, you know in the real world Hang out at all the time and ask my friend exactly some guy who's really into weed.
Scott: That's his number.
Scott: one thing is in that weed form that big popular one You just found right and he wants to ask a question about Minecraft.
Scott: doesn't go to the Minecraft community Doesn't find the Minecraft stack exchange doesn't Google it.
Scott: He goes to his weed is for him with all his weed friends and says hey guys Anyone play Minecraft?
Scott: anyone know the recipe to build a diamond pick?
Scott: I saw this guy had one yo, and it's like Dude, you didn't even need to ask that in you.
Scott: and not only did you not need to ask that you could have googled it And find it out in two seconds.
Scott: You asked it in a weed forum Even though that's your place.
Scott: Okay, so you're better with your.
Rym: One of these is not a weed forum.
Rym: It's the Anand tech hardware and technology forum.
Rym: Okay, so in the sub forum under hardware and technology, there is the highly technical forum Mmm, and the post here.
Rym: I'm gonna read it in its entirety.
Scott: This is in the highly technical form Put the air conditioner in the middle of the room with the whole.
Rym: how does sealed air condition room get oxygen so we not suffocate?
Rym: Hi all I always wonder how hotel rooms get oxygen in the rooms that people don't suffocate it.
Rym: They sealed two doors and windows.
Rym: the air condition in there does not have.
Rym: yes It's a fucking side in like first time window unit that option you can turn fresh air over.
Scott: So what hotel is he staying in with bulkhead fucking doors like car air condition?
Rym: do those air condition regenerate oxygen?
Rym: I hope some engineer can coming and provide answer.
Rym: Thank you and The rest of the thread is a big debate about this.
Scott: So I Mean look at look at our forum.
Scott: For example, right?
Scott: You know, we're we're technology people.
Scott: we talk about technology But there's a thread in our forum where people ask for like technology help with their computer doesn't work.
Scott: It's like get that shit the fuck out of here, right?
Scott: It's like come on go.
Scott: that answer is elsewhere on the internet.
Scott: This is not the place, you know.
Scott: I mean we talk about a lot of different stuff on our forum because we cover a lot of topics and you shouldn't just talk About GeekNights there.
Scott: That would be dumb and weird.
Scott: but a lot of stuff like that is sort of like don't you know how to Internet?
Scott: there's more websites than just this one and they're much they're going to.
Scott: you know Even if I could answer you and I probably could or I could help you.
Scott: You will get much better help and much better answers if you go to fucking Stack Overflow or something.
Rym: Here's what things going on.
Rym: these people for whatever reason.
Rym: there is something that causes certain people and it's not just a generational thing because as people who are our age and younger There's like a subset of those people who just don't connect to things on the internet and there's a subset of people who do in the land.
Rym: We noticed this when we were at RIT anime but we didn't realize the importance of it because back then we ran the anime club and One you know the booze the biggest club on campus.
Rym: it was huge and we had crazy like posters all over campus every week these big dance parties and social nights and all this bullshit.
Rym: and At the end of one school year We met someone who was like, oh my god, you guys are into anime man.
Rym: I wish there were other people in school her into anime than just us and we were like, uh Anime clubs the biggest club on campus.
Scott: Did you not notice the posters we hang up everywhere in the entire school every week?
Rym: and he was like How was I supposed to know there was an anime club?
Scott: How would I?
Scott: did you even think to type in like RIT anime into Google?
Scott: Did you even think to look at the signs on the wall all over the fucking when I told that did you read any of the?
Scott: Documentation that the school gave you about clubs that guy didn't know fan subs existed?
Scott: Yeah, I didn't either when I got to alright, but he's super into anime.
Rym: Yep So, I think there's just a subset of people who don't connect regardless of internet or whatever.
Rym: but because of so that was in 2002 or throws like a decade ago that we read ran into that situation.
Rym: because from that guy the eboard we started to recognize especially we started really going to anime conventions that There are people who went to Otakon the biggest anime con who didn't know anime conventions were a thing.
Rym: They thought Otakon was the only one and they didn't think of it as an anime convention.
Rym: They thought of it as an Otakon.
Rym: And when at Otakon one time I was like to these people.
Rym: Yeah, you guys ever go to Kazucon I'm like, they're like, what's that?
Rym: Like it's another anime con.
Rym: It's you know in DC the next time I was not far away and they were like There's more of these.
Scott: Yeah, they have a fucking table in the dealers room.
Scott: Did you not see them sitting there with their multi TV display saying hey guys come to our other Convention as you were right right there in the middle of the fucking dealers room.
Scott: They were there yelling at you.
Scott: How did you ask them?
Rym: There are some people who for whatever reason don't connect.
Rym: in the decades since then when we identified this we used to call them Off-the-radar anime fans.
Rym: people are super into anime didn't know.
Rym: there were other people who into anime didn't know their conventions didn't know.
Rym: There were fan subs had no idea completely disconnected that we're seeing a huge divergence between two.
Rym: Everything that has anything on the internet Which is everything at this point has two communities the connected community on the internet And then the Balkanized community, that's a hundred identical tiny communities.
Rym: While they might have different local color They're effectively identical in that they all have the same 11 threads or the same 11 conversations or whatever This.
Rym: but those all those Balkanized ones together are basically Disappearing from the world to people like me and Scott.
Rym: they those people don't exist And we're diverging further and further and further.
Scott: I think this is one other factor here.
Scott: It's a potential factor I have no evidence for it, right I think that you know.
Scott: we've talked to a lot of people like for example We met I was at doing an artist alley table at an Otakon one year.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and this and I was like hey We do a podcast you doubt.
Scott: and this girl basically said it she didn't have a computer and she kept walking.
Scott: And I was like what the fuck?
Scott: yeah, and it's they're into something.
Scott: Maybe they're into you know but their computer skills are just low.
Scott: so even though they're into a thing They just don't have the technology skills to be connected, and if they figure one thing out It's like they're never gonna figure out anything else.
Scott: right?
Scott: maybe they figure out how to get an email newsletter For like their model train.
Rym: a lot of these people that I meet are super internet II or fortunate or something.
Scott: This is why I don't write.
Scott: There's another thing.
Scott: I think that happens.
Scott: I think that some of these people had.
Scott: they just are not good at reading.
Scott: They're reading skills.
Scott: even if their internet skills are high they know how to use internets.
Scott: their reading skills are low.
Scott: They cannot like I can blaze through So many web pages so fast.
Scott: I can read like all the Kotaku's all the gaming blogs all the anime blogs in like 15 minutes it doesn't take.
Scott: I do it multiple times a day over and over and over again, right I See some people.
Scott: it would take them a while to like read a day's worth of Kotaku And quickly get all that gaming information and hold on to it long enough to matter you know.
Scott: so if you don't have the high Reading skills it takes you so long to absorb information even if you were in all these communities.
Scott: It's like the amount of time It would take you to catch up on all those threads and especially if you're not checking often like imagine if you read our forum once every two days.
Scott: Right there are so many new posts.
Scott: once every two days you open it up.
Scott: There's a zillion on.
Scott: you know new unread things.
Scott: how long would it take you to sit there and read through all of them and get all the information out of them?
Scott: and Doing it all at once is sort of But doing it a little bit at a time Reloading three or four times a day two or three posts at a time.
Scott: You can actually absorb all these things now you know.
Scott: and if you aren't able to do that Then even if you're in the communities even if you have technical skills it becomes Daunting or impossible to absorb all the information unless that's what you do.
Scott: That's what I do.
Scott: I have a mobile phone, and I'm sitting at a computer most of the day every day constantly absorbing information Most of the hours other than GeekNights, and then when I get home from GeekNights It's weird because there's a double pile of information.
Scott: I'm like whoa.
Rym: a sealed room doesn't have enough oxygen.
Rym: modern buildings are so well sealed the co2 levels over the course of night can affect your brain.
Rym: Really for a single person to get ventilation a window has to be cracked one inch at an additional inch for each additional person in The room.
Rym: the only reason no one realizes this?
Rym: because we don't have co2 detectors in our houses And he has a link at the bottom.
Rym: It's been proving that the concept of a living wage is a liberal fantasy.
Rym: Throck Morton share Houston, Texas posted in 2007 and guys like that.
Rym: he has posted Fifteen thousand two hundred and eighty-nine times in this forum and probably zero times in any other forum anywhere else ever.
Rym: I can't look at more details about him without logging into the Anantech forum.
Scott: that guy just lives an antique.
Scott: That's his thing.
Rym: He probably has nothing else.
Rym: I'm trying to google him.
Scott: You know.
Rym: This is a case study right now.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we're just guessing a lot about this But I really really really want to find some way to research and investigate And just find these people and figure out how they work.
Rym: I think there's a much more core level because I want the world to be connected.
Scott: There's people out there who like the same things I like and we could be best friends, but they're for whatever reason Not connected people and they could become connected people because I wasn't always connected.
Scott: I would lived in an era when connecting like that wasn't even possible.
Rym: I was always connected.
Rym: I had BBS's from very early age elementary school middle school.
Scott: There wasn't any connection school high school.
Scott: There was not connections until like middle early middle middle middle school middle school I was on BBS's.
Scott: Yeah, that was the time when we could connect.
Scott: so up until then connecting was not possible.
Scott: Yeah So, you know and I see other people who are much older than me who weren't connected, but now we're very connected All right, so they spent they were.
Rym: there might be something more fundamental one thing I've noticed among the people who just don't connect stuff and don't ever seem to know anything about their things is that they're extremely Unmotivated and they might think like if you were talking to one of those people that that's not true, but in my conversations with them They even if they're super smart super cool
Scott: But they'll be super excited when you tell them the thing they don't know that they should know.
Rym: But then they're immediately disinterested in any further details.
Rym: Maybe like sometimes like oh the penny arcade expose a gaming convention.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: Oh my god gaming conventions That sounds so awesome.
Rym: Oh, she could go to one.
Rym: and if you say any more details about packs, they don't give a shit Mmm, and it seems that there's a trend of when I talk to a person who's disconnected like this They very quickly lose interest in things.
Rym: so maybe it has to do with attention span or motivation.
Scott: That is one thing because I know I have this problem right where when I explain something I explain every fucking detail because sometimes to An annoying fault because you're explaining rules that don't matter to a game.
Scott: But if someone's explaining something to me, it's a golden rule.
Scott: I want to hear all those fucking details.
Scott: You can't leave shit out because I'll give you leave it out.
Scott: I'm gonna grill you.
Scott: I'm gonna be like, hey, wait a minute.
Rym: What like when Pete tried to tell you the epic of Beowulf exactly.
Rym: so wait, what was they will do with these guys?
Rym: Yeah, what what exactly?
Scott: which king I need?
Scott: you just kill the king.
Scott: That's why it's the same thing when I'm on the internet There's no one to ask.
Scott: I click on all the links and read all the Wikipedia's.
Scott: cuz I got to know all the inside bits.
Scott: Even if I forget them I look them up and I remember at least some of them vaguely.
Scott: and you know If I can if I ever come back to that, I'll come back to that, you know, and that's you know.
Scott: Keep you know, it's like you can't remember lots of things.
Scott: So just remember how to find things with Google and just keep refreshing the brain Constantly reading and looking and reading and looking all the time.
Rym: now, I'm gonna make a vow I'm gonna say something that's almost a value judgment here.
Scott: And this is why I always tell people I'm not smart.
Scott: I just read lots of Wikipedia and repeat what I read.
Rym: What was that xkcd?
Rym: It's like the realization people think I'm smart that you and another person are just quoting the Wikipedia article You both recently read back and forth at each other.
Scott: That's exactly my life.
Rym: So about to make kind of a value judgment, so I want to qualify this.
Scott: I value judge away.
Rym: There are many people who don't appear to be connected but are but you simply wouldn't recognize it Because the things they're connected to like their connections don't overlap with yours.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: Like I know a lot of people who are Super tumblers and they have like this crazy network in that whole area, but I don't tumble that much.
Rym: Yeah, but What I found is that when I talk to someone like that with whom I have Let's say very little if any shared interests It doesn't matter.
Rym: we still communicate on a pretty high level because they're connected and I'm connected.
Rym: So it's obvious that they're a connected person even if I cannot see any of their connections.
Rym: Meanwhile the people I meet even though I have a huge overlap in interests who are not connected.
Rym: It is obvious They're not connected because I can't find if I talk to the connected person who I don't have anything in common with Like I'll find all the connections like around the back of their head while we talk.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you read these tumblers and I read these Twitter's but you know There's gonna be a funny JPEGs that show up on both or Wikipedia's that we both link.
Rym: So it's like any something like they'll sign like.
Rym: oh I read an article About X and I know suddenly about this whole branch that they've been exploring on the internet.
Scott: The people who aren't connected like the under-the-radar gamer dudes Even if they love games RPGs and anime and comics they have everything in common with us.
Rym: Right, there'll be no shared citations.
Rym: They won't reference External things when I talk to them, they only ever reference their own anecdotes.
Rym: Yeah, I mean when I'm connected never say to me.
Rym: Oh, I just read an article about X. They say I just saw or did X I just played X. never I read a review about X.
Scott: whenever Whenever you talk to someone who you've never met before right most of the conversation is my friend.
Scott: this I saw this.
Scott: I read this right and it's never.
Scott: you know, what I did?
Scott: I said I sit around reading things all day.
Scott: What did I do?
Rym: But I think you can tell how connected someone is by tracking, you know This is going back to our IT.
Rym: when I took those communications classes one thing we did.
Rym: we diagram conversations to figure out social dynamics so you'd listen to or you'd watch a video of like a board meeting and You'd set up a metric for depending on the kinds of sentences people said you could objectively determine things about who's in charge Who has who's the power broker?
Rym: Who's the beta?
Rym: Who's the Omega?
Rym: You know all those kinds of things?
Rym: I think there's a similar thing going on with these unconnected people.
Rym: I think there's a correlation like people who make fewer Citations to things that are not anecdotal tend to be also the people who are very unconnected and unmotivated.
Scott: Mm-hmm, it's possible.
Rym: There's probably a much more.
Scott: I mean really it's a thing we can tell it exists and we really can't tell why.
Scott: and if we because there is the disconnected It's like we're.
Scott: it's like we know that there's a tribe of people in the jungle and we know that they're.
Scott: you know They're undiscovered tribe in this jungle And we know.
Scott: we know that they're there because we met someone who met them and one of them escaped once and we talked to Them a little bit, but we couldn't Because you didn't have a language in common.
Rym: I have a better another there and let's guess about how they're out there as a much much better analogy.
Rym: So we were you know We came out of the jungle into the big old wide world and connected with all the people who were out there.
Rym: And then ten years ago at the RIT anime club.
Rym: We found an isolated tribe the under-the-radar anime fans.
Rym: We're like, whoa, look at these people.
Rym: Yeah, we studied them and then we forgot about it.
Rym: and then in our travels around the world for the next ten years We kept running into identical tribes in different places that were not connected to each other.
Rym: a Thousand tribes that are all the same.
Rym: None of them have any actual connection to each other.
Rym: So it's connected on some human level.
Rym: Meanwhile, we're connected.
Rym: all of us connected people on this technology level.
Rym: So the human people have like a base human connection.
Rym: They start from the same point, but then they just don't go out beyond that for whatever reason.
Rym: I Don't I don't really understand it, but we this is something that we and the crew talk about a lot.
Rym: So I figured we'd talk about it on the show.
Scott: I guess one thing we can do right is that if you're listening to this you're at least connected in some way.
Scott: you're listening To a podcast.
Scott: that's pretty good.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Someone who's not right.
Scott: There are things that you like in this world, right?
Scott: So here's our and if you're not super connected like we are here's our advice for you.
Scott: Number one.
Scott: You need to Google and find multiple places that are you know the that are into the things that you're into and Check them a lot and Really get attached and find people all over the world and near you and around you who are into the same things that you can Say up-to-date and learn about these things that you're into, you know They really follow them and you will enjoy these things so much more, you know in a deep way because you're nerdy like that
Rym: and
Scott: also You should read a lot.
Scott: All right, don't be sitting there and just like, you know being a bum, you know not doing anything.
Scott: You should be constantly, you know, when you're sitting there doing nothing.
Scott: You should instead be talking to people or reading and learning about the things that you're into or doing the things that you're into.
Scott: Alright, and it's not like some or it's not like oh I spend all my day playing video games And I never have time to read gaming blogs.
Scott: No, it's like no.
Scott: you can sort of do both at the same time.
Scott: You know, I'll be like playing NS and in between around open up a little browser read an article back to the NS.
Scott: You know, you gotta be fast.
Scott: Try trying is good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.