Rym: It's Thursday, April 19th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, The Hunger Games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: The hunger.
Rym: I wish I had not remembered that that existed.
Scott: I wish you also had not remembered that or reminded me of it, forcing me to remember it.
Rym: Yup, it's quite a thing, that hunger.
Scott: I hunger.
Rym: I also live.
Rym: You just ate a whole ton of my cheese.
Rym: You should be good for a while.
Scott: I'm still hungry.
Rym: Still hungry?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Luckily, The Hunger Games describes food in excruciating detail at all times.
Scott: Let us save that for the part where we're going to talk about that.
Rym: Alright, so it's Thursday.
Rym: So it's the lounge, technically.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: It's the book club.
Scott: It's a different show.
Scott: It's not even a Thursday show.
Scott: It's a book club.
Rym: Oh, so I guess I shouldn't have said it's GeekNights.
Rym: It's the GeekNights book club.
Scott: You should have.
Rym: So, I got a question for you, Scott.
Rym: If I put this episode up as book club, where will it show up?
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: As opposed to Thursday.
Rym: Because it doesn't show up on the front page of GeekNights.
Scott: It does not.
Scott: It shows up in the book club section.
Rym: Does anyone out there know where that is?
Scott: No one goes to the website anyway.
Scott: They just go to the RSS feed where it will appear.
Scott: But, you will only see it in the Thursday RSS feed.
Scott: You won't see it.
Scott: You'll only see it in the total RSS feed or the book club RSS feed.
Scott: Because I only half upgraded the site and I didn't 100% upgrade it.
Rym: That's also why every episode has a link to a forum discussion that doesn't exist.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: I'm going to fix all that.
Rym: Oh well, we'll get there.
Rym: We'll get there.
Scott: I sort of mostly fixed it.
Scott: Well, we've been busy.
Scott: I got to work all day and then every, you know, it's like, "Oh, we just finished a convention.
Scott: Hey, there's another convention.
Scott: Fuck.".
Rym: I know, another convention that's coming up actually in a few weeks.
Scott: Non-stop stuff.
Scott: So, when the fuck am I supposed to do anything?
Rym: That's the life of a D-list celebrity.
Scott: That's an F-list.
Rym: If we're D-list.
Rym: Z-list.
Rym: We're on the level of like local news guy.
Scott: No, we're not.
Rym: Who's not the prime time news guy.
Scott: We're on the level of...
Rym: We're like the local backup news guy.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Backup news guy, right?
Scott: Like the guy who does the weather when the weather guy who usually does it is sick.
Rym: Or the guy who does the weather at like 6 a.m.
Rym: when no one's watching.
Scott: Oh, that's true.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or like any of the people who do the weather on the weather channel because it keeps rotating.
Scott: And no one actually knows any of those people because they're not, you know, known personalities.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: We're nowhere near Soledad O'Brien.
Rym: Surprisingly, one of the few people like that I know exists.
Scott: Don't know who that is.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Soledad O'Brien is the one who taught me that Cuzar existed.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Long time ago.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So, you know, because it's the book club, we're not going to really do news, but I do want to talk about how... Soledad O'Brien has not yet gotten used to the fact that there is stuff to do in New York.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You'd say we're doing stuff constantly.
Scott: He does stuff.
Scott: The thing is, he doesn't have a nine to five kind of job like we do.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Necessarily.
Scott: But he has enough monies to live.
Scott: So, and freelancing and that kind of thing.
Rym: So he, you know, he invites us to...
Scott: He constantly does anything that there is in the city, he does it.
Rym: I'll put it this way.
Rym: My calendar is like almost completely full.
Rym: And yet somehow he is doing stuff all the times that I'm doing stuff and not doing stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So he'll invite me to like every freaking thing in the universe.
Scott: Hey, you want to see this chiptune thing?
Scott: Hey, you want to go see this concert?
Scott: Hey, we're going to see this movie.
Scott: Hey, we're going to see... And I'm like, one out of 20 times I'll say, okay.
Rym: So I actually went to that chiptune concert and it was quite a happening.
Rym: It was not what I expected.
Scott: Should I have gone?
Rym: I'm going to go with yes.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So I went to Control Flow, which was a chiptune event.
Scott: So that was the name of the event?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: What was the name of the venue?
Rym: So the venue was called Suburbia.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So I said like a month prior, like, yeah, I'll go.
Rym: That sounds fucking awesome.
Rym: Chill Brave and Danimal were playing and I think a band called Knife City, which while I didn't know who they were, Knife City is a great name for a band.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: So I said, yeah, I'll go to this thing.
Rym: It could be cool, you know, Brooklyn hipstery kind of chiptune party.
Rym: I'm down with that.
Rym: I'll wear a kilt.
Rym: I'll be that guy.
Rym: And I forgot about it.
Rym: So the day of it comes and I'm like, oh, yeah, I wonder where this place is.
Rym: I know it's in Brooklyn somewhere.
Rym: It's probably going to be a pain in the ass to get to, but I'll deal.
Rym: And I just Google like Suburbia, Brooklyn.
Rym: It doesn't show up.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So I start digging around and I eventually find a forum post where I figure out what the address of Suburbia is.
Rym: It's 330 Melrose Street in Brooklyn.
Rym: I think it's kind of a residential neighborhood, but it's probably some like hip new place in a basement bar or something.
Rym: So it's all cool.
Rym: So I take a cab because it's Brooklyn and I'm in Queens.
Rym: And I get there and the cab lets me off and it's just apartments.
Rym: Like that's it.
Rym: It's just apartments and brownstones and empty warehouses.
Scott: Are you saying this is an illegal venue?
Rym: I am saying that this reeks of a not entirely legitimate venue.
Scott: Where did the tickets come from?
Scott: Not Ticketmaster.
Scott: Were they, this is the free, you know, the thing you buy at Staples that has dropped this ticket.
Rym: So the tickets were give a dude five bucks after you go into this apartment and they stamp your hand.
Scott: Was it at least a stamp that was like, you know, a stamp that said Suburbia or something?
Scott: Or was it just a stamp the guy bought at the store with an alligator on it?
Rym: It was a blob that covered the entire back of my right hand.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But it was just a blob.
Rym: So basically I'm walking down the street and it's just an empty street and there's all these just like brownstones and apartments.
Scott: So when you went inside, were there any people in there?
Rym: So I'm walking around, I'm like, did I get the address wrong?
Rym: Am I just stupid?
Rym: And then I see this one apartment that has the right address and there's this tiny handwritten sign propped in the door that says Chiptune concert here.
Rym: And I pull on the door and it's locked.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Did you get there too early?
Rym: No.
Rym: So I'm standing there.
Rym: I look around.
Rym: I try to yank the door open and I can't.
Rym: There's buzzers for apartments.
Rym: Two other guys walk up and they are confused like me and they look to me as though I should know what's going on.
Rym: So I'm like, Chiptunes?
Rym: They're like, yeah.
Rym: They look like Chiptunes-y dudes.
Rym: And I just wing it and I hit the buzzer for the basement apartment.
Scott: You just guessed?
Scott: There wasn't any indication of which one it was supposed to be?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: So I hit that and a couple other buttons and I start buzzing and eventually the door goes and I go in and I stand there in the landing.
Rym: I'm like, all right, do I go up or down?
Scott: So you had two guys with you.
Scott: You could have split up three ways and figured it out.
Rym: So they stand there confused.
Rym: I start to go up and they're like, whoa, dude, wait.
Rym: And then I stop and I turn around and behind me there's the tiniest sign that's like Sharpie and it says, do not go upstairs in all caps.
Rym: So I'm like, okay, we go to the basement and yeah, give a guy five grubby bucks.
Rym: I only had like $8 on me because...
Scott: Way to not be prepared.
Scott: What if it was 10?
Scott: What would you have done?
Rym: I knew it was five bucks, but I also assumed it was a real venue where I could then use a credit card at a bar.
Rym: So I go in and it's totally some dude's apartment.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: It's some dude's apartment.
Scott: Was there alcohol served at a bar?
Scott: Oh yes.
Scott: There was no liquor license though.
Rym: So here's the deal.
Scott: No liquor license.
Rym: There might've been.
Scott: What?
Scott: We can't get a liquor license for a basement.
Rym: Here's the deal.
Rym: Here's what this venue was.
Rym: In the basement of this apartment building, there is this sort of antechamber.
Rym: And in that chamber were what looked like doors with numbers that were entrances to other apartments.
Rym: But it was also this big like bar area.
Rym: There was a bar like set up and they were selling PBRs and shots of vodka.
Rym: And that was basically it.
Scott: No liquor license.
Rym: Probably not.
Scott: You didn't see one posted, right?
Rym: I had exactly $3 and it was $3.
Rym: So I bought a PBR because I needed something to hold while I stood there awkwardly in this venue with the kinds of people who show up to a venue like this.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's a basement.
Scott: I would just hold my dick, right?
Rym: So, and then there's a door.
Rym: And through that door is a straight up like club.
Rym: Complete with flammable ass looking walls.
Rym: These spotlights that look like they're going to start a fire.
Scott: But it was actually, how big was it?
Rym: Gigantic.
Rym: There were like 200 plus people in there.
Scott: So it was actually, there's a whole club in there somehow.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: This is the kind of venue where the concert's going full swing.
Rym: I look around, I count, there are over 200 people crammed in.
Rym: I look at Chase, I'm like, this is going to be on the news as a whole bunch of hipsters die in a fire when that light gets knocked over.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: There's a projector pointed at a sheet hanging from the wall.
Rym: And there's a couple more apartments, it looks like, just attached to the venue, like in there.
Scott: How awesome would that be?
Scott: You walk out of your apartment and you're in a club.
Rym: My best guess is that a whole bunch of dudes that were chill with this and chill with each other got apartments like all together in the basement of this building and just made a venue in the common space.
Rym: That was gigantic.
Scott: And the people upstairs don't mind as long as you don't go up there.
Rym: I guess, or they live there.
Rym: Now, I knew it was shady when I walk out to get some air because I couldn't breathe down there by the end of this.
Scott: No kidding.
Rym: So I go up after like three of the bands play.
Rym: And I walk outside and we're all kind of chilling outside like really quietly, just getting some air.
Rym: And the guy who, I guess, owns the place keeps coming out saying, "You can't hang out in front of the building.
Rym: You got to walk down the street.
Rym: Don't stand in front of the
Rym: building.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Smart guy.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And it was pretty rocking.
Rym: I mean, if you like chiptunes, it was a pretty happening, dancing thing.
Rym: There was some crazy moshing, some crazy stage diving.
Rym: Well, crowd surfing.
Scott: We should wait for them to host something shitty there that we don't like and then call the cops, like 311, just to see what happens.
Rym: I imagine Benny Hill music starts playing right about then.
Scott: And then video it for YouTube.
Scott: And then we could video all the hipsters like pouring out like a spigot.
Rym: But I had one of those moments.
Scott: And then we could put Benny Hill on top of it on our YouTube vid.
Rym: So I'm standing there talking to this girl who has like 8-bit style wings tattooed on her back.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: And she's drinking a PBR.
Rym: We're talking about chiptunes and packs because I'm wearing my pack shirt.
Rym: And I was wearing a kilt and I was drinking a PBR.
Rym: And I realized that I was, in fact, not ironically one of those people that the rest of the world makes fun of as hipsters.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And it was pretty awesome, actually, considering the fact that I could have died.
Rym: The only problem really was that the stench of B.O.
Scott: You're more afraid of dying down there than you are like skiing, which is much more dangerous.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I was more afraid of dying down there.
Rym: Because at one point the stage dive or the crowd surfers kicked the lights.
Rym: I was worried that shit was going to fall.
Rym: But so at one point I suddenly smell weed, which at a concert you expect.
Scott: Well, you know, I assumed it already smelled like weed the whole time.
Scott: It didn't until-.
Scott: The fact that it only smelled like weed once and later on is surprising.
Rym: No, what was surprising, and again, I turn and we all look at each other like,
Rym: "Really?"
Rym: Is that it didn't smell like that skunky kind of like awful weed that you smell at metal shows.
Scott: Someone has some high quality weed.
Rym: It smelled high quality.
Scott: Ah.
Rym: So it's alternating waves of weed smell and B.O.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And- No alcohol smell though.
Scott: No.
Rym: So I turn around at one point.
Rym: Because usually when you smell weed at a venue you don't see it, you just smell it.
Rym: It's like there's mist just there somewhere.
Rym: No, there's just like this ring of people passing it around like totally openly.
Scott: Yeah, that's okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It was fun.
Rym: It was an experience.
Rym: I would go back to an event at this venue.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It's all you.
Rym: It was five bucks.
Scott: It's about what it's worth.
Rym: It was fun.
Rym: You should have gone just to experience it.
Scott: I have better things to do.
Rym: Yeah, I think you would have had fun.
Rym: You could have listened to Knife City.
Scott: How good were the chip tunes?
Rym: It was the kind of chip tunes you get at Magfest.
Rym: You know, a bunch of guys sort of ad-libbing on retro synth kind of music.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Very ambient and very ... I can't ... I don't understand people who listen to music like that on its own more than once.
Rym: This is the kind of music that you have to listen to live at a venue or it really doesn't do anything, at least for me.
Rym: It was an experience.
Rym: I thought I'd share.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Do you want to do things of the day?
Rym: I guess I do.
Rym: So the Hunger Games ...
Scott: You didn't even say things of the day.
Rym: Because you said it.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: The Hunger Games is one thing.
Scott: This isn't a thing of the day yet.
Scott: You're skipping ahead again.
Rym: So the hunger ... Oh, God.
Rym: If your regular expression ... ... of looking for the Hunger Games is the hunger.star, you're going to find something called the hunger.
Rym: We've talked about this before.
Scott: This is already a thing of the day a long time ago.
Rym: Yes, but I bring it back because in case ... lest you forgot, lest you forgot, I just want to say one thing.
Scott: You should remain forgot.
Rym: I will say one thing and I will let this be.
Scott: Remain forgot for your own goodness.
Rym: And I will go to my real thing of the day, but this thing is not ironic, not a joke.
Rym: The individual responsible for making it was totally super serial in the making of it.
Rym: I will just say that.
Rym: It is what it is.
Rym: I will let it be what it is.
Rym: So my real thing of the day is the German Sailor Moon thing is badass and some cool individual decided to sing.
Scott: I was the one who found this.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: To sing that song translated back into English.
Rym: This is a fan translation of the German re-rendition of the Japanese Sailor Moon theme.
Rym: It's pretty great.
Scott: It is pretty great.
Scott: Check this out.
Scott: This is old and anyone who actually knows about this is like, "Oh man, this is so
Scott: old.".
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: It's also so great and 90% of people don't know it.
Scott: It got passed around the internet and I noticed it even though I didn't know about it before.
Scott: So what this is, is the conclusion of a MotoGP race.
Scott: If you don't know, MotoGP is basically F1 of motorcycles, right?
Rym: The ones that lean like 89 degrees out of the corner.
Scott: Exactly, right?
Scott: It's, you know, supercar, whatever it is, right?
Scott: So this is the race in Catalunya from 2009, the conclusion of that race.
Scott: And basically what the situation is, Valentino Rossi, who's probably the best MotoGP person there ever was, and Jorge Lorenzo, his rival, have pretty much separated from everyone else and in so close to the end of the race, one of them is going to win.
Scott: So it's just the two of them right next to each other and there's like a handful of laps left.
Scott: and oh man, shit gets off the hook in this video.
Scott: Someone posted it on YouTube and it got taken down.
Scott: Someone else posted it and you can still watch it, but this has the Italian commentators, which is actually kind of better, I say.
Scott: So yeah, you should, this is, you don't even need to understand anything about MotoGP.
Scott: All you need to know is that it's a race and the guy in front win is the winner.
Scott: And I think Rossi is the guy who is more yellowish in his color and the other guys Lorenzo and their race is almost over and it's awesome.
Rym: When the race is over, time to discover dreams and places.
Rym: So the Hunger Games.
Scott: Oh shit, so first I want to make, before we talk about the specifics of this book, I want to talk about some general associated things.
Rym: Alright, alright.
Scott: So specifically, some guy wrote an article, I forget what newspaper it was, it doesn't matter anymore.
Scott: And he was like, he was basically all angry that, he basically said that he cries inside whenever he sees like a grown man reading Hunger Games or Twilight or Harry Potter or anything like that because he's like, "Those are kids books.
Scott: You shouldn't be reading adult
Scott: books.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: And I want to say, that's bullshit.
Scott: A lot of, you know, just because-.
Rym: Well here are two easy counter examples.
Rym: I'd be reading I Want My Hat Back.
Rym: I was going to say I Want My Hat Back and The Little Prince.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: But, at the same time, I agree with him slightly in a way, in a different way.
Scott: And that is, right, obviously, it's obvious that any book that is targeted at a lower level of reading ability is going to be more popular because there is a larger potential audience of readers, right?
Scott: If you write I Want My Hat Back, well anyone who's even barely literate can read that.
Scott: So the potential number of people who could read that book is much, much bigger than, you know, how many people are capable of reading, I don't know, what's really hard to read?
Scott: Dostoevsky or something, right?
Rym: Crime and punishment?
Scott: Yeah, so a much smaller number of people are capable of reading that book and understanding it.
Scott: And, right, so therefore that book is going to be less popular no matter what.
Scott: But, obviously I have no evidence, but I have a feeling, right, and I, you know, you can just look around you and sort of, you know, sort of agree with it, looking at what people read on the subway, that we're getting dumber because, you know, old people-
Rym: Uh, Scott, I just point out that pulp novels were the majority reading book forever.
Scott: It's true.
Rym: I mean, look at the drivel that people read a hundred years ago and two hundred years ago.
Scott: That's true, but some of that drivel that was drivel in its day is now no longer considered drivel, right?
Scott: So, a hundred years from now, Hunger Games won't be like a young adult novel.
Scott: That'll be like, hi, like, you know, we'll look at that the way you looked at War and Peace.
Rym: Well, maybe.
Rym: I mean, Dumas stuff was, you know, drivel for its time, pulp nonsense.
Rym: Oh, it was super drivel.
Rym: But, nowadays, he's considered a classic.
Scott: It is.
Rym: How many other authors were published in the same anthologies and newspapers that no one remembers?
Rym: That no one considered about, right.
Rym: Yeah, the best of those survived.
Scott: I'm just saying, I kind of wish, you know, it seems.
Scott: lately there has been a long spurt of very popular novels that are mostly of the young adult, lower reading level variety.
Scott: I would like to see something become as popular as Hunger Games, Harry Potter, et cetera, Twilight.
Scott: That is a difficult adult book, like at least as difficult as Prince of Nothing.
Rym: I don't think it's possible because of just the intelligence and commitment spectrum of humans.
Scott: I mean, Game of Thrones is a little more intelligent than this.
Rym: Have you read any of it?
Scott: No, but I'm assuming, I mean, it is less of a kid's book.
Rym: No, Scott, I'll put it this way.
Rym: It is more complicated, but the way it is written...
Scott: It's about the difficulty of reading it and the level of the vocabulary used.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think it's substantially more difficult.
Scott: And the complexity of the sentence structures and those sorts of things.
Rym: Sentence structures do not impress me.
Scott: I'm not saying they impress me.
Scott: I'm saying it makes it more difficult to read as in a less literate person cannot...
Rym: But Scott, Scott, is it just a matter of more difficult to read?
Rym: For example, look at Hemingway.
Rym: Those are very simple sentences.
Scott: They are indeed.
Rym: And yet those are brilliant books.
Rym: In my estimation.
Rym: Some of them.
Rym: Fuck you if you disagree with me.
Scott: Some of them.
Rym: Which one isn't?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's just a lot, so I'm not going to... I've only read like three Hemingways, so I'm not going to go out and be like... Say that all of them are great.
Rym: I'm pointing it out because the thing I've run into often, this is totally an aside before we get into the book, is people, like when the God Delusion was making the rounds, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I would come up in conversation and most kind of normal, don't really think about that sort of thing, people I would talk to would say, "Yeah, I thought it was a great book.
Rym: I agree with most of it, but I don't agree with everything you
Rym: said.".
Rym: But then I would ask them, "What's one thing you disagreed
Rym: with?".
Rym: And they couldn't answer because they either hadn't actually read the book or they didn't read it thoroughly and didn't want to commit to an opinion.
Scott: I'm just not committing because I've read three Hemingways.
Scott: They were all fine.
Scott: But I'm not going to go out and say that all of them are great when I haven't read them all.
Rym: Nah, I've read a good portion of Hemingway.
Rym: But anyway, this is neither here nor there.
Rym: So in terms of The Hunger Games, the reason I chose this book was very simple.
Scott: It's way popular.
Rym: Before, we actually, it was on the horizon for us way before the movie was announced and it really caught fire.
Scott: Not for me.
Scott: I didn't even really pay attention to it.
Rym: Because you don't pay attention to half our forum and the things our friends say.
Scott: I knew there was a thing.
Scott: I sort of got whispers that there's a popular thing called The Hunger Games.
Scott: It's something.
Scott: And then I got some other whispers like, "Oh, it was a book and there's a movie in theaters
Scott: now.".
Scott: And I was like, "Oh,
Scott: okay.".
Scott: And then I got another whisper through the internet that, "Oh, it's about sort of the same thing-ish Battle Royale is about with kids killing each other in some sort of deathmatch
Scott: thing.".
Rym: Yep, so this is why I'm going to be brutally honest.
Rym: A few friends and listeners independently said, "Hey, Rym, you should do The Hunger
Rym: Games.".
Rym: Or at least read it.
Rym: I thought it was pretty good.
Rym: And my skepticism meter was already pretty high.
Scott: I mean, it was at the level of- I did not have a meter because it was just sort of, "Oh, there's a thing,
Scott: okay.".
Rym: Yeah, well, I have a high skepticism meter of anything that's recommended to me unless it comes from very specific channels.
Rym: Like, if Emily or Alex recommend something, the skepticism is way low unless there's evidence to the contrary.
Rym: But if some random dude is like, "Hey," skepticism starts out pretty high.
Rym: But I looked into it and I was like, "What's the book
Rym: about?".
Rym: And they were like, "Oh, it's a bunch of kids who have to fight to the death, blah, blah,
Rym: blah.".
Rym: And I immediately tripled my skepticism because none of those people had seen or knew anything about Battle Royale.
Scott: And that short description, right, that summary really sounds like Battle Royale.
Rym: So I immediately thought, "Oh, this is probably a situation of people who haven't seen X, so they find Y, which is inferior, and because they don't know about X and Y is a simulacrum of it, they think it's
Rym: great.".
Scott: And they think it's a new and original thing.
Scott: It's like it's one of those safe assumptions, right?
Scott: And we see that so often as nerds, right, where something comes out and people are crazy about it and you're like, "I've seen that before.
Scott: It was called
Scott: Avalon.".
Rym: "It was called Herzog
Rym: Zwei.".
Scott: "I've seen that.
Scott: It was called 1984.
Scott: I've seen that.
Scott: It was called...".
Scott: You know, and that happens every day in nerdery, right?
Scott: So it's, you know, whether it's a correct assumption or not, it is a safe assumption.
Scott: When you hear a short description of something and it sounds like something old, nine times out of ten, it is indeed a recopying or a redoing of that old thing that you know about because you're a nerd.
Scott: And it's just those people don't know about the old thing, so they're totally fooled, and they think it's original and awesome.
Rym: So I was very skeptical, almost on the level of my initial skepticism when a dude was like, "Yo, man, the new My Little Pony is really great.
Rym: You should watch
Rym: it.".
Rym: I was like, "Uh, what?
Scott: Really?".
Rym: And I'd just gotten into some arguments with some friends recently about taste and quality of works and this sort of thing.
Rym: So I was like, "You know what?
Rym: Fuck it.
Rym: I'm taking that book.
Rym: I'm going to read it.
Rym: It's probably going to be shit, and then I can just say I told you
Rym: shit.".
Scott: Oh, you went in with a low expectation.
Rym: I went in thinking, "You know what?
Rym: I'm going to destroy this
Rym: book.".
Scott: I went in with no expectation, but, and the only thing that I had in my mind that was a preconceived notion was the question of how much Battle Royale ripoff is this question mark.
Scott: Other than that, I had no other things in my brain about it when I started reading it.
Rym: So very quickly I realized that the answer is it's not at all.
Rym: They are related to each other in the same way that Bat and Birdwings are related to each other.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean, I believe the author, having read Battle Royale, but I've seen Battle Royale, and I've read The Hunger Games, and I'll soon get the other two, so I'll have the quad pecta, right?
Scott: I'll read Battle Royale, and I'll watch The Hunger Games.
Scott: But I believe the author, when she said that she had not even heard of Battle Royale, and that she didn't read it when her editor, whoever, told her not to, right?
Scott: So I believe her, but there are some similarities that it's like, clearly, you know, it just happens.
Scott: There are ideas that people get, and the same ideas spread around.
Scott: There are multiple people on Earth who have independently derived calculus.
Scott: Yeah, but I guess my point is it's not a rip-off of Battle Royale at all.
Rym: In fact, if anything, the way I saw she said something to the effect of she was watching some news reports and flipping channels and also seeing parts of a documentary, but it was kind of like a reality show, and between the two.
Rym: it kind of gave her the idea.
Rym: Like, imagine if you were watching Schwarzenegger, Running Man, and Robocop, and the news in Iraq all at the same time.
Rym: Like, I could see where that would cement the idea.
Rym: But right away, this is much more, in my opinion, like 1984 than it is like Battle Royale, other than the surface of a bunch of people have to fight to the death in an arena, which is actually a very common... I mean, The Running Man, Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Scott: That is Mad Max.
Scott: But I think what it has in common is, okay, the fighting to the death in the arena, right?
Scott: But it's the fact that it's children fighting to the death in an arena, which is a specific detail.
Scott: that's in common with Battle Royale.
Scott: Also, you know, the fact that the per- why are they fighting in the arena, right?
Scott: And Running Man, you know, Arnold Schwarzenegger, Running Man, they're fighting to the death in the arena for entertainment and as a game show.
Rym: No, but it's more than that.
Rym: The Running Man is fighting for entertainment to distract, like it's very specifically to distract the masses from the fact that they live in a shitty world run by a dictatorship.
Scott: Of course, same thing with Smash TV, right?
Scott: But in Battle Royale and in The Hunger Games, the reason the children fight to the death is to basically teach everyone a lesson.
Scott: It's like, you know, we own you, right?
Scott: But at the same time, it's entertainment, right?
Scott: It's the dual purpose.
Scott: It's the 1984 and the Brave New World at the same time.
Scott: Now this is why I like this.
Scott: Look at this, and that's in common between both Battle Royale and, you know, Hunger Games.
Scott: Now I have to read- We're gonna scare the fuck out of you because you could be the next one to have to fight in these horrible games.
Scott: But at the same time, watch these horrible games and be entertained at circuses.
Rym: Ah, but I guess, I haven't read Battle Royale, but I've seen the movie.
Scott: Ah, same here.
Rym: And I've read Hunger Games, but Hunger Games at least, the world that was set up around the games makes a lot more sense in terms of why the games would be the way they are than the contrived world that was set up to make Battle Royale happen as it was portrayed in the movie.
Rym: Yes, I have a feeling- In the movie, the movie was basically, "Uh, yeah, kids fight,
Rym: go!".
Scott: Yeah, but in the movie, you know, you definitely know that the world is like that.
Scott: They just don't show the world that much.
Scott: I have a feeling, I don't know if it's true or not, because the book is so big.
Scott: Alright, Hunger Games is a tiny book, you can read it so fast, two hours.
Rym: I read it like on my flight to India.
Scott: I read it so fast, like a couple days.
Scott: In fact, I read all three of them, but I know Rym told me where the first one ends, so I won't talk about two and three.
Rym: Yep, I'm gonna read the rest, but I've been busy.
Scott: Battle Royale is such a large book, I don't, I imagine, in order to fill all of that text, they have to talk about the world more.
Scott: I can't imagine that they don't.
Rym: It could be like that awful Battle Royale manga.
Rym: I heard the Battle Royale manga is not awful.
Rym: Uh, did you, how far did you read into it?
Scott: Two volumes.
Rym: Yeah, it is awful.
Scott: It's not as bad as like Trigun manga, it's not awful, it's just, you know, it's a manga.
Rym: No, I don't think, it is awful.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: It is awful, and I don't like it.
Scott: We need a Hunger Games manga so we can match him up.
Scott: Someone get on that, this is a Twilight manga.
Rym: There's gonna be a comic, you know they're.
Rym: well, what's the first thing you do with a successful franchise?
Rym: You make some shitty comic.
Scott: Should I buy it?
Rym: No, it'll be terrible.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Remember the Firefly comic?
Rym: That thing was awful.
Scott: I didn't read it.
Rym: Yeah, but it was awful.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Relative to Firefly, it was awful.
Rym: It was a mediocre, like, you know, generic-o comic.
Scott: Alright, so let's actually talk about Hunger Games.
Rym: But I guess, the whole, you know, again, one last thing, you know, book club.
Rym: We assume you've read the book.
Rym: We're gonna talk about it like you've read it and we've read it.
Rym: So one, spoilers, duh.
Rym: But two, we're not gonna explain the plot.
Rym: Because if you haven't read the book, why are you listening to this?
Rym: Read the book.
Rym: The point of the book club is that we come to the table with a shared understanding, a shared experience that we then discuss.
Scott: So we do not need a plot summary because you've read it.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: So if you're confused- So, as a plot summary, the books- So, really, the details of the way the world was set up- You wanna do the one, two, three at the same time?
Scott: Say your opinion of the book.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: So it'll be one, two, go.
Scott: Well, you wanna do- no, on the show, they do one, two, three and then they say the word.
Rym: So one, two, three, word?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And your word is basically, you sum up your feelings about the book in one word.
Scott: That way, whatever my word is will not influence your word.
Rym: Oh, yeah, yeah, but I don't like that because it's not consistent with rock, paper, scissors, which people fuck up all the time.
Scott: Dude, I gotta talk to you about it later, but they do a weird rock, paper, scissors.
Rym: Do they do the one where you have to look in the opposite direction of the point?
Rym: No.
Rym: Oh.
Scott: Even different.
Rym: Okay, we'll talk about that later.
Rym: Alright, so let's go.
Rym: one, two, three, blah.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Ready?
Rym: One, two, three.
Scott: We agree.
Rym: Yeah, I liked it okay.
Rym: It was an enjoyable read.
Scott: It was definitely enjoyable, entertaining.
Rym: I got choked up a couple of times.
Scott: I didn't get choked up, but I wanted to read it.
Scott: It's like, I got home, if it wasn't done yet, I wanted to read it.
Rym: It was the same thing with anime with any media, where some media, actually most media, start to consume it, and it's a chore.
Rym: I think, alright, I guess I should watch the next episode, but then you read something good, or watch something good, where you actually hit the end of a chapter, and you're like, I gotta read the next one.
Scott: But, at the same time, it's like, I liked it, it was entertaining, whatever.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it'll entertain most people who read it, but it really wasn't that, as in terms of how quality is this.
Scott: It's forgettable.
Scott: I put it in my own personal- It's a work of art.
Scott: It's like you go to the museum, and you see something that's pretty eye-catching and cool, but it's never gonna be a masterpiece.
Scott: It's never gonna be a history book.
Scott: You're not gonna buy a print of it.
Rym: It's on the same level, for me, as the first Fullmetal Alchemist anime, in that I liked it while I was reading it, mostly forgot about it as soon as I was done with it, and don't care to really consume it again.
Scott: I think it's like a half step under the lies of Locke Lamora, right?
Scott: It's like just a tiny bit step underneath, because at least- Oh my god, I want the next Locke Lamora book to come out.
Scott: Right, because the lies of Locke Lamora had the thing that puts it a little bit above The Hunger Games, is that- Precursor technology?
Scott: Well, no.
Rym: Well, they're in both, I guess.
Scott: Is that, in the lies of Locke Lamora, the plotting was sort of clever, and you didn't know, and you were surprised, and it was, "Oh man, look how he pulled it off,".
Scott: right?
Scott: In The Hunger Games, I knew exactly what was happening from page one to the hundredth page.
Rym: It's like- When they announced the rules are changing, two people can survive, I immediately thought they're going to renounce that rule as soon as two people are left.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Every- That was Telegraph, that was Chekhov's sentence.
Scott: It was Chekhov book.
Scott: It was like, and I'm not even talking about just book one, I'm talking about one, two, three.
Scott: Chekhov wrote the whole three books.
Scott: Suzanne Chekhov wrote these books.
Scott: There were no secrets, no anything.
Scott: The foreshadowing was a bajillion, and it was blatant and obvious.
Scott: I think what would have made this awesome is if it was written more like Lord of the Flies, right?
Scott: No.
Scott: That would have been, because that would have put it over the top in terms of the quality of its awesomeness.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Well, I guess I really appreciated in the setting how plausible the rationale for these games are, that it's literally the punishment for a rebellion.
Rym: That's the kind of thing an ancient empire would do.
Rym: Like, "Oh, you rebelled against us.
Rym: Every year for the rest of time, the first child born in the year of May will be
Rym: murdered."
Rym: You know, something like that.
Scott: I did enjoy, there were a lot of things in there that were very realistic-ish, right?
Scott: For example, obviously I don't know what goes on in a teenage girl's mind for real.
Rym: That sounded a lot like what goes on in the mind of what I expect of teenage girls.
Scott: But reading it, if someone told me, "Yeah, that's exactly how teenage girls think," I believe it.
Scott: And people who have been or are teenage girls told me that that is in fact the case, and so I believe it.
Scott: Also, consider how they portray the people from the Capitol, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, the Capitol is the evil place, but it's a lot like the United States.
Scott: It's like not everyone who lives there is evil.
Scott: They just live in the good place.
Rym: That's how they do.
Rym: But also, I really like the way the people in the Capitol were portrayed with their kind of over-the-top makeup, and it really reminded me of the Running Man kind of world, especially with Caesar, the announcer.
Scott: I actually want to see the movie, because the only images I've seen from the movie are Katniss with bow and arrow in the woods kind of pictures, right?
Scott: I want to see what the Capitol looks like in the movie, because I always love looking at futuristic stuff.
Scott: Is it going to be dark and Blade Runner-y?
Scott: Because I don't imagine it that way.
Scott: I imagine it would be bright and shiny, more like a Wizard of Oz kind of Emerald City.
Rym: I want to see the train into the Capitol.
Rym: I want to see the fire dress.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: I want to see all that kind of stuff, right?
Rym: I really want to see Caesar, because that announcer reminded me so much of the Running Man announcer.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I like that style of dude, because I like how he's kind of a good guy, too.
Rym: He does his best.
Rym: He really wants to help these kids out, but yet he's part of this horrible system.
Scott: He's just doing what he do.
Rym: Yeah, but he's genuinely pretty funny, actually, when you actually get what he's saying, though half the time you're stuck in Katniss's head with her whining about boys while he's talking.
Scott: Yeah, apparently from what I've heard is that in the movie you don't really hear what she's thinking, but basically the book is entirely in Katniss's head all the time.
Scott: And some people who saw the movie first or whatever were bothered by the reversal, like they wanted to know or they didn't want to.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Oh, well, I've heard that it's at least obvious what she's thinking if you watch the movie, like the body language is well acted and such.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, generally the plausibility of a lot of the situations, right, was really comforting.
Rym: In fact, the only false note, like the genetic stuff with the Mockingjays, I actually, that was cool, too, because this is a post-apocalyptic America, so stuff like that actually sets it in time pretty well.
Rym: But those fucking genetic wolves at the end of the first book, one, out of nowhere, two, false note compared to everything else in the book, and three, stupid.
Scott: Yep, I agree.
Rym: That just shouldn't have been there.
Scott: The other thing that bothered me, but it didn't bother me, but it was an implausible thing, right, was like this, you know, the separation of the numbered districts, right, is like they're in this big long line going to the capital with the one train connecting them.
Scott: That's such a contrived geographic situation, sort of like DMZ, the comic.
Scott: Yep, I mean, DMZ.
Scott: Like, yeah, OK, even if there was this horrible thing that happened, it wouldn't be like that, where like, you know, number this is mining and number this is technology, it's like it wouldn't happen like that.
Rym: Nope, that was very contrived.
Scott: Yeah, extremely contrived.
Scott: Just, it seemed like that's the kind of thing that you would make up for an RPG setting, right, you know, sort of like paranoia, like the different colors.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: You know, very contrived.
Scott: But other than that, it was fine.
Rym: Ah.
Scott: What else is there to say about this game?
Rym: I mean, I like how it really focused a lot more on food and water and basic stuff than the fighting.
Rym: The fighting was kind of just there.
Rym: I appreciate, too, how unlike Battle Royale, the fight itself, like the actual games, the rules were really well thought out.
Scott: Well, in Battle Royale, the rules are pretty well thought out.
Rym: Yeah, but it was a little, I don't know, this was more like if like you, me and Luke Crane and Jared sat down and someone was like, "You guys have to design a game where kids fight to the death and we film
Rym: it.".
Scott: Well, in Battle Royale...
Rym: Like the rule around the cornucopia in the beginning was great.
Scott: Oh yeah, that's... That was awesome.
Scott: That's clever, right?
Scott: But I mean, you know, I think Battle Royale, because it's, you know, it seems like it's a very Japanese thing, is those situational things.
Scott: Look at Death Note with its rules, right?
Scott: Or look at Nine Doors, Nine Hours, Nine Persons, right?
Rym: Oh yeah, 9-9-9-9.
Scott: Right, with all the, they always come with these rules, you know, and the rules involve like, you know, technology, enforcing things, right?
Scott: And that seems like something that happens in Japanese books, movies, stories, mangas, et cetera, right?
Scott: Whereas, you know, this isn't Japanese, so it, you know, even though it's one of those situational things, you know, the situation isn't the whole book, it's just this one part of the book and it doesn't go into that same sort of, you know, complexity.
Scott: So in Battle Royale, the rules are you have a necklace, if you fuck up, they explode the necklace.
Scott: There's different zones and you get a map and you have to be in the right zones at the right times, otherwise, if you go in an unallowed zone for you, then your necklace explodes, you know.
Scott: Ah, but look, the necklace- Maybe try to escape it explodes, if you try to remove it, it explodes.
Scott: See, that's the thing, the sudden exploding- And then when the time runs out at the end of the game, if you're not the only one left alive, it all explodes.
Rym: Yeah, but see, those rules, from a, you know, entertainment perspective, kind of suck.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Like, this is much better in that it seems to be designed to force the conflict and have a camera there.
Rym: I like how it really focused on the details of how would they stage this, the fact that she's always worried about-
Scott: That was awesome, how she was always thinking in the meta, the way we would think in the meta of like, you know, oh, you know-
Rym: The camera can see me, I'd better, you know, make this kind of face.
Scott: And I think that's why she was successful, because she could think about it in that way, you know, because she had been watching them at home, right, everyone's forced to watch them, right?
Scott: So, you know, in thinking about, you know, this is a thing for entertainment, so the way to win is this, and that's just like, as you know, as the author said, reality shows, right?
Scott: If you were to win on the reality show, you have to, you know, you can't just, you know, play the games by the rules and try to win and be boring, because they'll find some way to get you out of there by changing the rules or whatever bullshit, because that's what reality shows do, right?
Scott: They just try to be entertaining.
Scott: The way you win the reality show is by, you know, pleasing the producers and pleasing the audience at home, you know, by doing things that make you, you know, liked and appeal and, you know, do things that cause entertaining situations, even if it's putting yourself in danger, but at the same time, don't die.
Scott: And you know, the fact that she could think about it in the meta gave her this big advantage, but also was a way for you to have, you know, the full perspective, right?
Scott: Instead of, they could have done something where like, you know, they cut between her in the game and people watching at home, but they didn't have to do that, because her meta thinking was what the people at home and also the producers are thinking, so you got every perspective.
Rym: Which is probably why in the movie, from what I can tell, they do cut a lot more to the people at home watching.
Scott: Right, because this way, in the book, because you know what she's thinking and she's thinking from every angle, you get the full perspective on the games, even though it's entirely from the point of view of one person, whereas in the movie, if they don't, you know, do voiceover or something with her thoughts, you would need to cut away to get the other perspectives on the game.
Scott: Otherwise, you would just have sort of like this, you know, FPS half-life kind of view of Gordon Freeman trying to survive and that's it.
Scott: But I
Rym: like how this sets up a really nice contrast between, you know, the Katniss perceived by the people and what she's really thinking, because she is a much more normal, like she's just a teenage girl, but yet she, you know, she has this very different persona as far as people see her.
Rym: And I really like reality shows.
Scott: do again, right?
Scott: It's like if I want a reality show, they wouldn't portray me the way I am.
Scott: They would try to come up with some way to label me and, you know, characterize me.
Scott: And they would cut and edit so that, you know, maybe they portrayed me as angry guy or nerdy guy.
Rym: Remember how they showed the thing with Rue, but they didn't show the flowers.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: Those notes really rang true.
Rym: I also really liked how Katniss actually tried to win.
Rym: And while she cared about the people around her and through some luck didn't have to kill some people she liked, she had no qualms about killing someone when it came to it.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: She didn't.
Scott: But I think that was also maybe because it was a young adult novel, but they really set it up.
Scott: So she never actually had to do.
Rym: No, she killed the dude who killed Rue just like without even thinking.
Scott: Of course, but she never had to kill a good person.
Scott: You know, they would they always hinted and it could have come up and it was always a possibility, but it just never actually did.
Scott: And it feels like she got away with one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In reality, you know, if this actually went down, it's probably you wouldn't get off so easy that way.
Scott: You know, you'd probably have to kill or be killed by people that you liked and were good people.
Rym: Of course.
Scott: It's just the way things played out.
Scott: Good people never had to kill the good.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: I was a question, do you think if they hadn't backed down at the end, she would have they would have really killed themselves?
Scott: Absolutely.
Rym: So.
Rym: All the good people left could have done that together.
Rym: So there was still a way they could have.
Scott: So so because I mentioned, but but the thing is, there weren't enough good people left because of the order in which people died.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was them two and Rue, maybe, you know, but who knows how Rue would have felt about it.
Scott: But I know that Peta and Katniss definitely would have gone through with it.
Scott: But it's like even if you're a good person, right.
Scott: You know, would you necessarily go through with it?
Scott: Maybe, you know, like.
Scott: if you imagine if like, you know, a couple of us and some other good people were standing there and it's like, you know, you're thinking about like, OK, maybe we'll all maybe we'll pick a person we want to win.
Scott: But, you know, and maybe that person just can't do it.
Scott: They can't bring themselves to go through with it.
Scott: So we'll win for them.
Scott: You know, it's like you would.
Scott: you would be a different situation depending.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Of course, at the same time, they did a good job of making it obvious that Katniss kind of had to win.
Rym: Like she couldn't just abandon her family and an act of rebellion like that would have endangered all the people she left behind.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So it was set up well to where it was the difficult choice.
Rym: But because I mentioned Rue, I liked her character, but.
Rym: I'm amazed at the number of people who freaked out that she was portrayed as not white in the movie, even though she is clearly dark brown in the book.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: How do people not?
Rym: it's kind of like how people are surprised when you tell them that the wizards Ursula K. Le Guin, like, you know, that they're not white.
Scott: But it says right there.
Scott: they're not white.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: the first thing says it in plain text.
Scott: This is this is the thing that happens a lot.
Scott: It actually happens to me.
Scott: So I can understand it is you read a book and they'll introduce a character and sometimes they introduce a character like, for example, Katniss.
Scott: They only really describe like her braided hair and not too much about her appearance in the book.
Rym: I think olive ish skin.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they only describe it once at the beginning.
Scott: And that's it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They don't, you know, and they'll describe later on like, oh, she got a scar here or modifications, but they won't redescribe her whole appearance at any point other than the introductory part.
Scott: So if you weren't paying close attention, then you've already built this image of the person in your mind based on whatever your prejudices are in your brain.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And now that's stuck in there and it's hard to modify it.
Scott: So you had to pay.
Scott: when you're reading a book, you have to play really close attention to those initial character appearance descriptions or your image in your brain.
Scott: You know, obviously, it's never going to be exactly the same, even if you do pay close attention to that description.
Scott: But it's going to be way the fuck off and racist or who knows what if you just make one up based on nothing, because you didn't pay you didn't read the words carefully.
Rym: That's fine unless you find out on the Internet when it got right.
Scott: You know, like he doesn't look the way you expect, you know.
Scott: So if that happened to me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I perhaps, you know, it's only two words.
Scott: Anyone could, you know, reading quickly, you know, dark skin.
Scott: You can miss that.
Rym: I guess shooting the reaction of Ben.
Rym: Oh, I guess she was black.
Scott: You can legitimately miss that.
Scott: And if you do legitimately miss it, then don't freak out on the Internet.
Scott: Go look at the book again.
Scott: And if you see that you are wrong, be like, oh, and if there isn't a lot of times there isn't a description, a complete description of what someone looks like, in which case whatever you make up is fine, you know, and then in the movie they have complete creative freedom to do whatever they want.
Scott: Maybe ask the author, you know.
Scott: I mean, like, you know, I mean, I'm going to tell you something right now.
Scott: When I read Lord of the Rings, right.
Scott: Originally back in the middle school days, you thought Bilbo was nine feet tall.
Rym: No, no, no.
Scott: I knew what hobbits look like.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But elves, I imagine like Santa Claus elves like really.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I didn't know like, you know, tall, wavy, pointy eared elf like D&D style until way later.
Scott: I didn't even think of that as an.
Scott: I didn't even think of that as like anything.
Scott: That was not an image in my brain until much later.
Rym: Maybe it's because when I thought it, but I have never had a perception of elves that was not Tolkien-esque elves even before I read Tolkien.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I read Tolkien and I wasn't imagining Tolkien-esque elves.
Scott: I was imagining Santa Claus elves.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, Rivendell is a place full of tiny elves like, hey, you know, and I guess I had the dwarves right.
Scott: But the dwarves, well, I had the dwarves.
Scott: physical-ness, right.
Scott: You know, short, right.
Scott: But I imagine them like, you know, wearing like David the gnome clothes.
Scott: And not wearing like, you know, armors.
Scott: That's just me.
Scott: You know, obviously I have it right now.
Scott: I'm not wrong anymore, but that's the kind of thing that can happen to someone if you don't pay extremely close attention to the physical appearance descriptions at the character introduction stage of any novel.
Rym: So, I mean, I don't know.
Rym: I don't have any other specific points that really stood out.
Rym: I mean, I think I've covered every thing that was memorable or annoying or good.
Scott: Well, it's in the first book.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I haven't read the rest.
Rym: I read some spoilers and I don't think I like the other books as much as I like the first one.
Scott: Do I like the other?
Scott: I think they're all you know, the thing is, it's one of those ones where they all flow together into the same thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, and because, you know, and the whole thing, you know, I mean, it was all good.
Scott: I mean, I read to the end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If it wasn't good, I wouldn't have kept reading.
Scott: But it was like I said, check off everything right up to the end, 100 percent all the way to the end of the third book.
Scott: Check off all the way.
Scott: So, you know, none of it really felt, you know, profound.
Rym: And I have one question for you.
Rym: Do those fucking wolves come back?
Scott: They're mentioned.
Scott: They don't actually come.
Rym: OK, that's good.
Scott: But there were.
Scott: there are scenes where a character remember them and be haunted by that.
Rym: I remind me of them.
Rym: You know, did you put those in the book?
Scott: They'll just be like, you know, it's a quick thing.
Scott: It's not like a long, drawn out thing where someone, you know, but it'll be like someone has a nightmare that has the wolf in it or someone is thinking about something and is like, oh, man, what if something like those horrible wolves comes back?
Rym: I just I don't understand why those wolves are in the book.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: Just the thing they needed to come up with hazards.
Scott: And that's what they came could have just been wolves.
Scott: It could have been, but I guess they were trying to, I don't know, make a point about something.
Scott: That's another thing is that the book doesn't really make any subtle points.
Rym: No, it's up against tyranny.
Scott: But at the same time, you can't fault someone for not rising up because it's all this symbolism is just blatant and not even not even blatant, but like literally explained.
Scott: It's you know, it's not like well, like I said, Lord of the Flies before, right?
Scott: It's like, yeah, that kid is Jesus.
Scott: But this in, you know, in friggin Hunger Games, it would actually have the words, yeah, that kid is Jesus.
Scott: You know, it's like they literally tell you what all the thing, you know, and they'll do it.
Scott: They'll even repeat, you know, in case you forgot what a thing means, you know, like for example, you know, the Mockingjay symbolizes, you know, the fact that, you know, that literally the Mockingjays mocked the empire when it tried to use it.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And they'll actually explain that in words, whereas what they could have done to be subtle and intelligent would be tell the story of where the Mockingjays came from and, you know, what happened with them and just let it be.
Rym: And then people like us and then would say something like, ah, but notice how the symbol of the rebellion is the Mockingjays, the symbol is the Mockingjay.
Scott: Do you remember that the story of the Mockingjay was about these birds, right, that were a weapon, the, you know, the capital used against the people, but got turned against them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And notice how that is so similar to the fact that how, you know, Katniss is used as a weapon against the people in the Hunger Games and then she turned against them and mocked them.
Rym: It sounds like there's basically paragraphs like that in the book.
Scott: There are paragraphs in the book that basically say exactly that and they'll remind you of it.
Scott: It's like they'll tell the story of the Mockingjay and then in the second, third books, they'll tell the story again to explain it, because, you know, it's like, OK, for a young adult book, you know, lower reading levels, you know, it's understandable.
Scott: But, you know, it doesn't make the book better.
Scott: You could have just left that out.
Rym: Also, the word mutations is kind of dumb, that is a dumb word, it doesn't fit with the flow of the rest of the proper nouns at all.
Scott: No, you're really upset about these wolves.
Rym: They really pissed me off.
Scott: They did.
Scott: I mean, I do agree.
Rym: Like when the wolves came, I was like, all right, some monsters.
Rym: This is the end.
Scott: And then you get to the end of that first book and it's like, all right, there's got to be some climactic thing.
Scott: And it's like that was it.
Scott: And it's like, whoa, it kind of it was kind of like a weird doink.
Rym: And they didn't do anything with it.
Rym: It's not like the wolves had any like memory.
Rym: It's not like there was a hesitation or any character.
Rym: It was just random bullshit out of nowhere.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, the fact that it was, you know, the blatant trilogy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, I like it better when someone writes a first book and there's no assumption that there's going to be more books.
Scott: So that book is like contained and completed, you know, as opposed if you go into it knowing it's going to be a trilogy or a quadrigy or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, OK, you found good breaking points to split it up.
Scott: But I almost sort of feel like why not just make one big ass book?
Rym: Because then we would not yet have even heard of the Prince of Nothing.
Scott: Hey, they could know we could have had one big ass book of the first three.
Rym: That would have come out not that long ago.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: And then we would have said, what the fuck?
Rym: Where's the rest?
Rym: And then still waiting.
Scott: Well, you know, he would have made it a complete.
Scott: Yeah, I like it better when people write complete thingies that stand alone and then also go together.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When things are only going together, you start heading into superhero comic territory.
Rym: No, it depends.
Rym: There's a fine line.
Scott: There is.
Scott: It's not exactly the same, but I'm saying heads in that direction.
Scott: Is there anything else saying?
Rym: I'm amazed at the.
Rym: I don't like.
Rym: I guess I can see why it's so popular in retrospect.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But I'm surprised how quickly this caught like the fire of this book spread catching fire at much, much in the same pattern that Twilight did.
Rym: But I'm glad because Twilight is pretty shit compared to this.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: So I'm glad this is the new popular thing.
Scott: And it doesn't take long to read.
Scott: So even if, you know, your highbrow, you could read this and if you in, you know, it's not as quick as, you know, little prints, but you can read this in like a day or two after work and that'll be it.
Scott: And then if you want, you can read the other two.
Scott: I actually I'm gonna be honest, I've pirated books two and three.
Scott: You know why?
Scott: Not because they were hardcover only and I don't buy hardcover.
Rym: I do also in terms of like the books themselves, like the selling and the reading and everything in the movie and Emily, I talk about this a lot.
Rym: It seems like young adult books like this that can be interpreted kind of loosely like books that aren't that great, but have a good core where you can really like fudge and add details when you adapt them to movies tend to make really good movies compared to literal remakes of books.
Rym: I haven't seen the movie.
Scott: I haven't either.
Rym: So this is what I'm guessing I'm going to feel like when I see this because I've seen it happen with other similar works.
Rym: And with this in particular, from the scenes I've seen from trailers, I think I will enjoy the movie more than I enjoyed the book.
Scott: You know what I think?
Rym: Because the writing of the book, while it was serviceable, much like Locke Lamora was serviceable, it was it was no Hawthorne.
Scott: You know what I think.
Scott: it is, you know, I think makes these things popular and also makes Harry Potter popular and Twilight and all these sorts of things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I think it's mostly world world building.
Rym: Well, look at the way I went to Wikipedia to remember who wrote this.
Rym: And there here's this whole article on every individual.
Rym: The Hunger Games universe has its own page on Wikipedia.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And I think gigantic.
Scott: I think that, you know, it's like nerds love that world building.
Rym: That is the very unique to Panam, forgotten realms and unnamed tracker, jacker, venom absorbing plants.
Rym: But I actually has two paragraphs.
Scott: But I think actually world building has a mass appeal and not just a nerd.
Rym: Oh, I this we've said this a lot that there is a huge mass appeal for crazy science fiction and world building.
Rym: And yet it seems like the majority of the people who are involved in the media production world are scared to death of both of those.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But then once they get a successful world, then they go apeshit all in there and try to cram as much as they can.
Rym: I know.
Scott: And at the same time here, the fans come in because they can come in with their fan fictions and their fan arts and their fan fans.
Rym: So what's the next book?
Scott: What is the next book?
Rym: Have you decided yet?
Rym: We can wait.
Rym: I waited before.
Scott: I know, you know, I was debating and such.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I actually recently read Ready Player One.
Scott: I'm not making that the book.
Scott: OK, good.
Rym: I want to read it, but not now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm just going to sum that up for you.
Scott: It's the game, the book.
Scott: It's a combination of Damon, which we did a book club book on, I think.
Scott: Right.
Scott: No, we didn't.
Scott: I thought we did.
Rym: We talked about you did a Geek Bite, I think.
Scott: Anyway, it's a combination of that book and the Woo game.
Scott: That's Ready Player One.
Scott: I think, uh, OK, let's just do this book.
Scott: So it's one of those popular things, right?
Scott: Everyone's always talking about the Haruki Murakami person.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like all I see.
Scott: everywhere is people reading these books and it's sort of like, you know, the crazy popular book that hasn't had the movie yet, or at least not that I know of.
Scott: So I'm you know, I'm not what the person's written so many books.
Scott: I'm not sure which one is like the starting one, but it seems like the most popular one is the one Q eighty four.
Scott: So I think we should read it just to see what the deal is.
Scott: And so let's read that.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I'm game.
Rym: I'll kindle it.
Rym: And if I can't kindle it, I'll pirate it.
Rym: Because I'm done.
Rym: I'm I'm pretty much done.
Scott: Kindle edition, Kindle edition.
Scott: Fifteen bucks.
Rym: OK, fine.
Scott: I don't know if I'm going to pay fifteen bucks.
Rym: The thing is, I don't hardcover 1798.
Rym: I don't want a physical thing.
Rym: I'm only buying from like.
Rym: I don't even want paperbacks anymore.
Rym: I'll buy a hardcover of a book that I'm not only going to read again in the future, but I'm going to reference occasionally and lend to people.
Scott: I'll get paperbacks.
Scott: But my new strategy is to get them, read them, give them away and get rid of them, let loan them to someone and just never ask for them back or book off or who knows what.
Rym: That's better off giving them.
Rym: I think you don't get enough money.
Scott: I'm just saying that's my new strategy.
Rym: I'm actually thinking about doing a book purge.
Scott: I'm definitely got to do a purge soon because I got too many.
Rym: I got too many everything I bought.
Scott: So I keep buying comics and I haven't read a lot of them.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, we read those fifty two.
Scott: We did and I have a stack of fifty two.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.