Rym: It's November 5th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and it's got Fox day Tonight, we're talking about.
Scott: you can go check yourself.
Rym: It's a box with a bomb.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Oh wait.
Rym: I guess you haven't seen slayers.
Rym: try yet.
Rym: You don't know about the fox with bombs.
Scott: You and your foxes bomb.
Rym: you're gonna like that box and his bomb.
Scott: I can imagine the fox with bombs.
Scott: I probably you know almost like.
Scott: it's like there's a picture of one of my brain, and I'm pretty sure it'll match up.
Scott: When I see the one that is the one you were talking about at one point gallery eats one of his bombs.
Scott: I think why wouldn't you?
Rym: he was hungry, so yeah, yeah But I remember the fifth of November primarily because that's when I got my first job in the financial sector and started making money.
Scott: I didn't remember at all until some tweets talked about how most people you know talk about it But don't actually know anything about it.
Rym: You know anything about it?
Scott: There was a dude named Guy Fawkes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: He was a crazy monarchist.
Scott: yes He tried to bomb the Parliament in England.
Scott: in London He put a bunch of gunpowder in some barrels in the basement, and he's about to light it.
Scott: They caught him pretty much yeah, and he's basically like the Unabomber And he sort of looked like the v-mask but not really.
Scott: but pictures of him look like that right the same way.
Scott: You know what we think George Washington looked like.
Scott: he probably looked a little different You know because you know paintings of them don't look exactly the way he looked.
Scott: I don't think there's any photographs of George Washington.
Scott: right well.
Rym: We gotta wait.
Rym: There's got to be some guy on a TV George Washington.
Scott: so on the fifth of November right the tradition in The UK is to you know wear the mask or whatever while you know making sort of a a dummy Out of you know to to be Guy Fawkes and then setting him on fire
Rym: as it burns like an effigy
Scott: as an effigy.
Scott: So sort of be like you know it'd be like if we have we maybe put a hoodie on a guy.
Scott: I was like it's the Unabomber.
Scott: Let's fuck him and set him on fire.
Scott: so the other Not in the literal sense One of the other nothing fucks like an effigy.
Scott: There's a hundred definitions of fuck.
Scott: We're not talking about the sexual one.
Rym: so the reason I think about it is that on October 5th the Fake Twitter account for Archer like the character Archer tweeted something about Guy Fawkes day.
Scott: I don't think you got it wrong.
Scott: Yep, was that an intentional joke or guessing?
Scott: it was person who had that account was dumb.
Scott: I don't remember the fifth of October.
Rym: I am guessing the latter, but someone responded elegantly and they were like ah yes the rhyme says it well remember remember the fifth of October.
Scott: Yeah Remember it well It was ten five and I'm sure it in 2015 someone's gonna be like oh my god It's 1015 2015. lots of ones and fives.
Rym: I was up in Albany this weekend.
Rym: I went to visit a distillery Okay, where they distill spirits, and I tried to say legal distillery was any moonshine.
Rym: So it was a legal one and the guy who runs it was totally chill.
Rym: one.
Rym: He was like this isn't moonshine.
Rym: and two.
Rym: he was like.
Rym: we asked him a lot of questions as Pete was there.
Rym: Pete You know Pete knows this stuff.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So one point where we had I think we asked him something like Does it matter if you do this and that in the distilling process?
Rym: He was like it doesn't matter for fucking shit.
Rym: You're distilling it.
Rym: You're removing 99% of anything that was in there.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: He was like we do what matters and we don't do what doesn't matter and he was totally chill in science Mm-hmm, so I bought a very large bottle of vodka made from apple cores.
Scott: I thought vodka is made from potatoes.
Rym: Well it can be made from basically anything vodka.
Rym: Here's the thing in the US Americans like vodka to be grain neutral meaning it tastes like Nothing, but alcohol because they use it to make silly frou-frou bullshit drinks, and they don't like the taste of alcohol But they want to get drunk.
Rym: that is a vodak tastes like so when an American you know when people say they like gray Goose or one of those like good vodkas.
Scott: They actually smelled that.
Scott: it smelled like alcohol.
Rym: Yeah, they want something that doesn't taste like anything.
Rym: so in Russia It smells like.
Scott: it tastes like alcohol.
Rym: in Russia good vodka tastes like fucking potatoes.
Scott: I imagined it does but in America It tastes like nothing even though potato tastes good.
Scott: would you agree?
Scott: potato chip baked potato right potato?
Scott: You would not want to eat a plain of raw potato that does not taste good.
Scott: You need to do something to it to make it not taste like that.
Rym: so anyway this core vodka is made from apple cores But it's not well.
Scott: apple cores on tastes like apple, and is there an arsenic situation.
Rym: No it's not arsenic It's cyanide for one either one which not only.
Scott: Not only is the percentage so small it doesn't matter.
Rym: yeah, so you read the name of the wind right.
Scott: yeah That comes up there.
Rym: I know the girl is like isn't there arsenic in this bullshit.
Rym: He's like.
Rym: well one It's actually cyanide.
Scott: I'm glad that you got my reference far too late thinking.
Scott: I was not making a reference.
Rym: I got the reference right away, however I knew you and I was wondering if you in fact had it wrong and forgot that that was brought up in the book.
Scott: No, I know.
Rym: I do enjoy however how the dragons going nuts And then they realize I go you can't save this with a book club episode.
Rym: There's basically a meth lab out here in the forest.
Rym: That was a good scene.
Rym: I like that.
Rym: yeah, I finished the book on the subway home, so okay about that.
Rym: I'll save that for the matter moment.
Scott: shall we move on?
Rym: yeah, we can move on but anyway I am drinking the Applejack right now because they made core vodka which tastes It's like vodka with a hint of Apple instead of a hint of potato.
Rym: It's really fucking good.
Scott: and to don't drink how much him what amount of it.
Scott: can you drink?
Scott: That's basically what proof is that?
Rym: It's 80 proof.
Scott: You're drinking a very small amount.
Rym: Yes, this is 40% so that much of this glass is pure Grain alcohol.
Scott: should you not maybe put something in there besides that?
Scott: no how about a slice of Apple?
Rym: I guess I could do that.
Scott: the thing is this is what variety of Apple Did they use?
Rym: you know what that was asked?
Rym: You know what the distiller said.
Rym: mm-hmm doesn't fucking matter.
Scott: What do you matters?
Rym: You it doesn't matter.
Scott: I say you make it twice once with Fuji once with.
Scott: yeah, you know what he's there.
Rym: You distill it.
Rym: There's no difference.
Scott: There's some Apple flavor in there is there not?
Scott: yes What Apple flavor does it taste like Apple?
Rym: So like the Apple do you want to try to say every time Apple this tastes like I?
Scott: It's probably tastes like Apple juices every Apple mixed together If you use only one kind of Apple in one and only what he uses.
Rym: cider apples whatever cider apples.
Rym: Yeah, you know what Apple Jack is I?
Scott: Apples that fell on the ground.
Rym: so it was a common because they're cheaper because they can't sell them to the grocers a common alcoholic beverage In Michigan.
Rym: basically what you do is you take you make a hard apple cider Freeze it and you cut the middle out of the barrel because that's the alcohol and it was like this freeze distillation.
Rym: So This is Apple Jack.
Scott: prefer the science lab distillation?
Rym: yes, so this is the science lab version of Apple.
Scott: Oh, not the freezing method.
Rym: No.
Scott: This is a lot of people try to do the freezing method in their freezers.
Rym: Yeah, not doing that that is moonshine moonshine style.
Rym: So yeah, I'm drinking my Apple Jack.
Rym: I'm digging it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I'm getting jacked up.
Rym: So you got some news.
Rym: you want to try some Apple Jack.
Rym: No.
Scott: I have a news.
Scott: So you know how I was.
Scott: I was complaining very recently about companies Not telling people for reasons when they fuck them over like got rid of all your Kindle books.
Scott: not gonna Tell you why yeah, or closed your account.
Scott: not gonna Tell you why just that.
Scott: we closed your account.
Rym: meanwhile while we talked about this You know last time my company when we you know hurricane happened We were operating out of our like business continuity plan BS Rather than pretending that was completely business as normal actually emailed every one of her customers.
Rym: We were like hey, we're working out of the backup data center, so yeah good job.
Scott: Yeah props to you.
Scott: so Twitter.
Scott: if somebody sent in a copyright complaint to Twitter.
Scott: We're just kind of crazy.
Scott: I'll get a hundred.
Scott: you could invalid You know bringing infringe a copyright 140 characters, but theoretically couldn't any retweet.
Scott: Don't even get into that.
Scott: We've talked about this but Twitter does receive DMC notices And they don't really want to have a legal team.
Scott: fight them like if I link to an illegal thing in a tweet.
Scott: Someone might send a DMC thing to take my tweet down even though my tweets just a link.
Scott: But Twitter is not gonna fight that for you.
Scott: right that is gonna Take you down because I don't give a shit.
Scott: yep So.
Scott: but what they used to do is just delete your fucking tweet.
Scott: because but the fuck right.
Scott: But now they are actually doing a good thing.
Scott: The good thing is let's say I tweet something and somehow I put I don't know in that 140 characters I fit all of Star Wars And Disney sends a DMCA notice like hey Scott's tweet has fucking all of Star Wars in it.
Scott: what the fuck right.
Rym: wait So if I tweeted the entire script of Star Wars 144 characters at a time Would they send individual notices for each one of them?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: and how many of them would they have to remove before?
Rym: I would say well I'm no longer infringing.
Scott: I'm sure Twitter must have some policy about the close your account after so many but anyway what they are doing now is they're not Gonna delete your tweet.
Scott: instead they put a special thing on your tweet, so of course no one can see it.
Scott: But you you can still see your tweet that it's there.
Scott: You know you made it.
Scott: You won't hallucinate.
Rym: What do they do about retweets of the tree tweet prior?
Scott: I'm sure it does the same thing, but what if it's the old style RT retweets?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: or a quote anyway I don't know, but what they also do is they put a notice there for you to see like hey Yo, dog this tweet was taken down because blah blah blah and weren't they doing something like that for like tweets?
Scott: Notice that was sent to Twitter to tell them to take it down is posted on chilling effects where you can go.
Scott: check it Out nice, so this is like.
Scott: Oh wait auto posted.
Rym: What do you mean like automatically posted on chilling effects?
Scott: I?
Scott: See the copyright notices Twitter receives can be seen on the chilling effects website.
Scott: nice That is exactly how you should handle that so you can go and if you get a tweet that is taken down You can go.
Scott: see why.
Scott: if you don't want your tweet taking down at all and you want to fight it Set up your own Twitter on your own computer.
Rym: Remember when we decided Twitter was BS, and we ran a laconica server.
Scott: It is BS that it's not Federated.
Scott: yeah, yeah, it's.
Scott: there's not much you can do about things.
Rym: We could use laconica and all of it's not that goodness.
Scott: No this something better will come along soon enough.
Rym: Well, I don't think it will soon enough.
Scott: Federation has won every bad.
Rym: Yes, it has.
Scott: however It's only a matter of time before Federation wins this battle.
Scott: give it ten no one.
Rym: Yeah, ten years that is neither soon nor enough.
Scott: How is that not soon?
Rym: It's soon on the scale of social change among old people among Technologists now that ten years from now is effectively like Mad Max far well here.
Scott: Well, let's see about this.
Scott: when did instant messaging exist?
Scott: when a wall came out?
Scott: 97.
Scott: I was using ICQ.
Scott: Okay Neither one of those is federated right.
Scott: so let's give it 97 right.
Scott: 95 97 Right somewhere in there mid 90s.
Scott: When did G chat win?
Rym: It's hard to say because I kind of stopped using.
Rym: I am as AOL died.
Scott: you mean you used each head.
Rym: now I used each head But it doesn't actually serve the same purpose because the vast majority of people I know are never logged into it And I can't chat with them.
Scott: I'm just saying when did it win?
Scott: it didn't win.
Rym: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: did AOL and ICQ in my life were replaced with fucking nothing.
Scott: G chat won I'd say when I used name Scott.
Rym: I had like 300 people on my list and I knew all of them who would talk to them.
Rym: right now there are 14 people online in my list and another like 20 that are not online And you know what the majority of them are g-plus contacts who don't ever respond if I message them.
Scott: Pretty sure Google Chat won sometimes shortly after you're out of college.
Scott: You didn't win 06 so it took about 10 years like to not win.
Rym: It didn't win.
Scott: it won.
Rym: It didn't replay didn't do what it did before.
Scott: it does what it did before.
Scott: Well, just not just cuz you're not using it the same way.
Rym: You know, I am using it the same way.
Rym: The problem is everyone else I know and knew is not.
Scott: that's not my problem.
Scott: It's still the other instant messaging.
Scott: things have faded.
Scott: the G chat has elevated.
Rym: that is all that is therefore So the the previous world order disappeared and a very very pale simulacrum of that world order Instead of your craziness so long time ago as in October.
Rym: no, no, no, I'm gonna go even older.
Scott: even remember.
Scott: remember the October September 22nd.
Rym: There was news posted and people were talking about.
Rym: now the headlines were Ermagerd Ubuntu has Amazon ads Pre-installed.
Scott: let me just cheat you this link.
Rym: Yeah Chat I can.
Rym: I can listen.
Scott: you continue with your news here.
Scott: Stop diverting.
Rym: I'm just saying no one else does.
Scott: You're diverting Just repeating the same thing.
Scott: if I message everyone who's not gonna make that the whole show repeating the same thing over and over again?
Scott: That could be a show.
Scott: go back to your news.
Rym: Okay, so Ermagerd Ubuntu is gonna have Amazon ads in it.
Rym: now, of course true.
Rym: Yes, the majority of people who saw that at first were like no that is clearly some sort of hyperbolic.
Rym: No, it's true.
Rym: It's true straight up true.
Rym: So the deal is if you use Ubuntu Ubuntu 1210 or newer And you use that little - search feel like in Windows and I start like right now.
Rym: I start typing like I don't know putty Up there.
Rym: it is a found putty on my file system.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So now I'm going to determine.
Rym: Yeah if I do that equivalently It'll find putty.
Rym: I guess I don't need putty in Ubuntu.
Scott: It'll also give you a link to buy silly putty on Amazon.
Scott: And if you buy silly putty Amazon gets affiliate dollars.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So it's like if you type in terminal I tried this you get you know The link to click on to open your terminal.
Rym: you also get this like terminal you can buy for a dollar.
Scott: Well, you also get like terminal 5 the band by their album.
Rym: So one This is stupid.
Rym: Yeah - it's useless to anyone smart.
Rym: three.
Rym: It's only gonna piss off nerds who are a full half of Ubuntu's user base a full 90% now because I think the other half is grandmas and parents and Cheap people who for whom the neighborhood kid or grandson gave them a computer with Ubuntu on it.
Scott: that happens But I believe it is rarer than I
Rym: think that happens more than you think because the nerds By and large seem to be doubling down in the other direction and are using like scientific Linux or other craziness And outside like in no one's
Scott: using that
Rym: in companies.
Rym: Most people use CentOS or Suzy still.
Scott: yeah, it's true.
Scott: It's in the you know, the bigger company.
Rym: as an aside.
Rym: I recently installed Ubuntu Ubuntu.
Rym: yeah, so just cuz I needed a Linux box to you know, do real computing on And I had previously used CentOS.
Rym: Oh my god - sent OS suck fucking ass for anything desktop Yep, or server.
Rym: Yep, but it would use not good as server either.
Scott: So the server but is not too bad depends on what you need to run if they have the package.
Rym: for yeah You want to use Tomcat anything?
Scott: No, you don't do that.
Scott: No bad choice granted.
Scott: It's hard to use Tomcat in any Linux But the Ubuntu one the default Tomcat if you have to get it is all weird.
Rym: But anyway, this was the thing.
Rym: and of course there was the major crazy outrage.
Rym: So there's the follow-up story of shuttleworth saying trust us.
Rym: We're trying to make shopping better.
Rym: No, you're not.
Rym: No, what you're trying to do is siphon Affiliate dollars from people who are dumb enough to go.
Scott: Oh, I guess I do need silly putty Mostly nerds who are going to use that default desktop, right?
Scott: It's.
Scott: but just doing anything it can to try to find a way to make money When the only product they have is a free.
Rym: now pretty reason I bring all this up is one.
Rym: the newest story There's the trifecta here is that the EFF has basically come out and said hey Ubuntu stop this bullshit make that disabled by default because independent of my Ideological complaints and my I don't want to see ads ever complaints.
Rym: I mean, there's a reason I use adblock.
Rym: Yeah, the operating system is sacred ground.
Rym: You don't fuck with that.
Rym: And while you're gonna say That is not the operating system for the majority of people that is the operating system as far as they're concerned.
Scott: Yes, but not by the technical definition of the term operating system Yes, but by the definition of software that is installed on your computer before you have chosen to install additional software.
Rym: Yes, so you the GNU Linux beard is in fact a hundred percent technically correct and useless For a normal person.
Rym: if they install they put the Ubuntu CD in.
Rym: when they're done They've got that's Ubuntu.
Rym: Yeah, whatever they see when they log in even the applications that aren't Ubuntu like Firefox.
Rym: so people have been afraid.
Rym: nerds have been afraid forever of Microsoft or Larry Ellison and all his bullshit putting ads in the operating system.
Rym: I know what you're trying to do Ubuntu But all you're doing is going up to a bunch of angry nerds and poking them with a sharp stick.
Rym: I don't have anything else to say about it Other than that.
Rym: the EFS concerns have nothing to do with that.
Rym: Their concern is simply yeah, so you're sending Amazon Information and then getting back results.
Scott: You're sending Amazon.
Scott: everything everyone types into Their.
Rym: so when the guy's typing like my little pony fanfiction because he's trying to find his folder of fanfiction Amazon's gonna see that and recommend things.
Rym: now Gmail does that too, but at least it's.
Rym: you're not typing my little pony fan You're not searching you're not using Gmail to search your own computer.
Rym: Yep so this is bad all around and it is possible to turn it off, but Even if it is it really reduces the trust of Ubuntu as a Linux distribution.
Scott: That's why this stuff like mint and shit.
Scott: Yeah, but in that desktop that you know, it's not really that good.
Rym: I don't like it at all.
Rym: But Windows 8 the metro that's not called metro anymore is just as bad in every account except for the fact that doesn't show me Ads, but that's a separate discussion Really?
Scott: I know a lot of people who upgrade to Windows 8 because it is better in some under-the-hood ways And it is disable the metro and just go straight to the regular.
Rym: now My fear is not that metro sucks because I can get around it.
Rym: My fear is that the desktop side of it will be deprecated.
Rym: Mmm and a UEFI and all that other stuff, but The reason I bring up this whole thing with Ubuntu is because it wound to what it says.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Is that desktop Linux is in fact dead and they need money or it will die?
Scott: Well is the thing I actually they do need money.
Scott: at least Ubuntu needs money, but what other desktop Linux is there?
Scott: Well, I think what I think what could happen?
Rym: we had the HTPC movement with boxy, but boxy went a little bastard.
Scott: Here's here's what I can see in the future.
Scott: Notice boxy didn't do too well with this.
Scott: Here's what I see in the future, right?
Scott: Normal peoples who only use their computers for normal type things.
Scott: Right They don't really aren't gonna need a laptop desktop.
Scott: They're gonna get by with a tablet phone.
Scott: Maybe some you know similar Apple TV kind of device in the TV something something right.
Scott: and The only thing desktops will be used for is people who need to do work and people want to play games.
Scott: And that's pretty much it.
Scott: and they're not gonna be.
Rym: you know No, when you say games you mean PC games the traditional sense not Angry Birds serious games, right?
Scott: So that's the only reason people are gonna have desktops to do work and play games.
Rym: So I'm here to do work and play games and in that all out of operating.
Scott: and in that sense, right?
Scott: I think Windows was gonna.
Scott: you know, it's just the library of games for Windows is so big.
Scott: it's gonna take a long time to make Windows not needed for games,
Rym: but I
Scott: Could see the newer versions of Windows being bad and the steam Linux coming on so strong such that You know in some number of years, maybe ten years, whatever the other thing I talked about will happen when Twitter's federated You will have you know, the games will come out for Linux because that's the only you know.
Scott: Modern operating you couldn't you?
Scott: there'll be a point at which you know Windows 7 can read you only.
Scott: you need to keep a Windows 7 around to run the vast library of old games But it won't be an operating system.
Scott: You can actually use for computing daily.
Scott: So you'll need to use Linux for that or OS X those be.
Scott: if OS X is even still around It could be all iOS by then.
Scott: You don't know.
Scott: so you're gonna run Linux and new games and your everyday computing.
Scott: Linux II and Windows will be around for your old games the same way.
Scott: Some people's love DOS for old games.
Rym: Well, we'll see there's.
Scott: there's another factor that are but most people won't even have a desktop.
Rym: our good friend Conrad Did link to an article recently that was actually very interesting the one that talked about how it argued that the shittier a person is Using computers the more powerful machine They actually need the.
Rym: the gist of it was that someone like me or Scott or some of you who are listening If I have a shitty ask him like a 486, I understand its limitations and I can deal with all of its limitations.
Rym: I know what I'm doing.
Rym: So some some crappy little netbook or like my laptop my new laptop It only has like 120 gigabytes of space total.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and that's fine for what I'm doing.
Rym: But if you gave that laptop just some random schmo using the computer that's usually those people.
Scott: they only have one computer.
Scott: That's their computer period.
Scott: they don't have most.
Rym: fill it up immediately.
Scott: with his iTunes collection and his torrents He doesn't know about things being stored in spaces or which hard drives filling up or right and his CPU He'd probably install.
Scott: Kansas spywares Need a bigger CPU and more RAM to make the computer not be useless after he's fucked it up.
Rym: So this tablet revolution I think is going to come back real in the next years.
Rym: The lockdown OS prevents them from fucking the shit up but at the same time Such they'll be locked into a hardware upgrade cycle.
Rym: That is more rapid than they were before.
Rym: They're gonna have a weak laptop or a weak tablet a year later one That's twice as fast comes out.
Rym: and because their old one is slow.
Rym: I mean even Android might my phone Slightly sluggish if I use some of the advanced stuff.
Scott: Yeah I needed to upgrade my iPhone 4 which is still otherwise Unserviceable to iPhone 5 so that I could play Super Hexagon.
Rym: So there's a lot of concerns around this but the moral is that desktop Linux is having some trouble.
Scott: Well, when is it not had trouble?
Scott: more so than ever.
Scott: but I think it's looking promising Even though Ubuntu is doing stupid shit into simply because everyone else is just abandoning even fighting them.
Scott: It's like, you know, they just sort of Linux just sort of hang in there.
Scott: Yeah kept being the loser.
Scott: It'd be like if every team quit the NFL except the Cleveland Browns.
Scott: They'd be like Super Bowl.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: That's what it's like.
Rym: But anyway things of the day We talked about on an episode we recorded that has not aired yet about pre-hoc and post-hoc trash talk.
Rym: So I am now right now 645 p.m.
Rym: Dateline Guy Fawkes day.
Rym: I am going to pre-hoc trash talk.
Rym: the 2012 presidential election.
Rym: my thing of the day is a video from last year When Obama won or last year last election four years ago when Obama won and it is get your war On which is a they do kind of good funny Rotoscoped animations about politics.
Rym: It's kind of like a webcomic but in YouTube form and They have one of the funniest videos ever.
Rym: This is the kind of thing that tomorrow when Obama wins the election one of the funniest videos ever.
Rym: No, but tomorrow.
Rym: this is funny in one context.
Rym: tomorrow when Obama wins the election You mail this a link to this to your scary conservative aunt or Scott Johnson's dad.
Rym: That is what you do, okay, it's pretty funny - mostly the whole - cheeky thing.
Rym: Yeah, so everybody knows whatever scares you the most.
Scott: it's football time and everybody knows it.
Scott: nerds even nerds.
Scott: You don't like football.
Scott: no Tecmo Bowl and Tecmo Bowl is in fact in my opinion the most fun Football related video game ever made especially Tecmo Super Bowl, right and the also not so often noticed super Tecmo Bowl.
Scott: Yeah, the Super Nintendo, but anyway Tecmo Super Bowl everybody knows that there's some guys out there Who are so into Tecmo Super Bowl that every year?
Scott: They update the rosters of all the teams and they have all these ROM hacks.
Scott: So you can play updated Tecmo Super Bowl all the time.
Scott: It's pretty great.
Scott: So the website for that is actually Tecmo Bowl org.
Scott: I just learned that.
Scott: but more importantly my thing of the day is that NFL Films, you know the pretty much the reason the NFL is popular made a Documentary about Tecmo Super Bowl that already aired on ESPN 2 and the NFL Network a bunch of times.
Scott: But I'm sure if you wanted to you could find it somewhere to watch it.
Scott: So I'm linking to Tecmo Bowl org.
Scott: Actually, I'll link to the post about this documentary on Tecmo Bowl org.
Scott: But yeah, you should go and watch this documentary because they interview all the guys, you know, who are always You know hacking the game and playing in Tecmo Bowl tournaments and all that kind of stuff and It is pretty cool.
Rym: So in the meta moment, we're gonna be at magfest.
Rym: fucking shit up.
Scott: That is a long-ass time for now.
Rym: Oh, it's November.
Rym: So Two months from now not that far long time.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX East.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX Australia.
Rym: We're gonna be at Anime Boston and And Connecticut in July, that's right.
Rym: Actually Connecticut is slightly before PAX Australia.
Scott: Okay, the book club book is still The name of the wind which now I know.
Scott: yes, you know the name of the way.
Rym: It's like not to spoil.
Rym: but there's a point in the book where someone's like say this word I'm like, oh that's the name of the wind.
Rym: and they're like, yes, that is the name of the wind that word right there Mm-hmm.
Rym: It was just there it is.
Rym: I can say it.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, the name of the wind is the book.
Scott: I guess Rym finished it cuz he knows the name of the wind.
Scott: So we'll be talking about that relatively soon.
Scott: and then Rym will pick something else probably awful Probably the Great Gatsby.
Rym: great because I want to read it before that movie comes out.
Rym: great supposedly a good book.
Rym: Or I could pick the second book in the name of the wind.
Scott: I'm gonna read it.
Scott: I bought it.
Rym: I have it sitting there cuz granted I got a tired of some of the Harry Potter crap that happened.
Scott: But otherwise You always like reviewing the book club book before the episode These goddamn books.
Scott: I don't think any of that amount of tantalizing is gonna help.
Rym: It's a pretty good book.
Scott: Anyway, uh Any other met?
Scott: Oh, I sent out the newsletter today.
Scott: Yeah I think I fixed the problem where the text version is not screwed up.
Scott: Apparently there's a button you have to click to update the text version after you edit the HTML version.
Scott: Well, why do I have to click that button?
Scott: Seriously?
Scott: It should be automatic.
Scott: But Yeah, I said the newsletter.
Scott: if you want to email questions for the newsletter or fan art We really also need for the newsletter.
Scott: You just email that shit.
Scott: GeekNights at frontrecruit.com.
Scott: People seem to like the newsletter.
Scott: no one's ever unsubscribed from it.
Rym: Yeah follow the.
Rym: You know the Twitter.
Rym: follow all our business.
Rym: follow the YouTube channel.
Rym: watch out because as soon as new my little pony starts Radio free equestria is starting.
Rym: legit episode by episode.
Scott: My little pony when when is that starting?
Rym: that's coming up pretty soon.
Rym: How soon?
Scott: how soon would that be?
Rym: How many days?
Rym: I don't remember?
Scott: You don't remember how many days it is.
Rym: No, I guess I told you it was five days.
Rym: Oh Well, I am drinking Applejack as we speak.
Scott: that's what is it.
Scott: was it pony countdown calm or something up pony?
Scott: Pony countdown calm.
Scott: I still get four days 15 hours 9 minutes and 40 something seconds.
Scott: I was recording.
Rym: I get more Correspondence about fucking radio free equestria where we did like 13 episodes that I get about anything else I've ever done in my life except for Pony countdown just because.
Rym: But yeah for all of you who bother me all the time about that.
Rym: Yes, we're doing it.
Rym: We're starting a season of it in Four days and 15. well 15 hours plus the length of one episode plus however long it takes us to record an episode And put it online which is pretty quick.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I actually streamlined my process.
Rym: Okay, so Let's So hit relay chat.
Scott: Yeah, we're supposed to do an episode on this.
Scott: So I'll admit the idea we got so Way way back in the day.
Rym: I was really big.
Rym: I gotta get away from this pony countdown because I'm just staring at it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's a long time ago.
Rym: I Wanted to get on the internet And I didn't know how.
Rym: we had prodigy classic Mm-hmm there.
Rym: you couldn't get on the internet from there and I didn't know what the internet was.
Rym: So I remember trying to get went to the library and tried to find books on the internet and I start.
Rym: I vaguely learned about ISPs and ARPANET, but I couldn't quite figure it out and I'd log into like BBS's and chat with people and all this stuff.
Rym: I didn't ever actually use IRC Until I was in high school.
Rym: All right, I didn't use it that much.
Rym: Okay, because I by the time I learned about IRC and started using it I already had ICQ which 100% replaced it for me.
Rym: Yeah, I Used IRC more in RIT than I used it at any other place in my entire life.
Scott: I keep using.
Scott: my use of IRC is increase decrease increase decrease.
Scott: It goes up and down back and forth back and forth.
Scott: All right, but basically, you know back in the day I was much like you You know, I learned internetting Actually learned HTMLs before I had internets at my house at summer camp.
Scott: I learned the HTMLs at Netscape.
Rym: I was in the same boat.
Rym: I was in middle school and a guy was like I learned how to program and I was like what right?
Scott: So anyway, I went.
Scott: you know when I got AOL's at my house I wanted to use Netscape instead of this.
Scott: I knew that this browser and AOL was no good, you know.
Scott: So I learned you could run nets you could minimize AOL and just open up Netscape.
Rym: See, I never used AOL.
Rym: So I went straight from Prodigy to oh my god fucking internet.
Scott: Yeah Then I had it fucking internet.
Scott: after that I just had to dial up into the local phone company up when I had my own computer upstairs.
Scott: But anyway, you know once I learned you could do that.
Scott: I was like, hey, are there other programs that you can just run to?
Scott: Use the Internet.
Scott: So, of course, you know, I was using the chats inside of AOL But they were sort of very restricted by AOL.
Scott: So I discovered IRC and I was like, oh you get this M IRC program and look at all these chats about things.
Scott: Now
Rym: even as late as when we were in high school it's interesting because IRC and Usenet were two there are things now that the only people who really know about them and use them to this day are really old people usually with beards or Young punk kids who are in the like darknet of like super piracy
Scott: or super tech people
Rym: or child pornographers.
Scott: Yeah, people in the who doing dark evil things.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So even as late as when we were in high school IRC and Usenet still worked the way they were intended to a large degree Yep, but then they were ruined by things we'll talk about.
Scott: Well IRC mostly works the way as its intended.
Scott: Yeah, well the thing is bad news groups not as much.
Scott: but some news groups still do especially like the Academic ones that you know, people are still on like comp Lang something something.
Scott: this, you know If you're at a university that still has a news group server You can use that the old-school way you can.
Rym: but the problem with IRC Just talk about IRC not get into the additional problems of BBS's.
Rym: Yeah, and Usenet was that let's do using this.
Rym: Yeah So the way IRC works in the same way email does in that it was designed in an era when no one really Considered the possibilities of things like spam.
Rym: Yeah It was just all right, I'm gonna run an IRC server.
Rym: Hey Scott you run an IRC server - I'll tell you what Let's.
Rym: uh, let's join our server.
Rym: So all my channels show up on yours and vice versa and all our users can just chat.
Scott: Yeah, I mean who wants to connect to a server so far away where there's gonna be this big-ass delay, right?
Scott: Why would we?
Scott: you know that that's so annoying and if you want to chat with someone on one server and also chat with Someone on another server that kind of sucks is nice.
Scott: I suddenly have you're from your local computer.
Scott: You have to connect to all these different servers.
Scott: that fucking sucks.
Scott: instead Everyone can connect to one server right the one closest to them and join any channel.
Scott: They want to talk to anyone they want.
Scott: and if there's anyone who you want to talk to someone who's on it You know connected to a different server the servers will talk to each other, you know And no one needs to make these, you know multiple connections in their house clogging up the whole internet.
Rym: So there were big like.
Rym: there were semi-private.
Rym: IRC is like there were completely cordoned off.
Rym: IRC is like chunks of servers that would talk together and they have their own rules their Culture their own whatever.
Rym: but there are also a very large kind of Universal IRC networks the XM alternate server F net alternate down that there's basically big groups of IRC servers.
Scott: They have servers all over the world.
Scott: Yeah, and they all those servers are basically effectively the same server.
Scott: you connect to them and You see every channel.
Scott: that's on every one of those servers with every user and you can join any channel and talk to anyone.
Rym: Now think about that.
Rym: think of it how hard it is for example in the modern internet to ban One person from a network like that where all these servers are completely federated.
Rym: I'm running an IRC server.
Rym: if the network trusts me it trusts me.
Scott: Yep You have to send that ban to every single server.
Scott: So they all know that you're banned.
Rym: and even then what do you ban?
Rym: You can just change your nickname all the time.
Rym: You gotta ban some fucking IPs.
Scott: I change which IP I'm coming from Cuz I use a VPN.
Rym: now I get a ban entire net mask.
Scott: But now I'm using a VPN.
Scott: the tons of other people are using cuz it's like some.
Scott: It's you know, it's one of those tour things.
Scott: You can't ban it the whole thing.
Rym: Yep Well, you can maybe in some.
Rym: so now look at this problem.
Rym: to have a relatively usable IRC network Maybe you just fucking ban all those services.
Scott: never very restrictive No, instead what people do is they just let IRC go nuts.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is IRC was always this kind of Wild West place.
Rym: I mean the when I was hanging out in IRC when I would idle in high school, which basically IRC is the Idle relay protocol.
Rym: Well, it's so weird.
Scott: right back in those days those 90s and you chatted You turned your computer on you dialed in first of all.
Scott: Yep, you would open the chat and you would be looking at it.
Scott: That's all you would be doing is looking at the chat and chatting Occasionally, I'd be especially leaves.
Rym: at the same time I'd be like chatting with my magic friends in the magic room.
Scott: Maybe such a limit you a lot of role-playing chats would happen.
Scott: I guess those still happen.
Rym: I did a lot of that a lot of Forgotten Realms rope.
Rym: I'm sorry for God hidden items.
Rym: Correct.
Scott: That's correct Okay, but nowadays people don't do that, right?
Scott: But what do people do?
Scott: Well, in fact, you know, I've said this before nowadays We're talking 10 years ago - yeah, alrighty.
Scott: Well, but I'm saying is that nowadays people Sort of Twitter in my eyes has replaced the need of IRC, right?
Scott: It's you don't have to pay attention to all the time.
Scott: It's basically Twitter is one big chat room and the whole world is in the chat room.
Rym: Well, but I'm really in a chat room that consists of the list of all the people on subscribe But by default everyone is on mute.
Scott: So you basically join this chat room with everyone in the world in it and they're all on mute and then you unmute Individual people and that's Twitter, right?
Scott: So what IRC is?
Scott: basically?
Scott: everyone is not on mute by default.
Scott: But you go into a channel that doesn't have everyone in the world, you know, you go through the channel.
Scott: There's a few people who care about the same thing you care about And that, you know, but usually what happens is, you know, you go to a channel But the people in that channel, they're in there, but they're not at the computer right now.
Scott: They're doing something else like browsing the web or playing a game.
Scott: They just want to hang out in the channel.
Scott: So everyone's hanging out, but not saying anything.
Scott: But then if you need to say something you go in there and say it and there's no response.
Scott: But then later someone might come and look and notice.
Scott: Oh, someone said something and then respond.
Rym: You got to idle.
Rym: You got to just hang out in the room.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't hang out in there, you might miss when someone says something, right?
Scott: So now the way people use IRC is so messed up is now it's interesting.
Rym: You know talk about.
Rym: I like old.
Rym: I am the reason I hated AOL so much was that ICQ did a lot of that stuff.
Rym: like ICQ I could send messages to people who weren't online.
Rym: No I could start a chat room that people will come and go and I actually once ICQ really caught on I use that.
Rym: For I've spawned chat rooms and have 20 people in them all the time and I basically stopped using IRC.
Scott: Yeah, so but I see had other features You know that are Like like wars of like trying to flood someone out of a channel or bots and things crazy.
Rym: net split bullshit.
Rym: We're suddenly the channel like splits in two because the network had a problem.
Scott: Yeah that yeah.
Scott: Well, so a net split right.
Scott: we said an IRC is when there's.
Scott: you know You have all these servers that are all part of the same net.
Rym: Yeah, say I'm connected to my own IRC server that I run connected to alternate and my servers trusted alternate.
Rym: So we're chatting with each other.
Rym: There's much people in the room.
Rym: say my server loses its upstream connection to alternate.
Rym: Well, suddenly I'm still in my room with all the people who are connected to my server and all the servers connected to me in The tree up to the point where I lost the connection and Scott's connected to alternate with all those people.
Rym: So we're both in the same room but we see a different list of people and we see we're talking you.
Scott: they can't see what I'm saying and he can't see what He's saying because we're separated and then eventually when the internet comes back We'll be reconnected.
Rym: now Woe betide when like the the op in the room gets split away and then like someone else Abuses op to fuck up the room and then the rooms recombine.
Scott: Yeah, I are see, you know, unlike other chats has this sort of inherent structure of you know controlling the room being the operator You know who can ban people and kick people and set the title and yeah all the and gets all these privileges and setting who?
Rym: Has which caused a weird sort of social structure where like the people who had that little plus next to the name were just they Were the nobility they were better people.
Scott: Yeah, there's the you know, the the technology of how the rooms are managed, you know sort of you know Created this social structure around it that matched, you know It wasn't the other way around.
Scott: like we come up with the social structure we want and then we make the technology fit that They just sort of made this technology chance serve listserv stuff to manage.
Scott: you know who's in what rooms who controls the rooms and channels and From that came how you have to manage an IRC which is annoying because you really have no other choice.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: if you don't like the way PHP BB does it you can switch and use vanilla.
Scott: It's like this IRC.
Scott: in this IRC, you know, you can't switch to some other non IRC thing that does it differently.
Scott: But yeah, I mean you could I guess come up with.
Scott: you know, right your own chance or Bob but no one's gonna do that.
Scott: That's effectively part of IRC Right.
Rym: But it's interesting that again all this culture like.
Rym: there were ways to like block people ban people deal with stuff But it was very wild Westy And if you were smart enough you could get around any ban any problem.
Rym: You can always get in and fuck shit up and flood people.
Rym: There was no way to prevent it and that's why protocols like this like email the idea of spam is a problem because email
Scott: is
Rym: A very similar system by my email server has to trust any email it gets And the best we can do is rely on blacklists and like heuristic searches and things to identify spam.
Rym: There's no sort of Inherent rate limiting in the protocol.
Rym: meanwhile AOL instant messenger being a sort of private proprietary thing Had that rate limit.
Rym: if I chat at you too much and you're not responding Maya eventually won't let me chat at you anymore.
Scott: Yeah, well, you're only connecting to the AOL server.
Rym: It knows they control everything.
Scott: Yeah, well, there's so many servers, right?
Scott: You can hit each one once.
Rym: this is the power of IRC You can have this.
Rym: IRC is really useful in my opinion.
Rym: nowadays along with BBS is for subverting Bad governments getting information around barriers and sharing things that are difficult or illegal to share.
Scott: Yeah Well, it's so weird right.
Scott: on the one hand There's nothing about IRC that makes it any more or less secure than web or anything like right?
Scott: It's just you're sending text over your internet wire, you know.
Scott: You could put encryption or some sort of tunnel on it with some other technology.
Scott: But now I mean, it's no different than the web.
Scott: It's just a different protocol of bits going over TCP IP.
Rym: There's just so much going on and it's such a distributed structure.
Rym: It's very hard to police it.
Scott: Yeah, and the real big thing is that it's you know, most people when they use the internet quote, right?
Scott: All the only applications that they really use on there, you know locally are the web browser, you know Almost 90% of everything is in the web browser.
Scott: Maybe they have a desktop email client like outlook.
Scott: Maybe something like iTunes will use some internet, right?
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Scott: so all these other applications that are internet protocols It's like just because the fact that most people don't know about them or use them Sort of makes them hidden from the public.
Scott: just because they're not something that people know about You can just download them and use them for free no problem.
Rym: this day I have access to an internal IBM like straight-up listserv and there's just awesome tech discussions in there.
Scott: But it's like people just don't know about listserv so much except tech people.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So that whole part of the internet is super hidden away just by the nature of its obscurity and inaccessibility user interface and marketing which at the same time lends it a sort of mystique.
Rym: which is why I think like our own IRC channel is actually pretty popular and people nerds who use IRC because it's kind of this cool thing like the Super mundane people will never use IRC yeah, but the kind of slightly more hip people on the internet will use it because it's kind of a status symbol.
Rym: and Once you're in IRC, it's interesting how the culture of IRC use Seems to have like like I know I've seen people hanging out in these chat rooms who clearly never used IRC in the 90s.
Rym: And yet they sort of Rediscover the same culture the the it's.
Rym: we did that lecture.
Rym: the game makes the community the medium Makes the community in this case IRC community sort of forms the same way no matter who's using it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, it's just.
Scott: you know, there's a whole bunch of things like this, you know news groups also how because it's you know Hidden quote hidden.
Scott: It's not actually hidden, but it's just not.
Scott: you know, it doesn't put itself out there marketing wise And it doesn't put itself out there user interface like the hole-in-the-wall restaurant that no one knows about right?
Scott: It's like you have to know about it You have to learn how to use it and you have to Intentionally go do it to get in there.
Rym: that when you're using it You sort of get this false feeling that you're in a hidden secret place And as you learn the details like once you realize that you change your nickname you start learning those slash commands.
Rym: you get this.
Rym: Not necessarily false.
Rym: But you get this sense of accomplishment that you've learned an archaic skill Much like how people use those fucking Bloomberg terminals feel really proud of themselves that they know how to use that terrible UI.
Scott: So what you get is you get you know Pretty much you get free node where open source people chat about their open source projects.
Scott: You get like, you know channels for Ubuntu.
Scott: pretty much every open source project the universe has a channel on free node and what they use it for is You know Usually the overall discussion on an open source project is gonna happen on a news group newsletter Not a news group a newsletter.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: or listserv and they might have a forum somewhere.
Scott: Maybe they might have a bug tracker which has certain things.
Scott: but the IRC is Usually gonna be where you know, the real-time action happens.
Scott: You have a problem.
Scott: You need to get the answer right now.
Scott: You couldn't find it on Google.
Scott: You couldn't wait for it.
Scott: on Stack Exchange You go to the IRC channel for the thing.
Scott: you are the developers who actually work on the thing You know need to discuss and it's too slow for them to discuss in forums.
Scott: So they're always in the dev IRCs the big Ubuntu Ubuntu dev separate channel for the people who work on Ubuntu sitting in there hanging out talking about stuff You know because there's too many of them to use like an I am conversation.
Scott: Yeah, right You need to talk to all these people at once.
Scott: you're on some sort of team that needs to real-time communicate with each other.
Scott: All right, and these are the things that IRC still does and there really aren't any other chats out there.
Scott: You know the the I am protocols that are there.
Rym: They're too ephemeral.
Scott: You see anyone using G chat to have a real-time chat?
Rym: I do but again Right.
Rym: Yeah, I do often but it's very ephemeral and it lacks a lot of.
Scott: Yeah, you could use hangout but hangouts got like this video chat on it.
Scott: that's like when you start a hangout.
Scott: That's a temporary, you know thing that's gonna have a start and an end time.
Scott: It's like for a meeting and IRC is like an always-on You know discussion between multiple people's.
Scott: it's logged.
Scott: There's bots to do helpful things in there.
Scott: Right, you know and it's this really.
Scott: nothing else has been able to compete with it in any way.
Scott: And even if you did make something that all the features but how to use their interface is accessible Perhaps web-based perhaps a nice application.
Scott: There's so much already in IRC.
Scott: You couldn't get people to you know bail out of it Especially, you know with that network aspect.
Scott: That's really the thing is that you know You're you sign up you connect to this IRC network to join You know free node and you're always connected to the KDE channel because you're in the KDE community, right?
Scott: Well, you're already connected to freenode all the time.
Scott: And now you have a question for someone who works on I don't know Firefox, I guess the Firefox channels also on freenode.
Scott: I think they have a Mozilla one.
Scott: It's separate but you know the channel for the other open source project you need to question about is also on freenode.
Scott: so you're already on there too.
Scott: and now you're in two channels all the time and it just spreads like that.
Scott: and You know, you you would have to literally bring every single channel off of every IRC network to put any dent in that.
Scott: It's probably gonna hang around Forever.
Scott: Yeah, and as long as TCP IP is used and I think the culture is going to Persevere through all of that time as long as this Internet's is gonna be IRC.
Scott: So it it might be worth your time.
Scott: I mean, I you know, I used it.
Scott: I didn't use it.
Scott: I use it.
Scott: You know, sometimes I went in there to get files You know in the sort of dark ages of peer-to-peer like after Napster died But before BitTorrent came out I was using IRC to get animes and things like that.
Scott: But now, you know, some people still say IRC is the best place to get stuff Because people don't always make torrents of everything.
Scott: but you know the fansubbers themselves run the IRC channels where you can get everything But they're usually ops.
Rym: so you have to get in there.
Scott: good grace and then people ability and then people do weird stuff like they'll have.
Scott: You know, they'll have like ratios like you have to.
Scott: you know They'll have like these file servers.
Scott: in IRC you submit files to the file server like, okay I got to upload an anime So you upload it and get credits and you can use the credits to download some other anime But you can't upload something they already got Right and you're sort of contributing to this guy's file store needed to trade files.
Scott: Even though it's digital bits that are free I don't people trade them.
Rym: if you're going to get an idea of what now while some of these are somewhat fabricated Remember bash.org?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I'll link to it.
Rym: Just go here and read everything on the page I'm about to link to.
Rym: that's actually kind of what IRC is like.
Scott: Yep So I don't know.
Scott: there's much more we can say about IRC.
Scott: We're looking for Monday show ideas.
Scott: send them in.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand ok for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: as long as I wear this I'm able to cast the three spells simultaneously.
Scott: Remember, this is dangerous kid.
Rym: So don't try it at home.