Rym: It's Monday, February 13th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we'll blank destroy the free internet.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: And the answer's no, but we'll get to that.
Rym: So I went skiing over the weekend, and snow was kind of shitty, because it's been warm.
Rym: So I decided, alright, I can't do my fun stuff the whole time.
Rym: Well, it's slightly above freezing, so they couldn't make snow.
Rym: It's all like ice and shit.
Rym: So I decided I'll take a lesson.
Rym: So I go over and I stand, like they line up, they have all these different icons, and you stand at the level of your ability, like what you're trying to learn next.
Rym: So I stood at the far end of super advanced, I want to learn whatever you can teach me about the crazy bullshit on the backside of the mountain.
Rym: And the instructors are all kind of standing there, and one of them looks up and sees me standing there, and taps another guy on the shoulder and points at me.
Rym: And then they all start looking at me and talking and huddling.
Rym: And then I see a paper, rock, scissors, and then this older guy comes over, because apparently nobody ever takes the advanced lessons at Hunter Mountain.
Rym: Like, it's so rare that they were fighting over who got to do it, because it's the difference between 90 minutes of telling kids how to not fall over on the bunny slope, or jumping crazy off the back mountain doing crazy bullshit.
Scott: Right, but it's like, do these guys actually, are they actually super pros who are qualified?
Rym: Yes, they are certified pros.
Scott: Because I mean, you go to Hunter Mountain because it's close.
Scott: I mean, I don't ski, but I know that's not the awesomest, bestest mountain there is.
Rym: You know, it is the awesomest, bestest mountain within a day trip of New York City.
Scott: Yeah, but as overall mountains go, it's not like it's the fucking Alps, or Vermont, or pretty good, for what it is.
Rym: Yeah, the top 500.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot of dinky, like in Beacon, there was a place like 30 minutes from us called Thunder Ridge.
Rym: Thunder Ridge had like two trails.
Rym: Mount Beacon used to be a ski resort.
Scott: Is that like those two waterslide water parks?
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: Yeah, but no, they're like super legit pro instructors, because a lot of the race teams like practice at Hunter, and then they go compete all over elsewhere, and all this stuff.
Rym: But this was a real lesson, and it was difficult, and it was fun.
Scott: Yeah, they had the same shit at like golf courses.
Scott: You get the pro, whatever.
Scott: Anyway, so I gotta read you this email I just got at 5.18 PM.
Scott: "Dear lottery registrant,
Scott: congratulations.".
Rym: Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Rym: I think I won that same lottery.
Scott: You know the Powerball was $350 million, right?
Scott: "You have been selected to...".
Scott: You know, I'm gonna read it.
Scott: You got the same email?
Rym: I got the same email.
Rym: "Participate in the 2012 TD 5 borough bike
Rym: tour.".
Scott: Oh, dammit.
Rym: In fact, everyone in my office who signed up for the lottery also got it.
Scott: I have a feeling that there were so many prizes that everyone wins, and almost nobody loses.
Rym: I'm pretty excited about this.
Rym: I think it'll be fun.
Scott: The only thing was, it was annoying.
Scott: It's like, "Yeah, you can't bring a camera if you're in
Scott: it.".
Scott: And I was like, "Shit, I kind of want to take pictures of the bike
Scott: tour.".
Scott: I'm gonna... I can't take pictures of the bike tour and tour, but I have a feeling it's not hard, because they were like, "You can bring a
Scott: kid.".
Scott: And I'm like, "Oh, this is gonna be
Scott: easy.".
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: They have a shortcut thing they do for people who can't do the whole thing.
Scott: Oh, I'm not gonna take any shortcuts, but I'm not expecting to keep up with any Lance Armstrong types.
Rym: I'm looking.
Rym: I might just try to slip my GoPro in.
Scott: Oh, I don't know.
Scott: Maybe they'll let you do that.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: I didn't read the fullness of the rules, so I gotta go through all that.
Rym: I also gotta get to... I think I'm gonna use my bike.
Scott: I'm not gonna rent a road bike, I don't think you need that bike.
Scott: But who knows about it?
Rym: But I am gonna push it.
Rym: I'm gonna try to go as fast as I can.
Scott: I'm gonna try to go as fast as I can.
Rym: And more importantly, I gotta get a smaller CamelBak, because the CamelBak I got is like...
Scott: I think I might not even wear it, right?
Scott: It's because you can just grab waters on the way, because you get services.
Rym: We could just get away with having one water bottle.
Scott: We just need someone to be in the park or at the end or something with our shit, like your wallet.
Scott: Well, I guess you got to bring your wallet with you, but I need somebody to be there.
Rym: I'm not bringing my wallet.
Rym: I'm bringing a $20 bill and my driver's license with a rubber band.
Scott: You need someone, you know, to have your keys and all that stuff at the end of the thing.
Rym: One key, rubber banded.
Scott: I need like three keys.
Scott: You get the idea.
Rym: Yeah, I get the idea.
Scott: Your phone.
Scott: You need someone to be there to help you who's not biking.
Rym: I'm bringing my phone, because I want to do a GPS track on my whole track.
Rym: In fact, I did that when I was skiing.
Rym: I actually ran the GPS and got these great graphs.
Scott: Where are you gonna put it on you?
Rym: Pocket.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: I'll put it on one of those shoulder mount things.
Scott: Anyway, you know, I entered that lottery exactly 15 minutes before it closed.
Rym: Eleven minutes for me.
Scott: One of my coworkers- I think it actually might have been five, I don't remember.
Rym: I was like, oh, because I didn't even know the deadline was that day until they- I didn't even know it was the thing that existed.
Rym: I knew it existed.
Rym: Until you messaged me.
Rym: I never tried to sign up for it.
Rym: I messaged you because my coworker was like, oh shit, the deadline's now.
Scott: You messaged me and I was like, what is this thing?
Scott: And then I saw that the deadline was in five minutes and I was like, whatever the fuck it is, I'm signing up.
Scott: I don't care.
Rym: So I got a brief news, just because I gotta reiterate this.
Rym: Wi-Fi has no measurable health effects.
Rym: Stop being weird about this.
Rym: In this case, my admonition goes to Ontario, particularly an Ontario teachers union.
Scott: You're admonishing admonition.
Rym: Admonishment.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: It is directed at you, this teachers union is trying to get Wi-Fi banned in the school because of the deleterious health effects.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Wi-Fi is perfectly safe.
Scott: The only things you have to worry about are AM radio.
Scott: FM radio.
Rym: Oh my god, AM radio is the worst.
Scott: What about- Airplane radar, naval sonar.
Rym: So a lot of these kids, in fact a lot of the teachers, have devices in their pockets and in their pockets these devices are transmitting at orders of magnitude more power.
Scott: Cellphones.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Those are all dangerous.
Scott: What about that- Wi-Fi is totally safe.
Rym: What about that crazy ball of fusion in the sky spewing crazy radiation.
Scott: I said solar radiation.
Rym: Cosmic ray.
Rym: The thing is, I don't need to even say why.
Rym: this is BS.
Rym: Like it's ludicrous.
Scott: The odds are that a cosmic ray hit you today.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: In fact, once when I was at IBM and once when I was at that broker dealer on Wall Street, at both companies at one point we had an event that we could literally only describe as and in fact officially document it as a bit flip caused by a cosmic ray.
Scott: It could have been caused by any number of things that wasn't a cosmic ray.
Rym: Well the thing is, bit flips are pretty rare.
Scott: Why didn't you have ECC?
Rym: I don't want to get into it.
Rym: We didn't have ECC.
Scott: ECC statistically protects you from 99.99% of any cosmic rays.
Scott: Because the odds of the cosmic rays hitting both spots simultaneously.
Rym: Back when I was working at IBM, RAM that supported ECC, there was a lot of trouble with compatibility in different motherboards and things.
Scott: By servers they already have it.
Rym: Yeah, and there were problems with that.
Scott: Even Apple computers already have it.
Scott: Yes, and back then- The expensive Mac Pro has it.
Rym: Scott, this was in like 2003 or 2004 maybe.
Scott: Even then you could have gotten it.
Rym: Yeah, and there were firmware issues where it wasn't compatible.
Rym: so the ECC had to be disabled.
Scott: Let's continue.
Scott: Let's just do the show about ECC instead.
Rym: That'd be a good show.
Rym: We could talk about the hamming too.
Rym: Hamming algorithm.
Scott: That's all you.
Rym: Yeah, you don't know it?
Rym: No.
Rym: By heart?
Scott: No.
Rym: It removes single bit errors in transmissions trivially.
Rym: With okay overhead.
Rym: The hamming code.
Rym: It's basically a primitive checksum.
Scott: With pigs.
Rym: So yeah, this Ontario's teachers union is full of randy woo woo bullshit and I just wanted to point this out.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So there's a lot of online edumacations going on, right?
Scott: And I mean there's many different kinds of online edumacation.
Scott: You can take online classes which typically is there's a professor who gives you assignments via document sharing and there's a forum discussion and maybe there's video lectures and they're awful and they're just bullshit ways to get credit without actually learning anything.
Scott: And then there's online classes like OpenCourseWare where okay we put all the course materials online, teach yourself.
Scott: And then there's like video stuff like that Khan Academy and there's of course.
Scott: just there isn't actually a structured class.
Scott: You just go on the internet and learn things which is what I do all day every day.
Scott: But MIT has something new and this one actually looks pretty good.
Scott: This is MIT launches free online fully automated course.
Scott: It's called MITx.
Scott: And you take a course and the course is completely automated in that you take assignments, you hand them in, it grades you, it tells you what to do, it's step by step sort of thing.
Scott: And you know this thing doesn't really exist and they say that it is not watered down or any less intense than the real university program.
Scott: So it's like the computer just is like teaching you and only you and you have to do all this work and everything.
Scott: So I'm kind of curious you know for someone to test this out and see if it's any if you actually get a certificate for completing it because it's not like you can just complete it because it's not easy.
Scott: You have to actually do the work.
Scott: And the only one they have right now is an electronics course beginning in March which is real soon.
Rym: But I could do some electronics like.
Rym: what level is this at?
Scott: It's a university level MIT electronics course.
Rym: Yeah but like electronics.
Rym: so is this about like circuits and like flip flops?
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: I want to do it.
Scott: Then you can go click on the news and you can read.
Rym: But I'd have to click and read.
Rym: I want it aggregated for me.
Scott: You can't click and read this.
Scott: how are you going to pass this course?
Rym: You know me.
Rym: I have surprising discipline to do really useless things and yet no desire to do things that I actually need to do.
Scott: It's going to be interesting because like if there's enough of these classes I think you know skipping college might actually be even more legitimate.
Scott: Not you know.
Scott: the thing is though there are some online universities that don't suck.
Scott: I've heard things about like this Western governor's university.
Scott: it's actually supposed to be legit.
Rym: So I do have one more news I do want to talk about a little bit.
Scott: Extra news what are you doing?
Rym: Because they're you know this is something that has come up a few times in the past and I guess I wasn't paying attention to the EU so I didn't really realize this was still kind of a thing but you might have heard the phrase right to be forgotten.
Scott: Nope haven't heard it.
Rym: Really?
Rym: So it's the idea that and this is a Stanford Law Review article which is pretty good at explaining the whole problem.
Scott: Well you just said Europe though right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay so why is it Stanford which is a U.S.
Scott: university?
Rym: The Stanford Law Review examined the legal implications of the EU's continuing bullshit.
Scott: So why are they learning about European law in California?
Rym: Because law is law and it would affect U.S.
Rym: companies doing business in Europe.
Scott: I guess I could just see it being problematic like if I was a lawyer and I'm a U.S.
Scott: lawyer trying to pass the bar and I'm learning so much law they're cramming it in my brain and they cram the European laws in there too and then I forget that those are the European laws and I can feel them confused.
Scott: and then I'm like.
Scott: Better not read the Magna Carta.
Scott: I'll be in court.
Scott: I'll be like you can't do that blah blah blah law.
Scott: they'll be like that's a French law.
Scott: What are you going to be Scott?
Scott: You're going to be like well the Magna Carta states.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I'd be like fuck.
Scott: that was in the Magna Carta shit.
Rym: I was just reading.
Rym: I got this great book.
Rym: I was reading the laws that the Burgundians which was an empire.
Scott: Who the fuck are the Burgundians?
Rym: Yeah it's an empire that disappeared a whole bunch of times.
Scott: They're not from Burgundy?
Rym: Uh that's kind of where they're from or where they ended up.
Rym: They're from somewhere.
Rym: it's complicated.
Rym: I'm reading a book on it but anyway I got to read their laws and their laws were pretty funny.
Rym: They had a lot of laws about how much.
Rym: basically they had a pretty good system.
Rym: if you fucked with someone's shit you had to pay them like a number of times the value of the thing you fucked with and you had to pay a fine to the king.
Scott: Why to the king?
Rym: To enforce the law.
Scott: Dude wouldn't the king want people to do bad shit?
Rym: Because it would like that you get way more money.
Scott: It gives the king an incentive to have bad people.
Rym: Most of the money went to the person who was wrong though these were like if you break someone's cart you owe them twelve times.
Scott: That also gives me an incentive to do fraud.
Rym: we're like we're going to broke my shit.
Scott: I make it look like you broke a frame you for breaking my shit.
Rym: I have a feeling in the middle ages the peasants didn't really get justice anyway.
Rym: so I digress.
Rym: but anyway the idea of the right to be forgotten is that if I now don't interrupt because I know you're going to take issue with this right away say I post a picture of my dick to Facebook.
Scott: It's on the whole internets now tough shit.
Rym: So say then I decide I don't want my Facebook account to be there anymore and I delete it.
Scott: Doesn't matter your dick picture is still out there because someone definitely downloaded that shit.
Rym: Is that if I if a picture of my dick is out there and I decide I do not want this factual information about me to be available anymore on the internet.
Rym: I have the right for it to be taken down by anyone hosting it and people who don't can be fined.
Rym: crazy amounts of money.
Rym: They're talking like one or two percent of global income.
Scott: Good luck getting anyone on that.
Scott: that's not in your country.
Rym: Yeah so it's the European Union.
Rym: so they go after Google and Google can't easily just pull out of the European Union.
Rym: They should if this if this happens.
Scott: Oh so this isn't a thing they have already.
Rym: They want it as part of this gigantic.
Rym: basically I don't want to bring this up to talk about the specifics of this ludicrous idea.
Scott: I mean it's impossible.
Rym: I bring this up.
Scott: One person click save as on your dick.
Scott: Now your dick's gone.
Rym: I bring this up because many times people talk about the idea of privacy and they talked about this 10 billion times.
Rym: They want protections of privacy.
Rym: This is a very synced argument as to why it's not going to work in the long run.
Rym: Because if you actually want governments to try to pass laws that will give you any amount of control over your personal data once it's been published somewhere.
Rym: The only way to do that is with laws like this.
Rym: So if you read this story this article and you think that this is a good idea and that even if you don't think it's a good idea like even if you do think that it is a good idea you also think that it is enforceable in any reasonable way.
Scott: See it is a thing right.
Scott: We've tread the copyright ground as the most tread ground in the internet.
Scott: It is like there's not even dirt there anymore.
Scott: It's like just bedrock with like footprints all over it right.
Scott: It's actually this there's a groove in the bedrock for the pacing back and forth on the copyright grounds right.
Scott: And privacy is the second most tread.
Scott: like the bedrock is starting to sprout through the dirt right.
Scott: And we've talked about those things so much.
Scott: I don't want to talk about them again.
Scott: But the thing that's bothering me the most these days is when you go to the internets you go to places that are typically nerdy like say Boing Boing for example great example.
Scott: but any place that has similar ideas and philosophies and outlooks on life to Boing Boing and nerdy places they get this idea that copyright.
Scott: yeah there's no way that copyright is going to work.
Scott: dudes you got to tone it down but privacy they're like.
Scott: we got to make the privacy even more.
Scott: lots of privacy no copyright and I'm like we as you know.
Scott: okay I can.
Scott: I know why you think these things but look you're totally inconsistent here right you go copyright.
Scott: once that song is out there.
Scott: it's impossible to put it back in the jar you can't.
Scott: the analog hole is unsealable.
Scott: you just got to change the way you do business companies to deal with the fact that information is going to be shared around the world and you can't stop it.
Scott: when it comes to privacy it's like no one says.
Scott: you just got to change the way.
Scott: you got to change the way you live your life and share your information.
Scott: once your dick is on the internet it's just like that song there's no way to bring your dick back.
Scott: your dick is out your dicks out there.
Scott: this is why all right it's the same problem.
Scott: once information is released on the internet it's out for the entire world to see.
Scott: there's no putting it back.
Scott: deal with it.
Scott: no privacy no copyrights.
Scott: that's the way of the world.
Scott: you got to change the way you do business.
Scott: you got to change the way you live your life.
Scott: there is no technological or legal solution.
Scott: give the fuck up.
Scott: and as long as you're consistent on two issues right like if you say more copyright more privacy then i'm like all right.
Scott: at least you're consistent even though i disagree.
Scott: or if you say less copyright less privacy okay you're on my side but if you're backwards and those two you you're fucked the fuck up.
Rym: so read this article because it gives a very nice kind of legal analysis of the whole situation and it brings up all the examples that i would bring up if we were arguing this.
Rym: obviously like what if someone else posts factual information about me do i have any rights to that data that was acquired legally by someone else?
Scott: for example i took a picture dick and i put on my fligger.
Rym: yeah because i was i had my dick out at a party so you took a picture of it.
Rym: now what?
Rym: who?
Rym: who has the rights to that my dick?
Rym: now you really want my dick.
Scott: i took it really or its soul with my camera.
Rym: so things of the day.
Scott: this is actually kind of a serious cool thing of the day really i got a fun awesome thing.
Rym: that's not it's not.
Scott: it's not dancing or ponies or anything like that.
Rym: oh my god i'm looking at my history.
Rym: it's literally music video pokemon mashup dancing right.
Scott: so this one is uh new york city street photographer is 1950 50s photos found headed to queen's museum of art.
Rym: oh shit i want to go see that.
Rym: so yeah we can go down there and check them out but i just found there was an online archive of a whole bunch of photos of new york from the 70s and 80s that surfaced.
Scott: yeah they got really good sculptures there too.
Scott: i've been there but it was a long time ago.
Rym: uh we should go as soon as that exhibit opens.
Scott: but yeah they got awesome old photos in the 50s of new york city and you can see them right here.
Scott: uh on this post at least you can see one of you are six seven ten of them.
Scott: i don't know if there's uh but it says here the negatives had been stored in more than 100 envelopes meticulously noted with location and date into larson.
Scott: so i'm pretty sure that there's more than 10 photos there that could have been 10 envelopes.
Scott: photographs dating back to the 20s tested the fact that he was always the family shutterbug.
Scott: but wasn't until the early 50s that his passion blossomed.
Scott: throughout the 50s and early 60s he made weekend expeditions around new york with which is with his roly flex automat model 4 around his neck producing thousands of images which developed in a basement dark room.
Scott: so they found some dude's photos and uh there's 10 awesome ones right here in this in this blog post.
Rym: so think about this.
Rym: when we're 90 we're gonna be able to look back and see all the pictures we took of ourselves from like the 2000s.
Scott: this is why pictures are a great invention yeah and digital pictures are great.
Scott: and the thing is now we finally only recently have we actually had pictures that were you know good enough to actually sort of really really see.
Scott: you know you look at like 1800s photos and it's like a couple people kind of with a blurry you know vignette around them and i just enjoy seeing paintings like super good portrait paintings from like the 1678. the thing about paintings is like.
Scott: that's not what the dude looks like.
Rym: no because some of them it's like.
Rym: yeah the dude clearly did not look like that because that is too perfect and pretty.
Rym: but i got some pictures of people where it is clear that is what they actually looked like.
Rym: because who would make up that hideous wart?
Scott: maybe the dude liked his own war or it was just such a big war there was no way you could.
Scott: you could remove it.
Scott: yeah without people like who's that it's like gorbachev i can remove that.
Scott: it's like who's that?
Scott: who's that ball guy?
Rym: so i'm a big fan now of electro swing and it reminded me of a band that i was a huge fan of way back in the 90s the squirrel nut zippers.
Rym: and they do.
Scott: they did kind of like keep to reverse.
Scott: we're talking about digs now nuts.
Rym: so they used.
Rym: they did like squirrels swing music and it's really like i like their jam.
Rym: they're my jam.
Rym: to do a good degree.
Scott: they got weirder strangely obsessed with jam and they did.
Rym: they did i point out i haven't brought up ponies at all.
Rym: neither did i shut up brought ponies like three times all right.
Rym: so they did a song called the ghost of stephen foster which i really like.
Rym: stephen foster is the man who wrote such classics as camp town races and oh suzanna.
Rym: i learned recently some interesting stuff about him that i'm gonna save for another thing of the day that i did not know.
Rym: but anyway they have a song the ghost of stephen foster.
Rym: it's kind of a creepy cool song.
Rym: i think it's ripe for an electro swing remix.
Rym: however there's a music video to the song.
Rym: the music video is in the old mickey mouse like black and white haunted house style of animation.
Scott: that's a great style.
Rym: it's a great music video.
Rym: it's a great song.
Rym: it.
Rym: everything about this is great.
Rym: i think my favorite part's the little radies the radies.
Rym: there's little radies like riding the slide with them.
Rym: you should all watch this.
Rym: i wanted to get over to a million views by the time you're done watching it.
Rym: so briefly in the meta moment the book club book is done.
Rym: we haven't picked the next one yet.
Rym: the episode is out.
Rym: we will be at pax east doing so far.
Rym: we have one panel we can announce we will be lecturing on.
Rym: let's play money making game to 10 2050. on saturday at the con which is april 7th at 4 30 p.m in the cat theater.
Rym: more announcements will come.
Rym: we have not finalized the schedule for the other things we were doing but it's actually a lot closer than you think.
Scott: it's april right.
Rym: i know we gotta write this fucking panel.
Scott: i got it.
Scott: it was my idea.
Scott: i got it and my panels are better than yours.
Rym: anyway get it going quickly and i need something to do.
Rym: get it get it going quickly so i can contribute because we gotta we gotta get this going.
Scott: i don't need your country anyway.
Rym: besides i wrote the description for it.
Rym: sure games can make their money in many ways but how do these models affect intentionally or not the design choices of the game makers themselves?
Rym: what about the players?
Rym: you play a game differently depending on how you paid for it free.
Rym: if it's free i don't feel subscription or silly hats.
Rym: what do these different models mean to games at their core?
Scott: if it's free i don't feel bad stopping playing.
Scott: but if i paid a lot of money i feel bad if i don't beat only 10 rupees and hopefully you won't have to pay the door repair charge.
Rym: yeah i cannot account all that stuff coming up.
Rym: we'll talk about it later.
Rym: so apparently the internet's going to be destroyed.
Scott: how?
Scott: so?
Rym: so apparently like take out all 13 root dns servers at once with the bombs there's actually 26 because each one has a bag anyway i'm just saying so apparently the do not track functionality that people are using meaning hey advertisers don't track.
Rym: what i'm doing with your stupid cookies will ruin the entire free internet because every ad supported site will go under because they won't make any money anymore.
Rym: and before we get any further i'm gonna head all this off by pointing out that ad block did not end the free internet.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: so uh what now jeffra with your post?
Rym: what are you thinking?
Rym: the only people who are saying this are the same advertisers with their scammy bullshit tactics that we tried to get rid of with ad block.
Scott: uh i think the thing the article that you're reading is actually an article that agrees with us and is replying to someone else who disagrees with us.
Rym: yeah i have a list of articles here.
Rym: okay i have this whole like chain of discussions but this argument seems to come up perennially.
Rym: the idea that i mean.
Rym: remember we were at rit and we had a friend luke who ran a website that had some ads to make money.
Rym: he ran another website that made money another way.
Rym: i won't get into that now.
Rym: other than that i helped him get the uh content.
Scott: i don't know why he did work for free when you were poor.
Rym: no because he was paying.
Rym: oh he was paying for that hentai.
Scott: okay and then you just spilled the beans.
Rym: i i had a w get script that would just like raid hentai sites.
Rym: so anyway all that aside so he one day someone said something like yeah i just block ads and back then i mean we would use like host files to block ads because we already did a show on this.
Scott: i'm pretty sure.
Rym: we talked about internet advertising in a very general sense six years ago.
Scott: i think we discussed this exact thing.
Scott: so someone listen to that show and find out i don't think anyone today.
Rym: that's not even in the rss feed anymore.
Scott: well the rss feed is different story.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: so uh he basically he noticed.
Rym: you know i said something like yeah i block ads.
Rym: why would i want to see an ad?
Rym: and he flipped out.
Rym: he was angry that it you know arguing that it was stealing to block an ad on a website.
Rym: how are our websites supposed to make money without ads?
Scott: the thing is i've more recently he talked about how like.
Scott: oh well you know if you visit the site and you see the ad you don't click on it you actually harm the.
Scott: uh you know the the the rate at you know the like.
Scott: it's very important.
Scott: the.
Scott: uh what's it called rate?
Scott: the conversion rate.
Scott: yep right so he's like if you see the ad you don't click you're actually hurting the conversion rate and an ad block person isn't going to click anyway.
Scott: no so ad blocking actually helps the conversion rate even though it decreases the views.
Rym: i recall this argument occurring when vcr's appeared and even earlier when remote controls appeared.
Rym: i don't recall that personally but i've read articles of people complaining about it and talking about it.
Rym: people were worried that if you could just change the channel easily people would change the channel whenever there was an advertisement that maybe people didn't actually want to watch advertisements.
Rym: i mean isn't it stealing?
Rym: ted turner said something like this a long time ago.
Rym: i'm pretty sure he's come around now that if you are watching something and you mute the ads don't pay you know you get up and make a sandwich while the ads are on.
Rym: you're a thief.
Rym: you're getting your content for free.
Rym: you're not paying with your eyeballs but doesn't that?
Rym: what about the conversion rate?
Rym: what about i mean if i don't buy a chevy every time i see a chevy ad?
Rym: am not stealing from the advertiser?
Scott: yeah so his is the thing right.
Scott: there's the fundamental problem right and that all ad sales are bullshit.
Scott: this i can't understand.
Scott: why ad buyers continue to pay what they pay for ads.
Rym: i don't all ads are not bullshit.
Rym: the ads the whole ad the entire ad market is not bullshit.
Scott: it's mostly.
Scott: it is however mostly bullshit but it's like most ads.
Scott: it's like who is paying for ads on like weird ass cable channel.
Scott: you know that no one watches.
Scott: it's like that.
Scott: ad is not helping you at all but you're paying a lot of money.
Rym: how do you know?
Rym: you could argue that those ads are working because otherwise people couldn't afford to keep buying them.
Scott: maybe i don't know but anyway so in every time i you know i've seen a lot of ad buying and selling in all the places i've worked at websites you know at various places and it's always the situation where it seems like the people selling the ads are charging way too much money for something that's not worth what it costs.
Scott: but i wonder buyers keep buying.
Rym: what i always wonder in this whole thing like with tv ads for example are the ads on like hulu?
Rym: who exactly is the fool?
Rym: is it the person selling the ad having overvalued this entire business model?
Rym: or do they know?
Rym: is it is the person buying the ad like a sucker?
Rym: or do they know too when they're passing on the real cost to someone else they're just a middleman.
Scott: that's possible at one point.
Rym: who is the person who is specifically being ripped off by this?
Scott: it's all.
Scott: that's hard.
Scott: that's why it continues to work because it's like somehow everyone feels like they're getting good deal and then someone's.
Rym: so here's the messed up thing i see.
Rym: i do see articles talking about how statistically ads actually do work like car ads.
Rym: advertising cars translates directly into car sales like straight up.
Scott: i can't believe that you're telling me that it's a ford which is a well-known car brand that people buy right and drive.
Scott: if they just stopped advertising on tv that their sales would go way down.
Rym: so i've read if they just stopped spending money on saying that when you interview people who buy cars the majority of people are influenced primarily by advertisements they saw and secondarily by test drives but and third by word of mouth but two.
Rym: it talked a lot about how most people from the decision to buy a car to the execution of that is less than a couple of weeks and they do very little independent research.
Scott: but you're telling me that if you got rid of all ford advertisements that people would forget ford completely.
Scott: and then you know ford sales might go down.
Scott: but are they gonna go down enough to at the point at which you know?
Scott: the savings for not spending bajillions of dollars on ads is you know not a good profit?
Rym: you know i really wonder about that because notice during the super bowl most of the ads are cars or beer but cars mostly.
Rym: yeah cars soft drinks and beer are like the only things that get ads.
Scott: so it's like.
Scott: i can't even remember a single actual car that was in any of those ads.
Scott: i just remember they're a bunch of cars.
Rym: here's something i've noticed very telling that when i was a kid and tv was just you know i'd watch like the simpsons or whatever.
Rym: i could tell you what car manufacturer made every make and model of car.
Scott: well i just know that anyway and i haven't watched tv in years.
Rym: yeah here's the thing i used to just know that like just completely.
Rym: but now that i don't see any ads ever my knowledge is dropping and i've had to look up a couple of times like from a make of a car or a model of a car who made it.
Scott: oh i still know even though without seeing the ads.
Rym: you know 100 percent.
Scott: yeah tell me a car i'll tell you all right.
Rym: uh i don't know the elantra the honda elantra yep you got that.
Rym: i know that one too though it's hard because i can only think of the ones that i still know.
Scott: okay but anyway i've noticed.
Scott: yeah they don't say that though the commercials always say honda anyway.
Rym: so but i i saw these articles talking about how people don't actually research their buying decisions that much and are influenced a lot by advertising like ad campaigns correlate to sales pretty strongly in some areas.
Scott: correlate because maybe it's just the companies that are bigger.
Scott: they get more sales have more money to spend on ads yep.
Rym: but like pepsi right now is having trouble because sales are dropping.
Rym: so their plan is to do more advertising and historically every time a soft drink company does more advertising they make more sales.
Scott: but this the more advertising usually also uh goes along with.
Scott: like you know they always try to make different drinks and stuff.
Scott: i always wonder that too like why do they try to make like all these different pepsi's?
Scott: why don't they just try to really push hard on plain old fucking pepsi and not make all these different things to get all the niche markets?
Scott: are there really that many like?
Rym: i don't know.
Rym: all i remember is i used to drink surge that's you.
Rym: yeah surge was very important to me anyway.
Scott: so let's go back to the original topic.
Rym: so i don't want to talk about the social side of it anymore.
Rym: let's talk about the technology because i mean internet advertising right now really only exists at least on websites for people who are too dumb to install adblock.
Rym: yeah how is it still working?
Scott: because a lot of people don't put adblock.
Scott: so some people you know they have they actually feel like they want the sites to benefit from the ads.
Rym: but if i want that why don't you enable the mode that downloads the ads and just doesn't display them?
Rym: because then everybody wins except the person who bought the ad.
Scott: because you might like the ad and click on it and then the site really benefits depends on what kind of ad campaign it is.
Scott: it you know but you don't know.
Scott: you don't know without seeing it.
Rym: but then again what if i just every website i like i click on the ads all the time but i don't look at them?
Rym: what if i make a plug-in where i can say click on every ad of all of these sites to give them click-throughs?
Scott: because then it's click fraud and the site actually gets in trouble because they the ad networks can detect that.
Rym: but is it?
Rym: at what point is it click fraud?
Rym: what if i personally click on ads all the time on sites i like?
Scott: it depends how much you do it like.
Scott: if i did it on a site that i visited a zillion times a day you know that would be.
Scott: they might come through as a false positive for click fraud because i'm just clicking on the ads.
Scott: so much plus most of the money you can really make is on ads that do something like not just go to the site but it's like how many people actually fucking sign up for the mailing list and then you know only clicking on the ad once will actually get anything or get people to actually buy.
Scott: you know an ad for an e-commerce site and then they actually buy something.
Scott: then they make big money because they had like an affiliate you know.
Rym: so i guess i guess what i'm getting at is i do have a question for you.
Rym: because adblock didn't kill the internet.
Rym: you know the free internet.
Rym: but i'm wondering if the only reason that's the case is because ad blocking is not actually ubiquitous yet.
Scott: yeah i'm.
Rym: i'm wondering like like what would happen if firefox said you know what by default ad block?
Scott: well it wouldn't matter because firefox is actually losing market share.
Rym: so what if firefox and chrome and ie were all like you know what by default ad block?
Scott: that would be the awesomest thing ever.
Rym: but what would something happen?
Rym: because look at youtube the ad network youtube and college humor and all those sites have been going down the road of fucking interstitial.
Scott: yeah well first of all google would never do that.
Scott: google's been doing fucking interstitials.
Rym: google's an ad company i know but they've been doing interstitials on youtube already.
Scott: yeah um but second of all right uh number one all the companies that do ads would find ways to get around the ad block.
Scott: there would be a war of the ad block.
Rym: right because right now i point out that war happened like three times already and every time advertisers lost.
Scott: but here's the thing google was not on either side of that war.
Scott: if you if you know if i mean google runs chrome.
Scott: so pretend chrome was run by someone else.
Scott: yep.
Scott: so all the browsers were run by people who hated ads and they all put ad block in right.
Scott: um uh so someone's calling me from texas.
Scott: i got to see who that is.
Rym: oh well i can interrupt because i was just handed a valentine.
Rym: i got a valentine from emily.
Rym: uh no it's not from emily it's from someone else who came in a package quote.
Rym: you are 99.9 sweet and you know who.
Rym: it's from applejack.
Rym: okay no it's it's from uh our friend kristin but it's an applejack valentine.
Rym: okay.
Scott: so as i was saying right you know this ad this ad versus ad blocking war right has always been sort of like.
Scott: you know double click and ad networks which is now owned by google versus ad block.
Scott: and such right ad block plus is just some open source dudes.
Scott: yep if google was on the other side of that war you know they actually were fighting against adblock plus.
Scott: first of all they'd remove adblock plus.
Scott: you know.
Scott: well i've said assuming they don't own chrome right um they would.
Scott: you know there's no way you could out code google right.
Scott: they would totally find ways to make unblockable ads they already have.
Rym: but what they do is they have those stupid pop-ups within youtube.
Rym: you know the ones that like overlay the bottom of the video yeah and they have the interstitials in youtube that appear occasionally.
Rym: yep i know i can get around like i. the thing is you know how i get around that.
Rym: in the end what i always wanted to do just to like throw a monkey wrench in all this is make something like boxy right or like a browser plugin that whenever one of those interstitial things appears it downloads it like it's running but it plays a random youtube video of a cat instead because i you could make an ocr kind of thing.
Rym: that would go automatically.
Scott: youtube video of the cat has an ad in it too?
Rym: no i use a non-youtube video.
Rym: no i embed videos i don't know.
Rym: i make a server of videos okay.
Rym: or maybe i have a thing that just clicks and closes the overlay ad immediately when it appears.
Rym: then what do they do?
Rym: keep popping up.
Rym: i keep closing it.
Scott: the point is you still have to.
Scott: you have to keep waiting right?
Scott: you know even if you're.
Scott: if you're don't with the overlay they can make it so that it's possible to make it to where they will.
Scott: not you know the.
Scott: the data won't come through to your end until you have either seen the ad or waited an amount of time.
Rym: now that's the next step.
Rym: if i had to wait if they interstitialed everything like every third video on youtube would be an interstitial.
Rym: i would set up the equivalent of a dvr that would let me get ahead on picking videos i want to watch and it would just save every video and play them on my own like local server and like.
Rym: i could click on like a video and another video.
Rym: but even then you're still waiting because i'm watching the videos i want to watch from my queue.
Scott: i only wait for you but that does that time between when you queued them up and when you started watching.
Scott: that's your wait period.
Rym: it depends.
Scott: you could click and start watching right.
Rym: then by clicking on multiple videos in a row and making playlists you could set it up where you never had to actually wait unless google really went out of their way.
Rym: but i point out that as much as i love youtube if i couldn't get around all the ads like if the ads actually got in my way i would literally stop watching youtube videos.
Rym: i would go somewhere else.
Scott: but then where would you go?
Scott: that had the videos vimeo right now.
Scott: well vimeo doesn't have the videos that's enough.
Scott: it's also kind of strict.
Scott: they don't let you post like videos of video games or a lot of things.
Scott: they don't like what i would actually do like youtube where you can post anything if youtube videos got intrusive enough.
Rym: i mean i stopped watching tv partly because i didn't want to deal with the ads that were just so jarring.
Scott: stop watching youtube.
Rym: i would just stop consuming media that had so many ads.
Rym: i would rather pay for an ad for youtube than have intolerable ads.
Scott: yeah it's like you.
Scott: just go to bittorrent and download videos.
Rym: yeah i would go straight to piracy but it would kill the kicked in the nuts demographic?
Scott: it would for sure so is that it?
Rym: i mean the only way to.
Scott: actually there's some people who will sit through it.
Scott: so what do you do?
Rym: so?
Rym: so here's my question is the end game everyone has ad block and no one sees ads?
Rym: or is the actual end game?
Rym: everybody's smart has ad block and the brains of the less enlightened are basically the fodder that allow us to see.
Rym: like are they the guys thrown under the bus so that we can see?
Rym: is the future where tech guys block ads no one else?
Scott: no i i think i think yes because no company is ever going to block the ads.
Rym: uh what if i made it?
Scott: because that would they be?
Scott: that would be opening up the biggest you know can of worms in the universe.
Rym: i would not be uncomfortable forming a company that sold a dvr that straight up blocked ads.
Scott: i wonder we need talk to a lawyer and see what happens.
Rym: i'd form that company in like australia and i'd only sell it to non-australians or i run it through shady channels and you can donate to me semi-anonymously.
Scott: i'm surprised like what license is adblock plus?
Scott: because if it's like depending on the license you could just sell it.
Scott: you know you could just be like hey you can make a website that's like at the ultimate adblock or five bucks and all you're doing is giving them adblock plus which is free.
Rym: but i guess i'm wondering if there is a point at which everyone's using adblock or if there's a mass of people who just can't be asked to do the trivial thing to not see ads anymore.
Scott: i mean i even like i used to do custom stuff like when it's weird like there's some people they actually you know we've only considered so far.
Scott: the people who you know don't block ads because they don't know better or there are actually people i know where it's.
Scott: not even they you know feel bad for the companies.
Scott: they want to see the ads to help them out.
Scott: people legitimately say i like ads i want to see them.
Rym: now what i don't get is the only kind of ad that has ever been useful to me and or effective to me are ads that inform me a product or service class of which i did not know there was an offering exists.
Rym: but even then i don't go by the thing that was advertised.
Rym: i go investigate the class of products i discovered.
Rym: yep or at the best it might be a tv show i didn't know about.
Rym: but you know what i found out about that through word of mouth.
Rym: yeah and i usually pirate it to see if it's good before i would pay for it.
Rym: and if i can't pirate it and i can't get it cheaply i probably just give up right away.
Rym: but this article wasn't even talking about that.
Rym: they're trying to claim that the do not track will kill the free internet.
Rym: well what serves the same purpose that the current adblock does?
Rym: well people who let the do not track happen get better ads.
Rym: the people who don't want to be tracked are the kinds of people who are paranoid about ads anyway won't click on them.
Scott: yeah well you know what they're also saying is basically like look there are websites out there that make extra money and a lot more money because they have all sorts of tracking in their ads.
Scott: and if the ads can't track then those sites aren't going to make so much money and people won't be able to provide content for free on the internet if they can't make money on ads.
Scott: and the thing is you know it's just weird.
Scott: these people don't seem to understand.
Scott: it's like look okay i do go to a lot of sites on the internet that have free content and that is paid for by ads.
Scott: like you know you go to a website of a newspaper or something like that i go to.
Scott: you know i do go to some percentage of those.
Scott: most of this stuff or college humor perfect example.
Scott: right most of the stuff that i go see on the internet doesn't even have ads to block.
Scott: it's just content made by people like us like this podcast for people like us and there's no ads and there's no money being made.
Scott: it's just everyone putting in a small portion of their salary into say for example libsyn or linode or some hosting company or their isp and that just pays for everything.
Scott: or amazon and everyone is just sharing making things freely and sharing them freely with no ads on them.
Scott: so the free internet which is that's like 80 percent of the stuff i consume on the internet yep is in no danger of their advertising being completely outlawed by all world governments.
Scott: right it's there is no threat whatsoever.
Rym: now i've noticed too that when i do see ads for whatever reason like i turn off ad block to take a look like i went around looking at the internet today without ad block just to kind of prep for the show i did not see a single ad.
Rym: that was for a thing i would ever consider purchasing.
Rym: yeah it was mostly ads for cars.
Rym: i don't need a car and if i needed a car i'd do independent research on one.
Rym: what have i bought recently?
Rym: i bought the gopro camera.
Rym: i researched like two weeks out of that.
Rym: yeah i researched like.
Scott: i also researched that it's the best one.
Rym: yeah like of all the cameras like that was the best one everyone uses.
Scott: it's the best one.
Rym: i bought two hard drives.
Rym: i bought the cheapest ones with the most stars on newegg.
Rym: yeah uh i bought an sd card.
Rym: i bought the cheapest one on newegg.
Scott: yep i bought a shirt.
Rym: i bought a shower curtain.
Rym: bought the cheapest one on amazon.
Scott: actually i got this this the shower curtain i have is the highest rated plastic shower curtain on amazon and i know you don't want a plastic one right because we have had many a plastic one over the years and all of them got mildewy and we threw them away
Rym: right.
Rym: i had a fabric one that i could wash in a washing machine.
Rym: that worked really well for a long time.
Scott: the plastic one that i have now that i bought an amazon.
Scott: that's the highest rated one on amazon.
Scott: i bought two.
Scott: at the time i bought it because i thought i'd have to replace it.
Scott: it's been over a year.
Scott: it is still perfect.
Scott: nice it is best shower curtain.
Scott: it just never gets nasty ever.
Scott: it's like the perfect.
Scott: oh my god it's unbelievable.
Rym: so there's the other question of like do not track and all these things.
Rym: right now they're just cookies that i voluntarily accept.
Rym: it's trivial to stop that stuff.
Scott: yeah like just be like.
Scott: disable all third-party cookies done.
Rym: and also i think there's an inherent right that if i get media media is coming into me somehow like a website or something i can reformat that.
Rym: so i don't think anyone has any.
Rym: i mean if youtube really went off the hook with their uh overlay like bottom ads maybe i just make a thing that blurred them out so i didn't see it.
Scott: well the thing is right.
Scott: is you think you block a cookie right but the do not track the what it's supposed to do is there are so many different ways to track someone.
Scott: people have made these technology demonstrations of like.
Scott: you know the invince a cookie.
Scott: it's like it uses every method conceivable to try to keep some identification in your browser so that you can go to this site.
Scott: it'll hit you and then any other site you go to if it's got the code on it.
Scott: they know that it was the same you from the last site.
Scott: because even if you deleted the cookies and deleted this and deleted that they still have something in there where they can identify you and when they see get identify you they fill every possible thing back up again so you can delete everything again because they you know they put it in the in-browser database they put it in the cookies they put it in.
Rym: the makers were serious about it.
Scott: they could fight a really good fight to prevent that from working but it would also ruin a lot of other useful browser technologies.
Rym: i would give them up.
Scott: no you know you'd be surprised how much you depend on those.
Rym: yeah the thing is you know what i did in the old days before there was a reliable ad block you had like yes no yes no every single.
Rym: yeah i had it.
Rym: basically i had a blacklist by default on all images and all flash and everything and if i went to a website and i wanted to see its content i would whitelist either specific elements or specific classes of elements for those individual websites.
Scott: but you gotta admit that's a pretty horrible experience.
Rym: uh actually it wasn't because i as i learned i only went to about 20 websites on a regular basis and those websites i whitelisted like right away and very rarely did i go somewhere where i'd run into something but like oh i can't see something.
Rym: granted you had the problem where you didn't know.
Rym: there were images in kingdom of loathing that's true.
Scott: they got ad blocked.
Rym: that's so sad.
Rym: you never got to see the lick.
Scott: i just saw the word lick.
Scott: that's enough.
Rym: you didn't get to see the actual lick.
Rym: was you good it was.
Scott: i'm gonna search for him right now.
Rym: i don't actually remember what he looked like.
Rym: i'm looking for him and this guy the uh the smobbies.
Rym: uh scott there's meat in kingdom of loathing is there?
Scott: yes i'm getting it.
Rym: there's lots of meat.
Rym: remember the meat car.
Rym: yeah i guess made the meat.
Rym: you made the meat engine by combining the meat with the i think the transaxle or something and then you combine that with more meat to make it getting off topic here.
Rym: car meat okay.
Rym: so what do we do with all this?
Scott: i mean the point is this guy was like oh man if you if you know if companies actually respected do not track and everyone said don't track me.
Scott: add companies and add sellers and add buyers wouldn't be able to make as much money or sell more products.
Rym: no they'd go back to the 2000s.
Rym: and then you know
Scott: then people who make content on the internet and pay for that content with ads wouldn't be able to keep making that content because they wouldn't make enough monies and all the free content on the internet would have to be paid for and you know walled off like new york times or whatever behind pay walls.
Scott: because the people making the content and it's like dude most like i said most of the content is free with no ads anyway.
Scott: it's like these people think like the only content that's out there that's worth looking at.
Rym: is the people who bring this stuff up are usually the like the seo types or they're the people who like they run they talk about?
Rym: well you want to make money on the internet.
Rym: here's how to monetize your blog.
Scott: it's like yeah uh what about all these people who just don't try to monetize most of everybody?
Rym: i mean advertisers approach us pretty occasionally and scott usually responds with the same response we give to everyone.
Rym: can you give me enough money for my life to change?
Scott: yes if you give me a life-changing amount of money.
Scott: i'll put ads on GeekNights.
Rym: otherwise no i mean the first thing i did in my youtube account for GeekNights was turn off all advertising for all videos and disable any monetization whatsoever.
Rym: yep oh well yeah i just i really don't know what the end game is.
Rym: i don't know if ad block is gonna reach this kind of like.
Scott: i think it's gonna be ubiquity or not.
Rym: because another side thing is there have been issues with you know telemarketers and the do not call list apparently actually really hurt a lot of companies that made a ton of money preying mostly on the elderly.
Rym: and there are people who actually will buy more stuff if they're subjected to ads.
Rym: but if they have the ability to opt out of those ads then they don't buy as much stuff.
Scott: that is true.
Rym: but whose rights are there in that situation?
Rym: is it the right of the person to opt out or the right of the advertiser to contact the person?
Scott: and it's it's tough right it's like okay maybe we can save that person some money in the short term.
Scott: right because they won't be wasting it on bullshit they don't want.
Scott: but if we manage to like save all the people in that situation.
Scott: it'll actually hurt the economy which might end up hurting those people more.
Scott: but i saw another study for those people to waste their money.
Rym: i saw another study collected like 2002 or three at rit.
Rym: i even had to write a paper on it and it was in my hci class human computer interaction like interface design and all that and it showed that older people who were using the internet really wanted ad block and stuff because they clicked on ads they didn't want to like.
Rym: they wanted to avoid ads and spam because they were afraid they'd buy stuff and they couldn't ignore ads.
Rym: young people didn't even see the ads ad blocker no like.
Rym: they just glossed over them.
Rym: and it got to the point where if you designed a website where the button to like do a thing that the website act like you actually wanted to do looked even vaguely like an ad kids could not find it.
Rym: yep now not they didn't have.
Rym: they had no ad block.
Rym: this was a controlled situation.
Rym: they literally just blocked out in their brain anything that looked remotely like an advertisement.
Rym: so maybe that's the end game.
Scott: i don't think this is going to be any game.
Scott: actually this is one of the weird situations where i'm going to say you know what's going to happen maintaining of status quo for a very very long time.
Scott: i i see all these flaws all over the place that everyone else sees but i don't think anything's going to happen.
Scott: i think it's just going to keep going.
Scott: it's been going.
Scott: everyone's going to keep spending money on ads.
Scott: putting money putting ads i think i just agree.
Rym: i think for a very long time within the next 30 years y plus 30 there's going to be a crisis in the advertising supported business model across the western world.
Scott: i don't think so.
Rym: i think there's going to.
Scott: as long as companies have a lot of money they will all and you know because anyone who wants to get ideas out in the world has money they will continue to spend that money to put their message into the world.
Rym: because the santorum thing you know that that disgusting word that also happens to be the name of uh a disgusting guy.
Rym: so super packs spend untold millions of dollars to try to plant ideas like that in the populace with a pretty good you know level of success there are.
Rym: now there's a storm of articles funded by a lot of these organizations the people who support them trying to say that google and internet people are unfairly using their power to do things like this.
Rym: you know the santorum quote-unquote smear campaign.
Rym: okay not that anyone wants to think about a smear of santorum new and that it's unfair and that you know there should be regulation to prevent that sort of like bombing of people's identity online or whatever.
Rym: but i think that itself is astroturfing trying to cover up for the fact that look what happened there?
Rym: dan savage basically without a super pack and without spending millions of dollars did in 10 minutes what it takes.
Rym: someone old school trying to put a fake like top down meme into the population 10 million dollars to do so.
Rym: i think the dan savage type stuff is going to more and more powerful and i don't think the old media can keep up because the cost of planting memes in tech savvy people is going up at an exponential rate.
Scott: and here's the thing what is advertising right?
Scott: advertising now is like this specific spots for it right and it's like this sort of.
Scott: you can see that it's like advertising.
Scott: i think the advertising the future is simply.
Scott: look there is content.
Scott: it's all pull content right.
Scott: it's not going to be so much pushing.
Scott: it's going to be.
Scott: content is going to be popular.
Scott: certain content is going to be unpopular and content is just information.
Scott: so advertising is just going to be hey i want to no one's looking at my information because there's so much information in the world.
Scott: i will give you money if you put my information and attach it to your information.
Scott: that's pretty much the fundamental thing that it is now.
Scott: so you know if your dan savage is so good that he can get the messages out there he's going there going to be people who pay him a lot of money to get messages but then with his messages.
Rym: but then there's the penny arcade situation of the only reason their voice is so powerful because their voice is trusted.
Scott: if they ever backed a game that was really shitty like for real yeah but that's gonna be yeah but you're just assuming that anyone who pays to get a message out there is shitty.
Scott: there's gonna be plenty of people who aren't shitty paying to get their message out here.
Rym: but here's the question if someone who's not shitty is paying for the message to get out there the person who's getting the message out there if they agree with the message is basically getting free money because they were likely to spread that message anyway.
Scott: well maybe they weren't.
Rym: i mean how much burning wheel did we sell right?
Scott: or yeah but the thing is how you know.
Scott: if he had paid us money we would mention the burning wheel in every episode instead of every other episode.
Scott: yeah you would.
Scott: you know it.
Scott: it's you get.
Scott: there's something extra.
Scott: you know when you pay someone the monies you get them to do it.
Rym: i don't think that's the real.
Scott: they're reminded to do it.
Rym: i think it'll get even more subtle.
Rym: i think the real future is what we're seeing now with politics of the massive orchestrated astroturfing campaigns complete with entire armies of fake profiles making fake friendships in forums and acting like real people with these fake identities.
Scott: i mean you got you got fake amazon reviews fake new egg reviews.
Scott: you got fake everything.
Rym: so but then google's gonna probably step in with the algorithms to weed out the fake.
Scott: no that's really hard to do.
Scott: they've been trying a long time and i think it'll happen.
Rym: i think it's a big arms race but i think all that aside i think the traditional advertising model of here are ad spots.
Rym: they are paid directly to be put in places that our ads is going to have a crisis in the next 30 years.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand.
Scott: okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.