Rym: It's Thursday, November 15th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Ryan.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight on the GeekNights Book Club, the name of the wind.
Scott: What is it?
Rym: By Rothfuss.
Rym: Patrick.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: That is what we call in the industry, emergent behavior.
Scott: We used to do that in high school on purpose.
Rym: So we did something much more complex.
Rym: We had a game we called the chipmunk game.
Rym: So the game was you would have a number of people and usually two people was optimal or four people.
Rym: And you would alternate through the phrase chipmunk.
Rym: So chipmunk across the people.
Rym: And you had to just keep doing it as long as possible until somebody flipped out and threatened violence if you didn't shut the fuck up.
Rym: That was the whole game.
Scott: OK, so I guess I got to say, fuck the not daylight savings time.
Rym: I know it's dark.
Rym: Seriously, why can't it stay dark until I get out of work and then be like the entire time I'm home?
Scott: I mean, you know, I'm already feeling kind of black because it's dark.
Scott: And I can only imagine what it's like for someone who has, you know, like actual, you know, emotional problems.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, I'm making a new argument that fucking go, you know, turning off daylight savings time is killing people.
Rym: So the argument was made when they didn't when they implemented the let's go back and forth as opposed to let's go back and never look back.
Rym: That that was killing people because it was dark when kids went to schools.
Rym: They'd get hit by school buses.
Scott: Fucking don't get hit by a school bus.
Rym: That's good advice you should give to most kids.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: Anyway, I'm feeling bleh.
Rym: Blay.
Rym: Feeling bleh?
Rym: One of my coworkers was sick, so I was giving him the wide birth because I do not want to get sick.
Rym: I've been not sick for a long time.
Rym: I want to maintain this.
Scott: So something else.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, a lot of times people buy headphones, especially expensive ones.
Rym: I have an expensive pair of headphones right here hanging on a hook that I. we actually haven't worn headphones doing gig nights for years now.
Scott: But anyway, the thing is, you know, what happens undoubtedly is the wire starts to not do so good and not to look so good.
Scott: And some people, you know, actually those Dr.
Scott: Dre stupid headphones that I don't like, you know, I'm not sure what the audio quality is like on them, but I don't wear a gigantic headphone when I walk around town.
Scott: Those actually have a headphone cable that unplugs from the headphone.
Scott: So you can just replace the whole cable.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: I wish other headphones would fucking do that shit.
Rym: I guess it's partly I think people don't take good care of their headphones.
Scott: I try to.
Scott: I take extra good care of my etymotic.
Scott: I always put them in the case and oh, my etymotic.
Rym: I treat like gold, but you know what?
Scott: But they still wire so fucking breaks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The old like six, you know, barely.
Rym: Those are like the flimsiest pieces of shit.
Rym: The only reason I kept using mine is because they they've honored my warranty like five times.
Scott: Me too.
Scott: Anyway, so I discovered something I didn't know about.
Scott: that was sort of obvious in retrospect.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I watched a YouTube video, how to repair headphones, and he's pretty much cutting the wire, twisting the ends together, soldering them.
Scott: And I'm like, yeah, I know how to do all that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But then what he did at the end.
Scott: See, what I do is I just take electrical tape and sort of wrap it around the weak part.
Scott: What this guy did was genius.
Scott: Apparently, there's a thing I did not know about called heat shrink tubing.
Scott: You know about this?
Rym: Yes, I've used it extensively, mostly in Science Olympiad in middle school.
Scott: It's just a little black tube and you slide it over the wire and you take a lighter and you freaking heat that shit up and it shrinks.
Scott: And it's basically like having, you know, a real wire coating suddenly.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: And it's welcome to electronics.
Scott: Seventy seven dollars for 48 pieces in various sizes on Amazon.
Scott: I'm buying that shit.
Scott: So now it's like when headphones start to get weak.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, the wires poking out, but the headphones still works perfectly.
Scott: Boom.
Scott: He drink tubing right on that motherfucker.
Rym: All said, I just the thing is in my entire life, I'm not counting like headsets I've used for like gaming or like cheapo crap or whatever in terms of like actual headphones, like the kinds of studio headphones I'd use to like master.
Scott: You're not going to have the wire break on those.
Rym: Yeah, I own one pair from when I was like 11 until they broke a few years ago on my second pair ever.
Scott: Yeah, those things don't break.
Scott: I'm talking about the ones that you walk.
Scott: You have the phone in your pocket with the wire going into the pocket and under your coat as you walk around town,
Rym: who in their good goddamn mind would use anything but earbuds for that purpose, particularly
Scott: the wire on whether no matter what kind it is, earbud, headphone, whatever there's a wire and it is always fragile.
Scott: And if it is, if you're using it in the studio, the fragile a wire is not a problem.
Scott: If you're walking around town, no matter what kind, the fragile a wire becomes a problem.
Scott: That's why if you have the Dr.
Scott: Dre kind, you can replace the wire.
Rym: Otherwise you need to repair or I just got the slightly more expensive etymotic that are slightly less made of glass.
Scott: What I really was looking into was getting some Bluetooth headphones because then this whole problem goes.
Rym: actually Pete's got it going on because he's got the hearing aid.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: Got the box.
Rym: The box is also way to DP.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So I was looking for a TV headphones at the ones that a modic used to make.
Scott: They are discontinued.
Rym: What?
Rym: Really?
Scott: And and nobody really makes any that are good now that are wireless Bluetooth headphones.
Rym: I guess there was never much.
Scott: There's a few out there, but I guess here's my suspicion.
Rym: Why?
Rym: They're all there without the wire.
Rym: People lose them.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But they're all headsets for douchebags, you know, so you can talk on the phone.
Scott: But none of them are headphones with the stereo sound.
Scott: Really?
Scott: There's a few, but they all suck.
Rym: Yeah, that's how it goes.
Rym: Thing is, who uses a phone to talk?
Scott: The thing is, it would be really cool, right?
Scott: Imagine having, you know, like you wouldn't need to have the wire.
Scott: What I would like to have is the two in earbuds within like a plastic half circle sort of connecting.
Scott: They can go behind my head.
Scott: I want a sort of like backwards sunglasses.
Rym: I want a modern advanced neural input.
Rym: that just obviously.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: But then to take them off, I can just put them on my neck and then put them back up and then on the neck like that, you know, just like real headphones, but not gigantic.
Scott: And they would be Bluetooth wireless.
Scott: That's what my ideal product.
Rym: My ideal product would be a little step further if I guess I'm going to Google Glass and all that stuff.
Rym: I want.
Rym: Where is that, by the way?
Rym: Some day I want earbuds that I stick in that are complete isolation.
Rym: So and have little mechanical controls so that I can basically turn them into actual earplugs or listening to music in isolation or listening to stuff, but also hearing the real world or just hearing the real world.
Scott: Well, the way to hear the real world, right, is etymotic.
Scott: actually has this app on the iPhone called.
Rym: I saw the awareness.
Scott: And what it does is you put the etymotic in your ears.
Scott: You can't hear anything but the music.
Scott: But sometimes you do want to be aware of the outside world.
Scott: So you enable the awareness app and it actually uses the microphone on your phone or the microphone that's near your face on your phone to hear the outside world and then put that into your ear with but keeping it lower than the thing that you're listening to, you know, in the proper proportions so that you can be aware of the outside world while protecting your ears, while listening to music.
Rym: There are actually while being aware HCI terms for those sorts of like barriers of interaction between or feedback, like barriers between you and direct feedback.
Rym: It's analogous to the difference between like rack and pinion steering or completely electronic steering and all those kinds of things.
Rym: Only for ears.
Rym: But anyway, book club.
Rym: We'll get right to that.
Rym: But first, things of your mom, things of Scott's mom.
Rym: Oh, my God, I'm logged into my phone.
Rym: Who's calling me?
Rym: Screen this call.
Scott: OK, OK, sure.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Let us check this thing of the day.
Scott: Apparently in the UK, we missed the boat.
Scott: There was a sketch comedy show that I never heard of.
Scott: And someone from the UK is probably like, oh, my God, never heard of that.
Scott: Well, they probably never heard of the state or kids in the halls or whatever called the Mitchell and Webb situation.
Scott: And this is from, you know, the 2000s.
Scott: Actually, this is uploaded to YouTube in 07.
Scott: And it's a very funny sketch about farming.
Scott: And it's really hilarious and it kind of makes me want to be a farmer.
Scott: And it's funny.
Scott: Then it's only a minute and a half long.
Scott: So watch it.
Rym: It's about the same level as like one step under the really good white as kids, you know, stuff, but way above the mediocre white as kids, you know, stuff.
Rym: It's analogous to kids in the hall.
Rym: I think I agree.
Rym: Based on the one skit I saw, the nothing beats Lincoln.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: Lincoln?
Rym: What?
Rym: Okay.
Scott: What?
Rym: So you guys may not be aware of this, but a long time ago there was a musical called Les Miserables.
Rym: No.
Rym: Now wall is an obvious and very not from that long ago.
Rym: Very big musical.
Rym: It's from a while ago in that.
Rym: Where has it been touring recently?
Scott: You can go see it in places.
Rym: Yeah, not everywhere.
Rym: It's not like when I was a kid where it was in like every town and there were multiple international tours.
Rym: I saw him is like three times in the nineties and the official website.
Scott: Let's see where it's.
Rym: So anyway, my thing of the day is that if you weren't aware, there's a movie based on Les Mis coming, you know, there's trailers for it.
Rym: I actually saw the trailer during wreck at Ralph.
Rym: But the thing is, unlike the movie versions of Les Mis that just try to follow either the book or the plot of the musical, it's more of an actual musical that happens to be a movie.
Rym: I really dig musicals as movies.
Rym: So the trailer gave me those goosebumps of, oh, it's going to be good.
Scott: You can see it right now in Chicago starting tomorrow.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Until December 2nd.
Scott: Not bad.
Scott: Then it's going to Kansas City, then
Scott: D.C.,
Scott: then Philly, then Pittsburgh, then Kalamazoo.
Rym: So now New York.
Scott: Charlotte, Miami, Fort Myers.
Scott: Wait, hold on.
Rym: I'm holding.
Scott: Schenectady, April 30th, 2013.
Scott: Rochester, May 7th, 2013.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: New Haven, April 17th, Baltimore, Richmond, big cities.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: It's on tours from now until they got dates all the way up to June 9th, 2013.
Rym: I just got to realize I was chatting with Les Mis dot com.
Scott: LESMIS.
Rym: I was chatting with random listeners because the Counter-Strike server and everything.
Rym: and Les Mis came up and I realized a lot of people have never actually seen it.
Scott: Look at the coat on that master of the house, yo.
Scott: Wait, it disappeared.
Scott: They got a rotating image going on here.
Rym: I saw the same image you saw.
Rym: OK.
Scott: OK.
Rym: So the name of the win was your book club selection.
Scott: It was indeed.
Scott: So here's the story.
Scott: I was reading the Penny Arcade print editions, you know, which I buy all of.
Scott: And in one of them, there was an introduction and it was a pretty good introduction.
Scott: And in that introduction, the guy talked about how he was a fantasy author and Tycho read his books or something.
Scott: I don't remember the details.
Scott: All I remember is that at the end it said his name was Patrick Rothfuss.
Rym: Rothfuss.
Scott: I looked his ass up on the Internet because he wrote this introduction for Penny Arcade.
Scott: And I found out that he wrote this book called Name of the Wind and it was pretty popular.
Scott: And I was like, OK, that's good to know.
Scott: I'll read that book some fucking day.
Scott: And then the book started showing up all over the place.
Scott: And I and I mentioned it like a whole bunch of people had read it.
Scott: And I was like, oh, this is something I clearly escaped my radars.
Scott: Actually it didn't escape my radar.
Scott: It was just caught in it just now, at least at the time, just now, which was a long time ago because I bought the book at Amazon and had sat on my shelf, which is why I selected it as a book club book so I could read a book that I paid for instead of having to buy a new book.
Rym: So the usual warning.
Rym: This is the GeekNights book club.
Rym: We're assuming that you have already read The Name of the Wind by Patrick Rothfuss.
Rym: If not, we're going to spoil a bunch of stuff.
Scott: It is a fantasy novel of the typical nature.
Rym: So without further ado, what do you think of it?
Rym: Because honestly, I liked it.
Rym: OK, but I started the second book and got about a third of the way through it.
Rym: And now that I know that doesn't fucking go anywhere, I really like my opinion of the first book has gone down quite a bit.
Scott: Well, I mean, I'm not going to change.
Scott: I haven't read.
Scott: I have the second book.
Scott: I have not read any of it.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm not going through.
Rym: He's still in fucking school.
Rym: He doesn't have any money.
Rym: And then he pisses off the person to lend him money.
Rym: And then someone uses like malfeasance against some bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not going to modify my opinion.
Rym: And then he gets his loot back.
Scott: I'm not going to modify my opinion of the first book because of something in the second book.
Scott: I will, because now that is not legit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's like saying, man, you know, Mega Man 2 sucks because Mega Man 3 wasn't as good.
Rym: But if Mega Man 2 had been like ended with a story that clearly continued, it was like to be continued like Wiley gets away at the end.
Rym: And then the next game sucked.
Scott: Well, that means Mega Man 3 suck doesn't mean Mega Man 2 suck.
Rym: Ah, but remember, this book is part of a defined like pre hoc.
Scott: Well, yes, if I'm going to give a value judgment of the whole series as a whole, then, of course, the you know, all of the books together affect each other in that some judgment.
Scott: But if I'm judging only book one, book two and three got nothing to do with.
Rym: Ah, but I was judging book one under the assumption that the plot that the trilogy is a contiguous plot and it actually is a contiguous plot.
Rym: It's just one goddamn book.
Rym: There isn't.
Rym: the only reason it's a trilogy is for publishing reasons.
Scott: And also because it would be really quite large.
Rym: I have necessarily I have a copy of Kamara's Copper Serpent, Silver Dragon's Gold, some bullshit Piers Anthony book that's like that thick.
Scott: That's almost as thick as it would be.
Rym: It is ridiculous.
Scott: And I mean, I had you know, did you actually get the digital or physical version of book two of this?
Rym: Of course, digital of both.
Scott: I saw the physical ones.
Scott: Why would I buy a second?
Scott: one is bigger than the first one.
Scott: The third one's probably going to be bigger than that.
Scott: Knowing fantasy people.
Rym: Good God.
Scott: Anyway, so let's just talk about the first book.
Scott: OK, so the name of the wind.
Rym: It's about we don't we?
Rym: But everyone's read it.
Rym: We don't need to talk about what it's about.
Scott: There are some people listening who have not read it.
Scott: Fuck you.
Rym: OK, it's about a young boy who is the most perfect, best person ever.
Rym: He was born to a great family with awesome parents.
Rym: He's smarter than everyone.
Rym: Yeah, he's the smartest, most talented kid who have ever been born.
Rym: He's a goddamn Mary Sue and everything's perfect, except he sucks at flirting with women and he lives in a world of high school drama.
Rym: That's what it's about.
Rym: Oh, and his parents were killed by the Shandrian.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So that's really, you know, it's one of those situations, like a lot of fantasy things, where there's this big bad guy, this Shandrian.
Rym: It has to be Shandrian, otherwise the poems that he's referred to a few times, he rhymes Shandrian with plan.
Rym: OK, so unless it's plan, then it's Shandrian.
Scott: Well, it could be Shandrian.
Rym: Plan, Shandrian.
Rym: You don't say plan, you say plan.
Scott: It could be Shandrian at the end.
Scott: There's two different A's in there.
Scott: It could also be Shandrian.
Rym: I think they're evil enough.
Rym: Let's give them two Scranton A's.
Scott: Sure, whatever.
Scott: It doesn't fucking matter.
Scott: What does matter is that you sort of care about what the hell their fucking deal is.
Scott: It's like a group of bad guys in each one.
Scott: Like when one guy is nearby, all the fire turns blue.
Scott: And when the other guy is nearby, like you hear weird noises.
Scott: Well, what I kind of enjoy is these sort of the other guys nearby, all metal gets rusty.
Rym: But it's the piecing to get like the plot.
Rym: This is one of those situations of the proper nouns and the actual overall story is something I think is pretty cool.
Rym: I'm interested in.
Rym: There's a sort of precursor civilization and precursor magic, you know, the great days of tarpaulin, the great stars swirled the bearded away in the past.
Scott: That stuff isn't even that far in the past, but it's been largely forgotten and it's only like in tales and stuff like The Burning Wheel and stuff like that.
Scott: It's like, you know, relatively recent history, just some perhaps centuries ago, is now like legendary, even though it's totally true.
Scott: But you don't know what is totally true because, you know, they don't have a good record of history at all.
Scott: And you're basically just hearing from bards in the story.
Scott: And then the story is itself a story.
Scott: You know, it's just what the main character in the present is telling to this chronicler.
Scott: So how reliable is he?
Scott: Right.
Scott: How do you know how much of what he is saying is totally true?
Rym: If this book ends with him being the leader of the chandler and it's all a big sham.
Scott: Well, no, I can guarantee you.
Scott: I don't know if that's the case.
Rym: That would be great if he's an evil wizard and he's lying.
Scott: But I do know that he's definitely unreliable narrator.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You cannot trust that everything he is saying.
Rym: I don't get that impression.
Rym: I get the.
Rym: So Patrick Rothfuss, I get the impression that they're written from it reads like a young adult novel.
Rym: I have absolutely zero suspicion that there is anything in the retelling that is not the literal truth.
Rym: I don't think he's going for a story like that at all.
Rym: I think is I don't really because the rest of the book is written in a kind of I don't want to say novice, but it's written or amateurish, but it's really young adult, really straightforward.
Rym: There's very little subtlety.
Scott: I disagree.
Rym: There is no subtlety at any level in the level of writing the diction.
Rym: I'm not even talking about the story.
Rym: I'm talking about all the other elements.
Scott: I agree with that.
Scott: But I'm still.
Scott: I still think that he is not 100 percent reliable in his.
Scott: you know, what he is telling.
Scott: that chronicler is not the 100 percent, quote, truth in that fantasy world.
Rym: I'm not going to give.
Rym: I really don't think I see no evidence of that.
Rym: Just from the way the book is written, I don't feel like the author even considered doing something like that.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, we'll see.
Scott: Seriously, if you start reading the next book and you see where this is going, it's well, you know, we have a book and two thirds to find out if that's the case.
Scott: But that is that is my suspicion of what is going on here.
Rym: Also, the fact that there's it's a little sloppy.
Rym: This is why I don't believe he's doing anything like that in that the retelling occasionally will edge toward the character kind of saying like, no, it was like this or like this.
Rym: But then it always lapses into a sort of narrative as though that is the book itself, like the way it is written implies that the author is not putting care into making the distinction.
Rym: That is why I do not suspect that he's going to do anything clever like that anyway.
Scott: But yeah, I do agree with you that, you know, while like the story, you know, is sort of interesting and, you know, different parts of it, you end up caring or not caring about.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He really just sort of.
Scott: you know, the biggest problem overall is the sort of spinning of the wheels.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like not even the burning wheels.
Scott: No, the burning wheels spinning is the good part.
Rym: I know.
Scott: Why can't the whole book be that the bad part is, you know, he gets he's in a situation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And things are moving along.
Scott: And, you know, so for example, he's went at the part where he's poor in that city and he can't escape the life of being a street urchin.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it's he basically has these problems of being a street urchin and he runs into the same problems over and over again.
Scott: And, you know, he succeeds in getting some help and maybe moving out.
Scott: And then, no, he doesn't.
Scott: And then he does.
Scott: And he doesn't.
Scott: And it's like, how long are you going to go back and forth?
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: and the thing is, it would be OK if it was like, you know, something different.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like in Burning Wheel, you let it you let it ride when you try one way of solving a problem.
Rym: Oh, I'll go one step further.
Rym: In Burning Wheel, if you fail your resources test every time you fail it, different bullshit happens, not the exact same bullshit.
Scott: It's like if you if you want to have him fail or succeed with a particular problem, OK, the next part of the book should be a different problem with a different solution, not I have no money.
Scott: I try to get money.
Scott: I don't get money.
Scott: I have no money.
Scott: I try to get money.
Scott: I still have no money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like he just keeps trying multiple times in slightly different ways with very crook, slightly so differences between before actually moving forward to the next part.
Rym: So I think so.
Scott: And then when he gets to the magic school, then that becomes the book just fucking ends when it's magic school.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And then it gets into the sort of the three way cycle of, you know, the needs money, money, girl and academics, the trifecta.
Rym: And now this is where the book lost me.
Scott: Yeah, it's good.
Scott: All three of those things are good on their own, but he cycles between the three things, repeating at least three or four times.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: And it's like you should have dealt with each one of those things once and then maybe bring one of them back at the end to be like, oh, shit.
Rym: Right.
Rym: So this is indicative of a much sort of deeper fundamental problem, which is why I really this is a young adult fantasy novel is this is nowhere.
Rym: It's a lot of elements of it are fun in the same way that the lives of Locke Lammer are really fun.
Scott: But at least Locke Lammer doesn't, you know, doesn't spin like that move.
Rym: So what what this?
Rym: the elegance?
Rym: what's happening in this book is?
Rym: it does what I've called for many years myself, the proper noun march where Prince and nothing has a proper noun.
Rym: No, it does not.
Rym: It has proper nouns.
Scott: A lot more.
Scott: Yes, it has a lot more proper nouns.
Rym: The proper noun march has nothing to do with the number or extent of proper nouns in a book.
Rym: All right.
Rym: The proper noun march.
Rym: Here's an example.
Rym: He joins the school, right?
Rym: He gets into the university.
Rym: That is huge climax where he proves that he's a boy genius prodigy and the arcanist take the board.
Rym: You know, the masters take this unprecedented step of giving him a tuition of less three talents.
Scott: That was pretty clever.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: So that's immediately forgotten the next term around.
Rym: And he has to pay like four or five talents to.
Scott: I know that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So but the fact that it was this huge deal.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: This kid is going.
Rym: he's like he's a prodigy.
Rym: He's going to go to the wizard school.
Rym: Jesus fucking Christ.
Rym: And then immediately, oh, well, you're not an arcanist yet or you're not in L.A.
Rym: yet.
Rym: Oh, you're not a real are yet.
Rym: Oh, and you know what?
Rym: There are more levels beyond that that I've progressed through.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: He progresses through so many proper nouns of wizard bullshit, none of which are mentioned ever or Chekhov until it's time to use them like I want to use this kind of magic.
Rym: Oh, well, you need to be an L fuck yourself before you can do that.
Scott: Yeah, I think, you know, the best wizard school story I've ever read was, you know, the first book of Earthsea where the wizard school is actually only a small portion of the book.
Scott: But these stories, they tell of the wizard school.
Rym: Ah, now this would have been fine to see.
Scott: He shows up at the front of the wizard school and is the challenge with the guy with the door.
Scott: Remember?
Scott: And he's got it right.
Scott: And then on the way out, there's the doorman again, sealing the wizards.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that's you know, that is really the awesomeness.
Rym: Now, this could have had the same thing if it had just been about the wizard school, like that was the plot.
Rym: Like, here's the story of a dude who went through wizard school.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: It's like there's a guy and his story is elsewhere.
Scott: His story is with this Shandrian and what the how did he get to this bar with this, you know, demon companion and these rock spiders and this this whole world.
Scott: And clearly this guy is a really important, you know, awesome wizard character in this world at the present time, not like an ancient history.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like he's still a badass, supposedly.
Rym: But if I graph the percentage of time in the book spent on different things, it's mostly teen angst.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's mostly wizard school angst and like, oh, my God, he was a jerk to me.
Rym: So I'm going to pull a prank on him and it's going to escalate until someone tries to kill someone.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like what kind of, you know, you know, epic, awesome, important guy is so shallow, teen angst, revenge, right?
Scott: It's like that is not what, you know, the awesome wizard of the land is supposed to act and it makes you know that makes you not like him.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like I like.
Scott: Now, that would be fine.
Rym: I like these other characters more if that was also a plot that was resolved or something interesting happened with it.
Rym: But the fact that the book doesn't use those as like an example of something that shaped him or an example of him being a dumb kid, it just revels in it.
Rym: It revels like that, like this is the primary conflict for all these years.
Rym: The book basically moves at a pretty quick pace.
Rym: The story moves quickly until wizard school.
Rym: And then wizard school is just.
Rym: it's like a different book.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it gets mired in the wizard school.
Scott: It's like, yeah, you're still brand from the archives.
Rym: So the proper now in March gets a little bit worse in that problems will be raised.
Rym: And then the solution to the problems is almost always a proper noun.
Rym: that was the hitherto never foreshadowed or mentioned.
Scott: And yeah, like I need money.
Scott: Well, the solution is apparently there's this lending money lady in town.
Rym: The Prince of Nothing says the word Dunyane in the beginning and keeps using it consistently throughout.
Rym: This picks up and drops proper nouns as are necessary and to seal it off.
Rym: I'm complaining a lot, but I'm not saying it's a bad book.
Rym: Proper noun March culminates.
Rym: The thing that pisses me off the most.
Scott: Well, the reason, you know, whenever you complain like this and you and then you go to say this is not, you know, whenever you have any sort of media that you complain a lot about, but you go, but you also just sort of make an offhand remark like you like it.
Scott: It's not bad.
Scott: That's because it is a thing that has good parts and has flaws.
Scott: And in and in those cases, there's the more to complain about than if something sucks, because if something sucks, you can just say this fucking sucks.
Scott: Don't watch it.
Scott: Don't read it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you have a lot of complaints like this.
Scott: It's because there was a potential for greatness that was ruined because of a major flaw or two.
Rym: Not even ruined, because as much as I am like, oh, my God, this fucking school, it's like I was just about to put down the second book.
Rym: Right.
Rym: I was like, you know what?
Rym: I'm done with this.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And then malfeasance came out of nowhere.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I was like, oh, let's see where this goes.
Rym: And then that just got resolved.
Rym: And now we can't pay tuition like Jesus.
Rym: Jesus.
Rym: Oh, God.
Scott: But yeah.
Rym: So but so what I was getting?
Rym: the thing that pisses me off the most and it's bothering me to the point that I almost can't read the book anymore is that these proper nouns are brought up and used and dropped all the time.
Rym: But he does this particular thing.
Rym: I don't know if there's a word for this technique, but I see it in so many bad books that it feels out of place and stands in stark contrast in this book.
Scott: Are you talking about where he says exactly what's going to happen?
Scott: Oh, no, I love that.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I love that when he's like there's a part in the.
Scott: that is the major technique that I've seen used three or four in the early part of wizard school.
Rym: There's that paragraph.
Rym: There's a paragraph at the end of this chapter where everything was going really well for him.
Rym: It was like, yeah, of course, eventually Ambrose tried to kill me and then I got kicked out of the school.
Scott: But yeah, I didn't get expelled then and he tried to kill me.
Scott: And then, you know, I did get kicked out of school later.
Scott: And it's like he tells you exactly what's going to happen.
Scott: But you don't know that can work.
Scott: You don't know the how, why, what, when.
Scott: you don't know any details.
Scott: All you know is that this thing is going to happen for sure.
Scott: He is going to get kicked out of wizard school.
Scott: He says it for sure.
Rym: That can be done really well.
Rym: Look at American beauty.
Rym: It's not a spoiler to say the dude dies in the end because he tells you he dies in the end.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: The first season, even at the beginning of the book, he's pretty much.
Scott: he doesn't say it as explicitly, but he says his parents are going to get killed.
Scott: Right.
Rym: You know, in so many words that are now that even sets up an interesting tension.
Rym: And then I was drawn in.
Scott: his parents get killed.
Scott: But you don't know how what until it happens.
Scott: And then it's like, oh, that's how it went down.
Scott: And then it means something even more.
Scott: So, you know, that's it didn't matter that you knew that it was.
Rym: that stuff is cool.
Rym: For example, once it once he implied you knew that something bad was going to happen to his parents and everything was going to change.
Rym: Innocuous events seemed really sinister and yet nothing bad happened for a while.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: You never know.
Scott: It's like now you're looking for something.
Scott: So it's sort of like an alien when she's walking around and it's the cat.
Scott: It's the cat.
Scott: And then the alien doesn't even go jump out and go boo.
Scott: The alien is just right behind her going like.
Rym: So, no, that's not what bothers me.
Rym: What bothers me is when he will do this sort of snarky, self-indulgent thing of using proper nouns to make a pseudo clever point like he'll use pseudo like proper nouns to reference basically high school chemistry a lot.
Rym: Or more importantly, in the music stuff, he will refer he'll do it.
Rym: There's a scene where he plays a really hard song, but he does it like flippantly and he plays a really easy song.
Rym: But he acts like it's this huge effort and does like this comedy routine at the end.
Rym: I forgot his pipes and all that stuff.
Rym: But the way that is written just really rubbed me the wrong way.
Rym: It's like like he explains to me the reader after the fact, oh, you've probably never heard of this song, but this song is particularly known for being difficult.
Rym: It reeks of Montaigne's hedgehog.
Scott: What's Montaigne's hedgehog?
Rym: You've read The Man Who Was Thursday.
Rym: The Hedgehog of Montaigne.
Rym: OK, the Pig of Montaigne, although all those references of, you know, the false reference to something that isn't real, but seems very intellectual, the book does that a lot.
Rym: It'll reference, you know, I'm a musician.
Rym: The way music is referred to reeks of someone who hasn't actually ever been a professional musician, but has a very romanticized ideal of it.
Rym: The way romance is portrayed reeks of someone who has only ever experienced high school romance.
Scott: Well, I think what it is, is, you know, he's trying to show the how awesome.
Scott: forget the main characters, Rick and both both.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: He's trying to show how awesome both is.
Scott: So if he's like if he wants to show you how awesome he is at playing music, that's not easy with no audio.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So or video.
Scott: So he's got to pretty much describe it as difficult.
Scott: somehow, you know, as you know, with words, how awesome is he at music?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So how would you write that?
Scott: And so, you know, I'm not a writer.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: So I do know that this is not the best way to do that.
Rym: And thus the proper noun March, whenever he needs to, whenever the author needs to make a clever point, he'll use he'll refer to a proper noun that has very little context.
Rym: Like you could you you cannot really grok the different properties of these different proper nouns of alcohol because they're used sort of flippantly to make these funny points.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, well, like, you know, in terms of the music.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He has his his parents play this song.
Scott: that is, you know, and when his parents are playing the song, he make he tells the history of the song and how hard it is.
Scott: And then, of course, he just says, oh, and then both played the same song that has the same title, which is a proper noun, of course.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then it's like, oh, that's the hard song the parents play.
Scott: This must be way hard.
Scott: And he pulled it off with a string broken.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: But meanwhile, for example, take the Prince of Nothing, a lot more proper noun bullshit.
Scott: But it's not.
Rym: those proper nouns are used continuously and contextually and but they're not used in a way to replace describing something.
Rym: Here, I feel like Patrick Rothfuss too often will use a proper noun to replace having to actually describe something or to make a point that he couldn't otherwise make without setting a lot of other hooks up along the way.
Rym: That bothered me.
Rym: So all those criticisms aside, I still enjoyed the book.
Rym: The only reason I feel less good about it is that having read a whole bunch of the second book is not fucking going anywhere.
Scott: No, I haven't read the second book, so I don't know if it's going to go anywhere.
Scott: But really, you know, I think this is almost like a one piece situation, right?
Scott: Just replace the sort of fighting the fish man for 10 chapters.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then getting to the good part, if he would just like if we could somehow compress it, which is why I actually, you know, compress those sort of long fighting sequences and just have only the good parts.
Scott: I think this is actually the kind of thing where if it were made not to a TV series, the TV series would keep rolling around, you know, around in it, but either a miniseries or, you know, movies.
Rym: I know that is good writing.
Rym: The way you said rolling around it, it implies that it is poop.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That's why I just like talking about, you know, how he's rolling back.
Rym: You see how Scott did that?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Then, you know, it would if it was movies that those parts of where the same thing was repeated over and over again would be compressed or even, you know, some of those something I talk about a lot, some of those smaller plots would be removed entirely.
Scott: For example, I talk about like this.
Scott: What's that?
Scott: The girl who's like the sort of feral girl who lives in the sewer?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like she's pretty cool.
Scott: You know, that kind of plot.
Rym: Oh, she knows a lot about the Shandrian, too, apparently.
Scott: Oh, I didn't know that.
Scott: Got to read book two.
Scott: But but the point is, is that, you know, she is she's obviously useful in the overall story.
Scott: She shows him the secret way into the archives, which is kind of important.
Scott: And, you know, he worries about her when the horrible chemical breaks out in the, you know, chemistry alchemy, Arcanist lab, whatever, which is also kind of an important plot thingy or whatever.
Scott: But, you know, but really, it's like, do you need like this extra?
Scott: it's like she was barely so barely even in the story before she was used.
Scott: It's like he played music with her once and it was like in a very short scene.
Rym: She would be fine if not for the fact that she's clearly part of a harem.
Rym: Look at the way girls are written and portrayed in these books.
Rym: And especially as he starts getting all these girls around him who like him and he likes the one girl.
Rym: And it's all it's one step short of being a tenchi muyo situation.
Scott: Oh, that is true.
Scott: Is that there?
Scott: it seems like there.
Rym: once he saved fella, I was like, OK, there's two girls.
Scott: That's well, I mean, come on.
Scott: There's the scene where he walks into magic school for like the first time and he pretty much notices because, you know, there's not a lot of girls there, which, you know, this isn't a sexist situation.
Scott: I think it's actually sort of realistic RIT situation.
Scott: And on top of that, it's a fantasy world.
Scott: So it's even worse.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it does make sense that there are not a lot of women in this place, but it does seem that, you know, they're not treated by this society any more, you know, in a sexist way than any other fantasy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Then into another fancy world, as in a teenage boy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The perspective of an adolescent.
Scott: Any time there's a girl, it's like there's a girl.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: There's a girl.
Scott: There's a girl there.
Scott: And it's like whenever a girl is there, there's a spotlight.
Scott: She's noticed.
Scott: She's named.
Rym: He notices her like the galette galette that he borrows money from.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Any girl, anything with boobs and a vagina that's around, he notices it.
Scott: He has a name.
Scott: You know, not just that.
Scott: It gets focused on.
Rym: the girls are all it's it's the moe harem.
Rym: Every one of them is like an extreme in one direction or the other.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like there's the one he wants, but there's always this sort of tension with any of them that he could get with them, sort of because, you know, there's girls, you know, around.
Scott: And yeah, it's.
Scott: it's a little bit annoying, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, the dude friends.
Scott: It's sort of like I like dude friend characters.
Rym: But and it's like it took me until the second book to be able to even differentiate the two.
Scott: That's that's the thing, right?
Scott: It's like there's the.
Scott: there's the rich dude friend who's like sort of a risk.
Rym: Now, which one's which is William and Sam?
Rym: Which one's which?
Scott: Fuck if I know.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: See, and that's the thing is that it was so weird is how you would have things like you would refer to them like, oh, William and his blah, blah, blah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, you know, saying, you know, William was acting in his usual way like this and this and this.
Rym: Meanwhile, it was nothing.
Rym: I know exactly what I what an I known he looks like.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But William and Sam didn't.
Scott: Actually act in different ways.
Scott: They were effectively just the friends.
Scott: He could have had one friend.
Scott: It didn't matter.
Scott: And it's like he would talk about their personalities or the differences between them, but they wouldn't actually sort of behave in different ways.
Scott: And I couldn't.
Scott: you know, it's like you wouldn't notice immediately which one was which, which one did he bump into in the street, who was helping him, who wasn't helping him, who is stealing the girl from him, who wasn't.
Scott: It didn't.
Scott: it was just one of his friends.
Scott: It does not even name those guys.
Scott: They might have just said his good friends were we saw one of his good friends.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: Now, we do remember Ambrose, but he's basically actually the primary antagonist in the second half of the book.
Scott: He's the primary.
Scott: I mean, I think the the Shondrian are the real primary antagonist.
Rym: Yeah, but good luck reading that from the books.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, since they're the dark, evil, mysterious square boss, you can't show you too much of them.
Scott: So early in book one, we got to sell book three.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, even Prince of Nothing does that consult.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Same thing, you know, so they need this Ambrose to be the primary antagonist, but he's only there for the second half of the book.
Scott: And really, the antagonists in the, you know, for the rest of the book are the environment.
Scott: It's really him versus the world and not versus anyone in particular.
Rym: Now, here's the other thing I didn't like because there is a lot of stuff I like.
Rym: Don't get me wrong.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But the the the thing I didn't like was that the school is set up by the author to cause all of these problems.
Rym: The fact that the tuition cycle is literally.
Rym: they interview you, they make up tuition.
Rym: You have to pay it by like noon the next fucking day.
Rym: Really?
Rym: That's how the wizard school works.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They could have made.
Scott: you know, it is a fictional world.
Scott: He could have made the wizard school work any way he wanted to, but he made it work in this way.
Rym: It is kind of ridiculous.
Scott: cause this conflict to keep happening over and over again.
Scott: And the other thing that really bothered me was like, why couldn't it just be the wizard school recognizes him for a genius?
Scott: They let him.
Rym: you know, he's in the wizard school or they don't recognize him and force him to prove it.
Rym: And then he kicks him.
Scott: But yeah, but and he kicks him ass and he gets in.
Scott: And then it could all you could have focused more on the jealousy of the other people in the school.
Scott: Instead, it's like the other people in the school are just sort of vaguely jealous or support the other school.
Rym: Other people in the school are different side characters, right?
Scott: Except for Ambrose.
Scott: And the only dude.
Rym: why the fuck does Ambrose even hate him so much?
Rym: That doesn't actually make sense.
Scott: It's he meets.
Scott: Yeah, it's like he's.
Scott: he's like the bad guy he met on the first day of school, just like in any movie.
Rym: High school bully.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: You meet, you know, whenever you have a movie about high school, there's always shows up and up.
Scott: There's the bully rules.
Scott: It's like Doug.
Scott: Roger.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Why does Roger hate Doug?
Scott: It's just that he was the bully.
Scott: We was with a green face in the first episode.
Scott: That's why.
Scott: And Doug was the new kid in town.
Scott: That's why there's no reason.
Scott: It just how it is.
Rym: Yeah, it's just I got so sick of it.
Rym: And the last thing that bothered me of all these things is that the book is supposed to be in a fantasy world.
Rym: And while we're in this university where there's, you know, there's, you know, science and single degree and all these things, there's too many modern sensibilities and too many like modern real world references to like chemistry and things that just feel really out of place.
Rym: And it feels like I'm reading a fantasy book of someone who's currently taking like organic chemistry to a one in college.
Rym: Maybe one of what like Willemur Sim gets in trouble is like I was mixing water with acid instead of the other way around.
Rym: I just it stood out every time that happened.
Rym: Like, really, dude, it'd be like if I wrote a fantasy book and I was like, I went into the you know, I went into the kingdom of blah under the radar.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The other thing is, you know, while I like, you know, fantasy worlds and how does this fantasy world work, every fantasy world works differently.
Scott: Right.
Rym: This one doesn't give you enough context.
Rym: Know how it works.
Scott: Lord of the Rings works like this.
Scott: And prince of nothing.
Scott: It's all about how does it work?
Scott: That's the whole core of the book.
Scott: is how, you know, trying to figure that the fuck out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Why does the nose?
Scott: is this right?
Scott: And it's like Lord of the Rings.
Scott: Well, there's the magic of the elves and, you know, all this stuff.
Scott: But in this game, in this book, there's all these different kinds of magic that are completely unrelated.
Rym: Single degree alchemy, sympathy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They got nothing to do with each other.
Scott: And they don't.
Scott: even he doesn't even try to figure out what the fuck they have to do with each other.
Scott: Saying the name and all of them are like sort of stolen flat out from other fantasy worlds, like saying the names of things.
Scott: That's fucking Earthsea.
Scott: That's straight up Earthsea.
Scott: saying the names of things to get them to obey your will or whatever.
Rym: Let's go one step further.
Rym: So the way sympathy works with the Alar, you know, it's full metal fucking alchemist.
Rym: No, no, no, it's worse than that.
Rym: The Alar bothers me because he makes a big point about and then he split his mind into two pieces.
Rym: And do you remember that prince of nothing when he's with Abenthi and he goes through all the exercises and how to split his mind?
Rym: Mm hmm.
Rym: They're bullshit.
Rym: Like in the real world, they have no analogy to any actual meditative techniques.
Rym: They're so out there and kind of just made up.
Rym: Like if you're going to just make it up to that level, don't even go into that depth with it.
Rym: And then later, like he can do like eight Alar.
Rym: Now, fuck you.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The prince of it does the problem where it makes something seem so monumental.
Rym: And then the next chapter, it's trivial.
Rym: It's like Final Fantasy.
Rym: As soon as like an imp does a million damage to you and then you level up once and now you do a million damage to the imp.
Scott: So that is true.
Scott: It's like you did eight Alar.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: Well, you know, you're the master now.
Scott: You know, it's like, no, you're just still some kid in magic school.
Scott: You know, it's like, well, how many fuck could the masters do?
Scott: We've never seen them do crazy shit like that.
Rym: And or like when he does the in the beginning, right?
Rym: It's like it's like he's a kid with no education, came out of nowhere, got into the school in these weird circumstances.
Rym: And on his first day of classes, he uses magic.
Rym: And no one's like, how do you learn that?
Rym: No one's like, how come he already knows everything?
Rym: Instead, they get mad at him.
Rym: And the teacher holds a grudge to Hemi.
Scott: Yeah, that that's the thing.
Scott: Some of the masters are cool.
Scott: I like the crazy master who I like.
Rym: The crazy master.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Because he's sort of I sort of imagine him as like a timber.
Rym: Whenever they're doing the whenever they're doing the like, he's on the horns getting interviewed for something because he's in trouble.
Rym: That master is always like, what the fuck does this even matter?
Rym: Why am I even fucking awake?
Scott: I like that guy.
Scott: I actually like the archivist guy a little bit, too.
Rym: He's very.
Rym: he's like Snape.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I like the sort of, you know, the the the archivist guy, because he seems like a normal like a good shop teacher, which I think is what he's supposed to be.
Scott: But he's just like a completely normal, not crazy, not stupid, stand up, you know, stout guy like, yeah, I can like that guy.
Scott: But all the other ones are kind of like, they don't seem very masterly to me, especially the petty ones.
Scott: How did you get to be a master?
Scott: You know, and then one of them is like, you know, seems like the Supreme Court.
Scott: Who's the guy in the Supreme Court?
Rym: Chancellor?
Scott: No, on the real Supreme Court of the United States.
Scott: You always just a follower and does what he's told.
Scott: That's the guy who always does what Hemi tells him to do.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Or then the chancellor, who only actual opinion of anything seems to be.
Rym: I'm too old for this shit and I don't care.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So here's the get before we get to the stuff I liked about these books.
Rym: Emily and I talk about this a lot.
Rym: Works like this that have flaws, but have like these fun iconic moments in them or these good characters kind of scattered out within them are great to be turned into movies because you can't do it.
Rym: You can't do a literal adaptation.
Rym: It would suck.
Rym: It would be too long.
Rym: You have to do a liberal adaptation.
Rym: But because the source material is not super great to begin with, no one's going to flip out and get mad at you.
Rym: Like if you change something in Lord of the Rings.
Scott: Some crazy nerd.
Rym: No one who matters.
Rym: If you change, look at how many people were flipping out about Tom Bombadil.
Scott: Well, it's like think about Game of Thrones, right?
Scott: There were nerds who were already Game of Thrones fans who might be flipping out about the TV show, but not many.
Scott: Most of them actually like it.
Scott: And two, most people hit the TV show first, right?
Scott: So even though Name of the Wind was crazy best selling, even though it's not been adapted to anything, it wasn't actually crazy best selling.
Rym: Almost every book is a best seller, you know?
Rym: But I mean, this is the term that New York Times best seller means bullshit.
Scott: I know that.
Scott: But I'm saying regardless of how many copies it actually sold, it's not what I'm referring to.
Scott: What I'm referring to is how, you know, on a pond discussing this book on the Internet, many, many people say, oh, I read that.
Scott: Yeah, let me tell you about that one.
Scott: It was already quite popular among the nerd community.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So but, you know, even though it is relatively new, that are best to be made into a movie or something, because the wide audience won't have read the book.
Rym: Only the nerds will have.
Scott: And they never will.
Rym: And even if the nerds get mad, they'll be drowned out by all the people who, you know, you could.
Rym: basically you can adapt the story enough to where a creative adapter and a good director can really make the movie stand on its own by casting the right people, focusing on the right things, changing the parts that don't make sense, like Hunger Games.
Rym: They got rid of the stupid goddamn wolves.
Rym: They didn't.
Rym: They just got rid of it.
Scott: I still haven't seen that.
Scott: Maybe it'll be on Netflix soon.
Rym: Yeah, the wolves are just wolves.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: They don't.
Rym: They don't even in any way reference the bullshit that happened in the book and was stupid.
Scott: The weird genetic engineering nonsense.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So the things I liked about this book when Kvothe is trying to get a load and to teach him names and a load and takes him to the insane place and he's like, I was locked in here, la dee da dee da.
Rym: And he's like and close, like, what do I have to do to be your student?
Rym: I'll do anything.
Rym: And it looks like jump off the roof and he immediately jumps off the roof so fast that I can't even be like, just kidding.
Rym: And then you just see like he's the way he describes that scene.
Rym: Like he looks up as he's falling.
Rym: You see the master just kind of with his arm out like, oh, fuck.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because it's like that was so good.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: That was a great scene, because what he's doing there is unlike, say, just stealing straight from Earthsea, right?
Scott: He is taking the thing you have already have a set expectation of that from other things you've looked at.
Scott: Say the Matrix, the jump scene.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He's taking your set expectation of a cliche and turning it on its head.
Scott: In sort of an obvious way.
Scott: It's not you know, it's not that clever, but it just happens.
Scott: You didn't see it coming.
Scott: I was thinking Matrix seen all the way right up until the guy's like, you're fucking stupid.
Rym: And I like.
Scott: and then as soon as he said that, I was like, oh, that was awesome.
Rym: I also love the undercurrent of like.
Rym: the people don't know their own reputations, but they grow them anyway.
Rym: And it kind of fits in with the name thing.
Rym: That whole undercurrent is great.
Rym: I love when you get snippets of what other students think about him, because they don't know him.
Rym: They just have these stories of him, you know, both the bloodless because they did, you know, get whipped and he didn't bleed or he got in a fight with a load and a load and threw him off the roof.
Rym: Like that's what they think happened.
Rym: I like those little like flavor bits.
Scott: The thing that I you know, these after the cycling, the only other thing, you know, I mean, we complain it's sort of fan service and you know, stuff like that and sort of shallow.
Scott: But actually, that makes it kind of fun, right?
Scott: Yeah, we're nerds.
Scott: We like fantasy books.
Scott: If you put in fantasy, you know, what's what's the word for Mary Sue?
Scott: That's a dude.
Rym: Whatever it is, a couple of terms, I just use Mary Sue for all of them.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You know, it's kind of fun because he's so awesome.
Scott: There's an awesome dude.
Scott: It's a good time reading the book, except he's stupid around girls.
Rym: Yeah, it's I just I just tire of it.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like reading, you know, parties and, you know, light and happy reading.
Scott: But the thing I actually don't like the most is that it's sort of like just a story.
Scott: There's no real meaning or message or anything.
Scott: There's no deep anything, at least, you know, Prince of Nothing has some message about philosophy and knowledge and epistemology.
Scott: You know, Lord of the Rings also doesn't mean anything either.
Scott: But there are, you know, there are lots of other fantasy things to do.
Scott: Like I was reading the White Goldwielder stuff, and it's like this dude who's a leper, but then he somehow is in this fantasy world and he keeps telling the people in the fantasy world don't know what a leper is.
Scott: But it's like, you know, it's all about, you know, leprosy and how, you know, this person, you know, as a disability and living in a world where people don't see him as disabled and he sees himself, you know, and there's.
Scott: there's something going on there in the middle of this fantasy adventure that has a message and a meaning.
Scott: And this doesn't have one.
Scott: It's literally just a revenge story of a guy going to try to, you know, on his path of becoming awesome.
Scott: So the leveling up in a JRPG style so he could find the secret Chandri and bad guys and get revenge for killing his parents.
Rym: Yeah, but as soon as he levels up, it doesn't matter.
Rym: Like, oh, he's a R'laar, Jesus fucking Christ.
Rym: Oh, but he's not an L.L.
Rym: or whatever.
Scott: And there's mysterious spidery demons somewhere, and it's his fault.
Scott: And that's all we know.
Rym: I also liked the meth lab out in the woods when he slayed the dragon.
Scott: That was clever.
Rym: That was great.
Scott: Once once the best part about that whole dragon thing was not only the cleverness of it and of course, the dragons were foreshadowed with that dragon book, how his plan didn't fucking work, how it didn't work, but also how it was a break from wizard school.
Scott: I know they got you away from the wizard school.
Rym: Like so.
Rym: Yeah, here's the fun of all brothers book.
Rym: He slays the goddamn dragon.
Rym: And then the author like goes out of his way to undo.
Rym: Every advantage he got from that.
Scott: You make sure you think it was a Marvel comic book.
Rym: We had to reset the status that by the time he gets back to fucking wizard school.
Rym: He's poor.
Scott: In fact, that's exactly what it's like.
Scott: It's like, you know, you.
Scott: it's a. it's like a superhero comic book.
Scott: You play.
Scott: it's all about playing with the toys and smashing them up really interestingly and then resetting everything to the status quo when you're, you know, putting everything back away cleanly for the next person, even though it's the same person and it's not a comic book.
Scott: You don't need to fucking do that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You should just mess up the toys and keep messing them up more.
Scott: And when the toys are all broken, bring buy some new toys and add them into the mix and smash them up, too.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That's what you need to do in a novel series.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Not fucking keep resetting things all the time, you know, to make what you just smashed up now meaningless.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, it's a you know what?
Rym: It's an OK fantasy book.
Rym: I would only actually recommend it if you're starved for good fantasy because you've read everything else already.
Rym: That's good because it's not bad.
Rym: It's fun.
Scott: But if you haven't, there are a lot worse fantasy books you could be reading.
Scott: If you haven't read The Lies of Locke Lamora, read those two books first, because those are also meaningless, but more fun and don't have the same sort of, you know, plots.
Scott: Those are the opposite things.
Rym: Those just escalate and escalate and escalate and escalate and escalate and escalate and escalate.
Rym: I could go on.
Scott: Well, at the beginning of the second book, it starts out less escalated, but escalates quickly.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: To a to a somewhat an end that that author probably can't write himself out of it, which is probably why there isn't a third book yet.
Scott: I have the second book anyway, I guess The Wise Man's Fear.
Rym: I have it, too.
Scott: And I'm going to.
Scott: I'm going to read it eventually.
Scott: I think it's like I'm not super excited to read it, you know, but it's like I am curious about what the deal is with the Shondrian and all that stuff.
Scott: It is it is a a legit mystery.
Scott: I'm intrigued.
Rym: So I've started.
Rym: I'm reading it, but I'm literally skimming anything about the wizard school where plot is not moving forward.
Rym: And it's suddenly a lot more enjoyable.
Rym: I think the problem is I read books closely.
Scott: I do.
Scott: I always read any book I read.
Scott: I read fucking every word.
Rym: I mean, The Prince of Nothing, like I read and I work.
Scott: I write that multiple times.
Rym: I've read that multiple times, too.
Rym: But this you know what this is?
Rym: Lives of Black Lamora is like a solid B anime.
Rym: Like like a Lupin is like, yeah, exactly.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It is Lupin.
Rym: This is a B minus in that this is on the level of like causing no Yojimbo, like it's pretty good.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: OK, but when I finish an episode, I don't really care if I see the next episode or not, like I don't really.
Rym: But then if I read The Prince of Nothing or something, it's like when I watch the episode of Cowboy Bebop and suddenly I remember what it's like to watch something that's like a great.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think I'll give it a B minus.
Scott: I can give it a B because at RIT, we don't have plus minus.
Rym: I have to give it a B minus because I give Black Lamora a B and I give The Prince of Nothing an A.
Scott: I would give Black Lamora a B plus, B plus, B plus or A minus, B plus.
Rym: Right, because I think A minus requires something beyond the story.
Scott: I think it does.
Scott: So yeah, I'll give Black Lamora a B plus.
Scott: I'll give Name of the Wind just B.
Rym: A minus is a story that isn't written that well.
Rym: Like it's written less well than something that's written well.
Rym: That's a funny way to put it.
Rym: But also has the external message.
Rym: A B plus is written better than an A minus, but has less meat beyond the story itself.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what is the next book club?
Rym: The next book club book, because there is a movie coming next year, is The Great Gatsby.
Scott: Isn't it Gatsby?
Scott: You said Gatsby.
Rym: You know who's written by it?
Rym: F. F.
Scott: I guess I said it's Scott Fitzgerald.
Rym: F. Scott Fitzgerald.
Scott: I did not know that.
Scott: I know that.
Scott: I know that that is a name of a famous author person.
Rym: No, The Great Gatsby.
Scott: Wasn't he married to like Ella Fitzgerald?
Scott: Is a famous book that I said there was another Fitzgerald.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They were married.
Rym: That I have never read.
Rym: And I'm going to read it and the movie looks like it's going to be really good.
Rym: So I want to read the book before I see the movie.
Scott: I agree with all that.
Rym: Also, some other people I know read the book recently and said it was great.
Rym: I assume it's great.
Scott: Why would it not?
Scott: Why would it be so famous?
Scott: We've heard of it that even, you know, how many years later?
Rym: Scott, have you heard of a book called Ethan Frome?
Rym: Because I've heard of Ethan Frome.
Scott: I did not hear of Ethan Frome until I was made to read it.
Scott: And if I had not been made to read it, I would not have heard of it until people complained about in our forum.
Rym: Ever heard of Atlas Shrugged?
Scott: I have only because the entire South Park episode.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Yeah, I'll say this.
Scott: That's the first time I heard of that book was in that South Park episode.
Rym: Say the same thing I always say about Evangelion.
Rym: A lot of people say Evangelion is overrated or not that great.
Rym: Or, you know, they have all these million things they say about Neo Genesis Evangelion.
Rym: But no matter what, the one thing that is objective is that people are still fucking talking about Evangelion and arguing about it to this day.
Scott: It shows it's important.
Scott: There's if you like it or not, it's important to fucking see it.
Rym: So The Great Gatsby is one of those books that's in the like whole of famous books.
Rym: Rym probably should have read, but hasn't actually read.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I'm pretty much I'm getting close to seeing a lot of, you know, a great majority of these significant and famous movies in that category.
Scott: But I am woefully far behind in the book category, especially the real classics.
Rym: Maybe I'll get my next book club book, The Count of Monte Cristo.
Rym: I could read that.
Rym: Fuck your mother.
Rym: It's really good.
Rym: You'll blow through it.
Scott: I want to read more.
Rym: Actually, Scott, you will blow through it.
Rym: You will love the every living shit out of that book.
Scott: It's too damn big.
Scott: I have not read.
Scott: I have not read, you know, War and Peace.
Scott: I haven't read Crime and Punishment.
Scott: I haven't read.
Scott: really.
Scott: I haven't read any of these fucking classic books.
Scott: I haven't even read.
Rym: I guess it was a high school thing in high school.
Rym: We'd often use Raskolnikov to be a sort of verb like I totally Raskolnikov.
Scott: I've only read like two Shakespeare's.
Rym: You know, really?
Rym: Which ones?
Rym: Uh, Macbeth.
Scott: Well, no, Hamlet.
Scott: I've read Hamlet.
Scott: I've read Midsummer Night's Dream.
Scott: I haven't read Macbeth.
Rym: Wait, wait, you've never read Macbeth?
Scott: No.
Rym: Have I ever seen Macbeth perform?
Scott: I've read Romeo and Juliet.
Scott: That's three at least.
Scott: No.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: I don't know what to say about that, Scott.
Rym: I just don't.
Rym: I can't.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I think that's it.
Rym: Do you know the story of Macbeth?
Scott: There's a dude.
Scott: His aunts are like all witchy and shit.
Rym: What?
Scott: No.
Scott: I figure this is like when someone you ask someone what the story of Star Wars is who hasn't seen it, right?
Scott: Do you want me to keep going for hilarity?
Rym: You can stop.
Rym: You know, it's kind of unfair.
Rym: You should trap me in a similarly famous thing that I have not read, that you have read.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's hard, isn't it?
Scott: Have you seen Fritz Lang's Metropolis?
Rym: The new one?
Rym: The one with all the footage?
Scott: Yeah, the one with all the footage?
Rym: No, I've actually only seen snippets of it in classes.
Scott: What's it about?
Rym: It's about a city.
Rym: With a robot computer that can control it.
Rym: Everything's great.
Rym: Except everything's not actually great because of the underclass underground.
Rym: And eventually there's a revolution and it's a masterpiece of cinema.
Rym: It's close.
Scott: It's not exactly, but it's close.
Scott: Uh, have you seen, let's see.
Rym: Oh, there's this movie.
Rym: It's called Snatch.
Rym: Have you ever, have you ever seen Snatch?
Scott: Yeah, I've seen Snatch.
Scott: Uh, let's see.
Scott: What is...
Rym: Scott Macbeth.
Rym: Really?
Scott: What?
Rym: Macbeth.
Scott: What do you want from me?
Rym: I thought every single person in every high school in America read Macbeth.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Like I'd literally kind of assumed that everyone who ever went to high school read Macbeth at least once.
Rym: There was, uh, okay.
Scott: Do you know the story of Born on the Fourth of July?
Rym: That's the guy who is a veteran and legless in a wheelchair, right?
Scott: Uh, you're relatively close.
Scott: He's the guy who completely is unable to communicate sitting basically in a hospital.
Scott: And he... Oh, oh, yes!
Scott: And then he eventually learns to blink in Morse code at the end.
Rym: Spoilers!
Rym: Because that is referenced in, uh, Metallica and Justice for All.
Scott: The video one, uh, for the song one by Metallica uses the footage from the movie.
Rym: Yeah, I've never actually seen the movie.
Scott: I read the book, uh, and saw the movie and, and also the music video.
Scott: All in the same class in high school.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Anyway, I think we're done.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Name of the Wind.
Rym: It's okay.
Scott: And no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.