Rym: It's Thursday, November 1st, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights, Hurricane Edition.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So there's a big ass hurricane, everybody knows.
Rym: I heard something about that, but nothing happened here.
Rym: My power never went out, my internet never went out, water was fine.
Rym: I basically just spent the entire hurricane dicking around in the house, drinking wine and watching Netflix movies.
Scott: I mean, we've called it The Hurrication, is the name for it now.
Rym: Now I feel a little bad in that pretty much all my coworkers lost power, most of them still don't have power.
Scott: Save this for the actual main bit.
Scott: here, we talk about the hurricane, but I just got this opening bit.
Scott: that's a side shoot from the hurricane.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: I decided, being smart, to take a time-lapse video of the hurricane on my window with my GoPro, because I can do that.
Rym: Ah, Scott has a YouTube video.
Scott: That's right, I uploaded it to YouTube, you can watch it, it's not that exciting.
Rym: I point out...
Scott: It's an interesting cloud movement, you can see that it's facing mostly south, not due south.
Scott: And you can see the clouds begin going left to right, coming out of the east, to the west.
Scott: And as the video progresses day after day, you can see the cyclonic motion of the hurricane as the clouds begin to come from the south and turning over Manhattan.
Rym: There's however an unattributed source in the video.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So the audio, Scott faked it, it's a phony video, because...
Scott: You can't time-lapse the audio, we only do one sample of audio every minute.
Rym: So the audio is actually a recording of my balcony with the Marantz.
Scott: Yeah, with some windiness, which sounds pretty good.
Rym: That's why you hear a constant clanging, because the building next to me was going apeshit like a wizard was trying to bring it down.
Scott: Yeah, so anyway, I made this video, and then I got a message on YouTube that was like, "Hey, we want to use this
Scott: video.".
Scott: And it was actually not the usual, like some other guy wants to use the video, it was like MBC.
Scott: And I'm like, "It's a Creative Commons license, just use it,
Scott: right?".
Scott: Like standard response is like, "It's attribution only license, it even says so right on YouTube,
Scott: The guy actually emailed me back, and he's actually from MBC, I guess they want to use it for something.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: And he didn't fully understand what Creative Commons was, but basically his job is to call people and get people to sign.
Scott: Wait, if that's a job!
Scott: He had heard of it before, but he wasn't 100% on... Did you?
Rym: Was he schooled?
Scott: I tried to school him many times, but actually, in trying to school him, something happens.
Scott: This is why there's an Opie bit.
Scott: He actually called me at work, because I didn't have anything to do at work anyway.
Scott: No one else was there.
Rym: I've been working from home all week, and depending on the situation...
Scott: I'm the only one who went into work today, no one else went in but me in my little development office.
Scott: And it doesn't seem like anyone else is going to come in tomorrow.
Rym: My office doesn't have power, so there's no point.
Scott: There's no reason people can't go into my office.
Rym: Oh, my building's locked, and the building management didn't even send the doorman, there's no way in.
Scott: So this guy calls me, and I'm discussing with him, and he seems like a cool, smart, normal person.
Scott: He knows what's up with things.
Scott: But eventually, I figured out the one... There is actually, at least from my layman's poor-ass legal knowledge, one reason that I had to sign this sort of release, and the Creative Commons license was not good enough for the lawyers at NBC.
Scott: Basically, this release, I have it, it really is an agreement to two things.
Scott: The first thing I'm agreeing to is to give NBC a non-exclusive license to use the footage in this program.
Scott: They don't own it, I'm just giving them permission to use it once, without paying me anything.
Scott: Pretty much what the Creative Commons license is already giving them, that's sort of redundant.
Scott: The other thing it says is, I am legally saying that yes, this footage I'm giving you a license to use is mine, I made it, I didn't steal it from somewhere, I have the copyright on it, it belongs to me.
Rym: Ah, that is something the Creative Commons doesn't handle, for example.
Scott: And I went to the Creative Commons license after this discussion and looked through the document, you know, the legal version, not the, you know, layman's, you know, easy version, looking for anything that said that, and I could find nothing that said that.
Scott: Now, I am not a lawyer, obviously, but I am thinking, well, what if somebody were to take something that did not belong to them, say, for example, my TimeLapse video, if I had put that on YouTube with the regular YouTube license, and then they downloaded it from YouTube and uploaded it to their YouTube account, doubling it, but they chose Creative Commons license, NBC could be fooled, and if NBC had just used that from the other person's account, without, you know, just based on the Creative Commons license, not knowing that that other person did not have the right to put the Creative Commons
Rym: license,
Scott: I could theoretically sue NBC, and of course, NBC could probably sue that person who put the fuck, because that person's gonna get in trouble, too.
Rym: Yeah, that person committed fraud, basically.
Scott: By getting people to sign this release, instead of just agreeing to Creative Commons license and not even checking with anybody, NBC is avoiding that whole situation altogether.
Rym: Well, basically, they're just making it more likely that, one, you do actually have the rights, because if you're willing to sign that, either you're an idiot.
Scott: If they get the, all right, if you sign it and you don't, then you're fucked, and not, you know.
Rym: Yeah, it gives them, so they could probably sue you and win anyway if you'd uploaded it non-Creative Commons.
Rym: Like, you were just the dick who, you know, stole someone else's video.
Rym: Right.
Rym: But this gives them a little more ammo in court.
Rym: Yeah, there's no way to handle that, really, without the licenses.
Scott: Well, I think that they, you know, I was wondering, I don't know, obviously, the question I have now is, most of the reason I use the Creative Commons license on things is because I want people to just remix without bothering them.
Rym: You know what I do?
Rym: I remix anyway, and I don't check the license status of fucking anything I use, except the O.C.
Rym: Remix music, because they have a really reasonable, really good policy on that.
Scott: It's not a Creative Commons license, but it is a reasonable license.
Rym: It's actually a really good one.
Rym: It requires a little more attribution than a Creative Commons attribution does.
Scott: Well, I think the Creative Commons attribution simply isn't specific enough about what you need to do to meet the attribution requirement, whereas O.C.
Scott: Remix is very specific about what you need to do.
Rym: Now, O.C.
Rym: Remixes are themselves already a legal gray area because they're remixes.
Scott: Yeah, that's a different story, but anyway, some of them are.
Scott: They're arrangements.
Rym: So, Scott, legally, what's the difference between an arrangement and a remix?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: No one does.
Rym: That's the problem.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: So, I'm just wondering, there's a question I have is, is there something the Creative Commons people could do in version 4.0?
Scott: Because we're currently on the Creative Commons 3.0 license.
Scott: In version 4.0, is there something Creative Commons could do such that to save me from being called by NBC?
Rym: I think there is something they could do.
Rym: There are a couple things they could do.
Scott: And I think that that would be a thing that would be worth it for the Creative Commons lawyers to put their time into, figuring out what paragraph they could add to the license.
Rym: I don't want to dwell on it, but I can think of several things they could do.
Rym: The problem is every one of them makes it more likely to work and increases their burden of bullshit to deal with.
Rym: Like, the highest level would be if they had a registry where you could have a passive version of the license where you just declare you're using it and an active one where you register your use of the license with them.
Scott: Well, you can already register your use of the license with them.
Scott: But it's not any sort of official thing, it's just a searchable directory.
Rym: No, I'm talking registers and you sign a contract and fax it with real identification and contact info and all that.
Scott: I mean, all NBC wants is for me to print a piece of paper, sign it with a pen, and take a picture of it with my camera.
Scott: And then instead of them having to download the crappy version from YouTube, they want me to upload the video to their file server thingy.
Scott: They actually have an app set up that's just theirs for people to send them files, which is a good thing to have.
Rym: I have a pretty good video of biking all around downtown, but I didn't do anything with it.
Scott: I have about 100 videos of biking all around the city.
Rym: Well, downtown yesterday.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Well, that's a little bit different.
Scott: So, yeah, that's just something I wanted to talk about because it's related to hurricane, but also Creative Commons.
Rym: That was interesting.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, you might have heard that there's a presidential election going on in the United States.
Rym: It's almost over.
Rym: You saw that video of the girl who's crying.
Rym: She wants Obama.
Scott: I was about to reference that video.
Rym: She's like, I just want him to stop.
Rym: I don't.
Scott: So, little girl, high five.
Scott: I'm with you.
Rym: Only a few more days.
Rym: Five thirty eight.
Rym: It's a New York Times blog and I don't know if anyone knows about this.
Scott: Why is it called Five Thirty Eight?
Scott: Because of Five Thirty Eight electoral votes?
Rym: I'm glad you figured that out because I was about to make a whole bunch of fun of you.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So, the Electoral College in the U.S.
Rym: is a ridiculous joke and we know that.
Rym: We should really fix this, but that's not what I'm talking about.
Rym: The Five Thirty Eight blog is pretty notable in that it's pretty much the most respected prognosticator of elections.
Scott: Well, isn't that the guy Nate Silver?
Scott: Yes, it's Nate Silver.
Scott: I saw him on the Daily Show.
Scott: That was a really good interview.
Scott: Scott Johnson is a big fan of this guy.
Rym: I like how in that interview he was very honest about the reliability of polls and very open about his methodology.
Rym: And also very open about his own views.
Rym: I like interviews where people, I hate it when someone is super political and non-committal in an interview.
Rym: I want people to just be like, "No, I fucking hate that
Rym: guy."
Rym: Or, "No, I think that's a load of
Rym: crap.".
Rym: You know, whatever they think, I want to know.
Rym: So, I seem to trust this guy and he currently, as of Dateline 6.24pm, November 1st, 2012, gives Obama a 79% chance of winning the election.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Which is pretty good.
Scott: I mean, you know, no math on this is obviously going to be perfect, right?
Scott: But this guy, according to everything that I can tell, is the best at doing this kind of math.
Rym: He also pretty much says straight up, "Ohio is all that
Rym: matters.".
Rym: Literally, our election system is so fucked that Ohio is the only thing that has any chance of affecting the election.
Rym: In fact, Ohio has a more than 50% chance of being the mathematical tipping point of the election.
Rym: And the next highest state that has even a chance is Virginia, with like an 11% chance.
Scott: Okay, that's not a big chance at all.
Scott: Yeah, so Ohio- How much would you bet on an 11% chance with monies?
Scott: Zero monies.
Rym: No.
Rym: That's why I'm okay, though, because 79% chance of Obama winning.
Rym: I play roulette with, what, a 48% chance?
Scott: If I had that chance of winning the lottery, I would pay the monies.
Rym: So, I just want to talk a little bit about my, you know, it's the lounge, it's Thursday, I can talk about whatever I want.
Rym: I can bring something, I can bring anything up, and all Scott can do is complain about it.
Scott: He can't stop me.
Rym: He can't complain a lot.
Rym: So, one, I think if you vote for Mitt Romney, you're either really ill-informed or pretty dim.
Rym: I'm straight up, I believe that.
Rym: He's such a fake candidate, it's ridiculous.
Scott: There are people, right, who are not dim, nor are they ill-informed, yet they- Oh, wait, there's a third possibility, evil.
Rym: The rich people who want to not pay taxes are also voting for him.
Rym: But it's amazing that, you know, I'm very cynical about politics, but I'm like an order of magnitude less cynical than Scott.
Rym: But I cannot get over the fact that Mitt Romney basically became the ultra right-wing tea party fanatic to win the primary, and then, as soon as the debate started, basically did a complete 180 and tried to pull this super moderate middle ground.
Scott: Oh my god, politics, that's how it goes.
Rym: But how can you do it so openly?
Scott: Play to win.
Scott: the game doesn't seem to be hurting, does it?
Rym: In the movies, and in all the history up to this point, you had to at least be a little bit shady, and use a little bit of finesse, and like wrangle it, but no, he was just like outright, "Yeah, guess what, I'm pretending to be a moderate
Rym: now.".
Rym: And everyone's like,
Rym: "Yay!".
Rym: I can't even, I can't fathom, I can't deal with it.
Rym: So I hear by, Gig Knights is officially endorsing Barack Obama for the President of the United States.
Rym: No, I'm not.
Scott: I'm endorsing armed revolution, but you're not allowed to shoot.
Scott: You just have to threaten, because hurting people is wrong, but if we hold guns with no bullets in them, we might scare the government into just folding, and we can set up a new nerd government.
Scott: So, that is what I endorse.
Rym: I specifically want to un-endorse all third parties, because seriously...
Scott: Some third parties have the promise, but the problem is...
Rym: Name one in the United States.
Scott: I'm not done saying what I was saying.
Scott: Some third parties have promise, yet every third party has complete craziness in some area that invalidates all its goodness.
Rym: So Scott, third parties are possibly a good idea in the same way that communism is.
Rym: We just haven't implemented it correctly.
Scott: That's exactly right.
Rym: You know what these also have a good thing in common with?
Rym: X-Windows.
Scott: I like X-Windows.
Rym: I don't like X-Windows.
Rym: I don't think there's ever been a good implementation of it.
Rym: There have been functional ones, but no good ones.
Rym: Anyway, I officially endorse Barack Obama.
Rym: I think he's going to win the election, and the reason it's important... I didn't care in 2000.
Rym: I really didn't care.
Rym: It was two sides of the same coin, for all intents and purposes.
Rym: 2004... Well, Kerry did win, but I digress.
Rym: 2004 Gore won, but I digress.
Rym: The problems I have with politics today are really around the fact that our election system in the US is statistically meaningless.
Rym: Because the elections are so close, and our voting machines are so shitty.
Rym: What's amazing is that the reason they're shitty is because they let the states do it themselves.
Rym: But yet, it's a political position to try to naturalize it.
Scott: Well, the states could do it, not shitty, but they don't want to.
Rym: Because they have a vested political interest in doing it shittily.
Rym: I don't know what to do about that.
Rym: How do we fix that?
Rym: The 2000 election was a statistical tie.
Rym: The 2004 election was arguably also a statistical tie.
Rym: And even now, if it's not a tie, the election is determined by, I think, 11 or 12 districts in Ohio and Wisconsin.
Rym: What do we do about that if the only way to fix it is to play the game itself?
Scott: What do we do if those districts in Ohio and Wisconsin eventually get locked in, right?
Scott: Just as locked in as, say, New York is, and then there's no point in even campaigning.
Scott: Because they already know who's going to win every time.
Scott: It never changes.
Scott: People don't change their minds, and the only way that anything will change will be as old people die.
Scott: Which is the only way anything changes anyway.
Rym: That's why, despite all your cynicism and my long history of cynicism, despite the fact that I pay a lot more attention to politics than you, in fact, in RIT, I took a seminar class on political communication.
Scott: I only pay attention to Google News, and that's it.
Rym: So that was during the Democratic primary for 2004.
Rym: And the class was a seminar.
Rym: There were only 11 students in the class, so it was like a roundtable.
Rym: So we all took turns teaching the class.
Rym: It was super intense and super great.
Rym: The reason this election is important is not because of who will be president in a direct sense.
Rym: Because you and I know better.
Rym: It's not like the president says, "The economy will hereby be
Rym: good!"
Rym: Or, "The economy will be
Rym: bad!".
Scott: Yeah, I mean, people act like, you know, the crazy people act like if Obama wins, it's the end of the world, right?
Scott: But it's like, dude, if that was the case, he's been president for four years, has it been the end of the world?
Scott: People act like if Obama loses, it's the end of the world.
Scott: Bush was president for eight years, it wasn't the end of the world, right?
Rym: However, we had a distinctly constant downward trend for eight years.
Scott: I'm not saying it's, you know, but it's still, it's not the end of the world.
Scott: You'll live, you'll see another president depending how old you are, right?
Scott: Your life will not be ruined.
Scott: Your day-to-day life will be mostly the same.
Rym: No, no, that's not my point.
Rym: My point is that the presidency, most people vote based almost entirely on the economy or bullshit social red herring issues.
Rym: But the fact is that the president has basically zero influence on the economy.
Scott: At all.
Scott: He has zero influence on a lot of things.
Rym: No, he has a huge influence on foreign policy.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: I didn't say that there are nothing that he has influence on.
Rym: On the execution of domestic policies and all sorts of stuff.
Scott: But nothing else besides those things.
Rym: It's simpler.
Rym: He has a lot of power over things that are very important, but those are not the things that anyone votes based on.
Rym: So people are voting based on the things the president has the least control over and yet think that the president has the most control over.
Rym: It's ridiculous.
Scott: It's like the president can't suddenly make just abortion illegal.
Rym: So it's not important for Obama to win for any procedural stuff of the presidency.
Rym: And while Mitt Romney is either evil or a robot, it doesn't matter because he can't do that much damage.
Rym: Because it took two to tango and a lot of Democrats voted for that war with Iran.
Scott: Remember, that is the number one feature of our government system that we have in the United States.
Rym: It takes two to tango and the Supreme Court has been a ball-less sack of nothing for our entire lives?
Scott: Is that while it makes it very difficult to change things to be more awesome very quickly, it makes it equally difficult to change things to be really shitty really quickly.
Rym: However...
Scott: Change is slow and difficult in both directions.
Rym: However, I would argue that the Republicans under Bush in the last four years of his campaign... Actually, I should say the last eight years of his presidency because that's just funny.
Rym: But I think they did a lot of damage, actually.
Rym: And while it wasn't as bad as it could have been because our system is really good at mitigating damage, I think it was a lot of damage.
Scott: I didn't say it wasn't.
Rym: I think invading Iraq was a disaster and I think had we not done that, we would have been in a much... Things would have been a lot better.
Rym: We would have been much more equipped to handle the economic meltdown.
Rym: But that's not...
Scott: If it would have even happened at all.
Rym: That's not why I'm saying we should vote for Barack Obama.
Rym: Here's why.
Rym: If Mitt Romney wins, this newly energized right-wing movement in the government becomes super energized.
Rym: They see that they were right in doubling down on crazy and the party... Basically, the Republican Party has to move in that direction because the crazy people now will win every primary.
Scott: So now we'll have a party... Still playing the game.
Rym: So now we'll have a party that is increasingly right-wing by policy because it has no choice.
Rym: If it deviates anyone in the Republican Party who deviates from the right-wing, if Mitt Romney wins, is ostracized.
Rym: And now you have a legitimate party that's becoming crazy like a third party that also controls three fucking parts of our four-part government.
Scott: Hopefully what can happen, if he loses, is those Republicans who realize that going super right-wing crazy isn't going to win you anything unless you live in a state where it's crazy, will form the legitimate Republican Party, much like the previous Republican Party, pre-crazy.
Scott: And the crazies will then be just a crazy party, just like the Constitution Party, which is their party, really.
Rym: So, it's better than that.
Rym: If Barack Obama wins, there's going to be a schism in the Republican Party.
Rym: I predict this straight up.
Scott: What'll happen... Already schism slightly.
Rym: So what'll happen is that schism will be open because a good part of the party... Remember, Rick Santorum and Michelle Bachmann almost won the nomination.
Rym: They were leading for a time.
Rym: But moderation won out.
Rym: The establishment was still able to kind of push the idea of, "Look, if we put up, the super-crazy will lose.
Rym: We gotta put up a token moderate.
Rym: It's the only chance we
Rym: have.".
Rym: The crazy wing of the party is going to argue that they lost against Obama because they weren't conservative enough.
Scott: And they're going to put up the super-crazy in four years from now.
Rym: Yeah, if Obama wins, Rick Santorum is going to be the furthest-left candidate in the Republican Party.
Scott: And you know what the thing is, right?
Scott: You might think, "Oh no, four years from now, what if the super-crazy
Scott: wins?".
Scott: Well, I have absolutely no fear of the super-crazy winning, and I'm going to tell you why I have no fear of the super-crazy winning.
Rym: I'm going to guess.
Scott: Okay, wait.
Scott: Right now, today, if you think the super-crazy was in the election today, what percent of the vote do you think they would get by the polls?
Scott: I mean, it would be close, maybe?
Rym: I think they would be like 30 or 40 percent, but it wouldn't be like the 48 to 52 percent.
Scott: Four years down the line, think about how many more old people will have died, and think about how many more young internet people will have turned 18.
Rym: Now!
Scott: The super-crazy will have no chance.
Scott: Two reasons why.
Scott: Not even a chance.
Rym: There's two reasons, not just one.
Rym: Not even close.
Rym: Conservatism kind of disappears as people die, because people just kind of get conservative as they're old.
Rym: Not because they're getting more conservative, but just because people, when they hit like 20 or 30, just seem to stop moving forward, so the world increasingly... But, there's another factor.
Rym: A good percentage of young people today are also crazy, but they're stupid and crazy in the Ron Paul, Rand Paul, Jill Stein direction.
Rym: But they'll balance out.
Scott: There are crazy young people, right?
Scott: But, anecdotally speaking, if I look around at the people my age and younger and a little older, the crazy percentage...
Rym: Scott, there's like three people in our forum arguing to vote for Jill Stein in this election, and one guy...
Scott: Out of hundreds, right?
Scott: Oh yeah, no, I see where you're going.
Scott: You look around, you go to a high school, you go to a college, how many young Republicans are there at the college of a few thousand people?
Scott: Maybe like 20 people, right?
Scott: The percentage of young people, especially the internet generation, are mostly left-wing or indifferent, don't even care about voting at all people.
Rym: At worst, they are super liberal on social stuff and don't understand or care about any other issue.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So, as time goes on, I do not see, you know, this younger generation of people.
Scott: I see the whole country, nay, world, you know, the past pattern has been sort of like a little left-right swingy swingy.
Scott: I see a big left movement in the all-internet parts of the world over time, because that's how internet people go.
Rym: So...
Scott: And the non-internet people, every year, there are less of them.
Rym: So, the choice is, basically, if Romney wins, in the end, progressivism still wins, because the world keeps moving forward.
Rym: I think there's a famous song about if you can't keep up, get out of the way.
Scott: Can we talk about the hurricane now?
Rym: Okay, so, if Romney wins, it's going to take another generation for this bullshit to die out.
Rym: If Obama wins, the far right is basically going to explode, and it's going to be one of the greatest things to behold.
Scott: See, but they can still win, like, all these, you know, seats in the House and Senate...
Rym: Oh, they can, they can, but... But...
Scott: Is this crazy states?
Scott: The whole state's crazy.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but that one, there's enough states now, already, to basically guarantee Democrats win if one or two more states flip blue.
Rym: And the thing is, states that were staunchly red are starting to flip blue because young people are moving...
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: ...all the states that are getting undue votes in the Electoral College because their populations are growing.
Rym: I mean, New York State is shrinking, and New York City is growing.
Scott: This is also anecdotal, but you go on the internet all the time, and you talk to cool people from all around the world, and I see cool people on the internet from places like Alabama... ...or, well, yes, but, you know, I'm talking about crazy states and cool internet people in them, too.
Rym: Nevada and Arizona are growing rapidly in population and getting more influence, but most of that growth is in the cities, and there's lots of evidence that if you live in a city, you become more liberal over time.
Rym: Straight up.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And you're attracted to states if you're already liberal.
Rym: So, yeah, New Yorkers are leaving New York.
Rym: They're going to Arizona, and they're turning the state blue.
Rym: Meanwhile, New York's never gonna turn red.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: The old people, right?
Scott: You know, because the old, old people die, but there's still new, old people who just became old people.
Scott: They retire, and they're gonna move to a different state and not hang around the place where they happen to work, and they're gonna go somewhere, and they're gonna vote, and they usually like to go places that are in the South that are warm, where they need more votes, but those new, old people aren't as conservative as the old people who just went away.
Scott: They're our parents, not our grandparents.
Rym: So, young people...
Scott: Watch out.
Rym: While Barack Obama doesn't agree with me on 99% of what I care about, you know, anything related to technology
Scott: or science,
Rym: it doesn't matter because
Scott: a vote
Rym: for Obama is a vote for literally destroying the Republican Party and ushering in possibly an era of Congress starting to make the barest, tiniest, little millimeter step toward maybe debating one issue once.
Rym: And that's the best we can hope for.
Scott: You're so optimistic.
Scott: So, things of the day.
Scott: So, Ram always likes to talk about the fact that people who saw man land on the moon, their grandparents fought in the Civil War.
Rym: Might have been parents.
Rym: I have to look it up again.
Scott: That's your favorite thing to say.
Rym: It's just, it's such a great little factoid.
Scott: So, nothing, you know, you think that's pretty crazy, right?
Scott: Like, wow, time fucking flies.
Scott: Well, time really only fucking flies in the past few centuries.
Scott: You know, people who, you know, in the BC times, it's like, well, yeah, their grandparents were pretty much the same as them with maybe a little bit of difference.
Scott: Technology didn't really progress that rapidly.
Scott: Super historical events that we know about that were really important, that were so important that we know about them today weren't that frequent that like, oh my God, my grandpa saw Alexander the Great and I saw still pretty much the same kind of thing.
Scott: Only Alexander the Great's not here anymore.
Rym: One thing, entire, like, multi-generational families appeared, had many generations and completely died out in a span of the Roman Empire being relatively unchanged from an urban perspective.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So really, this is a recent development in our history and nothing illustrates that more than this video.
Scott: This is a video from 1956.
Rym: Which is already a long goddamn time ago.
Scott: That is over 50 years ago.
Scott: My parents were alive and perhaps very young.
Scott: I think they were both alive.
Scott: At least one of them was alive at the making of this video.
Rym: World War II had recently ended.
Scott: Although they would not remember it.
Scott: My grandparents, right, two of them are still living, were both alive and able to watch television.
Scott: When this was on television in 1956, they were already like our age, maybe, or even a little older, younger-ish, right?
Scott: And in this video is a game show.
Scott: And in the game show, there is like a celebrity panel, like a semi-celebrity panel, and they bring a special guest onto the panel.
Scott: They ask them questions, and they must guess what is significant about the special guest.
Scott: And in this video, I'm just gonna tell you the whole thing.
Scott: The special guest is a very old man, but he is alive in the year 1956.
Scott: And this old man witnessed at a young age with his own eyeballs.
Scott: And he was old enough to remember it, at least somewhat, not that old, I think he was like six, five or six at the time.
Scott: He saw, he was in Ford's Theater and saw Lincoln get assassinated, and he was alive and on television in 1956.
Rym: And then over fifty years later, we watched that on the internet.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: Take that Alexander the Great.
Rym: I love the part where he's like, "All I could think was that poor man, he fell from the balcony when John Wilkes Booth jumped out of the
Rym: stage.".
Scott: Right.
Scott: I wonder if he heard him say "Six Semper
Scott: Tyrannus.".
Scott: But yes, this man now, though, has passed.
Scott: There are no living witnesses to that event.
Scott: But, it's not that far away.
Rym: So, many of you know that Emily and I have two adorable little rabbits.
Rym: We rescued them from a bucket that somewhat abandoned them.
Rym: They're very cute.
Rym: Scott takes care of them sometimes when, you know, we're out of town.
Rym: Not often.
Rym: And this is just a video, a lot of people have rabbits or have seen rabbits, but don't, it's like they think rabbits just sit there.
Rym: Because if you lock a rabbit up in like a little hutch, it kind of just sits there.
Rym: But rabbits are about as smart as a low-end cat.
Rym: So, if you've got a rabbit and then you let them run around, they act like a slightly dumb cat.
Rym: Like, they're very, they're active.
Rym: They play with them.
Scott: Yeah, they're not even smart enough to stay in the cardboard castle all the time.
Scott: They only go in there sometimes, and usually they go in the cardboard tunnel, which is not nearly as good as the cardboard castle.
Rym: The cardboard tunnel is much more defensible if someone like me is coming to pick them up.
Scott: No, the cardboard castle is superior in all aspects.
Rym: Plus, Scott, notice how he can get the toys into the tunnel.
Rym: He can't get the big pine cone into the cardboard castle.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: Because it's hard to get it in there.
Scott: No, because he's fucking stupid.
Scott: I could get it in there.
Rym: So, this is a video of a rabbit who, because, you know, our, like, our one, the white one, Theo, has a basket of toys.
Rym: And every day when we let him out, while we're not home, he empties the basket out and carries the toys around and plays with them, like throws them at things.
Rym: This is a video of a rabbit playing with a toy.
Rym: He has a, his is a doll of a rabbit that he carries around everywhere with him.
Rym: the way a dog carries around his, like, favorite toy.
Rym: It's ridiculously adorable.
Rym: And if you don't, if you've never interacted with rabbits before, you should watch this because they're probably not the way you think they are.
Scott: They are who we thought they were.
Scott: Do you know what?
Scott: You want to know something?
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Yesterday was the tenth anniversary of Play to Win the Game.
Scott: You don't just play.
Scott: You don't play it, you just play it.
Scott: Play to win.
Rym: So, in the meta moment, the Book Club book is Patrick Rothfusses.
Rym: You gonna say the name?
Scott: The name of the wind.
Rym: Name of the wind.
Rym: Did you know the name of the wind?
Scott: Well, you said, you said you're gonna say the name.
Rym: Am I gonna learn the name of the wind in this first book?
Rym: Are you?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Am I?
Scott: It's the name of the book.
Scott: I mean, it would be kind of weird if you didn't, you know, learn anything.
Rym: Does it end with him learning the name of the wind?
Scott: It would be kind of weird if you didn't learn anything about the name of the wind in a book called The Name of the Wind.
Rym: Does he learn it from Master Loden or does he learn it from that crazy girl?
Scott: You know, I can't really say the name of the wind.
Scott: If I could, it would, I mean, I did it last week.
Scott: It's not what happened.
Scott: It wasn't too good.
Rym: So it's totally an aside, but in the forum, I think it was Matt who posted this.
Rym: He said that a friend of his said one of the funniest things he's ever said.
Rym: I'm going to pull out the tweet because I took advantage of this.
Rym: Basically, he was like, what if Gagnam Style is actually a rain dance?
Rym: and we brought this upon ourselves?
Scott: I saw that around the Internet.
Scott: It's not that funny.
Rym: Yeah, so basically he said this in our forum.
Scott: You think that's that funny?
Scott: No.
Rym: So I posted, I was like, I'm totally going to steal that and tweet that.
Scott: I think he was not the originator of that.
Rym: No, his friend, he overheard his friend do it.
Scott: I think his friend saw it on Reddit or something because they saw a JPEG that predates your JPEG.
Rym: I never made a JPEG.
Scott: Someone made a JPEG that predated whatever.
Rym: So all I did was I was like, I'm going to steal and tweet that.
Rym: So I tweeted it.
Rym: in a sea of other things I tweeted.
Rym: I think I also tweeted about that My Little Pony doujin that Emily translated and Sonic put online, which is actually really good.
Rym: I assume you're right.
Scott: Even the GeekNights IRC channel met a moment, met a moment.
Scott: And someone talked about how they had a friend who was at a comic convention in Japan who bought some MLP doujins and sent them to them in Europe.
Scott: So I said, you got to scan that.
Scott: So they scanned that and they put the JPEGs on Imgur.
Scott: And then I said, hey, Emily, check out this Japanese pony doujin that got someone to scan.
Rym: And it's actually pretty good.
Rym: There's that picture where Gilda, Pinkie Pie is like on Gilda.
Rym: Like, you miss me.
Scott: I'm really good at not doing stuff, but telling people to do stuff.
Scott: Someone should hire me to do that.
Rym: Scott, that's how I want inheritance.
Rym: You know what we should do?
Rym: You play the guy and I'll play your guard and we'll just fuck everybody up.
Scott: Don't draw me out of the envelope.
Rym: So I tweeted this, among other tweets, and it is now the most retweeted thing I've ever tweeted in the history of Twitter.
Rym: It has been retweeted so many times that it turned off all retweet notifications because it flooded my email.
Rym: It got retweeted back to me in a loop.
Rym: I started seeing my own tweet in my feed because people use these shitty old clients that do the old like RT space.
Rym: So I started getting my own bullshit retweeted back at me through multiple chains of people.
Scott: You know what I see in my feed all too often?
Scott: Someone so favorite in a video, Rainbow Dash, oh my gosh.
Scott: That is the thing I see most often.
Rym: I get that more for Gooney's Game of Thrones than I do for my Kanye pony.
Scott: Someone emailed us about Gooney's Game of Thrones, something weird, I ignored it.
Rym: The Brazilian thing?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So here's the deal.
Rym: I got a lot of emails about that.
Rym: So that went viral in Brazil.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: How viral in Brazil?
Scott: So a guy- Do they love the Goonies in Brazil?
Rym: So a guy fan subbed it into Brazilian and asked me if I would add that as an alternate language on the video in annotations.
Scott: Okay, so why not?
Rym: So I'm going to figure out how to do that and do it.
Rym: And I got all these people from Brazil now who are like, "Oh my God, that was the best thing
Rym: ever.".
Rym: They all got my email address.
Scott: So Brazilians know both Goonies and Game of Thrones.
Rym: I should email all of them and be like, "You fuckers ruined Orkut.
Rym: I'm giving you
Rym: nothing.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I can still be using Orkut today instead of Facebook or G+.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: Orkut was great.
Rym: Didn't scale well because Orkut had one fatal flaw.
Scott: Brazilians.
Rym: There was literally no way to deal with someone who has no etiquette.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: If someone decides to spam, there's literally no control over that.
Scott: Who knows how Orkut has changed though?
Rym: Apparently it's a den of kiddie porn and there's lots of lawsuits around it.
Scott: Why does Google keep it up?
Rym: Because it's also the most popular social network in Brazil.
Scott: Does it make them money?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Well, I'm not going there if there's kiddie porn.
Rym: Actually, it's really hard to get money out of Brazil.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So if you have a company and you have stuff like you have an office in Brazil, usually what happens is that office becomes ... This is kind of like the Rym business aside.
Rym: You have all this money you're making.
Rym: You can't easily get the money out of Brazil.
Rym: So all you can do really is reinvest it into that office.
Scott: Or something else in Brazil.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So you'll either spin up other businesses in Brazil or you'll just have one office.
Scott: Why don't you use the money to lobby the Brazilian government to make it easier to get the money out of Brazil?
Rym: Nah, nah, nah.
Scott: Why doesn't everyone team up to do that?
Rym: Scott, all I've learned about South America is you do not want to get involved with the government of South America in any capacity, any country.
Scott: I don't know much about the government of Brazil.
Rym: South and Central America, no.
Scott: I don't know much about the government of Brazil, but the very few things I do know are totally cool.
Scott: Like the awesome Creative Commons Culture Minister guy.
Rym: Oh dude, it's all nerds down there.
Rym: Everyone in the financial industry I met was a super nerd.
Rym: Chun Lees all over ... That's an aside, but it's cool.
Rym: people down there.
Rym: Guy introduced me to himself by his screen name, not his real name.
Scott: Just like you.
Rym: And that screen name was Trek.
Rym: Dude knows more about Star Trek than anyone I've ever met in my life.
Rym: And independently of that is a really cool guy.
Scott: I think you talked about this guy before.
Rym: I know.
Rym: I also really just made a dig at Star Trek people.
Scott: Let us go on to talk about the hurricane.
Scott: name name name.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: So there's a hurricane and ...
Scott: It blew past us.
Rym: So I prepared.
Rym: So how did you prepare?
Rym: One, I filled two buckets with water in case I lost water pressure and had to poop.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I filled every water bottle I owned with water and put in the fridge.
Rym: Because you know, say I lose water for a couple days.
Rym: If I didn't store water, that would actually be dangerous.
Rym: I had enough water for like three or four days if I needed it.
Rym: Filled the hot water heater with water to make tea and have more water.
Rym: And I ran the dishwasher because I didn't want anything stinky in my apartment.
Scott: I ran the dishwasher so I would have clean dishes upon which to eat.
Rym: I kept my cell phone charged and I kept my energy charged.
Scott: I closed the windows.
Rym: I charged both laptops that I own.
Scott: I taped the GoPro to the window so that it could time lapse.
Rym: I made sure that my ...
Scott: I bought a half gallon of orange juice.
Rym: I made sure that my FiOS connection was plugged into my UPS so I could use my laptop and stay online.
Scott: I went to the ATM and got pictures of Andrew Jackson.
Rym: I pulled out $500 in cash and kept it around.
Scott: Only 10 pictures of Andrew Jackson.
Rym: Oh, dude, the ATM downstairs has 10s in it now.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Is that the one at the Chase?
Rym: No, it's the one at that Bodega place.
Scott: Oh, fuck that one.
Scott: And then I went inside my apartment and locked the door and stayed inside and didn't leave.
Rym: I started playing video games, watching TNG on Netflix.
Scott: I played Link to the Past.
Scott: I only have a few dungeons left.
Scott: I'm in the Ice Temple and I got to the boss.
Scott: I couldn't beat him because I didn't have enough magic.
Rym: And occasionally, I went out on the balcony.
Rym: At one point, I went up on the roof to see what was doing.
Scott: I considered going on the roof and thought better of it.
Rym: So here's what we did.
Scott: Because when I thought about going on the roof, suddenly the wind gusts were amplified.
Scott: And I said, "Yeah, don't want to get blown off the
Scott: roof.".
Rym: I was outside during one of those moments.
Scott: Our roof has no sort of way to keep from falling off.
Rym: So we were on the balcony looking out because we're pretty well protected.
Rym: And there's an under-construction building next to us.
Rym: And let me tell you, the entire hurricane, it looks like a scene in a movie where there's a wizard fighting.
Scott: Like Pat LeVoir?
Rym: Yeah, like Pat LeVoir.
Scott: The first one?
Rym: Or take the fire away, but when it came in, it was fighting in that library.
Rym: This is what the outside of the library would have sounded like.
Rym: Jesus Christ, it was awesome.
Rym: I was kind of worried because basically the building's not done.
Rym: So it's open.
Rym: All the floors have no walls and it's way tall.
Rym: And every floor has the steel beams that hold drywall up, but nothing else.
Rym: So those beams were banging and clattering and breaking and shuttering and making one fuck of a racket.
Rym: I was waiting for one to just come flying out and impale something.
Rym: But nothing like that happened.
Rym: We're standing on the balcony and suddenly it's making all this noise.
Rym: And suddenly the noise escalated to a degree that I was like,
Rym: "Ugh!".
Rym: And then we went inside.
Scott: Yeah, I reconnoitered my neighborhood after the coast was clear.
Rym: Good use of a word.
Scott: A couple days, what?
Rym: Most people don't use that word.
Rym: It's a good word.
Rym: I like that word a lot.
Scott: You don't know that word?
Rym: I know that word.
Rym: I like it a lot.
Scott: It's a necessary word.
Scott: And the only thing that was wrong was a downed tree.
Scott: All the businesses were open.
Scott: People were walking and biking and all over the place.
Scott: There was no problem.
Scott: The only problems, as usual, when it comes to natural disasters, such as, you know, is that people put their houses in dangerous places and if it's not just your vacation home, what the fuck?
Rym: Well, well, well, well.
Scott: I mean, I feel very badly for somebody who has a house in a place and the house is destroyed and their life is ruined.
Rym: A good chunk of Connecticut, basically everywhere but where we are, is still fucked and won't have power for maybe weeks.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But not having power, you can still live.
Rym: It's tough, though, when you also don't have running water.
Scott: Uh, they have water.
Scott: My parents- A lot of people don't have water because- My parents have water but they don't have power.
Rym: And no cell service in a lot of places.
Scott: Uh, they think they have- the phone still works because the phone company has generators.
Rym: No, this was a $20 to $30 billion storm in terms of damage.
Rym: It hit a lot of places that are not traditionally thought of to be in dangerous places.
Scott: You know, I feel badly for anyone whose life is ruined.
Scott: I think about, like, my whole apartment just getting set on fire and I'm like,
Scott: "No.".
Rym: Atlantic City got proper fucked.
Scott: That would be the worst thing ever, right?
Rym: Like, Atlantic City apparently flooded entirely.
Scott: I cannot but empathize, you know, how bad it is for somebody to have the worst, almost the worst possible thing happen to them.
Scott: Losing everything pretty much but your life, right?
Scott: Or, in a few cases, even your life, that is the worst possible thing.
Rym: But, but- I'm just thinking of rarity.
Scott: I do have to hold back, in a very small sense at least, in some cases a large sense, why did you put your house right on the beach, right?
Scott: So, what about the guy- If that's a vacation house that's mostly empty and you only really vacation there and it gets knocked over, you were rich, you had a second house, I don't feel too bad for you that your beach house got knocked down, right?
Scott: That's like, "Oh, your Ferrari was smashed by a fallen tree, I will play this tiny violin for
Scott: you.".
Scott: But, you put your primary house on the beach, you could afford the beach house, which means you could have afforded a non-beach house instead, but that was your only house?
Scott: Not a smart move there, right?
Scott: You don't build your only house on the fault line or on the cliff where there's mudslides or in places in the middle of Kansas where there's tornadoes all the time, right?
Scott: You just don't do that.
Scott: And if you do do that, I will still feel badly that you had a horrible thing happen to you and your life was ruined, but I'll feel slightly less badly than I will for the person who put their house in a safe place and had it ruined, although they took reasonable precautions.
Scott: It's like, "Oh, you put your thing in a precarious position and it fell, yeah, that's what was gonna happen, we know
Scott: that.".
Scott: And if you look around New York City, most of the destroyed things were people living on tiny slivers of island.
Rym: And the island that flooded in the middle, you know, Manhattan.
Scott: Well, Manhattan itself, right?
Rym: More Manhattan is fucked.
Scott: It is out of power.
Rym: And subway, and the tunnels are still flooded and all the- But there isn't significant damage in terms of your house, your apartment was destroyed and your life was ruined.
Rym: No, no, nothing like that.
Scott: Right, so that's what I'm talking about.
Rym: Or how about by 14th Street where they had to evacuate all the intensive care babies from the hospital.
Scott: Someone tweeted this- But none of them, all of them lived.
Rym: Yes, due to a heroic effort and a lot of luck.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: Now, here's what bothers me.
Rym: The hospital had all these problems, and yet the financial sector basically came online the next day like nothing happened.
Scott: Well, a hospital, the technology is much busted.
Scott: We can make a whole episode about the crappy, much busted technology of hospitals.
Rym: We're not gonna make this the episode of talking about the political social ramifications of America.
Scott: Also, Wall Street buildings are typically large, more modern, and more durable.
Scott: In some cases, like the stock exchange itself is made of stone.
Scott: It's a flood isn't really gonna bother that fucker.
Rym: There's the side problems, there's just more money in the financials.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: I worked in hospitals.
Scott: The National Reserve, the Federal Reserve, flood ain't gonna matter.
Rym: IT in hospitals, in my experience, was pretty corrupt and pretty incompetent and way overpriced and way shittier than most other industries.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But yeah, damaged infrastructure like that is bad because we all pay for that together.
Scott: It is a shared cost.
Scott: It's like, "Oh, the federal government comes in and helps
Scott: you.".
Scott: Yeah, in other words, we all pay for that, right?
Scott: Our taxes are increased and our deficit is increased because there is a disaster that we must all pay to fix together.
Scott: And that is sucky, but that is what happens.
Scott: We set aside money for that, just like anyone should set aside money in their personal budget for a disaster, because it will happen at least once in your life.
Scott: You know, just about.
Scott: no matter where you live, there is some sort of disaster that can happen, and if you live long enough, will happen.
Scott: A hurricane, a tornado, an earthquake, a fire, a blizzard.
Scott: You know, name a place for me on Earth where a bad thing can't happen.
Scott: I'll move to that place tomorrow, right?
Rym: Actually, you know what?
Rym: The Midwest is pretty much one of the safest places- Tornadoes?
Rym: Blizzards?
Rym: No, the northern part of the Midwest.
Scott: Blizzards.
Rym: Dangerous Blizzards are actually not an issue because of the- It is possible.
Rym: It's so unlikely, and even huge Blizzards are actually much more readily dealt with because it's very easy to store enough supplies to ride it out.
Scott: There, you know, many bad things can happen.
Rym: No, very few compared to most other places in the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: actually.
Scott: Oh, the same, but things can happen.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's not a perfectly safe place.
Rym: But the likelihood is so much lower there that that is probably the safest place you could be.
Scott: There are many safe places you can be.
Scott: But, I mean, deserts, you think, oh, deserts weigh safe.
Scott: No.
Rym: Drought is- Drought is deadly.
Rym: I know that.
Rym: That's why I didn't say the desert was safe.
Scott: I'm just saying, there are unsafe places.
Scott: Anyway- And the place I'm in?
Rym: Pretty safe.
Rym: Yeah, I think you said it best.
Rym: It's worth the rent we pay.
Scott: We're pretty safe here, I think, right?
Scott: We're not right on the water, you know?
Scott: I'm on the third floor.
Scott: If a flood reaches the third floor, that's a fucking miracle.
Scott: I salute that flood, and I will accept the damage it does, because the third floor flood, that is apocalyptic Bible shit.
Rym: So here are my observations.
Rym: One, when I went out the next day for a run and biking around, pretty much all the traffic lights were- Like, there were a few traffic lights that were fucked up, but they were mostly all functioning.
Rym: Everyone was just running red lights, driving the wrong way on the road.
Rym: People were driving like it was Mad Max.
Scott: Yeah, so I don't drive.
Rym: But the roads were normal, so I was biking, and jackasses were literally just running red lights without even looking, and everyone's just driving like there's some sort of crazy disaster going on.
Scott: That's the news.
Scott: That's what the news creates, that psychology in people, right?
Scott: Yeah, but I feel like- How is that anything different from driving in India?
Scott: It's not so bad.
Rym: No, because here's the problem.
Rym: What it shows me is this.
Rym: If the police are not available in New York, social order starts to break down within about five fucking minutes.
Scott: We know that.
Rym: But I saw it in action, literally.
Rym: I've never seen someone run a red light, like straight up run a red light in this city before.
Rym: I have.
Rym: The day after the hurricane, everyone was running red lights, and driving just like in the middle of the lanes on perfectly fine roads.
Rym: And there were a lot of bikers out, but that was a separate thing.
Rym: Observation two.
Rym: People who are walking, people who are pedestrians, don't know how to walk, but it didn't bother me that much until I had a bike over the Queensborough Bridge yesterday.
Rym: The pedestrians literally blocked the entire bridge.
Rym: It took me 35 minutes.
Scott: Today, I was trying to get on the subway to go- 35 minutes!
Rym: It takes me three minutes to get over that thing on a normal day.
Scott: To get to work, I took the end to 49th Street.
Scott: The 57th Street was closed because of that crane thing, but I just got right in.
Scott: But, 49th Street, for whatever reason, no uptown trains at that station.
Scott: Also, I couldn't go to 57th Street, so the only option was to go south to 42nd Street.
Scott: The tourists today!
Scott: You'd think there would be not so many tourists.
Rym: No, because they're all in the hotels in Manhattan.
Rym: They can't get out and they can't get anywhere.
Scott: Today, they were so much worse at walking than they usually are.
Scott: It was so bad, the walking, to get to the subway station.
Scott: I really wish I could have just pushed people over the same way.
Scott: those guys ran red lights.
Rym: Oh, this is an aside, but I actually shoved a fat lady out of my way to get on the subway.
Scott: Physically, you shoved?
Scott: Woah, let's talk about this.
Rym: So, this had nothing to do with the hurricane.
Rym: So, I was running late for a thing, and the sixth train came up, door opened.
Rym: It was pretty crowded.
Scott: This was pre-cane.
Rym: Yeah, and there was a door that opens, right?
Rym: And there is plenty of space.
Rym: Like, tons of space behind the door.
Rym: There is a fat woman standing in front of the door, blocking the entire thing, and plenty of space behind her.
Rym: The other two doors are full.
Rym: You can't really get into them because there's a huge crowd of people.
Rym: But I'm standing right in front of her, and I look at her in the eye and say, "Hey, can I get
Rym: by?".
Rym: And she ignores me.
Rym: So, I start to squeeze past, and she still ignores me.
Rym: So, I shoved past her, and I got onto the train.
Rym: There was plenty of room.
Rym: She turns around and starts flipping out at me for being so rude.
Rym: And I let her be.
Rym: I just ignored her.
Rym: I could have done the whole, "I tried to get around you, but I
Rym: couldn't.".
Rym: But I felt that would have been mean.
Rym: So, I literally just ignored her, and she yelled at me for the entire ride.
Scott: She didn't do anything, though, right?
Rym: No, she just kept yelling at me about how rude I was.
Rym: And she looked around the train like, "You know how when people who are mad...".
Scott: You didn't flip out a phone camera and video the crazy lady?
Rym: No.
Rym: No one else did?
Rym: I was using my phone to read the stupid book.
Scott: No one else did this?
Rym: I don't know if they did it or not.
Rym: If you see a video of a fat lady flipping out on a guy with long hair, it's probably that fat lady.
Scott: Search YouTube.
Rym: The coup de gras was that she's trying to do that thing, which we've talked about before, on trains, where she's trying to make eye-counting for someone else and do that huff that indignant people do, to try to get them to huff with her, to share the indignation.
Rym: And she's like, "Huh,
Rym: huh.".
Rym: And she keeps looking.
Rym: One by one, she's looking at people and trying to get them mad.
Rym: And I'm surprised that the other people on the train did not, in fact, break out into a round of applause for me.
Rym: So she had no luck in her fishing expedition for a co-drama person.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: It felt kind of bad, but only a little bad.
Rym: But it was the first time I've actually shoved someone out of my way in New York.
Rym: Maybe that's an achievement.
Rym: Maybe I've leveled up.
Rym: Maybe Mayor Bloomberg is going to come to me and be like, "Congratulations, you're actually a real New Yorker
Rym: now.".
Scott: Here's the golden fist.
Rym: Here's the key to the real subway.
Rym: Here's the key to the real subway and the real Times Square.
Scott: Dude, if you get that, let me know.
Scott: I'm going to start pushing people away.
Scott: I've been in a lot of hurricanes, actually, in my life.
Rym: This is the first one I've ever been in.
Rym: The last hurricane, Irene.
Scott: Oh, because you were in the Midwest or Rochester.
Rym: Yeah, and then I was in Seattle for PAX during the last one.
Scott: Being in Connecticut, New York, in my life, there have been two or three hurricanes.
Scott: The only one of them was ever... I mean, Hurricane Andrew.
Scott: that really destroyed the fuck out of Florida didn't hurt us so bad, but it did come by us.
Scott: But there was one even earlier.
Scott: I forget the name of because I was so young.
Scott: But that was the only one that really fucked us over.
Scott: And we knew it was coming, even in those days.
Scott: And we were putting duct tape on the windows.
Rym: Oh, no, no.
Rym: You shouldn't do that.
Scott: It was the olden days.
Scott: We didn't know better.
Rym: Oh, Scott, we've known not to do that since the '80s.
Scott: Well, this was in the '80s.
Rym: So, you know what, Emily and I were walking.
Rym: I think a lot of people don't realize that taping your windows not only doesn't help, but it can hurt.
Rym: But every frickin' business taped up their windows.
Rym: Usually with masking tape, too.
Scott: That was the only time we ever did that.
Scott: We've never done it again because now we know better.
Scott: But that's how I'm selling.
Scott: how old this hurricane was, is that we taped up the windows, did not know better.
Rym: What's interesting is I've never been in hurricane kind of winds.
Rym: I've been in way more violent storms.
Scott: You can't walk.
Scott: Yeah, this one that came through was not as violent, at least where I was.
Rym: Well, when we went into the roof, the elevators were down, so we snuck up.
Rym: They were like, "Don't fuckin' go in the
Rym: elevators.".
Rym: So, of course, we snuck up the stairs.
Rym: We get up to the top, we open it, the door, a little bit.
Rym: It's pretty calm.
Rym: And we see that the regular door out is blocked.
Rym: Like, the building doesn't want you fuckin' goin' on the roof, which is understandable.
Rym: So we open the door, and I look, and I'm like, "You know, it doesn't seem so...".
Rym: And then the wind came again.
Rym: I was like, "Oh, okay.
Scott: Okay.".
Scott: Yeah, a hurricane is like being in a fuckin' wind tunnel.
Rym: But I've been in way, way more violent storms in my life.
Rym: In fact, I've gone out biking through way more violent storms.
Scott: I was gonna say, this hurricane had the strong hurricane winds, but because of our location, if you watch the storm move on the radar, the part of it that was raining, thundering, lightning, and in the high altitudes, snowing like crazy, did not pass over us.
Scott: We were on the sort of right side of the thing, which only had mostly wind.
Scott: There was very little rain or anything.
Scott: I mean, it was wet outside.
Scott: But all of the flooding was not due necessarily to rain and coming from the sky, but just the wind pushing the water up, you know, and a big surge up from, you know, the rivers.
Scott: And just the water level and high tide especially just went way the fuck up and just got water all over things that were too close to the coast.
Scott: And it wasn't, you know, tons of rain on things, which is why being slightly inland enough not to be near enough to East River, not really any action going on over here, right?
Scott: But people who were directly on the water, people who live on small islands in between the ocean and the bay, were completely devastated because the island 100% went under water as the wind blew the water through.
Rym: Now, the only reason I didn't actually go out was that, you know, I've never experienced hurricanes and all this sort of thing.
Scott: I didn't know you hadn't.
Rym: Because it's a different kind of wind, I could not accurately assess the level of danger I would be in.
Rym: Like if I went out running and then like the wind changed, I wouldn't know.
Scott: The worst that could happen is number one, a piece of debris could hit you.
Scott: It's not like a tornado where you're spinning in a circle with a bunch of debris at a zillion miles an hour, but, you know, some piece of wood could just come at you at 30 miles an hour or so.
Rym: Emily shared the fairly commonly known fact that in Japan, most people are killed in hurricanes and typhoons by roof tiles.
Rym: Because their roof tiles are those big red kind of things.
Scott: We don't have loose roof tiles here, but there's plenty of loose things.
Scott: The second most dangerous thing actually is the wind can knock you the fuck down.
Scott: I once, it was a hurricane that didn't really do a lot of damage.
Scott: But I was maybe a little older, maybe middle school, maybe a little before then.
Scott: And I had to bring the neighbors some sugar or eggs in the hurricane.
Scott: So I crossed the street and crossed back.
Rym: Why is it always eggs?
Rym: Just go without eggs for a few days.
Scott: And I think it might have been sugar.
Scott: I don't know what it was.
Scott: But I had to cross the street and cross back.
Scott: And I had, you know, a raincoat and an umbrella.
Scott: And this was sort of sideways rain situation here, right?
Scott: And it was crazy rain, thunder, and lightning.
Scott: And I just crossed the street and crossed back.
Scott: I fell down in the street.
Scott: The wind just knocked me the hell down.
Scott: It wasn't enough to really damage things.
Scott: I don't remember any big trees coming down that time.
Scott: You know, some branches maybe.
Scott: But yeah, the wind can knock you down, especially if you're a little kid.
Scott: But yeah, the big one, when I was even younger with the taped up windows, took the shed in our front lawn and blew it over the rock wall into the neighbor's yard.
Scott: As well as demolishing another shed in the back and knocking down a tree, right?
Scott: So, you know, and now, you know, I think my parents, they just keep losing trees left and right all the time.
Scott: They're down, I think, in recent years, like two or three trees.
Rym: What got knocked down around here was every empty lot that has those janky ass, like wooden walls around them, like those wooden fences.
Rym: Every one of those fences was knocked down around every vacant lot in Queens.
Scott: Yeah, the plywood wall.
Rym: Yeah, and sure enough, yesterday there were guys not being paid very much, just putting them back up.
Scott: There was one downed tree in my neighborhood, right?
Rym: There was literally no damage in Long Island City, like where we were, but then if you walked two blocks inland, like toward the river, trees were knocked down everywhere.
Scott: See, the thing with trees that's always weird, right, is like you think this tree's dead, yeah, it's in danger, and usually we get rid of dead trees before they're a problem, but sometimes they fall down because, well, they're dead, right?
Scott: But living trees, why do they fall?
Scott: And it's this.
Scott: During the summer, when it's not so stormy, tree fucking grows, and the tree can support its own weight just standing there, right?
Scott: But maybe this season it's bigger than last season, and it grew in such a way that, yeah, it can stand on its own still.
Scott: It's not a stupid tree.
Scott: But because it grew this branch here and that branch there, the weight is now in this different place, and if a storm comes through now or a big snow weighs the branches down now.
Rym: Well, that's the key if there's snow before the leaves fall off.
Scott: Then, because of the new weight distribution of the increasingly grown tree with its new leaves and branches, especially at this time of year where the tree still has leaves-- No, actually, I read that trees falling, like soil dampness and composition has way more to do with it.
Scott: I was about to get into the added weight on the branches of the new growth shifting, right, the new root increases into new places, and if you've got flooding, the tree's not grabbing onto solid dirt.
Scott: It's grabbing onto mud, so if a big wind comes and it's wet, that tree is busy just sitting in mush.
Scott: It just goes blorp, falls right over, right, even though the tree is perfectly A-OK.
Scott: And in some cases, I sort of wish, you know, they tend to just come with chainsaws and get the trees out of the hell out of there.
Scott: But it's like if the tree fell over because it was sitting in mud, you could sort of stand it back up and let it dry.
Scott: You know, it'll go back.
Rym: So I don't think-- we've gone on long enough.
Rym: I mean, we hung out, didn't affect us at all.
Rym: We rode the hurricane out.
Scott: Well, I said a whole week on hurricane.
Rym: I know, I'm working from home every day.
Rym: I did go to work today, but tomorrow-- The problem is my entire ops team didn't have-- basically, I'm the only person who had reliable internet power--.
Scott: Oh, so no one else had power at home or work.
Scott: They had no choice.
Rym: Yeah, so I had to cover for my entire ops team instead of doing my actual normal job, which I forgot how much I fucking hate supporting anything.
Rym: I hate-- I hate it when someone's like, "I can't connect to the WhatsApp.
Rym: I got to log into, like, a shell and tail a
Rym: log.".
Rym: I hate doing stuff like that.
Rym: So I've been doing that for most of the week.
Rym: But if I were working from home like this doing my actual job, this would perhaps be the best thing ever.
Scott: I talked to a person, and you know what they told me?
Rym: What did they tell you?
Scott: Their work gives them some vacation days and gives them infinite sick days.
Rym: Yeah, that's a good way to be.
Scott: Their work also gives them a month of telecommuting every year.
Scott: So they don't telecommute usually.
Scott: So 11 months out of the year, they go to work.
Rym: We did something like that at my old company, but not a whole month.
Scott: One month out of the year, you can telecommute.
Scott: So of course, during your telecommuting month, you just live in some other fucking country.
Scott: You don't stay around and keep telecommuting from home.
Scott: This person who I talked to one month out of the year just rented for one month an apartment in Paris.
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: Instead of, you know, and telecommuted from there.
Scott: So okay, sure, eight hours of the day.
Scott: So Scott, I'll tell you what.
Scott: They're sitting in this Parisian apartment working with their computer on the internets, and the rest of the day, they're just living in fucking Paris.
Scott: I don't know what kind of visa you need for that shit.
Rym: I will tell you what.
Rym: If I start a game studio someday...
Scott: I'm asking my work for this kind of scenario because it might fly, small chance.
Scott: And I'll spend my month in a different place every year.
Rym: I would spend at least one of them at just some ridiculous beach.
Scott: I will spend all of them at different ridiculous beaches until I have been on every ridiculous beach this earth has to offer when there are no hurricanes coming.
Rym: I'd get a cheap laptop that I would use on the beach and I wouldn't care if I lost it.
Scott: I don't know what if I'd even do the work.
Rym: Well, see, that's why everyone's so leery about letting people do it.
Scott: At least I'm honest.
Rym: So because Halloween was yesterday, Scott didn't come, but we had a low-key Halloween.
Rym: We watched a movie that I'm going to not say anything about because we're going to talk about it on a future show.
Rym: You need to watch the movie first.
Rym: It's pretty good, but not in the way you'd expect.
Scott: I need to eat.
Scott: I'm starting to get all ooze.
Rym: But because it was Halloween, I have an additional thing of the day.
Scott: No, you're not allowed to.
Rym: So there was a place.
Scott: Spooky ghost.
Rym: And in that place, there was a storm and the storm knocked over a tree.
Rym: A tree that was on an ancient graveyard.
Scott: Are you talking about the skull in the tree?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So people going to clear out the tree discovered that inside of the tree, embedded deep in the root system, was an upside-down human skeleton.
Rym: And all I could think of was Poltergeist, the movie.
Scott: Me?
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: Remember that movie?
Scott: Barely.
Rym: There's the famous line of, it's something like, "You moved the headstones, but you didn't move the bodies.
Rym: You asshole.
Rym: You moved the headstones, but you didn't move the
Rym: bodies.".
Rym: Because the movie ends not with ghosts, but with a storm happening.
Rym: And then all these bodies start popping up out of the ground.
Rym: And they're just dead bodies.
Scott: Isn't a poltergeist an invisible thing that messes shit up in your house, knocking things over?
Rym: A poltergeist is a teenager, according to mystical people.
Scott: A poltergeist is supposed to be this invisible thing that you're walking around your house and knocks a chair over.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So, pseudo-Randy, woo-woo, shitty people tend to believe nowadays that poltergeists are caused by young people going through puberty with extreme emotions who have latent psychic powers.
Scott: Alrighty then.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.