Rym: It's Wednesday, February 1st, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: Way late to the party.
Rym: We finish our review of all 52 of the new 52.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know, going into this thing, I expected it to be a slog, but I was optimistic.
Rym: I'm saddened at how much of a slog it became.
Scott: I mean, it just took us so long.
Scott: I mean, what?
Scott: I think it's been half a year almost.
Scott: It's like we did half of it, and then we stopped, and then finally we get around to doing the other half.
Scott: And I've pretty much forgotten.
Scott: Maybe we shouldn't talk about this until we actually get to the second part of the show.
Rym: Just so you know, we're late to the party, and the saddest thing is I read most of these way back, like right before we were gonna do the episode originally.
Scott: It's like you skip into the second half of the episode.
Rym: Yeah, but when I read them again now, I kind of forgot.
Scott: How many bits we can use right now?
Rym: Oh yeah, so we missed two shows because Scott went out of town, and, well no, you went to meet your parents or something.
Scott: My parents came to town.
Rym: And I got sick for the first time in like, for fuck ever.
Scott: Alright, so check this out this morning, right?
Scott: See, I have this MetroCard that lasts a whole year.
Scott: It's annoying because it sort of wears out.
Rym: Yeah, because I think about what my MetroCard looks like at the end of a month.
Rym: I can't imagine a year.
Scott: Well, I have one that lasted a year, and it actually worked right up until the end.
Scott: But I was thinking, you know, that today was the 31st, and it would still have one more day, and then I would have to use the new one tomorrow, right?
Scott: So I go into the subway, and like New York, you know, I didn't push a guy, but I sort of slightly cut in front of a slow guy to get to the thing, right?
Scott: Ah, ah, ah.
Scott: And I swipe it, and it said expired, and I'm like, "Oh, are you fucking kidding
Scott: me?".
Scott: I, you know, cut a guy to fail swipe, you know?
Scott: And I was like, "Why?
Scott: Why has it
Scott: expired?".
Scott: I looked at my phone, and I'm pretty sure my phone said 31st, and not first.
Scott: Obviously, it said first, because it is the first.
Scott: And then I went to the, you know, the check your MetroCard thing, and it said, "Yeah, that one's expired, and your new one's
Scott: good.".
Scott: And of course, I was carrying the new one with me just in case.
Rym: Yeah, I always have three MetroCards.
Rym: Current one, next monthly one, and cash card for, you know, bullshit.
Rym: Air train.
Rym: Yeah, and it invariably happens.
Rym: Or, you know, strangers in town doesn't have a MetroCard.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I go, you know, and I just swipe the other one, and it works.
Scott: And then, like, later in the day, I'm still thinking it's 31st.
Scott: And I look, and it says first, and I'm like,
Scott: "Whaaaat?".
Scott: And, like, it was just the weirdest, you know, brain exploding.
Scott: I know that makes not a good story.
Rym: I have a similar story.
Rym: So, for PAX, right?
Rym: You know, we submitted our panels and all our stuff, you know, a long time ago.
Rym: But the deadline for, like, completing any modifications, like the descriptions and whatever, was February 1st.
Rym: So, on the 30th, I was like, "Oh shit, I gotta make sure everything's good
Rym: tonight.".
Rym: I forgot there was a 31st day.
Scott: That's not a big deal.
Rym: Yeah, but, so we both were off by one.
Rym: See, this is not a terribly great anecdote.
Scott: So, since you have to go over, like, twice as many comics as we did in the previous comic episodes concerning the DC-52, we're just not gonna do news to save time, so I can go home.
Rym: Also, what news?
Rym: Bandai's dead.
Rym: There's a new Watchmen comic coming out.
Rym: Oh, God.
Scott: Kazuhiro Otomo is gonna be at San Diego Comic-Con, which would make me almost want to go, except for the fact that, uh, if you want to go, you'd have to buy tickets immediately, and hotel room, what are you gonna get?
Rym: A hotel, I don't know, but I could get us in.
Rym: I guarantee it.
Scott: It's already too late.
Scott: You have to basically buy tickets the day of the previous Comic-Con.
Rym: I am confident I could get us into the Comic-Con legitimately.
Rym: However, we would not have a hotel, and I don't really want to go that much.
Scott: Me either, but it's just, you know, I said it almost makes you want to go.
Scott: I didn't say I definitely need to go now.
Rym: The thing is, you know, PAX is en route to be in the same situation in terms of sellout.
Scott: That's not my problem.
Rym: Selling out of badges, not selling out of, you know, whatever it is you sell out of when you sell out.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Uh, but yeah, there's like a zillion newses, and I also have a zillion things of the day that I will now parse out very slow, parcel out, extremely slowly, one at a time, in fact, to make the most of them.
Scott: Uh, yeah.
Rym: So, of course, things of the day.
Rym: I'm gonna collect, there's a new meme, not a new meme, a new-ish meme that I just didn't know about.
Scott: Shit Astrus says.
Rym: Uh, so I like, uh, shit no one says.
Scott: We need to do shit FRCform says.
Rym: I was poking around on the internet, and my YouTube channel, partly because I'm me, and also partly because it's always logged in in the communal computer, which a lot of different people are using, pretty much recommends pony videos for everything.
Rym: You watch any video, and it recommends, like, some pony video.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, I see this when I'm something, and then, like, when I'm something else.
Rym: It's when I'm, and then, like, either a verb or a noun, like, when I'm Fluttershy, or when I'm assertive.
Rym: I'm like, wow, there's a lot of those.
Rym: I wonder what that is.
Rym: So, I click on it, and my ears are assailed with a techno beat.
Rym: Pretty good techno beat.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Rym: And in the, and behind this techno beat is- I don't know.
Scott: Is it technically more techno riff?
Scott: Yeah, it's a riffer.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: You know, we could go into the subgenre of techno, because it's a little more, like, electro than, but anyway.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: It's a pretty good, like, bit.
Rym: And the videos were all in the exact same format.
Rym: Like, they all followed the same pattern, and it seemed to be a template to make a particular kind of character music video set to this song.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And they were all really good.
Rym: I was like, hey.
Scott: But most of them were ponies or TF2 characters, and one was that girl from Gurren Lagann.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, 90% of them were ponies.
Rym: Like, I'd click on one, and then all the recommendations would be, like, ten more that I hadn't seen.
Rym: that were all My Little Pony.
Rym: And then I started digging and digging and digging.
Rym: We found, like, one to Heavy and, like, two other Team Fortress ones.
Rym: And as far as I can tell, that one to Gurren Lagann is the first one.
Rym: And from what I can gather- The Rainbow Dash is the second one?
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: It was from that to Rainbow Dash.
Rym: And then the pony community saw the Rainbow Dash one and made every possible- There are ones for side characters I didn't even recognize.
Rym: There's one for not Tom Dan, but for the other rock.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: What's the pile of rocks?
Rym: It's Madame Le Fleur.
Scott: Well, that's the bag of flour.
Rym: Yeah, I don't remember the rocks.
Scott: Oh, it's the name of the pile of rocks.
Scott: I forgot the name.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, we both forgot.
Scott: Madame Le Fleur.
Scott: Sir Lincelot.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Who was the rock?
Scott: The Bucket of Beats, which is- You don't remember that one either.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We're terrible fans.
Rym: So anyway, this is an interesting meme that kind of came about recently.
Rym: So one, I challenge you guys out there to make more entries into this meme that are not My Little Pony.
Scott: Well, you forgot to mention there was one that was sort of epic, which is the one that really stood out, which is- Oh my God.
Scott: King of Hyrule from Phillips CDI Zelda.
Scott: And it's like, so there's a whole bunch of pony ones and there's some TF2 ones and whatever, and then the one that stands out is Phillips CDI King of Hyrule.
Scott: And it's like, oh my God, someone just went and grabbed the most obscure, perfect, awesome character for this video style.
Rym: So my challenge to you is one, make videos of this to things that don't have videos to it.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: If you want, all of our videos- And find characters that make one that's more awesome than the King of Hyrule one.
Scott: That's going to be rough.
Scott: It's hard.
Rym: I got some ideas, but I got to save them because I might make them because it's a pretty easy formula to make a video for.
Rym: But two, what I'd love for someone to do, and I'd say I'll do it, but I'm not going to do it, is to chart out the time of upload of all these videos so we can confirm where it started, when it hit Pony, and then from Pony, find all the ones that came after that and try to figure out the overlaps of different fan bases.
Rym: I think this kind of current meme would be really interesting to research.
Rym: Like, right now, the exact timeline of it being popular.
Rym: Speaking of just kind of an aside, speaking of old memes and everything, so one of the developers, a young one at my company, said something like, "I'm really angry for
Rym: something.".
Rym: And I was like,
Rym: "Coins?".
Rym: Of course, nobody knew what the fuck I was talking about.
Rym: So I was like, "All right, I'm going to show you
Rym: something.".
Rym: And I explained the whole deal, and he watched it, and he looked at me, and he said, "What the fuck was
Rym: that?".
Rym: It's Coinbird, and it was the coins.
Rym: And I said to him, "You will never, for the rest of your life, hear the words 'angry for' and not immediately think coins.
Rym: I have infected you with a permanent, irreparable, irrecoverable, incurable, memory-based meme.
Rym: Virus.".
Scott: Great.
Rym: I was proud of that.
Scott: So, this is a website, right?
Scott: And I'm pretty sure this website is going to be hosed at some point, mostly because they're using Ustream, and they're probably going to get their Ustream account banned or something.
Rym: Oh, Ustream.
Scott: But, it's running right now.
Scott: This is ToonamiAftermath.com, and basically some dudes just set up their own Toonami to replace the lack of Toonami, and it's 24/7 Toonami.
Scott: Right now, if you go to the site, at least at the moment of this recording, it's currently playing Dragon Ball Z Abridged.
Scott: Up next, Dragon Ball Z Abridged.
Scott: After that, Dragon Ball Z Abridged.
Scott: If you look at the schedule, it's like Thundercats, Dragon Ball, Gundams, Power Puffs, you know, pretty much all the kind of things out beyond Toonami.
Scott: Old X-Men, The Tick, Transformers.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: There's only one thing to say.
Rym: Godspeed to you good sirs.
Scott: Yeah, if you guys can keep this thing going.
Scott: They've even got Lupin and the Midnight Run.
Rym: Oh my god, we used to watch that at midnight at RIT.
Scott: Right, it's like, you know, so, and it's, you just watch it on Ustream, illegally, I guess, or some get, I guess Dragon Ball Z Abridged is semi-legal.
Rym: In fact, we watched that, we watched that at midnight on the 1974 color RCA.
Scott: Yeah, but it's in Ustream, so there's a big chat going on pretty much all the time.
Scott: These people are watching Toonami.
Scott: It's also sort of questionable because they got like a little PayPal, like give us money, and I'm like, uh, yeah, dudes.
Rym: Yeah, it's one thing if you're violating copyright blatantly and awesomely for great awesome, but if you're also trying to make money.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, it doesn't matter, you can just go here and, you know, if you need to fill that void in your life that Toonami used to fill, just go to this website while it's still running, ToonamiAftermath.com, and press play and full screen that shit.
Rym: And of course, very briefly in the meta moment, the book club books are the same they've always been.
Rym: We didn't record the show yet because I was sick and Scott was busy.
Scott: Yeah, we were actually going to do the episode on Thursday, we just didn't.
Rym: It'll be done as soon as it will be.
Rym: PAX East is coming up, we'll be there.
Rym: Anime Boston is coming up, we will hopefully be there if we can work it out.
Rym: And beyond that, we uploaded some more panels and stuff from MAGFest, so check out our YouTube channel.
Scott: Check out all our internet places.
Scott: Facebook, Google+, Twitter, etc.
Scott: Fromacrew.com.
Rym: So, week three.
Scott: Alright, we gotta burn through this shit.
Rym: I got some notes.
Scott: So, it's been a while since we've done this, it's weird because these are the issue ones, and it's like, they're already on issue four, five, something like that.
Scott: So, is this even relevant?
Scott: It doesn't matter, I spent the money for it, so we're gonna do it.
Rym: It is relevant because I wager the majority of the people listening to this right now have not read any of them.
Scott: Probably.
Scott: Anyway, so, where we left off, the last one we did was Superboy, which was sort of the Astro Boy whatever.
Rym: Oh, speaking of which, remember how Superboy, I liked it, I wanted to see where it was going?
Rym: I read, I think, four and five in the comic book shop.
Rym: Good God, did that turn into superhero, boring bullshit.
Rym: So, it's no longer Astro Boy, but anyway.
Scott: Well, we're moving on, let's just get into it so we don't waste time.
Scott: Regular old Batman, just Batman.
Scott: Not any, you know, Batman colon something, not, you know, Detective Comics or Arkham and whatnot, it's just Batman.
Scott: And actually, this comic, believe it or not, has 25 pages of comics, which is four more than the average of 21.
Scott: But yeah, what to say about this.
Rym: What I wrote is interesting.
Rym: I wrote, "I'm
Rym: Batman!".
Rym: And then I wrote like hell next to it.
Rym: And I wrote that it's surreal, like, pseudo Frank Miller-esque bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, see the thing that bothered, I wrote down.
Rym: Like, it looks like the way something might have happened in Dark Knight Returns, but it's so, it's almost like a cliche of that kind of Batman.
Scott: Yeah, the things that I noticed that were sort of weird were, number one, I wrote three Robins hyphen pedo question mark.
Rym: I wrote Grayson, Drake, Damian, and then I wrote Jail Time.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's something going on with all these extra Robins.
Scott: It's like...
Rym: Oh, you think?
Scott: Yeah, he's got three of them with him, but then apparently the first one is apparently up to no good or someone pretending...
Rym: No, he's not.
Scott: Clearly he's not.
Scott: Obviously it's some bullshit.
Rym: But it's just like... I mean, this had that fake out with the Joker, like, "Hey, Batman in the Joker.
Rym: Nope.
Scott: Psych.".
Scott: Yeah, it's just sort of annoying how they just like, "Didn't one of the Robins die?
Scott: Why are they all
Scott: there?".
Rym: Maybe there's a fourth one?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: It's like this whole shit makes no sense.
Scott: And that's sort of what I don't like.
Scott: It's like, in the olden days, they had a character Robin.
Rym: No, no, to be fair, at least this one, it put a little word bubble under each one when it showed all three of them, and it showed their name, and it said, "This was the first Robin.
Rym: This was the second Robin.
Rym: It was not
Rym: inaccessible.".
Scott: But this is what the thing is.
Scott: In the olden days of comics, they had a character Robin, they died, and then replaced him.
Scott: And nowadays, more recently...
Rym: They turned him into a superhero with his own line.
Scott: Right, around the '80s-ish.
Scott: It's like they take all... They're like, "Oh, well, all these Robins died and came back, so what we can do is we can actually just make a whole bunch of Robins at
Scott: once.".
Scott: It's like, "Well, no, there's one Robin.
Scott: You killed the other
Scott: ones.".
Scott: And obviously, this is incredibly old news.
Scott: This is not a recent development, but it's just, as a non-superhero reader, someone who new comes into this as number one issue and sees four Robins there, most people in the world don't know there's more than one Robin.
Scott: So when they see four Robins, they're like,
Scott: "What?".
Scott: It's fucked up.
Rym: My only real complaint...
Scott: And the thing is, most people, they know Bruce Wayne is Batman.
Scott: Most people on the street could not give you the real name of any of the Robins.
Rym: Now, note, they did this well, in that it did not bother trying to explain who the Joker was.
Scott: It just assumed.
Scott: I think they can let that one go.
Rym: And Batman and Bruce Wayne.
Rym: That's okay.
Rym: But they did feel the need to explain who the Robins were, so I think you're right on that front.
Rym: I think it handled it well.
Rym: My complaint wasn't the Robins.
Rym: My complaint was that the story...
Scott: It's just something that stood out to me.
Rym: The story just didn't... I didn't give one shit about the story.
Scott: I didn't give one shit about the story in most of these comics.
Rym: All the other non-Justice League Batman so far that we've read were way better than the actual Batman.
Rym: This was the worst of the non-Justice League Batman.
Scott: Yeah, so I gave it a meh.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much a meh.
Rym: I might read, too.
Scott: I think the only reason I gave it a meh is because it wasn't painfully bad, as he knows.
Scott: It was just not good.
Rym: It felt forced.
Rym: It felt like, "This is what Batman is, so we're going to make Batman what Batman
Rym: is.".
Scott: And it's the one called Batman, so they can't diverge.
Scott: It's just got to be the core of what Batman's about.
Rym: I think All-Star Western was a better Batman than this Batman.
Scott: Well, we'll get to that.
Rym: Yeah, but I would read this if I was pooping and it happened to be in the bathroom with me and I didn't have something else to read.
Scott: That's true for almost every comic book.
Rym: That's true for almost any written words.
Scott: Yeah, okay, so Birds of Prey.
Scott: So basically, I kind of sort of was getting into this, right?
Scott: It's about this reporter guy and he's sort of following these girls to see what's up with them.
Rym: But they fucking kill him at the end of the first issue and I didn't care anymore.
Scott: Hello, right?
Scott: That was exactly what I wrote.
Scott: I liked him.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's what I wrote in my notes was like, "Wow, it takes balls to kill the main guy in the first
Scott: issue.".
Rym: Because he's not the main guy.
Rym: The T and A are the main guy.
Scott: Exactly, but I sort of liked that guy, but they killed him because he wasn't a superhero or something.
Scott: I know.
Rym: What I thought this was going to be was the Birds of Prey are these kind of superhero stereotypical comic book badass women and they were going to have cool heists and stories around and this reporter was going to follow them and he was going to be the straight man or the observer.
Rym: It would all be through his eyes.
Scott: That's why Marvels, the comic named Marvels, which is about this guy who's just a reporter and it's all seeing the history of the Marvel universe through from that guy's perspective and that's why it's so awesome.
Scott: Here, it was sort of good in that way, but then it was really just.
Scott: he was a temporary one issue vehicle for this T and A fest.
Rym: Unless he didn't actually.
Rym: The T and A wasn't that bad.
Scott: It wasn't as bad as the other comics that we will discuss soon.
Rym: I wouldn't even call this T and A because we're on orders of magnitude.
Scott: See, I can't do that.
Scott: Here's the thing.
Scott: Relative to the other things, it is not bad at all.
Rym: Relative to Hitler, Pinochet not that bad.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So this is still Pinochet, right?
Rym: You can't, you know, it's still Pinochet.
Scott: It's just because there's a Hitler over there.
Scott: It doesn't mean this is not T and A.
Rym: The words I wrote are without the awesome guy, this is comic bookie cliche bullshit dot dot dot.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, that's another meh.
Rym: Yeah, meh.
Scott: At least, you know, I wouldn't, the thing is it's like if it was, if all the issues are like this, it might, you know, and here's the thing though, I just realized just because I was reviewing these just before the show to get the fresh in the memory, you look at the end and actually the guy's got blood coming out his eyes and then he's on fire and we're just like, oh, he's dead.
Scott: He might not be dead.
Scott: He might be becoming a superhero right there, which is equally bad to being dead.
Rym: Especially because you got his internal monologue right before this happened.
Scott: But it's called Birds of Prey.
Scott: I'm pretty sure the point of this book is it's about girl heroes and he's a dude, so that's not going to happen.
Rym: The thing is, I think Birds of Prey as characters would probably work as a summer blockbuster like superhero movie.
Scott: Well, yeah, I mean, it's semi Batman universe, right?
Rym: And they were throwing out one liners and it was all this kind of actiony stuff.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: The action seemed like it was a little better choreographed.
Rym: It would feel like some of the Ghost in the Shell kind of like action I like.
Scott: Kick and punching, yeah, maybe.
Rym: The kicking and punching was more Ghost in the Shelly than other superheroes, but I didn't care about the plot.
Scott: And there's a little bit less of it.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Blue Beetle.
Scott: So what do you give it, the Birds of Prey?
Rym: First, I wrote Squark because I think that's the sound that the Scarab made when it teleported away.
Scott: Let me look it up.
Rym: I think that's why I wrote that.
Rym: Because that was just kind of like cute and I wasn't sure what to think about it.
Scott: I'm looking at the sound effects.
Rym: When the Green Lantern appears and he's like, "Hey, Blue Beetle
Rym: thing."
Rym: Here it is.
Scott: Lethal threat, Green Lantern, Squark.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Told you.
Rym: But I wrote Green Lantern BS, Planet 3, Oh God, it's Green Lantern BS.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So here we go.
Rym: Bunch of superheroes and villains, teen drama, origin story, everything I hate about comic books.
Scott: I did like the coloring, right?
Scott: It has that bright coloring in it, especially in the high school parts, where everything's bright and high contrast with sort of pony-esque colors.
Scott: I really like that when it's not just everything's gray like Batman.
Scott: Even when they get to the action, right, it's like Blue Beetle is crazy neon blue and the other things are not blue.
Scott: Like this bad guy is crazy yellow and this other bad guy is crazy red and they're in a cyan old school convertible car.
Scott: It's like the colors are just really awesome and I like the arts a lot.
Rym: My only real complaints are that one, it started with the origin story, which always annoys me in stuff like this.
Rym: It always feels better if it starts in media res with this kind of contiguous whatever universe.
Rym: And two, why the Green Lantern bullshit?
Rym: Why is the Green Lantern bullshit in so many of these comics?
Scott: You could have just had that whole beetle thing without the Green Lantern coming and zapping the beetle, whatever.
Rym: The only interesting thing is that that Green Lantern thing, coupled with the Mayan stuff, like oh, it landed in the Mayan era, kind of sets up all this timeline stuff for the other comics, but that's what I hate about DC Comics.
Scott: Well, the other thing that I don't like is just Blue Beetle himself, once he turns into the superhero.
Rym: Is boring.
Scott: I mean, look at that guy.
Scott: That does not look like a guy.
Scott: He looks like a bad guy.
Rym: He is a bad guy.
Rym: Remember, basically Blue Beetle, as far as I can tell, is a rip off of the Silver Surfer story.
Scott: But Silver Surfer is a good guy.
Scott: He's the goodest guy.
Rym: But he was sent as the herald to the place that Galactus is going to fucking eat.
Scott: No, that's not the story of the Silver Surfer at all.
Rym: But isn't that what he was supposed to do?
Scott: Well, that was his temporary job.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what, that's the Blue Beetle's temporary job, too.
Rym: The Scarab goes to a planet and makes a super killing whatever that prepares the planet for the rest of them to cocoon it and eat it or whatever it is they do.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: They told you all this in this comic.
Rym: You just don't remember.
Scott: Most likely.
Rym: It's bullshit.
Rym: I didn't like it.
Rym: This is bad.
Scott: Also,
Scott: V.I.V.,
Scott: our discussion last time about the forced racial diversity, this one was forcing the Hispanics, you know, yeah, it really it bothered me how much it went out of its way.
Scott: So and it's like it's like it's weird because it's like we're trying to be diverse.
Scott: So what we're going to do is we're going to put in a sort of toned down, not so caricatured racial stereotype in there.
Rym: But they do it in such a milquetoast way that it almost feels like if I need it.
Scott: It's like if I needed my comic to be more, you know, Russian and I put sort of Soda Popinsky in there, but I made him less comical.
Rym: Less Drunkinski?
Scott: Yes, less Drunkinski.
Scott: So what did you give this one?
Scott: Bad.
Rym: I just have no interest in ever reading another page of Blue Beetle.
Scott: I gave it meh, but it was low meh.
Rym: So Captain Atom.
Scott: So I got to ask you.
Rym: So when you looked at Captain Atom, I thought first I picked it up and I said, "What, Watchmen?
Rym: Is this just Dr.
Rym: Manhattan?".
Rym: And I flipped through it like, "Yeah, it is just Dr.
Rym: Manhattan.".
Scott: Well, I looked at it and my first thing was like, "Oh, this is going to be real
Scott: bad.".
Rym: Oh, I just assumed it was Dr.
Rym: Manhattan.
Scott: I assumed it was going to be awful.
Scott: So then I read it and actually, uh, it was surprisingly awesome.
Scott: Really?
Rym: I found it really boring and trite.
Scott: You thought it was boring?
Scott: For some reason, his is the weird thing, right?
Scott: It's like my memory tells me that when I first read it, I thought it was awesome.
Scott: Like unexpectedly so.
Scott: But upon rereading it, like the first half of it is mostly that typical talking about nonsense words.
Rym: Quote, quote.
Rym: I wrote Dr.
Rym: Manhattan question mark and then expository explanation of the bullshit made up powers.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: I don't need that.
Scott: For some reason, the first time I read it, right, I thought it was awesome.
Scott: And looking at it now, the only reason I think that I thought it was awesome originally was because the art is like just unbelievably awesome.
Rym: The art's pretty good.
Rym: I'll give it that.
Scott: Like, look at that fucking monster on this page in the back.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: With all the mouths coming out of it and shit?
Rym: That's part of my problem with it.
Rym: It had too many kind of discontinuous plot threads and the sudden volcano and all this kind of just...
Scott: Plus, I sort of like how Captain Adam himself is drawn sort of all pencil-y, you know?
Scott: It's like, oh man, that's kind of cool.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It had a lot going for it.
Rym: The only thing I really didn't like other than the expository bullshit of the made up powers was one, Indian Point doesn't look anything like that.
Scott: Well, no.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: This is like, what was the other one?
Scott: Static Shock.
Scott: Where I was complaining... The Queensborough Bridge.
Scott: It's like these people... I can see the Queensborough Bridge right now.
Scott: R and DC and Marvel Comics in New York.
Scott: I know the artists live all over the place and they use FTP to send in their pages.
Rym: Just take Google Maps and just go somewhere if you're going to say something in London.
Scott: Google Earth and Google Street View will cover you.
Scott: There is no fucking excuse.
Rym: Just zoom in and look at what it looks like and at least approximate it.
Rym: But I don't know, there were too many plot threads that I just, I didn't care and it seemed a little too super hero-y.
Rym: When he kept internally monologuing what he was doing with his powers is when I didn't care anymore.
Scott: Yeah, that was the part that I noticed on the just now, taking another look at it, that I was like, why did I think this was good?
Rym: Now here's the thing, if I had never read The Watchmen, I might have thought this was a lot better.
Scott: But... I've read Watchmen 20 times.
Scott: When Dr.
Rym: Manhattan is doing his internal monologue of his identical powers, it was brilliant.
Scott: Here's the difference between Captain Adam and Dr.
Scott: Manhattan.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Manhattan is omniscient and Captain Adam is not.
Rym: Here's another difference.
Rym: One of them has a dick.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Well, I think Captain Adam does have a dick, he's just hiding it between his legs.
Rym: If they never show it, he doesn't have it.
Rym: I've decided that that is now, if you don't see it, it's not there.
Scott: Yes sir, it's true, this man has no dick.
Rym: I've seen dicks in shows more and more lately and I think we need to end this prejudice against dicks.
Scott: Okay, dickless.
Scott: So yeah, the thing is, I'm gonna read it again before I adjust my original first impression of good.
Rym: Alright, well based on what you said, it's definitely low good.
Rym: I'm gonna adjust my original from bad to meh, because you make valid points, I kind of forgot about that art.
Scott: So, meh.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Catwoman.
Scott: The worst.
Scott: Oh god.
Rym: No, not the worst, bad.
Scott: It was real bad.
Rym: It was not the worst.
Rym: So, is it just me or was the sex scene between Catwoman and Batman gross?
Scott: It was so gross.
Scott: In fact, if you look at my notes, it says there's only two things in my notes, I think.
Scott: They are, oh no, three things.
Rym: I wrote weird Batman sex and cheesecake.
Scott: Number one, the first thing I wrote was everyone said it was awful before I read it, because it was all people saying how bad it was, right?
Scott: So I went in with sort of a bad expectation from people.
Rym: Interesting.
Scott: Number two was cheesecake, just like everyone said, and number three, ew.
Scott: Just ew.
Scott: Ew.
Scott: Normally, when you have sex in a comic, it's kind of hot.
Scott: If you read Lost Girls, it's impossible not to be aroused unless you're a eunuch.
Rym: Or it's tastefully done.
Rym: Like in Watchmen, there is a sex scene between some 30-something, a pretty schlubby guy, and you know what?
Rym: It's an interesting and tasteful, heartfelt scene.
Scott: This- Is disgusting.
Scott: Now, you can arm solve- It's also because sort of Batman has how many ribs?
Rym: It's like- Also because Batman, I don't know, Batman's face while they're having sex, I feel like, I don't know, you could argue that the sex was gross on purpose because that relationship between those two kinds of people would actually be pretty gross and fucked up.
Rym: I think the other thing is that- So you could argue that that was an artistic way to present how fucked up that relationship would be.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But it's like, you don't want to have this shit explicitly depicted, right?
Scott: You want to have it just, you know, you can imply that, that's fine.
Scott: But don't just be drawing, you know, straight up stuff like that.
Rym: It's like- But beyond that, it focused way too much on cat girls' tits and ass.
Scott: No, I mean, look at, did you see what this page, earlier in the book, before there's any sexing, and it's just like, "Excuse to draw boobs in a
Scott: bra.".
Scott: It looks like, look how much detail's in that bra.
Scott: Dude fucking went to Victoria's Secret to get like, you know, look at the mannequins or whatever.
Rym: Yup, and meanwhile, all the background characters are just like hardly there.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And the story, like, whatever.
Scott: What story?
Rym: Well, they referenced all this stuff.
Rym: that was not explained, you had to already know about Catwoman, or it didn't make sense.
Scott: This was bad.
Scott: Real bad.
Rym: I can't say it's the worst, though, in terms of sexism.
Scott: I mean, the Catwoman movie was bad, I didn't even see it, but everyone said it was bad.
Rym: It's not the worst in sexism.
Rym: All right.
Rym: 'Cause we haven't talked about what's coming up.
Scott: What's coming up.
Scott: So, DC Universe presents Dead Man.
Scott: All right.
Scott: The comic series is actually, you know, it's not just Dead Man.
Scott: I mean, this issue is just Dead Man, but the comic is actually DC Universe Presents, which means it'll change eventually, it might have changed already, from Dead Man to something else.
Rym: So, I want to talk about this one.
Rym: first, because I read Dead Man last because I saw what Dead Man looked like, and I kept running- It looks like Daredevil.
Rym: So, I kept running into Dead Man, like in a bunch of the other comics.
Scott: Well, didn't you read, yeah, I know, but didn't you read Dead Man in, what's it called, the Wednesday comics?
Scott: I just remember there was a Dead Man in there.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So, I ran into Dead Man in all these places, right?
Rym: And even in the New 52, like he was in there.
Scott: He was in a lot of comics, apparently.
Rym: And I didn't care at all about him.
Scott: I've never cared about him.
Rym: So, when I picked this one up, I was like, "Oh my God, now I have to read Dead
Rym: Man?".
Rym: So, I put it at the bottom of the pile.
Rym: I five-read it, actually, yesterday.
Rym: And I actually like the comic a lot.
Rym: You really do?
Rym: I like the Dead Man comic.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I think it's a neat story.
Rym: It's not super-hero-y at all.
Scott: Well, I mean, Dead Man's not supposed to be super-hero.
Scott: I don't know much about the history of Dead Man, but it seems like he's just- Oh, fuck the history.
Rym: Pretend I read just this.
Rym: It's a pretty good story about mythology and death and this guy's kind of quantum... It's like Hindu mythology mixed with quantum leap.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And I kind of dig that.
Scott: I can't figure out, though, what the deal with Dead Man is, because every time I read a comic with Dead Man in it, which is... I don't know why.
Scott: Is he that popular that he's in all these things?
Scott: That's what I couldn't figure out until I read this.
Scott: It's like he has a different... I can't tell what his story is.
Scott: I have to read the Wikipedia about him or something to get the real deal.
Scott: You know what, though?
Scott: It's hard to tell.
Rym: If his story is what I read in this right here, I want to read the rest of this Dead Man story.
Scott: Yeah, but basically, from what I can tell, it's just anything dealing with death is like, you know, that's Dead Man.
Scott: He deals... You know, he's already dead, but he's still alive somehow.
Rym: Well, because Rama and Saj did.
Scott: But, yeah.
Scott: You know, I didn't like it as much as you did.
Scott: I was just sort of mad.
Rym: Well, Scott, did you like quantum leap?
Scott: I never watched that much quantum leap.
Scott: I watched like maybe one or two episodes when it was on after some cartoon.
Rym: I may have seen all of quantum leap.
Scott: That's good for you.
Rym: So, I like Dead Man.
Scott: I've seen about as much quantum leap as I've seen MacGyver or anything else like that.
Rym: I was really surprised that... It was a pleasant surprise, partly because I went into Dead Man with probably the lowest expectations because I kept... Not because I expected I'd hate it, because I expected it to be boring and I wouldn't give a shit.
Rym: Because every time I'd ever run into Dead Man in any other media, I didn't care.
Rym: And then when I actually got to Dead Man himself, I actually cared about his story.
Scott: So Green Lantern Corps... What the fuck is this bullshit?
Scott: What?
Scott: So my notes...
Rym: That's all I wrote in my notes.
Rym: What the fuck is this bullshit?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the first thing I wrote is "Lone wolf, no cubs" and I don't know why I wrote that.
Rym: Uh, doesn't... I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, the second thing I wrote was "I only care about the badass evil
Scott: dude."
Scott: About the red guy?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: "Earth stuff is
Scott: moronic.".
Scott: And the third thing I wrote was "Planet Nerd,
Scott: seriously?".
Scott: Or is it "Planet
Scott: Nero?"?
Scott: What's the name of the stupid planet?
Rym: Oh, I don't even...
Scott: I think it's Nero, but it's like, "Oh, come
Scott: on.".
Rym: Really?
Rym: Here's what bothers me.
Rym: One, why is the Green Lantern crap all over all these comics?
Scott: Because that's the most popular shit they got going on.
Rym: No, the Green Lantern story.
Rym: This cosmology of the Green Lantern Corps and all these different colored rings is actually very similar to Sailor Moon's overall cosmology.
Scott: Well, there's the thing.
Scott: Before the '52, before they ended that and started this whole new thing where they wiped the slate almost clean, right?
Scott: The Green Lantern stuff was the biggest, most popular stuff that the superhero fans loved the most that the Geoff Johns guy wrote.
Scott: Remember we read that rebirth and it was awful?
Scott: I know, I know, but I don't get it.
Scott: That rebirth comic that we read and hated started this big wave of all this Green Lantern stuff spawns directly from that trade, and this is just carrying that forward because they're not fixing what ain't broke, at least in terms of what they care about, which is selling to nerds.
Rym: Here's why I don't like the Green Lantern.
Rym: Because it is both the epic space, gigantic, incomprehensible plot, and the super, I'm just a dude trying to get by on Earth plot, and it tries to let those two overlap, and they don't overlap at all.
Scott: Yeah, this is why I actually like a lot of things like, say, Silver Surfer and such, because what you get is just epic space plot only.
Scott: It's like, "There are gods.
Scott: They have godly powers and they have godly battles.
Scott: End of
Scott: story.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: God versus God.
Scott: No man.
Scott: And then, if they're giving you a man story, right?
Scott: It's Spider-Man.
Scott: It's just a dude.
Scott: And you don't see Spider-Man fighting the gods, at least not for serious.
Scott: He always sort of hides in the corner while the big boys take care of it, and he's like, "Why the fuck am I here?
Scott: Just because I'm the most famous character.
Scott: I have to be in the comic.
Scott: I'm just gonna hide in the corner with my webs.
Scott: My webs, they're gonna stop the gods.
Rym: Squirt.".
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: The Green Lantern stuff is just so, like it doesn't even make sense that a lot of the other things that happen, like if they overlap all these universes, fine.
Rym: But then, half the other problems that happen don't make sense because the Green Lantern car would have just stepped in and fixed it.
Rym: And also, this comic makes zero sense if you don't know what the deal is with all these other rings.
Scott: Yeah, this is, well, I mean, none of this stuff.
Scott: So yeah, I put it as bad.
Rym: I put it as the worst.
Scott: The worst.
Scott: I'll change yours to worst.
Rym: Not in terms of sexism.
Rym: Again, we're getting to that.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's coming.
Scott: So, Legion of Superheroes.
Scott: We did Legion Lost last time.
Scott: This was the same fucking thing!
Scott: Well, hold on, hold on.
Scott: This was a little better than Legion Lost, right?
Scott: It had all the same problems as Legion Lost, like plot.
Scott: that doesn't make sense, a million characters that, you know, they just like, look at this double-page spread.
Scott: They drew all these characters in this scene, like so that, 'cause there's fans of these obscure characters, and they put little tags on some of them, you know, like Dream Girl, Element Lad, Cosmic Boy.
Scott: Cosmic Boy, really?
Scott: That's like something a five-year-old would make up.
Scott: Like X-Cop.
Rym: Well, LA Poet noted some of their powers, like the one guy his power is, he can induce mass to way more.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Scott: Comic Queen, really.
Scott: Okay, so they drew all these characters in this double-page spread, so fanboys could be like, "Oh, there's the character I like,".
Scott: but they're not even saying anything.
Scott: Like, they're just there to appear, and that's like, I noticed that same thing when I read the extremely famous DC comic, Crisis of Infinite Earths, you know, the original Crisis.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: And it's like, they would just have pages and pages where they would just show all these universes, and they just draw all these characters, hundreds of them, and none of them would really do anything, you know, pertinent to the plot, except for the big ones, like Superman and Flash and whatever.
Scott: And it was just, they put them in there just so they could put them all in there to, you know, I guess, because if you're a fan, and you're just seeing the picture of the character gives you some feeling or idea, but it doesn't do anything for a normal person.
Rym: The only thing that made this better, I think, than the other Legion laws- Are you gonna say the same thing as me?
Scott: Let's find out.
Rym: Was that the two characters we followed the most, the two who actually- Ah, you're saying the same thing as me.
Rym: Actually seemed to have some personality and talked to each other and did stuff like real people.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And the art was better.
Scott: Right, so the Brainiac guy, and who was the other one?
Rym: I don't know, but I really like her.
Scott: No, not the girl, the other, the dude.
Rym: I don't, don't ask me names of these people.
Scott: Okay, Mon-El, so he's a Superman kind of guy.
Scott: He's from the Superman planet.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that guy.
Scott: And Brainiac, whatever, the green guy.
Scott: They actually had character, and they were kind of awesome, and I kind of wish they would just make a buddy book with those two guys, right?
Scott: Just like the really smart guy and the really strong guy.
Scott: It's a stereotypical cliche deal, but you throw in the superhero powers, and you sort of surround them with, bring in one of these crazy characters per issue.
Scott: that can sort of mix it up and put a different spin on them, because they have all these people to mix up with.
Scott: So it's like, issue number one could be smart guy, strong guy, and comet boy, and issue number two could be smart guy, strong guy, and harmonia, or I'm just looking at characters in this book, or Starboy.
Scott: Wow, Starboy looks so gay, oh my god.
Scott: I don't want to say gay to be homophobic, but really, look at this dude.
Scott: I mean gay as in he looks like he is a homosexual, not, you know, like, yeah.
Rym: Not that there's anything wrong with that.
Scott: Yeah, exactly, like straight up.
Scott: You know, it's like they did that on purpose.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know if they did.
Scott: But anyway.
Rym: But it doesn't matter, because the plot is still largely incomprehensible.
Scott: Yeah, despite liking those two characters, it's still bad.
Scott: Okay, Nightwing, so this is the missing Robin, right?
Scott: As far as I can tell, this guy was the first Robin.
Rym: I like this guy.
Scott: Really?
Rym: I don't like the comic, but I kind of like him as a guy, because it's kind of similar to Batman stories, but he's a little more, it's like Batman if you didn't have crippling emotional problems.
Scott: I guess that's what it is.
Rym: I enjoy that.
Rym: I enjoy watching a Batman who isn't just like, "I'm brooding
Rym: Batman.".
Scott: What I actually like the most about this comic is that it, you know, of course it had fighting and whatever, but in terms of pages of fighting, a lot less, you know, than the other comics.
Scott: Some of the comics you had here are just pages and pages of fighting.
Scott: Here you had a whole bunch of pages of circus and talking to people at the circus and stuff like that.
Scott: It was actually, and it wasn't just talking, you know, to explain what the bad guys are.
Rym: Yeah, the dialogue was reasonable dialogue.
Rym: I wrote reasonable dialogue on my notes.
Scott: Yeah, and you know, it was like, "Hey, something is sort of happening
Scott: here.".
Scott: The only note I wrote was emo Robin.
Rym: So meh.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely meh.
Rym: It doesn't stand out as bad.
Scott: No.
Rym: So Supergirl.
Scott: No, Red Hood and the Outlaws is next.
Rym: Oh, right.
Rym: The worst.
Scott: The worst?
Rym: So the worst, in terms of sexism, Red Hood and the Outlaws, you win.
Scott: You think this is the most sexist?
Scott: I think, "Oh, you're right.
Scott: This is the one.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Scott: I thought that one was called something different, but no.
Scott: This is the
Scott: one.".
Rym: While voodoo is pretty goddamn sexist, it at least tries to pretend it's not.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And this one was made extra bad, Red Hood and the Outlaws, by the fact that there's that interview in the back of every comic, and they ask the guy who drew Starfire- Oh, really?
Scott: I gotta find this.
Rym: Oh, my.
Rym: Let me read it verbatim.
Rym: Jesus Christ.
Rym: That sold... Oh, it's not... Let me find it.
Rym: Let me pause it.
Scott: Oh, right.
Rym: So they ask, "What was your favorite page in this first issue and
Rym: why?".
Scott: Oh, let me guess.
Scott: The perverted page.
Rym: So one guy gives a crappy answer.
Rym: I like them all, and I can't choose.
Rym: But Scott says, and I quote- Well, not me, Scott.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Corey, aka Starshine or whatever, stepping out of the ocean, just basking in the sunshine.
Rym: I love the joy on her face.
Rym: The people of this planet may not want her here, but God, how she loves this place.
Rym: Now, if you look at that page, none of that is conveyed.
Rym: What is conveyed is ridiculous tits, ridiculous ass.
Scott: It's all shiny.
Rym: It is amazing to behold.
Rym: And the fact that this guy could say that with a straight face means that he is either a misogynistic pervert or- I think so.
Scott: He's the kind of guy who reads the comics of the TNA and loves it.
Scott: And if you question him about it, he'll probably be like, "Yeah, it's fucking
Scott: awesome.".
Scott: He's like, "Superman's drawn all muscly.
Scott: What's the
Scott: problem?".
Rym: This comic makes almost no sense.
Rym: The plot's all over the place.
Rym: Who's that girl with the black eyes?
Rym: What's all this stuff she's talking about?
Rym: Who's that guy who got murdered?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Actually, I didn't even notice that those are interviews in the back of these books because it was just like you get to the back of every book and there's the white page with the black text and I thought it was just advertisement copy and I thought it was the same in every book.
Scott: I didn't bother to read them.
Scott: So now that I know that there's these sort of interviews in the back, I might go and actually check some of them out just to see if there's other crazy shit like that.
Rym: But I'm amazed at how horrible this was just for that.
Scott: This was the worst-.
Rym: I mean, hey, you want to have sex with me because I'm not having sex with my boyfriend right now.
Scott: The only things worse than this that I've seen are things like Chewbra and Kiss X Sis and those sorts of things.
Scott: In terms of superhero comics that aren't actually porn, it's almost like actual porn is better in this, right?
Scott: It's just like, ah, it's awful.
Rym: I mean, they literally made her a character who will just totally have sex with guys with no strings attached and no consequences- Because she's an alien.
Scott: She doesn't care about having sex.
Rym: And seriously, those are breasts.
Scott: Right, but she's an alien, so she's bright orange, but that also happens to be the color of being super tanned and she's in a tropical paradise and she's wearing almost nothing.
Scott: And yeah.
Scott: And that's the focus of three or four pages of the book.
Scott: She takes up the whole page.
Rym: It's pretty bad.
Scott: It's the worst.
Rym: So Supergirl.
Rym: Supergirl is much less scantily clad, although still sort of- I kind of dug the story in that it didn't really give you one.
Rym: It kind of set you in the middle of this crazy situation and then Superman appears at the end, but I don't know if I care what the story is.
Scott: No, I mean, most of it was just fighting robots and actually the way it's drawn and the action- Well, it had
Rym: the nice touch of she's basically screaming that she doesn't understand what's going on and all the guys she's fighting are also screaming the same thing, but because they don't speak each other's languages, they're fighting with each other because neither one of them realizes what's happening.
Rym: But I don't know, I'm not sure where this is going.
Scott: I kind of liked how they sort of- The thing that always bothers me all the time is when superheroes, superpowers are not used to their maximum extent.
Scott: It's like, how come if there's a bad guy, you shouldn't even see Superman coming?
Scott: You shouldn't even talk to him.
Scott: You should just see the bad guy explode like Kenshiro.
Scott: And it won't even be like Kenshiro.
Scott: where Kenshiro walks up and goes,
Scott: "Wata!".
Scott: It's just, maybe you'll see a blur.
Scott: You know, it's just like instantly the bad guy would just explode because Superman is just everywhere on Earth at all times and every bad guy gets punched in the face and that's it.
Scott: But that never happens.
Scott: But in this, they sort of do, you know, when anyone does anything that sort of pushes a superpower to the limit and shows the potential of it, it sort of gets me a little optimistic because she starts hearing things that people are saying really far away.
Rym: Notice how all those things are from all the other new people too.
Scott: From the other comic books.
Scott: She can hear the things that other people are saying in these other 52 with her super hearing and it's like, you know, you would, and I wonder if I hadn't read the other 52, if I had read this very first, would I have known that those things she was hearing were from the other, or even from far away, you know?
Scott: It's like, I don't know, but it was still cool whether I knew it or not, but yeah.
Scott: And then, you know, Superman sort of shows up at the end and it's sort of like I was simultaneously happy and sad to see him at the same time.
Scott: Because on the one hand, it's like, okay, he's just going to come and fix this bullshit, you know, which is sort of what probably should have happened.
Scott: But B, why can't it just be about Supergirl?
Scott: Why does it also have to be about Super Everyone?
Rym: Why does everything have to be about the Green Lantern?
Scott: Right, so I gave it a meh.
Rym: I also gave it a meh.
Rym: And I would read the second one just to find out, but I read the fourth one, I think, and it seems to turn into the same bullshit as everything else.
Scott: So Wonder Woman.
Scott: So, I said this before about a billion times, but the cover of Wonder Woman is like the best cover.
Rym: I wish the whole comic looked like that with those thick lines.
Scott: You see this cover and you're just like, oh my god, this is going to be the greatest.
Scott: And you know, it's sort of like we have those things today that are like, oh my god, look at this drawing of the X-Men.
Scott: I wish there was a whole X-Men comic that looked like this one drawing and there never is.
Scott: This is like, oh my god, look at the cover of this Wonder Woman.
Scott: I wish there was a whole comic that looked like this Wonder Woman.
Scott: Wait a minute, this is on the cover of comic.
Scott: I bet this whole comic looks like, and then it doesn't.
Scott: And it's like, are you kidding me?
Scott: Are you kidding me?
Scott: You've used this image of Wonder Woman to advertise the fuck out of the 52 so much.
Scott: And then the inside of the comic doesn't even fucking look like that.
Scott: I mean, it looks, you know, close.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: It's not bad.
Scott: It's not bad, but it doesn't look like that.
Scott: It's like, ah, dammit.
Rym: But that brought it down from, I'm going to read all this, but you know what?
Rym: I kind of like the story.
Rym: I like how it didn't involve a lot of the other superhero BS.
Scott: Yeah, it only involved Wonder Woman.
Rym: And the analogy is kind of in keeping with the whole Wonder Woman thing.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they didn't really exploit Wonder Woman for TNA or anything like that.
Scott: But I think it's sort of like they purposefully don't do that, right?
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: Because it's Wonder Woman.
Rym: That's a dangerous argument to make.
Rym: If they do exploit, it's because they're exploitative.
Rym: If they don't exploit, it's because they're trying to pretend they're not exploitative.
Scott: And also Wonder Woman is an Amazon, right?
Scott: So it's actually did a really good job of drawing her really tall.
Scott: A lot of times people fail to do that.
Scott: But it's like you look at Wonder Woman and you're like, damn, she's like seven feet tall.
Scott: Watch the fuck out.
Scott: She's like a giant.
Scott: And she's supposed to be.
Scott: She's defending this other person.
Scott: And the thing is, by drawing her that way, it actually not only makes her look as tall as she is and is supposed to be, but actually she sort of explodes off the page because he's so gigantic.
Rym: But I dug this.
Rym: I actually want to read the next one.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I would definitely want to read it more if it looked like the cover.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, I give it a high meh.
Scott: I also give it a high meh.
Rym: It's like meh plus.
Scott: Yeah, meh plus, but not good.
Rym: OK, so that actually took a while.
Rym: So we're going to not do the fourth week.
Scott: That also happens to be the end of the third week.
Scott: We thought we would do them both at once, but we had just so much to say.
Scott: Yeah, we did, I guess.
Scott: Yeah, so let's we'll do week four.
Scott: You know, it won't be six months from now.
Rym: It'll be soonish.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: Some of the ones that we said were good, some of them, I'll get the trade and maybe we'll talk about those first trade volumes.
Rym: Yeah, any one I said I want to read more of, that means I would read the trade.
Scott: Yeah, like a couple months from now, they're actually going to come out with the hardcover volume ones of some of these.
Rym: So none of these was good enough where I would buy the refuse.
Scott: No, but, you know, a couple.
Scott: So give it like four or five months and you'll start to see some trades of this stuff.
Scott: So a trade will usually cover the first six issues of one of these.
Rym: So, yeah, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando Kay for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.