Rym: It's Tuesday, November 27th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, the board game seasons.
Rym: It's alright.
Scott: Just give it away, what?
Rym: Spoilers.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So this past weekend, our friends Phil and Chie came out and we had a sort of post-Thanksgiving feast.
Rym: I feel like a big boy now.
Rym: There's a point in your life when you're able to cook a full Thanksgiving family-style dinner and not feel like you're just faking it.
Rym: I feel like I'm actually an old man now.
Scott: Way to go.
Rym: Yeah, I'm proud of myself.
Scott: Add it to your list of things that make you an old man.
Scott: that started, I don't know, ten years ago.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: Has played Counter-Strike for more than a decade?
Rym: Check.
Scott: Everyone should go to the forum and check that picture.
Scott: I put up where it shows on Wikipedia the date Steam came out and then shows right under it a picture from my Steam profile.
Scott: What's funny is the date of my Steam account creation was the date Steam came out.
Rym: Responding to you clearly have no sense of when games come out and what was important because Steam, when it came out, existed solely to download Counter-Strike patches.
Scott: And also because Juan had died, you needed to find servers to play on using Steam, which was a much improved UI over.
Scott: the problem was Steam itself at the time did not work for many people.
Rym: Remember when Steam...
Scott: It never not worked for me.
Rym: For the longest time, the friends stuff just didn't fucking work.
Scott: Well, they had the friends stuff in there as like.
Scott: they put the GUI and framework in there before they had the network up.
Rym: But it just didn't do anything.
Scott: And it's like, it's like, why did you put this in here if it's not working yet?
Scott: And then when they even had it working, it's like they didn't, the friends servers weren't always running.
Scott: So they'd be like on and off and on and off.
Scott: So basically you just ignored that shit.
Scott: Now it pretty much works.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, it really did.
Scott: All it was when Steam originally came out was automatically get Counter-Strike patches without having to go to counter-strike.net and click on every mirror.
Scott: And which is why all those mirror sites died and to find Counter-Strike servers.
Rym: But so this weekend our friend Chie recommended we go to a tea place.
Rym: We got together and we went out to Flushing to this place called Fang Gourmet Tea.
Scott: I did not go.
Rym: Well, of course you didn't.
Rym: Would you want to go have a tea tasting with us?
Scott: No, I don't like tea.
Rym: So basically what this was, we had the equivalent of a sommelier, but for tea.
Rym: And we did tastings and the sommelier explained like what each tea was.
Scott: When you make tea.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if you have wine, you can take a bottle of wine and pour a little bit.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So she did this complicated thing.
Scott: And then you can give little bits to people at another table.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, you know, you're not really wasting it when you make tea.
Scott: It's like there's a minimum amount of tea you make from.
Rym: No, you can make single glasses of tea.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if you're having a tasting, how many glasses of tea are you going to have?
Rym: Five tiny ones that are each one sip per type of tea.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So how do they mean?
Scott: But you make tea in a teapot.
Scott: They have a whole.
Rym: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Rym: You make tea in a teapot if you're making tea in bulk.
Rym: OK, so basically what she does is a tea thimble.
Rym: First she'd take out the tea leaves for the particular tea.
Rym: We tried a high mountain Taiwanese one leaf, put it in a cup first and then we try to something else, some kind of roasted black tea and then our rapport.
Rym: Basically what she do is you take the leaves out and show them to us and explain like where it came from and the characteristics past the leaves around fucks with them.
Rym: Then she'd put enough for, you know, one small pot and do a little thing and pour hot water over it.
Rym: Let it steep for a little bit, rinse it out and do all this stuff.
Rym: And then she'd pour each of us a little glass and she'd repeat this five times.
Rym: You could resteep what she had poured out five times and she'd point out how the flavors change with each steeping.
Scott: It gets steeping.
Scott: Number six tastes like water.
Rym: Actually no.
Rym: Apparently that only happens to shitty tea.
Scott: So but you did it five times.
Scott: So I'm saying the sixth time.
Scott: we could have done more.
Rym: She said that she'll steep tea herself seven or eight times.
Rym: What was cool.
Scott: So tea number 10 tastes like water.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: The coolest thing was that she was so much like the girl in drops of God who wants to be a sommelier.
Rym: It was ridiculous.
Rym: She like lives alone and she works in this place and she worked here for many years and she does the tea tastings.
Rym: And of course she tasted each tea too as she was preparing everything for us.
Rym: She knows her shit.
Rym: Like she knows tea really well.
Rym: And then she was telling us about how at home she makes the tea herself and does the same thing.
Rym: Like she owned the place.
Rym: So she does the same thing.
Rym: The drops of God girl does.
Rym: She like taste the tea at home and practices and learns that it was, I don't know, it was really fun.
Rym: And as as cool as it was, should have given her drops.
Rym: I am not going to learn much more about this because I have enough on my hands with beer and wine.
Scott: I already have too many.
Scott: I already took on too many things.
Scott: You should see the robot.
Rym: One could say that my cup overflowed.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I just bought these plastic robots or I bought the RG.
Scott: They actually made membrane Gundam seed.
Scott: There was the air, the jet that the kid would fly.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: I forget the kid's name.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it would.
Scott: it would deploy the different equipment onto the strike Gundam.
Scott: So I said, whoa, they made a model of that thing.
Scott: And it's RG.
Scott: I got to get that, you know, because it's like usually just make robots that they're making the jet.
Scott: I've like sold.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then I'm like, you know what?
Scott: I'll buy the strike Gundam also because, you know, that's also RG.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Apparently, they go together and the jet actually comes with the equipment to deploy onto the strike Gundam.
Scott: So if you buy both, which I now have, you can switch the strike Gundam to have, you know, the big green desert backpack thing or, you know, the sword thing.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: How about that?
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Suddenly I forgot about that entire aspect of Gundam seed.
Rym: Now I kind of just want to watch Gundam see it.
Scott: Well, we're going to steal it back from Scott Johnson very soon.
Scott: You want to do a, uh, the utensil analysis of Gundam seed has a lot of recap episodes and it's also got maybe too many episodes.
Scott: I think we'd be better off doing some evangelical and after we do a tenant, that would be a good one.
Scott: I think that is, we'll see.
Rym: if we do one a week, it'll be 39 or 40 weeks.
Scott: That's plenty.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Let's move along some news.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So we, you came out, we didn't buy one.
Scott: Didn't buy one.
Rym: Nintendo's stock, not, uh, not reacting so well.
Rym: Uh, every game stop I've passed in New York city has had plenty of the white one and all but one of them had at least one, if not more of the black ones, I haven't seen anyone actually have the black.
Rym: I was out in flushing.
Rym: There was a pile of both just in the goddamn window.
Scott: And uh, see, here's the thing that, you know, I'm going to say it again, right?
Scott: I mean, there's always the stuff that we know and have said about Nintendo.
Scott: You can listen to old dude.
Rym: Look at that stock chart I linked to.
Rym: It's like Nintendo's stock peak.
Rym: I'm not after the right.
Scott: I'm not going to repeat myself.
Scott: You've heard this before.
Scott: If you haven't, you can go hear it again.
Scott: But I want to say is that those things that we have said in the past are more true now than they were before, right?
Scott: We've said things, for example, man, if Nintendo would just open up and let anyone make software on their shit, they would really rock the house.
Scott: That's more true.
Scott: Now, if you could write any software you wanted for that pad with that thing, they'll be selling even more.
Scott: That's, you know, it's more true for the Wii U than it was for the Wii and the DS, right?
Scott: It's you know, if somebody would just make a game like the game we said, like four swords and everyone would buy it.
Scott: That's more true now.
Scott: So it's just, it's the disappointment, lack of potential is just, that's what's bothering me.
Scott: The gap has just widened, but nothing has changed.
Rym: It's such a, for me now, not for the market at large, but for me, it's such a too little, too late thing.
Rym: It's like to use the analogy I used on the forum around 2002, you know, in the early GameCube days, it was a brand new link cables, all that stuff.
Rym: Nintendo had a party going on and they had plenty of beer, beer being the analogy for games that were innovative and cool and different, the kinds of stuff that is my jam.
Rym: And then the beer ran out, as happens at parties, Nintendo wouldn't buy any more beer.
Rym: So I left and I went back to the PC gaming party.
Scott: 10 years later, you know, it's cheap beer while it's all varieties of beer on the PC.
Scott: The thing is, but it overflows.
Rym: The PC beer party had been nothing but Budweiser for a while and suddenly it came back.
Rym: We're not always right.
Rym: I mean, well, I think that we were right in the sense that PC gaming was out of beer back when we said it was dead, but a new PC gaming has emerged.
Scott: And now that is every microbrew in the universe and also the prices have come crashing down.
Scott: So the PC gaming right now is freaking every fancy microbrew for a dollar.
Rym: So after Crystal Chronicles, I mean, the beer ran out and 10 years later, give or take, I get an invite to Nintendo's party.
Rym: They're like, hey, we got a couple of cans of beer.
Scott: If you want to come back over, how many can join our party and how much are they?
Scott: It's a three hundred dollar can.
Scott: How much is we even cost?
Rym: And basically the games that people are saying are fun on the Wii U right now are basically Pac-Man verse.
Scott: at best a game that has existed for a Wii U is four hundred twenty.
Scott: I can't be right.
Rym: Is that the deluxe one?
Rym: I guess with the.
Scott: I guess that the Amazon price because it's it's that that does the deluxe one.
Scott: Let me go out.
Scott: It can't.
Scott: that can't be the real price.
Scott: That has to be like the inflated third party seller price.
Scott: Let me see.
Scott: Find the real price.
Rym: But here's the most damning thing against the Wii U, because I could talk about what I want, but I know that what I want is not what the industry wants or what other gamers want.
Rym: For example, I want a game like Mega Team Fortress, even though I know that is a shit game.
Scott: The deluxe one is three fifty.
Scott: God, that is way too much money.
Rym: So the most damning thing I can say is that I know three parents, three parents in different contexts of my life who in the past week have told me they're going to go buy their kids a Nintendo Wii.
Rym: And upon questioning, I learned that, no, they mean the Nintendo Wii.
Rym: They had no idea.
Rym: a Wii U came out.
Rym: They had no intention of purchasing one.
Rym: The idea of paying more than one hundred and fifty dollars for a console seemed ridiculous to them.
Rym: And they asked me, what are the hot games on the Wii other than that bowling game?
Rym: But that bowling game is the only one they actually wanted to buy.
Rym: This is three people who don't know each other.
Rym: Normal people have no idea, no idea that the Nintendo Wii U came out.
Rym: They think of Nintendo as the company that made the Wii, and they don't know it in any other context.
Rym: So Nintendo now couple this with the fact that the regular Wii, the Wii U, the non deluxe edition, that's basically the bullshit edition, not to sell them so well.
Rym: And a lot of places have plenty in stock.
Rym: It's the deluxe one that sold out.
Rym: So the hardcore Nintendo people who haven't backed away like we have seem to be the primary market now, unless the distribution of which ones are available is just way off.
Rym: I don't know how this is going to go for Nintendo.
Scott: I mean, whatever the system came out.
Scott: It's the same news over and over again.
Scott: So I really don't have much to say without just repeating myself and making this part of the podcast incredibly long.
Rym: Well, it's not the same news.
Rym: The last time we talked about this was when the 3DS came out.
Scott: I mean, I'm saying it's different consoles, same Nintendo.
Scott: They haven't changed anything since.
Scott: they have turned down the dark path and that's it.
Rym: But they turn back.
Rym: The problem is they turn back so late in the game.
Rym: It would be I'm trying to think of a good analogy.
Scott: They haven't turned back at all.
Scott: It's the same thing they've been doing for years.
Scott: There were same complaints.
Scott: They're still valid.
Scott: Nothing's changed.
Rym: Now what they do is have a new console with the same complaint.
Rym: They went back to doing something a little innovative.
Rym: The whole asymmetric play, the idea of having.
Scott: But they didn't make any games that did it.
Scott: They did.
Scott: They made what game?
Rym: They made three clones of Pac-Man verse.
Rym: OK, so they have made more games that do the same thing, but the console came out.
Rym: So now we're in the post release drought, which Nintendo consoles always have.
Rym: So it's going to be a couple of months before anything new comes out.
Scott: And I've been to ever fucking launched a console with like an A plus full on Zelda game ever Zelda game.
Scott: I mean, come on.
Scott: It's like that's the game that people actually want.
Scott: Always is Smash Brothers.
Scott: Real Zelda only hardcore people want Smash Brothers.
Scott: I'm saying these are the games people want.
Scott: They want Smash Brothers Mario.
Scott: They want hardcore Zelda game, right?
Scott: They want these things and they never launch with that.
Scott: They always bring that out like when the console is like near death.
Rym: Well, because that's to bump the sales.
Scott: Why don't they make fucking like an awesome Pokemon or something?
Scott: People love that shit, too.
Rym: Well, we already know.
Rym: We did a whole lecture at PAX and how they don't utilize.
Scott: Anyway, let's move on to the same Nintendo complete.
Scott: So the big steam sale happened.
Scott: Not really that much to buy so much.
Rym: I bought limbo because it was like a dollar.
Rym: I didn't.
Rym: I don't even like limbo.
Scott: But there were two interesting things happened.
Scott: Number one, there was this game called Hotline Miami.
Scott: I didn't really know anything about this game at all.
Scott: But people started talking about it and it was crazy cheap.
Scott: But I saw some talk that it was mad buggy.
Scott: So I was like, all right, I'm going to take one for the team and buy Hotline Miami and see what the deal is.
Scott: So now I have taken it for the team.
Scott: I'm going to tell you how it is.
Scott: It's actually it's a single player game.
Scott: Mostly I didn't see any multiplayer action.
Scott: I mean, there might be, but I didn't try it out.
Rym: I've been too busy playing, I don't know, Counter-Strike, NS2, FTL.
Scott: It is mad buggy.
Scott: It barely worked like the audio didn't work and it crashed.
Scott: And people said the same things online.
Scott: A lot of people had problems with it.
Scott: Some people didn't have any problems, bad problems.
Scott: I'm going to try it on some different machine, see what happens.
Scott: And it's actually kind of fun, clever game.
Scott: The way it works is it's sort of a straight top down situation, like litter, not three quarters, not isometric, straight down.
Scott: And you're this criminal dude and you're sitting at home and you get a phone call and the phone calls like, hey, I need you to do this job, usually involving killing people or stealing something.
Scott: So you go and get in a car and they drive you somewhere and you get out and you put on a mask and the different masks have different abilities.
Scott: It was like Rooster, Al, you know, whatever.
Scott: And then you go to town on these guys in this building.
Scott: So it's actually pretty hard because all the bad guys are really smart.
Scott: If a guy with a gun sees you, he shoots you and he doesn't really miss.
Scott: See, and it's like if you hit someone with melee weapons, not everyone will hear.
Scott: So you can use only melee weapons.
Scott: You can sort of go slowly and go one room at a time taking guys out.
Scott: But if there's a room, for example, with a guy on patrol behind the door and another guy sitting on the couch or the gun, you have to like open the door on the first guy to knock him down, get to the guy with the gun before he shoots you, then kill the guy.
Scott: You knock down or use a gun.
Scott: But if you use a gun, everyone in the whole map frickin hears it and starts running straight at you.
Scott: So it's like this pretty challenging kind of fun action game.
Scott: And I kind of wish it wasn't mad buggy.
Rym: So how buggy is it?
Scott: They know the sound effects work.
Scott: The music did not work, which is disappointing because the credits talked about, you know, we're like music by so-and-so.
Scott: And I was like, man, I bet these songs are probably really good.
Scott: I can't hear them.
Rym: Yeah, there's been a nice trend for good music and games like particular like FTL has an amazing soundtrack.
Scott: It's pretty crashy, a little bit, a little bit of video errors.
Scott: If you put it in, I tried to put it in Xbox 360 gamepad mode.
Scott: It was a little bit flaky and putting it in gamepad mode because I was playing on the HDBC made it not work with the keyboard anymore.
Scott: It's one or the other, not both.
Scott: What the hell, guys?
Scott: It's come on.
Scott: That's basic.
Scott: That's, you know, step one.
Scott: Everything should work.
Scott: You know, but other than that, like if this game worked, it'd be awesome.
Scott: And I heard, I guess there's going to be a Hotline Miami, too, which I hope will not be as buggy.
Scott: In other news, Magical Drop V is out.
Rym: I heard you had some trouble with that one, too.
Scott: So Magical Drop V is, from everything I can tell, the ultimate in Magical Drop.
Scott: All the characters, a bunch of crazy modes, works on the PC, modern graphics, modern software, modern everything.
Scott: But it's fucking magical drop.
Scott: Hells yeah.
Scott: Let's go.
Scott: Justice.
Rym: Where's my battle balls?
Scott: Justice is the best, right?
Scott: But if you go to the Steam forums for this game, this game is super crashy.
Scott: Doesn't even launch crazy bugs for all kinds of people.
Scott: But the guy who makes it, who doesn't speak very good English, he keeps posting.
Scott: He's actively in that forum thread as recently as a few hours ago on the Steam forums, telling people of all the bugs they're going to fix and how they're going to work on Saturday and do all this stuff to me.
Scott: So there's a free demo.
Scott: I downloaded the demo on my work PC.
Scott: I didn't even launch.
Scott: I click play in steam and it said starting.
Scott: the little steam dialog box disappeared and then nothing happened and the game did not launch.
Scott: I'm going to try the demo on some other computers to see if it works on those.
Scott: So I recommend doing the same right.
Scott: If you can get the demo to work without flaws or crashing, then it's probably worth the 10 bucks if you try it, because I do have a magical drought.
Rym: I do have a butt old video card.
Scott: I got a GTX 260, but if the demo to 60 beware, though, because I did read in the in the in that forum thread, there were some discussions about how you should go to your services and turn off the print spooler.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I was going to say something about that in the forum and the thread about this.
Rym: If that is ever the answer.
Scott: That is not the answer.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Also, I was reading that like one guy had the game working perfectly and he was playing through the story mode and he got really far in like level something level, you know, who know, deep in the game.
Scott: And then a certain level is making it crash.
Scott: So he couldn't get past that.
Scott: And like that is the worst.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because you could be fooled, even if you do the demo to see if it's going to work and then you pay for it and then you can't beat it because it's buggy.
Scott: So maybe you should wait like a few weeks on this one.
Scott: See if this guy or the development team is actually going to fix it, like they say.
Scott: And I think they will fix a lot of the bugs if they're if they're actively posting in the steam forum.
Scott: I trust that they're actually going to do something, but I'm not going to give them the money until I see that something.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see how it goes.
Scott: Meaning the demo runs.
Rym: Not only do I have plenty of games, but I bought X-Com while I was on sale.
Scott: I did not.
Scott: You know how much?
Rym: you know how much I've played of it?
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: According to Steam.
Scott: Zero.
Rym: Three minutes.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I started it and I started playing through the sort of like, here's how to play the game.
Scott: And it was X-Com and it was great.
Rym: And then I stopped playing it to go play Counter-Strike.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: So so there you go.
Scott: Magical Drop V Hotline Miami.
Rym: What else did I buy?
Scott: Pretty good games that were mad cheap during the sales.
Scott: Still kind of cheap.
Rym: Speaking of a man.
Rym: Guns of Icarus online was on sale and so was and is as of right now.
Rym: Counter-Strike go.
Scott: There was actually a kind of complete seven dollars and fifty cents.
Scott: There was a Counter-Strike complete pack that was ten bucks.
Scott: They got you every Counter-Strike ever.
Scott: If you didn't have any of them, that was a good deal.
Scott: And also super hexagon for anyone doesn't have an iPhone or iPad is now on the Steam store for like two dollars.
Scott: And the PC version might be much more playable than the iPhone version.
Scott: And in addition, they have a two pack for three dollars and change.
Scott: Since I already have the iOS one Rym should buy the two pack for three dollars and give me the other one, because I think on the PC I could do much better than I could on the phone.
Rym: Sadly, though, if you want to you want to see where the state of all that is right now.
Rym: Dota two is still far and away the most popular game on Steam.
Scott: Yeah, it has been for quite a while now.
Rym: Football manager number two.
Scott: That's always been up there.
Rym: Team Fortress two is next.
Rym: Civ five has had a huge resurgence.
Scott: Well, they just had that gods and kings thing was on super sale.
Scott: And it was also a Civ five super pack during the sale.
Scott: So a bunch of people who never bought Civ five all bought the whole thing for mad cheap with an expansion.
Rym: So number five is Counter-Strike one six.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: Global Offensive is down to number 10 and source is even below that.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Global Offensive only has, you know, 20 ish thousand players.
Scott: That's because half the people got banned for leaving competitive games early.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: See, Civ five actually, you know, has a inflated concurrent player figure because you play Civ five for longer amounts of time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So a lot is, you know, more players will overlap to get a higher peak number, whereas a game with a shorter plate.
Rym: Not because the current number is also higher at any given point.
Scott: OK, no, that's what I'm saying is that they're showing you a current number and they're showing a peak.
Rym: So the current of those, the current and peak are almost identical all the time.
Rym: Meanwhile, Counter-Strike's peak is more than double its current at any given time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But this is what I'm saying at the peak.
Scott: This is what I'm telling you is those numbers are numbers of players simultaneously either now or at some point during the day.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It is not the total number of people who have played at some point at any time today.
Scott: None of those numbers are that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: So Civ five, that peak number, because you play that game for hours at a time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That is probably much closer to the total number of people who have played at any point today.
Scott: Whereas the Counter-Strike number, it's like, yeah, OK, there might only be twenty thousand people playing Counter-Strike right now.
Scott: But if we add up anyone who has launched and played a single round of Counter-Strike during the entire 24 past 24 hours, that number is probably well above the peak and current numbers, which is why I wish they would give you that third number of number of people who have played this game at all in the past 24 hours, as opposed to only these two figures that are number of players at the same exact moment.
Scott: Now, a number of players at the same exact moment at any time in the past 24 hours.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: This is a video I saw this weekend.
Rym: It is an ad for the Central Institute of Technology in Western Australia.
Scott: Well, we're not going close to that.
Rym: And it's a snap.
Rym: It's kind of a spoof on sort of the kinds of ads you see for colleges.
Rym: It's actually pretty funny.
Rym: And I recommend you watch to the end.
Scott: OK, is that it?
Rym: The only thing I have to say is that this is kind of a sanctioned ad for the university, which makes me really respect that university.
Scott: OK.
Rym: Not that I'm going to ever visit that place because it's in the western side of Australia.
Scott: Maybe one day.
Scott: So we know in the world, right, there are instruments that everyone knows.
Scott: And then there are the weird instruments that are slightly weird, but they're still normal.
Scott: You see them played.
Scott: They're useful, right?
Scott: Like oboes.
Scott: It's like, you know, a lot of people on the street, maybe most of them wouldn't even know an oboe if they saw one.
Scott: But orchestras fucking use oboes.
Scott: If you go, there's going to be an oboe there.
Scott: But then there are other instruments that are very rare because they're very not useful.
Scott: But someone invented them and some crazy instrument making guy somewhere produced some number of them.
Scott: And they're good for novelty reasons.
Scott: And extremely weird musical pieces might require one or two weird instruments of some kind.
Scott: So here I have a video of this dude named Jose Valentino, and he is playing a double contrabass flute.
Rym: Now, a contrabass flute, a single one is already a rarely if ever used.
Scott: OK, so he plays this.
Scott: He kind of the video is kind of backwards because he plays the double contrabass and then plays the single contrabass.
Scott: I would have played the single and then been like, all right, here's the double.
Scott: Oh, but he does the double first.
Scott: The double one basically is so bass, you can barely hear it.
Scott: You hear his the air coming out of his mouth going like more than you hear the bass from the flute.
Scott: They could just be because of the way it was recorded.
Scott: And maybe if you're in the room with him, you would hear the flute.
Rym: No, like I'll say this when I you know, when I was in a jazz band, we had a bass flute flautist for a single bass flat, which is slightly weird, but still a useful instrument.
Rym: But the thing is, that was only used for these sort of hunting accents or beatboxing solos and nothing else.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So the single contrabass flute, however, while also extremely weird and not so useful, you can actually hear it in the in the YouTube video.
Scott: It sounds pretty good.
Scott: You can make some good music with that thing.
Scott: That would be enjoyable to people.
Rym: So in the meta moment, the book club book was The Name of the Wind by Patrick Roth Fuss.
Rym: It's all done.
Rym: The episode's up.
Rym: Everything's out.
Rym: The new book club, which I'm going to start up soon as I type it all in, is The Great Gatsby by F. Scott Fitzgerald.
Rym: It's a classic.
Rym: You guys should read it if you haven't read it.
Rym: I haven't read it, so I don't feel dumb unless you don't read it by the time I read it.
Scott: I also have not read it, but I have begun.
Scott: I read a few pages.
Rym: I read reading other book, three quarters of the second book in the Kingkiller Chronicle.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I'm done with those books.
Scott: So bad news.
Scott: I do want to say, though, it's currently it's about to be December, right?
Scott: So the episode for the book club book might occur in late December, if not after Magfest.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's either going to be right before New Year's when I have a week off of work or it's going to be after Magfest.
Scott: So you have some time to read this mother.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's why I haven't even updated it yet.
Scott: Any other metamol?
Rym: We have an official GeekNights' Counter Strike Global Offensive server.
Rym: If you want to play Counter Strike Global Offensive with us and people in our forum, go to it.
Rym: It is geeknight.game.nfoservers.com.
Rym: That's geeknight.game.nfoservers.com.
Scott: Sunday, Sunday, Saturday.
Rym: So also very briefly, a while ago, Dude emailed us with a question and Scott covered this in the newsletter.
Rym: So one, if you're not subscribed to the GeekNights' email newsletter, you should because it has content that is not in the show, not on the website, not in the forum.
Scott: And people read it.
Scott: And so far, nobody is unsubscribed from it, which you'll find strange.
Rym: It's a it's a good newsletter.
Rym: Scott does a good job and has its own thing of the day and everything.
Rym: But SR.UpperCase A sent us some questions and I said, oh, I will answer these on the show the next time we record a Tuesday show.
Rym: We basically hadn't recorded a normal Tuesday show since then because we'd recorded ahead and then we had hurricane.
Rym: All this all this stuff happened.
Rym: So this is the first show that I'm live recording since I said I would do that.
Rym: OK, so I would like to answer the question.
Rym: Now, if you subscribe to the newsletter, you can see that Scott gave his own answer to this question as well, which I would not agree with my answer.
Rym: No, I'm just not going to paraphrase it here.
Rym: They'll have to subscribe to the newsletter to get future ones and to find out what was in that one.
Rym: They'd better make a friend.
Rym: I hear there's an underground swapping market for old newsletters.
Scott: I think MailChimp actually hosts HTML versions of the newsletters on their site.
Scott: If you can get the links like.
Scott: if you go to the newsletter email and you click on like, you know, view this email in your browser, you'll get a URL.
Scott: And you can just share that URL and that'll.
Scott: anyone can use that URL to read the newsletter.
Rym: So first of all, regarding Rims Post, do cheap tactics ruin online multiplayer?
Rym: Rims states that if you are playing in a competitive game, you play to win.
Scott: You're going to read this whole thing?
Rym: Not the whole thing.
Rym: By any means necessary without cheating.
Rym: I understand your point, but don't you think there is a line beyond which there is no point in winning because you are not playing the same game anymore?
Rym: And don't you think it's unethical to use cheap tactics that were not meant to be there like snaking?
Rym: And an example is provided here.
Rym: Imagine if in Mario Kart DS, if you could hit a hundred times, you would instantly win the race.
Rym: Should you use that or not?
Scott: Well, can the guy get around the track the right the normal way before you press a hundred?
Rym: Let's say there's no chance of that.
Scott: OK, because if he can do that, then you probably want to raise because pressing a hundred times is not going to win before someone else wins.
Rym: So, of course, my opinion is that in general, any game that has a tactic that is so cheap that it can win the game trivially is a very poorly designed game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, cheapness.
Scott: What is cheapness?
Scott: Cheapness?
Rym: Did you get to the chapter in Garfield's book on what cheap is yet?
Scott: I already know what it is.
Scott: I need to read that.
Scott: It's cheapness is when you have a tactic or move or strategy available in a game that is legal, that is extremely low effort, is extremely easy to do.
Scott: Anyone can figure it out and execute it trivially, but is extremely powerful and puts you way ahead.
Rym: It's to be like a very high return on investment.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's like if you're playing Street Fighter and it's like there was one guy, a new character and his jab did a half life bar of damage, that would be cheap because anyone can push the chuck and jab button.
Scott: It's so easy and it takes away so much damage.
Scott: Why would you choose any other character?
Scott: Whereas to do a half bar of damage with someone else, you maybe need to execute a combo, which is rather difficult and you need to get it to hit.
Scott: Yeah, so that's that's what cheap is, is low effort, high reward.
Rym: Now I play to win.
Rym: So, for example, Mario Kart DS, I only ever snaked once you knew you could do it.
Rym: As soon as I learned to do it, I snaked because that was the strategy to beat the game.
Rym: There's no way I was going to let myself lose a race that I could win.
Rym: And as a result, I ended up not playing the game much.
Rym: Now, it would have been fine to play to try to play the game and kind of patch around that by saying like, no snaking.
Rym: But then you have to very extremely precisely define what snaking means and it becomes a prisoner's dilemma situation.
Scott: See, the way I see it is I wish they would have just implemented the same.
Scott: It's going to talk about Mario Kart because everyone loves it.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Mario Kart is such a great example of all these things.
Scott: Super Mario Kart, Super Circuit, the best one.
Scott: You could only get blue sparks once per corner.
Scott: You couldn't just sort of like slide sideways in a straightaway.
Scott: That fucking didn't do shit, right?
Scott: If you went around a corner perfectly with the drift, right, it would give you one blue spark as your reward.
Scott: And that was all you could do, right?
Scott: That was that was the maximum sneakiness you could get out of that game.
Scott: And I think if they would have just that's sort of what they intended.
Scott: You know, if you look at, you know, say what's the one with the two people double dash, it was sort of the same idea.
Scott: If the other character sitting in the backseat shifts the way to help you go around the corner faster with the drift, you would get the blue sparks.
Scott: And that was the intent of the mechanic.
Scott: The problem wasn't how they programmed it is that you could just if the if the straightaway was wide enough, you could drift in the middle of it and would give you sparks and you could just keep doing it over and over.
Rym: Now, one, I would argue that it's pointless to argue what the intent of the games.
Scott: I agree with that as well.
Scott: But the only reason I know the intent is because of Super Mario Kart, Super Circuit.
Rym: Yeah, but that could still be argued.
Scott: It is.
Scott: I admit that.
Scott: But I'm just saying is that if I were going to create rules to police a Mario Kart DS tournament and I wanted to eliminate snaking, the rule would be you can get blue if you get more than if you get a blue spark.
Scott: that is not on a corner.
Rym: And what defines the corners is a slight bend in the track count.
Scott: It's we would define the corners on every single track what they are.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So how do you officiate that without spectators?
Scott: We would have a spec.
Scott: We would need a spectator for every single driver.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So now you're.
Rym: now you're.
Rym: you have fallible humans and no way to do a replay.
Scott: We would have a video also of the entire race.
Rym: So what is the punishment for snaking?
Scott: disqualification?
Rym: All right.
Scott: Or you could do it like so.
Scott: So here's what you restart the race, like if someone has a false start.
Rym: So here's what I'm getting at.
Rym: If a bunch of players agree to change the rules of the game, it is technically a different game, but so on.
Rym: We're fine.
Rym: It's still.
Scott: it's like you play Magic in a tournament.
Scott: Certain cards are banned, right?
Rym: It's the same, but it's still magic.
Rym: But it's like magic, you know, version one dot eight dot seven.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: So but there's still magic in the sense of the history and the word means kind of like how hockey is still hockey, even though the rules have been different every year.
Rym: But the difference is that here what Scott's talking about, we have all these people playing together in person.
Rym: We have a way to an objective, external way to enforce the rule we have all agreed upon.
Rym: The only way you could really play Mario Kart online or even in person, in most cases, was such that there is no possible way to enforce a rule of no snaking and even worse in online play, because Nintendo doesn't let you talk to people.
Rym: There is no way to even enforce a social contract.
Rym: There is no way to interact with the other players and come to consensus or to punish someone who doesn't follow the rule.
Rym: The only way you can even have the rule is by putting it like in your name.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Even if you could start a race and say no snaking and everyone said, yes, I agree.
Scott: No snaking.
Scott: You still couldn't define snaking amongst you.
Scott: So someone's inevitably going to do something someone else considers to be snaking and when and the other people like, oh, no, we allow two sparks, two sparks.
Scott: And it becomes playground rules again, right?
Scott: Where it's like, you know, no backseas.
Scott: You didn't shoot me.
Rym: Yes, I did.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So we can't have that bullshit.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So rules, mods like that to change the rules of a game, to eliminate a cheap tactic only work if you have a strong social contract that can actually enforce the rule and you can all agree what the change should be before you start, which
Scott: usually means you're playing a game in a room with friends together and you have a social contract or you're playing in a strict tournament setting.
Rym: But for example, if I started losing it all in a Mario Kart online, even if I hadn't snaked up to that point, I would snake whenever no one could see me to catch up because I want to win.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it's like if you could if you could decide to restart a hundred meter dash, if you're behind, it's like, yeah, I'll restart it a hundred times until I'm not.
Rym: But for example, the thing we always use in lectures is counter strike.
Rym: If you if you really think that the AWP is OP, you as the server administrator, just remove it from the list of weapons people can buy.
Rym: Totally enforced.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So briefly, and then we'll get on to the rest of the show.
Rym: The other question changing subject.
Rym: You think cheating can be considered metagaming?
Rym: One could say that cheating is only invalid if you get caught.
Rym: So using a strategy to cheat without getting caught wouldn't be metagaming.
Rym: Of course, I'm only talk about cheating in a way you get caught, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: And the answer to that is complicated.
Rym: What I would say is that, again, it depends on the social contract and the ramifications of cheating.
Scott: For example, is he asking if all cheating is metagaming or is he asking if metagaming is cheating?
Rym: Do you think cheating can be considered metagaming?
Scott: There's cheating that is not metagaming and there's cheating that might be considered metagaming.
Rym: So let's start with examples first.
Rym: Briefly, if I cheat in hockey, I have too many men on the ice.
Rym: The rules actually say how that is enforced.
Scott: Yeah, it's not metagaming at all.
Rym: Enforcing it is part of the rules.
Rym: It's part of the game.
Rym: A coach might make the decision to put too many men out for a brief period, especially in, you know, like college games, hoping the refs won't notice.
Rym: And that while cheating, there is a mechanic for resolving that action.
Scott: It's not cheating.
Scott: It's completely.
Scott: it's actually I would argue that, you know, too many men on the ice, you know, is it cheating?
Scott: It's like, well, yes, you're not.
Scott: it's a rule against that.
Scott: You are breaking the rule.
Scott: But at the same time, the game handles that.
Scott: You go in the box as a penalty for it.
Scott: You haven't broken the game by doing this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You've just broken a rule of the game.
Scott: But it's there.
Rym: But there is a built in rule and means of mitigating that and continuing the game.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: The game isn't immediately an asterisk if there's too many men on the ice.
Scott: Instead, it's not cheating.
Scott: Like, you know, I had cards up my sleeve in poker.
Rym: So if there is an in-game punishment to deal with a contextual result of the cheating and a means of dealing with it and continuing the game without placing the game under a sort of asterisk situation, then it is not actually cheating.
Rym: For example, soccer taking falls and all these other forms of, you know, quote unquote, cheating are a core part of the strategy of soccer.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, there are rules for it, but they don't fucking enforce them.
Rym: Or in Fury of Dracula, a board game.
Rym: If Dracula fucks up or cheats and is caught, there are rules for what happens.
Scott: So in the book, exactly what to do if Dracula fucks up.
Rym: In which case it would be a perfectly legitimate strategy.
Scott: Shady Dracula is to avoid and not get caught.
Rym: shady and maybe a little cheap, but not cheating in this sense.
Rym: Now, take a game of Puerto Rico.
Rym: If I just fucking take a building when no one's looking one, I've violated something much more severe than the rules of a game like hockey.
Rym: I've violated the social contract among my friends because there is literally nothing in the rules to address that situation.
Rym: If a player violates the rules of a board game like Puerto Rico, there is no possible recourse except outside the game, stopping the game.
Rym: If you notice it too late, the game is done.
Rym: There's no way to fix that short of having perfect memory and stepping back through the game to the point it happened and then continuing after preventing the action.
Rym: You basically have to stop playing the game.
Rym: And since there is no way in the rules to deal with it, the only way to deal with it is via the social contract of not being friends with that person anymore.
Rym: So in my opinion, it is only cheating if the rules of the game do not address a contextual means of resolving it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, if the rules of the game say, you know, if you trip the guy in hockey, you get two minutes in the box, then, you know, you probably shouldn't trip a guy because you want to win.
Rym: But for example, if I hold out a knife and stabbed a dude on the ice in the middle of a hockey game, that game would be asterisk.
Rym: They'd probably replay it later.
Rym: I'd go to jail.
Rym: Yeah, it's not like the ref's going to be like, oh, stabbing, four minutes.
Scott: Yeah, but, you know, tripping a guy, it's like, well, you did it.
Scott: It happens.
Scott: It happens a lot, right?
Scott: It's like we don't suddenly hate you or anything.
Scott: But, you know, or maybe you do.
Rym: But it's part.
Rym: it's a cheap tactic, maybe.
Rym: But it's part of the game.
Rym: But doing something that the rules do not address is cheating.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, that might have been a little long.
Rym: But considering how long it took me to do this.
Rym: S.R.A.,
Rym: those are your answers.
Rym: If you have any more questions, be sure to email us.
Rym: We actually respond to emails sometimes.
Scott: So the game Seasons.
Scott: So I heard about this game from people on the Internet.
Scott: So I bought it.
Scott: It's a pretty new, hot, new game.
Scott: I wanted to talk about a hot new game on the show instead, you know, because you're running out of old games we've all played.
Scott: So what is the deal with Seasons?
Scott: Well, the first thing that gets you in this game that you notice is the artworks, which are crazy, colorful and pretty cool.
Rym: I really like the evil.
Rym: Well, not evil, but the nervous looking rabbit wizard.
Rym: I've played him every time.
Scott: It's weird, like the character designs, like a lot of them, especially those main characters, like I'm not too into them.
Scott: Like I don't really like.
Scott: I wouldn't, you know, want the weird, freaky bunny on my wall or anything, you know, but or as my desktop wallpaper.
Scott: But the style, like the way they're drawn and the bright colors and the high contrast and the high resolution, it's like the quality of it is like, oh, that is so nice.
Scott: It's just not.
Scott: it's like a really nice drawing of a thing.
Scott: I don't want to see a drawing of, but it's fun.
Rym: It's cute.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you're someone who likes game artworks, this is this is like, you know, a territory here.
Scott: The game itself, you know, when I read about it, the thing that made me want to buy it was how this was a confluence of so many different game mechanics that we already knew.
Scott: Sort of mashed into one in an interesting way.
Scott: So here's how the game is.
Scott: The basic rundown, right?
Scott: First, you do a card draft like seven wonders where everyone has nine cards and you take one and you pass the rest to the left.
Scott: You take one and you pass to the left.
Scott: You take and eventually you're left with nine cards in front of you.
Rym: So you're constructing your deck based on an initial set.
Rym: And this drives the entire game.
Rym: Everything beyond this deck construction is just moving the mice.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you and everyone ends up with nine cards through a draft like seven wonders.
Scott: And those, you know, however many people are playing, this is going to be nine times over the three player game.
Scott: They'll be twenty seven cards.
Scott: The deck has a lot more than twenty seven cards.
Scott: So we actually we played it a few times now and we have probably not really experienced the depth of all the possible cards.
Rym: I, however, have won every game I've played and I've used.
Rym: I use different strategies.
Rym: It just didn't matter.
Rym: Oh, we'll get to my opinion in a minute.
Scott: But I'm I'm still running down the game and you're jumping ahead.
Rym: I'm just saying I'm increasingly sour on the game.
Rym: The more times I win it.
Scott: So anyway, you get these nine cards.
Scott: And here's the interesting part is you split them into three piles of three each.
Scott: The first three cards are your starting hand.
Scott: The second three are for part two and the third three are for part three.
Scott: So this is this beginning setup of the game forces you to create a long term plan where you say these are the cards I'm going to have in the second part of the game.
Scott: And these are the cards you have in the third part of the game.
Scott: You know, you really have to long term think right from the get go.
Scott: What are you going to do in this game?
Scott: And you can look at those cards later.
Scott: You just can't pick them up until the time is right.
Scott: So you really you know, a lot of games you just sort of get a starting hand and you make a decision based on what's going on on that turn.
Scott: And you don't really have to think too much about the future.
Scott: or you maybe there's a game like chess.
Scott: You have to look at the future, but you're looking at what's possible in the future.
Scott: And this one, you already know a lot of the future, right?
Scott: Because you planned that future and now you have to make that happen.
Scott: So if you set up a bad future for yourself from the beginning, it's going to be very hard to make it happen no matter what you do now to to balance that up a good future.
Scott: Then you still have to be able to make it happen, considering all the other things that other players in my opinion, the decisions as to what to put in one, two, three and also what cards to choose.
Scott: Relatively obvious, trivial.
Scott: Yeah, it's not too hard mostly because there's not too many cards.
Rym: Now, more to the point, the real strategy, the game breaks down pretty quickly and that the real strategy is looking at the set of cards in the draft, anticipating what cards other players took,
Scott: remembering them and
Rym: will take and constructing your deck such that you will mitigate the cards they have.
Rym: Know they're coming, know the order they're going to put them in a win.
Rym: The problem is that is a very high effort for relatively little return.
Rym: And I frankly don't bother with that and still win every time I play.
Scott: So the next all two times you play.
Rym: Yeah, I won by so much both times.
Scott: So the next thing that happens is you start to play the actual game and it's what it does.
Scott: You have a rondel that goes around and it goes around the seasons of the year and just three years in the game.
Scott: So the second year is the second part.
Scott: in the third year is the third part.
Scott: So four seasons per year, three years per game, and each season has a set of dice.
Scott: And what you do is you roll those dice, you know, so if you're in winter, you roll blue dice.
Scott: If you're in summer, you roll yellow dice.
Scott: Everyone complains about this in their right to complain about it.
Scott: The guy who made this game is the one thing he fucked up.
Scott: He people confronted him on board game geek.
Scott: He is wrong.
Scott: Yes, he made summer and fire yellow and he made fall and autumn and air red.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: Why is the fire not red?
Rym: As a result, I refer to them purely as fires and feathers, and I ignore the colors.
Scott: I also ignore the colors.
Scott: But anyway, you roll the season dice associated with the season and then people each take one die.
Scott: So it's sort of a Puerto Rico situation.
Scott: I'll take the captain.
Scott: I'll take the craftsman only instead of taking, you know, these cards that are always available every time you roll dice.
Scott: So the thing you want might not be available.
Scott: So everyone picks a die that came up on in different seasons, you're on different dice, too.
Scott: So, you know, the thing you want might not be available that season at all.
Scott: And you got to get the game to go around.
Rym: Now, this ends up already in terms of review being it really influences the game too much.
Rym: Every both times I've played, I have had no more useful actions to take long before the end of the game.
Rym: And the only chance I will have of being able to make a further decision of any kind is if there happens to come up the option to draw another card to then play.
Scott: Yeah, one of the die, some of the die will allow you to draw another card.
Scott: So, you know, if you've already used all your cards, which can happen if you play pretty well or if you picked a bunch of cards that were easy to play at the beginning, then you really need that draw more card thing to happen, because there's really not much you can do in the game to score points besides transmute other than play cards.
Scott: It's really all about getting resources to be able to play the cards.
Scott: You roll dice and you need summoning, you need stars, you need all these different elements.
Scott: You basically need to collect resources from dice and other things in order to be able to put cards on the table.
Scott: And then what the cards do is sort of the whole game and as getting you victory points either in the forms of the cards themselves or crystals are also worth points.
Scott: And you basically go around three times doing this.
Rym: I found that cards worth a lot of victory points are way more useful than cards that do fucking anything.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And whoever gets the gauntlet that gives you a one discount and everything is pretty much guaranteed to win.
Scott: That card is ridiculously powerful because it basically makes everything easier to every card easier to play.
Scott: And being able to play all your cards is pretty much the hard thing to do in the game.
Scott: That's that's what you have to do to win.
Scott: So and you lose at the end of the game negative five points for every card you didn't play.
Scott: And you've got nine cards minimum to play.
Scott: Now, what's interesting is the people may make you forced you to draw more, which for me is great because I play them immediately if you've got the freaking glove, which I always do.
Scott: You've had twice.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So the thing is that this is where the game is interesting because it breaks a few of the sort of standard assumptions of games and standard limitations, especially of card games, kind of like how Dominion got rid of the.
Rym: I have a hand of cards and I kind of play one card at a time or, you know, I have a limited number of actions.
Rym: Dominion, you play your whole fucking hand every turn.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And when I first played Dominion, that was a big deal.
Rym: That was like that was like doing something.
Scott: first played him in your enemy, Boston.
Scott: We were like, fuck this shit.
Scott: The second time you played Dominion.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But it was like this forbidden thing.
Rym: It was.
Rym: it was refreshing because there's always the thing you want to do in games that games never let you do because the mechanics tend to break down.
Rym: This game does that in this sense.
Rym: You can play as many goddamn cards as you can possibly spend mana on.
Rym: or energy tokens?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's the vocabulary.
Scott: This game is a little weird.
Scott: Crystals, energy tokens.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And some of them are gauges, but some of them are meters.
Scott: By the way, the story of this game is that you're a bunch of wizards and you're all competing to see who's going to become the archmage.
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: And it's a three year wizard's duel.
Rym: Good thing Kvothe didn't show up.
Scott: That's another thing.
Scott: There's two different kinds of cards is purple and orange.
Scott: Purple cards are magic items.
Scott: So when you play those, they're generally just boosts to you.
Scott: Those are the cards you really want to play a lot of.
Scott: But there's also these orange cards which are all familiars and they all have creature themes, you know, that's like so and so the destroyer or whatever.
Scott: All of those cards sort of damage everybody else at the table and they usually damage everybody else to the table relatively equally.
Scott: So you can't sort of target the guy in the lead to do any king making.
Scott: If you want to fuck people over, you fuck over everyone but yourself with the orange familiar card.
Rym: So the game has no direct fucking, as we call it, or as Richard Garfield calls it, politics.
Scott: Yes, but it does have that sort of interaction.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, I mean, you saw most of the cards during the draft.
Scott: Not all of them, obviously, but most of them, whether you took them or not.
Scott: So you know that someone has, you know, whatever card you passed to the left.
Scott: So you know that, you know, that's going to come around at some point, like the air elemental, which no one.
Rym: it was the end of the game.
Rym: I only had a couple of cards left in my hand.
Rym: None of you expected me to do that.
Scott: I knew the air elemental was coming eventually.
Scott: It just came in a really bad time.
Rym: I didn't even care about the attack.
Rym: I only played it because it's worth a bunch of victory points.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: My strategy to win this game is simple.
Rym: I get cards that help me play more cards or that are worth a bunch of victory points.
Scott: And are easy to play.
Rym: And otherwise, I just move my mice.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There really isn't too much to think about.
Rym: Well, no, there are things you can do to... You can spend a lot of mental effort that is not terribly fun.
Rym: to have a slight edge.
Rym: For example, Scott played a card, fuck you, that went around the table for the whole rest of the game.
Scott: When I played at Nerd NYC, two of those went around the table at the same time.
Rym: The problem is that card is only effective if you count out the modulus math of when it's going to hit different people and what resources will be available.
Scott: Usually it hits anyone who, A, doesn't have water, right?
Scott: So you can play it after everyone has used their water or there won't be water for another couple of seasons.
Scott: Or B, it hits the first player, because even if the first player has water, when it'll get to them, their turn is already passed.
Scott: So they can't do anything to get rid of it again because they've already done their stuff this turn.
Scott: So they get hit.
Scott: They pass it to the left the next turn with their water.
Scott: And then the next player to the left of them is obviously the new first player.
Scott: So they're stuck with it now.
Rym: So you could count it out and figure out and plan and make that card be fairly effective.
Rym: But for example, Phil passed it to me and then a card came out that we were forced to give up, you know, take back a discard or sacrifice a card we had out.
Rym: So I sacrificed the fucking monster and kept all my real cards.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So in a way, that card to be beneficial, it's also a very beneficial card.
Rym: There is no way to plan on that beneficial effect unless you spend an unreasonable amount of unfun brain effort.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's also that card.
Scott: Just to add to it, right, if you're the person who plays the card, not only can you easily immediately pass it off at the beginning, but it gives you a huge bonus when you immediately play it in the form of I think it might put your summoning gauge up one, but I know it gives you 10 crystals.
Scott: So it's not a bad if you just play it, it's already helping you and hurting everyone else.
Rym: Yeah, except it's almost guaranteed to come around and hurt you very soon.
Scott: Even if it comes around and hurts you, you're still better off than everyone else.
Rym: The other thing that makes the game interesting, but kind of bad, is that you have crystals are victory points and you can spend crystals to do stuff.
Rym: And a lot of attacks remove crystals from you so you can remove victory points from other.
Scott: people will take crystals from you.
Rym: The problem is I tend to play decks where, well, strategies, and it seems very effective where I hover around zero and these attacks don't hurt me at all.
Rym: So basically at every round, there was a thing happening where everyone's losing four victory points, except me, because I had zero victory points on the board.
Rym: My victory points were all in cards.
Rym: As a result, I was effectively gaining four victory points on everyone except the person doing that action every round.
Scott: Yeah, there are very few cards that and I think there's actually a problem with the cards, at least when I've played, there are very few cards that attack the cards of other players.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And when they do, they're always like everyone picks a card to take back into their hand.
Scott: There's no counter spells.
Scott: There's no randomly, you know, I mean, the worst thing that you can do is make everyone draw.
Scott: And it only hurts people who are having a hard time playing who are already losing.
Scott: If somebody is winning, drawing a card for them is great.
Scott: So it's like it's not necessarily a negative.
Scott: There's.
Scott: no you know, there's nothing.
Scott: that's like you choose a card from everyone else's pile or everyone must sacrifice a card.
Scott: That is, you know, there's some cards that are negative, like the one we just talked about that are negative victory points.
Scott: So forcing everyone to sacrifice a card could be good or bad for opponents.
Scott: There is no universal way that I found there might be one I haven't seen.
Scott: that hurts everyone other than you in the cards as opposed to in the crystals.
Rym: Now, my real kind of core problem with the game is just that you have so few options.
Rym: It is likely as in I'd say there's about a 30 percent chance on any given time it is your turn, that there is literally no action you can take and you just pass.
Rym: I pass easily a third of the turns I take in this game because there's just nothing you can do.
Rym: You take some crystals.
Rym: You don't have the little transmute icons.
Scott: You can't do that and you don't want to use your superpower because you lose victory points.
Scott: You don't have your summoning gauges at max.
Scott: You can't play any cards.
Scott: So you take your energy tokens and your turns over.
Rym: Just fucking sit there.
Rym: A lot of times I have no cards in my hand, but at least it makes the game go around quickly.
Rym: No, it doesn't.
Rym: People take for fucking ever on their turn.
Scott: Well, that's the thing, right?
Scott: Is that on the one hand, it's quick to decide what to do on your turn, but it's slow because you eventually have a lot of cards in front of you and everyone has cards in front of them that are always doing stuff like.
Scott: this card does this whenever this happens.
Scott: So even though you quickly decided on my turn, I'm going to take two forests and pass.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Someone else is like, wait a minute.
Scott: When this happens, this card does this and this card does that.
Scott: And that ends up being.
Scott: where all the time gets taken up is all this management and remembering of cards that do things.
Rym: So while the game is relatively simple and should be relatively quick to play, it does have interesting mechanics that other games do not have and has a light strategic depth because complex strategy is difficult to enact and not terribly fun to enact.
Rym: The problem is the nature of this game with all the proper noun cards with tons of text on them and different effects means that the majority of the people you would ever play this game with will take for fucking ever on their turn.
Rym: You cannot play this with people who take time on their turn.
Scott: I played it at Nerd NYC and it took longer than any game I've ever played at Nerd NYC and the one other smart guy I was playing with said the same thing.
Scott: And we were playing with the two other people just like didn't really get it.
Scott: And the game took so long.
Scott: It says on the box one hour.
Scott: It is a one hour game.
Scott: They really only play tested this, I think, with people who knew how to fucking play card games like CCGs and things.
Rym: Well, here's what I think is going on.
Rym: The people who take too long on their turn, it's a fairly simple problem that it's not specific to this game.
Rym: It's universal.
Rym: In my experience, anyone who takes a long time on their turn in board games typically does not have the sort of generic aptitude for discarding clearly bad decisions or clearly bad choices.
Rym: They have very poor, to use a Garfield term, they have personally very poor directional heuristics and he's end up computing all the different possibilities.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Because he said a beginner in a game is very likely to not notice a lot of the options.
Scott: They'll only know about a few things they can do.
Scott: So their turn is quick because they only can see three ways to go and they pick one of them.
Scott: A really advanced player can see all the different ways to go, but knows that 90 percent of the ways to go are completely meaningless.
Scott: So also has pretty much like a two or three choices and picks one quickly.
Rym: Like in chess, I know not to start with the Polish Open.
Scott: Right.
Rym: As much as I like.
Scott: It's the intermediate players.
Scott: They can see all the choices, but they don't know that most of those choices are completely stupid and useless.
Scott: They're considering each and every one, even though they're not able to just quickly and swiftly say, yeah, none of those are good ideas.
Scott: There's really only two good ones.
Scott: So they take for fucking ever.
Scott: And that's the kind of person you're going to find at board game night.
Rym: Now, it's funny because if you go to a convention like packs, there's fewer of those people because most of the people in tabletop are either before that point in their board gaming career or after that point.
Rym: It's like that point only exists in quantity in like local board gaming groups that meet up somewhere.
Rym: But it's an intractable problem, which is why this game fails in the sense that the strategy level is perfect for people at that level.
Rym: But because of all the text and all the fiddliness, those are the people who take the longest on their turns, thus making it an unbearable game to play.
Scott: I think this game could do well, right.
Scott: If they were, you know, they sort of changed it up a little bit, you know, mathematically, right.
Scott: Like if you had more cards, if there were if there were different cards of more variety.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And if, you know, you didn't you weren't penalized so heavily for not playing every single freaking card, you know, then the game would be more dynamic as you went around, as opposed to just sort of after you plan the game, it's a race to play all your cards and whatever they do, they do.
Scott: And also the drafting thing at the beginning, I want to experiment with this.
Scott: It's everyone draws nine and everyone ends with nine.
Scott: Why not draw fifteen and end with nine?
Rym: Sure, you'll get more powerful.
Rym: Everyone will.
Rym: Maybe it'll be a Dune situation then.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or why not do something like, you know, you know, everyone gets, you know, you know, twelve.
Scott: And, you know, you can either take one and put it in front of you or you can take one and throw it out of the game.
Scott: or, you know, you can make.
Scott: if you mix up that draft at the beginning, then I think people would end up with a lot more interesting.
Scott: or maybe like everyone draws, you know, some number of cards, you give one to yourself and you give one to someone else to start with and then and then you pass.
Scott: I think a lot of things we mixed up in that draft phase such that, you know, and then so someone gave you a card during the draft.
Rym: You look because the draft phase is basically 80 percent of the game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So now if you mix up that draft phase a little bit and you had different cards or more of them or whatever, someone gives you a card during the draft, it's going to be in your hand.
Scott: You've got to play it during the game.
Scott: So now when you get the next set to pick from, you see a really awesome card in there.
Scott: You would have picked otherwise, but now you've got to pick a different one because it'll help you deal with the shitty card someone else gave you that you're stuck with.
Scott: So and then you end up handing that other really good card to the next guy and so on and so forth.
Rym: So I think if I had to recommend this game, I would actually recommend you not buy it.
Rym: Yeah, I say you I say generically because if you're the kind of people I would recommend this game to, like I said, are the people who, you know, the sort of novice board gamers, it's like a light game.
Rym: you can play relatively quickly.
Rym: But odds are you're going to end up playing with people who will take so long on their turns that you will hate this game.
Rym: And if you're an advanced board gamer, the only time you should buy this game is if you are bored and you've played every game you already own to death and you're looking for something novel.
Rym: That's really.
Scott: Yeah, that's really the biggest benefit of this game is the artwork and the novelty of this combination of mechanics that, you know, are some of which are in other games, but really aren't all together in one place.
Scott: And you will learn something by playing it.
Scott: if you're big into games, which we did learn something from it.
Scott: Things the other.
Scott: one more thing I say about this game is that the the boxing of this game is the most wasted space of any game ever.
Scott: It's like a deck of cards, a bag of chips and a few boards, and it's in a giant full sized box that has got to be at least 80, 90 percent air.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This needs a reboxing so hard, harder than any game I've ever owned.
Scott: So if you're the kind of person who wants a game that doesn't take up a lot of space, this is a good game to get because you can rebox it.
Scott: But if you keep the original box, man, this game is going to eat up your whole freaking shelf for no reason at all.
Scott: And I hate that.
Scott: And I wish people would stop that.
Rym: So, yeah, and as a result, there are so few people I can recommend this game for that I actually, despite relatively enjoying it, have to say that I would not recommend anyone by this game.
Scott: I'm trying to think of any group to recommend it to.
Scott: And the only one I can think of right is if you are someone who or delete this.
Scott: No.
Scott: If you are somebody who wants to sort of move over into the European board gaming situation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you want to learn some of these mechanics like action taking and but you come from a CCG kind of background like that.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Then where you're going, if you take back my right, if you're a CCG person, this could be a transition game into the euro board gaming world because it has both aspects combined.
Rym: But what I would say to you there is harden the fuck up and just play El Grande.
Scott: Of course, of course.
Scott: But, you know, that at least, you know, what other game does that really?
Rym: Yeah, that's that's the only thing I could recommend it to.
Scott: I mean, I'd grickle a little bit.
Rym: Either that or if you're a bored elitist in board games like us.
Scott: If anyone wants a copy of Seasons, I'm likely only to play it a few more times.
Rym: If I'm going to make another recommendation, this is a good game.
Rym: If you are someone who really enjoys German board games or board games in general, have played a lot of them, have started to understand them and want to design your own games.
Rym: Use this game to see some mechanics that don't really work that well and kind of follow through a game and try to identify like where it fails and see if you can come up with ways to fix it.
Scott: It's a game that is, you know, it has problems, but it's not one of those games that's like, oh, so obviously broken.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Like Mario Kart or or what was that board game we had with the Greek guys?
Scott: Well, that was just poorly written rules.
Scott: Yeah, that wasn't I think that game.
Scott: If you if you figured out the rules, actually not so bad.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: But Helis, Helis, but this game is a game that's like just slightly problematic.
Scott: So if you really want to learn a lot about game design and a lot of the pros and cons of all the different mechanics it uses, they're all only slightly broken.
Scott: And only someone who's really learned a lot about games will be able to see the flaws in this.
Scott: I think a lot of people will play this game and who aren't like us and will think it's kind of pretty great.
Rym: And I can.
Scott: I can anticipate it at all.
Rym: I had the entire discussion I would have with certain unnamed people about this game where they would tell me that, one, I haven't solved the game, that I'm not.
Rym: I'm giving it a shot.
Rym: I solved it in the sense that I'm giving it a short shrift.
Rym: And they would say that it's much more strategically complex than I give it credit for.
Scott: Maybe if you added a fistful of extra cards.
Rym: Well, there is depth there.
Rym: The problem is it's dota depth.
Rym: It's it's depth that is not enjoyable to explore, nor is it analogous to the game itself.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.