Rym: It's Wednesday, February 29th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk about Sailor Moon, the Super S movie.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: As opposed to, you know, the Super S show or all the other, anyway.
Scott: R, S, Q, P.
Rym: There's no Q.
Scott: Are you sure?
Rym: So we got some friends coming out this weekend.
Rym: It's basically, there may or may not be much GeekNights next week, because I'm flying to India for a week.
Rym: Leaving like Saturday.
Rym: And we got some friends coming out right before that.
Scott: Give the great tiger my regards.
Rym: They're coming, of all things, for a yoga tournament.
Rym: And I realize that I cannot conceive...
Scott: Wait, a yoga tournament?
Scott: As in yoga, fire, yoga, flame.
Rym: I'm assuming that this is basically a street fight, because I cannot conceive of any other sort of yoga competition.
Scott: I know yoga, and I can respect some kinds of yoga that aren't full of magical bullshit, you know.
Scott: But it's like, how do you compete at that?
Scott: Is it like, who can stay in the hot room the longest without passing out?
Scott: Is it who can do the hardest position?
Scott: It can do...
Rym: I think it's who can beat the other guy to death with yoga catastrophes first.
Scott: Is it like, who does the positions better?
Scott: You know, is it like with a little score rating system, like figure skating?
Scott: Like, oh, 9.8, 9.7, you know?
Scott: Is it... Like, how does that freaking work?
Scott: Is it like horse, where it's like, I do a yoga, then you have to do it?
Scott: That'd be a good tournament.
Rym: Actually, you know what?
Scott: Then you do a yoga, then I have to do it?
Rym: It's impractical simply for the fact that no one is a video game renaissance man anymore, because there's too many genres.
Rym: I'd love to see you in a megathon around, or a finale that was video game horse.
Rym: Like, each candidate gives them like, here are the 10 horse things I will present to the other person.
Scott: No, pick like 10, or some odd number, 9.
Scott: You know, direct versus 1 versus 1 games that are short.
Scott: And you have to win 5 out of 4 rounds, and it's like, street fighter, go!
Scott: Then it's like, so it's a fighting game, then it's like, you know, some other, you know, racing game, go!
Rym: I was thinking more like, you pick, you know...
Scott: Othello, go!
Rym: Within a constrained set, you're like, alright, you know, just like they do for trick pool tournaments.
Rym: I will beat ball bull with only using jabs.
Rym: Right, jabs.
Rym: And then you do it, and then the other guy has to do the same thing.
Scott: The thing is, it was just the person who made the challenge would maybe sometimes fail, you know, and the person who was being challenged would hardly ever be able to succeed.
Rym: Yeah, it works better in trick pool, because there's a very constrained set of pool skills.
Rym: So maybe you set it to like, one game.
Scott: Still, yoga tournament?
Scott: I mean, I could look this up on the internet to figure out how competitive yoga works.
Rym: But I'm just going to assume that it's street fighter.
Scott: But it's much more fun to make fun of it than to look it up.
Scott: Though I probably will look it up when I get home.
Rym: Yoga flame.
Scott: Yoga flame.
Rym: So it's Wednesday, and you know, sadly, a couple of people have pointed out in the forums, we haven't talked about a lot of anime recently.
Scott: There really hasn't been a lot of anime recently.
Rym: Well, there has been, but the last anime I watched was Madoka Magica.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The last anime I watched before that, I'm still kind of watching Fist of the North Star, but I'm reading Drops of God.
Rym: I'm playing a lot of video games lately.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: It's not anime season.
Scott: No, it really isn't.
Scott: Another thing I noticed, right, is that, I've been reading, instead of Anime News Network, the Crunchyroll news, I think has been, you know, mostly the same, but also a little bit better.
Scott: Nah.
Scott: Right?
Scott: But there was an article on there, this isn't my news, this is just relevant, right?
Scott: This is Japanese fans name the most needed anime sequels, right?
Rym: Wait a minute, wait a minute, I wonder, before you tell me, what- So they had a poll, and it's almost 2,000.
Scott: Japanese fans name the anime series most in need of a sequel.
Rym: Because I want to see the same thing in the US, because I, if I had to say something, it's literally Ghost in the Shell Stand Alone Complex is all I want.
Rym: Crap, wait a minute, anyway- No, I don't want, I don't actually want more Cowboy Bebop, because I know why.
Scott: But the point is, if you look at this list, it's like, Angel Beats is number one.
Scott: What?
Scott: Ha-ru-si-suzumi is two.
Rym: I could see that, I could see that, I could watch more of that.
Scott: Natsume Yuu-jin Show is three.
Scott: Working with an exclamation point is four.
Scott: Clannad, After Story, then K-On, then Full Metal Panic, Second Raid, which is a sequel, so I guess they want another sequel, Minami-kei, Squid Girl, Zansayonara Zetsubo Sensei, The World, God Only Knows, My Ordinary Life, Usagi Drop, Sekirei, Rosen Maiden, Genshiken 2, Initial D, Fourth Stage- No, you don't need- Toradora, Okami-san,
Rym: The Strongest
Scott: Disciple, Kenichi, Banner of the Stars 3, Spicenwolf 2, Strike Witches, Elfin'
Rym: Lead,
Scott: right?
Scott: And it's like, most of the animes, if you look at those JPEGs that show you all the animes coming out, most of them we don't give a shit about.
Scott: All I want, now here's the thing- Madoka 2, I take that, but that isn't on the list, they don't want Madoka 2.
Rym: I wouldn't want Madoka 2 either-.
Rym: Well, here's the thing, I don't want Madoka 2, the same reason I don't want Cowboy Bebop 2.
Scott: I'll take Madoka 2.
Scott: However- More than I'll take Angel Beats 2.
Rym: What did Cowboy Bebop do to get around that?
Rym: They set the movie in the middle of the show with no ramifications outside.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But if there was a Madoka sequel, I'd actually want it to be a prequel.
Rym: I want to see like, imagine if they did a Madoka OAV or something.
Scott: Well, I mean, I would call the show Magical Homura.
Rym: Well, there's two ways to handle this.
Rym: You go for the fan fulfillment, which is Homura the Badass kicking ass all around the world.
Scott: That's right, the name of the show would be Magical Badass Homura, the end.
Rym: But my real serious suggestion would be another show, like 13 episodes, and maybe it's 13 vignettes, maybe a few two-parters in there.
Scott: Well, they wanted to make, you know, Happy School Days Madoka.
Rym: No, don't do that!
Scott: That's what they wanted, that's what the guy said he was thinking about making.
Scott: Cause he didn't get enough school days in the regular Madoka.
Rym: That's the worst possible idea.
Rym: Short of showing me all the bad endings.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: But what I would do is, you know, I have a show that's prequels, and every episode is some magical girl from some point in history.
Rym: Because this goes, you know, not to spoil stuff, but I... You just did.
Rym: I spoiled a little bit, I didn't spoil the real spoils.
Rym: I want to see like, the Cleopatra magical girl, and the Greek magical girl, and the Indian magical girl.
Scott: Well, you can watch Tezuka's Cleopatra.
Rym: I could.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: But that's what I would do.
Scott: But the point is, just the reason that there's not so much new animes, is cause the Japanese fans don't like good animes.
Scott: They're making too many Moe shows, not making enough good shows.
Rym: The Japanese fans who care enough to respond to online polls about said thing.
Scott: I know, but the point is, it seems like if you look at those JPEGs that say what anime are they coming out, most of them are...
Rym: Scott, go to the average American, and do an online poll that only targets people who are super into American comics, and ask them what superhero needs another comic.
Scott: Then explain why most of the animes coming out are targeting this market.
Rym: Uh, partly because that is probably a cheap and easy market to target.
Scott: Anyway, you get the idea.
Scott: What new animes are coming out that aren't Moe crap?
Scott: Ghost in the Shell, Stand Alone, Gold Bricks, third gig.
Scott: That's actually coming out.
Rym: It's coming.
Rym: I gotta be optimistic here.
Rym: I'd love to see that survey on American anime fans.
Scott: I would also.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So here's some actual news, right?
Scott: And I learned something from this news.
Scott: There are some mangas that have been on hiatus or away for various reasons.
Rym: Like every super long running series that did Mend?
Scott: That they're coming back.
Scott: Bastard is coming back.
Rym: March 19th.
Rym: That's bad, because the fact that Bastard was on hiatus meant that there was a chance I could somehow catch up.
Scott: Arakawa, Under the Bridgy Bridge, coming back.
Rym: I kind of want to watch and/or read that.
Scott: Saint Young Men, that's the one with Buddha and Jesus.
Scott: Also coming back.
Scott: You know why?
Scott: I didn't know this.
Scott: I learned something.
Scott: Arakawa, Under the Bridge, and Saint Young Men.
Scott: Same person.
Scott: She was on maternity leave.
Scott: What?
Scott: I didn't know that either.
Scott: I didn't know that, but now I do.
Scott: And I started reading Saint Young Men on scans because she apparently people have tried to license it and she refuses.
Scott: She doesn't want anyone to put it out in different countries.
Scott: So I've been reading it illegally, whatever.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: And it's kind of awesome.
Scott: It's Buddha and Jesus, their roommates in Japan.
Rym: Emily's got it, because she can read Japanese.
Scott: Yeah, it's coming back.
Scott: Because again, maternity leave, she's done.
Scott: With the babying, right?
Scott: And you know what else is coming back?
Scott: You're not going to believe this one, right?
Rym: Elf Princess Rain.
Rym: No.
Scott: The mystery adventure series Master Keaton ran in big comic original for 18 volumes and now it's returning.
Scott: According to the band on volume 8, the series we released Keaton will be returning with Master Keaton remaster set 20 years after the original.
Rym: What?
Rym: Whoa, whoa.
Scott: I want to read this.
Scott: Whether this will be an ongoing or one shot has not been specified.
Rym: Don't care.
Rym: Want to read.
Scott: Won't be in English.
Scott: Well, I mean, I haven't read the irregular mangas.
Rym: Yeah, but I saw the cartoon and that's good enough.
Rym: The problem is, nobody in America likes Master Keaton except us.
Scott: Right, but the thing here, right, is like, okay, so there's some mangas coming back from hiatus.
Scott: This isn't really enough to say there's a trend here, especially since two out of the four are, you know, one person.
Scott: It is if there's no other news.
Scott: Right, but I mean, like, is there a trend of like old mangas coming back you know, for a reprise or encore or is or is this just, you know, a coincidence?
Scott: okay, these four and it's not really a trend or something that's going to happen a lot.
Rym: I'm going with coincidence and call me back if Ranma starts up again.
Scott: Yeah, because I mean, it could be that like, you know, the manga publishers in Japan are like man, these new mangas aren't doing so well.
Scott: Let's go and get the creators of the old manga to sort of start them up again and maybe that will sell better to the nostalgia crowd.
Scott: You know, that could be a thing that happens.
Scott: I don't know if it's happening right now.
Rym: I'm not sure.
Scott: I don't know either, but it's a possibility.
Rym: Because like, Bastard is a very kind of special odd case.
Rym: We could do, we should do a show on Bastard.
Scott: We have to watch Bastard again.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, well, we should read some too.
Rym: Oh my god, let's watch Bastard again and do a show on it.
Rym: I haven't seen Bastard since it was like 3 am at RIT.
Scott: Have you ever done a show on Gokudo?
Rym: Gokudo?
Rym: I don't think we ever did a show on it.
Rym: We didn't even finish Gokudo.
Rym: We should.
Rym: We watched like the first eight episodes.
Scott: It kind of, you know, it started out pretty fun and then it was less fun as he kept going.
Rym: As things go.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, so speaking of reading and watching things illegally, Oricon had a, Oricon Communications had a questionnaire where they asked people stuff about media.
Rym: and supposedly in Japan based on these responses, 28 and a half percent of Japanese middle and high school students have illegally downloaded.
Scott: Well, did they, I mean, admitted to legally downloading?
Scott: because it was a survey.
Rym: I point out that I'm really interested in this.
Rym: So, alright, 28 percent have ever downloaded anything illegally.
Rym: Either that number is completely wrong or Japan is way different from the rest of the world because I think in America the survey answer would actually be like 99 percent.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, that's a survey.
Scott: There's people admitting to it, right?
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time it's weird because I'll admit to stuff.
Scott: But also you've got to remember how many people are even internet-y, right?
Scott: So it's like all the non-internet-y people are, you know, that's probably more than half right there.
Scott: But a hundred percent of the internet-y people definitely.
Scott: And then there's people who don't realize, you know, so it's...
Rym: Japan's copyright law actually changed and I didn't even know this.
Scott: Yeah, they're like arrest people for shit.
Scott: It's crazy.
Rym: No, so they changed the law and apparently it is actually illegal to download copyrighted material, which has never really been proven to be illegal in the US.
Rym: Only distribution has been gone after.
Rym: But in Japan they go after consumption.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Which is interesting.
Scott: Like if you download some, you know, animes in Japan, you could go to jail.
Scott: Like criminal, not they need to sue you, but like the police will just come after you.
Scott: And they're like watching the internet.
Scott: It's crazy.
Rym: But at the same time, they're also really...
Scott: Singapore too.
Scott: Singapore is just as bad in their respect.
Rym: Japan's also really down on re-importation, which is, you know, basically legal, and yet undercuts their domestic production almost as much.
Rym: No, I would argue it doesn't anymore because hardly anything's getting released in the US.
Scott: Plus remember, this also is only counting teenagers.
Scott: So like, are the 30 year olds downloading a lot more than the 20 year olds than the, you know, 13 to 18 year olds?
Rym: I also I really wonder what the actual rates are, because like I said, in America, I think even people like age 30, 40 the rate is like 100%.
Rym: Because one of the first things my parents asked me...
Scott: Of internetty people.
Rym: When we got broadband was, so how do I download music?
Scott: Those people at the jury duty who didn't even read a book while they were there and just stared at the TV?
Scott: They're not downloading anything illegally, and they're the majority.
Rym: You know, you say that, but they probably have like an iPod, like an old one or something, and they probably just download stuff.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: It's possible.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I did not know this existed, and Emily the other day was like, "Hey, this is a
Rym: thing.".
Rym: And I was like,
Rym: "What?".
Rym: So apparently, when Deke got the rights to Sailor Moon in the US back in the day, one of the options they considered was to not actually release Sailor Moon as it was in Japan, and to just take the characters and make their own show.
Scott: Why would you do that?
Scott: It would cost money to make your own show, but if you just take the show that already exists, it doesn't cause nearly as much money to just put it out there.
Rym: Because one, the licensing cost probably would have been less.
Rym: Two, they then would not have had to localize and westernize and dumb down and all the stuff that they ended up having to do with the Sailor Moon because they wanted to pretend it wasn't in Japan, and pretend that it wasn't actually, you know, a show for slightly older girls.
Scott: Why didn't they just let it be in Japan?
Rym: Scott, you really, really asked that.
Rym: That's how people have been.
Rym: So anyway, not only were they going to remake it and reanimate it, but they were only going to reanimate half of it, because the other half was live action.
Scott: Well, that was the trend in those days, right?
Scott: You could save a lot of money by making a show, you know, partially live action in a lot of these cheap filler scenes, and then using other stuff for the rest.
Rym: Like, Power Rangers.
Scott: Power Rangers in the US.
Scott: You have some English US actors act out these in-between scenes.
Rym: And then an unrelated Sentai show.
Scott: Then you just dub over this other Sentai show for the fighting monster scenes.
Scott: Or, you know, a lot of VR Troopers, same kind of thing.
Scott: Superhuman Samurai, Cyber Squad, same thing.
Rym: So, what's amazing is that in 1995 at Anime Expo, that's before I knew anime cons existed, someone showed the only screening I have ever been able to find.
Scott: The thing I don't understand is why would you show this to anime fans at Anime Expo?
Rym: I think the reason is apparent.
Rym: The audience is dumbstruck by this thing.
Rym: It's pretty amazing.
Rym: So, bonus points about this are that 1.
Rym: Sailor Moon is also in a wheelchair, and the cast is diverse to a degree that would make Captain Planet cringe at the political correctness.
Rym: But she can walk around just fine in the animated part, but she has a wheelchair mech in that part.
Rym: And I think the icing on the cake is that they made them literal sailors sailing things through space.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, because kids wouldn't understand.
Scott: Like, "She's called Sailor Moon.
Scott: How come she doesn't have a
Scott: boat?".
Rym: It's... This is pretty dangerous.
Rym: This is anime hell territory.
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty sure this has already been in anime hell, and we just weren't at that anime hell.
Rym: Yeah, the number of views on this video is pretty low, so, uh...
Scott: There might have been other times posted to YouTube.
Rym: I want to get the word out.
Rym: I want people to, uh, know that this is a thing, and that it is perhaps one of the worst things the world has ever seen.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So, my thing of the day is the best, right?
Scott: For many years, I have been looking for things like this, right?
Scott: And it has been hard to find things like this, which is something that was originally English, but was dubbed in some other country.
Scott: Because other countries tend to just sort of subtitle.
Scott: True.
Scott: And you only get the weird... And a lot of times, you get stuff like Turkish Star Wars, where it isn't even a dub.
Scott: It's just, like, some, you know, remake rip-off thing, right?
Scott: And, you know, it's kind of hard to find dubs of stuff from the US that is in other languages.
Scott: Uh, and at least, you know, even if you do find dubs, they're not that interesting.
Scott: Like, I watched Spanish ET once in high school and Spanish class.
Scott: Or, like, the Lion King.
Scott: Oh, it's middle school, not high school.
Rym: I watched the Lion King in French.
Rym: It's just perfect and in French.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right?
Scott: You know, but, I mean, there's nothing funny about that.
Scott: There's nothing good to go with, right?
Scott: So, here is, right, thanks to, I guess, I assume Patrick Massey is Crunchyroll News, right?
Scott: It was actually in a link to something from another story.
Scott: This is the Japanese dub of Star Wars, right?
Scott: Which is actually really good.
Scott: Like, you're watching it and you're like, "Damn, that is some good dubbing right
Scott: there.".
Scott: But, specifically, this video isn't just the Japanese dub of Star Wars.
Scott: It's specifically all 11 minutes and 18 seconds of Lando Calrissian screen time.
Scott: Uh-oh.
Scott: In the, uh, you know, Japanese Star Wars.
Scott: It's just all of Lando's screen time cut up out of the movies.
Rym: It's got the danger alert.
Rym: Something that hasn't gone off many times in my life is going out.
Rym: This is, this is edging into most territory right here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, so it's pretty much, you're watching all of Star Wars but only the Lando Calrissian parts in the Japanese dub.
Scott: There's no other modifications to this video whatsoever.
Rym: So, is the moral of this, that there are two options.
Rym: Either Japan found someone amazing to do that voice, or they actually did a good job with a black man's voice in Japanese.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So, uh, first of all, the dub is amazing overall.
Scott: Like, just watching it.
Scott: Like, oh, Leia.
Scott: Oh, and the C-3PO voice, and the Darth Vader voice is pretty good.
Rym: Overall.
Scott: Can you, can you guess at the reason that it is a Lando Calrissian?
Rym: Ah, all the Japanese are stupid.
Rym: I hate all Japanese.
Rym: Is it one of those situations?
Scott: The voice of Lando Calrissian in Japanese Star Wars is it?
Scott: Oh my God, it really is.
Scott: It absolutely is.
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: It is amazing.
Scott: So, is the greatest.
Rym: So, he is now actually my favorite voice actor.
Rym: My second favorite voice actor.
Scott: He is like Because it's pretty much uh, Koyasu, him, and uh, Akira Kamiya.
Scott: He doesn't talk to Yoda ever.
Scott: I know.
Scott: He doesn't even see Yoda.
Scott: Yoda's only ever talks to Luke.
Rym: That's some good stuff.
Scott: But yes, Norio Wakamoto is the voice of Lando Calrissian in Japan.
Scott: Does a great job.
Rym: Oh my gosh.
Scott: It's amazing.
Rym: So, in the meta moment, Easter weekend, which is coming up pretty soon.
Rym: We will be at the Pinair Gate Expo doing one lecture.
Rym: Let's play a money making game.
Scott: We will all be doing one.
Scott: Ten, thirty, fifty.
Rym: We will be doing one two hour classroom workshop on how to play some German style board games.
Scott: Ah, yeah.
Rym: And we will be at Anime Boston doing diamonds in the rough.
Scott: And eating dinner.
Rym: We will also be at the going cardboard uh, screening where we will say hi.
Rym: Hi.
Rym: To people who want to say hi to us.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Otherwise, we're pretty much going to be in tabletop playing games the entire time.
Scott: Except for like an hour in the expo hall or something.
Rym: And an hour or so at the Whiskey Priest.
Rym: And the illegal test kitchen.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Other meta things.
Scott: Do we have a new book club book?
Rym: Uh, yes we do.
Rym: But I'll announce that in the separate book club episode.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Do we have internets?
Scott: We do.
Scott: You should visit us on the internets.
Scott: A lot of people, they subscribe to this show on iTunes or something.
Scott: They listen to it maybe.
Scott: But they never visit us on the internets.
Scott: Well, we have internets.
Scott: You should go to twitter.com/geeknights.
Scott: You should go to Google Plus GeekNights, Facebook dot.
Scott: com slash forum dot.
Rym: front row crew dot.
Rym: com.
Rym: Our forum's pretty fucking rocking.
Scott: You can also go to just front row crew dot.
Scott: com.
Scott: You can go to all kinds of places.
Scott: Just search for Front Row Crew or GeekNights on the Google.
Scott: Whatever part of the internets you like to use, you can find us there.
Scott: And hook up with us and you will be well notified.
Rym: In particular, the GeekNights Rym YouTube channel, our official YouTube channel, has many of our panels and lectures throughout the recent years.
Rym: And I just uploaded a new video that if you weren't already going out of your mind waiting for PAX, this video is probably...
Scott: You know how many, there's only like 36 37 days till PAX East.
Rym: It's coming.
Scott: It's real close.
Scott: I gotta get that panel together.
Scott: I'm gonna do it this week.
Scott: I'm doing it this week.
Rym: I gotta get all the other panels together.
Scott: I'm doing it this weekend.
Scott: I'm putting together the money making game.
Scott: I know what the first slide is.
Rym: Old man.
Scott: Oh man, why you give me useless hint for 50?
Rym: So... So the other day, a conversation that I never thought would happen happened.
Rym: Scott comes to me and says, "Hey, we should do a show on Sailor
Rym: Moon.".
Scott: Well, the thing is, Rym is the biggest Sailor Moon nut there is.
Rym: No, that is not true.
Scott: He's a huge Sailor Moon nut.
Rym: I am not actually a big fan of Sailor Moon.
Scott: Yes, you are a gigantic fan of Sailor Moon.
Scott: And it's a very important anime in the US especially.
Scott: And we'd never done a show on it and we really needed some anime shows.
Scott: So I'm like, "Hey, that's a good show to do an episode on.
Scott: Let's watch some kind of Sailor Moon something.
Scott: Since you're such a big fan, you know what to watch.
Scott: Let's watch something and then do an episode on
Scott: it.".
Rym: Back in the day, I watched Vampire 100D when I was in fourth grade.
Rym: My little brother was in second grade.
Rym: And it was a big deal.
Rym: And I really got into anime.
Rym: And I watched all the anime Blockbuster.
Rym: And then what?
Rym: Like, then what do I do?
Rym: Go to Suncoast?
Rym: There's like four more shows to watch.
Rym: Now I've seen all that.
Rym: Now what?
Rym: So I eventually found fan subs.
Rym: And the first fan sub I ever got, I actually got tapes mailed to me of all of Sailor Moon.
Scott: A big show.
Scott: Every letter like regular Sailor Moon, S, R, Q, P, T.
Rym: I have VHS's made from the original laserdisc releases with English subtitles.
Scott: Of every single episode, OAV and movie of Sailor Moon ever?
Rym: In order?
Rym: Every bit of animation ever related to Sailor Moon directly is in fact on VHS format in boxes somewhere.
Scott: In your possession?
Rym: And the cases themselves had color print out scans of the laserdisc covers.
Rym: They are super pro.
Scott: Is this in, you know, you watch including the movie we just watched is also in there?
Rym: Uh, yes.
Rym: All three movies plus the special Ami-chan the Hopsicle.
Scott: How much did this cost you in those days?
Scott: $240.
Rym: That's pretty cheap.
Rym: For shipping and the cost of the tapes because I had to buy all the tapes.
Rym: Now I could have had him ship me SVHS's which would have been higher quality, but...
Scott: You need an SVHS player.
Rym: I had an SVHS player.
Rym: Whoa!
Rym: I was not confident I would have another one ever, nor was I confident that anyone would let me take that thing to college.
Rym: I don't even know where it is anymore.
Scott: I don't know either.
Scott: We had it in Beacon I think.
Rym: Uh, yeah we did but it didn't work that well.
Rym: Remember we also had that ghetto DVD player that we had to take the case off or it would overheat?
Rym: That we hacked to be region free and then never played a single region free disc ever?
Scott: Yeah, well because we had Video Barn which had broken with the discs were hacked so it didn't matter.
Rym: So Scott was like, "What should I
Rym: watch?".
Rym: and after a long sort of explanation of Sailor Moon R, S, Super S, stars, manga, movies I realized that there's no way I'll ever get Scott to watch all of Sailor Moon.
Scott: Yeah, no kidding.
Rym: And the thing is I'd love to get him to watch enough to do a show on Sailor Moon the way we did on Slayers but it's not going to happen anytime soon.
Rym: It's too much.
Rym: It's only 200 episodes.
Scott: Oh, only 200.
Scott: It's only more than Fist of the North Star.
Rym: That's all.
Rym: So rather than explain it or anything I figured let's just pick a movie.
Rym: So I took the three movies and I didn't really explain what they were.
Rym: I just offered Scott the following choice.
Rym: Do you want to watch the movie about the gay guy from space who comes down and fucks shit up?
Rym: The movie about candy?
Rym: Or the movie that's actually about the cat and the moon?
Scott: Well, I don't care about the cat and the moon.
Rym: That's actually the best one.
Scott: Well the other one sounds crazy, right?
Scott: So it's got to be one of the crazy ones.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So, I don't know.
Scott: We ended up with the candy one.
Scott: But it wasn't about candy.
Scott: It was about Pedobear.
Rym: No, it was about the Pedo Piper.
Rym: We're going to spoil the Sailor Moon Super-S movie.
Rym: You don't really You don't give a shit about that.
Rym: You should probably watch the movie.
Scott: No, you probably shouldn't.
Rym: So I learned some stuff about this movie because when I watched Sailor Moon you know, Young and Innocent I did not know yet who Kunihiko Ikuhara was.
Rym: Ikuhara, you know, Utena Craziness Pedophile.
Rym: Not a pedophile.
Rym: More of a hebophile as far as we can tell.
Rym: He would at least.
Scott: Oh, because that's so much better.
Rym: Yeah, it's arguably a little bit better.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: I'm not going to impinge upon his character because some of it's second hand.
Rym: Some of it's just obvious from listening to him in interviews.
Rym: He's an odd dude but he caused Utena to be made so I got to give him some respect.
Rym: But he was, you know, also deeply involved in Sailor Moon.
Rym: And apparently the Sailor Moon Super-S movie was originally going to be primarily about sailors Uranus and Neptune and have a basically totally different plot all about them.
Rym: And he left the series before that got made.
Rym: so they just dropped it all.
Rym: So this was not the movie that could've been.
Rym: I'm almost sad about that because Uranus and Neptune are pretty much the best characters in the show.
Rym: Let's talk about this movie.
Scott: So here's how this movie goes.
Scott: So you're sitting in this town, happy town, and suddenly this is, you know, Pied Piper but he's a Pied Piper of children bringing the children into his magical flying boat with promises of candy.
Scott: Pedo bear, pedo bear, pedo bear.
Scott: How can you not see the pedo?
Scott: He brings a whole town's full of children into his flying candy arc.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: That's really what the movie's about.
Scott: That's the central plot.
Scott: Of course, Sailor Moon and friends wake up to try and fight this shit.
Scott: Well, not originally.
Rym: A whole bunch of kids get abducted.
Scott: Well, in all their towns.
Scott: Yeah, all over the world.
Scott: Like, thousands of kids.
Scott: That's until they try to kidnap from the sailor town where the sailors live.
Rym: So immediately I realized...
Scott: The thing is, if they're supposed to be protecting the whole solar system they can't even protect...
Rym: No, no they're not.
Scott: They can't even protect the other towns on Earth.
Scott: They can only protect their own town.
Scott: What the fuck is up with that?
Rym: Shortly in the movie, the first thing Scott asked me is, "How come none of these Sailor Scouts are competent at all?
Rym: Are any of them
Rym: smart?".
Rym: And that's pretty much when the Outer Senshi...
Scott: Even the computery one with the cool goggles and stuff was stupid.
Scott: It's like, they're sitting there, there's a bad guy and they're yelling at him and saying stuff and they're fighting the same minions over and over again.
Scott: And I'm like, "Just use all of your Sailor magical attacks at
Scott: once!".
Rym: But Scott, it is the deepest insult to Japanese culture.
Rym: you could ever have to use your full power immediately or at any point until the last possible second.
Scott: You obviously need to use your full power because children are getting abducted probably for raping.
Rym: I love how they don't even put much of an effort.
Rym: They see these massive kids walking toward this scary ark and they kind of stand in front of the kids like, "Hey, eh, don't go.
Rym: Eh, fuck it, let him
Rym: go.".
Scott: Not really all that much happens in this movie.
Scott: It's really, the amount of stuff that happens in this movie is about the same amount of stuff that would happen in a TV episode is just sort of dragged out with like, the pace is kind of slow.
Rym: Welcome to the Sailor Moon movies.
Scott: There's a lot of useless talking that doesn't advance the plot and a lot of scenes where it's like, there'll be these blue bad guys falling down at them and they'll attack them and it'll work.
Rym: Apparently those blue candy bomb bomb bomb babies!
Scott: Yeah, the bomb bomb babies will attack, they'll fight them off and then more will come and they'll fight them off and they'll kill like ten minutes just fighting bomb bomb babies.
Scott: eh, you know, fruitlessly.
Rym: Which apparently in this intergalactic like, fairy space civilization bomb bomb babies are actually the only weapon they have.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean even the cannon seems to shoot like, weaponized bomb bomb babies.
Scott: It's very strange.
Rym: I do also like how the intersenshi, the main Sailor Scouts pretty much fall for any trick.
Scott: Yeah, they're just dumb, they don't... They're fighting a candy monster that tricked children with promises of candy and then they got a scary ride boat.
Scott: And then the guy uses gingerbread house to fool them and it kinda works.
Rym: They're like, we're gonna stop you from tricking people with candy, oh hey look a gingerbread house, hey how come we're all babies now, who the fuck cares, candy!
Scott: It's like, oh my god you have magical attacking powers.
Scott: you just fucking transformed in a crazy transforming scene, use your super magical attack and defeat the bad guy, no we're just gonna stand here and get hit by bomb bomb babies.
Rym: What was more interesting is Chibi-Usa, you know the pink one, the little girl, is you know, she has this whole like, mechanon like childish, innocent romance with petal du du du, who's I guess the main good side character.
Scott: Right, there's like, you know, there's the three petal kidnappers, but then there's one person who's...
Rym: Well, the petal kidnappers.
Rym: one of them, Populin, is kinda normal.
Scott: Then there's like these two other ones that appear...
Rym: Banana and Orangin?
Scott: Banana and Orangin, which I looked at and I was like, oh my god, banana guy and orange guy.
Scott: oh my god.
Rym: I like the orange guy a lot.
Scott: They're in the movie for like a minute.
Scott: They're hilarious though.
Scott: They don't really say anything too much but they appear, and it's like, oh my god They pretty much go down like jumps.
Rym: They're hilarious.
Rym: Oh, don't forget Queen Badine.
Scott: Right, so that's basically it, the chief pedophile who is like, you know, cause there always has to be a square boss behind the regular bad guy.
Rym: Of course.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But you know, the pink haired one is kind of like like it's obvious she has this weird crush on, you know, Mamoru, sailor not sailor, Tuxedo Mask.
Rym: I keep, I always wanted like.
Rym: I'm never sure if I should say the English name or the Japanese, whatever.
Rym: And Scott points that out.
Rym: and then I realize suddenly something that I never noticed when I watched the show the first time how fucked up that is because Scott was bothered by it not knowing that that girl is actually his daughter from the future and everyone involved knows that.
Scott: I mean the fact that that's even what this plot is, is crazy.
Scott: That's like something fans would come up in a fanfiction.
Scott: I know it's amazing Scott.
Scott: The fact that that little chibi thing even exists is like she's totally seems like the kind of thing that would only exist in fanfiction and would never actually be in a show.
Scott: So it's like maybe that's actually sort of in some ways that and maybe other shows that have similar things are responsible maybe for the crazy shit in fanfiction because sometimes that shit happens in the actual canon.
Scott: It's like are you kidding me?
Rym: Are you kidding me?
Scott: This taught me something.
Scott: There's some tiny Sailor Moon with pink hair from the future who's like three years old and is the daughter of Sailor Moon.
Rym: She's like six or seven or eight.
Scott: Fine, she's six, seven or eight.
Scott: She's from the Sailor Moon's daughter from the future who went back in time.
Rym: The one who's three is called Chibi Chibi and is even smaller.
Scott: That's double fanfiction.
Rym: But no, she's actually the goddess of the universe.
Rym: Spoilers I guess.
Scott: That is fucked up shit right there.
Scott: That is fanfiction.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: What I realized and this is like a revelation because I happen to have seen all of Sailor Moon from an earlier Desperate Arrow.
Scott: You just happened to have seen it.
Scott: You didn't.
Scott: You went out of your way to see.
Scott: it is the truth.
Scott: It's not like you were sitting in a room and it just happened to be gone.
Rym: I just happened to scour the internet find a guy, call him on the phone get him to give me an address where I could mail him VHS tapes and he would then send me fan subs of a show from Japan.
Rym: I just happened to do that.
Scott: Yeah, I just happened to do that.
Rym: This was an era when I had seen literally every piece of anime I could get my grubby little meat hooks on.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I would have watched anything.
Rym: In fact, I watched some shit.
Rym: I watched Armageddon more than once.
Rym: No.
Rym: Doom Megalopolis, Wind of Amnesia.
Rym: Anyway, so I'm going to say right now that Sailor Moon, the expanded universe is basically Green Lantern, manga style.
Scott: I think it might even be worse even though I hesitate to say that anything could be worse.
Scott: It's equal at best.
Rym: Watching this movie which should be relatively like, alright Sailor Moon, you kind of know they have magical powers based on the planets and they fight crime.
Rym: You can deal with this.
Rym: Every question Scott would ask I would start to answer and realize that there was no way to answer that would make any sense to anyone who had not seen all the rest of this bullshit.
Rym: It's got to be like, who's that one?
Rym: Well, so that's the daughter of Sailor Moon and the tuxedo guy from the future.
Rym: when they re-found the empire.
Scott: but... What empire?
Scott: These are like high school girls who live in some town.
Rym: Oh yeah, because in the past before the show started there was another empire that collapsed and all those sailors are the reincarnated people from that empire.
Rym: And there was no way to answer any questions Scott had about this show basically.
Scott: Keep going.
Rym: But the best part was that at the peak of all the bomb bomb babies are kicking their asses in a tuxedo mask.
Rym: who is still to this day one of those ridiculous characters.
Scott: I don't understand this guy.
Scott: They have these people with magical powers and they're failing.
Scott: So this guy with no magical powers whatsoever.
Scott: It was just a human wearing a tuxedo, a top hat and a mask on his face.
Rym: He can throw a rose and he can hit you with his little cane.
Scott: He throws roses and he's just a dude.
Scott: he comes in and he actually tries to think he can help out the magical people who are failing.
Scott: That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
Scott: But at least, it's even dumber than Batman trying to help Superman, but at least he gets friggin' sent to the hospital.
Scott: That makes sense.
Scott: I was glad for that.
Scott: Because it's like yeah, normal guy can't do shit and he gets sent to the hospital.
Rym: So he does actually get powers and become a space knight at one point, but that stops happening.
Rym: Anyway, part of it too is that a lot of the weird things that happen in this movie and all the Sailor Moon movies, and they're all only an hour long, are basically like shout outs.
Scott: Yeah, that was.
Scott: the saving grace of this movie is that it was short.
Rym: They're shout outs and are callbacks to tropes of the show.
Rym: A trope of the show, especially early on, was Sailor Moon can't do shit and doesn't know what to do.
Rym: And then Tuxedo Mask appears and says, "Sailor Moon, use your
Rym: powers!".
Rym: She's like, "Oh right, she uses her
Rym: powers.".
Rym: Oh right, I have magic.
Scott: That's how I transform.
Scott: Maybe I should use that on the bad guy.
Rym: Her first power is to take her little tiara off and throw it at someone.
Rym: Just keep doing that!
Rym: They turn to dust!
Rym: They die immediately.
Scott: I was like, why didn't she just throw that tiara at the big queen, whatever she was?
Rym: Nah, I can't.
Rym: You can't use your full power.
Scott: You used it on the bonbon babies!
Scott: You can't use it on the big baws?
Scott: If I had a tiara that turned people to dust, I'd just be throwing it all the time at any bad guys.
Scott: But not good guys, like X-Cop.
Rym: But Sailor says she is completely incompetent through this whole situation.
Scott: And then, later in the show, these other Sailors show up.
Scott: The extra Sailors.
Rym: Yeah, Scott's like, "Is anyone
Rym: competent?".
Rym: I'm like, "Actually, yes.
Rym: The outer
Rym: sentient.".
Rym: Then they show up, and they're like, "What the fuck is up?
Rym: I got a sword!
Rym: Let's kick some
Rym: ass!".
Scott: Yeah, they show up, and they're like, "Aw
Scott: shit.".
Scott: They actually use their magic powers.
Scott: And I was like, "Fuck
Scott: yeah.".
Rym: Now, again, I had to explain that their job, Green Lantern Universe, is to defend the solar system from external threats.
Rym: They're not supposed to get involved.
Scott: Then why do they show up?
Scott: to get involved with Candy Prawn?
Rym: And I realized the only argument I had here, this is some Radio Free Equestria Gandalf girthing, is that they showed up because the plot is basically
Scott: Sailor-esque
Rym: alien comes down with technology and forces the fairies, the candy fairies, of planet Earth to help her steal children so she can have wonderful dreams with them in her black dream hole.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And because this happened, the Outer Senji were like, "Oh shit, we let one through.
Rym: We better go clean that up before we get in
Rym: trouble.".
Rym: Also, the Inner Senji can't deal with this shit.
Rym: The Green Lantern on Earth can't deal with the Galactus whatevers.
Scott: It is a thing, right?
Scott: Those Outer Senji, whatever, they were way confident and way stronger powers, and they looked older and cooler.
Rym: Yeah, they're in high school.
Scott: And they actually didn't hesitate to use- they look like college.
Scott: I guess like the Sailor Moon, it's weird, it's like the opposite of current animes.
Scott: Current animes, it's like, "What is she in?
Scott: She's in high school.
Scott: She looks like she's
Scott: two.".
Scott: But now it's like, "Well, those middle school girls look like high school girls, and the high school girls look like college
Scott: girls.".
Scott: But do those outer ones, do they live on the outer planets, like Pluto, or do they actually go to school somewhere on Earth?
Rym: So, it's complicated, depending on what era of Sailor Moon we're in, but yeah, the two- Do they live on Titan or Europa or something?
Rym: So, Haruka and Michiru, Ernest and Neptune, they actually- The lesbians?
Rym: Yeah, the lesbians.
Rym: They went to a high school.
Rym: There's stuff with that high school that tried to destroy the world.
Rym: Great.
Scott: It's a pedo high school.
Rym: No, when the Holy Grail came, and they had to stop Pharaoh from destroying the world with the Holy Grail.
Rym: Wait, King Arthur's Holy Grail?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the Pharaoh Ramses wanted the Holy Grail?
Rym: No, basically the Pharaoh is the same as the villain from The Fifth Element.
Scott: Oh.
Rym: Like, actually, to the point that when I saw The Fifth Element- Stargate?
Rym: No, more like Fifth Element.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: When I saw The Fifth Element- Ruby Rodd?
Rym: I remember literally thinking, "Wow, did they steal this from Sailor
Rym: Moon?".
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: Like, it's so the same thing.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Ruby Rodd.
Scott: But they showed up, and they're all confident, but they didn't actually get the job done.
Scott: They just sort of picked off the Bon-Bon babies and stuff, and- Well, they picked them off.
Scott: Sailor Moon had to actually get the real job done.
Rym: So, there's a trope to the Sailor Moon movies of Sailor Moon, you know, everyone's failed.
Scott: But Sailor Moon is way less powerful and way less dumb.
Rym: She is, in fact, the most powerful.
Scott: Then why?
Rym: the powers are weird and different, and it's complicated.
Scott: Just use them.
Scott: You've used them before.
Rym: This isn't the first movie, right?
Scott: No.
Scott: So.
Scott: It's not movie one, which means you've used the power before.
Scott: Use whatever you used before, right?
Scott: Fist of the North Star doesn't get this wrong.
Scott: He learns Musou Tensei.
Scott: He uses Musou Tensei.
Scott: He doesn't forget it, right?
Scott: When he needs to use it, he whips it out.
Rym: So, in the show, every half-season or so, she learns a new power, like, levels up.
Rym: They all learn new powers.
Rym: Cool.
Scott: How many powers did they know by the time this episode?
Rym: So, you notice how all the individual sailors kept using, like, different powers that was based on?
Scott: They didn't really have that many of them, but they used three or four each.
Scott: And the thing that really bothered me is, like, they whipped out, like, all these sword handles that didn't have swords on them.
Scott: So, they transformed, but then they didn't actually even have the handles afterwards.
Scott: And I'm like, you have this tool used in your transformation sequence, and where'd the tool go?
Scott: But then the better ones showed up, and they actually had, like, swords and staves, and they actually used them.
Rym: Well, because they're the badasses.
Rym: Pluto is one of the baddest asses there is.
Scott: Right, why didn't the badasses get the whole job done, and why didn't Sailor Moon just go back home and take care of the frickin' tuxedo guy?
Rym: Who's in the hospital?
Rym: Sailor Saturn's power is destroy all of existence right the fuck.
Rym: now, the end of everything.
Scott: Alright, so you should stay home, because that power's useless.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: In fact, why didn't the other sailors just fucking kill Sailor Saturn?
Scott: That doesn't ever happen.
Rym: Uh, that's actually the plot of Sailor--.
Scott: 'Cause somebody is just gonna, like, possess Sailor Saturn and make that happen.
Rym: So, Scott, that's pretty much the plot of Sailor Moon S.
Scott: Oh, at least that's not so dumb.
Rym: She's a girl, and, you know, all the sense-- Is she some, like, high school girl who's dumb?
Rym: Uh, no, she's actually eerily, like, scarily smart and weird.
Rym: Well, that's good.
Rym: And she knows what's up, and her dad's a scientist, and that's actually-- If you're ever gonna watch Sailor Moon, Sailor Moon S is probably the best one to watch.
Scott: So that's not what we watched?
Rym: No, Sailor Moon S, the show.
Scott: So we watched Super S, the movie.
Scott: The movie.
Scott: What's super about it?
Scott: It's just Super S, as opposed to S, and I-- Is there a Super S TV show?
Rym: Yes, the TV shows go Sailor Moon, then there's that Alan and Anne bullshit.
Scott: What's that?
Rym: Just, like, between that and Sailor Moon R.
Scott: Is it an OAV or a TV or a movie?
Rym: It's like just the next season after the first Queen Beryl thing ends.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: So there's the Queen Beryl arc, then there's the Alan and Anne arc, and then what is colloquial known as Sailor Moon R, which is arguably Alan and Anne and the next thing with Prince Diamond.
Rym: Then there's Sailor Moon S, which is about the Holy Grail, Pharaoh, Saturn destroying the universe.
Scott: So that's all the epic stuff?
Scott: That's the epic stuff.
Scott: That's why you want people to watch that one?
Rym: Super S is Pegasus--.
Scott: So that has all the cosmic stuff?
Rym: Super S is Pegasus and candy and bullshit.
Scott: The TV show and the movie?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: But different Pegasuses and different bullshit and different candy.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And Sailor Stars is the girls who turn into guys who come from, it's like super galactic.
Rym: Andromeda.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Sailor S is like the Green Lantern expanded universe, then Super S is like, I don't even know.
Scott: You mean stars.
Rym: Yeah, stars.
Rym: Stars is like the next step out.
Scott: So then what's the end of Sailor Moon?
Rym: Stars.
Rym: Is it?
Rym: So stars basically is like--.
Scott: So each of these things is a TV show and a movie?
Scott: Are there OAVs?
Rym: There's no stars movie.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Scott: But every other thing is a TV show and a movie?
Rym: Yes, and the movies have nothing to do with the show.
Scott: So like there's an R TV series and an R movie?
Rym: Yes, the R movie is the gay guy from space who ruins every movie.
Scott: And the movie comes after each TV series?
Rym: The movie does not make sense or fit into the continuity at all.
Scott: None of the movies?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: They're like the comic book movie.
Scott: Were these movies in theaters?
Rym: As far as I can tell, they were.
Rym: Whoa.
Scott: They're like Pokemon movies.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: As far as I can tell.
Scott: Or One Piece movies.
Rym: So another trope of a Sailor Moon movie is that everyone fails and then there's an impossible situation like we're all gonna die or you can't stop this.
Rym: You can't get out of a black dream hole once you crawl into it.
Rym: And then Sailor Moon will say, "I have to try
Rym: anyway!".
Rym: And then she dies.
Rym: Or something.
Rym: And then magically she comes back anyway.
Scott: That's exactly what happened.
Rym: That happens in all the movies.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Happens all the time.
Rym: Though in the R movie she actually just dies.
Rym: And then comes back to life.
Rym: For basically no reason.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But they have a Sailor Teleport in that one, which I'm surprised they didn't use here because the fact that they meet the outer sentries.
Scott: Yeah, they had to go make a boat or something to get to where the space station they need to go to.
Rym: Even if these don't fit in the continuity, they knew Sailor Teleport before they met those outer sentries, so ugh.
Rym: God.
Rym: Also, Queen Badine looks almost exactly like Sailor Galaxia from Starz, so maybe there's a connection?
Scott: Maybe it's just the same artist, lazy character designer?
Rym: I can Gandalf girth a connection, but I'm not going to.
Rym: And also, we're not talking about the manga, which is different.
Rym: No manga.
Scott: How much of the manga have you read?
Rym: I've read like five or six random volumes of the manga in random books.
Scott: Okay, I thought you were gonna say you read the whole thing.
Rym: I've read like two Starzes and a few others.
Scott: Didn't you read all of Meisani Goku off the shelf?
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Without ever buying a volume?
Rym: I also read all the Sailor Moon that I ever read at the same Walden books.
Scott: Okay, so, Sailor Moon, the one we watched was super S.
Rym: Super S movie.
Rym: The last Sailor Moon movie ever made.
Scott: Candy pedophiles and stupidity.
Rym: The movie.
Scott: If you really want to lull and you were mad wasted on some substances and you want to see some guys convince children into his boat with candy.
Rym: To then take him to his master to put them in a black hole.
Rym: Queen Badian.
Rym: Which means, roughly, Star Anus.
Scott: So he's gonna put him in the Anus black hole, these children that were lured.
Rym: No, into her wonderful black dream hole.
Scott: Right, so they lure children with candy into the queen's wonderful black dream hole of Anus.
Scott: You can watch this movie.
Scott: It's only an hour.
Scott: You're not suffering that much.
Rym: And all the Sailor Moon movies are actually really well animated.
Scott: Yeah, the animation was actually pretty good.
Scott: I don't know what year it was from, but I was like, "Oh, high budget on the
Scott: animation.".
Rym: Sailor Moon's hit or miss.
Rym: There's a point in stars where the animation goes way to shit.
Rym: I think there were scab artists because something happened during the series.
Scott: I'm sure Wikipedia knows it.
Rym: There's a few episodes where the animation goes way off model and way to shit.
Scott: Island episodes.
Rym: There are parts of Sailor Moon, especially the movies.
Rym: They're actually the facial expressions and the way they're drawn.
Rym: The animation is great.
Rym: I forgot how much I like some of this old cel animation.
Rym: The animation alone makes up for...
Scott: I mean, there was a lot of stuff where you would see they weren't trying.
Scott: They were skimping on the animation, right?
Scott: There'd be a scene where only the mouth moves or the people are just sort of standing there.
Rym: But it was all.
Scott: really the colors are nice.
Scott: It was high resolution, even though it wasn't HD.
Scott: It was pretty good.
Scott: Like, wow, this looks pretty great, considering it's a one hour throwaway kind of movie situation.
Rym: It was surprisingly okay to watch, again.
Rym: I saw it once a long time ago.
Scott: It wasn't painful to watch, and it was fun to make fun of, but this isn't some great anime movie you've got to run out to see right away.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Though it is worth watching at least one of the three Sailor Moon movies, just to kind of get a feel for what Sailor Moon is and was.
Rym: And to know that thing.
Rym: To know what that is.
Rym: Also, the plot of this really is The Matrix.
Rym: But with pied pedo pepper pipers.
Rym: Pedo piper bear pepper.
Scott: Imagine if Noah from Noah's Ark was collecting to children.
Scott: But because he wanted to start the flood, not because the flood already was coming.
Scott: He was going to use the children to make a flood.
Rym: If only.
Rym: I kind of want to know what Kunihiko Ikuhara's version of this was going to be because it focused only on the awesome sailors.
Rym: And the plot was apparently going to be that one of them was in a deep sleep, like in this dream world, and the other one was going to go attack the other normal sailors and steal their shit and use that to save her girlfriend.
Scott: Dude, one sailor with all the sailor shit who's confident and actually can cast all those spells at once.
Scott: That's got to be much better than this movie.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That we just saw.
Rym: Ikuhara said, which is really interesting, in an interview, that he took a lot of the ideas he had for what was going to be the Sailor Moon Super S movie and pulled them out of his bag when it was time to make Shoujo Kakumei Utena.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Which, that's why I want to see what this movie would have been because I think it would have been a lot like Utena because he realized there's swords being pulled out of people's chests and stuff.
Scott: Instead, it's just a throw away whatever.
Rym: Yeah, with the guys who turned into birds.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Banana and orange.
Scott: At least their existence in character design is humorous.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's the best I can say about that.
Rym: That's all we can say.
Rym: I don't know, watch some anime.
Scott: Yeah, there's probably something else you could be watching instead of this.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.