Rym: It's Thursday October 18th 2012.
Rym: Scott doesn't seem to be mad anymore than I say the year every time we do an opener And this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: What are we talking about Scott?
Rym: Can't catch your tongue.
Rym: We're talking about real haunted houses.
Scott: I still get mad that you say too many words for the title part.
Rym: Why would you be mad about that?
Scott: You should have just said tonight haunted houses.
Scott: Instead you went on and we're still going on.
Scott: so skip it.
Rym: Are we still going on?
Scott: Are we?
Rym: We're uh, actually yeah, the music's still playing.
Scott: Fuck your face.
Scott: Okay anyway Let's do this.
Rym: So I finally many of you might have seen the movie Brazil The Terry Gilliam one?
Rym: Yes, the movie about what happens when bureaucracy becomes too powerful.
Rym: So it's a good movie.
Rym: You should all see it.
Rym: While it's a classic and I really really like it.
Rym: I will not pretend That it could not have used an editor and is not perhaps about 40 minutes too long.
Scott: It's got problems But like, you know, I mean I can see why it's like a cult classic and why there's people who are big fans of it.
Rym: I also respect it as a movie a great deal, but personally not gonna.
Rym: I don't enjoy watching it at all I enjoy watching pieces of it.
Rym: But anyway, so I lived through a Brazilian scenario that I will now relate to you all.
Rym: so Almost one year ago today.
Rym: I received a notification That my taxes both federal and state had not been processed.
Scott: didn't use turbo tax Back then.
Rym: no, it wasn't my taxes from any recent year.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: It was my taxes from like 2009 or 2008.
Rym: I forget it's already okay.
Rym: so I did some follow-up stuff and the feds responded right away and they're like, yeah for whatever reason we didn't get it.
Scott: and Why did it take you this long to say something?
Rym: Yeah, I didn't matter cuz both the feds and the state owed me a tiny bit of money So it didn't even matter.
Rym: It's like, alright, so I never got my five bucks or whatever.
Rym: but don't you to pay a fine for not filing into on time, so I Investigated and I discovered that I had in fact filed my taxes through H&R block and those pig fuckers just fucked it up somehow.
Rym: So I called them and they start to help me and they're like, wait a minute It looks like you used in a free e-file.
Rym: I was like, yes, they're like we don't support those.
Rym: they hung up on me.
Rym: So all I had was the receipt showing that I had paid them to do my fat my state return which they also didn't support cuz I did it as part as a free e-file or whatever right and I had the email receipt stating that I had in fact done my taxes.
Rym: So I put together I put that in an email and I sent it back to the feds like I did file him.
Rym: Here's the evidence.
Rym: I have no response.
Rym: Okay, so Maybe I don't know.
Rym: a week before taxes were due for this current year.
Rym: I got two letters one for the feds that were like You've got to file these taxes.
Rym: you never filed them.
Rym: They basically ignored the letter Of course and the state sent me a similar letter.
Rym: Hmm So I refiled my federal taxes by hand from 2009. so I dug up all my old fucking documents and I calculated everything and I sent the the 1040 and all that business and Several months later.
Rym: I got a response back that said all good.
Rym: You're set.
Scott: Everything was fine from the state of the feds feds.
Scott: Okay, so New York State, New York State.
Rym: So see this coming.
Rym: I sent them the same thing.
Rym: I redid the taxes and I just sent him and everything was good.
Rym: and then I got a letter back.
Rym: I guess they either never got or never processed the reef, you know, the paperwork I sent in again.
Scott: Well, you saved that so you could do.
Rym: And what I got was this innocuous letter that I ignored for a while.
Rym: cuz they get a lot of mail I don't read it that often because there's never anything important.
Rym: So I opened this letter and it's like you never filed your state taxes.
Rym: You lot of da-da-da you owe us.
Rym: I'm like, all right, they're probably gonna find me.
Rym: I'll just pay it and it'll be done.
Rym: It's like And I'm like what fuck you What?
Rym: What If it had been like even a few hundred dollars, I would have been like, all right I probably should have like gotten a lawyer probably shouldn't use agent our blog.
Scott: Yeah, that's the more That's you get me for the easy free file.
Scott: You get we deserve.
Rym: Yeah I've been using turbo to our quicken actually since then with Marry.
Rym: a problem.
Scott: quicken is turbo.
Scott: text the same companies into it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you're right.
Rym: In fact with into it.
Rym: I actually got a ridiculous refund this year because I made enough money to get a tax credit.
Rym: that was Basically, I got one of those rich person tax credits and I felt really dirty.
Scott: But at the same time you wouldn't say no to that.
Rym: who would Cuz me not saying no is not gonna fix the problem.
Rym: Anyway, so I Get this.
Rym: I'm like, alright, I have to do something.
Rym: I can't just ignore this.
Scott: Yeah, otherwise you go to jail.
Rym: Am I going to pay this?
Scott: of course not?
Rym: So I go through this Document over the course of like a week because I don't have a lot of time in my free time, you know my life.
Rym: so I sit down like every day for like an hour and I go over this gigantic document they sent me and Basically, they saw that I had they actually recorded that
Scott: I had paid them
Rym: money in taxes And they recorded the money I had included in the check because I think in the state.
Rym: I think I was wrong.
Rym: earlier The feds owed me money, but I owed the state like five or six bucks.
Rym: So I'd written him a check and they had that.
Rym: they just didn't have the return that was with the check But that didn't.
Rym: that evidence didn't help me.
Rym: so eventually I discovered after trying to read this whole fucking thing that They had calculated what they thought my taxes were on their own Mm-hmm, and because I live in New York City.
Rym: now They assumed I'd always lived in New York City when in fact in 2009 I did not live in New York City.
Rym: So the itemized thing basically said like you owed, you know, four or five, you know I think it was like five thousand something dollars.
Rym: This is the state that you didn't pay because basically you paid zero city tax.
Scott: Yeah, and they wanted the city tax and they were like, what do you the city?
Scott: as for the city tax?
Rym: No, no, the state handles that.
Rym: Okay, so and then they're like.
Rym: and because you didn't pay it by this deadline There's a 10% penalty and because you didn't pay it by this egregious deadline.
Rym: You owe a 100% like egregious whatever penalty on the interest and the engine and it totally was pushing 10 grand by the end.
Rym: so I redid my taxes following their formula which includes all the penalties for filing late and They actually ended up owing me money.
Rym: Mm-hmm if I lived Where I lived instead of in New York City.
Rym: So I sent them back an envelope filled with I think 30 pages of documentary evidence that I did not live in nor even have a residence in New York City for the entirety of 2009 and this included like pay stubs from the beginning of the year the middle of the year the end of the year.
Rym: utility bills a utility bill one of my I think.
Rym: I put a copy of the lease from the house we used to live in.
Rym: I Put all this bullshit together and I included this huge huge document that itemized like Article number one assuming a human is ever gonna look at this.
Rym: yeah, so I sent this whole thing off certified mail signature, whatever and I decided that that's the best I can do and I Expected nothing to happen and then like a year later to get fucked with like a $40,000 bill or something.
Scott: Yeah, and you know, I probably should have gotten a lawyer but I didn't have brought tax lawyer.
Rym: Yeah, so I Have a little bit of faith in America.
Rym: now it worked because a week ago I got a letter from New York State.
Rym: Emily hands it to me.
Rym: It's in the mail.
Rym: I look at it.
Rym: I'm like, all right.
Rym: This is when they fuck me.
Rym: This is this is all over for him.
Rym: I'm gonna have to give up my nice apartment gonna go to jail.
Rym: I open it and they're like and it's just literally two sentences.
Rym: We reviewed the documents you provided.
Rym: you now owe The following and then it listed this huge itemized bill and every item on it was zero dollars Mm-hmm.
Rym: So here's the open question that zero dollar bill has a due date.
Rym: Yep Should I send a check for zero dollars?
Rym: Nothing, you should send a check for zero dollars, but I think I think I came out on top.
Rym: So I feel like I feel like it worked out.
Rym: Okay, the moral don't fucking use H&R block for anything.
Rym: They will fuck.
Scott: Why would you do that?
Scott: Don't use any of those things.
Scott: This is the same thing, it's like.
Scott: don't download the shady ass software.
Scott: don't do your taxes at the shady ass tax, dude It was 2009.
Rym: I didn't even make that much money back then.
Scott: I'm just saying Anyway, anyway, that's your open event.
Rym: Well, actually according to the forum I did make a ton of money back then but that's a separate thread anyway, so I got some news.
Rym: Oh This is the lounge for Thursday.
Scott: mom for Thursday lounge this week Announced hey, they be GoPro Hero 3, but I just bought the GoPro Hero 2.
Scott: So here's the deal the GoPro Hero 3. it is Better but also worse and this is why there are actually three.
Scott: wait worse.
Scott: There are actually three GoPro Hero 3s.
Scott: There is the white edition which is $200.
Scott: it's so cheap right the white edition right Has you know?
Scott: it can do sort of the same thing as the GoPro Hero 2 right at 1080p at 30 frames per second 960p at 30 720p at 60. right but it has Wi-Fi built in.
Scott: you don't need it a pack and All of these new GoPro Hero 3s the plastic enclosure is already has the dive housing thingy on the front.
Scott: So, you know that?
Scott: you know, you don't need to go and like buy the different dive housing to go deeper underwater.
Rym: I will never need the dive house.
Scott: I'm just saying it's by default.
Scott: No, cuz we're going to Australia.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just saying by default.
Scott: It's on there right on all of them.
Scott: So you don't need to get a set and the clamp on top is better.
Scott: This is totally unrelated.
Rym: I saw a guy on the subway today walking along the subway while the train was going with a GoPro on a very similar Homemade steady cam to the one I have.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So this one only was only five megapixels of the quality not the best But it's $200.
Scott: It's so cheap.
Scott: It's sort of like getting a GoPro Hero 1 the original for magic.
Rym: We should tell Mike tool cuz he was just asking me like should I get a GoPro to film panels at conventions?
Scott: I saw I'm not done yet.
Scott: There's the silver edition $300 racist basic.
Scott: I Think that'd be ages.
Scott: It's basically the same thing as the white edition.
Scott: what so only it's $100 more but you made it 11 megapixels.
Scott: Oh, so it's better.
Scott: It's slightly better.
Scott: It's basically the hero - only slightly better because again the housing is it.
Scott: but wait You said there's something bad and the Wi-Fi built-in.
Rym: you said there's something bad.
Scott: What was bad You said you?
Rym: you implied that there was something not all great about the new GoPro.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: You know what the bad thing about the silver edition is.
Scott: it cost like $800 not the black edition, which is the best edition.
Scott: Okay, black edition is $400.
Scott: It is 12 megapixels and check this.
Scott: it has the Wi-Fi built in.
Scott: it comes with a shammy The Wi-Fi remote control.
Scott: so you don't even need to touch it to like turn it on.
Scott: You can buy the room.
Rym: I really wanted that for the GoPro - but it was too much money for how little I use.
Scott: Right, you can buy the remote separately for the other ones But you this one comes with the remote and the remote is 80 bucks on its own.
Scott: So if you think about it The black edition is really only $20 more than the silver edition.
Scott: that if you count the price of the remote it's 12 megapixels, so the quality there is slightly better than the silver edition, but Here's the craziness.
Scott: Here it comes 720p not at 60 FPS like the other GoPros, but at 120 1080p at 60 which is It gets crazier 1440p at 48 frames a second.
Rym: Oh, so it's doing those like 2k 4k like ultra HD 2.7.
Scott: K at 30 FPS and 4k at 12 FPS.
Scott: So the 4k is good.
Scott: for like, you know the time lapses.
Rym: You're not getting able to fit that much of that on a an SD card.
Scott: get a really big SD card.
Scott: But also remember it has the Wi-Fi so you could have it be Wi-Fiing that too.
Rym: Um, how much bandwidth Does Wi-Fi have?
Scott: I'm saying use it.
Scott: just say for the time lapses the 4k.
Scott: Yeah, you want to just say you mostly you're gonna run this thing though at the 1080p 60 which is Insane.
Scott: or if you want to do some image digital image stabilization or post-processing digital zoom Well, that was the other thing I was do the 14 do the 1440 or the 2.7 K at 4 48 or 30 FPS and then you could crop down to 1080p and you won't.
Scott: it'll be awesome Yeah, so for 400 bucks plus it includes a free remote.
Scott: I'm thinking I'm gonna get one but in the spring and what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna put.
Scott: it's gonna make my life miserable When it comes to editing together our stuff from conventions Oh and also all of these because there's so much smaller than the old GoPros.
Scott: use micro SD So you can get a 64 gig micro SD for this.
Scott: I'm gonna put the Better one on the front of my bike and I'm gonna put my old one on the back and then double it up.
Rym: I'm going to see how much I use my current GoPro cuz last year.
Scott: I use it every fucking day.
Rym: I don't anymore because the video.
Rym: so yes, I have what 40 videos of me biking to work Whoop-dee-doo.
Scott: I can compile them into a really awesome video.
Rym: My your commute must be a lot more exciting than mine, maybe My commutes also a half-hour long.
Scott: You also gotta use the magic of video editing to make it look exciting.
Rym: Nothing has ever happened on my GoPro in the entire time that I had it on my bike every day.
Scott: one day the exciting will Happen and you'll have won't have the GoPro Have.
Rym: the GoPro really is for skiing and last season I got a bunch of good okay videos.
Rym: But by the time I got the GoPro and got it going ski season was kind of over and the one time I went to A really good place or would have gotten good video.
Rym: It was like super snowy and you can't see anything in the video.
Scott: I've also learned techniques how to get more exciting shots with the GoPro that I wasn't getting.
Scott: So now if I have a spare do riskier things.
Scott: No, you put the camera in a in a better spot.
Scott: That is clever.
Rym: I picture Scott's not gonna have 40 videos of his crotch while he bikes.
Rym: So My tool was asking, you know, he was like gosh.
Rym: I get a GoPro to record my panels.
Rym: So it's about 400 bucks for the new good for this GoPro the super high-end one.
Rym: Yeah for a Thousand bucks.
Scott: That's a lot more than 400.
Rym: You can get a camcorder That is way better quality than that.
Rym: GoPro probably has a 300 gigabyte internal hard drive.
Rym: Yeah, you can record like 20 hours of your panels, but does it do more than 1080p?
Rym: 60 you don't need that for a panel.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: 1080p 60 is plenty for two doofuses or one doofus up on a stage talking.
Scott: It's true.
Rym: Also, the GoPro is low-light performance is probably not nearly as good.
Rym: Dedicated can be black edition.
Scott: the high-end $400 has better light low-light performance.
Rym: Every camera ever says it has better low-light performance than all previous does not say better.
Scott: It says pro low-light performance.
Scott: So it's pro which means as good as row Row is.
Rym: in fact, don't we only ever call people pros pejoratively?
Rym: Yes, so I Have a question for you Scott.
Rym: when you said that when I on the silver GoPro that that was a gist Were you making a joke because old people have silver hair or because the symbol for silver is a G Which joke were you making?
Rym: I don't think you were making both jokes you don't think?
Scott: so I don't.
Scott: how do you not know?
Scott: I got a hunch hunch because you're old So silvery.
Rym: This is something Scott and I talked about a lot on our own whenever it comes up because we actually have different opinions on it.
Rym: So recently the government in New York, and actually there's a picture in this article.
Rym: That's right Government like the Federal Reserve like I walked past the Federal Reserve every day on my way to like Good Burger to get lunch.
Scott: Yeah, I was down there today.
Rym: Really were you?
Rym: yeah, I was just there because I was over there Twice today both for work stuff and for other work stuff.
Scott: I was there because I was going to 30 Broad Street So I was very close 30 broad.
Rym: I've been in that building before for work stuff.
Rym: Yeah, what were you doing there?
Scott: I was signing up for them.
Scott: I had to go get fingerprinted so that oh Okay, the government can find me.
Scott: Now I'm really can't commit any crimes.
Scott: Yeah, because now I'm in a database.
Rym: That's great.
Rym: I'm in one of those databases, too So don't worry about that.
Rym: Yeah, so a dude was arrested for Buying fake bomb equipment from the FBI undercover FBI agents buying instructions asking them to help him Constructing something that he thought was a gigantic bomb Taking it to the Federal Reserve attempting Repeatedly to detonate it and he was arrested for conspiracy to terrorism and all that stuff.
Rym: I'm actually okay with this.
Scott: I Mean obviously, here's my rash.
Scott: Obviously dude was pushing the button.
Scott: He wanted to blow stuff up.
Rym: He's a crazy dude that before we even get to the the low-level argument is guilty of something I'm gonna make.
Rym: I mean, let's make the philosophical argument first.
Rym: if there's a person in a free society where there's free speech.
Rym: who?
Rym: Merely by being given the opportunity Will pretty much immediately attempt to commit mass murder.
Rym: You can argue that the FBI in this case is basically acting as an antibody Provoking a response from a virus to then isolate and destroy it for the betterment of all society.
Scott: Not a bad analogy.
Scott: So I Winning me over with the analogy.
Rym: I'm just saying I'm okay with that on a philosophical level.
Rym: However, I will agree right now that lupus exists and that we do not want it to turn into the autoimmune situation Where someone who actually wasn't a danger is tricked or coerced into doing something like that here.
Scott: Let me hit you with my analogy, right?
Scott: Crazy guy wants to kill someone.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: He is.
Scott: he has a mentality of wanting to kill bad guy.
Scott: No question.
Scott: And right, there's clearly no question about this guy either.
Scott: right goes to the store to buy a weapon, right?
Scott: All right, dude at the gun store sells him a Super Soaker and says yes.
Scott: Yes, this will kill people.
Scott: The guy's just really dumb and he says okay and he goes and he shoots someone with water.
Scott: Right now take a second guy same situation only buys a real gun and shoot somebody and kills them as opposed to shooting them With water.
Scott: Yeah should not be water guy.
Scott: I think I'm.
Scott: you know, I'm not a lawyer.
Scott: obviously I would argue the water guy would be treated differently in court and receive a less sentence and a different He would be charged with a different crime.
Scott: Now then the guy with the real guy.
Rym: if the guy if the gun shop sold him Something that looked and felt for all intents and purposes to be a real gun But was actually a squirt gun Then it would then he would probably be charged with attempted murder because he did attempt to murder.
Scott: He was just incompetent No, but it's like but he didn't actually.
Scott: No attempted murder the law didn't murder.
Scott: they can't charge him with murder That's clear.
Rym: and they're not charging this guy with bombing That's true.
Rym: charging him with attempted bombing and conspiracy to bomb.
Rym: but if then she did commit both of those things I know but it's conspiracy to do something does not require you to actually do it.
Rym: If you do it, you also get charged with doing it.
Scott: I know No, I still I just feel like this, you know, if we just if the FBI had not, you know set up this What would this guy have done?
Rym: so probably no so so so this is the interesting part.
Rym: That's why I brought up the anatomy because the high-level argument of philosophy and pragmatism and everything.
Rym: There's an interesting debate to be had.
Scott: Was it entrapment of some kind?
Scott: I don't you know, I don't know the legal.
Scott: Don't come after me, please.
Rym: I have the whole sequence of what happened here, but on the high level We're just talking about there's a good argument to be had and I can see both cases.
Rym: my final counter argument before we move on to the details of this dude and where what you're about to bring up is that the.
Rym: How should I approach this?
Rym: I got a couple of ways I could argue.
Rym: All right, so Charles Manson, right?
Rym: Yeah, didn't actually murder anyone.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: bunch of stupid people were tricked basically convinced to murder on his behalf, but he told people to do something.
Scott: So did it.
Scott: it's the same thing as Al Capone didn't kill anyone did he right?
Scott: but he told people to kill people.
Scott: Ah, but so Charles Manson is equally guilty to Al Capone which is very very bad.
Rym: But Al Capone was only guilty of tax evasion.
Scott: That's all they could pin him on.
Scott: just cuz he's good at hiding evidence.
Scott: Imagine if they could actually you know, if the evidence that Al Capone told people to kill people was readily available He would have been locked up like Charles Manson.
Rym: You can argue that the people who killed for Al Capone Were just shitty people doing their shitty mob.
Scott: I think the difference between Al Capone and Charles Manson was the Al Capone paid the people to do the killing whereas Charles Manson just Convinced them.
Rym: Ah, but the people Charles Manson convinced were also charged with murder and arrested.
Scott: Yes, and many of them Al Capone's people were all hitmen and they also would have gone to jail.
Rym: Could you not argue that we cannot eliminate the Charles Mansions before we identify him?
Rym: and people like that are usually Clever enough to avoid detection.
Scott: Well, the Al Capone was that's for sure.
Rym: But simultaneously the people who would commit the crimes on their behalf who are less intelligent and who are susceptible to these sorts of memes are Equally dangerous to society because it's very easy to get them to do bad things.
Rym: a smart person could use them to murder by proxy.
Rym: so should they not also be in some way either deactivated in terms of their willingness to go murder or somehow segregated from society?
Scott: But if they if the bad people, you know out there, I understand your pragmatic viewpoint.
Scott: But if the bad if that you know, there's probably plenty of people around the world, you know Who are those kind of susceptible people who simply have not encountered the Charles Manson Al Capone because those are actually very rare?
Scott: Ah, so and those people are living their lives Perfectly happily and innocently because they have been lucky enough not to encounter but at the same time they are taking time bombs.
Rym: they are.
Rym: would our society not be stronger if in addition to trying to stop bad people we did something to make the Average person less susceptible to that thereby being stronger as you are now Taking out these people who would have been innocent.
Scott: Is that fair?
Rym: Who says taking out?
Rym: There's other ways to approach.
Scott: What do you do with them?
Scott: So you you you have some system?
Scott: We don't know what the system is.
Scott: What if you have a system?
Scott: Hypothetically you identify you identify a person who would kill if they met a Charles Manson But they have not yet met one and there is not one in the area.
Scott: So maybe what do you do with that person?
Rym: Maybe you set up a system where those people are approached by Social workers to see like maybe to help them out to make them more some sort of like voluntary program.
Scott: Oh, well that's different than tricking them into killing people and faking and becoming a Charles Manson tricking them into not actually killing someone and locking them.
Rym: so this Dude, this particular dude apparently came to America Specifically to be a terrorist and was dedicating his entire life.
Scott: How did he get in then toward this?
Rym: Well, they let him in because they were following him.
Rym: They'd been spying on me.
Scott: Why did they just get him at the border?
Rym: if they knew he hadn't committed anything yet They could they could have arrested him on basically nothing.
Rym: They had.
Rym: they had all this evidence that he came here for it.
Rym: So basically he put together a group of people to do it.
Scott: Why didn't they just get him with that evidence that he came here for it?
Rym: because here's a better way they did.
Rym: But first they waited to be absolutely sure beyond any possible doubt that he would have done it that he wasn't just one of those You know guys who's loud and pissed off about stuff.
Rym: They wanted to make sure he was a dude who actually would get a bomb and actually try to detonate.
Scott: That is a good thing because there are plenty of loud pissed off people who I know on the Internet's.
Scott: who?
Scott: Probably if that if that was all it took to lock them up would be locked up even though they are perfectly innocent People who should not be in jail
Rym: exactly so allegedly he came to the US with the intent of doing this Gathered up a posse of people and put together a plan to bomb buildings eventually settled on the Federal Reserve.
Scott: Why did he pick the Federal Reserve?
Rym: that thing because it had less security than all the other buildings He was looking after.
Scott: what the fuck buildings was he looking at?
Scott: Is like a picket box of iron?
Scott: yes, it's not a bomb next to it.
Scott: So he bought a thousand pounds of bomb It's not gonna do anything even if it worked and kill people on the street and maybe the building across the street.
Rym: He recruited a posse of people who might sell FBI agents.
Rym: he He helped them build the bomb with him.
Rym: he finished it he put the detonator in he drove the truck over Parked it went away tried to they don't even let you drive trucks in that neighborhood.
Scott: There's all these barriers and shit.
Rym: when the bomb failed to go off He kept trying to do it and he had a plan B And apparently it also constructed a suicide vest again from the fake bomb.
Scott: he was planning to kill himself with the bomb.
Rym: That was his plan B.
Scott: If plan a failed so plan a he was still trying to detonate the bomb.
Scott: How was he gonna get away?
Rym: he was far enough away from the bomb.
Rym: get like a remote detonator, okay?
Rym: So Philosophy aside I think pragmatically this particular dude based on everything.
Rym: I've read.
Rym: It's probably good We're right.
Scott: well if those FBI agents were not there if they just kept my appears that from what I can gather right Approached them Rob, but here's the clip, but that they were making themselves approachable right.
Scott: yeah They put out some sort of front like bombs sets bomb store that he went in.
Rym: This doesn't follow your original analogy.
Rym: those people are perfectly content to live their lives unless the Charles mansion of Manson approaches them.
Rym: This is a guy who is susceptible to Manson who is looking for char, right?
Scott: But here's the question what if you know the FBI just stood back and kept watching him, and he never actually found anybody?
Scott: He wouldn't have done anything.
Rym: Then they have to keep watching him forever because he cuz clearly if he ever found anyone immediate bomb plot.
Scott: But if he found someone You know what it was.
Scott: maybe it was worth watching him all those years because now you got two guys.
Scott: Ah, but at the same time that bomb store and bomb by.
Rym: how many people are they watching like this and you know what?
Rym: The other nose.
Rym: the other thing I would point out there aren't that many stories like this.
Scott: like we talked about it a lot There's not that many crazy people on earth.
Scott: if there were actually a lot of people who wanted to bomb We would already be bombed a lot.
Rym: so because it happens rarely and because this dude Clearly wanted to bomb that thing that is why pragmatically.
Scott: I'm also okay with I'm just a little a Cuz it's a little bit.
Rym: I will say I'm leery of This going too far, but I think it's well before the line where I would actually be worried it.
Scott: You know I mean I am leery.
Scott: how would you feel right if the police?
Scott: Opened up a brothel and if you went to the brothel they just arrested you, but it looked like a brothel.
Rym: So that's where our trappin laws come in.
Rym: yeah Asking someone to do the crime is entrapment.
Rym: if you're there, and they ask you it's not.
Scott: So what if they had this brothel and they just put ads out that were said hey brothel on now No, you can't do that, so how did this guy find the FBI guys if they weren't advertising their bomb shop?
Rym: I didn't read the entire article.
Rym: doesn't actually say specifically As alleged complaint country.
Rym: the defendant thought he was striking a blow to the American economy.
Scott: How could you even strike even if even if your bomb worked the gold is way underground and your bomb wouldn't hurt the gold.
Scott: And it's oh my god.
Scott: This guy was so dumb already.
Rym: No, he's smart in one regard.
Rym: any bomb attack anywhere would put America into a shitstorm.
Scott: It would cause a shitstorm.
Scott: Yeah, but it wouldn't do anything to the Federal Reserve, or I don't?
Rym: He clearly didn't knew that but knew that a terror attack on anything would have the same effect.
Scott: Then why was he going after something with low security?
Scott: because low security means Low security.
Scott: that does go for like someone's house compared to Town hall in some town.
Rym: so Scott when I was a kid a house blew up there my name in my neighborhood straight up.
Rym: So yes, yeah, ghastly.
Rym: No one was home, so it was not a terrorist anyway.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Scott: In our crew there are Games at which they are experts and better than everyone else at for example Scott is probably the best Mega Man 2 player in the entire crew.
Rym: He's really good at.
Scott: he's one of these a world-class pac-man xd xd x player CED and but yeah one of the games that I'm better at than everyone that I know is dr.
Scott: Mario.
Scott: Some reason I can't play penalty pawn for shit, but I'm really good at dr.
Scott: Mario at least compared to other people I know with all qualifications.
Rym: I'm pretty good at dr.
Rym: Mario.
Rym: Well you cannot bad In a world without Scott.
Rym: I'm really good at dr.
Rym: Mario.
Rym: Scott beats the ever-living fuck out of me.
Scott: I don't know how come you people can't play this game.
Rym: It's not hard cuz I'll play against like one of our other friends and the gulf between me and them is The same as the gulf between me and Scott.
Scott: like what are you doing?
Scott: It's like you fucking this three colors of pill.
Rym: It's got hard.
Rym: so Scott.
Rym: Let's turn this around advanced wars.
Rym: What are you doing?
Scott: Just move the inventory out of the city more complex than dr.
Scott: Mario.
Scott: So here's a video, I think it's computer-assisted it has to.
Scott: there's no way a human being could do this on purpose and No human could stack books like this right.
Scott: and it's a video of a guy playing dr.
Scott: Mario in the NES or a computer playing dr.
Scott: Mario in the NES and Basically almost filling the entire pill bottle.
Scott: I think he's like three spaces away from filling it and then setting off a combo that clears the entire pill bottle.
Rym: All I could think watching it the entire time was battle balls.
Scott: Yep, but the real thing I have The problem I have with this video is that you look at the score.
Scott: When he starts setting up the combo the score is 600 and when it ends the score is 1500.
Scott: He only got 900 points for the best possible move you could make because the game does not reward combos except in multiplayer Where the game I first.
Scott: I think the game only Rewards you with points for killing the viruses.
Scott: and he did it in level one where they're only like a handful of viruses in There right?
Scott: All right.
Scott: I think he just did it like there.
Scott: Yeah level zero They're only like three viruses in the pill bottle or something.
Rym: when he said no How come there isn't a DS 3ds game?
Rym: That's like the Tetris but is also dr.
Rym: Mario.
Scott: It's 3d.
Scott: Dr.
Rym: Mario That might be terrible.
Scott: three.
Rym: Remember welteris 3d?
Rym: things like that are never good.
Scott: Rotate the pill bottle and get the nails in there.
Rym: That would be a terrible game that you would hate and never play.
Scott: The pills get like a plus shaped pill But it's a 3d plus.
Scott: that's got two pieces going through the middle and your l-shaped ones.
Scott: You got to spin them around Okay.
Rym: Yeah, it sounds pretty horrible.
Scott: That's bad.
Scott: But this is pretty epic to watch.
Scott: It'd be like if someone is playing Tetris in a long piece.
Scott: That was as long as the whole Tetris Boom.
Rym: So Alright, I guess I should do my thing of the day - yeah, you should.
Rym: so probably my favorite thing in the Simpsons is groundskeeper Willie and This is a small compilation.
Rym: It's not really the best of groundskeeper Willie because he has some other really good moments.
Rym: How long is this video pretty short?
Rym: Actually, it's not like a minute and a half one minute.
Scott: That's Willie's time.
Rym: It's not every Willie It's not all the best Willie but it is.
Rym: it is a. It covers the full breadth of Willie.
Rym: Rym is a connoisseur of Willie and I gotta say I get a lot.
Scott: They're really being penises.
Rym: The reason I like Gravity Falls is that the background characters feel very Simpsons esque.
Rym: Okay, they're being used the same way.
Rym: I feel like this family is related like you're really - Willie's family.
Scott: Anyway, Willie jokes insert here.
Scott: All right, that's all your thing today.
Rym: That's my thing.
Scott: is that a moment time book club book is the name of the wind by Rock fuss.
Rym: I'm 17% of the way through it.
Scott: I have finished reading it.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Rym: It's a young adult novel as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: very light reading read it.
Scott: It's book club book.
Scott: He's so far.
Rym: I like it, but the main character a little bit of Mary Sue just saying well, what fantasy book?
Scott: it's fantasy book.
Rym: It's not a the Prince of Nothing at no point.
Rym: Do I think man?
Scott: I really want to be so-and-so I really want to be Alright not our acts.
Rym: Anyway, what about cell?
Rym: you want to be cell whatever?
Rym: I'd like to be the dragon father, you know, he's not bad to be The priest guy.
Rym: You don't remember any of their names do you?
Scott: You mean the holy Shreya, yeah my thinet that's right news M you're not bad being him.
Scott: Yeah things don't go well for him though I'm just saying it's not the worst job.
Rym: Okay, so I'd rather be confidence.
Rym: any other meta moments We got so not this weekend, but next weekend.
Scott: burning con burning con.
Scott: It's too late to join burning con.
Rym: if you're not already in on it It's gonna be a pretty great time But if you're not already in on it, then there's nothing I can say to you.
Rym: But if you were a gamer of any stripe in the role-playing variety Lou Crane has posted some helpful hints for how to run a scenario.
Rym: These are not applicable just to burning con.
Scott: These should be your Bible any our commandment for any RPG any one-shot RPG at any con should follow these Commandments.
Scott: and also You should follow us on the internet and all the internet places because you listen to this show.
Scott: So why don't you follow us on Twitter or Facebook or our forum or our newsletter or?
Scott: iTunes or etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: Why don't you?
Scott: you should?
Rym: forums full of flame wars right now YouTube or Yeah, our YouTube tracking website from crack on lots of YouTube.
Scott: Yeah, come on.
Rym: so when I was a really little kid.
Rym: I went to a haunted house at local high school and I remember very distinctly that it was this big maze.
Rym: and when you first go up to it there are two doors that you pick one and me and my dad went.
Rym: one was terror and One was death.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I think they both led to the same place, but I wasn't sure Because they did not immediately lead to the same place.
Rym: No, and I chose terror and immediately regretted it and to this day I wonder what was behind.
Rym: death Should have gone back in for a second try and this was actually one of the best haunted houses I ever did in my entire life.
Rym: You know why.
Rym: you know what it was?
Rym: It was just a maze Filling an entire high school gym of just black walls and a black ceiling very dimly lit and it was just amazed and there were sounds and stuff going on around and the lighting was kind of different in all these different places.
Rym: it was a difficult and long maze and They're all.
Rym: you always hear someone like following you and you'd see their shadow But they'd never.
Scott: and no didn't you run into other people who are normal people?
Rym: No, they sent you in one tiny group at a time And you never actually see any other person in the maze But you'd hear them and you'd like see them like just around the corner like they'd be someone there But there'd be no one there.
Rym: when you got there you never act.
Rym: at no point Did anyone go boo and I got to tell you about three quarters away through I was so ready For someone to yell boo that that was actually making me nervous.
Rym: That was the best haunted house ever went to and nothing else has ever even come close.
Scott: That is definitely better than a lot of haunted houses.
Scott: I have seen and heard in my life, but it is not amazing.
Rym: Yeah, well it is amazing compared to most haunted houses.
Scott: That is true because most haunted houses are shit They're awful and it's usually just walk through a place.
Scott: It's dark there's a bunch of stuff with like neon lights and you know ultraviolet blacklight action and Then there's like a you know skeletons and vampires and then there's a few people who work there that jump out and go boo you know and stuff like that and stuff that pops out of the walls and goes boo and Things that you can't see but they feel real nasty like spaghetti, but it feels like you know worms all that kind of nonsense.
Scott: and then you know, maybe wacky mirrors and other things to surprise you and That's it.
Scott: Then you get out.
Rym: So I remember once when I was a little older.
Rym: I was in like middle school I think maybe a late elementary school.
Rym: I went to Florida with my family and we heard there was this really awesome haunted house called like the terror on Church Street.
Rym: So it was expensive.
Rym: So we went to it and it wasn't really that scary.
Rym: But the people with me flip the fuck out because the production values were extremely high and the actors were really good Expensive it better be and the sets were amazing, but it's still just the same as all the other.
Rym: Yeah, but it was more.
Rym: while it wasn't going to scare me It was very well done.
Scott: It was almost I mean, that's like the Disney haunted house, right?
Scott: The Haunted Mansion.
Scott: you go in there and it's like you're not scared of anything in the fucking Haunted Mansion.
Rym: But oh, you know what?
Scott: There's so many effects in there and all these.
Scott: it's like a work of art.
Scott: almost It's like you're walking.
Scott: you're going through this living painting that has a haunted theme to it.
Scott: You will be.
Scott: it's so awesome You want to do it like four or five times just to see all the stuff they got.
Rym: when I was a little kid I was riding that with my brother and I started telling him that a kid died in there because the ride broke and it crushed Him and that you could still see the bloodstains.
Rym: and I think I scared him.
Scott: Your brother is scared of skeletons.
Rym: Skeletons are scary as fuck if you're like four.
Scott: No, I like skeletons.
Rym: even when you were four I was never.
Scott: I was scared of things obviously when I was small, right?
Scott: Just like everyone is but I was not scared of skeletons.
Rym: So there is something to be afraid of in the Disney haunted house.
Rym: Mm-hmm when I the first time I ever wrote it I was actually sitting with my grandma was his California, Florida, Florida.
Scott: I've also never been to Disneyland also only been to the Florida one and not the California.
Rym: I was like, we're going to Disneyland.
Rym: I'm almost like no you're going to Disney World.
Rym: I was like, what's the difference?
Rym: She was like one of them's tiny and the other one is gigantic and awesome.
Rym: Yeah, I was like, okay, we're going California.
Scott: one is is while it's tiny is more historic.
Rym: Yeah anyway, so we were in it and you know that point where there's like these ghouls that go like They come out at you like a blah right in your face.
Rym: Yeah, the ride broke down.
Rym: Okay, right in front of that thing For like a half hour you're stuck in there for a half hour.
Rym: I was stuck in there for a half.
Scott: you're in there that long.
Scott: they'll just say get off and use the emergency.
Rym: know that we just sat there and It kept starting up again.
Rym: So every couple of minutes this ghoul would go in our faces.
Scott: Oh So the crack.
Scott: the cars weren't moving but the all the other effects are still running.
Rym: Yes, maybe because the effects were running they wouldn't let us get on walk But the ghoul kept jumping out for like a half hour.
Scott: That's not scary that's just that's scary.
Scott: but it is scary.
Rym: It's scary in the same way that I'm moderately afraid of entering a subway car filled with hobo Not existential horror but practical horror exactly Like that guy might actually stab me.
Scott: a half hour of my life wasted and listening to horrible repeated noise and I can't escape.
Rym: So Scott, how do we make haunted houses that would scare us?
Scott: to scare us is incredibly difficult to make a haunted house to scare someone like us right because what you need to do is You need to because you know, we're so smart not that we're geniuses, right?
Scott: But we're smart enough to know there's no such thing as actual ghosts.
Scott: There's other things actual monsters.
Scott: We know that no one in the haunted house is actually gonna hurt us, right?
Scott: We are no in no real danger at any at any time, you know things like, you know, you know what?
Rym: I enjoy the.
Rym: the roller coaster is still enjoyable because the Sensations of zero-g and flipping upside down are pleasurable in and of themselves.
Rym: Yes but most people I know scream on the roller coaster and actually get scared and my hobby in middle school was to Being like be doing something weird and nonchalant when the picture was taken.
Scott: Yeah, you should get a cup of tea and a mustache.
Rym: Once we had I had a piece of cardboard and I had newspaper taped around him.
Rym: So I unfold this big newspaper just reading it.
Rym: One of them.
Rym: I took my seatbelt off and stood up one of them.
Scott: I'm not doing that except listen to the kiddie coaster.
Rym: that anyway, it was on the Magnum XL 200.
Scott: So here's here's you know I've tried to think of like what would it take to make a haunted house?
Scott: That could actually scare someone like me and I could.
Scott: I came up with the parameters and then I came up with only one Example that met the parameters, right?
Scott: Alright, so the parameters are you really have to?
Scott: you know, you have to go farther.
Scott: Obviously the normal haunted house are gonna go perhaps beyond legality beyond waver area.
Rym: Well, there is that haunted house.
Rym: You have to sign a waiver for in New York City.
Scott: Okay, well that I heard about that and I heard about that too.
Rym: So I read They sexually assault you and waterboard you.
Scott: Yeah, like all I knew about it originally was hey, there's a haunted house.
Scott: It's supposed to be actually like crazy adult sign a waiver pay a lot of money.
Scott: That's all I knew about it and knowing only those facts.
Scott: I thought huh?
Scott: Maybe that's good, but I'm not paying for it.
Scott: And then I heard later Oh, they actually just hurt you and it's like well if they actually hurt you that sort of Right.
Rym: It was if it was if the weird sexual stuff wasn't there.
Scott: cuz it feels reading that yes I want you to literally waterboard me so that I feel like I am suffocating.
Scott: Yeah, I'll be fucking scared that you're gonna fuck up and I'm gonna die.
Rym: You know what though?
Rym: imagine if it were that.
Rym: but it wasn't themed as a haunted house.
Rym: It was themed as like a James Bond adventure.
Rym: But for real where you have to like fight dudes off and I get a pain.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't want anyone to actually hurt me.
Scott: Why would I want to actually be hurt?
Rym: Well, it doesn't physically hurt you.
Rym: It's just terrifying.
Scott: Uh, if somebody's fucking suffocating you.
Scott: Yeah or whipping you.
Rym: That would be an interesting experience.
Scott: You can sign up for that.
Rym: I would.
Rym: it's like Penn Jillette when he said well famously that yeah if you're into that They have those no, but he said famously that when he finally does die.
Rym: He wants to die in lingering Excruciating pain because he's a large dungeon in this house.
Rym: He'd at least like to know what that feels like but then he qualified it by saying but not anytime soon.
Scott: you fucking sickos Yeah I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm planned to go out doing all kinds of drugs to know what they feel like.
Scott: cuz the side effects and permanent harm of The drugs won't matter if I'm gonna die soon.
Rym: I read that article about how bath salts basically cause permanent brain damage.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want bath salts.
Scott: Let's not talk about that.
Scott: So what would it say?
Rym: Wait, there's a haunted house.
Rym: You drug people with LSD on the way in sure.
Scott: Here's how you actually make the haunted house.
Scott: Here's the parameters right?
Scott: What you need to do is you need to make it.
Scott: you can't fool anyone with special effects like us Right.
Scott: It has to be Actual.
Scott: I would argue there could be special effects that could fool me But you wouldn't actually believe that they were actually like a monster or that you you need to believe monster No, but like knife trap.
Rym: that is so realistic, right?
Scott: You need to somehow penetrate your suspension of disbelief, right?
Scott: Which is incredibly difficult, right?
Scott: Because at first you're gonna think yeah Okay fake skeleton right.
Scott: then the skeletons coming after you and you're like, yeah that skeletons not actually gonna hurt me It's a haunted.
Scott: It's a haunted house.
Scott: That's a pretty cool skeleton.
Scott: I admire your handiwork.
Scott: then it kills your dad cuz he's in on it, right and you're like, yeah, okay I know my dad's in on it.
Scott: Yeah, my dad's not actually dead.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Whatever right?
Scott: It needs to actually, you know, it's getting close to you and you're like, yeah It's not gonna actually hurt me.
Scott: It needs to get so close to actually hurting you that it Doesn't smash you.
Scott: obviously cuz I don't actually hurt anyone like that stupid haunted house.
Scott: But it needs to get so close to hurting you that it just doesn't hurt you But hurts your suspension of disbelief and shatters.
Scott: Oh Scott And at that moment, you will actually be fearing for your life or tearing for your body.
Rym: did that for a moment?
Rym: It had this one of the early areas.
Rym: There's like this graveyard and an iron like fence blocking it off like a really tall fence And there's this guy with the shovel kind of shambling around over there and there's a gates there's a fence You're like looking at him and walking by and it's kind of like a zoo and and he kind of shambles over to the fence And then he just like fucking tears it open and there's more.
Rym: It's kind of like a boo but like you thought he couldn't be near you and then suddenly the the parameters changed.
Rym: Yep, changing the parameters.
Rym: I think is a good way to start the suspension.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I think so Here's the thing you can't use it's not?
Scott: you can't jump out and go boo because that's startling or surprised It's not fear.
Rym: So he just follows us for a while with this shovel Yeah.
Rym: and then eventually he's like he's really close to us and he's standing like Literally, like we like a centimeter or two behind my mom like right there like right next to her Yeah, and he's holding this shovel like whatever and then he looks at her and he raises the shovel.
Rym: It's like yeah He's not gonna hear with the show and then he swings it at her way hard and it ended up being a boffer shovel But it but because he'd been beating it against something before.
Rym: I think there was a piece of metal in it that he then like Palmed later.
Rym: It looked like it was a real shovel that he was beating against metal.
Rym: And then he hit my mother with the same shovel and it did not it.
Rym: There was no point where I realized that he had swapped it out or done something different.
Scott: Yeah, that's not bad.
Scott: There was a momentary suspension of disbelief not bad.
Scott: So that's getting close to what I'm thinking right?
Scott: So or maybe that is even on target.
Scott: So You can't do startling and surprise.
Scott: You also can't do oh my god, so gross cuz.
Scott: that doesn't work on everybody, right?
Scott: There's only some Pete and it's like it's weird cuz like for me.
Scott: if I see real gore like some like a surgery on TV I'm gonna bargo right and that would I guess that does account.
Scott: it's more nauseous than scared, right?
Scott: So what do you think?
Rym: or because there was a situation?
Scott: I watch movies that I know are not real movies But the gore is realistic or even better than realistic and has no effect on me whatsoever.
Scott: So if I know that I'm in the haunted house, there's no gore that could actually get me And in fact, maybe I don't know about this.
Scott: But maybe if you like what if someone actually like spilled their intestines out for reals while I was in a haunted house Would I be grossed out?
Scott: Cuz it's real gore.
Scott: and maybe a psycho murderer broke into the haunted house and thought he could get away with psycho murders in there.
Scott: So Scott there, I don't know what would happen.
Rym: There are multiple stories that are true and I've got pictures of them right here.
Rym: this mummy and haunted house.
Rym: It was a real dead guy.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: No one knew they just had this body that was hanging.
Rym: and the story is this is this is like for real.
Rym: some kids were basically in this haunted house one day and they're dicking around and They like hit it and I broke open.
Rym: there was a bone in there and it was a real body.
Rym: It was this guy who was killed.
Rym: Okay, so it was real gore But nobody freaked out because of it.
Rym: it appears that the people who discover that it was a real body did in fact freak out Right, but the people who just saw it in the haunted house did never.
Rym: yeah So what if the haunted house was set up for something looks like a cheesy decoration?
Rym: But then like it breaks and there it looks really realistically like there was a real body in there like someone fucked up.
Scott: I wouldn't believe it like, you know, it's really a replica.
Rym: Here's another one.
Rym: This is a real dead dude, but everyone thought it was a Halloween decoration.
Rym: Okay So it can't happen.
Scott: it would be very hard for me to actually start believing that it was an actual, you know.
Scott: Anyway, because it's like, you know, like anyway, whatever like how it would had to be basically So perfect and I would have to investigate it for so long before I believed it was actually a dead person.
Scott: Right, because even if the staff came in and were like, oh shit, I'd be like, yeah, they're faking it, right?
Scott: It's like you would need like the real police to come and you know You need so much for me to suspend the disbelief.
Scott: by then I wouldn't even be near the body anymore to freak out.
Scott: So here's the here's the haunted house thing.
Scott: I came up with right?
Rym: All right.
Rym: I still like my LSD idea.
Scott: That's not a bad idea, but it's also sort of cheating but it's not bad.
Scott: Plus you don't know if that'll scare everybody but if you accompany it with this the imagery of hauntedness it probably work.
Scott: so here's the idea I came up with.
Scott: that would be Possibly and it's close to your shovel example, right?
Scott: All right, you go into a narrow hallway, right?
Scott: And obviously for safety reasons there is an escape but it is hidden so no one knows about it and it's like.
Scott: You know, you just want to make the fire marshal happy, right?
Scott: But no one can see it and it's so hard to see.
Scott: but it could be open from the outside by the workers Right, so it's it totally safe.
Scott: and then you go down the narrow hallway.
Scott: So you're all single file.
Scott: Then you're cramped in like he and it's all decorated haunted like and you get to the end of the hallway into the door And it's fucking locked and you really can't open it.
Scott: So you go dirt bitter.
Scott: It's gonna open we know okay Maybe this is secret.
Scott: Whatever you try to go back Yeah, we lock the door behind you also and you're actually locked in except for the fire exit that you know, so You're in there for a while, right and you're like what the fuck.
Rym: so This terror on Church Street another scene that happened, right?
Rym: you eventually come into this room that has like a fireplace with what looks like a real fire going and There's these figures all sitting around the table shrouded black that just don't move.
Rym: They look like statues or people but you can't tell yeah, and then the door closes locks behind you and nothing happens.
Scott: Yeah for many minutes You got to have someone watching the people in there because there's gonna be the difference.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: The reality is all the people sitting around the table weren't dummies?
Rym: Of course not but they still didn't move at all.
Rym: Good job, so we're sitting there and we're sitting there and we're sitting there and we're sitting there and I would have investigated them.
Rym: Though yeah, we did so we started investigating and once we finally someone goes over to the table and as soon as they get really close one of like They all stand up and turn and they all simultaneously point toward this for toward the fireplace.
Scott: Yeah, I'd be like, yeah Okay, I know that you're all people So I that wouldn't work.
Rym: so continue.
Scott: so you're trapped in this thing and everyone's watching.
Scott: right that the staff are watching to make to follow you through the stages of Horror of being locked in for reals, right or mostly for reals.
Scott: as far as you can't get out you look for secret exits.
Scott: You have to make it like I would almost you try to bash down the doors on either end.
Scott: They don't open Go out and you know this or there's barely any lighting and you just actually can't get out.
Rym: I would do yours Like the power had gone out and like the employees were gone or something too.
Scott: Yeah, cuz then you know that that's bullshit.
Rym: Not necessarily.
Scott: Well, you know this bullshit.
Scott: I would I would assume a right away that that was bullshit and you had to leave me locked in there for quite a while before like the point where you're actually worried right.
Scott: and then what you do is you come in with the Spikes.
Scott: this, you know, these ceiling opens up and spikes come down right and it's like, okay.
Scott: Yeah, haha Those are gonna stop before they actually hurt anybody right?
Scott: Everyone knows that you're not gonna actually, you know Impale me on a spike ceiling that's coming down like freakin trash compactor in Star Wars, right?
Scott: Or you can even do the walls squishing in also and it's like yeah, those are gonna stop, right?
Scott: You know, we'll just stand here in the middle and then whatever right but then they keep coming and they keep coming and it's like It's like, okay, they're gonna stop real soon but now you're like forced to actually lie on the ground because they're gonna keep coming and It's like oh Jesus Christ They're really letting these things go farther than they will.
Scott: and then like they're actually sort of poking you But you're not actually stabbed right?
Scott: They're just sort of poking you and you're like, uh, Yeah To the point where you're actually made, you know You got to keep it going can't actually stab anyone with the spikes but you got to get it to the point where they're worried and then At the last second instead of you know, it stops or it pulls back or there's squishy spikes or anything like that.
Scott: You got to do something else and my idea that I came up with was spikes coming down from the ceiling.
Scott: You're basically lying on the floor sucking in your gut and then the floor opens and you fall Alright, so you're actually falling now.
Scott: You obviously can't make me fall too far because they'll get hurt and you can't make them fall onto something dangerous because they will get Hurt.
Scott: you don't want to do that.
Scott: That's not cool That's.
Scott: you might as well go to the haunted house with the waterboarding if you can do that, right?
Scott: But while you're falling that you a surprise.
Scott: you are actually falling now.
Scott: Your body will go and now you might think that's a startling kind of cheating.
Scott: it is.
Scott: it is so what you.
Scott: but the thing is immediately after the startling part comes you use that to basically, that's not the thing itself.
Scott: what it is is the disabling and distraction of the minds that the fear can come in without time to process the Doubt.
Scott: and what you see is when you look down there would be some while you're still falling in that, you know mere moments there would be an illusion of some kinds that you look like you're gonna fall onto deadly spikes below.
Scott: and You know, you might think yeah, those are fake, but you don't have time to think that when you're falling like that now I think a low and then of course It's just an illusion and you fall into something soft and go a lower.
Rym: if I way to do that Would be to do it is obviously very high-five would be to do a blindfolded haunted house.
Rym: Not bad, but then I know where you are blindfolded and then led Well, you know like holding hands Okay, very long distance because then there's the fear of what if they fuck up that'll be increasingly grow.
Scott: that would not grow.
Scott: I just feel like yeah, I know they're leading me a safe place because the haunted house?
Rym: No, but they might make a mistake.
Rym: They might remember.
Scott: Now I would not be worried about that.
Rym: I'm not worried about scaring you because fuck you I wanted to make a haunted house that scares most people as opposed to Well, if you want it most people are pussies.
Scott: you can scare him with a baby rollercoaster.
Scott: you can eat.
Rym: I still feel my favorite haunted house idea is to do the sort of Meta haunted house where you've got like the normal haunted house.
Rym: There's the normal dressed up guy and he's dressed up as like the Jason serial killer and he's doing his thing And then he notices another guy who's kind of normal looking and then they have like a little confrontation And then the first guy just fucking stabs him and the other guy runs and it seems like it's a serial killer got loose.
Scott: Everyone who would not?
Scott: who would actually believe that?
Rym: I think a lot of you would believe it morons.
Rym: That's how people roll.
Rym: Plus really the proper way to do a scare haunted house is to make it not a haunted house But more like a prank more like a good night for flying.
Scott: Well, that's the other thing right.
Scott: as soon as you've got somebody know.
Scott: that's the best.
Scott: the challenge though right is if you bring me in, you know, someone who's very hard to scare and I don't know.
Scott: I'm going it.
Scott: if I know I'm going in a haunted house, then the shields It's like shields on full.
Scott: you ain't get me with.
Rym: so do it like a Japanese show like the one with the sniper if I Sniper start shooting everyone in the room.
Scott: I do not know I'm going into a haunted house.
Scott: Then it's really much much easier to scare me because I do not have the shields on full.
Scott: You know if someone just like fucking dies, I'll be like in the middle of the street while I'm walking to work.
Scott: I think that that's what happened right as opposed to in the haunted house.
Scott: If someone dies, my first thought is yeah, that's fake.
Rym: So maybe you just make an old house like a bed-and-breakfast that people go up to and you know, it's not a haunted house.
Rym: But you just run a haunted house like spooky shit happens for the people who don't realize it's on a house.
Scott: Yeah, they just think they're staying in a bed-and-breakfast.
Rym: legit and then you know, it escalates and scary shit keeps happening.
Scott: Yeah, that that totally works.
Rym: The thing is that that's too easy.
Rym: No, it's not too easy.
Scott: No, it's a haunted house.
Rym: That edges away from haunted house and into prank territory.
Scott: Yes, but it's also too too easy For it's like shoot.
Scott: It's easy to shoot.
Scott: a guy doesn't have shields up to hit a guy when he's got full armor.
Scott: That is hard Scott.
Rym: If I manage some shields, you gotta get rid of those shields.
Scott: No, you just have to penetrate.
Rym: So this is all about penetration.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: You should go to that sexual assault creep You want in New York City?
Scott: You got to use missiles that go.
Rym: I don't know if they actually penetrate you.
Scott: I don't think they do.
Rym: The reviews of that thing were weird.
Scott: It's not something I'm gonna pay money.
Rym: but no, I'm a big fan of the haunted house or something like it where literally Everyone is in on the gimmick except one person not just on house.
Rym: in general I love anything where there is one person and Everyone else involved in the situation is in on something that they are not in.
Scott: I remember this one prank where they had this friend who is some dumb girl who believed that in like the rapture and shit and Then like she went to the bathroom and they all left their stuff behind and she thought the rapture it happened.
Scott: That's that kind of thing my favorite, but that's only worked on a really dumb person.
Rym: Ah, but the the good night for flying would work on anyone that combined Hi-fi special effects.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: artful like, you know an artful setup good acting and everyone sticking to the part Mm-hmm, and the person didn't know they were going on.
Rym: but then here's the problem.
Rym: Even if you do that in a situation where it is a haunted house Like say it's a haunted house like a whole bunch of friends go But actually ahead of time all but one friend is in on some elaborate plot.
Rym: The problem is that's impractical because that's the same level as close-up magic.
Rym: close-up magic is awesome.
Rym: That is magic.
Rym: or you have a magician like a Penn and Teller level magician doing tricks for you Only in front of you at a table.
Scott: Here's another idea.
Scott: I just came up with.
Scott: it's somewhat of a genius idea.
Scott: You go into a haunted house, it's just a very good haunted house.
Scott: Maybe it has some really good stuff.
Rym: your friend disappears.
Scott: So you are.
Scott: no you are satisfied with the price you pay for this haunted house.
Scott: Then you exit the haunted house Believing it is over when it is.
Scott: In fact not over.
Rym: I was in a haunted house.
Rym: once for example, I had the exit right.
Scott: for example at the end of the haunted house There would be a gift shop like a cracker barrel, but then serial killer jumps out in the gift shop No more.
Scott: like you just get fucking abducted in the gift shop.
Scott: and you're like you.
Scott: you're in a you know places that look normal Like someone grabs you and pulls you into like the janitor closet and it's just a janitor closet, but it's like oh fucking shit, right?
Scott: It's like you could get someone with that kind of thing Because they believe the haunted house is over and there's just like a crazy person.
Scott: So I was at the at the you know haunted hayride area.
Scott: It was no game on the house right at the pumpkin farm and then you see a thing that's like exit.
Rym: you walk out and you're In this like you're.
Rym: like it looks like you're in the parking lot But really you don't kind of notice.
Rym: but actually there's some stuff further on and it's still kind of like cordoned off But you don't realize it right away because you feel like you're in the parking lot.
Rym: They got a bunch of cars parked there and then they have this one fake car that Suddenly revs up and comes right at you and stops like a foot away from hitting you.
Rym: Not bad Just a boo, but you know what?
Scott: Well, no, it's a boo when the car revs up But when the car is coming at you now, it's fear of dying.
Rym: But it's fear of dying if you go.
Rym: if you believe not haunted house, of course just asshole driver It's fear.
Scott: Well, you could believe that there's a ghost driving.
Scott: No, you couldn't If you were dumb.
Scott: but no but you could you know that you would actually have real fear if you if you actually thought the car was gonna hit you and You didn't say it's gonna stop.
Rym: So here's what you do at the end.
Rym: There's a gift shop, right?
Rym: Yeah You get to the gift shop and there's a bunch of people laying like dead covered in blood In what looks like the gift shop and stuff's all fucked up.
Rym: and then a bunch of cops bust in with guns and point them at you and start screaming at everyone to get on the ground and then make you lay on the ground While they investigate this grizzly murder for like five minutes.
Scott: Here's another way to do it.
Scott: Imagine this scenario, right?
Rym: Yeah I'm listening.
Scott: so you go to a Farm on Halloween at night and it's got a pumpkin patch and it's got the corn maze and it's got all the two.
Scott: You know apple cider doughnuts all this stuff, right?
Scott: There is no haunted house there.
Scott: There is.
Scott: maybe there's a corny haunted hayride.
Scott: that kind of sucks, right?
Scott: And that's you know, you're just hanging out with the family at the nice haunted fall activity, right?
Scott: But then see you don't have any thought that you're in a haunted house.
Scott: You're just standing in line for fucking cider doughnuts, right?
Scott: Cuz that's the longest line and you got your apple cider.
Scott: you're sipping it, right?
Scott: But then actually the whole thing is a haunted event You just don't know and there was no way for you to expect that to be.
Scott: and then the shit goes down on the whole place at the same time Right and as long as it's done in a way, that's believable.
Rym: So if you go full-on cuz remember, you know Penn and Teller one of their big things I just keep bringing it up lately.
Rym: It seems like the right time is that they always make this point that their magic really works because Nobody really believes that someone would put forth that much effort exactly.
Rym: and the answer is yes They put forth that much ever had to put.
Rym: someone really practiced crawling through a tube like that.
Scott: Yes So you just have to put that much effort into that giant event.
Rym: All right, so that giant event scare all the people who had giant event.
Rym: Everyone at the event except you like the like maybe like the people who paid tickets like maybe 20 people there aren't in on it.
Rym: Everyone else there is in.
Scott: I think it's better.
Scott: Staff and the police are in on it.
Scott: and maybe in the fire department I'm talking like none of the people who paid to be there.
Rym: I'm talking like zombies break out but you start to realize that you know Hundreds and hundreds of people here are all Acting like zombies.
Scott: it's too many you want to get.
Scott: the thing is if you put that much effort you could find a way to Scare most of the people and not actually have to have all the people in on it.
Scott: You could just bring in.
Scott: you know outside people.
Rym: I know I just really dig and then you could do people.
Scott: You could do really cool stuff like fucking.
Scott: the place is fucking on fire and you're trapped inside and the fire Departments coming and you think it's a real fire.
Rym: and but then again, it's not a haunted house.
Scott: go set the fire.
Rym: That's why I think the best haunted houses would be ones that aren't advertised as such.
Rym: however You know what that leads to.
Rym: an episode of unsolved mystery is about the haunted bed-and-breakfast.
Scott: George Washington stayed here and his ghost talked to me.
Rym: So maybe that's it.
Rym: maybe we need to take the next level.
Rym: We need to go to like all the beds and breakfasts in places like that and you plant the seed Like in.
Rym: will he run here's another great and then you just have the ghost of George Washington talk to someone and never Up to it.
Scott: here is that now that guy Scott thinks he saw a ghost I have an idea that might land you in trouble, but it will absolutely work.
Scott: every time one time.
Rym: I saw goes.
Scott: This is the idea.
Scott: I just came up with two seconds ago reverse haunted house we are.
Scott: we just go to a bed-and-breakfast and we haunt the fuck out of the people who own it or We go to a regular boring ass haunted hayride as customers But we just haunt the fuck out of the people who work there.
Scott: Right because it's like they're just some guy standing in a costume but jumps out and goes boo every time.
Rym: Oh, yes, this is we And I'm dressed up as like a skeleton monster and I just come up behind the guy who's working the boo factory.
Scott: Yeah, you can totally scare the fuck out of those people.
Scott: real easy, right?
Scott: or you know, we go to a haunted Cheesy Frankenstein house in Niagara Falls and scare the fuck out of.
Scott: he was gone.
Rym: that has a secondary effect.
Scott: So say the hayride going to jail for?
Scott: no.
Rym: No, so the hayrides coming up, right?
Rym: The boo factory guy comes out to do his boo and the kids go and the adults go hahaha.
Rym: and then me and my skeleton costume taps him on the shoulder and he goes on runs away.
Rym: a Percentage of the people who went haha before now go.
Scott: Ah, yeah.
Scott: So now I have upped the ante on everyone especially if I then disappear and since you do not work for the place You get up there and actually like fuck with the people.
Rym: serious like no You don't even have to.
Rym: then you disappear like dish like destroy the costume and just leave That way.
Rym: You know There's this rumor like the one guy's like this fucking skeleton monster came out who was dressed up as that and now you've scared them all in the meta because they're all like there was No one in a costume like that.
Rym: Haha.
Rym: You must just have been seeing things but in the back of their mind They're all like Or you know you could do right.
Scott: you best Imagine the haunted hayride is going along right and there's the people working it or doing their thing But you and me are hiding in the woods.
Scott: We snuck onto the property, right?
Scott: I got like a Jason thing going on and like I had you to death and you bleed all over the fucking die, right?
Scott: Yeah, but then you know the people working the haunted hair.
Scott: I would be make sure they see it.
Scott: So they're like what the fuck?
Scott: that's not part of our haunted hayride?
Scott: Well, yeah, and they come over to investigate but by then both of us are gone, but they swear to fucking God.
Scott: They saw exactly.
Scott: now they are fucking hidden.
Scott: We get like camo and we hide under like, you know a sheet of leaves.
Rym: now Scott there you're talking leaves a leaf blanket.
Rym: Here's why that is great.
Rym: Look at the normal person who shrieks and actually gets like startled and scared.
Rym: it even based on houses They're okay at the end because you know what they get they get closure.
Rym: There is eventually an exit where they say, you know The context has changed kind of like how when humans walk through doors, they forget stuff.
Rym: Yeah, the experience is over.
Rym: if you do a meta thing like that with no closure Even if it's a minor thing like like it's the same as goodnight for flying.
Rym: They're second-guessing what they actually saw.
Rym: they start thinking did I really see that?
Rym: I remember seeing it, but no one else saw it.
Rym: There's no evidence.
Rym: and now they're weirded out, but they never get closure because you just went back home.
Scott: Yeah, we're hot.
Scott: We had like a blanket covered in leaves so hide under it until no no and then we both.
Rym: if you do that Every year at like one towns like haunted hayride Eventually the workers at that haunted hayride don't be actually afraid of ghosts No, but they'll be camping out for you.
Rym: No, they won't spot.
Rym: No, you do something different and fucked up every year And then one year you don't do any to us Simultaneously.
Scott: make sure it matches some local legend or spread a legend to match.
Rym: Yeah now we're talking.
Rym: So GeekNights listeners.
Rym: You know what to do.
Rym: You're under 18.
Rym: You're not gonna go to jail.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot-com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.