Rym: It's Monday July 2nd 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight hardware lockdown and all that bullshit.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: We often say this at the start of the show, but warm today.
Rym: It is warm, but actually even warmer yesterday.
Scott: Ah It's not yet been so warm that I did not want it to be Warmer not at all.
Rym: However, there was a Guy today in fact a 10-minute span yesterday when we were biking up the hill in the Sun with no breeze Back from New Jersey where I would have liked it to be cooler.
Rym: in a zone around my body for about 10 minutes There's.
Scott: I was getting a fruit juice at the juice truck today juice cart.
Rym: and what kind of fruit juice?
Scott: I think it was pineapple orange banana mango.
Scott: Yeah, and There's a guy in front of me and a tourist walks up and says right where's Rockefeller Center?
Scott: and I'm like right behind that fucking building.
Scott: and the guy in front of me is like, ah, thanks cuz I didn't I didn't remember where it was and I was like Okay, and he's like it's pretty warm today.
Scott: and I'm like, yeah, it's pretty warm But I'd rather have be warmer like maybe 120.
Rym: I've had that weird that same kind of conversation with a lot of strangers lately.
Rym: if someone complains about the heat or says something about The heat.
Rym: Yeah, and my response is always I'd like it to be about 10 degrees hotter.
Scott: I'm like, I wanted to be about 120 right and the guys like what was the last time you were in 120?
Scott: and I'm like The shower.
Scott: Nah, and he's like, uh, he's like I've been in 120.
Scott: It was rough But I was carrying a whole bunch of gear and he was.
Scott: uh I assume he was probably like an India Sun because he was an Indian guy.
Scott: So Racist, I'm just saying because India is a warm place It's near the equator.
Rym: I would not terribly enjoy once.
Scott: I assume that that's the place that he was when it was 120.
Rym: I actually prefer about 95.
Rym: That's my like go-to zone for heat.
Rym: I'll take 500,000 anyway, so as you all know as I tweeted there was you know, we got an extra second over the weekend.
Rym: We had a leap second now.
Rym: I don't really want to debate the long weekend guys.
Rym: Yeah deep question, man Why could we get that leap second during packs?
Scott: I know right.
Rym: Anyway, so, you know The whether or not we need to do that is up for debate because we live on earth.
Rym: we don't live anywhere else.
Rym: So keep your time.
Rym: It's because in sync with earth in the fact that the earth is slowing down Make sense that we have to update our calendar, but at the same time Leap seconds cause Linux to shit itself.
Rym: There are there are numerous kernel bugs in Linux and there's all sorts of different issues.
Rym: But basically if any of you out there have a Linux server, I would highly recommend at some point From today onward reboot it because Some crap happens and you might think oh, this is just tech people being alarmist.
Rym: I Personally witnessed such crazy things as threads being spawned But then the kernel thought that they returned from like nano sleep before they started because the kernel was off by exactly a second from the system time in another place because it didn't handle the leap second right and Crazy bullshit happened and I'm.
Rym: I will link to you two Examples of this because this is a real problem I actually had to deal with as a computer.
Scott: the problem was very much tied to Java.
Scott: I noticed a lot of the fixes.
Scott: Ah, there were two separate sets of problems Related and I know you do Java stuff because I had no problems with my lampsticks.
Rym: Yep No, Java itself would have problems with this but independently there were some generic system things that could also go.
Scott: wonder if Java had The problem on Windows or Mac or something.
Rym: I don't know because Windows servers get rebooted all the time.
Scott: So Yeah, I mean my my opinion on leap second right is if you want to keep the calendar in sync with the earth Which I think we need to for now.
Scott: The reason that you keep the calendar in sync with the earth is so that the seasons line up right with things.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know you can say for example aha It'll always be cold in December right and you know around the Christmas time.
Scott: Otherwise if we don't do that, eventually we're gonna have Christmas summer sit.
Rym: you know That happened at several points in our history.
Scott: You're gonna have San Diego.
Scott: comic-con is every year in July.
Scott: Oh, why is it snowing?
Scott: Fuck?
Scott: That's why I guess It doesn't snow in San Diego.
Rym: That's why we kept.
Rym: you know First we had to leap years and then the rules were every four years, but not every hundred years But yes every 400, right?
Scott: So that's why we have.
Scott: you know If we're gonna keep the calendar we have and keep it in sync with the seasons you got to leap it but the only air.
Scott: so the alternative is either keep doing what we're doing or Metric kind of calendar.
Rym: Yeah, you know what.
Rym: there was a metric calendar, you know what it.
Rym: you know, how many people used it?
Rym: one zero.
Rym: It was in France Napoleon era.
Rym: it was all tens.
Rym: It was kind of stupid didn't really work.
Scott: Did you see those trucks that were delivering some sort of alcohol and had a giant Napoleon on the side?
Scott: No We piked right past him.
Rym: I guess I wasn't making tension.
Scott: but there's some brand of alcohol and the.
Scott: the label is Napoleon.
Scott: and I wonder like is that the The alcohol that Napoleon liked to drink?
Scott: is it made by him?
Scott: Is it made by you know?
Scott: I'm pretty sure it is it made in the place that he's from.
Scott: what's the deal with it?
Rym: Where is Napoleon?
Rym: from France?
Rym: Corsica anyway.
Rym: But you know biking is neither here nor there nor our kernel panic.
Rym: So this is when I was didn't really a kernel panic.
Rym: if it was just panicked that would have been fine.
Rym: if Linux had just Crashed would have been cool.
Rym: But the fact that in Determinate state where threads didn't behave right my god.
Scott: But anyway, I'm going to Corsica.
Rym: I'll see you later to talk about some more, you know to have a news bit I had a personal experience recently see.
Rym: almost exactly a week ago.
Rym: I opened a door and I had my cell phone in my pocket and I bumped it against the door in my pocket Normal bump the kind of thing that happens all the time.
Rym: But later I get to work and I pull my phone out.
Rym: You know my instinct to look at it for something and I noticed the screen has shattered.
Rym: So I had to go.
Rym: I didn't you know.
Rym: I couldn't just get it replaced at the Sprint store because that's not covered by the normal warranty.
Rym: nor is my phone You know new.
Rym: And I didn't want to sign another two-year contract with Sprint because Google Glass and the new iPhone are on the horizon.
Rym: I'm not gonna sign up a two-year contract for the privilege of paying $200 instead of $700 for the next Samsung phone.
Rym: that isn't as good as the phone I've got.
Rym: So I look at my options.
Rym: basically, I found for like a hundred bucks a refurbished Identical version of my phone from some guy was used.
Rym: he like refurbished it and sold it on Amazon.
Rym: So I bought it and I activated it.
Rym: and you know what.
Rym: right now ice cream sandwich is reinstalling looks fine alright, but I had to go a week without a cell phone and It was rough.
Rym: Yeah, but it's interesting.
Rym: It wasn't rough in the ways.
Rym: I expected I did not feel Withdrawal the way so many articles said I would because the phone is like an extension.
Scott: Just rough in that anytime you want to look at it.
Scott: You go.
Scott: Ah, it's not there.
Rym: I felt like I was missing a sense Like I felt like one of my senses was gone the sense of access external memory and know exactly where I am Geophysically at all times because the day my phone broke I had to bike home.
Rym: All right, I'll bike home.
Rym: I start biking.
Rym: I get just far enough away from work to where we take too long to walk back before the building was closed and Nowhere near a subway station and my rear tire exploded.
Rym: I don't carry a patch kit on me or anything.
Rym: So I'm like fuck All right.
Rym: Well, I'll just look up where a bike shop.
Rym: fuck fuck Start walking.
Rym: I ask everyone I pass.
Rym: Hey, is there a bike shop around here?
Scott: You know, there's one on both sides of the bridge.
Rym: So yeah, which bridge?
Scott: the one that you used to get home?
Rym: Yeah, so I couldn't find one.
Rym: So I found one bike shop at the base of the Williamsburg bridge.
Rym: They did not have tires in the size of my bike.
Scott: Why didn't you just get a tube?
Scott: you need a tire for?
Rym: because the tire was shot a nay This gigantic like wood screw went through it sideways.
Rym: I don't even know how.
Rym: so there was a chunk out of it.
Rym: There was no way safe way to ride on that tire.
Rym: tire was fucked.
Rym: so that bike shop couldn't help me and No one could tell me where another bike shop was.
Rym: So I just kept walking north until I hit 14th Street Because I knew there was a bike shop there that I knew could help me and I got my bike fixed And then I biked home.
Scott: I know a bike shop less.
Scott: That's more south than 14th Street.
Scott: You go to bike habitat, which is on Lafayette.
Rym: Yeah, I would have to find that with no phone and apparently I know exactly.
Rym: Now.
Rym: yeah I now I know why people ask for directions all the time in New York because I learned that if you ask someone in New York for directions the majority of them unless you're asking for subway directions have no fucking idea.
Rym: Yep They don't know where anything is.
Rym: you ask someone like hey, where's you know, the Empire Staple?
Scott: I told you today the guy in front of me was a New Yorker and someone asked him Where's Rockefeller Center and I knew where it was and we were like one block away from it.
Rym: He's like no, but if that person had asked hey, how do I get to the F train?
Rym: They'd be like one block.
Scott: that way maybe the F train was actually right underneath.
Scott: worst.
Rym: But the fact that bike like the other day at Saturday had to bike to the beach again not having my instant Always on always perfect GPS on me huge problem.
Scott: I actually made it to the beach of the map made of paper.
Rym: I don't carry maps made of paper because my phone is so much faster than that.
Scott: It's not much faster than paper.
Rym: Uh, yeah, I think the problem is you're on an iPhone Loads no matter what Scott my phone loads no matter what.
Rym: the whole of New York is cashed and the GPS is Independent of my data plan.
Rym: So even if I'm an airplane mode, I turn it on.
Rym: It shows me exactly where I am on the map.
Scott: Uh-huh, like within five seconds of turning my screen on five seconds I could do the map whole map in less than five seconds.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Really?
Rym: All right, pull your map out.
Rym: go Three four.
Scott: if I had the map I would have been out and back in our.
Rym: I highly doubt that Having having that phone on me all the time.
Scott: This is what this is what it's like if I have the map ready.
Scott: ready Huh?
Scott: It took two seconds, I actually doubt that the map is out.
Scott: It's folded to the spot where you are is already facing out.
Scott: But how do you know where you are?
Scott: take it?
Scott: Cuz you look at the street sign or some shit.
Rym: All right, so you've already had to look at the street sign.
Scott: How do you know where you are?
Scott: and in Metro?
Scott: It's like Metroid right you push start to bring the map up.
Scott: Oh and you push start again in the maps gone.
Scott: How do I know where?
Scott: I know I'm in fucking Norfair?
Rym: All right You gotta find it.
Rym: what if your bike?
Scott: I know the elevator was three screens to the left.
Scott: cuz I've gone.
Scott: three screens.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So you know what the map out of Norfair I go.
Rym: Oh, yeah You already have to pull the map out.
Rym: my phone already shows me exactly where I am and my cargo direction.
Scott: pulling the phone out.
Scott: It's just as long as you're kidding pulling my phone You got to unlock the phone and then you got to push the map icon.
Rym: Actually, the maps already open because I put my phone in navigation mode with the Google my places thing Not my places Google on my tracks.
Rym: Uh-huh So whenever I'm going anywhere, my phone is always in like super GPS mode.
Rym: Mmm, you should try that.
Rym: Oh wait, you have an iPhone.
Rym: That's not that stuff works.
Rym: I just see your maps are kind of shitty.
Scott: My map is paper map is the best.
Rym: Yeah Because you have an iPhone with shitty Google Maps.
Rym: if you had a Google map that worked all the time Really catching a lot.
Scott: I I'm not saying I'm not gonna have a phone I'm saying the paper map is faster.
Rym: But the thing that I missed the most was literally primarily if the paper map was in fear.
Scott: here I use the best technology for any job.
Rym: Yes, and I think the best technology for that is Made of paper the Android phone.
Scott: So anyway, and your battery dies.
Scott: and now I look at my paper map My battery is fine.
Rym: actually doing biking.
Rym: a whole day of biking with GPS is fine.
Scott: Anyway, you done.
Rym: Uh, no But it was in I'm thinking about.
Rym: I'm trying to like put down all the like problems I ran into in my life not having this phone and I guess I'd always kind of posited like how heavily I rely on having an always-on always available data plan with GPS and all these things and Not having it for a week Validated that to a ludicrous degree.
Rym: Like maybe I might have thought oh, maybe I can get away just fine with my foot without my phone.
Rym: No, I can't.
Rym: that phone is so pivotal to my life That I would have to change my entire way of doing things if I were not to have a phone for an extended period of Time.
Scott: and this is the person when you didn't have a smartphone.
Scott: You're even against getting a phone with a camera on it.
Scott: and I was like Just like when you were using Internet Explorer and I was like you should really use fire When I was against cameras on phones.
Rym: That was when I worked in a place where if you had a camera on your phone You weren't allowed to bring it in the building.
Scott: Listen many times throughout history.
Scott: I've been the one Example so one.
Rym: I wasn't allowed to bring a phone.
Scott: No, you were also in my office.
Scott: You got one while you were working at that place.
Scott: In fact, right?
Scott: So apparently it wasn't too much of an issue and you did not end.
Scott: that was your at the time.
Scott: You said I quote you do.
Scott: that was not your excuse for not needing one.
Scott: Your excuse was who needs a camera on a phone?
Rym: So Scott stupid my first cell phone didn't have a camera.
Rym: because of that they didn't exist.
Rym: Yeah, they did.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, I got another phone later.
Rym: I worked in a different building.
Rym: at that point I could have a camera but the cat the pictures the camera took were so shitty.
Scott: and Yeah, you use that camera Relatively often.
Rym: actually.
Rym: that what I didn't cuz I had no way to get the pictures off of that phone.
Scott: I remember you getting the pictures off.
Rym: No, no, you're thinking of my pre.
Scott: No the blue phone.
Rym: I couldn't get pictures off of that.
Scott: I remember you getting pictures.
Rym: I had no way to get pictures off of that.
Rym: I had a fee.
Rym: I took pictures of things I Lost.
Rym: my next phone was the palm pre and you know what.
Rym: the camera was high enough megapixel and I could just dump them to My computer.
Rym: that suddenly the camera was awesome.
Rym: the only reason the camera wasn't awesome on the older phones is because the phone the pictures on those cameras sucked and it was hard to Get the pictures off on those old ass phones.
Scott: Just want to say who needs tab browsing?
Scott: who?
Scott: Who needs a phone with a camera in it?
Scott: who need right?
Scott: this is Rym.
Rym: Like smartphones, I wanted a smartphone from day one, but I couldn't afford one.
Scott: Yeah, uncle moneybags vice president couldn't afford to smart.
Rym: Yes, because I was a vice president in like 2006 a lot of people we know who are way poor.
Scott: they got plenty of smartphones.
Rym: Okay, you realize data plans were a lot more expensive.
Scott: They're still the same 2004-2005 more expensive now because they're giving you less.
Rym: and also back then a lot of phones.
Rym: the GPS Sucked and was useless.
Rym: the maps sucked and were useless.
Rym: things were very different back.
Rym: Then it wasn't worth the money for the pity piddly benefit I get because I realized from this experience that the primary things I use my phone for are basically Looking at videos and or kind of high bandwidth data getting emails in a push format using Twitter and High precision GPS stuff.
Rym: Those are literally the primary things that I needed and everything else really didn't matter.
Scott: Anyway, let's move on.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Let it Rym.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: So Google+ a lot of people they'd be down on Google+ all over the Internet's and you know what?
Scott: I think you know, it's I'm always the person who's just like whatever, you know, everyone's always like, oh this service is good That one's bad.
Scott: It's like who get or that, you know, one changes the because it's a good change.
Scott: Oh, it's a bad change.
Scott: Mostly people say it's a bad only problem with you.
Scott: It is bad change.
Rym: hardly anyone uses it and there's no API.
Rym: So I never actually look at anything.
Rym: But I never look at anything.
Rym: anyone posts, but I post stuff anyway.
Scott: So, you know people are always, you know up and down on these different services switching between them choosing different ones.
Scott: I'm just like, yeah, whatever others use fucking everything.
Scott: I don't care But Google+ is doing something that is potentially the awesomest.
Scott: So they have to hangouts right and hangouts have already sort of replaced Skype ish for the group conference situation with video Because it lets you do extra stuff like share, you know, watch YouTube videos together and stuff like that.
Scott: They have an API for Google Hangouts and you might think oh, what is this API do?
Scott: it lets you make apps for Google Hangout, which is genius.
Scott: amazing because now you can basically Start a hangout and you can write an app and then basically your app will occupy all that space that the faces aren't Occupying on the screen and everyone can sort of interact in that space with whatever your app does which happens to be perfect for Every board game in the goddamn known universe
Rym: never mind every role-playing game
Scott: right.
Scott: in addition You know, it's also The.
Scott: the reason people found out about this thing is because someone's making Dominion for they showed it off at Google.
Scott: It looks like fucking Dominion.
Scott: but really the real magic here that people don't realize is that a very hard thing to do.
Scott: a Relatively difficult thing to do is to write a web application that has real-time synchronized Updated shared data between the different people right?
Scott: So, you know you think about you know, pretty much any real-time multiplayer thing.
Scott: There has to be some sort of shared data data that everyone has in common that Different people can modify and all of those data modifications by the different participants is updated to all the other participants, right?
Scott: The Google Hangout API pretty much makes that just work like brain-dead easy.
Scott: You pretty much say hey Update the state and then on the other people there's an event that's like on the state.
Scott: when the state is changed do this Then change the state and when the state is and the other people have when this data change do that.
Scott: It's just straightforward and really simple.
Scott: You don't have to code any of this hard stuff because the Google servers just take care of it.
Rym: So Scott, here's the thing Should.
Rym: are we going to do anything with this or we should talking?
Scott: You know, we could make YouTube the game on it.
Rym: We probably should make YouTube the game probably but will we?
Rym: that's what I'm asking Since we're on air now, you know, are we going to?
Rym: you know, we're kings of shit.
Scott: talk.
Rym: You want to move up to Emperor Emperor shit the Emperor of shit and talk dude, at least I'll be an emperor.
Scott: Emperor God Emperor.
Scott: The only thing above Emperor.
Scott: all they have left is modifications of Emperor.
Scott: You can't really get better than them, you know if we're gonna use that title?
Rym: I actually prefer Imperator because it sounds so much more In the Imperator.
Scott: someone below the Emperor sort of like a chance.
Scott: allure is below the chance.
Rym: I think they just come from the same route.
Scott: I thought it was like you're the Emperor and the Imperator.
Rym: Here we go.
Rym: Latin word Imperator was originally a title roughly equivalent to commander under the Roman Republic.
Rym: It later became part of the titulature of the Roman emperors as part of their cognomen.
Scott: What's cognomen?
Rym: All right Let me click on that.
Rym: like you don't know Cognomen Latin plural cognomenia together with was the third name of a citizen of ancient Rome Under Roman naming conventions, so I would be Scott Rubin cognomen.
Rym: No, you would have a cognomen and the cognitive your nickname like Scott Rubin Dicker.
Scott: Oh I get it nom name nom and hog nom.
Scott: I know what the cog is for but Nomine is clearly name related.
Scott: All right, anyway We'll see.
Rym: Let's see if we move up to Emperor because I got some ideas and you have some ideas.
Scott: Yeah, but you know back when in the day I remember the Facebook apps first appeared and I was like what kind of app would you make on Facebook?
Scott: And I really right.
Scott: but if you had made a quick move on that you would have been Swinging right if you had made like early Facebook apps, so here's your chance to make early Google+ hangout apps.
Scott: Which could you know make Google+?
Scott: it's a chicken and egg situation, right?
Scott: And it's like, you know, will this succeed or fail?
Scott: who knows but making apps for it Is the chicken to the egg to make it succeed?
Scott: If you could make an app and it could still fail.
Scott: but making more apps for it helps.
Scott: it Decreases the chance of the failing.
Scott: so that goes both ways.
Rym: Well, we'll see if we do anything with it.
Scott: Yep, I can at least try out hello world.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: I hope none of you have seen this but if you watch every TED talk Then you've probably run into it at some point.
Rym: This is Marco tempest doing an amazing little sort of performance art biography of Nikola Tesla, okay, it is Pretty amazing to watch just for the way it's presented and I don't want to say anything else.
Rym: It's only six minutes long.
Rym: Just watch it.
Rym: It's great.
Scott: I'll take the time of grove over.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So everyone probably saw this already.
Scott: It's a Japanese robot because they seem to make the best robots and it plays rock-paper-scissors.
Scott: It's a robot fist But it has a 100% win rate.
Scott: Now.
Scott: You're probably thinking whoa, how can you have a 100% win rate?
Scott: With rock-paper-scissors.
Scott: I mean if I can't write a rock-paper-scissors bot that always win.
Rym: now what I would assume I would think maybe it's using like Resonance imaging or like facial stuff to like read the person's mind, which we'll probably have someday.
Rym: But this thing works in such a simpler principle?
Scott: yeah, so what this does actually is as a camera that watches your fist to see what you through and Then the robot is just so fast that it will always Counter-attack and win after it.
Scott: so basically it's cheating.
Scott: It's like if I look and I see what Rym does and then he throws scissor.
Scott: I put out a rock He throws out a paper.
Scott: I throw out a scissor only it's so fast You can't realize that I'm cheating cuz I'm like, you know Superman now.
Scott: That's what this robot does.
Rym: it's questionable as to whether or not it actually is cheating because it's non-detectable.
Rym: and No, what?
Rym: most people who play?
Rym: Most people who play paper-rock-scissors?
Rym: Don't think about it.
Rym: in terms of is there a race condition like what is the allowable?
Rym: Interval between the two hands opening before it's considered a foul?
Rym: and you try again because it is Impossible to be perfectly synchronized.
Rym: You have to allow for some manner of deviation.
Scott: yes, but it's any it?
Scott: I think what it is is if two humans are playing if the if the you know if the differ if The time difference is detectable by humans then it's too long Right.
Rym: So you're saying if a human and a robot play then if the time difference is detectable by a robot.
Scott: let's discuss the more fundamental question, right is Undetected?
Scott: is it cheating?
Scott: Okay, if you are not caught Well, it depends.
Rym: You know what cheating is only defined as violating the explicit rules of the game, right?
Rym: So let's say so what are the rules?
Scott: So let's say I play baseball.
Scott: Yeah, and I take steroids which is against the rules.
Rym: Yep, so you're cheating and I'm never.
Scott: and I but I do I'm so good at it They I'm never ever caught or even suspected.
Rym: I would argue that you still cheated.
Scott: Okay, so therefore the robot you'd.
Rym: ah.
Rym: But what is the definition of cheating in tic-tac-toe or paper-rock-scissors?
Rym: I don't know why you can't cheat a tic-tac-toe.
Rym: Maybe I can't I erase your oh and put it.
Scott: I think there's a situation though, right?
Rym: Where Scott if you and I play paper-rock-scissors if you're a Fraction behind me.
Rym: What's the line?
Scott: If you could detect that I'm a fraction.
Rym: so if I detect I'll just every time I lose I'll say up you were too late You couldn't actually detect it.
Rym: I would just say I detected it.
Scott: You just say you detected.
Rym: How do you lose until you win and I'd foul everything until I won Four thousand.
Rym: you're out like baseball Calls the foul the person who's late of the person who's early.
Scott: if you're late you're fouled.
Scott: early is always better.
Rym: So I declare that I saw you being late every time We had.
Scott: if you're gonna be a jerk then we need Judge.
Scott: this is if you're gonna be a jerk on a video reap.
Rym: What I'm saying is that this is why soccer needs goddamn video replay.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: Fuck the World Cup.
Scott: All the cups that don't I.
Rym: just I can't care about soccer anymore.
Rym: all that all the FIFA's because of the officiating situation.
Rym: Pretend everything.
Rym: I just said fuck Something anus.
Scott: I don't know I was trying to turn FIFA because it had I in it to be.
Scott: to use the word instant use fucking an anus?
Scott: Well, no to be.
Scott: I was trying to make an acronym out of it.
Scott: That would be get some fucking instant replay assholes because it had F an instant.
Scott: So F. Yes I don't know what to do with the F and the The other F in the a few men do.
Rym: The book club book is what you're going to do.
Rym: show on as soon as we get a chance because we're both done with the Book, but we had to bail out a show cutie in 84
Scott: Other meta moments not this weekend, but next weekend, which happens to be July 13 14 15 2012 is Connecticut 2012
Rym: in hard to for to connect a kid.
Scott: You should fucking go.
Rym: if you're close We run the panels.
Scott: don't come too far to go there.
Scott: But if you're close better be there.
Rym: and I will tell you this we have scheduled more panels Workshops and events in the 11 panel of workshop rooms we have than any Connecticut has ever had which means if you show up you're gonna see even less percentage of the stuff there is to see.
Rym: But at the same time it's a amount of time you there is no way I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna take Saturday All right.
Rym: Saturday at 2 o'clock You could see story time with the vagabonds Q&A with the macho men of video game voice acting.
Rym: Michelle Lang's She's a guest of the con to Jeopardy stuck, which is a homestuck panel.
Scott: Why did we allow that?
Rym: because home sucks popular and of the 11 that were submitted I picked the two that looked best.
Scott: Jeopardy stuck.
Rym: the D&D we never knew.
Rym: the 36 chamber an intro to kung fu cinema I'm going there.
Rym: the atomic Robo 8-bit theater meet-and-greet with Brian Clevenger.
Rym: I've been to that twice of anime opening style and symbolism.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Star Trek and feminism and maintaining motivation in writing and the cutting truth of medieval swords a lesson in sword fighting.
Rym: those are Simultaneously.
Rym: those are all simultaneously around.
Scott: I want to go like three of them.
Rym: Yeah, this is a pretty fucking awesome Kind.
Scott: so anyway also and John St.
Rym: John's gonna be there again.
Scott: You can go to this con and just play board games.
Scott: I've said this before best board games there are at any convention I've been to ever.
Rym: that includes any acts and mags.
Scott: There's plenty of tables.
Scott: This is the best game library ever and it by playing just by playing games.
Scott: even if you lose you get tickets.
Scott: a very small Amount of tickets will get you free games that are worth a lot of money and real dollars.
Scott: You can pay for your own badge just like playing a lot of board games.
Scott: Connecticut okay Pax prime is Labor Day.
Scott: You know the score.
Rym: probably be there Pax devs.
Rym: before that there's a chance I will be there maybe with Scott.
Rym: Yeah, if Scott's not there It's just because he doesn't want to spend vacation days because I don't have them all right.
Scott: in addition Other news we've been keeping updating the website.
Scott: You know the website that not too many people go to and we keep spreading.
Scott: You know our philosophy is hey, we don't.
Scott: if you don't like coming to our website fine We're gonna post our shit on Google Facebook Twitter fucking everywhere.
Scott: We added something new an old-fashioned email newsletter.
Scott: if you are old and busted Luddite We are emailing out an update about once every other week or so.
Scott: ish, right?
Scott: Reminding you of what GeekNights has done in the past couple weeks with some other content in there as well.
Scott: email reminder of what?
Scott: we're up to.
Scott: if you like email reminders you can go to front recruitment calm and Subscribe to the email newsletter.
Scott: all the only information you have to type in is your email address.
Scott: unsubscribing actually works.
Scott: mail chimp just takes care of it.
Scott: and It's so far.
Scott: I wrote one email.
Scott: People didn't seem to complain.
Scott: so there you go.
Scott: if you like email newsletters I know.
Rym: if you don't like email newsletters, then don't sign up all right, so uh UEFI has been in the news a lot, but only nerds care about it.
Rym: and Cisco's cloud connect has been in the news a lot and only nerds care about it.
Rym: mm-hmm This these both reek of a really fundamental problem.
Scott: It's somebody's cloud care.
Scott: cuz I looked up the cloud connect It was actually called on the website that I found the official Cisco website.
Rym: It was called connect cloud, but on the website There's another site that said Cisco cloud vision.
Scott: uh-huh so what I read was that it's pretty much You know we have this problem where you have your home network But your ISP gives you dynamic IPS and they suck and you have a router that gnats you so it's very hard to provide Services from your home internet service.
Scott: can you know internet connection?
Scott: so with this cloud connect?
Scott: Theoretically does or connect cloud is on your router.
Scott: your router links.
Scott: this router supports connect cloud.
Scott: you can get apps for it.
Scott: So for example you could enable the file transferring app and then no matter where you were in the world You'd be able to connect to the computers in your house as if it was the cloud.
Scott: You know a cloud service and upload and send files back and forth to your house from anywhere as if you were Hosting cloud things at your house.
Scott: There are already a lot of equipments that a lot of NAS is do this where they'll use UPnP and a dynamic DNS service to achieve the same effect.
Scott: So that's what the cloud connect thing does according to the website.
Rym: So I'm gonna read a statement from one of many articles about this.
Rym: alright last week a number of Cisco customers bit began reporting problems with three specific links.
Rym: is routers the E2700 e3500 e4500.
Rym: okay one day they attempted to log in and They were told to log in and register using their Cisco connect cloud account information, which they did not have accounts They was.
Rym: there was no way to get into their own physical router without registering with Cisco cloud connect.
Rym: Cisco had silently upgraded their firmware removed any option of downgrading and forced them to set this up.
Rym: Cisco now controlled their router.
Rym: So it gets worse.
Rym: It gets way worse.
Scott: cuz they want you to cry cuz the way it works is you have to log in to the Cisco server.
Scott: So once you run on the cloud And then that connects you to your router manage your router.
Rym: you can no longer manage your own router anymore And there's no way to turn it off once it happens.
Rym: There's no way to do anything with your router.
Rym: Suddenly they have power over you.
Rym: so it gets way worse.
Rym: I'm going to read a few sentences from the actual Terms of service of this thing which you are now forced to use if you want.
Scott: Did you search other routers terms of service to see if they say similar?
Rym: No this isn't router terms of service.
Rym: This is Cisco cloud connect terms of service or your router.
Rym: if you're using it All right as the condition of your use of the service you agree that your sister blah blah blah will comply with all applicable laws.
Rym: blah blah blah.
Rym: you agree to not use or permit the use of the service to invade another's privacy to for obscene pornographic or offensive purposes.
Rym: so you Another's rights including but not limited to intellectual property rights to email upload or otherwise transmitter make available unauthorized Advertising promotional materials spam junk mail or any form of solicitation.
Scott: because you know how this thing probably works.
Scott: It's probably not doing just dynamic DNS with a you know an IP hole on your router.
Scott: What it's probably doing is you're sending stuff to Cisco's cloud servers, and then they're sending it to your router.
Scott: That's probably how it works, and they don't want you to put that shit on their servers.
Rym: so Yeah, yeah, so basically without now.
Rym: It looks like after the crazy nerd outcry They backpedaled and they provided instructions on how to like physically reset And then download the old firmware and get your router back, but that's not the end of this and we're gonna see what happens because once Cisco controls my router and not me fuck you Cisco.
Scott: Well, I mean I don't know anybody's buying a Cisco router.
Scott: everyone.
Rym: Yeah, you mean you mean a linksys router.
Scott: I mean everyone knows that the good linksys router is the oldest best one Yes, you are t54g and that every other linksys router except for that one is shit alright.
Rym: So if I need to buy a new router today, which one do I buy?
Rym: the one I have all right?
Rym: Which one is that the netgear?
Scott: WNDR 3700. there's actually slightly newer better ones.
Rym: so we cool with the world where Cisco if you buy a Cisco router you don't know better.
Rym: You know you just plug it in and it just starts working.
Rym: But Cisco actually now controls it and can do stuff to you.
Scott: This is why we say every person who uses computers no matter how you know No, you know little technological stuff You think you're involved in you need to fucking learn computers.
Scott: no matter if you're a plumber or a schoolteacher or a student Everyone in the world needs to know computers so that you don't get fucked anyone who doesn't learn computers.
Scott: in the modern world You will be fucked by companies pulling the shit out.
Rym: So here's another part of the privacy statement.
Rym: if you're using a router that has this When you use the service.
Scott: Cisco can look at all your internets yeah, and they send it to Cisco among they specifically track your internet history.
Rym: Yep, there you go and all network traffic.
Scott: The thing is a nerd who was using one of these right could be smart enough to VPN And it wouldn't even matter to you right because if I'd use my little eye Predator VPN for my laptop, and I happen to can say a coffee shop is using this you know crappy Cisco router I'll be totally safe.
Rym: Yeah, but this would be like buying a router.
Rym: That's a black box that someone else controls and just trusting it.
Scott: well you see what they want to do in the UK.
Scott: Yeah, trying to push a thing where the force is PS to install black boxes and those black boxes basically Will man in the middle all the SSL gmails and things like of that nature so that the UK government can spy on pretty much everyone using a UK is be And that's why I will not live there.
Rym: So that if I did if I visited there I would VPN all the time, but much more dangerous to the health of computers everywhere.
Rym: this this harkens back to like CBD TPA kind of stuff right.
Scott: so this is thing and it's been coming for a while But now it's really on the verge of coming out for real, and it's starting to you know the talk about it is greatly increased.
Scott: It's called EFI right well It's really the name for is secure boot, which is a facet of oh you EFI.
Scott: well Yeah, so if I support secure boot basically yeah, so secure boot is a feature of an people don't know.
Scott: Let's go back to the beginning right.
Scott: so PCs have BIOS right and max use basically the newer better replacement for BIOS Which is EFI which is this Intel thing right?
Scott: It's it's basically something firmware or something I was gonna ask because I don't think it's enhanced firmware interface.
Scott: Maybe something like that anyway.
Scott: So it's basically a better BIOS.
Scott: is?
Scott: that's why you can't just easily installed like Windows directly out of Mac without like boot camp Weirdness because Windows is built for BIOS.
Scott: It's not built for EFI.
Scott: so For Windows 8 right they're gonna finally move to EFI which is better than BIOS But has all these features such as restrictions and whatnot which is why you can't just install Windows on a Mac hardware.
Scott: so anyway That's an EFI is no problem really right.
Scott: everyone can deal with that.
Scott: the problem is that the Windows 8 they are making a contractual agreement right.
Scott: this is Microsoft is forcing this.
Scott: Microsoft is saying look if You want right on your computers that you're selling to put a sticker that says Windows 8 compatible
Rym: You
Scott: must not only use UAF I
Rym: you
Scott: have to and have it secure boot, which is a feature of UFI installed and Loaded and configured on that hardware, so if a motherboard wants to say we're compatible with Windows 8 in their marketing Microsoft will not let them do that and will sue them if they say it unless they have UFI and secure boot, so what is secure boot?
Scott: Secure boot is also known by some people as restricted boot.
Scott: What this does is let's say you got it's sort of what the TiVo does.
Scott: it's in fact It's exactly what the TiVo did only standardized.
Scott: So what TiVo did is they people were buying TiVos and trying to replace the operating system on there But they couldn't because the TiVo would refuse to boot.
Scott: unless you had the exact TiVo software and any other TiVo software It wouldn't boot.
Scott: so secure boot is like that same thing.
Scott: it.
Scott: You have some software your operating system, and there is some key some security key.
Scott: the operating system has alright and that there's a hash of the operating system matches a certain number so you can't fake it and They can.
Scott: when the computer turns on it looks at the operating system, and it says is that the operating system I'm supposed to boot?
Scott: now the hardware is doing this right.
Scott: this isn't some software You can change.
Scott: the hardware knows about a particular program And it will refuse to start any other program when the computer boots.
Rym: now This is a lot like SSL in terms of certificates work in that you have to trust someone to sign stuff Or this is all pointless.
Rym: so basically all right.
Rym: well We'll trust Microsoft to sign stuff and the only thing they're gonna sign is their own software And you can pay them a hundred bucks, and they'll do it.
Rym: Yeah, so every everyone who wants to make malware should pay them a hundred bucks.
Scott: right?
Scott: so let's say I buy a motherboard with secure boot and a new Intel chip And I load it up big time and then I write an assembly program that does some cool graphical demo And I want to run that assembly program.
Scott: I want to put it in the master bootloader and just boot it directly on the chips that I have bought.
Scott: Well my that software is not signed by anyone.
Rym: What if I want to install a Linux distro that didn't go through the hoops and get a signature right?
Scott: I make my roll my own Linux distro with my own kernel and my own bootloader.
Rym: And there's also a problem that you can't have multiple signatures for a piece of software right.
Scott: and Now this is fine.
Scott: the hardware is gonna look at my custom Linux, or it's gonna look at my you know cool assembly program.
Scott: I wrote that runs directly on the hardware, and it's gonna say that's not one of the programs I'm supposed to be running.
Rym: I ain't gonna boot now once you can't load arbitrary software on your computer It's not your computer anymore No kidding.
Rym: But Microsoft backed off a little bit in that you can self sign and turn off the like mandatory higher up signature stuff for Windows on Intel
Scott: Mm-hmm
Rym: like x86 architecture, so on ARM They're mandating that any hardware that Windows will be certified for that has that sticker Cannot allow anything that is not signed by them to run on it under any circumstance
Scott: Or they won't.
Scott: well if you can make such hardware and sell it if you want to know But they
Rym: won't let you have it to be certified
Scott: exactly you won't be able to have that sticker that says Windows 8 Compatible or whatever and you can't and they definitely can't sell it with Windows already installed on it
Rym: now.
Rym: that's a big deal because the What if you add a barrier to entry to install non Microsoft OS is the vast majority of people are incapable of getting around those Barriers exactly.
Scott: I mean already.
Scott: people have trouble when they want to install Linux like telling their computer to boot from USB or CD ROM Instead of you know from the hard drive That's already in there Which is what you need to do if you want to actually reinstall Linux for reals which is why people had things like wubby Which is kind of crap, but it kind of works.
Scott: so to make people do even harder work of like signing something with a security key and Doing the equivalent of that messing around in the BIOS or the setup screen.
Scott: It's gonna be even harder to get people to install Linux instead of Windows or something like that right now or Absolutely impossible because their hardware will not allow it now.
Scott: in Theory the secure boot feature having it on your computer is not so bad because what you can do for example is You can install Linux distribution or Windows and you could then enable it and say all right look you know Secure boot see what's installed right now.
Scott: Yeah, I see that don't run anything else, but that okay, and this would be the good.
Scott: You know implementation be theoretical good implementation.
Rym: Yeah, what are the first name?
Rym: install right?
Scott: So then if say some virus or evil hacker or something came around and modified your operating system your computer would say hey I'm not booting in fact.
Scott: I'm not even running anymore, and you would bet very well you would know immediately Oh someone hacked and screwed with my operating system.
Scott: I better reflash that shit Reinstall that part.
Scott: you know the boot loading part so that it's clean again And you would just do that and you would be all set and that would be secure boot.
Scott: the problem is the the restricted Secure boot the evil implementation.
Scott: the user is unable to tell the the motherboard or the CPU That no you should trust this.
Scott: It's the people telling the computer what to trust our companies who make ironing systems and not the person who owns that computer.
Scott: I should be able to tell my computer trust this Linux trust that Linux trust this.
Scott: I want to run DOS.
Scott: What's it called free DOS.
Scott: trust this free DOS?
Scott: It's cool, but you can't do that.
Rym: the way they're doing things now It's you know like Ubuntu and Red Hat are both like working and getting around this and they're doing deals with Microsoft to make It easy for now, but the pragmatic solution right now is not the thing that bothers me.
Rym: What bothers me is that we as technologists cannot tolerate going down this road at all because I'm not making the slippery slope argument This is not a slippery slope.
Scott: This is the horrible thing at the bottom.
Rym: We don't need to slide anywhere because if your boot itself is bad if we tolerate an implementation like this This is the kind of stuff like the CBD tPA that a lot of people in our government would really like to have.
Scott: Yep, remember this evening you basically want.
Scott: there was a decade ago.
Rym: You know how hard we had to fight to get that shot down.
Scott: what will happen here if this goes?
Scott: You know full-on if no one makes motherboards that don't have this anymore is you'll basically Have to buy as soon as it comes out the last motherboard CPU combination that doesn't have this bullshit funny.
Scott: When are you going to be able to upgrade?
Rym: never I remember in 2002. give or take posting the Posting or reading.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: You know I'm an old man But that exact argument was made in 2002 because if the CBD tPA had passed We would have all had to buy the last free hardware
Scott: yep,
Rym: and then from there forth somehow We would had to make do and there would have been an underground in illegal technology.
Scott: Oh, well not necessarily legal right in that case.
Rym: It would have been at least in this case.
Scott: It's not illegal technology It's simply not Microsoft certified technology.
Scott: So I would hope now that there would be a some Chinese some manufacturer of hardware that would Continue to make non certified stuff and we thought we could get it on new way.
Rym: governments of the world Not to sound paranoid have a vested interest.
Rym: the idea of trusted computing Flies pretty much directly in the face of free computing.
Rym: What is made?
Rym: Technology great and open communication to the world forever the computer.
Rym: the idea that we can have a generic computing thing a machine that does Computations that can do any kind of computation has probably revolutionized mankind more than anything else We've ever done in our entire history.
Scott: and the road.
Scott: We're going down now.
Scott: iPad iPod all Mac Everything is a road where the you can buy machines that are theoretically capable of computing anything but Forces beyond your control.
Scott: companies and governments are going to design that hardware in such a way that they will decide what computations those things can perform and what they cannot.
Scott: and it might even get so if they put it in the hardware and There is no hardware company on earth that cooperates It may get to the point where even nerds won't be able to compute whatever they want to compute now.
Rym: It's fine.
Rym: If we have divergent paths like an iPad that's really locked down is fine in an ecosystem.
Scott: It's okay for it to exist.
Rym: It just can't be the only exactly in an ecosystem where there are also free computers But without free access to your own hardware to do whatever you want with.
Rym: You know short of you know, if I fill it with c4 and blow it up.
Rym: Well, that's a bomb.
Rym: That's not a computer, right?
Rym: but The fact that computing devices are open and free and then I can I can type whatever the fuck I want into that thing is Probably one of the most important things humans can do right now Because ideas and memes are the only way to fight things that we perceive as being bad in the world.
Scott: So there's there's an additional issue here, right?
Scott: Which is the GPL v3.
Scott: now some people use the GPL v3 and some aren't but in fact What happened is because of the TVO which I already explained the GPL v3 in most of its uses has clauses Specifically not allowing the TVO trick of you know, you're only allowing signed whatever's.
Scott: So in fact what Ubuntu is doing to get around this problem?
Scott: because right part of what they are doing is not using grub2 as their bootloader anymore because That would violate the GPL v3.
Scott: for them to do what they're doing to get around the secure boot.
Scott: So they're actually switching to an Intel Bootloader for the later Ubuntu versions that has a more open license than the GPL v3.
Scott: Well, so it's gonna be really weird to see what happens because suddenly you might get it, you know Linux itself is GPL v2.
Scott: So it's still cool, but we might get into situations coming up where you know You've got a new computer You've managed to get around secure boot to install the OS you want but no GPL v3 software can be run on your computer.
Scott: Be unless you know you you know without violating the GPL v3.
Scott: So it's gonna get shaky real shaky.
Rym: Well, that's that's a separate problem of Free as in beer free as in speech.
Rym: I like and free as in GNU.
Scott: Yeah but the free there is stuff that is freezing GNU and there's might be some divergence and some troubles and Get a certain program to run where I
Rym: want pragmatism to prevail in that I Am less concerned about binary blob like Nvidia drivers than I am about hardware restrictions
Scott: You know.
Scott: and then there's always the concern we bring up all the time Which is like even if we come out of this, okay, and nerds can still buy open motherboards and CPUs a new egg Great.
Scott: We're still in that situation where Yeah, we told you so a hundred times Nerds have freedom and no one else does the CBD tPA passes.
Rym: that would have meant that if I made a mashup of my little pony Normal people could not watch it.
Rym: Hardware could not play media at the hardware level unless that media was signed by government Bodies saying it was legit and not pirated.
Rym: think about that for a minute.
Rym: Think about what that would do to free speech.
Rym: Hardware restrictions like this are basically attempts at that.
Scott: Yep, and if you look at something like the iPad you could totally get there.
Rym: We're fine with the iPad being there But imagine a world where iPad is the only way to compute and it's already.
Scott: and it's not.
Rym: even you can't write an ad Unless the government says it's okay to write an ad.
Rym: I imagine that.
Scott: and it's not.
Scott: and the thing is it's even take the government out of it right.
Scott: if we merely get to the point where Consumers like it the most so it becomes the most popular Right, then even if governments aren't forcing you to do that and all the nerds have open computers where they can do whatever they want Normal people won't have them.
Scott: so if you make open media right and you know Apple or some corporate gatekeeper doesn't like you you can't get it spread out there because Everyone is using these lockdown things even though they don't have to Side argument.
Rym: as long as we have real open computing platforms Then the nerds who care can use those platforms to circumvent the controls on other.
Scott: But we still need the open platform to be the most popular platform Even if I don't know if that's feasible in the modern.
Rym: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: That's the problem is that even if governments don't force a close even if you're not forced You're arguing that Huxley is the dystopia as opposed to Orwell.
Scott: if the closeness Right of iPad and you know secure boot systems become the most popular most widely spread systems then the government doesn't have to step in and it beat you to get the same effect.
Scott: and Basically, we're only nerds are living free and everyone else is living locked down.
Scott: I Still my choice and they wouldn't choose to leave.
Rym: I still think it's a separate argument because in this case this hardware lockdown is Much more immediate in effect and harder to route around Mm-hmm, at least if it's just software like lockdown platforms.
Rym: Then there the fact that the open platforms can be ubiquitous even if they're the minority.
Rym: It's sort of a checks and balances where even if iPads are most popular if someone does something on the open platform That non nerd see and go hey, how come?
Rym: I can't do that?
Rym: It puts pressure on the lockdown platform to allow analogous functionality.
Scott: I could see and like a few years right when Windows 7 isn't really any good anymore and Windows 8 and 9 or whatever and OS X the only other choices Going back to full-on Linux.
Scott: We're seeing steam come out on Linux.
Scott: I bet valve this is at least you know, they're at least thinking about this a little tiny fraction of a bit.
Scott: You know of what?
Rym: That's why as long as we can keep open access to hardware then it'll always be a pendulum because whenever Government or corporate intrusion gets too high and starts restricting what people actually want to do with their technology.
Rym: Those people will go to their nerd friends and say hey How come I can't do all those things because you bought an iPad or Windows 8 computer dumbass.
Rym: That's why there have been periods in my life.
Rym: You know, I've been using computers for a long time.
Rym: We're old now.
Rym: we've known GeekNights since 2005 and There have been eras where there have been big shifts in normal ish people toward Linux because they'd say hey I want to do X and Y and they couldn't really do that on their more closed platforms.
Rym: if the iPad model gets too closed and Nerds continue to do cool things there will always be this pushback But no close.
Scott: but how will normal people know about the cool things nerds do?
Scott: because nerds never shut the fuck up But they can't see us on the internet because they're all locked down.
Rym: They can see us on the internet because at least for now.
Rym: Yes, and that's the for now.
Rym: That's why That's why as much as we complain about this stuff the CBD tPA was literally the worst most Egregious attempt at this.
Scott: Anyway, here's my pragmatic strategy for the near future.
Scott: Right number one.
Scott: if this becomes so prevalent that like every motherboard has it you can't build, you know I'm planning to build a computer like two three years away, but I might wow You're really gonna hold out two or three years.
Scott: my computer's just fun.
Rym: I guess you're not editing video.
Scott: if I have to I'll just buy the last great computer that doesn't have this bullshit.
Scott: If there's still like some motherboard companies that are still producing good, you know And CPU companies still making computers that don't have the bullshit or have ways around it that they just they say Yeah, the motherboard was selling a new egg doesn't need to say Windows 8 compatible on the on the box You know, then we're pretty good, right?
Scott: We can just buy those motherboards.
Scott: We'll be all set.
Scott: If it gets bad and there isn't a motherboard that's like that or a CPU that's like that Then I'm gonna start a Kickstarter to get enough monies to get like aces or someone to make a motherboard like that.
Rym: Yeah, and secure boot will make sure that your web browser can't go to that Kickstarter.
Scott: I don't think no secure boot at least for now.
Scott: No slippery slope is just operating system.
Scott: So it's really just an issue.
Rym: and other than ARM it is.
Rym: Actually even with ARM in certain situations is circumventable, but it pushes normal consumers.
Rym: It adds a barrier to the even makes it hard.
Scott: you even you couldn't even run Windows XP on such a computer.
Scott: Yeah, your Windows 7 even right unless maybe they sign that.
Scott: but the thing is you it would be hard to run Something that was.
Rym: the idea of a secure platform that I can enable is awesome.
Scott: If I'm running a company that they just give me give me the feature and let me choose.
Scott: Yeah, what the key is?
Rym: I run the IT of a small company that has like sensitive financial information.
Rym: Yeah, everyone gets a laptop with an encrypted hard drive and a crazy secure boot.
Scott: Yep Bam done, but you can't force I have to be the one to put the key in the secure boot.
Scott: I you know I can't have a lock on my house or someone else decides what the lock looks like and holds all the keys.
Scott: I can't open my house unless Microsoft opens it for me.
Rym: It's the same fundamental problem with self-signed SSL.
Rym: It's why if you want to use SSL and anyone's using it other than you You pretty much have to pay one of the gatekeepers for you Like
Scott: if you mortgage the house and every time you wanted to go in or out the bank came to open and close the door And lock it for you.
Scott: And if you fucked up on the mortgage payment They would just lock you out.
Rym: and if it's like Cisco's cloud thing if they find porn in your house Then they shut your house down.
Rym: Yeah All right, so ravel about this stuff kids ravel ravel ravel ravel.
Scott: sign the EFF whatever's secure boot rest You know, whatever they want to call it restricted boot.
Rym: You don't understand anything.
Rym: We said just remember this UEFI is a UFIA.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: When you think of it, I've actually thought about that all day I've been.
Rym: I was waiting for tonight to say that at the end of the episode.
Scott: There you go.