Rym: It's Wednesday November 9th 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: the red line.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So if I had to summarize red line in a sentence, I would say hi this Everybody.
Rym: I would say this is the story of a planet called Robo world that is administered by the most incompetent people in the universe.
Rym: so Like Robo world fucking up is the real theme of red line.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much all there is to it.
Rym: Yeah It's amazing.
Rym: What goes on?
Rym: the story of red line is so much more insane.
Scott: Well, it's not really isn't about the story of red line, right?
Scott: It's like the story is just an excuse.
Rym: Here's what I expected Crazy like animation machine wacky races awesome.
Rym: Let's go craziness.
Rym: I did not also expect the military of Robo world trying to stop the race and being so incompetent.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So for people don't know right there was this movie called red line that has been hyped.
Scott: It's sort of like, you know hyped.
Rym: it's been ignored by most of the media.
Scott: Well, it's weird.
Scott: right because the fans have been like crazy about it But the everyone else is like it's non-existent, which is why the fans are crazy about it.
Scott: It's sort of like the hipster thing, right?
Scott: It's it's this cool thing.
Scott: No one knows about.
Scott: we got to make everyone know about it And basically they spent a zillion dollars animating it and tons and tons of time and everything.
Scott: But it's like how come they didn't actually push it harder?
Rym: and the worst thing is those us fans to push it.
Rym: This is the kind of movie where if you just took this fucking thing and put it on TV at prime time sometime Just and just market it like check this thing out People would like it for the same reasons.
Rym: They like to Kara back in the day.
Scott: I mean, yes I mean, it's not as good as a Kara now.
Rym: but I'm saying a lot of people who aren't anime fans and wouldn't even really know much about What anime is saw Akira in the theater and thought it was really cool.
Rym: Yeah, but I saw a ghost in the shell in the theater and thought it was really talking about this a zillion times.
Scott: You know all these things like.
Scott: how come they don't market the anime to the normal people?
Scott: Yeah, anime movies come around so rarely.
Rym: This is such a poster child of it.
Rym: That is a recent example.
Scott: Yes But it's kind of weird because I feel like I've been.
Scott: I've been preaching that story of anime movies come around So rarely.
Scott: you should watch them all kind of often as in like our enemy who's coming around more often lately.
Scott: More shows about.
Rym: we pretty much watch every anime movie that comes out.
Scott: Yeah and this one is no exception.
Rym: everyone that isn't a Sequel to one piece or Naruto or Pokemon or Pokemon though we did watch.
Rym: I've only ever seen one Pokemon movie and that was the one with mommy.
Scott: Yeah, the third one.
Scott: I am daddy You are now mommy, but we had echo the sentiments of all the other anime fans people who are like Yeah, red lines the shit.
Scott: you got to see this.
Rym: Yeah, if you have if you haven't seen it don't even listen to our review.
Rym: just go why you can listen the review Yeah, but go watch it cuz I'm gonna spoil some stuff toward the end though.
Scott: But it's been scientifically demonstrated.
Scott: spoilers actually increase enjoyment.
Rym: However, that's one study.
Scott: I agree with it.
Rym: Uh, That doesn't in any way impact the legitimacy of the study.
Rym: You have to repeat studies to prove things.
Scott: I trust it Okay.
Rym: Anyway, captain bias.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, you should just watch the movie without even thinking about it because if you're an anime fan Even if you end up hating this movie You can't call yourself an anime fan if you don't watch one of the more important or bigger budget Movies in the medium of your fandom that has come out in recent memory.
Rym: Yeah, also this movie is pretty beautiful.
Rym: It harkens back to the old era of Extremely detailed like background characters doing wacky stuff and machines.
Scott: Yeah, they definitely put.
Scott: the number one thing about this movie is the animations right and the arts.
Scott: they put a hundred percent effort to It and got a hundred percent quality.
Rym: and not just the foreground a lot of great-looking shows.
Rym: today.
Rym: you look in the background There's really nothing going on.
Rym: But you look at old anime, especially a lot of the old cell animated stuff.
Rym: You know some guys working on like one bit of the machinery or like one background guy.
Rym: he's got to animate it a little bit and they put a Lot of detail into.
Scott: except when you go to really old anime where it's just a still, you know panning over the still shot.
Rym: Yeah, there's an ebb and flow But this has that like every like in these huge crowd scenes during the races every individual dude in the background It's got something going on.
Scott: Yep So, yeah, and it's the thing that really gets you is the colors right because the colors are just.
Scott: you know They're a lot like the colors in that Justice League comic that we Justice League number one that recently came out Where everything is just really bright and all sorts of like, you know Sort of like neon ish colors But like darker neon and they have like this really great contrast that is like eye candy all the time.
Scott: And there's plenty of scenes where like, you know, there's all.
Scott: it's not super deformed But like there's all sorts of like cartoon deformities.
Scott: You know of the Looney Tunes style like people stretching out when they go really fast in the cars Or all kinds of stuff like that, but without changing the style.
Scott: It's not like they change it into a cartoony style to do cartoony stuff.
Scott: They like keep it in that style and it's like whoa.
Scott: Look at that.
Scott: That's crazy So awesome.
Rym: It is pretty crazy.
Rym: It's I cannot stress this enough watch this movie.
Rym: But yeah, the story of red line is pretty straightforward.
Rym: on its surface There is the yellow line, which is one of many f-zero style.
Rym: anything goes crazy races.
Scott: yellow line is basically F-3000 and red line is F1 or f-zero.
Rym: I mean in this case yellow line was a qualifier.
Scott: I really I think gonna go play a GameCube f-zero because it really just was the best f-zero.
Scott: I've gotten in the mood big time.
Rym: but so at red line is like the race like imagine if the Super Bowl and the World Series and the Stanley Cup and Every f1 race were all combined into one Single winner-take-all event at the Super Bowl of racing and not only that.
Scott: but there's no rules Right except get to the end first.
Rym: Yeah, anything goes.
Scott: you can just kill all the other racers if you really want and there's only like eight racers in it Which is kind of weird.
Scott: Well, the thing is f1 is like 20.
Rym: It is partly implied that people dropped out because they didn't want to know that there were.
Scott: there were eight people in originally I'm too drunk dropped out because the plot happened Which is the red line.
Scott: people decided that the race this year was gonna be held on Robo world.
Rym: now to put this into an analogy to the real world That would be as though we had an f1 race.
Rym: That was Like yeah blatantly anti-korea like if the race Enraged Korean people culturally like it there and we decided that we were going to host it in North Korea in their capital against their wishes.
Scott: Well, it's like, you know, the red line is like governed by Some you know Oregon the red line or racing organization.
Rym: and they're like, yes, let's put it in robo Fucking hate.
Scott: like not under the purview of any government whatsoever.
Scott: It's like this independent thing like the galaxy railways its own thing.
Scott: So it's like I guess FIFA, right so FIFA is its own thing.
Scott: it governs soccer.
Scott: So FIFA was like, yeah, we're putting the World Cup in rims bathroom.
Scott: Yeah, that's where it's going.
Rym: And right now there's no saying they're like It's gonna be in a robo world.
Scott: and then the movie gets to Rym gets home one day and like Pele's in his bathroom Kicking the soccer ball, you know.
Rym: And then it cuts to the high government of robo world and the president is like what the fuck I'm gonna kill.
Rym: all of them.
Rym: fuck racing.
Rym: This sucks.
Scott: He's like anyone if you when you show up I'm going to send the military of robo world to just to kill the people in your race.
Scott: So basically the course of the movie.
Scott: if you think the weird if you take the other meaning of the word race You could say robo world was genociding because he was killing an entire race.
Scott: Anyway, that was terrible.
Scott: it was terrible, but the I don't.
Rym: I don't want to really like spoil a lot.
Rym: But basically the robo world military and like government apparatus are going to stop this.
Scott: Well, the first which is like which is happening illegally.
Scott: Well, the reason is like why does robo world even want to stop?
Scott: the race wouldn't erase usually boost your economy.
Rym: Well, like I said, just go back to the North Korea analogy.
Rym: So not only is the race like in the center of the capital of North Korea But the finish line is on top of their most secret military base, right?
Scott: So basically robo robo world is just really afraid of their military secrets on their planet being shown to the world.
Rym: They also on galaxy-wide television.
Rym: They also appear to hate races and hate people, right?
Scott: So, you know, there's a leader of robo world that he's got two assistants one volt.
Scott: What's his name?
Rym: Oh a captive court.
Scott: colonel volt on right who is colonel volt on is basically sort of like the badass like quiet Powerful evil dude and then the other like Oh Kefka kind of evil, dude.
Rym: I thought that guy was gonna be a square boss, but it turns out he just doesn't give up.
Rym: He's just like whatever just a crazy killer, but he keeps coming down Like he'll be like the president's like arm the hyper disintegrator and the guy's like, okay He's like, oh, yeah hyper disintegrator didn't work.
Rym: what it was broken by the racers.
Scott: Oh, we can use the disintegrator again.
Rym: Now the most he's the second most unflappable guy in the world second only to Machine machine has the best.
Rym: machine head is my favorite character.
Scott: She is my favorite because of all these are seen.
Rym: apparently machine head is one the last seven red lines.
Scott: Yeah, he's basically the Tiger Woods Roger Federer Michael Jordan, but he's a giant Michael Schumacher.
Rym: He is his car.
Rym: He races.
Rym: He's like, you know, you drive a car.
Rym: I fucking am a car That's right.
Scott: I can't lose a machine head.
Scott: and the thing the thing that I liked about machine head Right was the even though he's basically Michael Schumacher Right, and even though he's like that You know the the guy that the real main character has to be in the race.
Scott: any other movie ultra in the bad guy exactly, and like if he normally would have been the evil team like in Mighty Ducks or Shaolin soccer, but he wasn't.
Scott: he was actually an okay guy.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: he was also the best racer in the galaxy.
Rym: There's this great scene where someone's giving him shit and he's like like he stands.
Rym: some guy stands in his way in a restaurant.
Rym: I mean shit looks.
Rym: him is like you'd better move or I'll be forced to walk around you.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like it's bad.
Scott: What's even better?
Scott: Is it the pretty visual like what machine had looks like?
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: He looks like a giant guy.
Scott: He's.
Scott: he's gigantic.
Scott: He's gonna be the bad guy, but actually he's not a bad guy.
Scott: There's a scene like he's petting a dog.
Rym: He has a really cute dog.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Rym: it's like he also has a theme song.
Rym: That's just machine.
Scott: That just makes me really like him because it's like if he was the evil team I would have been like Oh evil team boo.
Rym: This is where this movie I think extends beyond what I would call a typical movie or an anime or whatever.
Scott: That's what separates it from Hanna-Barbera's wacky races.
Rym: It's that it threw me for a loop a bunch of times that I saw something happen.
Rym: I said and Scott and I were like, oh duh now X is going to happen as a result of this and about half the time Something so unexpected happened.
Scott: Well, it was weird like cuz I could predict five seconds in the future.
Scott: Right, like they were in the early in the movie I was like, oh that's that.
Scott: and then literally as soon as I finished talking they said what I said Yeah, and I was like, oh shit, but then you know, I couldn't predict the long run.
Scott: I was like, well, here's the possibilities for the long run.
Scott: They win they lose they crash, you know, it's like every possibility.
Scott: So I had no idea where it's going.
Scott: long term.
Scott: I could only predict like five seconds out which is pretty good But it threw me for a loop so many times.
Rym: and the things that threw me for a loop because it had a really cut Together style like in one hand is following the kind of main character plot and then on another hand like a second angle is following the government of robo world Incompetently trying to stop this race with its entire planetary military might.
Rym: and then the third angle is just like Interviews and news clips and character profiles and just kind of showing you.
Scott: it's showing you like two different worlds You're learning about.
Scott: it's like almost three different worlds.
Scott: It's showing you an exploration of the world of this galaxy this this civilization Also the world of robo world.
Scott: What's it like and what the community of racing fans and racing participants of?
Scott: Red line and yellow line are like.
Scott: so it's like, you know, it really fills in every possible gap in the movie.
Scott: But in the end all of this plot really doesn't matter which is great.
Scott: All this plot is is an excuse to have insanely awesomely animated action scenes.
Rym: The crazy I think because you had a carry of defense titan
Scott: and I think the robo world trying to destroy the race is the ultimate excuse because what you can do is you can alternate between scenes of racing action and scenes of exploding military fighting action and Both at the same time.
Scott: so it's like climax of the movie is this gigantic running battle race?
Scott: Yes, like.
Scott: there is no sure it's like.
Scott: if you could go to normal like a mecha show it's all fighting or like a racing show will be all racing, you know.
Scott: and But by combining the two You're basically like like doubling down on the insane things that can happen.
Scott: and then they push it all the way to the limit Literally with what's the star speckled whatever the streamlight streamlight?
Scott: Yeah, they put it to the limit with the stream.
Rym: But there's so many just great iconic scenes like the.
Rym: the robo world police keep like busting in unlike people because a bunch of people in robo world want to bet on the race because they think it's awesome and the Please bust in and the police basically just fucking murder everybody, you know, they yeah the police robots.
Rym: Yeah, it's sort of like bots like this little cute police bots like please disperse and then it starts firing missiles.
Rym: It's great And like the race the yellow line race You I love the culture of racing because if you ever see a real rally like a real US or world like there are any US rallies Anyway an earth rally in the real world.
Rym: today 2011 people will stand as Close to the most dangerous corners as they can as packed in as tightly as they can.
Scott: when and when the car is on its Way, they'll run out into the road and watch the car come at them.
Scott: Then when the car is about to hit them They'll run out of the way and go back to watch the car go around the corner.
Scott: Then they'll run out onto the track and watch and run and follow the car so they can see it.
Scott: leave To see the car as much as possible.
Rym: the culture of racing in red line is the same way except that thousands die at every Corner every time anyone comes by.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it's like because it's animated they're like and we can just do all sorts of ridiculous shit.
Scott: people died all over the place You know cars exploding whatever the fuck.
Scott: they didn't give a shit, right?
Scott: so the the plus the physics be damned.
Rym: aside from Robo world being Amazingly incompetent as a love story and surprisingly evil is that we've got the main guy JP who has an Intergalactic pompadour.
Rym: it is it is a pompadour to be to be.
Scott: It is not.
Scott: it is not as feared as the one in kamikaze girls.
Rym: So the thing is and I think this is actually my favorite thing in the movie because it only comes up twice.
Rym: Mm-hmm JP isn't is driven by two things in his life.
Rym: one He met a girl when he was young and into cars It was totally hot.
Rym: who's totally hot?
Rym: and he just really likes her and he really likes racing.
Rym: Yeah, too He saw who I can only guess is the god of pimps.
Scott: Oh, right the god of it.
Rym: There's the scene in the beginning.
Scott: It's the fact that you forget about it because it's like it's twice.
Scott: Basically, the god of pimps is like in one in one.
Scott: It's you know, they get one piece this red-haired shanks.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It's like the guy that luffy is always thinking about like what would red-haired shanks do right.
Rym: the god of pimps is He's the god of pimps, but so in the beginning the movie get this flash back.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I've upgraded him above machine head best character in the movie machine heads number two.
Rym: But you basically see this guy who is Akio times 10.
Rym: Akio would blow his load even looking at this.
Scott: definitely I guarantee a hundred Percent.
Scott: I'll bet money that they were inspired Slightly by Akio.
Scott: when making the god of there is he does the same car flip into the convertible.
Scott: that there is no way.
Rym: This is not the case.
Rym: but Black dynamite could learn a lot from the kid the god of pimps and for black dynamite to be able to learn for something from somebody.
Rym: As JP a young JP looks on this guy flips over into his amazing car and kisses two women Simultaneously.
Rym: and you might think what do you mean?
Rym: How literally you'll see.
Rym: he kisses two women Simultaneously And drives off into the sunset.
Rym: You see the kid the god of pimps one more time in the movie and I will not spoil it.
Rym: What happens in that scene is?
Rym: Great.
Scott: It is the greatest part of this movie is definitely the number one Part of the entire.
Scott: you will know it when it happens because it is the number two part of the movie is When the dude rescues the dude is gonna get killed.
Rym: Oh my god, cuz that comes out of nowhere is a big O scenario.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's like why don't they Joe?
Rym: They just did Oh times 10.
Rym: Oh and then one other twist happen when he hits the button thing.
Scott: That's great.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean this movie, you know, I While there's it's basically just so many awesome parts, right?
Scott: It's just awesome part after awesome part after awesome part with awesome animation.
Scott: But I I don't really remember any music from it.
Rym: Do you up the closing the credits theme?
Rym: because all right, that's really like the song from the credits And it's okay song that song see.
Rym: when I first heard about red line I didn't hear anything about it.
Rym: Someone sent me a link and it was a trailer for a red line and I had that song and it had that song and that Trailer amazed me.
Rym: Yep, but I was trying to keep my expectations low, even though the trailer filled me with a Surprising desire like we're talking like point four or five ponies worth of anticipation.
Rym: Yeah, and the fact that the movie lived up to that feeling really surprised me.
Scott: But while it is just this crazy awesome thing, but what are you gonna say?
Scott: Well, it's it's not like a life-changing movie.
Rym: there's no depth or No, there is depth, but it's not.
Rym: it's not deep To a degree that it's no Shakespeare the story.
Rym: It's not even a shake guy likes girl and also wants to be like the god of pimps.
Scott: So he pursues that and he gets into racing and then racing.
Rym: He's actually a really nice guy.
Rym: Like I like him and also Robo world The government of Robo world king offense.
Rym: the evil of the government of Robo world is eclipsed only by its incompetence.
Scott: That's right And that's pretty much all there is to it I think by the end of the movie the entire military of Robo world as a planetary system is gone Destroyed by the race.
Scott: But basically this is I would recommend this right.
Scott: this is basically in the same category as like You know the Lupin movies that aren't the castle of Cagliostre, right?
Scott: You bust like a mom.
Scott: Oh, well, not like mama.
Scott: Oh mama's like fume of conspiracy.
Rym: Columbus egg.
Scott: Sure Columbus egg a gold.
Scott: It was a gold battle on gold.
Scott: No, it's not like Babylon going, you know, you bust it's not.
Scott: you know, I'm not talking about the level of quality.
Scott: I'm saying is in the category right.
Scott: you bust this movie out at the party when everyone's over you watch it and go Show to the people who are drunk at a party like fuck that anime whatever.
Scott: but you can't put it.
Scott: I'm like your IMDb top 250 because it's not you know 250.
Rym: I think I might be able to.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: It's not 100.
Scott: No 250 maybe because it's not that kind right?
Scott: This is the kind.
Scott: It's not the kind of thing you could watch or you have any strong, you know It's just.
Scott: it's just like the funnest fun.
Scott: That's all there is to it.
Scott: It's just fun straight up.
Scott: It's like eating you're not?
Scott: it's like this right?
Scott: you might get some gummy bears and you eat the gummy bears.
Scott: You're like, oh shit.
Scott: Ah, it's the best right, but it's not French cuisine.
Scott: You can't rate gummy bears Like if you're.
Scott: if there's like a restaurant that served gummy bears you wouldn't put them on the list of best restaurants.
Rym: What if they were the best gummy bears?
Scott: I'm the saying these are the best gummy bears, but there's still gummy bears.
Scott: It's like you're not gonna put you know, if I can just you know a chocolate bar.
Rym: There's so many little touches though, like the money changer.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's pretty good.
Rym: or the scared guy selling cigarettes?
Scott: Well, that's part of the culture of the world.
Rym: yeah, all right, you know just same with the restaurant scene or like the the little things like the fact that JP gets a Motorcycle and he sits down on it and they give you this pretty great.
Scott: They give you this POV from him and you realize that can't see anything.
Rym: He can't actually see over the engine Or frisbee when frisbees like yeah, you want to win the race I put I got something for you And he unveils the car and he's basically put an anti-tank cannon on it.
Scott: It was extra wheel in the front Yeah, the fifth wheel.
Scott: Yeah, but it's just.
Scott: you know, it's that kind of thing, right?
Scott: It's just a huge.
Scott: have a good time party, but the brow is low, but it's like the highest quality It's not.
Scott: I wouldn't say it's low brows.
Rym: his middle brow expect a good time.
Scott: It's like the best middle brow there is.
Rym: This is the first movie in a while where I were somewhere.
Rym: I expected a roller coaster and I got a roller coaster.
Scott: It's like, you know, you have to.
Scott: the brow has to go separate from the regular old quality score, right?
Scott: So it's like of middle brow 10 out of 10, but high brow.
Scott: Well, it's not high brow.
Scott: So it doesn't rank.
Scott: You know, it's like not not.
Scott: it's like na not applicable when judging the high brow.
Rym: Also madhouse, so yeah.
Scott: Yeah can't go wrong.
Scott: Well you can But You want with this one.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Monday's gaming Tuesday's and a comic Wednesday's and indiscriminate Thursday's.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.