Rym: It's Wednesday, May 25th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: How'd you may know it?
Rym: Oh?
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I don't know if I ever mentioned this on the show.
Rym: cuz I've been biking a lot But the best part of having a bike at work is that when it's lunchtime?
Rym: I can get on that bike and go bike around.
Scott: I could do that also But that would mean going to elevator trips, which is not really worth it.
Rym: I got an elevator no matter what cuz I'm if I go out you know every lunch.
Rym: I go out I'm not staying in the office.
Scott: I mean elevator trips.
Scott: in the freight elevator We get away for the guy.
Rym: I leave my bike outside because the Lincoln building one Grand Central Plaza is run by douchebags But it won't let me bring my bike in because I work too early for their tiny Hours and also they suck even if you do use the elevator takes forever.
Scott: Blame the union.
Scott: labor is not you know?
Rym: Yeah, no the building is run pretty badly in general.
Rym: I have a lot of complaints about it But that shit.
Rym: That's one of many, but yes of my bikes outside, but I biked over to Fleet week.
Rym: I don't know what what ship it was.
Rym: But as I got over to buy the intrepid this huge ship easily as big as the intrepid very similarly set up Was wait so is an aircraft carrier.
Rym: Ah I guess the intrepid isn't like a supercarrier like I know But it is an aircraft carrier.
Rym: Yeah, though.
Rym: It's funny Aircraft carriers are massive and yet the intrepid is actually fairly small compared to aircraft carriers that are bigger than it.
Rym: Well compared to modern aircraft carrier.
Rym: Yes, you know But we're getting the space shuttle so fuck all y'all.
Scott: I think I still say that you with the space shuttle in Queens where all the rockets are as opposed to on the intrepid word You know why.
Scott: the reason I'm putting on the trip is they can charge money for.
Rym: no There's more to it than that.
Rym: Do you know which one we're getting?
Rym: No, no, you really don't know.
Rym: we're getting the enterprise, okay, you know why we're getting the enterprise.
Rym: The intrepid went and picked it up after a test thing.
Rym: The intrepid has a history with that space shuttle.
Rym: Hey Yeah But the ship pulled in.
Rym: it was sideways like perpendicular to the back of the intrepid.
Rym: I guess the front the intrepid back.
Scott: I'm Side is the front mister.
Rym: You don't know if you show me a picture.
Rym: I think I could I guess pretty accurately Based on the engines and whatnot.
Rym: I guess I don't know if it's a screwdriver.
Rym: I don't know that much about ships I'm not even anything.
Rym: I know some.
Rym: I know a lot about Napoleonic era ships.
Scott: I know they float in the water and they have planes on them.
Rym: I know about the history of nuclear reactors on them and different kinds of drive mechanisms, but I know more about Horatio boats than about.
Rym: For some reason.
Rym: I know a lot about the armaments on the ships, but I don't know much about the ships themselves.
Scott: Thus is the way of you know, a kind of person who plays video games like Counter Strike.
Scott: Yep, you know a lot about.
Rym: I can tell you all about the FNP 90 Useless anyway, yeah But the ship was perpendicular it was being tugged in and I happened to arrive just as the entire ship screw was Presenting themselves along the rails and there's a big celebration.
Rym: So I watched that and then I biked back to work.
Scott: Hey Exciting.
Rym: Yeah, that was the most exciting part of my day until just now when we're doing GeekNights All right.
Scott: So let us uh Let us move along to some newses, right?
Rym: So that's Wednesday anime night.
Scott: There's actually some mild news here.
Rym: mild That's the best we got like.
Rym: hey, we got mild mild medium.
Scott: Maybe it's medium news.
Scott: It's definitely not hot.
Scott: So this?
Scott: this is a rumor, right but it seems to be.
Scott: there's a great deal of evidence for it So I'm gonna bring it out, right?
Scott: basically Someone was interviewing Takashi Mika a inner director of such films as Each of the killer and my number one movie.
Rym: Yeah Tons of awesome violent movies, by the way, if you have not seen each of the key we should do a show on each of the killer Didn't we do ultraviolet movies?
Rym: No, I think we could do a show just on each of the killer though I'd have to watch it again.
Scott: Well, I haven't you know.
Rym: anyway, yeah, if you've not seen each of the killer and You are okay with ultra violence.
Rym: I Want you all to watch it just so I can see your rage face at the ending.
Scott: The thing is people people don't realize but you know Mika for all his Reputation of making a bunch of ultraviolet movies of which Mika was probably I mean each he was the most violent.
Scott: He actually is.
Rym: act is a pretty good film director period More of those semi-violent Yakuza movies we used to watch every day.
Scott: but anyway He was being interviewed by someone at the Cannes Film Festival and he said that his next film he said out of his mouth his next film is a court drama based on a Nintendo DS video game and He said that his Little blood and it is a light comedy that he's filming now
Rym: Scott.
Rym: Let's let's see if we can.
Rym: we can narrow this down.
Rym: I mean, we're intelligent people, right?
Rym: So I mean, can you think of any?
Rym: DS games that are based on courtrooms.
Scott: There are pretty much two.
Scott: there's Yuzai x muzai, which is a Namco game and Phoenix Wright.
Rym: On top of that I'm so excited about the upcoming Phoenix Wright movie.
Scott: on top of that There was some photographs of what can only be a movie set for a Phoenix Wright game.
Scott: It could not possibly be anything else.
Scott: Well, I guess it could be Phoenix Wright land if there were an amusement park that was going to make a Phoenix Wright land.
Rym: So they every day they murder a random person.
Scott: There's photos that were put on the internet that were definitely not photoshopped that were clearly not can tell by the pixels.
Scott: Yes, I can tell by the pixels It was absolutely.
Scott: it could not be anything other than a Phoenix Wright movie set.
Scott: Therefore it is pretty much they're making this or at least they made a set.
Rym: now The big question really is going to be how much Mika like is he gonna do his kind of crazy stuff?
Scott: Well, I mean maybe during, you know when they're showing the people being horribly murdered.
Scott: I'm feeling it's gonna be incorrect.
Scott: judging based on the look of that set I think it's gonna be pretty faithful adaptation to the game.
Rym: I concur on that front.
Rym: But I wonder if he'll pull some sort of crazy mind fuck as he seems to like to do like some clothes Already a crazy mind fuck.
Scott: It already has a twist.
Scott: That's the whole point of Phoenix, right?
Rym: You know him.
Rym: he'll twist it again like the movie will end with Phoenix.
Scott: He's not writing it.
Scott: He's just directing.
Rym: Yeah, he'll direct it.
Rym: He'll add a scene at the end where Phoenix wakes up and he's actually No, but naga.
Scott: but anyway, this is totally awesome Like it's the kind of unexpected thing that is like, you know, it's a little nerd.
Scott: It's like nerd.
Rym: Ah, man It's a lot like when the Scott Pilgrim movie was announced.
Rym: people like oh they're making a Scott Pilgrim movie.
Rym: Man wouldn't be awesome if they oh they did get on a Monoguchi due to the music.
Scott: Well, he did.
Scott: they did the music for the video.
Rym: Oh, yeah the video game.
Rym: Oh, well, how's the view him gonna be?
Rym: Oh a bit styling 16-bit style.
Scott: Yeah It's one of those things where someone does right by the nerds and there is some sort of nerd Collision in the in the Adam Smasher.
Scott: That is the entertainment world.
Rym: My favorite occurrences of those are when it's the kind of thing that nerd would say Oh that would never happen.
Rym: but would it be awesome if it did?
Scott: because like you would never even think of it that it would happen because it's such a Combination of awesome things the nerds love.
Rym: if two years ago you came to me and you're like, hey What if Takashi Miike made a movie for Phoenix Wright?
Rym: I'd be like, huh?
Scott: That's a combination of two things that are really far apart from each other that we that we like both of right.
Scott: It's sort of crazy Scott.
Rym: What if Takashi Miike made an adaptation movie of sanctuary?
Scott: I'm just saying you know it's like you have two nerderies that are both your nerderies that are far apart and somehow they get together like What if there was a My Little Pony manga drawn by the guys do Death Note?
Scott: It's like oh my god.
Scott: It's like you.
Scott: just take two nerderies that are so far apart and separated From each other and you bring them all the way together.
Rym: imagine if you could have like a sampling like a thousand people in front of you and they represent a perfect cross-section of the modern industrialized worlds population Announcing.
Rym: any one of those combinations will have 1.5 dudes going And everyone else not even like.
Rym: I'm giving a shit.
Rym: Yeah So the in huge news the big Apple comic-con was big.
Scott: if you have the word big in it Yeah.
Rym: and apples Guess those are good.
Scott: I like them.
Rym: So we've talked about this before.
Rym: basically The big Apple comic-con is one of many attempts by wizard to not go out of business.
Scott: Well, they already stopped their magazine right.
Scott: wizard magazines dead.
Rym: Yeah, so they're basically going head-to-head.
Rym: Well They're going head-to-head with Reed exposition actually read pop.
Rym: Yeah, because they split all that off and it's complicated business relationship.
Rym: They're going head-to-head with them in the same way that I could go head-to-head in the boxing ring with I don't know Mike Tyson.
Rym: I Mean.
Rym: technically I could say I'm challenging Mike Tyson to some boxing and when he refuses I can say that yeah I want to fight him, but he just won't.
Rym: clearly he's afraid of me.
Scott: Well, he would if there was money involved and then you would just be dead.
Rym: Yeah, I would one punch not even lunch.
Scott: He's like, well, you wouldn't see the punch, but there would be one of them.
Scott: It might take two weeks on there.
Scott: You would walk up to him and then you would be.
Rym: it might take two because he punched me and I'd be falling over Already dead, but he hit me again before I hit the ground.
Scott: You'd be surprised how fast you can fall.
Rym: You'd be surprised how fast he can punch.
Rym: you would probably crumple forwards maybe yeah.
Rym: But yeah, the Big Apple comic-con was you know one of their attempts and I actually could not find any real press about it or attendance numbers or anything Like.
Rym: I wanted to know how it was.
Scott: It's just one of those rooms full of people selling shit.
Rym: I knew some of our like you go to noth were there Yeah, and they didn't have anything to say about it and no one had anything to say about it.
Rym: and I looked around online and I found one article for my Fox, New York.
Rym: and The reason I make this my news is because whenever there's something nerdy Mainstream news it's like why do they even bother reporting on it because they put forth articles like this.
Rym: I'll read for you the entire article Big Apple comic-con opens in New York City.
Rym: Wizard world Big Apple comic-con spring edition is in full swing at the Penn Plaza Pavilion.
Rym: The event is the largest and longest-running comic-con in New York.
Rym: That's longest-running Well, actually it's renamed.
Rym: So that's actually kind of not true either.
Rym: Yeah Thousands of fans of all ages got their chance to meet their favorite comic book creators.
Rym: Comic-con is North America's largest pop culture tour And the event runs through the weekends.
Rym: So it's not the largest pop culture tour.
Scott: It is if you count because they have so many conventions that there's no really no other tours.
Rym: Ah, but I mean, what does pop culture to remain?
Rym: I mean, what about a band that's traveling and doing like a thousand concerts over the course of a year, you know It's all definition.
Rym: Yeah, but the fact that this article consists of four paragraphs Each of us a PR article written by the comic-con that they just the.
Rym: no It's not.
Rym: this is that this is.
Rym: there's a separate kind of news article.
Rym: This isn't the PR article written by the comic-con This is the board reporter and his intern had to cover The event because it was an event and they knew it was happening.
Rym: So they sent a guy down.
Rym: They got like two minutes of video and this guy wrote four single-sentence paragraphs Claiming it was the largest and longest-running comic-con in New York, which is interesting because I did a little of my own research.
Rym: So the New York comic-con run by Reed is in the Jacob Javits Convention Center.
Rym: The big apple comic-con is in the Penn Plaza Pavilion the PPP.
Rym: Yeah, not to be confused with the PPP.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It features over 50,000 square feet of convex of conference space.
Scott: So that's very small.
Rym: It's clearly much larger than the 675,000 square foot Jacob Javits Convention Center gets somehow a larger convention fit inside.
Rym: It must be a TARDIS.
Rym: Yeah Four-dimensional convention, I don't know I wanted to report on like the numbers or like something about the big apple comic-con But all I could find it's just a room full of comics.
Rym: There's nothing else to it, but I was looking for like a blog someone saying something.
Rym: Here's what I found someone stole 10 grand worth of Neil Adams original art.
Rym: Oh, it was on his table and I guess the earth expanded and it fell through a crack and disappeared.
Rym: And One of the guests of the con didn't show up because he was arrested in Connecticut for having child porn.
Rym: Yep, and possibly making child porn.
Scott: The thing is that guy's actually kind of a good artist.
Rym: Yeah, he does a countdown mystery something.
Rym: I see a picture of here.
Scott: Yeah, basically it was interesting because somebody in Over, you know on the Internet's was had a question right there.
Scott: Like look I have a piece of art by this guy Who turned out to be a pedophile later, right?
Scott: But it's on sort of a jam piece, right?
Scott: So a jam piece is when like you get a big piece of paper and you go around to different artists and you might say Hey you draw your favorite x-man.
Scott: Hey you draw your favorite x-man on the same piece of.
Scott: you know, you go to different artists You have each person draw a different x-man, right?
Scott: That's like a jam piece.
Scott: So imagine if you had this pedophile guy Draw something on the jam piece at before.
Scott: you knew he's a pedophile, right and he was still in pencil.
Scott: So you could still erase it.
Rym: Oh, so so if the debate is do you sell it for more money to face the work buyer?
Scott: Well, no No, it's a jam piece.
Scott: So this art by other artists on the same piece of paper.
Scott: So you're either erase it or keep it or sell it.
Scott: Well, no, you can't sell the whole piece because you want to finish it.
Scott: It's not done.
Rym: yet It's like maybe you want to but maybe you want to finish it and then sell it pointing out that yeah That pedophiles on there.
Scott: No, it's it's because you're.
Scott: yeah You're assuming that you're gonna keep it because it's this jam piece You've been having.
Scott: you've been getting worked on at convention after convention.
Rym: Because go back to John Wayne Gacy the clown serial killer.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and he started painting a lot especially in prison and all his paintings were auctioned and People debated like at one point maybe they should sell them and have the money go to like charities for victims of crime or whatever Mm-hmm.
Rym: So instead a Whole bunch of people got together bought up as many of the paintings as they could and then burn them.
Scott: Oh How much they pay though, I don't know who got that money I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I would say I don't know.
Rym: if I were him I would erase it.
Rym: Yeah, if you were found guilty, but the evidence is looking pretty big in this news article I mean, it's pretty much.
Scott: I mean, you know, we don't know if he's guilty or not.
Scott: So I would definitely wait at least for that.
Scott: Yeah, but the evidence As was reported in my in my opinion the evidence as reported by the news if accurate is pretty damning Had a USB stick he gave to a funeral allegedly.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, he did have everything allegedly.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah USB stick Allegedly gave it to a funeral home.
Rym: funeral home allegedly found child porn on it.
Rym: a warrant was issued in his house.
Rym: They found much more child porn.
Scott: There is a reasonable doubt the child including the child porn could have put on been put on the USB stick By the funeral home and then the child porn in his house could have been put there by someone else.
Rym: But the child porn in his house allegedly includes one of his nieces.
Rym: I mean, I guess the funeral home could have kidnapped his niece.
Scott: Does he live with anyone?
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'm gonna link to this news article.
Rym: The sad thing is this news article right on CBR which looks like a comic news place is basically like.
Rym: So far the mainstream news hasn't really picked up on the fact that this guy was a comic artist.
Rym: Kind of hope that doesn't happen.
Rym: We don't want to get bad publicity.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the thing is right, you know You were just complaining about how bad the the news article about the you know, the big apple comic-con is.
Rym: Well, this article is like one two, it's four paragraphs, but there are multiple sentences per paragraph.
Rym: It's actually there's almost journalism here almost.
Scott: but that's the thing is like, you know Anyone who has an area of expertise like maybe your science is notorious.
Rym: I could write a better article on the New York or the big Comic-con.
Rym: then these people did and I didn't even go to it.
Scott: What I'm saying is anyone's an area of expertise, right?
Scott: So if we read something in the New York Times about technology, right?
Scott: We see that it's an awful article almost all the time.
Scott: Yep, right and we read an article maybe not in our area of expertise Maybe something in the food or art section or you know, right and we don't really see anything wrong with it.
Scott: But the thing is I can guarantee you the people who are like professional chefs or artists or whatever They they look at that food art section article the same way we look at the technology section article.
Scott: every almost every article in Mainstream news is awful.
Scott: Well, it's just whatever your area of expertise is.
Scott: Your articles are awful, but you don't realize it about the other one.
Rym: at the same time There are degrees and my main point there is that if you look at this article While there's probably problems with it and problems with many articles is at least a number of words strung together with no grammatical errors.
Rym: That's true, which is more than I can say for many news articles.
Scott: I read well, I'm talking about mainstream media Right, like the main news.
Rym: Yeah, cuz right cuz the one you CNN that looked like they were written by kindergartners, right?
Scott: So that first article you mentioned was from Fox or something, right?
Scott: But Fox right but CBR that's a specialized thing.
Scott: So if you read news from a specialized source, they're probably gonna get it more right if it's in their area of expertise, right?
Scott: So if you're reading a site that's only technology news The technology news is on that site might be less crappy than the ones from New York Times, which is generic newspaper You know, yep anyway.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: I was watching My Little Pony videos last night Just kind of because and it reminded me how much I like PMVs which reminded me how much I like AMVs.
Scott: these are good.
Rym: I'm actually a really big fan of anime music video.
Rym: good ones.
Rym: I don't go to convention contests anymore because That's a waste of time.
Rym: I think we've talked about it before but I'll sum it up.
Rym: even the biggest anime cons have Pretty shit anime music video contests because they often insist on showing bad ones and they have rules that often will exclude good videos from actually being showed or being competing because they'll say like oh if you Already won a con.
Rym: You can't win our con as opposed.
Rym: I mean if I were like Otakon or anime Boston I would say you have to have already won another con within the past 365 days or we won't even show your video.
Rym: Yeah, that's what I would do.
Rym: But anyway, I really like anime music videos.
Rym: So I thought this is a good opportunity to pick a random one but a newish one and it just so happens.
Rym: I ran afoul of this pretty funny AMV to Hajime No Ippo about Takamura Who is possibly my second or third favorite character?
Scott: Yeah, actually I was reading some of the mangas that pick up after where The show ends because I've watched every episode.
Scott: Yeah, and there was a I don't know if it was the first favorite character poll but it was a favorite character poll among the readers who actually read Shonen Jump for real and Takamura was number one of course kind of like mr.
Scott: Tokai exactly anyway, so I have for you.
Scott: I don't know if this is actually a valid thing of the day.
Scott: It's an anti thing of the day, right?
Rym: So it's something bad exactly.
Rym: Oh You want to do like a reverse week?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: we should do that.
Rym: We should do a four night.
Scott: This isn't is an anti thing of the day thing.
Scott: They supposed to be the best thing we found on the internet today or what recently since the last show.
Scott: But this is something bad real bad.
Rym: So I was gonna.
Rym: I was gonna make a joke, but I stopped.
Scott: so This is basically a blog post right from May 5th, which I guess is 20 days or May 20 May 11.
Rym: I don't know What is it May 5th or May 11th?
Scott: This is I can't tell but whatever is that?
Rym: What kind of journalism is this?
Scott: because the way the date is formatted on this site is not easy to read.
Scott: It's like just it's like the numbers are just all around.
Rym: But how could you confuse May 5th and May 11th?
Scott: because it says five.
Scott: There's a big number five And then it says May slash 11, uh 5th of May 2011. it could be that's could possibly but you know.
Scott: Anyway, this guy's like.
Scott: let me read the opening paragraph of this blog post.
Scott: Folks, it is no secret that I like children even as a we let It is.
Rym: oftentimes I'll read something that is bad and I'm reading it's like ah, ah, ah, it is rare for that to happen In the first sentence,
Scott: all right, even as a we led back in the day I would more often than not favor the younger cast members in the anime I watched and this remains unchanged even till today.
Rym: However, I think Daryl Surrett tweeted this art.
Rym: He did.
Scott: That's why I found it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: However in this time and age my fondness for the little ones is misconstrued to be malicious in nature.
Scott: in order to dispel some of That prejudice I would like to take this opportunity to celebrate Children's Day.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Scott: So, you know this guy is doing by listing five of my favorite children in Japanese cartoons.
Rym: I Saw that article.
Rym: Yeah, I'd scroll down to the pictures my favorite.
Scott: Wow I mean, you know you think from that opening paragraph right that he's basically like look I know you guys are probably gonna think I'm a pedophile like, you know, totally dude, bro situation imagine fashion You know, he's probably thinking oh everyone thinks I'm a pedophile.
Rym: It's like dude.
Rym: I'm bad because I'm dressing up babies.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: I mean you're playing.
Scott: What if I just happen to like younger care?
Scott: I have a preference.
Scott: I like younger characters in anime which could be legitimate Right, it's sort of like, you know, look I'm not a pervert.
Scott: I just you know, I don't like them in that way I like them in just.
Scott: I you know, everyone has favorite characters.
Scott: some people like, you know, the badass giant character Everybody likes for example of Chio-chan from asa manga dial exactly, right?
Scott: So you just like it yotsuba, right?
Scott: You just like them the way, you know in a totally or not only because according to this guy She's technically 400 years old.
Scott: So it's okay a totally non malicious normal liking, right?
Rym: Yeah, pretty much sounds like he's straight-up saying like I want to have sex with little kid.
Scott: Well in the first paragraph, it sounds like he's not.
Scott: but then as soon as he actually lists the characters He posts really perverted panty shots and he's like, yeah I want to take them to town and he's like he's.
Scott: at least I got to give the guy credit.
Scott: He's not hiding that he's a pedophile.
Scott: He's like, yep.
Scott: I want to rape little girlies.
Rym: Ah to his credit sounds like he doesn't want to forcibly.
Rym: It's not rape rape No, okay, and to at least he's taking his predilections out on two-dimensional characters that don't exist.
Scott: But the thing is right.
Scott: it's like, you know Typically what you have is you have like the love Hina situation where it's like, you know You you.
Scott: it's perverted but it's not perverted right?
Scott: There's some sort of cover like, you know chew brah.
Scott: It's okay I'm learning about underwear love Hina.
Scott: It's a wacky comedy, right?
Scott: You know, there's some sort of cover for the pervertedness, but this guy doesn't even bother with cover.
Scott: He's just you know a sick fuck and it's like.
Scott: this is the perfect example of all that is wrong With these kinds of anime people and most of the new animes that are all moe perverted crap.
Rym: I would argue that they're similarly messed up people who just don't know anime exists, right?
Scott: But I'm just saying is that you know this kind of shit gives no normal people.
Scott: if they see this they think all anime.
Rym: Is this got by the same token?
Rym: I mean most people think that all IT people are fat.
Rym: Unix Santa's and all computer science guys are like Jonathan Colton.
Scott: They aren't Yeah Yeah, yeah, okay my point exactly.
Rym: Well, it's funny cuz I'm not really an IT guy like I'm an engineer.
Rym: it's kind of all the IT guys I know tend to do more IT Stereotypical stuff.
Scott: This is this is horrible, but you have to see it just so you can like, you know It's like you got to see what what's the worst that you have a good perspective on the world?
Scott: Wow of disgusting horrible people.
Rym: All right in the meta moment We will be at PAX Prime and PAX dev probably and all that stuff in the far future.
Rym: The book club book is Isaac Asimov's foundation.
Rym: You should be in the forum because it's rockin.
Scott: Let's keep it short.
Rym: Keep it short.
Rym: Nothing else.
Scott: recess is coming up pretty soon.
Rym: Yeah, you know all that stuff.
Rym: Anime, we watched an anime.
Scott: We did watch an anime.
Rym: Scott watched all of it.
Rym: I watched five episodes.
Rym: Yeah, so apparently Scott has nothing else to do.
Scott: I got plenty to do.
Scott: You know how much I got done?
Scott: Lots.
Scott: Anyway, so Hajime no Ippo is a shounen fighting.
Scott: Manga slash anime about boxing the sport of boxing.
Scott: So I guess it's not.
Scott: shounen fighting is shown in sports But it it's the same formula as initial D or as Dragon Ball or as any of those shounen Naruto or hakara.
Scott: no go It's the same formula, you know And it's about boxing and it's been going for an incredibly long time.
Scott: There's like hundreds and hundreds of chapters The manga is still going.
Scott: as far as I can tell the anime Consists of a 75 episode TV series from about you know, it was basically.
Scott: it came out you know in the about a decade ago, then there's a Like a one episode TV special that is sort of like champion road.
Scott: It's like it.
Scott: basically it's an.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's a long episode that follows up the 75 episode series.
Scott: Then there's an OAV single episode and then there is a newer series.
Scott: That is 26 episodes.
Scott: That came out just a few years ago.
Scott: that just pretty much picks up right where the other stuff left off you know and the anime as far as I can tell is almost a Direct translation of the manga.
Scott: like I read a couple manga chapters that overlapped with the anime that I saw which is all the anime And it was effectively identically the same.
Scott: like the manga is storyboards for the anime 99%.
Scott: Now, why do we care about Hajime no Ippo at all?
Scott: Another shown in fighting things.
Rym: Well on one end.
Rym: I mean forget our tastes.
Rym: just look at popularity.
Rym: It's just one of those kind of always there.
Rym: a lot of people watch it generally just really really popular.
Scott: Well, the thing is it's not really really popular, right?
Scott: It's really really popular among the sort of you know The anime people who care enough about anime and are hardcore and want to watch the.
Scott: you know The series good animes.
Scott: those people seem to like Hajime and talk about it a lot.
Scott: Among the general anime fandom in America.
Rym: Most people have never heard of it never heard of it and don't care I mean, I didn't know much about it until relatively recently.
Scott: I knew that it was an anime about boxing.
Rym: It just wasn't on my radar cuz I was watching other stuff.
Scott: Yeah I mean it was on the list, you know, cuz people kept talking about it.
Scott: I didn't watch it at all.
Scott: But anyway, so why do we care about this shonen fighting?
Scott: Just you know, just another formulaic show.
Scott: Well, the thing is while it is entirely 100% formulaic it is an incredible I don't want to say the best but an incredible Execution of that formula.
Scott: right.
Scott: there are plenty of shows that follow this formula Poorly, well even even shows I like like initial D.
Rym: I will say I like initial D Initially is kind of stupid and it has has a lot of problems.
Rym: It does not pull off the formula as well as Hajime no Ippo does.
Rym: the only reason initial D Eeks past it my personal like is because of the music.
Scott: I happen to like that music a lot Yeah, but like something like rave master or my god Naruto anime or bleach, right?
Scott: Those actually execute the formula poor very poorly compared to Hajime.
Scott: no info right?
Scott: They drag out the fights Forget the Final Fantasy anime.
Scott: Yeah, right There's plenty of you know shows in the same exact genre that are just bad.
Scott: They don't you know, even though they're the same show they on the sir on this, you know the foundation.
Scott: They just the animations not good.
Rym: The character designs aren't as good And Naruto are well animated and have good characters.
Scott: Yes The humor isn't as good, you know this stuff about it.
Scott: This is not as good Even though the story is the same thing only to replace boxing with ninja fights or whatever else.
Scott: you want to replace it with The other thing about her car Hajime no Ippo.
Scott: Alright as I learned this that The show the anime didn't start until after there was already a whole bunch of manga, right?
Scott: So something like Naruto.
Scott: actually the anime gets ahead of the manga or catches up to it.
Rym: and then what happens?
Scott: they filler episodes filler episodes and tournaments.
Scott: Right guys, y'all got to come back home to do the tournament Whereas Ippo is still even today far behind the manga.
Scott: if you watch all of the anime as I have You can go to ish a manga chapter number 400 and you're exactly.
Scott: but there's like way more than 400 chapters.
Scott: Wait hundreds more right?
Scott: so they still if they're gonna animate it They have tons of material to work with and they can get the pacing exactly, right?
Scott: They can make the fights last the correct number of episodes.
Scott: They don't have to drag them out for 10 episodes while they wait for another month.
Rym: Oh, that is what I really like about the show.
Rym: It is one thing initial D did well too.
Rym: is that the the formula like the fights?
Rym: Keep me engaged the whole time and there they they don't just kind of go back and forth like a lot of crappy shown in Fighting.
Rym: shows will kind of go back and forth with nothing happening.
Rym: everything that happens in the fight matters.
Scott: Yep, right then and there and it's all and most of it is just building suspense, right?
Scott: And the only really negative thing I can say about the fights is that at least you know Is that the fights have sort of this every single fight is the ultimate battle, right?
Scott: At least every fight that matters almost every fight that matters is like so epic.
Scott: They both go down ten times to the final round, you know.
Scott: Whereas in real boxing a lot of fights are uneventful because they're sort of one-sided ish like all those Mike Tyson fights.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, you see people these boxing records of like, you know, 62 KOs or something.
Scott: Well, that's because he fought a whole bunch of chumps that he knocked out in the first round.
Scott: Right and you don't you know All the fights that are important to the plot of Hajime no Ippo are always epic fights Everything's like that.
Rym: I mean what sanctuary have been nearly as interesting if it kept showing him just taking a poop.
Scott: No, but I mean a couple times the fights got to be lame, right?
Rym: So like he goes to fight with the senator in America and the guy just as push over.
Scott: Yeah I think there was one non epic fight in Hajime in a bow.
Rym: Oh, yeah, he fights that bear.
Rym: I mean, whatever.
Scott: Yeah The other thing is this show right.
Scott: the first the 75 episode first series at least right was made by Madhouse And they made it pretty much right after they made Trigun and it was directed by the same guy directed Trigun Yeah And it seems like it was pretty much the same people.
Scott: and you can tell like the music is similar Like it has to be made by the exact same people and it was actually the last hand animated like cell Painted show done by Madhouse.
Rym: after that's a very nice piece of trivia.
Rym: You can lay on people.
Scott: Yeah after that they went digital.
Scott: So it's like, you know all of the animation Qualities and musical qualities and production qualities of Trigun are there.
Scott: and Hajime no Ippo only better, right?
Scott: So for that aspect, you know, it's got a whole bunch of a pluses in its execution doesn't have the same Pacifism vibe.
Scott: No, it's usually about punching someone's face.
Scott: Yep and you know the show is done while it there is a lot of Realistic boxing knowledge because that's how these shows work, right?
Scott: Go teaches you about go.
Rym: even initial D teaches like some things about Your car.
Rym: no go also has ghosts telling you what move to make.
Rym: Why do you think you always lose it go?
Rym: Yeah, how'd you go?
Scott: How'd?
Scott: you may know Ippo has a lot of real boxing stuff, but it also has lots of basically superhero nonsense Like, you know, everyone has special attacks and people take some unreason Everyone takes some unreasonable out amount of damage like they would have been severely brain damaged by now.
Rym: Oh, these characters are all gonna have There's a you know punch drunk.
Rym: love the movie.
Rym: Yeah punch drunk is a term.
Rym: There's a medical term for now.
Rym: that basically is the dementia that happens if you're a boxer.
Scott: Yeah, they.
Scott: they do refer to punch drunkenness and it does take place in the plot and you know There are.
Scott: they are like you got to throw in the towel.
Scott: He's gonna be permanently damaged.
Scott: and you know, there's a lot of they talk about it In they're already permanently damaged.
Scott: Yeah, it's not completely ignored.
Scott: But the thing is the amount of damage they portray versus the amount of damage it would take to incur permanent injury is Not matching right, you know, it's like they're like, oh no if he takes any more hits He'll be.
Scott: you know, he might get brain damage and it's like.
Scott: actually he's probably already been brain damage apparently based on that number and level of hits and You know, so if you're looking for ultra realistic boxing you're not gonna get it But it you will learn about boxing and just like you watch any Shonen thing if you get into it You'll suddenly care about whatever it's about.
Scott: Like if you watch a car now go you start wanting to play.
Scott: go if you watch an initial D You start wanting to drive cars.
Scott: if you watch how'd you man Apple?
Scott: You start thinking that you could be a boxer and then you say wait a minute.
Scott: I don't want brain damage And I'm way too old to start boxing now way too late.
Scott: You got to start that shit when you're like 18.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, I mean Scott's seen all of it.
Rym: We're not gonna spoil anything.
Rym: This is a review to get you to watch it.
Rym: But what I mean one thing I really enjoy about the show and a lot of the kind of shown any fighting shows I do like have this is that the characters are kind of goony and they're all friends with each other and they rip on each other and fight with each other and just a kind Of funny.
Scott: Yeah, the cast of characters is is pretty good, right?
Scott: You've got you know You got like the mom and you know Some other side characters and it starts out in school, but eventually gets away from schools.
Scott: But some of the school characters stick around But most of the main characters are all the people in the gym Right the coach and you know these three other boxers that are in the same gym as Ippo the main character.
Scott: I guess we should summarize the plot at least a little bit.
Rym: Oh becomes a boxer.
Scott: This yeah, Ippo is a kid who gets picked on And his mom runs a fishing boat.
Scott: So he doesn't really.
Scott: he's always working to help his mom with the fishing boat.
Scott: his dad is dead we had to assume right.
Scott: and So because of that he doesn't hang out with people really.
Scott: after school he gets picked on.
Scott: one day He's getting picked on under a bridge and some guy comes to save him.
Scott: Who is?
Scott: Takamura?
Scott: the the the king of perverts.
Scott: It was also an amazing box.
Rym: It's pretty great.
Rym: I love the scene.
Scott: I think he's like the funniest character.
Rym: they get him into that They're like, alright, you're gonna train at our gym and the two goons like I we're gonna we're gonna train you.
Rym: Takamura is like nah, I'm gonna train him.
Rym: then the old guys like screw you all I'm gonna train him.
Scott: Yeah, Takamura is basically the second most important boxer in the show after Ippo, right?
Scott: It's like if they're not so sometimes they're focused the most of the time they're focusing on Ippo's plot.
Scott: But Takamura's plot is like the second plot, you know It's like.
Scott: you know.
Scott: when Ippo's taking a rest after taking a beating your Takamura is fighting someone for a championship or something like that You know.
Scott: But yeah, so Takamura saves him from some bullies and then Ippo starts boxing and then he likes it and then he Advances and levels up and fights like shows that we like.
Rym: it breaks One of the tropes of these kinds of shows and that he's the main character and he is special.
Rym: He has a lot of raw talent.
Scott: Yeah his raw talent You know.
Scott: in initial D the raw talent comes from his dad tricked him by giving him a fast car and making him Deliver the tofu every day, but that was all in the past.
Rym: So when the show starts he is already like in the top 1% of drivers in the world Like he's already invincible and your car no go he gets his power from the ghost.
Scott: right what other shonen things are there.
Rym: But in this show, he basically He's you know, it's like, uh, what was that movie?
Rym: God the kid who can throw the baseball really fast?
Scott: Oh the one really the year we get Rookie of the year, I think I don't know what it was called.
Rym: I think I saw in the theater.
Scott: I might have yeah, but anyway, yeah.
Scott: So that's sort of like a lot of things a lot of other shonen properties.
Scott: Someone gets their powers of being awesome because of course the main character is like the greatest, right?
Scott: They get it by Fiat or by supernatural events like Naruto.
Scott: just has this fox spirit in him or whatever, right?
Scott: But in Hajime no Ippo, he has some natural talent.
Scott: because he worked on the fishing boat.
Scott: He was always carrying lots of heavy things to build up his strength, right?
Scott: we're just sort of a side effect of carrying heavy things.
Scott: he became strong and And Because he was always on a fishing boat.
Scott: He has excellent legs for balance, right?
Scott: So that's his natural talent, but that alone doesn't help you box and he actually builds up his boxing skills by Intense training.
Rym: Well, his first fight is great.
Rym: He's basically just like Defending and doing nothing else just sitting there like, uh, uh, get ya in his first fight ever which isn't a real fight It's just basically sparring.
Scott: the first time he went to the gym He's basically like.
Scott: my goal is to make it to the end of the thing, right?
Scott: You know, my goal is to not get knocked out and just to survive to the end of this fight.
Scott: So it's sort of like hey, you know, they're not starting out with like some ridiculous thing where he knocks out some champion.
Scott: You know in the first go.
Scott: it's sort of like look you've never boxed before.
Scott: if you tried you would just get just killed Like if you walked into the ring, so and fight number one You just dodge and defend yourself and turtle up right and that's what he does.
Scott: You know, it's it's.
Scott: and it's kind of cool that you actually see him even later in the show.
Scott: He's always working hard and every time he has a new fight.
Scott: They follow that same formula of here's the next opponent.
Scott: Oh my god, the next opponent is so dangerous.
Scott: There's no way the main character can win.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: It's key.
Rym: What's wrong with you?
Rym: He'll always win, right?
Scott: There's no way you can win.
Scott: The next guy is so dangerous or sometimes it's like maybe you can win But there's always this threat where you're not certain whether he can win or not.
Scott: right?
Scott: the opponent is almost always threatening.
Scott: has some Thing about the opponent that makes you not sure if the main character will win or not?
Scott: Right, like you wouldn't bet your life on it And then they'd be main character.
Scott: all info always trains a whole fuck ton right between every fight.
Scott: They actually show you him training and what kind of training he's doing and then in the fight They show you how that particular training that he was doing comes out to help him win and he wins like
Rym: Pretty good and all the like training and everything like that maintains a high quality pretty much all the time.
Scott: Yeah, there it's a first.
Rym: I mean try gun.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I like the show.
Rym: it goes way off model.
Rym: Yeah a lot.
Scott: and the thing is why.
Scott: well the thing is Hajime and it was easy to stay on model because I think the character designs make it easy and because the the manga storyboards Make it easy, right?
Scott: Where's try gun?
Scott: do I can use the try gun manga for shit, right?
Scott: It doesn't help you with anything.
Scott: I think that's also why they change all the does the try gun designs.
Scott: I got hiccups.
Scott: Oh great Yeah, the thing is right is they show you how the training comes out to help him And in doing so right?
Scott: Oh, no, we were talking about the animation super hiccups, right?
Rym: So what the hiccup hit your brain?
Scott: Yeah, it did.
Scott: I got punched in the head too many times because I was I was I was pretending to be Anyway, so the thing is you would think for a hand-drawn show there'd be lots of reused animation lots of stock footage, right?
Scott: But really in all those anime episodes, there are only one.
Scott: I can only remember one or two Maybe one only Recap episodes right and even then there isn't a lot of reused footage, right?
Scott: It's like even though he's training again, it's like there's some things that are very quick like a two-second clip.
Scott: You might see them use a whole bunch of times but for the most part it's different training and different animation every time.
Scott: Of course over the course of what's now a total of a hundred something episodes, but 75 of them were hand-done, right?
Scott: So even of course 75 episodes is very little reused stock footage, you know.
Scott: And you know They might not animate though every fight punch for punch the way they do say in cowboy bebop And they'll show you a lot of you know.
Scott: And there's a flurry of blows and it's just sort of a loop of two guys going pump it above it above it above it I. but you know They animate all the important parts of the fight the parts that matter to the to the plot to the story of you know Is trading into the story of how he's actually gonna win.
Scott: and you know, every fight is up and down and up and down.
Scott: So it's you know, you got animations guys, you know passing out falling down Getting up right and the one trick that the manga and the anime both use to extensively especially during the fights is Sort of putting the camera in the worst place when something dramatic happens, right?
Scott: So it's like you'll see some guy from the back obscuring the other boxer and it'll look like they got dude just got uppercutted and it's like oh he's going down right and then There'll be a pause a suspenseful pause.
Scott: maybe the crowd will scream or something like that or someone will yell something and Then after this is with the exact correct timing.
Scott: They'll show you the other angle.
Rym: It's like oh my god, he blocked it.
Rym: Classic two guys guns pointed at each other.
Rym: You hear a gun go off They stand there the winds blowing and then one of them falls over.
Scott: Yeah, the show does it like 10,000 times?
Scott: Yes for episode I mean it works every time.
Rym: I think Scott liked the show a lot since he watched all of it Almost immediately.
Rym: Yeah, I like it.
Rym: Okay, I'm gonna finish it in the next month or so like just watching it.
Scott: Well, I mean it sort of drags you in because the pacing of it is the correct pacing.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's sort of like the same pacing as Hokuto.
Scott: no Ken right where the fights don't last a long time It keeps moving.
Scott: It keeps progressing.
Scott: things that actually matter to the plot are constantly happening.
Scott: It doesn't drag out with a 10 episode fight.
Scott: It doesn't have an island episode where a bunch of stuff happens Meaningless you don't care about.
Scott: every single episode moves things forward and a lot of times they'll do something like they'll end a fight Halfway through an episode and then they'll begin the threat of the next fight in the second half of the episode.
Scott: So now there was no unless you stopped watching in the middle of the episode.
Scott: It wasn't a breaking off point.
Scott: It's always a keep watching the next episode.
Scott: point, you know, there's.
Scott: no it's not like really a cliffhanger.
Scott: so much, you know.
Scott: But it's it's the.
Scott: there's.
Scott: no.
Scott: If you stop at the end of an episode you want to see what happens next all the time if you care, right?
Rym: I mean, it's a solid show and if you're an anime fan You should watch like four or five episodes of this show just to see if you like it.
Rym: Yeah And if you don't like it and you're new to anime watch a ton of other stuff and after you've seen a whole bunch of Anime come back to a show like this.
Rym: watch it again.
Rym: Make sure.
Scott: well, I think the thing is right.
Scott: This show is obviously not for everybody right this, you know There's very.
Scott: there's a certain kind of person who's gonna.
Rym: I mean if boxers killed your mom while you watched when you were a baby.
Rym: Yeah, it might not want to watch.
Scott: Yeah, I mean this, you know, this show will be boring to many people.
Scott: But the thing is if you are going to watch a shounen show a formulaic shounen show You should watch this one before you watch the other ones except maybe fist of the North Star, right?
Scott: It's pretty much this and fist of the North Star and and if you're like us initial D But most people not initially, right?
Scott: But if you're gonna watch shounen fighting shows or shounen sport shows that follow the formula make a hook don't?
Scott: okay?
Scott: And how'd you mean a bow that the top two in terms of well doneness?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows Sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.