Rym: It's Monday June 20th 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight DNS.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, you know, I got the blackberry for work which I hate and really just turn off unless there's like the very few times where I'm on call for something and It just it's a tech.
Rym: I hate blackberries.
Rym: They're like the worst possible smartphone.
Rym: They have all the bad qualities of a corporate phone without any of the good qualities of a smartphone.
Scott: Actually, I think blackberries don't get enough credit because I you know, I mean, I'm not saying they're good or anything.
Rym: Well, though they get credit from me in the same way that Dungeons & Dragons gets credit.
Scott: No What I'm saying is that there's most.
Scott: 99% of people have blackberries have them hooked up to the company's network Yep on a blackberry enterprise server with all this stuff.
Scott: Right, if you actually get a blackberry like the and they don't get the newest fanciest ones either It's usually whichever one the company gives you now.
Rym: We have all the newest fanciest ones.
Rym: I pointedly refused to get the upgrade.
Rym: I still have that asshole blackberry.
Scott: You know, I the battery lasts like two weeks That's true But if you get the newest fanciest possible blackberry and it's not like hooked up to a company and locked down or whatever It's actually got.
Scott: you know, it's it.
Scott: you can do a whole bunch of stuff Yeah, but like here's one thing I've noticed everyone.
Rym: I know who has a blackberry.
Rym: Google latitude either doesn't work or just sucks.
Scott: Well, yeah, cuz he sucks.
Scott: They're not big on the GPS and blackberries is not the hottest Yeah, and the batteries don't last that long and the interface is pretty bad.
Rym: And I just I don't like blackberries.
Rym: I've had to use them for a long for my life.
Scott: I don't understand why it seems like there's a whole bunch of people this uses class like people especially business like top.
Scott: I'll tell you why we're high up.
Scott: I'll tell you why they want it.
Scott: they want a blackberry because it has a keyboard and they want to write long emails on it.
Rym: That's not why they want it.
Rym: They want.
Rym: here's why they say they like the inner.
Scott: Well, that's what they say.
Rym: No, because first of all, you know until recently my blackberry still doesn't have the little a wheel Because a lot of them are not touch screens like most of them aren't?
Rym: it has the slidey wheel like the mouse wheel on the side for your thumb.
Scott: Yep, and What has some of them?
Scott: have the nub on the front?
Rym: Yeah, that's kind of new and a lot of people actually hate that and they want the old blackberry cuz they want the old way.
Rym: Yeah, these people had blackberries back when only rich executives and middle management people had blackberries.
Rym: It was like a status symbol and They learned about like.
Rym: they felt very powerful and very cool using this technology.
Rym: There's like ultra modern.
Rym: I'm connected all the time when most people didn't even have a normal cell phone.
Rym: Now those people are still in business.
Rym: they're like the super senior executives and the CEOs and all those people the upper management and People just never change.
Rym: and because they've been using that interface for so long They're used to it and they still have this misplaced desire Like they feel like it's something worth being accustomed to kind of like the people who like to use the stupid Bloomberg terminal.
Rym: It's like the worst interface in the world, but people feel Accomplished when they learn it especially because it feels like expert knowledge when really it's just obtuse proprietary stupid.
Scott: Now that is an aspect but you know even just today I was on the train from Connecticut and I heard two guys Discussing, you know, I try to Android and I try to iPhone but it just does it I can't.
Scott: I need the real keyboard so I can type real fast and it's like.
Scott: I think these people's problems Right is that they are writing tons and tons of either dude I saw sure or few really long or tons of long emails got on their black.
Rym: I saw a guy on Metro North on multiple occasions back when I used to take the train who had a little Keyboard that he'd like take out of a bag and plug into his blackberry What the fuck.
Rym: and then he'd type like it was a computer.
Scott: Yeah, see these people the it's like they want to write really long emails on their blackberry.
Scott: The solution is don't write long emails on the blackberry Then you won't need a real keyboard and you can just call me short email.
Rym: The solution is laptop.
Rym: Use a laptop.
Scott: It's like I know.
Scott: I even know that Robert coup is one of those people who has the blackberry and writes tons of emails To have the physical.
Rym: I've gotten emails from Robert coup and they're always short blackberry style emails.
Rym: They're always just.
Scott: here's the point is Little punctuation as possible.
Scott: He'll tell you that he absolutely needs the physical keyboard because he you know Writes a lot of emails and needs to write him fast.
Rym: No, I'll say I prefer the physical keyboard.
Scott: I dislike the touchscreen keyboard, but I just like the touchscreen keyboard at first.
Scott: but you get used to it, right?
Scott: I'm like to it.
Scott: It's the same way as like I'm saying I'm used to it.
Rym: But I still given the choice.
Rym: I would take the physical keyboard over the digital keyboard.
Rym: I would not.
Scott: cuz I'll take the extra screen real estate.
Rym: Yeah, I could have both.
Scott: keyboard could be on the back Yeah, but then it's got to be a slider.
Rym: No, I want I really like slider.
Scott: I don't like it cuz then it's fatter.
Rym: Ah My actually my pre is not fatter than most people's droids.
Scott: It's better than iPhone Not by much.
Scott: It is you'd be surprised plus it's so much curve.
Rym: The pre still yeah Less screen.
Scott: the iPhone is all screen.
Rym: It had the same resolution as the previous iPhone.
Scott: Yeah, the retina display kicks everyone's ass.
Scott: That's just too bad.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, no, no, I'm not saying I like my Nexus S. But if I could have the Nexus S yet somehow also have a physical keyboard in it That did not make it heavier or thicker.
Rym: I would do that.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just saying it's a preference.
Rym: all things can being equal.
Scott: I mean, I'll take a physical keyboard, but the problem is the trade-offs necessary for it are more important.
Rym: But anyway, it's the other problems with blackberries So that I think a lot of the people who use them are the kinds of people who want to be connected to their business All the time.
Rym: now.
Rym: some people it's because their business is their passion.
Rym: because we're talking about Robert Coo I mean if I was connected to just works all the time.
Rym: Oh, wait, I am connected to GeekNights all the time.
Rym: Oh with my droid, huh?
Scott: Which doesn't have a keyboard.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but I think these people too.
Rym: I've watched a lot of old people interacting with phones, especially if they get a new more fancy blackberry.
Rym: they seem to Not understand or want to use any of the other features of the phone and they really want it.
Rym: Just turn on and show them all their email whether or not they have an internet connection.
Rym: That's all they care about.
Scott: It's the same problem that you know, these are the same old things.
Scott: We talk about all the time like the Yeah, it's like oh the guy who needs a car, but he says who needs a car?
Scott: I never left this town in my life and then you eventually force him to leave the town and he goes Oh and he realizes the whole world outside the town.
Scott: and now he absolutely Desperately needs a car because the whole world is open to him.
Scott: They didn't know about.
Scott: he was just too stubborn to go look at the world.
Scott: So he didn't know that he wanted it and needed it.
Scott: Never used those other things on their blackberries.
Scott: They never knew they wanted them.
Scott: and yet to force them to use them, you know So that they realize that it's something they want Well, like young nerds I have the opposite problem.
Rym: if they want things that don't exist yet.
Rym: Yeah They just wait until they can afford it.
Rym: I mean nerd.
Rym: when the blackberry first existed every nerd wanted one kind of like how you wanted a fancy palm back when there was palm.
Rym: And then you know, I got a fancy palm.
Rym: IBM gave me one and I realized five seconds in that it was useless.
Scott: Well, that was after fancy palm was no longer.
Rym: That was before cell phones.
Rym: I Did not have a cell phone when I first got my palm.
Scott: That's pretty sad.
Rym: You got a cell phone around that time herself on the year 2000.
Scott: Yeah, you got that palm pilot when you're already in like beacon.
Rym: No, you got.
Rym: you got the phone.
Rym: I remember we were in colony when you got it.
Rym: cuz we took it to that con.
Scott: I had it near 2000 Did you?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So the next year I got a phone.
Rym: yeah, I think it was the only one the crew.
Rym: because remember we went to Otakon and You had the cell phone.
Rym: So we had to like call the one other person in the crew who had the cell phone that he had like a track phone Or something like the old equivalent of a track phone.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, anyway So, uh, I was really going anywhere with that.
Rym: other than that I've got an app on my droid that gives me access through some company to My enterprise blackberry stuff.
Scott: So it's a blackberry enterprise - I map translation server.
Rym: Well, it acts like that in terms of Michael, you know My company trusts it which is a first and a lot of big companies seem to be using this thing.
Rym: But it actually interfaces directly with our exchange server as opposed to with our blackberry enterprise The iPhone.
Scott: you can just go into the settings and enable the Cisco VPN and just connect to your company's network and then go to The exchange server directly.
Rym: Yeah, if they let you do that most companies I've seen won't let anyone even consider that.
Scott: I mean if there's I. they gave me a Cisco VPN client so I could just use the same credentials and they can't stop me.
Scott: And then the iPhone is just a device that used talks to the exchange servers So they can't.
Scott: what can they do about it?
Scott: Yeah, then it to specifically target the iPhone and disable that.
Scott: but even though I don't actually have to do that because they enabled Active sync on the exchange server, which means I can just go to it directly from the phone and it does the pushing.
Rym: Yeah, so I just have I now draw it.
Rym: I have the full integration with exchange and it's pretty great for what it is.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I use the same exact, you know, people might not know this but Gmail has a feature Gmail sync.
Scott: We're basically Google licensed the exchange server active sync technology from Microsoft.
Scott: They pay Microsoft money for this.
Scott: so Google has what appears to be exchange servers, right?
Scott: They look like exchange servers as far as your phone is concerned, but really it's Gmail on the other side.
Scott: So you tell your phone or whatever it is that you know connect to this exchange server at mail google.com And you get your Gmail pushed to you, you know automatically on your blackberry or whatever.
Scott: it is Gmail but it works like exchange as far as the phone knows.
Scott: And you know, that's that's always.
Scott: that's the way I go.
Rym: Yeah, so my blackberry is now off in the corner and I just give it back.
Scott: It also does you know calendars and all those other things.
Scott: to contacts.
Rym: Yep I get all that the contacts didn't sync yet, but doesn't really matter.
Scott: I don't think the company contacts because I don't know I use the personal contacts But I do.
Scott: I can sync the company calendar and the personal Google calendar together in the same iPhone calendar.
Rym: I want to keep mine very separate, but it's the same UI.
Scott: so it's like It's it's there.
Scott: It's still separate calendars.
Rym: Yeah, this thing has its own.
Scott: one of the calendars is on the company's exchange server And one of the calendars is on Gmail But they're both in the same calendar app on.
Rym: this thing exists as its own standalone app.
Rym: So inside of that is like all work and then I close it and no work.
Scott: I'll see I click on.
Scott: you know, there's the email app but in the email app each email account is separate.
Scott: So the emails aren't like shuffled together anything like that now the free they would have been but yeah.
Rym: So I do briefly want to talk about.
Rym: we're not gonna do a show on it or anything.
Rym: But well sec has been the rising star of the internet lately.
Rym: I guess so and I'm curious what's really going on because I mean look at what we had for a long time.
Rym: Remember the era of script keys when suddenly like every I don't know IIS server in the world was hacked by script kiddies Just like every day.
Rym: Yep, and then things kind of calm down for a while and we've had this long era of Relative peace on the internet.
Scott: wasn't relative peace.
Scott: I think that it was just the peace there were.
Scott: the war was not highly visible right and a lot of the people who formerly were writing viruses moved to things like spyware and the Motivations became you know switched from making mischief or hurting people or whatever to it or being cool and hacking To making money.
Rym: Oh, but simultaneously there was I think a lack of When there was low-hanging fruit like oh dude got that guy's running is three.
Rym: here I go Versus oh, it's Apache.
Rym: I'm not gonna even bother.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know part of it was you know, a lot of those low-hanging fruits disappeared.
Rym: Yeah, but I think what's happened now is that it's not that lulz like is going after the low-hanging fruit.
Rym: It's that because people have been into this relative peace for a while at least this perception of perception of peace That it's all low-hanging fruit.
Scott: I mean, there's lots of low-hanging fruit because what you know Because of various technologies that make it, you know easier and easier for non-professionals to create software and set up.
Rym: So not even that wasn't it city?
Rym: I think was the one where they hacked all the accounts just by logging into one account and then changing the string in the URL.
Rym: Yeah, I mean that it's because they're already on the ground.
Rym: That's not even low-hanging.
Rym: That's like rotten on the ground being carried away by a squirrel.
Scott: But this is what I'm talking about.
Scott: is that there aren't enough You know Highly skilled and highly knowledgeable technology people in the world and there's a lot of people who are like, you know I just want to get a website up and I'm like Do you realize how many things you have to know to get the website at?
Scott: you know to put a website up?
Scott: That's actually you know, right?
Scott: It's it's this you have to know this vast amount of knowledge.
Scott: and the thing is some guy puts up some HTMLs or does the Ruby on Rails tutorial and put something up and it feels all accomplished.
Scott: But really he's basically set up a rickety shack.
Scott: He just thinks it's a mansion You know.
Scott: to actually build a house that will stand up and not a house of cards is like this ludicrously difficult thing that not enough people can do.
Scott: but This is not a high enough number of people who can do it properly as the demand is for people who can do it and the Result is there's a whole lot of rickety shacks.
Rym: But it is kind of amazing though that there it's not like.
Rym: alright This is a pretty well done system that has a few fatal flaws.
Rym: Like someone was careless.
Rym: It's like I don't even know how to describe it.
Rym: It's like they don't even try.
Rym: it's like there's no one who even has ever heard of security.
Scott: It's also because the people who are the experts technologically.
Scott: we've discussed this many times, right?
Scott: companies tend to either have all smart tech people or all stupid tech people because if you have a stupid person the smart people won't Hire them and if you have stupid people in charge, they'll hire stupid people.
Scott: But if any smart person gets hired there They'll bail and try to go work where smart people work and as a result You've got like Facebook with thousands and thousands of really smart tech people or Google with thousands of smart tech people and they're all You know teamed up.
Scott: It was one I was waiting for you to say a name of someone that has all stupid people All of the other ones all of them You know, you basically have the smart tech people teaming up on these huge teams at very specific places like Google.
Scott: You know who's?
Scott: none of these attacks have been on Google right or Microsoft or anything like that.
Rym: Well, I mean look at who.
Rym: Google.
Rym: Google got compromised by the Chinese government.
Scott: Yeah, and barely so.
Scott: but I mean Lulsec.
Rym: I'm not sure what it really is because you know, there was that that anonymous like hey Let's fuck shit up video a little while ago.
Rym: And yeah, I don't know Lulsec's a little too high-profile and I'm gonna put on my conspiracy hat.
Rym: We get the tinfoil.
Rym: it is possible that Lulsec is a false flag operation to get all the script kiddies and all the people who self-identify as being these kinds of hackers To basically out themselves by attacking low-hanging honeypots.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know it's possible But it is possible but a lot of things are possible.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time the reason I don't hold to that is that there is that much low-hanging fruit.
Rym: You know engineers always say, you know when there's a terrorist attack engineers aren't evil, but they always have the twinge.
Rym: They think wow, I could have done that way better.
Scott: or yeah, they're lucky I'm not evil, but I think what Lulsec demonstrates is that even though you know They're getting low-hanging fruit like SQL injections or DD OS's or whatever.
Rym: Well hanging fruit works on almost everyone.
Scott: Right is that?
Scott: you know?
Scott: is that even though their skill level isn't you know, isn't very high?
Scott: It's that if you even just use a modicum of security modern technologies like you use real encryption You know that doesn't suck and you put some proxies between you and your IRC server.
Scott: You can just chat about your hacks on a perfectly like public IRC and no one will ever catch you.
Scott: You know, yeah, it's like all the pedophiles do the same thing.
Rym: There's just you know, I mean look at the converse of this.
Rym: So the government.
Rym: obviously there are organizations that would like to arrest the people involved in all this internet.
Scott: You know shenanigans and they can't find them even though they're doing just simple basic stuff.
Rym: Occasionally they get one or two of these people and you know who they're getting the low-hanging fruit.
Scott: Yeah Nobody if anyone actually does any you know uses any serious technology.
Scott: you think you can't.
Scott: no one can get you.
Scott: It's so encrypted.
Scott: It's unbreakable and that's just available for free open source Which is behind seven proxies.
Scott: and this is why you know, this is why the government is, you know I guess governments around the world are really afraid of just if everyone used open source software, right?
Scott: Like imagine if everyone abandoned Apple and Windows and everyone just started using Linux tomorrow and everyone, you know.
Scott: But GPG on their email game over.
Scott: It's like everyone in the world is so secure that it's impossible to get any information from anyone unless they want to give it To you, you know all the days of like, oh my god, my Facebook's was hacked.
Scott: Oh my god Someone stole my ex by.
Rym: this is why I'm kind of enjoying low sex modus operandi because I saw what I'm following their Twitter now just to see what they're up to.
Rym: but Notice how they're very pointedly.
Scott: you can have a Twitter account and not be caught.
Rym: Notice how they're going very pointedly After very easy targets and they're trying to get them in the least sophisticated way possible because that brings way more public shame.
Rym: I mean if you get someone they said something like you get someone with a really complicated hack.
Rym: I mean, what's the news gonna say?
Rym: Super elite hackers got this company as opposed to this company was so egregiously insecure that it was ridiculous.
Scott: But on the other hand, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, what if you walk down the street and there's two different buildings, right?
Scott: One of them is the museum and some of the fine arts and the other one is an old lady's house?
Scott: Yeah, if you robbed the old lady's house, it's like yeah, good job, dude Yeah, whatever.
Rym: But if you robbed the museum, you're a total badass, ah, but they're not trying to be badasses They're trying to just shame people.
Scott: imagine, right?
Scott: But at the same time they're shaming themselves because it's like, you know, obviously they're shaming people because it's like oh look You didn't even lock your door, but it's like okay, dude.
Scott: Wow, you're so great.
Scott: You busted into a house that unlock door.
Scott: Ah, but at the same time You're awesome, dude.
Rym: This is a situation where there's an entire city and Everyone in that city.
Rym: They've never heard of doors.
Rym: Yeah, so these guys just walk into the city and take everything Yeah, and then they walk out and they're like you mad it still does.
Scott: Yeah, it's you know, it's funny in that way but it's still.
Rym: My position here is that I'm curious as to whether or not the people involved in this have the ability to do the big hack.
Scott: I doubt it.
Scott: I don't know I don't think I think that anyone with the ability to do the big hack all those people who have had or have that ability currently Do not are not going.
Scott: they could make more money and more with in a safer fashion.
Scott: So they don't do that for now.
Scott: Of the world who used to do the big hack don't do it any now, but what if you know?
Rym: The government pisses them off enough.
Scott: the other thing is I don't think the big hack is possible because The people who are the targets of the big hack they use those very same encryption technologies.
Rym: this in perspective I mean, what does it mean to do the big hack?
Rym: I mean, I think Considering how insecure I mean a lot of these targets are like banks and things.
Scott: Yeah, but when for example the Citibank hack they put in you know user IDs and they were able to see how much money people Had.
Scott: they couldn't actually spend or transfer any money.
Rym: So Scott to the average American that sort of.
Rym: it's not just that They can see they can manipulate too and also you're getting the passwords.
Rym: They you can.
Rym: if you find someone's password on say Facebook You probably have their password to everything else.
Rym: They've got probably and then you can start stealing their money.
Scott: So you you got some random guy on Facebook.
Scott: good job.
Rym: That's not a big hack Yeah, but if you get everybody on Facebook that causes chaos to a degree that is unsettling.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, but notice nobody's hacked Facebook cuz Facebook has smart people.
Rym: Yeah, but Facebook is now vulnerable to.
Rym: if you have a Facebook account and you have an account anywhere else The majority of people use the same password everywhere, right?
Rym: But it's one of those places but it doesn't.
Scott: that doesn't count.
Scott: that's that's like.
Scott: you didn't actually hack Facebook.
Scott: You just have to hack.
Scott: the target wasn't Facebook?
Scott: target was that guy?
Rym: if you're a con man, right?
Rym: If you get the million dollars, it's the big score doesn't matter.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: It doesn't it's not the same.
Scott: Let's say I find a thousand morons and I take advantage of those morons and you get a million dollars.
Scott: Yeah, it's like yeah, but it doesn't matter how much I get.
Scott: the point is all I did was the the thing that was What's it called.
Rym: I can't think of this word right now, well, I guess in that case you were separate.
Rym: There's two separate things.
Rym: There's one There's the pragmatic reality of how much damage and or theft happens as a result of their action.
Rym: You could use that as the scale is what the big hack is.
Rym: or I thinking you're more from the Lupin The sting style.
Rym: if you're gonna pull off a heist, it doesn't matter how much you get.
Rym: What matters is how awesome and elaborate it is.
Scott: Well, it's not about how elaborate it is.
Scott: It's that you know, okay You know you all you did.
Scott: you didn't actually hack Facebook, right?
Scott: You can't do that.
Scott: You don't need to write.
Scott: you hacked a bunch of morons who happen to have Facebook.
Scott: It's got the more and everyone else with the Facebook account is totally say it's got the morons of the majority.
Rym: I'm pretty sure if you got you know If you hacked enough sites out there like even slashdot and things you could probably compromise a majority of the Facebook account.
Scott: Yeah, but you didn't actually compromise Facebook.
Scott: Facebook is still solid.
Rym: Well, they're solid except for the fact that everyone's account Just got wiped right.
Scott: So so here I got it.
Scott: I got a way to explain this you ready?
Scott: So I stand outside of a bank branch.
Scott: Yeah, right and everyone who walks out of the bank branch I mug them and take the money.
Rym: They just took out of the ATM and you get away with this come every day.
Scott: Yes, then I but the bank is still totally secure.
Scott: Yeah, but it doesn't matter that you got your money, but the bank is just like Bank doesn't give a shit Yeah, but the customers do so.
Rym: you effectively robbed you.
Scott: In fact, I didn't.
Scott: I compromised the customers not the bank.
Rym: I didn't say you compromised the bank, which is basically it's stupid.
Rym: I said the effect is the same.
Rym: you got your money and an equivalent amount of money was stolen from people.
Scott: Yeah from people but not from the bank.
Rym: Uh, if I steal it from the bank, I can't.
Rym: I would effectively be stealing it from the people but for the FDIC Yeah, you can't.
Scott: the point is is you can't steal it from the bank.
Scott: is who cares?
Scott: I care why?
Scott: cuz that's not the big hack.
Scott: So we were just discussing whether anyone will pull off the big hack.
Scott: Little hacks is not the big house Scott.
Rym: I think we disagree on what the big hack is because for me the big hack just means something that affects So many people so significantly that no one know that's a million little hacks.
Scott: the way you're talking about It's not the big head.
Scott: I would consider that the big It doesn't matter the effect it's still it's.
Scott: those are a million little hacks.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what the effects the same It doesn't matter.
Scott: it's not the bit no It's not.
Scott: actually if you stole from the bank directly the effect would be completely different.
Scott: that if you stole from all those people Individually, uh, I argue now actually yeah would because think about what the bank would have to do.
Scott: Scott banks How about how the money would move versus Scott?
Scott: What insurances would pay out?
Rym: There's a lot Scott banks out.
Rym: Yeah, but in the end the same amount of economic damage is done.
Rym: not necessarily Yeah, plus banks have problems like that all the time.
Rym: They just keep it on the down low.
Scott: That's another thing is that you know who knows the big hack has probably happened a bunch of times and we just don't know.
Rym: That's I would.
Rym: then I wouldn't consider it the big hack.
Rym: It only.
Rym: it's only the big hack if it affects enough people to where everybody knows what happened and everybody's affected by it.
Scott: No, cuz there are big hacks that are really big that you know, you just don't know Cuz who gives a shit?
Rym: Oh, thank you But you don't know they affect if a fancy cat burglar steals a fancy diamond that isn't the hope diamond and no one's heard of it.
Rym: who gives a shit except the people who own the diamond?
Scott: a Lot of people.
Scott: it's not makes a really good story.
Rym: Yeah, but no one knows about that diamond.
Scott: No one cares It's not the back but sometimes there is the big hack and it might affect you But you don't know that it was the big hack that caused that effect right?
Scott: For example, I'm not saying this is true I know it's not but you know the big stock market dip What if that?
Scott: what if that was a big hack?
Scott: But you don't know is a big hack because they come up with some other story, right?
Scott: So it did have this humongous effect, you know, but I'm not saying that one.
Scott: But it's just an example of something that could have been the big hack and kept on the down low Right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, then it's the big hack and Lupin succeeded.
Scott: it affected everybody but nobody knew That it was the big hat.
Rym: Well because in every heist movie ever enough people know.
Scott: Only the people you see on the screen know.
Scott: but though, you know, the whole world doesn't know.
Rym: look at the sting.
Scott: There's like 200 people who know yeah, that's it But it's not the big, you know, the big hack you actually have to hit the bank directly.
Scott: You can't just hit the people walking out of the back.
Rym: I think if I compromised 80% of Facebook's accounts by individually attacking all the users simultaneously I think that counts as the big doesn't count.
Rym: Anyway, you got a little yes.
Scott: Yeah, I do have some news So people might not be paying too much attention, you know to.
Scott: you know A lot of these goings-on and you know various minutiae of the open source communities.
Scott: But basically there used to be a thing called star office which then became open office.
Scott: Right, and then, you know Oracle bought Sun and things got weird, right?
Rym: Meanwhile, I've switched to using office because it is just better.
Scott: Well, you have to pay for that.
Scott: Yeah, I use Google Docs I use I use Microsoft Office when I can get a copy of it, but I refuse to pay.
Rym: I have a copy on my work laptop.
Scott: I have a copy on my work laptop and I you know But I don't.
Scott: I'm not gonna pay for one.
Rym: and I when I if I ever get to a point where I don't have access To Microsoft Office on any PC I use on a regular basis.
Rym: I think I would buy it.
Scott: I would need it.
Scott: If I had a ton of money lying around I would buy it that expensive.
Scott: It's hundreds of dollars.
Scott: Oh, no, it's a lot of money something that I use currently recording GeekNights in Adobe Audition.
Scott: I also would not pay for yeah, and then we would be doing GeekNights We could have used.
Scott: we didn't use audition for a very long.
Rym: Yeah, we used audacity and it kind of sounded like shit and I had to run everything through that hack audition Resound.
Scott: if we had zero dollars, he would have continued that way with no problems.
Rym: Actually, I can't get resound to work on modern computers.
Scott: I'm just saying we could have continued without acid or whatever.
Rym: I probably would have given up.
Scott: It was too much for you to give it up on GeekNights completely without spending.
Scott: it was about your money.
Rym: It was way too much of a pain in the ass.
Scott: You did it for years.
Scott: Anyway, yeah And you say that now but you know what if you hadn't if you had no money We would be doing GeekNights right now with audacity.
Scott: Maybe not guaranteed anyway.
Scott: Yeah, okay anyway Alright, so there was a lot of hubbub because you know Oracle was abandoning a lot of the projects Or they were you know converting a lot of them to be more closed or whatever.
Rym: We're suing Google for billions of dollars.
Scott: Yeah, what's a bunch of bullshit, right?
Scott: So So open office is sort of in shaky territory, right?
Scott: But open office was you know Very much needed by a bunch of people where Google Docs wasn't enough for them and they didn't want to pay for Microsoft Office.
Scott: Open office is actually really popular.
Scott: It was also like a default installed thing in many Linux distributions.
Scott: So it was shaky.
Scott: and what eventually happened was they forked it and they made LibreOffice and it's like, alright.
Scott: So the Free Software Foundation and other open source groups are like, yeah LibreOffice.
Scott: That's the real deal.
Scott: I think Ubuntu now has LibreOffice instead of OpenOffice as the default.
Scott: So LibreOffice came out and it's like, okay.
Scott: Well now there's two.
Scott: this is great and OpenOffice was then.
Scott: basically Oracle gave up and they gave OpenOffice to the Apache Software Foundation.
Scott: now Apache has OpenOffice and Free Software Foundation has LibreOffice, but LibreOffice has made some big moves that people may not realize.
Scott: Number one, Google sort of threw their weight behind LibreOffice, right?
Scott: Giving like a thumbs up.
Scott: So that helps that a lot.
Scott: Two, LibreOffice just had some releases and Basically they went through the OpenOffice code and removed a whole bunch of bullshit.
Scott: Like OpenOffice is sort of notorious for being big and slow LibreOffice has cleaned it up a whole bunch and made it way smaller and not necessarily faster.
Scott: But the download size is a whole bunch less and they've got ways to make it even smaller.
Scott: They're just keep working on it.
Scott: So they're improving Technologically a whole bunch on OpenOffice and it's pretty much at the point now where you don't want to use OpenOffice.
Scott: You want to use LibreOffice Starting, you know today, so and there's actually two versions of it.
Scott: there's the the stable version which they say is like use this if you're you know need stability like in an enterprise or your company and The sort of yellow beta.
Scott: ish, you know use this.
Scott: it has more of the work, you know fancy work We've done but isn't as tested version which you can use in your home computer.
Scott: Probably just fine.
Scott: It'll actually probably a little bit faster and smaller.
Rym: Yeah, then the Are you anytime I'm doing anything substantial.
Rym: I'm writing more than a few paragraphs.
Rym: I use Microsoft Office.
Scott: I don't have Microsoft Office.
Scott: I use Google Docs.
Rym: Yeah for everything else.
Rym: I use Google Docs.
Scott: The reason the only reason I have LibreOffice at all right for the you know Cuz when am I gonna use it?
Scott: is like if I download an XLS file on a computer?
Scott: For or something like that and I don't have Microsoft Office Google Docs, but huge limitations on it And it sucks balls.
Scott: if Google Docs ever gets to the point where it's like has parity with Excel Then I probably won't need to install Libre.
Rym: my trouble is Google Docs typing is okay Yeah, but the spreadsheet just really does not do what I.
Scott: there's also a couple times you get a PPT file And I don't have Microsoft Office on that computer because those I just import into Google, but they don't always come out exactly.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like sometimes you just want to double-click it and open it.
Scott: Maybe I'm not online you know.
Scott: so it's.
Scott: I don't use it like heavily But it's you gotta have it on that computer.
Scott: cuz that one or two times you're gonna need it.
Scott: You're gonna be like fuck.
Rym: actually on my laptop I use Abby word just because yeah every word works if you want to do word processing.
Scott: But I actually do pretty much everything in VIM Yeah, or the WordPress editor or Google Docs or what you know whatever.
Rym: so I got one more a little bit.
Rym: So Sarah Palin we're gonna skip all the politics not going to express any opinion on her Or anything related to that, but there was a Freedom of Information Act request to get all of her official emails years ago.
Rym: It took over a thousand days for this to be complied with and the state.
Scott: I don't know why.
Scott: how could it take a thousand days?
Rym: So the state of Alaska when people first put these queries in said that it would cost almost 15 million dollars for them to provide the email.
Rym: Really that is how much it would cost them to get it all together.
Scott: and whoever said that?
Scott: who said that was stupid because it Would take about five minutes and zero dollars?
Rym: not so in the end.
Rym: Here's what happened.
Rym: They eventually came down and agreed that it would cost seven hundred and twenty five dollars and ninety seven cents plus shipping To get the archive.
Scott: that well plus shipping.
Scott: how?
Scott: what do you mean plus shipping?
Scott: Sending you a hard drive.
Rym: They're sending you 250 pounds of printed out fucking email.
Scott: Oh, you know why?
Scott: because it's an FOIA request and those always get you just get paper.
Scott: I've done those before.
Scott: you know why?
Rym: no here's what bothers me.
Rym: They actually from what I can gather had to dump them into a digital form first turn them into PDFs and then print them.
Rym: Yeah, and yet they would not give anyone the digital copies.
Scott: I think the FOIA actually law requires paper to be sent which one is right.
Scott: well No, because think about this right what if I'm a person?
Scott: I'm an old lady I don't have a computer or anything and I may I say I send in a paper Request.
Rym: paper should be available as an option.
Rym: I feel like the only reason they don't offer digital because it would save everybody money.
Rym: It would save them money.
Rym: It would save the people requesting money if they only gave you paper if you asked for it.
Rym: Yeah I think the reason they don't change anything and the reason they give the stuff on paper is Because it makes it a pain in the ass to actually request anything.
Scott: No, because they were doing it on paper before there was even digital.
Rym: Yes, and now that they can do digital they pointedly do not do digital and no one is trying to change this.
Scott: It's not it's just.
Scott: that's just what the law is.
Scott: That's what the law says.
Rym: I'm pretty sure I don't know if that's it or not.
Rym: And the thing is alright, they provide the paper.
Scott: They're just following the law.
Rym: They could also provide the digital at no cost to anyone.
Rym: yet They choose not to.
Scott: I think the law.
Rym: I think the law says they just send a real copy and I think you would need to change the FOIA Lawyer, I'm saying obviously I'm pretty sure regardless of what the law says There is no prohibition from giving the digital version as well.
Scott: No But no what government worker is gonna do something that is not required by law?
Scott: I think they're gonna go the extra mile to do something extra that the law doesn't say they have to do.
Scott: that's never gonna.
Scott: Well everything
Rym: I've read about this story and other freedom of information requests in the last decade or so seems to indicate that Recently like in the last few years people have been flooding this office to a degree that they've never been prepared to handle and A lot of people suggest I'm starting to agree with this that they want to keep it paper Because that just slows down the flow of information out Heavily and the only
Scott: yeah, but I'm that that may be true now, but the point that wasn't the original intent.
Scott: I didn't say it was.
Scott: I didn't even imply that.
Rym: so instead they shipped Twenty four thousand one hundred ninety nine pages of emails.
Rym: and Coolly enough the Sunlight Foundation Which basically exists to shed light on fraud and government and be open about government.
Rym: I should join them set up a huge thing and scan them all in and put them all online in a digital format almost Immediately.
Scott: there you go.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: Whatever they are guys send us some money.
Scott: Sunlight Foundation Sunlight Foundation.
Scott: Let me go give them a donation.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: have you ever heard of a ganbach?
Rym: Fuck no, it's alright stupid.
Rym: I hate pronunciation things because Wikipedia is like a ganbach Which is G O with two dots over at MBO with two dots over at C pronounced ganbachs in Hungarian, but it's O's with lines through them and a note before the G.
Scott: Let's just call it Ganbach in English.
Rym: Okay is a complex three-dimensional homogeneous body and It has an orientation.
Scott: So it's a shape.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It's a shape with an orientation.
Rym: Okay, no matter how you set it down No matter what amount of force you set it down with on a flat surface.
Rym: It will always have the same orient.
Scott: Yeah, I know I've seen those before.
Scott: I just didn't know that that was what that was a very particular and specific shape.
Rym: now Many things that look like they're ganbachs are not there are.
Scott: but the thing is there are more than one ganbach.
Scott: There's bunches of them.
Scott: It's not like there's only one ganbach.
Scott: There's quite a few.
Rym: Well, it says specifically here that there is one particular shape and there are other things that are like this shape.
Rym: There's a whole bunch of math.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: So a ganbach is one of those things that always writes itself because I've seen like two or three of them.
Rym: Okay There's one particular design that most are manufactured as because they're very difficult to manufacture Mmm, well, I mean, I'm sure it's very difficult to make a perfect one, right?
Scott: But if you go to like science museum gift shops, you'll find quite a few.
Rym: Apparently the cheapest one anyone can find online is like 170 pounds.
Rym: Well, it's to buy.
Scott: I've seen like, you know little gimmicky plastic things.
Rym: Let me finish most things.
Rym: you see that purport to be ganbachs are actually weighted Part of its heavier than another part to make it work.
Rym: a real one does not equally dense uniformly dense Yet, it still always writes itself.
Scott: I have seen those also, but I did okay.
Rym: But now apparently turtles have shapes that resemble ganbachs and that's why it's easy for them to flip themselves back over.
Rym: Yep, there are two pictures of turtles in this Wikipedia article.
Rym: I just learned about ganbachs like 20 minutes ago So I thought I'd share this with you.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: They're an infinite number of ganbachs theoretically Yeah, but there's one particular one that appears to be the one that is made for people to buy For a hundred dollars hundred and sixty nine euro.
Scott: I suggest getting the weighted plastic thing from the museum gift shop and It's good enough.
Rym: quote.
Rym: They may look like they were knocked together in a toy shop But the different angles and proportions have to be measured to within ten microns.
Scott: Yeah, you can get one that's a little less than ten microns and it'll work ninety nine percent of the time Really?
Scott: It'll be really fun when you get it in one of those positions where it doesn't work.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, so here's a video.
Scott: I thought I did a thing of the day with this already, but I guess it didn't.
Scott: It's a video called three-way street and basically Let me read the little description here on Vimeo.
Scott: By summer 2010 the expansion of bike lanes in New York City opposed a clash of long-standing bad habits such as pedestrians jaywalking Cyclists running red lights and motorists plowing through crosswalks by focusing on one intersection.
Scott: as a case study My video aims to show our interconnection and shared role in improving the safety and usability of our streets.
Scott: The video is part of a longer campaign called three-way street.
Scott: So in this video, basically, he picks one intersection in New York City and he shows you over the course of a day All the different times that basically bad news happened, right?
Scott: Most of it is cyclists who just completely ignore all traffic laws completely except ours are pretty bad, too Though the cars are pretty bad and the pedestrians are also pretty bad.
Scott: It's basically pretty bad on everybody.
Scott: So you've got like a guy one guy's jaywalking and there's a car that went right into the crosswalk And as a cyclist going the wrong way down the road all at the same time and the cyclist goes right in between the pedestrian Jaywalking and the car creeping in there, right and you know, it's basically constantly like this.
Scott: I bike to work almost every day when it doesn't rain and I can And this is exactly what it's like.
Scott: if you watch this video You pretty much get a perfect sense of what it's like to bike to need to work in the New York City Except for when you're on the bridge then it's just straight.
Rym: It seems to just come down to the fact that the majority people who are on bikes in the city are gigantic douche nozzles and Cars even you know, basically are forced to be douche nozzles by the other cars, right?
Scott: like if you're in a car and you never turn on red and stop before the Intersection and never block never go across and when you're attempting you'll
Rym: get to 42nd Street unless in Lexington have and never progress beyond that And you
Scott: get you'll get honked at if you don't say go out and block the box or do other illegal things, right?
Scott: Or There's all sorts of stuff.
Rym: Hey, I used to work in the Bronx.
Scott: I at one point or like if you don't double park, you'll just never park.
Rym: I at one point drove on the sidewalk.
Scott: Yep I've seen that happen
Rym: and I did it because everyone else was doing it and it was the only way to get to the entrance ramp To the freeway that I was trying to get on to basically
Scott: if everyone followed all the rules all the time You would have almost permanent gridlock, but at the same time when people don't follow the rules, right?
Scott: It's like we've gone, you know, there's like a balance right?
Rym: Well, there's two sets of rules.
Rym: There's a new there's a real set of rules.
Rym: Then there's the laws.
Rym: for example jaywalking in my opinion is 100% Okay, you should be able to jaywalk anytime you want.
Scott: Yeah There's lots.
Scott: there's no point in just standing there when there's a completely empty road and not cross.
Rym: but if you enter the street when you Do not have the right away and you're entering the street Causes anyone else to have to alter their path.
Rym: you are sir are a douche nozzle.
Scott: Yep I don't know.
Scott: I like the term douche as opposed to the douche bag.
Rym: douche nozzle because a douche bag all the douche is like in them.
Rym: like they're a bag of douche and if you interact with The nozzle is where the douche comes out.
Rym: Yeah But the douche bag if you interact with them you might get douche on you But the douche is mostly they're a douche.
Rym: you can avoid them.
Rym: the douche nozzles are spraying their douche all over everyone else.
Scott: But yeah watch this video and you'll get an idea of what it's like, you know.
Scott: So there's thousands of intersections in the city.
Scott: most of the outer boroughs ones are not all as bad as this but many of them Are this.
Scott: there's a few thousand intersections that are this bad?
Scott: Almost all the time and at night, you know and on weekends It's a little easier but tourists make it a little bit worse.
Scott: and you know, it varies.
Rym: obviously This is very similar to I didn't use it to think of the day But there's this video someone sent me of and I think it was on College Humor later the guy Who got a ticket for not riding in the bike lane, which wasn't.
Rym: this is not illegal Yeah, not even a law.
Rym: but so to protest this because he was out of the bike lane because it was blocked He rode around the bike lane ramming into anything that was in the bike lane people cars Trash bins any.
Scott: I think really what we need to do is there are certain violations, right?
Scott: That could be ticketed with almost 100% enforcement, right?
Scott: But they're not pretty much ever enforced You know, at least very rarely enforced.
Scott: and I think if we enforce them and the penalties were severe, right?
Rym: I'm talking about like thousands of players a good example outside of my building right is the approach to the Queen Queensboro Bridge.
Rym: Yeah, and occasionally as in every goddamn day, there are cops directing traffic because the traffic lights are not time.
Rym: very well Yeah.
Rym: So occasionally the cops will stop traffic on the approach to the bridge to let other people go by While the light is green which causes everyone Waiting to honk their horns, even though honking your horn is illegal on that Street.
Scott: Yeah, they could have one more cop right.
Rym: basically just write $350 tickets to 100 people every 10 minutes.
Scott: He could just stand amongst the cars and anyone who honks just slap a ticket on the window.
Scott: I think part of the problem is that to write a ticket is actually it's kind of weird, right?
Scott: If a cop has to write a ticket He has to get your license and registration and your insurance card and talk to you and waste a bunch of time.
Scott: Right, but but they have in many places and they're totally legal.
Rym: they have Red light cameras, but those are starting to be torn down or because they're not economical.
Rym: Also because some places where there's referendums able to be passed though.
Scott: They got rid of them.
Rym: There have been referendums to get rid of them even right towns.
Scott: one, but I'm saying is that they weren't.
Scott: they are legal So it is possible.
Scott: an easy pass lane can give you a ticket for running a toll just with the camera.
Rym: Simultaneously there is that technology.
Rym: this was from like two decades ago, but I remember seeing a cool demonstration of it.
Rym: It was a sniper finder where you set up this system And if a gunshot goes off three spotlights immediately aim it where the gunshot came from.
Scott: I think what we need is a balance between those two things.
Scott: give cops a special camera where they take a picture of a car and they get the license plate in the picture and then a menu comes up and they Enter the violation and then the ticket is mailed.
Scott: So a cop could stand amongst the parked.
Scott: you know the cars that are honking their horns.
Scott: take a picture of the cars that honk with this camera and then Touch the button.
Scott: This is honk the horn.
Scott: We could just have a camera a camera that just takes pictures of honking cars But that would run into the same problems as the red light camera.
Scott: That's why I'm saying we had need to balance.
Rym: I except imagine except it's almost all cabbies who are honking and The people who live in the area who would actually get to vote or interact with our government.
Rym: No, cuz all the cabbies don't live right here.
Rym: they get their cabs fixed right here.
Rym: they don't live here.
Rym: They live slightly further.
Scott: But imagine it for example Let's say there's a street and everyone's double parked in the whole street.
Scott: The cop is too lazy to walk down the street riding a ticket for every frickin car.
Scott: But imagine if you could just go Manhattan.
Rym: they do sometimes.
Scott: but imagine if a cop all I had to do was go picture picture picture picture.
Rym: There's a line of delivery trucks parked on 41st Street every day.
Rym: Every one of them every day gets a new ticket.
Rym: one of them has like a hundred tickets on it.
Rym: Nice And I don't think anyone ever pays those tickets.
Scott: Well, that's another thing.
Scott: right is that they should make the penalties much more severe, right?
Scott: And I mean there's something to be said for punishment fitting the crime.
Scott: You don't want to be like double parked death.
Scott: That would be bad obviously or jail.
Scott: that would also be bad right.
Rym: death would really only be for say if you're riding a fixie Without breaks right but it's like they do give you know, some pretty high fines.
Scott: It's like passing a school bus on the wrong side when the stoplight is out is like 350 450 dollars Which is pretty big but it's not so big that it you know is like devastating, right?
Scott: So people still kind of do it and the enforcement rate isn't so high so people still kind of do it.
Scott: What if Almost every time you double park like 99% of the time you got a ticket and the ticket was $2,000 you would see double parking fucking disappear real quick because pretty much everyone would make the mistake once and $2,000 later they would stop.
Rym: Ah, but thus the secondary problem.
Scott: people double park because there just isn't enough parking I know and it would just be tough shit.
Scott: Don't park Yeah, that's trouble.
Rym: when there's more people who live in an area with cars, you know You know who would love this?
Scott: me people who own parking garages Yeah, and I the thing is parking garages don't charge nearly enough as much as they should.
Scott: parking garages charge way more.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: I mean the economics of it works out well right now.
Scott: Yeah, but that's only because a lot of the places where there are parking garages I figured that I learned this the reason that there's often a parking garage on a spot is because Something about the land in that spot made it so that you couldn't build anything else there.
Scott: So Like people wanted to build a building but they couldn't parking garage is the only thing that you're allowed to build there.
Scott: So they did.
Rym: So anyway, very briefly in the meta moment Connecticut is coming up.
Rym: You should check that out.
Rym: if you're anywhere near Connecticut We're gonna be at the penny arcade Expo.
Rym: we might be at PAX dev.
Rym: the book club book is Isaac Abazov's foundation.
Rym: The unofficial book club book is all of the Prince of Nothing books by our Scott backer and that's about it.
Rym: Yep, nothing big coming on other than that.
Rym: It's summer and Radio free Equestria will move to a Wednesday upload schedule instead of a Sunday upload schedule Because I realized that if I put it up Sunday night people can't watch it at work on Monday And I actually got a lot of complaints about that.
Scott: This weekend Saturday and Sunday is game hack day in New York City.
Scott: I think it's a General Assembly.
Scott: if you go just search Google for game hack day You can come on Saturday.
Scott: If you actually want to make a game you can help me Join my team.
Scott: Yeah, it's game hack day org.
Scott: You have to register but it doesn't cost anything.
Scott: You can also register just to come on Sunday, which is where you only See the demos right.
Scott: so the schedule is like doors open.
Scott: hacking begins 10 a.m.. On Saturday 8 p.m As a party you hack overnight you still hack overnight, and then at noon on Sunday you register to show your demo Although red demo registration closes, and then at 2 o'clock on Sunday We start showing demos.
Scott: if you just want to see the demos of things people hacked you can come at 2 on Sunday.
Scott: But if you want to work on a game, it's from 9 a.m.. Saturday to 2 p.m.. Sunday, so It's sure to be a fun time sure to see a bunch of people Making cool new interesting.
Scott: You know minigames and things like that.
Scott: There's gonna be a bunch of game Duinos there.
Scott: I think the game do you know guys coming?
Scott: I got to talk to him because my game Do you know doesn't fit on top of my ether shield?
Scott: Even though he said it would.
Rym: so What do we do about DNS?
Rym: It's it's starting to become problematic because as a pedant I disagree with all the changes that have been coming lately.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you know I can.
Scott: when they started out was doing good stuff You know.
Scott: as far as not you know it wasn't very sign anymore.
Scott: Yeah, right, but more recently They've been starting some bad news.
Rym: It's like the sellout just started happening all at once.
Rym: I mean, I think dot brand name T.
Scott: You should go and look and see like if they if they change if the people on the icon board changed And that may be instigated these you know they're like there was some borderline between the period of good decisions and bad decisions.
Scott: There was a changing of the guard we didn't hear about.
Rym: I mean doesn't help that the majority of users of the internet and people who are like creators of the internet pretty much immediately gave up on DNS as it was designed and everything became.
Rym: you know it was kind of like this Binomial nomenclature like it was like something about something and no one used like proper subdomaining.
Rym: I mean no.
Rym: imagine a world when it was cats Dot org and then there was something dot cats dot org something dot something dot something dot cats dot org.
Scott: You know why do the first wet?
Scott: a lot of the problem is that the vast majority of DNS is used for the web even?
Scott: Though it's used for other things as well.
Scott: Yeah Well, why did web browsers the like mosaic?
Scott: I guess why did they put the domains backwards in the first place?
Rym: Oh, that's how the spec was Really?
Rym: Yeah, that's just how it was kind of designed.
Scott: It's like because they could have made the original browsers do com dot whatever right.
Rym: well you can think of.
Rym: I mean imagine reading it As though the dots are ads.
Rym: so I'm going to www at cats at calm.
Rym: Then it makes sense.
Rym: Yeah, because it's the www server at cats and but it's not a dot.
Scott: but I think of it this way What if the URL said org cats dot?
Scott: Www?
Scott: then things like the up button would sort of make sense, right?
Scott: You could go up.
Rym: Oh wait Wait, you mean like usenet?
Scott: Yeah, right exactly what I'm saying dot furry dot porn dot more porn exactly Navigationally, it would make a lot more sense And you also would save a lot of typing You know because you wouldn't have to always put the dot-com at the end.
Scott: The comm would just always be there and you would just replace like that last part.
Rym: I think part of it is that as soon as the internet grew at all people were no longer Cooperative in this world like it was an ecosystem where I should make a chromium fork that displays the URL properly.
Scott: It's just the HTTP.
Scott: comm dot is always there and you start typing after it by default.
Rym: So, I mean think about the way if in the old system would only work if whoever managed cats calm Was willing to share and work with everybody and be kind of neutral on all issues.
Rym: Yeah, you know let you know whatever dot cats calm whatever dot whatever.
Rym: you needed this huge chain of trust for that to work.
Rym: And as we've learned as soon as the internet opened up to the masses and even slightly before that You can't trust anyone.
Rym: and the chain of trust basically didn't extend past the TLDs.
Rym: no immediately.
Rym: so we're stuck with that I can't argue.
Scott: Well, the other problem is that they used to be just one registrar right and now there's.
Scott: anyone can be a registrar.
Scott: pretty much even you know, even Google's a registrar and Because of that there's a bunch of people in the dome, you know, even now still in the domain.
Scott: money-making game.
Scott: Yeah, let's play money-making.
Rym: domain name squatting would have been trivial to quash.
Rym: It's just that no one involved actually wanted to quash it.
Scott: Yeah And it's it's.
Scott: even now.
Scott: some of the policies that I can is thinking up are like, you know for these new domain These new top-level domains they're coming up with they're gonna have like Proportional pricing.
Scott: like you know a word in the domain.
Scott: if your domain that you want to register has words in it It'll cost more than if it's a bunch of random gibberish.
Scott: or the less characters in the domain you register the more money It'll cost as opposed to having a flat registration fee across the board.
Rym: Well, it seems like this is really aimed at brand names.
Rym: Yeah That is just dot brand name.
Rym: so we could get dot GeekNights.
Rym: we could and then everything we do would be dot GeekNights.
Rym: And I just I feel like that.
Scott: that becomes available.
Scott: We have to get it but it might think they might charge a lot of money.
Rym: They probably will charge a lot of money Yeah, and I almost don't want it at that point.
Rym: I know right but maybe if they do it this way Maybe they'll have something like you can't get something that someone else's trademark Maybe there's.
Rym: there's been a lot of The fact that trademarks in America don't necessarily line up with trademarks in other countries I know and you can have two trademarks that are identical, but are in different realms.
Rym: you know what.
Scott: this is a huge problem because you have this internationally shared system and The laws about this system are different everywhere right luckily What if I buy?
Scott: what if I get dot McDonald's?
Scott: But I live in a country where I have the trademark for McDonald's.
Scott: can the McDonald's in the United States?
Scott: Maybe that McDonald's is a bad example because it's a global guy.
Rym: Here's the answer the u.s One will always win because Whether or not people agree with it being the right thing or not Most of the internet infrastructure is in the u.s.
Rym: Most of the control of the internet is in the u.s.
Rym: And yeah pretty much I mean dot-com is synonymous with dot u.s.
Scott: But the other problem is right is what you know.
Scott: even if we go to like a distributed DNS system Right then we'll get rid of all these.
Scott: you know governmental and and Whatever money issues, but instead we'll have the incredible trust issues.
Rym: Let's look at the.
Rym: you know originally the idea of adding like dot biz and all these other TLDs was to allow more people to get domains.
Rym: now We were running out of useful domain space because that was before the era of Everyone.
Rym: just types in what they're looking for in the browser bar and Google just figures it out.
Rym: Yep, which means don't do this doesn't matter that much anymore to most people.
Scott: well Yeah, I mean most people only use DNS for the web right at least as far as they know.
Scott: And if they just Google everything we could.
Scott: just you know Google is some.
Scott: there's some browsers that are experimenting.
Scott: We get hiding the location bar and just you click on links for everything and Google search everything.
Scott: Yeah, then you know eat the URL could be a fucking ipv6 address.
Scott: You don't even give a shit because you don't see it.
Scott: But then what you know?
Scott: you still need to be able to give someone Tell someone in the world a URL for them to go to.
Scott: you know and it can't give its numbers.
Scott: That's not gonna work.
Rym: We could replace that with QR codes.
Scott: QR codes are helpful, but you know you still need to be able to tell somebody right it can't.
Scott: What if someone doesn't have a phone?
Scott: yeah, all right There's it's and you know it's still needs to happen and also there's a lot of time.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: if you say want to go configure?
Scott: Your you need to configure your phone to connect to your gmails.
Scott: So what if you can't type in mail that google.com?
Scott: you have to type in a bunch of gibberish.
Scott: That's gonna make it a lot more difficult for a lot of people.
Rym: yep But I think the real you know.
Rym: to get back to what I was going for this I think the real reason this happened is just a gigantic cash grab because Every big company already buys every domain is even close to the name of their company.
Scott: I mistyped Amazon today, and I ended up at Amazon.
Scott: Yeah before I was able to correct myself.
Rym: however if you mistype FARC you get to a surprising number of extremely shady websites.
Rym: But I feel like every big company is just going to have to buy Dot everything even close to their company's name.
Rym: yep And no one else is really good that everyone else is gonna be priced out of this pretty much.
Rym: I mean, maybe valve will get dot valve or dot steam.
Rym: that could be a little cool.
Scott: Yeah, it could be.
Scott: it could be cool But it's not like.
Rym: you know if I had money.
Rym: I would do whatever I could to get dot sucks.
Scott: No That's gonna be something like a million dollars million dollars you kidding.
Scott: and then someone's gonna have the trademark on sucks.
Rym: Ah, then I could get like someone on slash.
Rym: I had the same idea.
Rym: They're like.
Rym: so then I can get.
Rym: I can dot org dot sucks dot sucks dot sucks.
Scott: Oh Maybe we should get Cox and then we can do sucks that Cox and then we could do anything else.
Scott: you could do Whatever sucks Cox.
Rym: I'm gonna turn into a techno kind of pedant for a moment.
Rym: my only Technological argument against this is that the whole point of top-level domains is do not have a flat namespace.
Rym: No We already fucked it up by having the second level effectively be a flat namespace.
Rym: Because every way if you know GeekNights that if we were a big company We don't GeekNights calm dot org dot gov dot biz on everything well They're not gonna have it be completely flat right they're just gonna have you know More.
Scott: oh no.
Rym: This is the first step.
Rym: you realize I'm pretty sure.
Rym: Eventually if you have money you can get dot whatever the fuck you want.
Scott: well if they do it that way Why don't they just get rid of DNS and just have it be one flat namespace?
Scott: forget any hierarchy entirely.
Rym: yeah Because it's very.
Rym: the thing is some people are gonna have the business model of getting dot sucks And then selling something dot sucks.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good business model.
Rym: Yeah, that's gonna be a great business model for a long time to come from.
Scott: no I should write a piece of software that basically Where if you have a top-level domain you plug it in and it does the job of selling this up the you know regular domains.
Rym: Yeah This is gonna be like another gold rush of domain squatting.
Rym: well They're thinking about doing some sort of auction system - I know and imagine how many lawsuits they're gonna be about trademarks immediately.
Rym: Everything about this pisses me off What this is.
Scott: why right we need the only people who should ever make decisions about technology our Tim Berners-Lee our technology People Tim Berners-Lee and Steve Jobs, maybe he's a technology person Wozniak.
Scott: Yeah, only technology people should be allowed to make technology decisions.
Scott: right.
Scott: you wouldn't let me You know decide some medical decision for you.
Scott: Why cuz I'm not a fucking doctor?
Scott: So why are we letting these governments who are politicians?
Rym: We can let them make political but many governments do have a position like technological secretary or something.
Scott: meanwhile the government the United States.
Scott: Was he the chief information officer where Vivek Kundra?
Scott: he quit.
Scott: he just quit.
Scott: yeah, he's he's gone.
Scott: He's going to Harvard.
Rym: I have a feeling if I had that job.
Rym: I would quit no or I would go crazy and just punch somebody in Congress.
Scott: Yeah, I think what we actually need.
Rym: picture myself like running into Congress Just like punching people.
Scott: if I wanted to you know if I wanted to experiment with new forms of government I would have some form of government where it was pretty much technocracy.
Scott: well No, I don't know if you would call it technocracy But basically right there would be the president of doctors and the doctors would vote for the president of doctors.
Rym: How do you decide who's the doctor in the first place?
Rym: They have medical degrees so anyone with a credit universities anyone with a medical degree from an accredited university and They elect their doctor, so how do who counts as a tech guy?
Rym: then who counts for IT?
Rym: only people with IT degrees.
Scott: There you know we basically we I mean do you not get a vote?
Rym: obviously You don't get a vote in the IT president.
Rym: listen.
Rym: I'm the I listen obviously Pragmatically right terrible idea.
Scott: our current world doesn't have this you know system in place And you'd have to you know if you wanted to realistically do this you sort of have to start based on our you know current Organizational constructs and evolve them into a you know.
Scott: so over time to something.
Rym: It's impossible because even if you ignore the vast majority of the concerns around it There's a primary concern that everyone involved in the process has a vested interest in corrupting it to their own ends.
Scott: Yeah, but what you do.
Rym: There's no way to have a system of checks and balances because every group regulates itself.
Scott: No, there's easy way to make a system of checks and balance.
Scott: Yeah, there is a. you will have the the justice squad All right, and the justice squad basically are people who love to go catch corrupt people and if you're corrupt Flaying Alright, so the justice squad is already ten corrupt guys and one guy who doesn't know the rest of corrupt.
Scott: Nope Because there's the justice the watching watchmen and they watch the each other and they just really want to play each other.
Rym: look ye mighty.
Rym: exactly.
Scott: So you know the penalty is so severe.
Scott: You know it's not like oh you get a slap on the wrist and you get to go work at a company instead of the being In the government anymore.
Scott: right it's?
Scott: oh you're corrupt even if you're a little corrupt.
Scott: Oh, what's that?
Scott: You you know you gave some government money to some company.
Scott: you favored them on a government contract.
Scott: Guess what flaying?
Scott: Yeah, no one will fucking do that anymore.
Rym: I I feel like if I had my druthers and I had the role of DNA.
Scott: obviously deflaying is a joke.
Scott: Yeah, not that I wouldn't like to see a few flings Depends on the context.
Scott: It depends Flensing perhaps.
Rym: Oh shit much worse than flaying.
Scott: You're you're getting too rough on me.
Scott: There's a reason.
Rym: If I had my way with DNS I would not let any of this happen No kidding.
Rym: And I would set it up such that you couldn't effectively domain squat and there are ways to prevent that mainly by not letting you know.
Rym: There was that the borrowing system where you know Like get a domain name but not have to pay for it if you gave it back before a certain amount of time.
Rym: There were like all these loopholes so trivial to get rid of.
Scott: here's the solution for domain squatting.
Scott: You're ready some sort of system that counts like DNS queries And if your domain isn't queried then you lose it.
Scott: Also, there's a lot of this.
Scott: who is shielding?
Scott: I would basically if you I would just have a thing that goes and checks the who is is and It would actually be like a group of people and all they do is slowly check the who is is.
Scott: they don't have to do It very efficient.
Rym: Alright Scott, so I hire some guy to get the domain in his name, but really it's mine done.
Scott: I'm safe as long as he's got his full address and everything on there and it's for real.
Rym: Also, do you worry?
Rym: I mean I'm ambivalent on that cuz.
Rym: on one hand I like the idea that you could get a domain name and yet you're anonymous But on the other hand, I feel like the privilege of a domain name is worth forcing people to legitimately identify themselves Thus making domain names very powerful mechanisms of trust,
Scott: you know, we could do is we could set up a separate DNS system
Rym: Anonymous domains and Verified domains.
Scott: Yeah, and basically you would choose like it would be the.
Scott: you know Real people would.
Scott: normal people would never be able to use this.
Scott: but I could imagine a user interface.
Scott: We're in your web browser.
Scott: You basically have a little pull down or some sort of switch that switches between namespaces, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you'd like click and it would be like old world DNS would be the default and you would like uncheck the checkbox or go to the poll.
Rym: example, maybe I'll go to.
Rym: you know Anonymous lead hacker dot something that is totally anonymous and you know I'm taking my life in my own hands when I go there at least my browser, right?
Scott: So like in the normal DNS system google.com points here But in the nerd special DNS system google.com goes to some other server, you know nerds could just do that.
Scott: We could just set that up.
Scott: We don't even need a new software.
Scott: You just bind.
Scott: Yeah, I set up.
Scott: I just all bind and everyone just changes their DNS settings to point at it done.
Scott: Yeah, the only problem is that the way most had the only problem most DNS clients, right?
Scott: The way they're set up is to just go down the list of DNS servers trying each one in order.
Scott: They're not set up to like you got to basically have some sort of resolve.com switcher that switched it back and forth.
Rym: the way that DNS actually works is one of those weird things where I Feel like I know it because I went to university and most techies don't actually know how DNS were all that most Weird problems.
Rym: They can't understand why when they try to like multi home themselves.
Scott: Yeah, even tech people most of them all they know is that names translate into numbers and that's all they know.
Rym: Yeah, tell me what a quadruple a record is and we'll talk.
Scott: I know what a 1a record is.
Scott: I don't know what a quadruple a record really, you know, yeah So what's a 1a record?
Scott: That's just you've mapped, you know in a domain directly to an IP address.
Rym: Yeah, you know what a quadruple a is same thing ipv6.
Scott: Oh, I didn't know that ipv6 had to have a different name.
Rym: Yeah, how about MX record?
Scott: That's for mail the mail exchange.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, that's because when an email client is looking for the IP address It doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't just look for say, you know, the the a record it looks for the MX.
Rym: here's a sad question.
Rym: don't feel bad if you can't answer this one because I've never interviewed anyone ever who can answer it and these are all people who had DNS written on their resume.
Rym: All right, what's a PTR record?
Scott: It's uh, I used it once.
Scott: it's like it's a it's fuck.
Scott: Yeah, I used it for like jabber or some shit.
Scott: Yeah, you did.
Scott: Yeah, but I forget it's the reverse lookup.
Scott: No reverse solid.
Scott: is that's the reason that I don't know?
Scott: that is because every time I set up the reverse automatic for most people No, it's that when you set it up It's in like a separate UI as opposed to actually being a PTR record.
Rym: Oh because you set it up through our Provider.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know every other I write every configuration file.
Scott: Yeah, every other kind of record I set up even like TXT records and MX records.
Scott: They're all in the same like blob of text, but the PTR record isn't a separate bit.
Scott: Yeah, I get you know You don't just put it in with the other records and don't even get into.
Rym: people can't ever explain to me.
Rym: you know in dot adder dot our power any of the head.
Rym: but But now people who wrote DNS on the resume never could tell me what a pointer record was exciting.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it's kind of.
Scott: it's kind of sad.
Scott: we have the system and it's basically the whole internet relies on the system very much Not just that system and it's mismanaged Bigger problem that a lot of the core architecture of the internet.
Rym: This is the separate show I think is Based on technology where there are fewer people who know it today than I think there were 20 years ago.
Rym: Maybe I think fewer people understand how things like NTP or SNMP work now than did 20 years ago.
Scott: Yeah, cuz they're probably more.
Scott: More of the people who worked on it are dead or forgot or fought fell out of practice.
Scott: Things have changed.
Scott: They haven't kept up with it and fewer people have picked up on it and learned it from scratch.
Rym: Yeah I mean the number of people I've met in my life who can configure an Apache server like like guru legit style Configure for performance.
Rym: I've met maybe four people who I think could do that on a nine out of ten.
Scott: I mean I can do it nine out of ten, but I can't do it ten out of ten.
Rym: No one can do a ten out of ten.
Rym: There was one guy and he's dead.
Scott: There's all sorts of magic weird shit I just ignore in there.
Rym: Yeah, I I often look up what other people have done who I trust It's like.
Scott: I know a whole bunch of it But I only know the parts that you know You have to use 90% of the time Parts that like you don't really use that often that are configured by default to be the right way.
Rym: A lot of it's the performance tuning stuff.
Rym: I'm often unclear on.
Scott: I've even I've Studied it and can done it a whole bunch of times and it's still confusing because the documentation is just so awful Especially Depending on what modules you use underneath.
Scott: it can get really fucked up, right?
Scott: It's like well, you know the worker NPM works like this and the event NPM which is new works like this.
Scott: But what if you have the mod WSGI working underneath the worker NPM?
Scott: Well, and that has its own specific specified configuration.
Scott: what then?
Scott: And you even ask people they can't give you straight answers people who pretend to be experts.
Rym: Yeah, I had I had one of those O'Reilly books.
Rym: I'm like mastering Apache and I never read it.
Scott: yeah But yeah, this is sad.
Scott: I Don't know we're gonna do.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio And no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.