Rym: It's Monday February 28th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight model rockets.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So Scott you have some criticism of the way.
Rym: I introduced the show.
Scott: yes, I do.
Rym: What is your criticism?
Scott: you did not make any jokes about rockets or end or so.
Rym: so you're gonna pull and or space being cold You're gonna pull a luke you're gonna pull the.
Rym: ah I could have made a joke about blah as To actually making the joke about blah, no that's not what I said at all.
Scott: I said we should have joked.
Scott: we had a joke opportunity.
Scott: we did not use.
Rym: you know through the magic of podcasting and radio and Adobe Audition we could just rerecord the opening and you could make your joke.
Scott: I want to go home.
Scott: Ten seconds, that's a long time.
Rym: So how come?
Rym: you've been kind of managing servers at work lately.
Scott: What do you mean this whole Amazon thing?
Rym: like you it seems like you're doing a lot of IT work lately.
Scott: No the guy you know It's not really that much IT work.
Scott: I mean Amazon does all the actual IT work But it's basically.
Scott: you know there was policy that the IT guy had to do all that stuff And I'm the only Unix person there, so You know he wasn't doing it quite right, so now I finally let me do it because you know we got bought And so the policy goes away and whatever.
Scott: so now it's like aha.
Scott: I will do this properly.
Rym: I just found it funny because I'm kind of being pushed in the opposite direction And I'm getting sent for a lot of training And they basically want me to be a computer scientist and start working on the source code.
Scott: I guess they don't have enough computer scientists.
Rym: It's a complicated situation, but basically issues get complex to the point that when we need to troubleshoot them I Really need to see the source code or I can't troubleshoot.
Scott: This is why the Sarbanes-Oxley policy of developers can't be IT and IT can't be developers is retarded because it's not About code and you know software and hardware it's about systems and the whole thing is an integrated system.
Scott: everything goes together.
Scott: You can't be separating this stuff out.
Scott: one person has you know.
Scott: every person involved has to be able to get the whole picture in Their brain from the chips all the way electricity all the way to the user.
Rym: Every person involved the back office doesn't need to know about the code.
Rym: They just know what works and if it doesn't work the way they expect then someone like me has to fix All the tech people.
Scott: yeah, if you're a tech person you only All the tech people.
Rym: you said all the janitor needs to know yeah, okay?
Scott: No, if the tech you know if a tech person only understands one part of the system, right?
Scott: They're inevitably going to fail and fuck up in some way because they will not have accounted for some other part of the system.
Rym: Not about a well-managed project.
Rym: I mean you can have like the people who write the stuff that consume the market data for example.
Rym: just to use Examples from my industry They really only need to worry about an input stream and an output stream.
Rym: And then there's the contract between you know them sending the data out After they've processed it and all the people internally who will subscribe to it and use it.
Rym: as long as both ends follow the contract Then neither end needs to know jack shit about what the rest of them are doing.
Rym: this is true But but there has to be at least one person who knows how the whole thing works.
Scott: That's here's the thing right.
Scott: so okay?
Scott: So now you've got two groups right the group that's doing the data Whatever and the group on the other side of that?
Rym: well that you have the third group the glue group the project manager.
Scott: Now you.
Scott: so now you every time you split up something like that you add bureaucracy and documentation and management.
Scott: that now also Cannot fail.
Scott: yes, right if you have just a group that handles everything then it you know it might become a deal.
Scott: It might become unwieldy as the system becomes too large.
Scott: But have you subdivide the labor?
Scott: now you have to add meta labor every time you sub divide.
Rym: I would argue that there are projects that are large enough to where if you do not subdivide it is Basically impossible to actually.
Rym: well obviously obviously But I mean I'm in a position where it's an industry where no one person could do Any of this let alone all of it of course.
Scott: I mean that's just obvious right?
Scott: I mean like Microsoft every person at Microsoft is gonna know all the office and all of Windows and right as retarded.
Rym: Well I guess it's like for you the way you'd like for your job the stuff you need to do on a daily basis.
Rym: you Could do it all but for the fact that there might not be enough hours you care to work.
Scott: Yeah, I mean at my work.
Scott: There are one two three four five tech people.
Scott: Yeah total Almost entirely tech people and in turn you know the work that I actually do work right.
Scott: There's only three of us, and we're trying to get more people you know.
Scott: so there's really only three people.
Scott: so we do not need Meta work.
Scott: we need less meta work, so we can do more work.
Rym: The reason I brought all this up is I was thinking about the problems I'm facing in my company and the problems that you deal with and the problems other tech people we know deal with.
Rym: and I Feel like every company.
Rym: That's small is not doing enough subdivision and every company That's big is doing too much subdivision and like nobody has figured out the right balance except Google.
Scott: Here's the is the right balance.
Scott: right is pretty much you want to do the most work with the least employees.
Scott: That's how you do the math.
Scott: so you say okay?
Scott: If we you know right now We've got the system and really none of these people that I have on the team completely understand the whole system.
Scott: They're specializing right which means we probably need a subdivision.
Scott: and so if we subdivide then you know these people who are maybe Spending your 20 this four guys And they're on the team and they're spending like a quarter of the day in Meetings because they got to talk stuff over with each other because they don't know the whole thing individually.
Scott: So we can add one more person and then these people won't need to have those meetings anymore, and we'll break even right.
Scott: So then you're all you know, but if you have to add three people to do the management, and that's thing That's not a good deal.
Scott: It's you know bad move.
Rym: well You got to do it like raid is you know?
Rym: for every one stripe of parity you lose one disk exactly.
Scott: so you got it?
Scott: Maximized your storage space.
Rym: of course one problem with the philosophy of minimizing the number of employees.
Rym: if that's your only metric That's good except.
Rym: You have now increased the truck factor.
Rym: That's like a raid zero of people.
Scott: Well I mean you should never have.
Scott: you know.
Rym: Minimizing employees, I mean really that's not minimum.
Scott: You know that's that's a necessary employees You need to have.
Scott: any individual thing needs to be known by at least two people Maybe more though.
Rym: I mean we've had problems.
Rym: We're a small company.
Rym: only two people know.
Scott: and uh well If it's a really small company the company itself is in a truck anyway.
Scott: So you're basically everyone is working their asses off to get the company off the truck.
Rym: Think about a weird unintended consequence.
Rym: say you have double redundancy.
Rym: you have two people who are escalation contacts like they're experts at Everything like there are two people for everything.
Rym: if one of any of those pairs quits at any point The second person now has infinite power to demand whatever they want or quit.
Scott: This is why you hire someone really soon.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time even if you hire someone soon takes a while to train and during that time You've got a dictator.
Rym: Just waiting just ready.
Scott: When does that ever happen?
Rym: I've considered doing it at times in my life.
Scott: I've never seen anyone actually do it.
Scott: You know there's all these stories.
Scott: people tell like oh obviously the code You'll have job security.
Scott: or oh you know You know if you are the only one who knows something hold your company hostage and demand a raise.
Rym: You know why I think we have those stories.
Rym: I don't think anyone ever actually says I'm going to do this though There was that Slashdot article like a week ago about a guy who did that for a bunch of arcade games.
Scott: I was gonna say the guy who did the whack-a-mole, and you know what they totally got caught.
Rym: well I think someone a Slashdot said that we were very lucky that very few people in the world have three factors together that are one good at software engineering two also good at social engineering and three evil evil or evil.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't happen to us.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I think what happens is smart people find Poor code or a bad situation tech wise and they look at it And they think there's no way someone's that stupid.
Rym: it had to have been someone who's really clever trying to keep the job.
Rym: So it's Monday.
Rym: There's a ton of tech news.
Rym: I don't think we need to talk about Libya.
Rym: I think it's obvious.
Rym: the internet's starting to come back online bit by bit in all the free areas and go internet goo.
Rym: I think the nerds are winning in at least two of these countries.
Rym: all right.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: So got any tech news?
Scott: Yeah, so Apple announced this thunderbolt today or not today a while ago last week something few days ago right, and it's basically it's a new connector that goes on the new MacBooks.
Rym: right and What does it replace?
Scott: Well, it's actually kind of interesting right in that it replaces.
Scott: I guess it doesn't replace USB.
Scott: I mean at least not yet because the laptop still has two USBs.
Rym: It doesn't replace firewire because the laptop still has a firewire on it At least yeah, well when I got piece you know when I got a PCI there were still ISAs in my computers, right?
Scott: So they're hoping to you know get you know to beat out USB and also firewire and hopefully move everything to Thunder.
Scott: That's their whole their goal right?
Rym: I'm all.
Rym: I don't think that'll happen.
Scott: know what I think is interesting though.
Scott: Is that they managed to?
Scott: You know cuz Steve Jobs hates more connectors right he wants less.
Scott: so even though he might be dead soon, which is weird He wants less connectors in the side of the laptop.
Scott: So what he did is he said aha the Thunderbolt will simultaneously not only be a new really fast data port but it will also be the video out port and it's the same shape as the Like the display adapters, so if you have one of those you know the newest MacBook.
Scott: So he's the second newest now because there's newer ones right or even the third newest.
Scott: I think is the same connector And you have the thing that you know.
Scott: so it's basically the mic.
Scott: the mini display port is the same shape.
Scott: So if you want to hook up to a projector you connect it to the Thunderbolt port the same port that you would have connected You know before.
Scott: So it's.
Scott: it's a port that can go theoretically up to 10 gigabits per second Which is twice as fast as the theoretical maximum of USB 3.0 and is Three point something times as fast as the theoretical maximum of e of it.
Scott: Yes, ATA, so it is the fastest theoretically.
Scott: yeah, it can do video output So connecting to the projector and it can also do just data, and it can also daisy chain.
Scott: So if they get their wish and this is the only connector on the laptops of the future or at least the MacBooks of the Future you won't.
Scott: they'll decrease.
Scott: they won't have any USBs or firewires.
Scott: It'll just be power Ethernet's The Thunderbolt right which will do your video out and your data out And your headphone hole your microphone hole and maybe your SD card hole right the and those will be the only holes.
Scott: They'll lose three holes.
Rym: see the thing is with stuff like this the killer app would be It would have to be able to have adapters on it where you could plug in firewire and USB devices because the amount of Legacy equipment isn't just like in many cases.
Rym: I always say yeah fuck the legacy equipment when we're trying to move to some modern technology.
Rym: But there is just way too much legacy equipment, I mean I just bought a brand new HD camera.
Rym: What's it got?
Rym: USB?
Scott: Yeah, so here's the thing right is first of all can't.
Scott: in terms of cameras and like you know He's mostly aiming this because this was Simultaneous with the release of a new final cut.
Scott: I think I think there was a new final cut.
Scott: So this is aimed at the video.
Scott: people right they want you to get the ultra high-res videos Onto your Mac and they also want the ultra high-res videos to go on like a raid and you could work so fast with that If you have ten gigabits per second, but
Rym: I have a NAS ten
Scott: times gigabit Ethernet.
Rym: Yeah, but I have a NAS that stores my video library and hard drives are cheap.
Rym: I have a local disk that just has everything on it.
Rym: That's fast enough.
Scott: Okay, so how fast your local disk is?
Scott: sata?
Scott: Yeah, right, which is three.
Scott: This is not.
Rym: this is ten all right, so this is ten.
Rym: How long before the next standard of you know whatever?
Rym: say that dry?
Scott: What if you're working with like you know high high resolution from a video from like a red camera, right?
Scott: This is actually gonna be significant for you.
Rym: It's gonna be significant only in the short term because that sort of external connector when there's so many different things that need to connect To it cannot evolve as quickly as something like an internal hard drive connector.
Rym: where the industry has been nervous.
Rym: It's very successful at saying fuck it.
Rym: There's the new one over and over again and a very short cycle.
Rym: Yeah, I mean USB.
Rym: it.
Rym: look how long it took to get USB to USB 3. thunderbolt will not be able to advance I don't think in the long run.
Scott: Well USB 3 isn't even out yet And it's only theoretically five gigabits per second, that's what I'm saying.
Rym: I don't think that anything external like this if it is the you know what the connector to rule them all is Going to be able to keep up with just the advancement of internal proprietary things.
Rym: Plus if you're doing so gonna make the time if you're doing stuff with red like for real.
Rym: if I was doing real video editing I'd have some iSCSI or some fiber channel.
Scott: How fast is that theoretically?
Rym: Fucking fast.
Rym: that is what we use for like multi terabyte real-time databases.
Scott: Let's go look at how fast fiber channel is Speaking.
Rym: the other question is how fast are the disks?
Rym: I mean disks often can't even drive network bandwidth in some cases.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know, you're never gonna.
Scott: it is a theoretical maximums, right?
Scott: so but the point is is that there definitely is a bottleneck in this transfer department for You know people working with high-res videos, especially right, you know I mean these people are like, oh I gotta wait so long to you know transfer my videos Anyway, so I think it'll be interesting if they actually push this to say like iPods and stuff like that.
Scott: You know if the iPhone just has one of these and they get rid of the dock connector or something like that You know what?
Rym: This really means it's gonna be a fucking pain in the ass to run panels at conventions.
Scott: Well, no it might.
Scott: if everyone will have the same stupid little video adapter Then we'll buy the little adapter for it to VGA and you'll connect.
Scott: Yeah, exactly and you it's the same adapter They already sell right?
Scott: so I have one at work and so basically you would you could attach it if they put it on The iPhone or whatever.
Scott: you could attach it directly to your iPhone to VGA instead of using the weird dock connector to RCA thing I have now anyway, so it is sort of interesting in those departments.
Scott: However, I think it is still kind of I'm bleh on it even though it is ridiculously fast Oh or a reason other than the ones we've already talked about and this is the thing.
Scott: I don't understand right?
Scott: It's like why are they so in love with these external connectors, right?
Scott: It's like he wants to reduce the number of ports on the side of the laptop to make it more beautiful and I can understand That.
Scott: right that you definitely things look better when there's less holes in them, right?
Scott: This is it's obvious, but How is it less?
Rym: I couldn't make it made a joke there about less holes, right?
Scott: But how is it less ugly right to have a huge stack of daisy chained?
Scott: External devices because you can't modify any internal parts of the computer?
Rym: Yeah, that's the one thing about my PC is that inside is an ugly mess of cables.
Rym: You know what's connected to those cables like six terabytes worth of storage, right?
Scott: So it's like if they would just they only make one computer.
Scott: that lets you put anything inside the Mac Pro Which is ridiculous, you know and I can understand.
Scott: you don't put anything in a laptop, right?
Scott: But it's like you want to make it more beautiful, right?
Scott: You should maybe make the iMac right allow people to put stuff in it make the iMac more like, you know Something small that you can open.
Scott: well Maybe at least I just I feel like this standard won't and then you won't have a nasty ugly mess of external piles of crap But the wires all over your desk.
Rym: I don't think it'll matter in the long run.
Rym: I mean I agree with you there But I just think this is going to be like firewire and that it'll eventually it could replace firewire in the long I think it will.
Scott: I think that's what it will be.
Scott: It will be like firewire and it there'll be a lot of Mac specific things for it and there will be lots of the high Video people my audio.
Rym: because the thing is I had never had used for firewire in my entire life Until I started doing audio.
Scott: for I mean these are on the MacBook Pro, right?
Scott: They're not on the MacBook At least I don't think that.
Rym: well The thing is because firewire that the advantage over USB is that it's higher bandwidth.
Rym: I can actually have you know eight streams of real quality audio going into my computer into eight channels and they haven't removed the USB yet.
Scott: So this is that you know This is a thing for the pro video type people who are all about max and they will love it and you know.
Scott: Well, hopefully, you know replace firewire.
Rym: I I think it'll absolutely replace firewire if it works.
Scott: Yeah, except for the people but people those people are still gonna demand firewire for a couple years.
Rym: Well, the thing is I haven't looked at the spec.
Rym: I mean, I assume it does all the kind of low latency synchronized time things that fire.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's actually kind of ridiculous because it's bi-directional so you can actually get 10 gigabits both ways Right.
Scott: and because you can daisy chain it you could for example Load video from a camera So that's one direction at 10 gigabits per second and also save it to a disk In the daisy chain at 10 gigabits per second theoretically right at the same time simultaneously, right?
Rym: So that's just a flashback to the old days of daisy chaining scuzzy devices together and having that little terminator cap at the end.
Scott: I mean technology wise, you know, there's nothing really wrong with it.
Scott: It's faster than everything else on paper and you can do it's you know, you can use it for you know Video like just plug a monitor into it because it is just a video out port and also data.
Scott: That's pretty nice But it's still.
Scott: it's just gonna replace for the pros.
Scott: I don't think anyone is gonna use it for normal.
Rym: You know what else would have made it work if it were a replacement for HDMI.
Scott: I think yeah You can do that.
Rym: know what I mean straight up and TVs supported it with no DRM.
Scott: Yeah, you just need it.
Scott: You can if you get a. if you if you buy a Mac monitor You just plug the monitor directly.
Rym: Yeah, but if I buy a Sony TV They're not gonna have out in and outputs on the TV for this anytime.
Scott: Well, I think that's Apple's one problem.
Scott: right is the last.
Scott: every time they come there are certain things Apple does openly and certain things They do closed.
Scott: Lee right and their ports have always been something they do openly.
Scott: they you know The mini DisplayPort which is the same shape as this.
Scott: they put out the specs like people.
Scott: Please make things using mini DisplayPort right.
Scott: if they made it an open standard, you know They wanted people to do it, but no one did.
Scott: they really need to stop being you know Non-communicative assholes and they need to go out to other the companies they hate right and be like look Sony Make TVs with this hole in it, you know, hey, you know Dell make laptops with this hole in it.
Scott: Let's all make laptops and and TVs and displays and dry.
Rym: You know, they don't.
Rym: how do you know?
Rym: There aren't all these NDA conversations all the time Like hey, we're doing this and maybe Dell says fuck you.
Scott: I mean, we have no idea.
Scott: It's could possibly be that the other companies say fuck you.
Rym: I don't think Apple is run stupidly.
Rym: I don't think they would do something stupid unless they didn't want it to actually be the end-all.
Rym: I don't think that's the case either.
Scott: I think I think they should.
Scott: you know, they're really if they whoever's saying no to it Right, whether it's Thunderbolt or something else, right?
Scott: It could be not invented here syndrome on the part of the other guys Right being like oh we don't use Thunderbolt as an Apple thing then Apple have power.
Rym: I mean, it could be we're already working on USB 4 or something internally.
Scott: Yeah You know They should all.
Scott: everybody including Apple needs to get together.
Scott: and what really we need?
Scott: all of these ports every single one of.
Rym: we can't even Convince them to agree on a power standard.
Scott: Yeah, actually the cell phone guys are getting pretty close.
Scott: Yeah, they're close.
Rym: But how long did it take forever?
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: I you know, cuz they all wanted to sell their AC adapters.
Scott: They make a lot of money on this.
Scott: Yeah I remember how would you tell the shirt tell the shareholders that you're gonna standardize that you're gonna lose all your revenue from Not gonna fly.
Scott: Anyway, they're really all these ports USB firewire every.
Scott: everything is just serial data transfer every.
Scott: that's all it is.
Scott: And we really need one wire for serial data transfer, right and we just need to crank the fuck up, you know And just put it out.
Scott: and I think the reason that Apple was able to come out with this is because like USB for example USB 3 is Slow because it is a working group.
Scott: all these guys get together and argue until they finally agree on what it should be Whereas Apple just says here's what it should be and here's the spec.
Scott: Everyone can look at it right which allows because they don't have to argue with anyone.
Scott: They just do what they want.
Scott: They're able to just come out with it and have it be finalized immediately.
Scott: But then who else is going to adapt it?
Scott: if they you know, they have complaints with it so they're like well That's your.
Scott: Apple did things the way they wanted to and if they were Arguing with us in a consortium and we wouldn't have agreed and we wouldn't have done, you know.
Scott: So we're not gonna put that in our computer because it doesn't do X Y & Z which we would have argued for and are arguing for so that all that sort of you know What's it called all those concessions and
Rym: Compromise compromise
Scott: the thing
Rym: that we hate above all other things.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That's what slows one down You know, but at the same time without the compromise, it's an Apple only thing.
Rym: Yeah, well then you get into the Constantine since you a situation that we always talk about on Friday night party line Which may be coming back.
Rym: Okay, so very briefly I don't want to talk about this a lot But there's an article on slash shot and it was from business and law About how Craigslist is and there was a group that was studying this.
Rym: I quote cesspool of crime.
Scott: It's I wouldn't say it's a cesspool.
Scott: It's more of a. it's more of a bog.
Rym: I mean you want a cesspool.
Rym: YouTube comments.
Rym: That is a cesspool.
Scott: It's not really a cesspool at cesspool.
Scott: That's more of a.
Rym: Or alright fine cesspool, let's look at the common sense any local newspaper in America.
Scott: Well, those thing is those aren't cess at all.
Scott: The problem is is it's more.
Scott: those are more if it's all says no Those are like a latrine.
Scott: They've been cleaned thoroughly and it's stupid.
Scott: I don't understand why the newspapers do this.
Scott: They leave the comments there, but all the comments say comment removed.
Scott: if don't put the words comment removed Just completely remove it.
Scott: So no one even knows the comment was ever there.
Rym: I realize it'd be simple enough to remove most of the stuff that happens on every local newspaper site.
Rym: Just filter out basic swear words and racial slurs 90% of it and spelling every possible spelling of every racial slur.
Scott: if anyone has bad spelling just don't let their post go through.
Rym: Yeah We need that cat like, you know stupid like detecting or system.
Rym: anyway Craigslist is kind of a cesspool in my opinion partly because it is used by the masses like Everybody except the oldest of the old and the disconnected of the disconnected Knows that if you want to get rid of a busted old refrigerator you put it on Craigslist and someone will come take it.
Rym: Yep, and if you want to have sex with a stranger Craigslist is where you go.
Rym: Yeah, I want to buy a crack pipe.
Rym: You want to complain about crack pipes.
Rym: Craigslist is where you go.
Rym: Yeah, it is democratized.
Rym: It's so simple.
Rym: It's so dumb.
Rym: It looks like it's out of 1992.
Rym: It is so everyone can use it and as a result There's a lot of crap on there and smart people don't fall for the crap because they're not Stupid.
Scott: Craigslist also has many warnings.
Scott: It tells you how not to fall for crap.
Rym: They get you're like, hey If somebody doesn't say where they are if a dude Leads you at 1130 at night behind the Walmart to pick up your free HDTV Yeah, you're gonna get raped.
Rym: Yeah, but I want to point something out this study.
Rym: I was reading the article I was thinking about this and I had a lot to say about society and culture and technology.
Rym: And then I noticed who did this study?
Rym: this study the yellow page list sucks and is a bastion of crime Newspaper classified organization.
Rym: It is done by the aim group.
Rym: Are you familiar with the aim group?
Scott: Are you talking about a?
Scott: I am from Marvel Comics?
Scott: What?
Scott: No, you don't know.
Scott: aim from Marvel Comics.
Rym: Oh quote consulting services for interactive media and classified advertising.
Rym: huh, so the people who organize the people who sell ads in out-of-date ad selling.
Rym: media like newspapers are Trying to say that Craigslist is a den of iniquity.
Scott: But yeah aim in Marvel Comics is advanced idea mechanics and it's sort of just generic terrorist bad guy.
Rym: Not that bad of a name though.
Scott: Yeah, it was originally no apparent according to Wikipedia.
Scott: I didn't know this.
Scott: It was originally known as them.
Scott: It's first mentioned in strange tales.
Rym: What does them stand for?
Scott: It just it's the word them really?
Scott: Yeah It could have been an acronym.
Scott: no, but aim is advanced idea mechanics, they're just generic.
Scott: They're sort of like foot.
Scott: so the Foot Clan, right generic.
Scott: It's like we need some bad guys in this in this comic But we don't have any specific villain we want to use right because that would mean plots.
Scott: So we had to just have generic bad guys Terrorists of some sort to fight because we're focusing on some heroes internal drama and they need to fight something.
Scott: So here we go aim bat.
Scott: just some aim agents are doing some terrorism.
Scott: There we go.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: So things of the day, I think this is pretty cool.
Rym: So a lot of people don't realize that air rifles have existed since the 1500s.
Rym: give or take wait.
Scott: How could there be an air rifle in the 1500s if they didn't have compressors?
Rym: They did have compressors.
Scott: Okay, that's fun.
Rym: So basically these air rifles and later 1617 even up through the 1800s they were used by militaries Especially in Austria should be with BBs.
Rym: You realize if you take basically a musket and make it air power to have like a metal canister That'll hold a lot of air in it compressed.
Rym: It'll kill a guy at a surprising range.
Scott: Well, it's shooting.
Scott: what a musket ball.
Rym: Yes, a rifle musket ball.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: Yeah, there's science.
Rym: I watch videos of them shooting it through inch thick pieces of wood from quite a distance.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that'll kill a guy.
Scott: but the thing is even actual muskets You know weren't as good at killing people as guns with actual bullets.
Scott: because you know Balls, they're not bullets.
Rym: Uh You realize we invented rifling a long time ago, right?
Rym: Yeah, these are rifled air rifles.
Scott: Oh, they're not just yes.
Scott: It's not just a musket ball going down a tube.
Rym: Yes, and even it does.
Scott: the front of it doesn't look like a trumpet Scott.
Rym: There was even a time when you could shoot musket balls that would take advantage of rifling to a degree Really because they conform to the edges and there was this famous but it has to be point in the in the front?
Rym: No, it doesn't that's not why anyway, so There there's this one particular air rifle that was used by the Austrian military and they had a lot of advantages.
Rym: For example, if you had a squad that had these rifles they could shoot like 20 times before they had to be recharged.
Scott: Oh, yeah, cuz you wouldn't have to keep you know, pulling the thing back and they had auto loaders.
Rym: They put all the ammo in him.
Rym: So basically you could shoot like 20 rounds like bam bam bam bam bam.
Scott: Well, but didn't you have?
Scott: maybe the thing is did you have to pump it?
Rym: It's no.
Rym: you shoot 20 or so and then you have to pump it.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah So hard was it to pump?
Scott: was it all like it to oil it?
Rym: really good You had to pump it 1,500 times to reload it.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Is that really how many?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: What?
Rym: Yes, so what they do is they carry like three canisters of compressed.
Scott: So wait, but someone did the original 1,500 pumpings times three canisters.
Scott: Yes, who's doing these pumpings?
Rym: board soldiers.
Scott: Why don't they do it with a?
Rym: Because they had cars in the 1500s.
Rym: Oh, what do you mean cars?
Rym: No with engines?
Rym: Yeah, exactly how else are they gonna do it with that?
Scott: the lumber mill.
Scott: you can have a you know You can have the the sawmill or the.
Rym: alright, so I'm on the road.
Rym: Now what I shot?
Scott: 22 guys three times No, but you can load up so many of them and fill your heavy.
Scott: They're made of iron.
Scott: You put them in the wagon.
Scott: Yeah soldiers gotta get anyway.
Scott: and the oxen pole.
Rym: That's not the point.
Rym: So the point of this is that apparently Lewis and Clark brought one of these particular ones the Giordoni With them on their famous adventure and this one rifle that they brought that was an air rifle is actually credited with them Surviving the expedition.
Scott: Uh-huh Single-handedly did it like get wet and they had to shoot something?
Scott: No, so That would be a major advantage.
Scott: Right is that if you're ever musk of an old-fashioned muskie gets wet might as well just throw it out.
Rym: That is one advantage.
Scott: But if this thing gets wet It'll probably fire some time.
Rym: another advantage that if you designed these to be subsonic to where the projectiles coming out Don't break the sound barrier.
Rym: They don't have much of a muzzle report.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: If you even get a modern-day BB gun is basically silenced even about a silencer on it.
Rym: It goes like so there are many advantages.
Rym: but Lewis and Clark's expedition had a lot of people with it a lot of supplies a lot of very valuable materials Yeah, and a lot of weapons a lot of muskets and powder.
Rym: apparently only one air rifle Yeah, and the air rifles would save them.
Rym: So it is argued in this video goes into a lot more detail that Basically while they were traveling Any one of the Indian tribes along there, you know multi-year expedition could have trivially overpowered them and all their firepower.
Rym: Had any of the tribes done that?
Rym: Lewis and Clark had with them enough musket balls and powder and rifles and provisions to where that tribe could have basically subjugated every other tribe in the area.
Scott: oh, that's clever.
Rym: and The question was how did they travel so far without even one Indian tribe thinking we could totally take these fuckers out hiding?
Rym: They didn't hide.
Rym: they traveled openly.
Scott: They're using the air rifle.
Scott: The Indian tribes wouldn't have heard them.
Rym: So they only had one and they weren't just killing all the people as they've marched.
Scott: No, I mean if they were hunting using only the air rifle now No Indians only would have been able to find them by sight and hidden.
Rym: so visually you want me to spoil it.
Rym: You want to watch the video you can spoil it.
Rym: So what they did is they put out they carry dress uniforms with them and Every time they think they knew an Indian tribe was like up the river or something.
Rym: They were dressed in full regalia and they'd play the fights.
Rym: They banged the drums and they just marched right into the Indian City Mmm, and they march in and they give them gifts like here's some cloth.
Rym: Here's some stuff.
Rym: We're nice.
Rym: And then what they would do is take the air rifle out and demonstrate it.
Rym: Now these Indians knew about rifles and muskets, but they didn't know about air rifles.
Rym: so he'd basically stand there and go pop pop just destroying a whole bunch of stuff in a demonstration.
Rym: and basically as far as the Indians were concerned this rifle had infinite ammo and could shoot forever with almost no sound and kill everybody.
Rym: and They they used this and credited it as the reason why the Indians left them alone because they were afraid of these weapons.
Rym: They thought that they had a ton of these things when really they just had one.
Rym: Uh-huh It's a neat bit of history and that's all I got to say.
Scott: those sites Um, someone actually has that exact rifle.
Scott: No, not like a copy of it, but that particular one.
Rym: No, they have the exact same model, but it isn't the one that Lewis and Clark.
Scott: No one has the one now, but it's the same model pretty much Uh-huh, then how do we actually know they had one if we don't have that one cuz they wrote about it Uh-huh.
Rym: In fact every time they mention it they also talk about how they scared some Indian tribe or other with it.
Rym: Uh-huh It's neat stuff.
Scott: All right So this is a video Much less involved, right?
Scott: It is a the first performance ever of the hit song smack my bitch up in Night back my bitch up.
Scott: You don't know this song.
Rym: I don't know that song.
Rym: That's a famous song.
Scott: Anyway is the first performance of it ever.
Scott: who did it in 1965?
Scott: That's a good question.
Rym: All right, I don't know Who sang the song in 1965.
Scott: Oh in 1965, yeah Someone else other than who actually sang it.
Scott: that is the joke of the video.
Rym: All right Are you gonna let on?
Rym: are we just gonna leave it be?
Scott: it's really not that complex a joke.
Scott: So there's really if I say it, there's no reason to watch the video.
Rym: Okay, and of course the meta moment We will be not this weekend But next weekend at the penny arcade Expo bitch packs in East.
Rym: March 11 12th and 13th We will be doing five panels and three panel rooms.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: Yep, Friday night and then two on Sunday All right, and also the weekend immediately after that March 19th and 20th.
Rym: We won't be there on the 18th Zenkai Khan anime con in the Philly area.
Rym: We will be there doing bunch of panels.
Rym: I gotta look up what.
Rym: when are we supposed to do laundry and then write those panels?
Rym: I took the day before we leave for packs off to do all my stuff And of course announcing this for people who didn't catch it.
Rym: It's a ways off.
Rym: But in April we will definitely be at the anime Boston like we go to every year.
Rym: We've confirmed it.
Scott: Yeah And before panels and I think a couple week or two before anime Boston I forget the exact date is the Museum of comic and cartoon art festival, which you should all go to.
Rym: we will.
Rym: We will be attendees.
Scott: In other words no sleep till May.
Scott: Yeah That's it's no sleep till May.
Rym: the book club book, which we're just waiting for Scott to finish reading is Michio Kaku's hyperspace.
Rym: I'll be reading that pretty soon And you should join the GeekNights forum because a lot of you have been joining lately and it's pretty fucking rocking in there.
Rym: Yeah, especially especially if you are a fan of the my little ponies, maybe I have a special Intrudy to all of you Rainbow Dash is clearly the best my little pony but yet of late.
Scott: Well, the best friendship is magic my little pony.
Rym: Well, that's the only my little pony as far as I'm.
Rym: yeah But there's been trouble lately.
Rym: these Fluttershy fanatics and these Pinkie Pie.
Rym: I don't have a word for them Are encroaching.
Rym: Yeah, so if you truly love Rainbow Dash Like all true men do get into the forum and vote in our which my little pony pony is the best pony poll.
Scott: Every pony vote Rainbow Dash.
Rym: Some model rockets something more manly.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, this is sort of like we're running out of Monday ideas.
Scott: So if anyone's Monday ideas send them on over.
Rym: but plenty of Monday ID.
Rym: No, you just don't want to do Shit for Monday.
Rym: I got plenty of nothing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What's name one?
Rym: Let's talk about Advice for me to you since you're doing more IT and you know cuz I'm doing CS.
Scott: stupid Stupid because I know I know everything I need to know.
Rym: Yeah, do you do?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: How do you set up NTP?
Scott: It's already installed.
Scott: I have to get install NTP done.
Rym: that actually doesn't configure it.
Rym: It won't work that way.
Rym: I was on Ubuntu.
Rym: Actually, it connects to shitty time sources.
Scott: if you do that it doesn't matter because I don't need the precise time that you need.
Rym: How do you know you don't?
Scott: Because I know I'm running a web server.
Scott: I'm not running whatever anyway.
Scott: So we figure hey model rockets.
Scott: that would sort of feel like a Thursday show, but it's science.
Scott: So we'll make it a Monday show.
Rym: take that I would argue that it's more engineering.
Rym: Yeah, probably but I'm gonna make a controversial statement right now And then I'm going to sidestep it and not talk about it again until the end of this episode.
Scott: All right, mr.
Scott: Controversy.
Rym: I was really big in the model rocketry as a kid.
Rym: I went to space camp.
Scott: I wasn't big in the model rocketry, but I did it, you know I went to a bunch of summer camp right and I also did did it once an actual shop class at school.
Scott: So I've done quite a few of the rockets.
Rym: Oh, I owned all the equipment.
Rym: I had my own launch pad.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I didn't actually own any stuff but I done it at many camps over many wide array of different rockets I'd built and played with.
Rym: but My controversial statement is as such I feel that model rocketry As it is practiced by the majority of the people in the u.s Who practice it is not educational in any meaningful way.
Rym: nor is it in any way a preparation for science or math education?
Scott: No, I don't think so either.
Rym: I think at best it's an expensive and slightly dangerous toy for most people.
Scott: I think it's pretty much the equivalent of Gundam models in terms of a hobby.
Scott: It's not a bad.
Scott: It's not a bad hobby It's not harmful, but it is not.
Rym: At least basic model rocketry like they have at summer camp or school is not helping you become a rocket scientist at all Or any kind of scientist, but so Scott, uh How many rockets did you ever launch that you were able to retrieve?
Scott: Uh, I think all of them.
Rym: really yeah, I lost about 75% of my rockets.
Scott: Well, I mean, did you do like the double stage guys?
Rym: I did very large rockets because I grew up in Michigan where the laws were much laxer than they are.
Scott: I've done him in Pennsylvania.
Scott: I've done him in New York.
Rym: I've done the biggest engine you ever used.
Rym: see see see really Yeah, see it's like the baby engine.
Scott: the baby engine was a double-a triple-a.
Scott: I never seen double-a or triple-a.
Scott: It was ABC.
Scott: No one ever used anything less.
Scott: and one guy really wanted to use II but they didn't let.
Rym: him is even legal in Connecticut I don't know.
Scott: It wasn't in Connecticut.
Scott: It was in Pennsylvania.
Rym: I've only ever used the engines a few times.
Rym: I was very I liked them, but I didn't do them on my own.
Rym: I had helped.
Rym: I did them like in events But these were pretty much my go-to engine.
Rym: So I'd make these rockets that I was trying to send them into orbit and I don't know if they got there.
Scott: No, I mean the basic.
Rym: one time I bought the transponder and I was waiting.
Scott: What a waste of money.
Rym: I figured alright, I'll lose my rocket.
Rym: Then I'll go find it and I shoot it and the transponder goes And I never found it.
Scott: good job, you know, but really it was annoying even sometimes even if I was able to retrieve the rocket Which is most of the time.
Scott: Yeah, the parachute didn't always work.
Scott: It worked about 50% of the time.
Rym: That means you packed it poorly.
Scott: So if some pony doesn't know how to pack a proper parachute so 50% of the time the parachute wouldn't eject and What happened was he would basically just go nose going first.
Rym: You're using the rock kind of engines right because you realize like plug engines don't have the ejection charge.
Scott: I they all had the ejection charge.
Rym: Are you sure?
Rym: Yeah, what's the ejection plug in the top?
Rym: Did you put wadding in?
Scott: Yeah, you always did the wadding.
Rym: How much wadding?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Did you pack it in real tight?
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: Because if you pack it in real tight, it might not blow.
Scott: I do.
Scott: I definitely use the wadding all the time.
Rym: Anyway, did you pack the parachute properly?
Scott: Yeah, you tie it up with a rubber band.
Scott: No, God no.
Rym: If you tie it up with a rubber band, it's not gonna work.
Rym: How's it gonna open?
Scott: No, you would.
Scott: no you didn't actually tie the rubber band around the parachute.
Scott: What you did is you you had you cut the rubber band and you attach the rubber band from the parachute to the nose cone Right on the inside.
Rym: You attach it to the inside of the tube not to the nose cone.
Scott: I think that I'm trying to remember.
Scott: I think the rubber band goes to all three because it connect.
Scott: the rubber band connects the tube to the nose cone.
Scott: Oh, I'm sorry.
Rym: You were an Estes kid.
Rym: I used quest components because they were far superior.
Scott: Actually, right, you know most of the time when I built one at like say regular old summer camp or in school They just bought Estes kits and we're just like follow the instructions kids.
Scott: But and when I went to real nerd summer camp, right?
Scott: There was no kits involved.
Scott: They basically had just tubes and nose cones and fins and all these parts everywhere.
Scott: You just built whatever you came up with.
Scott: There was no kit.
Scott: No instructions.
Scott: It was just go nuts, but they did force you to build.
Scott: Basically, basically what they did is they would they would ration out the parts, right?
Scott: So you if you went in we're like, I want to build like a three-stage monstrosity.
Scott: They'd be like, uh-uh, and they would give you the parts for basically what was known as a wizard Which is basically the smallest possible rocket.
Rym: The wizard is a specific Estes one.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: Yeah, they call this shit.
Rym: It's like the basic baby rocket.
Scott: They basically gave you the parts for you know The smallest baby rocket and they said build that and if you finish it and it works Then we'll let we'll let you get what other parts.
Rym: it takes less than two minutes to make the wizard.
Scott: Well, they forced you to.
Scott: actually the thing is they forced you to.
Scott: it was basically trying to.
Scott: it was a barrier to entry Right, so they forced you to paint it properly.
Scott: spray paint Yeah They basically forced you to do the job right and they examined it to make sure that you actually cared.
Rym: I never made my rockets look good.
Rym: Yeah but you realize if you get they just wanted.
Scott: they didn't have to look good asked it.
Scott: they just wanted to prove that you were Putting in the work.
Scott: and then if you put the work in and you were serious Then they would let you get more parts Special.
Rym: if you give them that freedom and like you give even simple parts Like let them make a rocket and you don't force them to make a specific design They will think to themselves that lighter rocket plus bigger engine equals higher.
Rym: So they'll.
Rym: so I knew many kids who would basically glue nose cones and fins to an engine.
Rym: Let me tell you that goes about five feet up spins around and come straight back at you.
Scott: No, but I mean because of the way they did things, right?
Scott: The only people were actually able to make anything cool or people who are like dedicated to it Right and they and if anyone is making something with more than a stage, right?
Scott: They would always like examine to make sure you weren't making something stupid.
Scott: They'd be like, no you can't do that.
Scott: or the thing was they had.
Scott: it wasn't like.
Scott: you just launched when you were done.
Scott: They had launch day twice at camp.
Scott: So every four weeks if you built three rockets, you'd get to launch three times on launch day, right?
Scott: But on launch day you would basically walk up to the launch pad with the rocket as everyone was sitting there and they would Look at it and they would.
Scott: they would make a spot judgment.
Scott: Yes or no?
Scott: And if you made a stupid rocket, they just say no, so you got a fudged you got a.
Rym: I made rockets that would explode.
Rym: They'd get up.
Rym: first stage second stage.
Scott: Boom.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the most ridiculous.
Scott: they wouldn't allow that to go.
Scott: The one thing is gonna hide it in there one kid.
Scott: They knew what you were doing though because they observed everybody.
Scott: It was a little tiny rocket hut.
Scott: They had a special hut the rocket hut and all the rocketing went got went on in the hut.
Scott: So they watched you rocketing in the hut.
Rym: You couldn't rock it outside the hut one kid I remember at Starbase filled his with gravel because he thought like you get up there and just for gravel and everybody but the fuck it Didn't even take off.
Rym: It basically got halfway up the launch pole like Hovered and then came back down.
Rym: the parachute went pop and some gravel went.
Rym: Yeah, and like one pebble fell out and then the kid got sent home.
Scott: Anyway, the the most ridiculous thing I ever saw though was this guy.
Scott: He basically made a gigantic rocket like as tall as a person.
Rym: Yeah, I made one like that.
Scott: It was like it was a tube that I could put my leg through.
Scott: It was a giant tube.
Rym: What kind of engines did he use?
Rym: that's like it because that was the interesting part of rocketry.
Rym: for me It was when you made the ones that use multiple.
Scott: that was the guy.
Scott: that was the guy who used the e engine Right.
Scott: So just one e. I don't know if it was just one e but I know there was definitely least one e involved.
Scott: There may have been a ring of other engines around it and I didn't look very closely.
Rym: It was difficult to set those off properly.
Rym: You needed the multi-stagers.
Rym: I know
Scott: I didn't know who that it wasn't multi-stage It was just one big tube with the biggest fins and the biggest cone and he spray-painted actually really nicely and it sat on The on the porch in front of his cabin for like as soon as he for me the time He finished it to the end of camp and on the last day of camp or the second last day before the parents showed up It was the final launch day and he brought it out there Basically all the rockets.
Scott: they put them out on display and they just grab them one at a time to decide if they're gonna launch Or not.
Scott: and he was sitting out there ready to launch right and at one point They went over and picked it up and they tried to slide it on to the launch pad and they stay.
Scott: all the counselors were Like discussing and they were like, hmm and you could tell the kid He sort of wanted to do it and he sort of didn't want to do it.
Scott: He's like he wanted to for awesome.
Scott: Yeah, but he also didn't want to because it probably would not have survived Right or just you know, and it was all so they have.
Scott: in the end They were like hesitant and then they didn't do it.
Scott: Ah, but it was like this thing was.
Scott: it was like it was at least four or five feet tall If not six feet tall.
Scott: it was big real big.
Scott: and uh, every kid wanted to see it go if it because it wasn't theirs.
Scott: Right, they didn't work on it.
Scott: Yeah, but it would have made might have killed someone because we were sitting pretty close.
Rym: So I think it would have been fine.
Rym: It was pretty dangerous.
Rym: You realize it seems like you were using all the Estes stuff because the rubber bandy crab That's that's kind of like the hallmark of cheapo Estes.
Scott: Well, I never.
Scott: I was never you know at the level where they would let me do it because I didn't you know.
Scott: I dedicated my time at some other areas of the camp like the computer area and the Area and the hockey area.
Rym: so I would sell more like components like design a rocket and the individual components were higher Quality like that have better seals.
Rym: or the biggest one is the nose cone would be connected Root like through the tube to the base of the rocket with a teflon cord or a Kevlar core.
Scott: Yeah, I think yeah if you you know, they had all these the base.
Scott: I think they might have had just quest and Estes parts at the good camp, right?
Scott: Most of the all the other camps just bought an Estes kit and handed to you in the bag still.
Scott: But at the good camp, right?
Scott: I think they just said every component imaginable like this tons of them of every shape and size and they definitely had you know The teflon cord and they had fancier nose cones and they had like multi-stage release tubes and all sorts of it.
Scott: Also different shapes of fins you could get.
Scott: they would even like make parts like.
Scott: they would go and buy balsa wood and go To the wood shop and cut out fins.
Scott: Yeah, that's how the kid got the giant fins for the.
Rym: you know That was the interesting part for me too.
Rym: Is that when you did the more advanced rockets like I would make fins you sand them down and paint them and then they look Terrible because I was bad at that.
Scott: Yeah At least you could.
Scott: even it wasn't too hard to do them all identically with a bandsaw though But even if they were all they just all be equally ugly.
Rym: Yeah But then you got to shape them and it's not so easy gonna sand them down to where they're.
Rym: like thick at the front they Come to a point at the bottom.
Scott: Yeah, but if you what you do is you clamp them all together, you know identically The whole times that they're all gonna be the same.
Rym: But then you have to sand them down and make the shape.
Scott: you sand them while they're clamped.
Rym: Uh, you can't say that wouldn't work.
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: How are you getting?
Rym: it's a fin?
Rym: There's two sides and it's a three-dimensional surface and you have four of them.
Rym: Are you gonna sand them all at the same time to be identical?
Scott: Well, no You'll.
Scott: you send the the edges right while they're all clamped and then when you actually want to send the two faces You have to unclamp it obviously.
Rym: Yeah, but the faces are anyway It's.
Rym: you can't just do it like that.
Rym: But I think my trouble with model rocketry is that like like you said of this camp, you know They give you a kit you build it and it goes.
Rym: very few children actually get to the point of experimenting and Trying to learn from their experiments or trying to actually chart a trajectory or thinking things like alright I want to launch a rocket to accomplish X So I'll use an a engine with in the first stage with this characteristic cuz remember the numbers.
Scott: That's true at no point.
Scott: But did anyone ever discuss like any sort of math or physics in relation to the model rocketry?
Scott: at no point Did anyone discuss like, you know any correlation between actually trying to do something?
Scott: It's pretty much just like a fun activity like building.
Scott: Like I said building a Gundam robot It was like, you know follow the instructions make something and then it's fun when you get to launch it.
Scott: Yay.
Scott: It's fun.
Scott: There was no learning or education in terms of you know, you know any sort of rocket science.
Rym: It usually wasn't even engineering because the kid no matter how shittily you built it They'd all launch about the same.
Scott: It was mostly right is the number one priority was pretty much safety.
Scott: Right because these all these camps and stuff had liability issues in schools All right and I never knew anyone who did it like on their spare time on their own where they would actually experiment or anything like that.
Scott: and After safety, it was pretty much just like, you know, it's basically the equivalent of arts and crafts, you know It was like make the rocket have fun making it don't.
Scott: there was no at any point ever any education.
Scott: It was you know, it was pretty much all we knew is a bigger letters, you know And everyone kids would be like man, I'll gonna make a rocket that used the 5z engine And then they would.
Scott: some kids would be like all the space shuttle the white ones on the side or s and the big red One is you know, I'd be like what.
Scott: I don't think that it works that way.
Scott: I don't think the NASA's like yeah get the s engines out for the space shuttle.
Rym: So, how do we make model rocketry, um a worthwhile endeavor other than just arts and crafts.
Scott: Well, I think what you know in the kit right because it's always gonna be kids.
Scott: You're not gonna be able to deliver it without kids, right?
Rym: so in the I think you could if you're like if you're if you're a counselor at a camp that was willing to let you Do it you basically assemble all the component parts and kind of as a class design rockets.
Rym: Yeah, sure.
Scott: But the thing is if you're gonna deliver it in a wide scale, right?
Scott: You need to deliver it in kit form right to get any sort of traction and you know At least for the entry level.
Rym: Well, there's two and what you need to do?
Rym: There's the there's the the entry level mass-market like, you know kit thing.
Rym: So you gotta start with the entry level Yeah, but there's also the focused instruction like rich kid camp, right?
Scott: But where are you gonna?
Scott: you need focused instructors and there are many.
Scott: so yeah, you can't have enough instructors.
Scott: So you need to do is in the kit itself Don't just include the instructions and how to stop.
Rym: they all included all the math and science.
Rym: No one paid attention to it Really?
Scott: Yeah, no one.
Rym: No, I never saw any math or science got I know instructions from Estes that explain everything you needed to know about making rockets how to balance them different.
Scott: Well, I think the problem is simple.
Scott: Let the kids see that goddamn book is.
Scott: I didn't know that book existed.
Scott: I never saw it.
Scott: No one ever showed that book.
Rym: I don't blame the creators of the Mass-market products and while I like quest better quest failed and Estes still is around as far as I can tell you just need to Show that book to the kids.
Scott: That's pretty much all it comes down to.
Scott: but even there have the person in charge read the book.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: it's that the instructors at camps and things even at Space Academy and you know space camp and star base in these programs I went to they did even if they knew rocketry they didn't care and most of them were kind of Nerds who actually cared mostly about the appearance.
Rym: They'd make like the one shaped like an x-wing Yeah, as opposed to the one that teaches a valuable lesson Like what if you want to make one that's going to fly up take a picture at its apex and then launch the parachute you know having a kid calculate what kinds of engines and what waiting and what delays and what fin Configurations and how to aim it in the wind where the apex will be right.
Rym: That's the interesting stuff But no one ever presents it in that manner.
Scott: Well, there are people who work on model rockets right in that manner But you know, it's much like you.
Scott: look at RC cars, right?
Scott: There's people who buy an RC car Tycho and there's some people who make one that's gas-powered right.
Scott: or there's some people who make Model air, you know a model airplane, you know Like the helicopter from Radio Shack and the.
Scott: some people make a model airplane for reals, right?
Scott: So model rocketry is the same way.
Scott: Most people are doing these kits at summer camp But then you got like John Carmack who's making rockets that are metal and have rocket fuel in them, you know and so there are not.
Scott: I guess there are some kids into the serious model rocketry also, but there are Serious model rocketry hobbyists that do exist.
Scott: Yep, and they actually are really doing model rocketry for reals.
Scott: It's just that's not being exposed to children or anyone else on a wide scale.
Scott: It's it's very a small a much smaller hobby than RC car.
Rym: I also worry that the hobby is getting even smaller.
Rym: I feel like liability concerns are taking it out of schools.
Rym: I feel like just like New York has kind of restrictive laws on different levels of engines and everything and yeah It's kind of.
Rym: it's a hobby that I think is going to largely disappear from the anything that children have access to.
Rym: Independent of the problems that the hobby has I feel like it's gonna go away.
Scott: I don't know if it'll go away completely not completely.
Rym: It'll still be it's.
Scott: I think it's pretty much.
Scott: I think it's gonna hold steady.
Scott: I just where it is, which is low.
Rym: I think it'll decline.
Rym: I think a lot of just adults are afraid to teach children about it partly because they're afraid of terrorism stuff.
Scott: on a vague level I mean, I worry more about the RC planes and RC cars than the.
Rym: I wouldn't give a kid an RC plane or an hour.
Rym: Maybe an RC car.
Scott: Well a plastic one.
Scott: Yeah, not a real one Anyway, but yeah, I guess model rocketry.
Scott: It's you know, I guess it was sort of.
Scott: it's it's like when we were kids.
Scott: It was sort of big.
Scott: it was it wasn't huge, but it was always sort of there.
Rym: I remember I used to go to local hobby shops and they'd have just like every Isles of them every hobby shop and Toys R Us had them when I was a kid.
Rym: Yep sure did I haven't been to a Toys R Us in a while.
Rym: I feel like I should go and see if they have model rockets or not.
Scott: I even think you can find them at craft stores too Like, you know, not a good one.
Rym: I wonder if you still can.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen it in a craft store kind of recently ish.
Scott: But yeah, it's sort of like this thing.
Scott: It was always sort of there But it didn't have any staying power, you know, and I just happened to go to a weird nerd science camp Where they had a rocket hut.
Rym: Yep I happen to live next to the Southridge Air National Guard base and they had programs where they teach kids about Military and science and space stuff.
Rym: so we'd make a lot of rockets there.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean that was pretty much it.
Scott: it was like, you know, and then once you're out of you know, I don't know a single person who did it on their own outside of a Official Regulated setting.
Rym: Yeah, I did a lot but it was never signed.
Rym: You just built him at home and said I build him at home And then I had all the equipment.
Rym: me and my brother would go to a park big football field or something And we'd launch him and lose him and they'd be the end of it.
Rym: All right, as they flew off over the horizon sometimes you see the parachute deploy and they'd catch a headwind and just Bye.
Rym: Bye.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, those are those are good days and you know, they're probably gone.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.