Rym: It's Wednesday, August 31st, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we review the last show to excite us in quite some time, Puella Magi Madoka Magica.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: We're back from PAX.
Rym: You can tell that our voices are a little off, but not to like of the older days.
Rym: I feel like we've leveled up the voices.
Scott: Have we really?
Rym: It's not like that one Otakon.
Rym: we were coughing up blood.
Rym: We couldn't even talk for like a day after the con.
Scott: You were the one who was coughing up blood.
Rym: You couldn't talk either.
Scott: I was just uncomfortable to talk.
Scott: I could've talked if I needed to.
Rym: You could not talk because I know you.
Rym: There were some discussions that were happening at the time.
Rym: where could you have said a word?
Rym: A word would have been said.
Scott: A word.
Rym: A word it is.
Scott: So there was a real fire near my work.
Scott: It wasn't that exciting.
Scott: Some of those garbage stores that just sell shit to tourists.
Scott: You know those, right?
Scott: They sell magnets for six bucks.
Rym: They basically sell garbage.
Scott: I love New York t-shirts and other trash, right?
Scott: A couple of them.
Scott: From the looks of the debris because I didn't see the fire happening I just walked past it and said, "Oh, a fire happened
Scott: here.".
Scott: It looked like they had some junky old Coca-Cola beverage refrigerator that had an electrical fire of some sort.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: So PAX, right?
Rym: PAX is awesome.
Rym: We'll talk about it some other time.
Rym: So any of you who are new listeners from PAX, welcome, but tonight is anime night.
Rym: And comics.
Rym: All that stuff.
Rym: So if you're looking for our PAX coverage it'll probably be next Tuesday.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I will gladly pay you on Tuesday.
Scott: For a PAX Sun.
Rym: Oh my god, the lucky thing is it's only six months till PAX.
Scott: Ah, thank god.
Scott: Hopefully there will be a third PAX and there will be even less time between PAXes.
Rym: So we're not going to talk about PAX tonight, but I do want to talk about the PAX-termath.
Rym: Because, you know, it's a weekend, I'm in Seattle, and we pretty much do nothing but eat incredibly dense, greasy, meaty food.
Scott: I kept it light by eating less meals but making all of them big.
Rym: Which is bad, because every time I go out to eat, all I would think, I'm like an animal.
Rym: I'm like, you know what?
Rym: I don't know when next there will be food in front of me, so I am going to gorge.
Scott: I didn't gorge, I thought I was full.
Scott: I didn't gorge.
Rym: But that was all well and good until we were going to the airport and we got to stand in security to get back on the plane to go back to New York.
Rym: Farted.
Rym: Kept farting.
Rym: They were silent.
Rym: To say that they were deadly was an understatement.
Rym: I think I killed eight people.
Scott: You were making jokes about who trailed the teams.
Rym: This is what I'm getting to, so we're in line, right?
Rym: And I fart.
Rym: And Emily just looks at me, and I look at her with the look of, yeah, it was me, and she starts laughing.
Rym: And then the people behind me walk into it, because the line was moving at quite a surprising pace.
Rym: It was just fast enough to where I think I maximized the number of people affected by my stinking cloud.
Rym: Maybe cloud kill at this point.
Scott: Cloud kill.
Rym: Coffee!
Rym: And I fart again.
Rym: We walk, and I fart again.
Rym: And I can hear people down the line making the noise of oof, they go like oof as they walked into it, like it hit them in the face.
Rym: So finally, I'm like, this is very reminiscent of the Trail of Tears.
Rym: And Emily lost it, and then everyone knew it was me.
Rym: I was very proud of that, and the worst thing is because I was thinking Trail of Tears, every time I farted, I started laughing.
Rym: It was like this vicious cycle.
Rym: So then we go to get on the plane, and as we're walking in, I turn to Emily, and I'm like, and now, the gas chamber.
Rym: That was the worst gas I've ever had.
Scott: Great.
Rym: So welcome to GeekNights, this is what we talk about.
Rym: Farts.
Scott: High class.
Scott: High class, high brow.
Rym: It's Wednesday, we got anime, we got manga, we got comics.
Scott: So, there's a new comic that came out somewhat recently, probably between the last Wednesday show and this one, that I saw on the ordering list, and I just wanted people to be aware that now, you can order this comic on the Amazon, as Jerry Holkin says.
Scott: And it will come and be delivered to your house, where you can read it for a very low price.
Scott: The comic is called Feynman.
Scott: It's a biography comic.
Rym: Surely you must be joking.
Scott: Richard Feynman, the famous person.
Scott: If you don't know who that is, what the fuck?
Scott: That's pretty much all there is to it.
Scott: Actually, you know, I saw that listed and I was like, okay, the premise on paper, that's awesome.
Scott: But in reality, I mean, is this really gonna be good?
Scott: You know, it could be terrible.
Scott: But, I was reassured because on the Amazon, there was a little video trailer for it, which had included music and showed you frames from the comic, and actually really sold me on it.
Scott: I was like, wow, not disappointed that I ordered that.
Scott: Didn't go wrong.
Rym: Alright.
Scott: Highly recommend.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: So, it was a Twitter thing, but it's comic related.
Rym: I'm gonna talk about this briefly because I just Googled it to figure out what the deal was.
Rym: I saw a bunch of people tweeting something about the blob.
Rym: ate the wasp.
Rym: And I'm like, what, you mean like?
Rym: nothing moves the blob?
Rym: And I guess the wasp is also a superhero.
Scott: Yeah, that could have been a Marvel Comics thing, right?
Rym: And it was people tweeting who know about comics.
Rym: I figured this is what they're tweeting about.
Rym: And then, one of them's like, yeah, Loeb something something.
Rym: I'm like, alright, this has got to be.
Scott: Jeff Loeb is a comic writer.
Rym: So, I was like, did the blob eat the wasp?
Rym: And who's the wasp?
Rym: I look up and the wasp.
Scott: The wasp is an Avenger.
Scott: She's very tiny.
Rym: And apparently, the blob ate her.
Scott: Alrighty.
Rym: And I Googled it and there it is.
Rym: Apparently famous as being one of the worst pages in any mainstream superhero comic ever.
Scott: Is she like still flying around inside of him?
Rym: No, he's like tearing her guts open and like eating her.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: When did this happen?
Rym: There's another picture.
Rym: I don't know if this is canon or not, but it's Hank Pym eating the blob maybe in revenge.
Rym: I can't quite tell.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know what the deal is, but I had to Google it because too many people were tweeting about it.
Rym: I was like, what?
Rym: Really?
Rym: The blob?
Rym: You know, all the moves him?
Scott: All the underwear perfect comics are just getting crazy.
Scott: Go nuts.
Scott: Lately going off the deep end, like the X men have like some kind of crazy schism thing going on.
Scott: We're like uncanny X men is actually going to be a final issue.
Scott: And then that's it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Just like how they all die.
Scott: And it's like, yeah, no, but like they're not going to not going to be, you know, it's uncanny X men issue, whatever, 500 something.
Scott: And then there isn't going to be whatever.
Scott: that is plus one.
Scott: The unholy X men, right?
Scott: No, I mean, like, let's pretend the number is like 599.
Scott: There isn't going to be 600.
Scott: It's over.
Rym: That almost doesn't mean anything.
Scott: I know.
Scott: And then it does, if you're some crazy collecting, you know, nut job, like they sell to.
Scott: And there's going to basically the X men, they had a big fight.
Scott: It's like an X men fighting with themselves.
Scott: The Wolverine side and the Cyclops side.
Scott: It's like, well, Iceman's on the Wolverine side.
Scott: You know, it's that kind of bullshit.
Scott: It's like, OK.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, didn't they do that?
Rym: Like, didn't Captain America have some stuff like that?
Scott: That was the Avengers.
Scott: They're basically doing the same thing with the X.
Rym: Probably because that seemed to be pretty popular.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: It's getting crazy.
Scott: But at least DC is doing the reset thing, which that might just be crazy and stupid, too.
Scott: But we'll check it out at the end of this month.
Scott: We're going to get a holding box of comments.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm looking forward to that.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: I kind of am a little bit.
Scott: A little bit.
Scott: Just to see its curiosity more than expectation of high quality.
Rym: I pretty much just want all the Batman's.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Batman.
Rym: Well, I think it's Batman's is what I'm going to say from now on.
Rym: Batsmen.
Scott: That's so the first.
Scott: the first one of those number ones actually just came out this morning, I guess last night at midnight.
Scott: And the Jeff Johns, who I hate, and Jim Lee, who's all right, who did the Justice League.
Scott: They were at the Midtown Comics with a huge line of people and everything.
Rym: So so I do not have a news, nor do I have a geek bite, as is often my cop out.
Rym: I'm going to do something that I don't think we've said this word on the show in over a year.
Rym: I have a geek back shit.
Rym: I got an email from 12 days ago from Jarvis.
Scott: What did Jarvis say?
Rym: Jarvis said.
Rym: And I bring this up partly because I've received many other emails on the same topic topic.
Rym: I don't remember saying anything about this show, but I must have because people wouldn't all be bothering us about this randomly.
Rym: So to quote Jarvis, I finished listening to the Anime We Want to See podcast.
Rym: I guess that's the one a few days ago.
Rym: I'm really hoping you guys come through with what you said about putting together a show on Gossa Rocky.
Scott: Oh, snap.
Rym: I'm not the biggest super fan of the show.
Rym: Who is?
Rym: But I did finish the whole thing.
Rym: Bravo.
Rym: Good, sir.
Rym: Good job.
Rym: You win maybe two years ago and it was well worth the time.
Rym: I even bought and built some of the model kits.
Rym: Whoa, man.
Rym: They're good models, actually.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, if you get a big model stick with the Gundams do.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The band I put out maybe like battle textile as far out the farthest I'll go is maybe Matt Cross.
Rym: I'm not going to read the rest because he asks me a question.
Rym: that's kind of a spoiler.
Rym: And it's the kind of show where I don't want to spoil this.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But for people who don't know, there's an anime called Gossa Rocky.
Scott: It's your dog.
Rym: I like Gossa Rocky, but it is one of the more boring things you will ever see.
Scott: It's a really slow, boring like business and military show that has some fantasy and some robot.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The way I would describe Gossa Rocky is imagine a world where there are mechs but the mechs are literally just tanks.
Scott: Yeah, they work just like tanks only they happen to have legs.
Rym: Simultaneously, imagine an anime that treats the way tanks work the way tanks work.
Rym: And the people driving the tanks are talking the way that real people who are driving tanks are going to talk to each other and there's no time compression.
Scott: Or at least convincingly so.
Rym: Yeah, in the ineffect that it's just like move four clicks to the north.
Rym: Affirmative that.
Rym: Moving four clicks to the north.
Rym: Click.
Rym: We are engaging hostiles.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it is so boring.
Rym: I cannot express this to you.
Scott: But I like it.
Scott: It's a good show.
Rym: I really like it anyway because it's boring and procedural but it's a show that builds and builds.
Rym: Basically the entire show is set up for three scenes at the end of the show.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: And you'll know if you like this show.
Rym: I highly recommend at least watching it until something happens where a mech is hanging on a wire out the back of a plane shooting its stuff.
Scott: That was a great scene.
Rym: Or when a dude gets backed over by a jeep.
Rym: Those two scenes, if you notice those scenes and you enjoy them, you should watch the entire show.
Rym: Now it also has an ancient mystery and it also has the cliche that we've been talking about a lot lately because both Madoka and Trigun had this.
Rym: An episode that we like to call "Suddenly in
Rym: Space."
Rym: Meaning you turn on the episode, you know like somewhere in the middle of the show and you stop it a few minutes in because you think you've got the wrong show.
Rym: Like you opened the wrong file.
Rym: Maybe the DVD's messed up.
Rym: Kind of like in "Innocence" where I was in the theater and I was convinced that the digital copy they were showing us was messed up and was looping.
Rym: And then I was like "Oh no, it's just
Rym: Oshii.".
Rym: Now, I keep saying boring.
Rym: You gotta trust me guys.
Rym: You might like this show.
Rym: It's super good.
Rym: Way good.
Rym: But, let's see what's a good example?
Scott: The thing is it's way good for the people who like it.
Scott: There's a lot of people who won't like it.
Scott: Most people.
Rym: Like if you like say "Skycrawlers" like the slow Oshii style.
Rym: you know, it's slow and boring because that's part of the message and you're cool with an hour and forty minutes of very little happening punctuated by action scenes, you're gonna dig this.
Rym: It's got a similar kind of message too.
Rym: It's even gotta be shown in it.
Scott: Remember him?
Scott: I guess.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: He pretty much is.
Scott: He's got a good mystery.
Scott: We actually watched the show.
Scott: I bought the whole show on VHS.
Scott: We watched it all dubbed a long time ago.
Scott: We don't have VCRs anymore really.
Rym: The dub averages out to a C but that's basically a B dub with one line that brought it down to a C average.
Rym: That's the worst line in any anime ever.
Scott: I bought the dub on VHS because it was cheaper in those days.
Scott: I didn't have a DVD player in those days.
Scott: Now you can get it on DVD probably cheap but I don't think it's in print anymore.
Scott: so you're gonna have to dig it up.
Rym: The main reason I say to watch it, I guess it's turned into a geek bite now.
Rym: I did a geek back that turned into a geek bite.
Rym: Like what happens here.
Scott: Double power.
Rym: We're really like it's anime season again so there's gonna be a lot of anime reviews coming down the pipe.
Rym: So I'm just gonna tell you right now to watch Gasaraki and then we'll watch it at some point soon.
Rym: We'll probably do a show or two on it.
Scott: Probably.
Rym: Because lately it's anime.
Rym: Maybe it's because PAX is done and all the games I want to play that I saw at PAX I cannot play yet.
Rym: So I'm gonna watch anime until Aramac and Monaco and Spy Party are in my house.
Rym: And then I'm pretty much gonna play those games.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: Counter Strike Go.
Rym: Yup yup.
Scott: Tribes Ascend.
Rym: The best part is I traded a pretty crap ass board game for a box set.
Scott: You traded the number one board game on BoardGameGeek.
Rym: Yeah you know what the number one board game on BoardGameGeek kinda sucks.
Scott: For like 75, 80 bucks you paid for it.
Rym: That was one of the biggest mistakes I ever made was buying that game.
Scott: You realize the price of it now is like 100 plus.
Rym: Don't even care.
Rym: I just don't want it.
Scott: And you traded it for an anime.
Scott: you probably could have got used for a lot less.
Rym: I just wanted to get rid of Twilight Struggle.
Rym: Fuck that game.
Rym: And dude who got it from me you're gonna play it and you're gonna be like oh.
Scott: Maybe he'll like it.
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: Apparently a lot of people do.
Rym: I know but who are these people?
Scott: It's not a good game.
Scott: Balls guys.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: Usually Scott sees things like this before I do.
Rym: Somehow I saw this one first.
Scott: We really like it.
Scott: You were just having to read more internets today.
Rym: We really like it when people make stylized posters in an old style or a neat style about something that is not traditionally in that style.
Rym: I think the poster child for this is that awesome X-Men poster.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So this is that and it's also kind of like those posters.
Scott: See the thing I don't understand right.
Scott: You always see this style of poster.
Scott: Why doesn't anyone use this style for like a video game or a whole movie or something like that.
Rym: Why don't we make turn flicked in this style.
Scott: Let's do it.
Scott: Done.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: Now we have to make turn flicked.
Scott: We're working on it.
Rym: I haven't worked on it in like three months.
Scott: That's alright.
Rym: In fact I still have it's.
Rym: on my desk is a piece of paper where I sketched out four maps and I wrote down the numbers for five kinds of units.
Rym: I have not even typed that into a computer yet.
Scott: Yeah it's fine.
Rym: Anyway so these are travel posters for historic planet Zeebs.
Scott: Let's travel to planet Zeebs.
Rym: They're pretty great.
Scott: What a great place to visit.
Scott: You know what.
Rym: You know what.
Scott: Tons of horrible creatures that want to rip your face off.
Rym: I point out this might be horrible acid everywhere.
Rym: Maybe this is from an era before the planet sucked because I mean the Chozo were there was kind of awesome wasn't it?
Scott: Oh did you want to go there when the Chozo were still there?
Rym: Or maybe.
Rym: Maybe like the Chozo fell.
Rym: Maybe it was nice for a while and then eventually it went to shit.
Rym: Maybe the space pirates made it go to shit.
Rym: Maybe after Sam has fixed everything it's nice again.
Rym: We don't know.
Rym: I mean it was kind of empty when Sam has went back in Super Metroid.
Scott: Except for these space pirates living there.
Rym: Just space pirates.
Rym: There weren't that much else going on.
Scott: Metroids.
Scott: Horribly dangerous flora and fauna.
Rym: Not that bad.
Scott: It doesn't get much more dangerous in terms of the flora and fauna danger department.
Rym: I guess my perspective is skewed because every time I visited it has been through the most badass woman to have ever not lived.
Scott: You've never visited the West Indies.
Rym: You've never been to the West Indies.
Rym: Kids you win a point if you know what we're referencing there.
Rym: So what do you got for me Scott?
Scott: Why don't we do a show on the thing you were referencing on a Thursday?
Rym: We had to have done a show on that.
Scott: We'll check it.
Rym: I will check while you do your thing of the day.
Scott: You'll have to rewatch.
Scott: Don't you have it?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I have two DVD box sets of the thing to which we referred a moment ago.
Scott: If you haven't done the show, let's watch an episode after the show is done.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: And then you want to drink some laudanum?
Rym: No.
Rym: You have a party?
Rym: Maudanum party?
Scott: No.
Scott: Thing of the day, right?
Scott: So for those of you who are aware Hatsune Miku was made using a technology known as Vocaloid 2.
Scott: And Hatsune Miku sounds pretty good depending on the person orchestrating her.
Scott: I guess would be the verb.
Rym: That sounds a little bit kinky.
Scott: Yeah, depending on how much...
Rym: Scott, we did a show on this on June 7th, 2007.
Scott: Shit.
Scott: Here's the news.
Rym: You did something from Fark.
Rym: I don't know what.
Rym: I'm going to click on it now.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: And I said that fidgeting is good for people.
Rym: Your thing of the day was the Jill Jet.
Scott: Jill Jet.
Rym: And my thing of the day was Chairbot, which is basically hedonism bot the cosplay.
Scott: Alright, so what was my news from Fark?
Rym: Your news was something from the Daily Mail that no longer exists.
Rym: Great.
Rym: Nope, that's mine about fidgeting.
Rym: Yours was a man was in a wheelchair and got hit by a semi truck.
Scott: What?
Scott: That was your news.
Scott: There had to be something more to it.
Scott: Hot to go listen to this episode.
Rym: I'm loading this old news article.
Rym: Oh, a man was hit by a truck in his wheelchair.
Rym: It did not kill him or hurt him in any way.
Rym: The truck pushed him for two miles at over 50 miles an hour.
Rym: Okay, okay.
Scott: Alright, so Hatsune Miku has made a Vocaloid too.
Rym: You know what town this happened in?
Rym: Pawpaw.
Scott: So, Hatsune Miku has made a Vocaloid too and depending on who, you know, if some amateur just opens up Hatsune Miku and tries to make her sing it sounds like a robot.
Scott: But if a professional does it and spends a lot of time on it.
Scott: it can often sound very close to a real person.
Scott: But even if you listen closely you can tell that it's not a real person.
Scott: At best, it's a person with extremely heavy autotune, right?
Scott: There has been a leaked audio file from someone who in Korea, they're working on a different company not Krypton Future Media who makes Hatsune Miku.
Scott: But this other company in Korea is making a new voice using Vocaloid 3.
Scott: Oh shit son.
Scott: And this leaked audio was put on the internets and it sounds like a person with a very light autotune.
Rym: The next step after this.
Scott: This is still in development, first of all.
Scott: And second of all, if that did they put the full effort of a professional into it?
Scott: Like if the best Vocaloid users on earth use this, it's probably going to sound like a person with very very little autotunes on them.
Rym: Vocaloid 4 is one step away from Super Matt Cross.
Scott: Vocaloid 4 is probably going to be in the uncanny valley deep into it and Vocaloid 5 is probably going to sound like a real person.
Scott: So I predict, what year is it?
Scott: 2011? 2012?
Scott: So 2022?
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: 2011? 2012?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: you have to estimate what year it is?
Scott: It's pretty close to 2012.
Rym: It's August!
Scott: Right, so in 2021 or 2028 you're probably going to have Vocaloid 5 and Vocaloid 5 is going to sound like a real person and you won't be able to tell.
Rym: Vocaloid 6 is going to take over the world.
Scott: Vocaloid 6, you won't have to even type anything in.
Scott: it'll just sing songs.
Scott: You turn it on.
Scott: But yeah this is pretty impressive.
Scott: You should listen to this.
Scott: This is not a person singing every last.
Scott: what was it?
Scott: We will not have a vocal cord left in the singing of these internal machines.
Rym: So for a while now I've known about the show Puella Magi, Madoka, Magica you know, the weird title.
Rym: I always just called it Puella.
Scott: Yeah, well you know it's one of those situations where you're on the internets and you know sometimes there's like a thread that explodes about something and it's like you just notice it and you're like wow there's a pony thread over there.
Scott: I guess there's a thing called ponies and it's pretty popular.
Scott: Let me go see what the deal is.
Scott: So there was a Madoka Magica thread and I knew that there was a relatively new anime called Madoka Magica.
Scott: I didn't know anything else about it other than it was magical girly and it was getting and the people were talking about it.
Scott: so I was like yeah.
Rym: I had a little more going for me ahead of time because one, I knew it was done by Shaft.
Scott: All right.
Rym: You know they did Wreck which we also kind of liked.
Rym: And Arakawa under the Bridgie and Arakawa under the Bridgie-Bridgie.
Scott: You love the Bridgie-Bridgie.
Rym: I do love the Bridgie-Bridgie.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: But also Nate had been telling me forever like from the moment it was out he was like this show is up your alley and the way he sold it to me was he was like it's Utena Eva with music by Yuki Kajira.
Scott: Yeah so I asked Emily, I was like what's the deal with that show?
Scott: and she's like.
Scott: it's like magical girls but it's serious and dark and I was like all right whatever.
Scott: so I started watching it.
Scott: you know people and I I realized what made me watch it.
Scott: you know people talked about it.
Scott: I needed a show to watch.
Scott: I checked it out.
Scott: it was only 12 episodes.
Scott: I'm like oh even if this is awful I can watch 12 episodes.
Rym: That's like two afternoons.
Scott: Right and I need to do a GeekNights show about something on a Wednesday.
Rym: Now it is very telling Scott that usually when there's a new show like this that isn't a million episodes you'll start watching it.
Rym: you'll say like hey I'm watching X and then like a month later you'll be like yeah I finished it you should watch it you should be doing a show on it.
Rym: You came to me like right away you're like watch this god damn show.
Scott: Yeah well as soon as I started watching it on a night and I watched five episodes and then the next day I watched seven and by noon I had watched the whole show because it's 12 episodes.
Rym: It's been a long time since Scott's been excited about an anime.
Rym: Never mind it's been a long time since I've been excited enough about anime to where I start watching it and I can't stop.
Scott: That happens sometimes.
Rym: I mean the last show that did that to me that wasn't My Little Pony was watching Ghost in the Shell Stand Alone Complex.
Scott: So I did it somewhat recently.
Rym: Bocorato did it to me.
Rym: Eva, Eska, Trigun, Bebop.
Scott: And trying to think of times I couldn't stop.
Scott: I mean there'd be times like watching Okotenu Ken.
Scott: right so you just keep watching but there's a zillion episodes so you only watch like five at a time or something like that.
Scott: You know you don't just keep going and going without stopping because you can't.
Scott: You'll die.
Rym: Yeah but some shows like Bebop, if you've never seen it before you've just got to see the next episode.
Scott: Yeah even if you've seen Kawi Bebop before you start watching, you just can't stop watching.
Scott: You go straight to the end.
Scott: So what is Madoka Magica?
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: There's magical girls in the real world.
Scott: It's sort of actually a futuristic world right?
Scott: It's like everything.
Rym: Yeah I think 20, 40 years into our future pretty realistically.
Scott: Everything is somewhat higher tech than the things we have in the world today.
Rym: I kind of like that.
Rym: It was a nice touch.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So you know this girl is in school and her name is Madoka and one day this transfer student shows up at the school.
Rym: Wow this is pretty stereotypical sounding so far isn't it?
Scott: She runs out of her house to go to school with a piece of toast in her mouth.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: but she finishes the toast.
Rym: I've never seen that happen.
Scott: Yeah she ate the whole toast.
Rym: Usually the toast is it causes like a gravitational field that causes a boy to be in front of her.
Rym: They'll bump into each other and it goes flying.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know and it's typical.
Scott: you know at least on the surface level.
Scott: you know high school magical girl stuff.
Scott: but at the very beginning of the show the opening scene is that typical anime trick where they show you some crazy action scene of something else and then after the opener it's happy school and they somehow tie in that thing.
Scott: that happened before the opener of the first episode is like a glimpse of the real plot later.
Rym: Well like remember When They Cry?
Scott: I didn't really watch it.
Rym: Before the credits it was the savage beating to death of someone with a baseball bat and then it was Moe School for like 23 minutes.
Scott: So it's you know.
Scott: and that's the thing about Madoka I don't want.
Scott: you know it's only 12 episodes.
Scott: you can pretty much spoil the whole thing by saying anything.
Rym: Well but here's the deal.
Rym: so Madoka she's cute girl typical.
Rym: everything's stereotypical.
Rym: the transfer student all mysterious and badass and she takes her aside.
Rym: and actually Homura the transfer student has a lot of really good lines in this show like she has good delivery of things in it but she kind of takes Madoka aside.
Rym: she's like I need you to show me to the nurses office.
Rym: and she's like do you value your life?
Rym: do you value the things in your life and she's like yes and then Homura's like well then you don't need to be anyone else do you?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: She's obviously from the start being like look you know that it's a magical girl show.
Scott: Madoka's name is in the show.
Scott: you see her as a magical girl in the opener which isn't anything like the show at all.
Scott: you know that.
Scott: you know.
Scott: you're thinking she's gonna become a magical girl and the first thing that happens is this mysterious girl who was magical in the opening before the opener.
Scott: right who's now the transfer student is like don't become a magical girl.
Rym: pretty much yep especially because in the opener once like Madoka is clearly a magical girl.
Scott: so within the first couple minutes they've set up the conflict already.
Scott: Madoka had a dream about this magical girl.
Scott: the girl who looks just like the magical girl appears at school as a transfer student and it tells Madoka not to become a magical girl.
Scott: and pretty much you know she's the main character.
Scott: so she's got to become one.
Rym: and right after that I mean things conspire and there's this cute mascot Q-Bay who's kind of like Luna and Dung Beetle and all those cute things kind of mixed together into one.
Scott: yeah he's the same thing as Dung Beetle from Bocorano.
Scott: basically he's the alien who tries to.
Scott: you know has it's like?
Scott: there's all these different sorts of.
Scott: you know Madoka's combined all these different things right.
Scott: a lot of the show has the mood of Eva right where you know you'll have shots of.
Scott: you know weird things or like shots where the characters are off camera while sort of an eerie music plays and people talk.
Scott: or you know a quiet scene of an empty street with cicadas chirping right a lot of the Eva kind of stuff and the same.
Scott: and that's the mood you'll have through a lot of the show.
Rym: but like the backgrounds and the like the stark silhouette landscapes are so utenna it's ridiculous.
Scott: yeah also you'll have you know how Battle Royale or Bocorano or a lot of those or Nine People Nine Doors Nine Hours whatever Death Note, Monster even Death Note, Monster not really.
Scott: but you know all these shows that have a premise where all the conflict Bocorano centers around a set of rules like they set up.
Scott: you know in some sci-fi or fantasy reason for a set of rules like these are the rules of the Death Note.
Scott: this is the rules of the Battle Royale while Madoka there's these set of rules about magical girls that are set up that create conflict because
Rym: if you pull back a little bit there aren't that many rules that come into play in this show and they're very rarely stated as like in Death Note like rule number eight blah blah blah.
Scott: they're not stated so strictly like they are in the other rules shows.
Rym: it's more that the mystery of the show is what the rules are or like in Monster the mystery is kind of like what is the monster after and what made him and why is he doing this to all those kids?
Scott: yeah and also right the show also has the Trigun going on.
Scott: if you don't if you've never seen Trigun I'm not going to spoil that either but it's also a Gasaraki same show does the same thing we call it now.
Rym: I think Scott coined the term suddenly in space right.
Scott: so in Trigun episode 17 I'm not going to tell you what happens but basically suddenly right.
Scott: the episode 16 ends.
Scott: episode 17 does not pick up where 16 left off.
Scott: in fact you might think did I put in the wrong DVD right because it doesn't look like Trigun even though you just saw a Trigun opener?
Rym: uh Gasaraki did the same thing episode.
Rym: I think it's 12 or 13. it's like what this isn't Gasaraki?
Rym: did they fuck up.
Scott: but it is you know they.
Scott: just suddenly there's an episode at the very beginning of the episode.
Scott: you're in the past and you're seeing.
Scott: you're basically having the secrets of the show answered for you and episode 10 out of 12 of Madoka is just like that.
Scott: it doesn't pick up where 9 left off it just starts at some other point in some other place and teaches you all the secrets of the show and blows your brains out.
Rym: now very rarely if I had an episode of it I've had shows that have oh shit moments where like oh shit Akio something oh shit you know some sort of like.
Scott: yeah but the thing is those more typically right come towards the end of an episode.
Scott: it's like an episode will pick up where the last one went off build up and then something crazy will happen at some sort of climax.
Rym: more importantly there will only be one oh shit in an episode.
Scott: right it's a totally different technique to start an episode like what is going on oh shit.
Scott: and then the whole episode is like crazy.
Scott: and the thing is Scott hyped it up because he watched the show and I was like I hyped it up because I couldn't help myself but then I was like Rym did I overhype it?
Rym: oh my god.
Rym: so literally 5 seconds into that episode 10 all of us are like oh shit and then we oh shit again and then again and again and it like and as soon as I'm like okay I see what's going on.
Rym: there was another oh shit that just blew everything out of the water like.
Rym: I cannot express to you it was a similar feeling.
Rym: the last time an anime made me feel that way was that one episode of Utena with the the car and Anthony holding the candles and they're going out one by one and then you see somebody in the background.
Rym: that was the last time I had even close to that.
Rym: much oh shit in an episode of an anime.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I've had that a bunch of times but it hasn't been in a while because it hasn't been a good show in a while.
Scott: and I think the thing about this show I think the key is that it's 12 episodes right.
Scott: so every episode is the episode where X happens.
Scott: you know each episode is big.
Scott: there's no meaningless episodes.
Scott: there's no slow parts there's.
Scott: no.
Scott: you know everything that happens.
Scott: you know it's very economical with its scenes and everything is meaningful.
Scott: you're always in the heat of it and then before it drags on it ends.
Scott: it's like Gonzo shows.
Scott: if all the Gonzo shows like say Last Exile.
Scott: Last Exile started just about as strong as Madoka started but it had 26 episodes and it sort of dragged a bit.
Scott: I'm watching number 6 right now started pretty strong but dragged.
Scott: Eden of the East so I don't know.
Scott: I don't think that was as long but it you know it still.
Rym: it wasn't that it dragged.
Scott: is that it introduced characters I didn't care about right and or know why they were there or anything.
Scott: but you know Madoka perfect 12 episodes.
Scott: we're ending it.
Scott: period done.
Rym: also it's very important to note that Madoka has a real ending.
Scott: yeah it's not like say shows like scrap princess.
Rym: lets reveal the whole plot at the end out of nowhere.
Rym: or let's see Bokerano has a real ending too or a candidate for goddess.
Scott: right that show was one that was clearly was.
Scott: they were intending to go more than 13 episodes but they got cut to 13 and you could see the 13th episode was sort of like oh shit we weren't planning to end it right now but we have to.
Scott: so like Eden of the East had a stupid ending yeah but Madoka they knew they were going to end it at 12 episodes well in advance and they did so.
Scott: so they brought it to the ending with the exact right pacing.
Scott: it wasn't rushed it wasn't slow it was perfect.
Rym: and the thing is the show like as you're going on and more oh shits are happening.
Rym: you're like you're learning things about this universe like what is a magical girl?
Rym: what is Cubase contract?
Rym: what does all this really mean?
Rym: who is Homura?
Rym: why is she the way she is?
Rym: how does she know all this?
Scott: why is everyone the way they are?
Rym: and it gets to a point around episode 8 8 and a half where there is no conclusion you can make but that everybody's fucked in a way that is almost unimaginably depressing.
Rym: yeah like as an intelligent person you're like there is no way out of this and the way the show ends is pretty fantastic.
Scott: yeah it's pretty.
Scott: it's one of those you know.
Scott: sometimes you'll be watching something and you'll be like just do this.
Rym: just do this Scott it's we have to call this the guns moment when Neo is like guns.
Scott: exactly you're like just do this and then you get really happy because in the show they actually end up doing something pretty similar to what you were hoping someone would do right.
Scott: yeah like I was thinking the whole time just do this and in the end they did something sort of close.
Rym: they kind of was beyond what I thought I would be like.
Rym: do X. they were like do X times 10.
Scott: yeah it definitely was not exactly what I was thinking but it worked out you know in the same sort of way.
Rym: it's also very worth mentioning that the show has fantastic music but it has a very limited repertoire of songs that are used almost like leitmotifs.
Rym: there's like the action.
Rym: stuff is happening.
Rym: song.
Rym: there is the variation on that for you're learning stuff about the universe.
Rym: there is the ominous.
Rym: you're learning stuff about the universe or is more questions.
Rym: song.
Rym: there is the happy.
Rym: we are doing stuff.
Rym: song.
Scott: well actually if you pay attention right there's pretty much each of the girls has.
Scott: everyone has a theme song Scott that's called a leitmotif character.
Scott: right it's a leitmotif but most of the other songs are just variations of the opener or the closer.
Scott: and the opener and the closer are great like.
Scott: they're super awesome.
Rym: they're reminiscent of good old anime.
Rym: yeah actually the opener song really reminds me of the song from the remake of bird of the mighty.
Scott: yeah the thing about the opener is like.
Scott: I don't know if it's the greatest song but I really like it and it gives me sort of this nostalgic feeling.
Scott: it feels like an older anime song.
Rym: well what's funny?
Scott: because you know it brings me back to like the 90s we're hanging out with.
Rym: and it's funny.
Rym: Scott has seen all of Madoka twice and I've seen it 1.7 times because our friend Nuri came.
Rym: we showed a bunch of our friends the first three episodes and she just stuck around instead of going home the next day to watch all the rest of the show up to episode 9. so me her and Emily could then finish it and then you know she couldn't.
Rym: she got to 9. she's like oh shit I can't watch more can I?
Rym: and I'm like hells.
Rym: no you can't.
Scott: well you could've just.
Rym: no no no she couldn't.
Rym: so she was like.
Rym: well what do I watch now?
Rym: something less hardcore.
Rym: so I was like mahotsukaita.
Rym: but seriously this is the first time in history I have seen a show with music by Yuki Kajira where the show wasn't shit.
Scott: yeah I mean she's done actually in my opinion the hak-san music and the noir music.
Scott: I like those musics actually better than the Madoka music.
Scott: not that the Madoka music is that much worse.
Scott: it's a step under mostly because there's less of it.
Rym: those were longer shows with arguably more complex plots though not better plots.
Rym: like there's more stuff going on.
Scott: and also it's just that I tend to judge music not based on any sort of measure of musical quality because I don't know anything about music or music theory.
Scott: but it's like I like a song more if it gets stuck in my head even though you usually get annoyed when a song gets stuck in your head.
Rym: I had the closing song to Madoka stuck in my head.
Scott: the opening and closings of Madoka definitely had head stickage.
Rym: but the other songs I had Mami's "I am awesome and happy doing awesome stuff" song.
Scott: that's definitely the third best song.
Scott: but the other music I can't really recall it.
Rym: think about "Head Sign".
Rym: the only songs you remember are the "Key of the Twilight" song that opening the world song yup and maybe the "Ara" song which is the sad girl singing about sad people.
Scott: I remember songs.
Scott: not only do I remember the opening and closing songs but also multiples of the non opening and closing songs.
Rym: granted Scott you were the one who with a straight face said that Giant Robo's music was uninspired and unmemorable.
Scott: I don't remember a single song from Giant Robo.
Rym: I think Giant Robo had one of the stronger anime soundtracks.
Scott: I don't remember a single song from it at all.
Scott: if you played me the Giant Robo soundtrack and another similar soundtrack I probably would just be one out of two guesses to figure out which one's Giant Robo and which one's not.
Rym: so here's the deal.
Rym: back in the day, "Head Sign" the first episode.
Rym: that in of itself I was like this is some A material right here.
Scott: like it had everything cool but then nothing happened between episodes 5 and 13.
Rym: ah but pretend those didn't exist.
Rym: it had the awesome Yuki Kajiro music and the awesome hook.
Rym: that music alone tricked me into watching that show all the way to episode 13 before I realized it was shit and nothing else had happened.
Rym: same thing with "Head Sign" and "Noir" which was almost as bad as "Head Sign" just because the music made me think and the first episode combined made me think.
Scott: I think "Noir" was better than "Head Sign".
Rym: it was, but it was still bad, I got to the end and I regretted watching it.
Scott: yeah the later parts of the show really jumped off the shark.
Rym: there I mean the first episode had.
Scott: it was a guy jumping off a cliff and as he fell down the cliff he passed by a bunch of sharks also falling off the cliff.
Rym: but how come?
Rym: that's the same show that had the Yuki Kajiro music and it had the dude strangled with his own tie silhouetted off of a staircase.
Rym: yeah, everyone remembers that scene in that show is just like the guy hitting the propeller in "Titanic".
Scott: oh shit.
Rym: so you've got that high quality really intense Yuki Kajiro music in a good show.
Rym: the show is good and the music is good.
Scott: yup what else is good about the show?
Scott: the animation is actually just pretty normal modern animation, but there's some things about it.
Scott: number one is the magical girls fight.
Scott: bad guys these witches, obviously the magical girls.
Scott: they're gonna fight something.
Scott: the witches are some EVA pop art material so the witches are all in these reality spheres.
Scott: this isn't a spoiler whatever you want to call it, but basically whenever they fight the witches they sort of go to this other world to fight them and the other world has this crazy art style that's different for every witch and is nothing like anime style.
Rym: so you see the anime characters one of the witches they fight pretty early on is basically a Murakami super flat worm dragon unicorn bot.
Scott: so it's really awesome.
Scott: just to see what kind of crazy art is gonna be going on in the witches' reality marvel.
Rym: you'll never see mustaches so sinister ever again.
Scott: it's crazy awesome, I love it whenever a witch comes, it's like a feast for the eyes to see what's going on with all the details in the background and all the other weird characters coming out.
Rym: it's also a minor point, but the show is really colorful and it has.
Scott: sometimes it's really colorful and sometimes it's not.
Rym: but it has really cute young characters, but they're not moe, there's like no fan service at all, zero.
Scott: it's like the characters could be if you use them easily moe perverted characters.
Scott: but there's never any up skirts or boob shots, you know, the opener has a second of it.
Rym: I don't want to talk about things to say about the opener that are kind of spoilers.
Scott: yeah, the opener is nothing like the show.
Scott: that's all you gotta know, but the thing is there's never any fan service or any porn or anything like that in the show ever, right?
Scott: They're just magical girls, their magical girl costumes are not revealing or porny at all you know, it's just straight up.
Rym: but also they never go super deformed.
Rym: it doesn't really do any wacky anime stuff, it's actually a very tight and crisp looking show.
Scott: the only thing though is that sometimes they do this trick where they're drawn in a very digital clean modern way but their faces will sort of be sort of sketchy and pastel colored pencil manga-ish, so it's like you have a completely normal character, but like their eyes will be sort of scratchy.
Rym: I really like the eyes, all the eyes almost look like they're out of a colored manga.
Rym: it's neat, the eyes stood out and I really like that style of eye.
Scott: it's pretty clever.
Rym: so who should watch the show?
Rym: I'm gonna tell you straight up it's very rare, it's been a long time since I have unhesitatingly called a show an A anime.
Scott: the thing is, I also call it an A anime but I don't call it an A+ anime.
Rym: well A+ is different, A+ has the combination of universal appeal brilliant both from like the fanboy perspective and from the like, just art perspective.
Rym: yeah, it's not Kawaii Bebop, it's not a Miyazaki movie, it's not Matt Cross TV, you know but it holds its own next to Escaflowne, next to Trigun, it pumped me up similarly to the way Kawaii Bebop pumped me up.
Scott: I call it Exactly Equal with Big O which is great.
Scott: it's Exactly Equal with Big O which also had 13 episodes in its first season.
Scott: it did, but I've actually heard a rumor of a Madoka's second season not really a second season but a you know, another show where you take the characters and it's just happy school time the whole time.
Rym: I know leave it alone, you know what that would be like?
Rym: that would be like if you had Cowgirl Ed and Ayn's adventures.
Scott: well, didn't we want that?
Rym: no, I wanted that, but I didn't really want it.
Scott: right, exactly, I think it's one of those situations where because it was 12 episodes right, you know, usually most of these shows follow a path where it's happy school time and then later on the darkness.
Scott: this show is the darkness from before.
Scott: in the first one second is the darkness.
Rym: it's like episode 1, you really want to be a magical girl?
Rym: episode 2, here's what it's really like, episode 3, off the deep end and you still got a bunch more episodes.
Scott: 9, 9 episodes.
Rym: but
Scott: other shows start off with a lot more school a lot more getting to know the characters a lot more side characters that are humorous that fade away and aren't in the show later on stuff like that, and this show didn't have any of that because it only had 12 episodes and I think because it was popular they want to go back to
Rym: it.
Rym: yet it lulls you into a sense of complacency because after alright, it's magical girls, let's go you really expect them to be just fighting witches and it presents itself like alright, they're going to fight this witch and then no that's not what happens.
Scott: you don't know what's going to happen, it's crazy awesome.
Rym: so who should watch the show?
Scott: like we said, everyone, the reason I say you've never watched an anime in your life ever, and you're not a big if you're a big nerd.
Scott: you've never watched an anime before.
Scott: this might actually be a good thing to watch because if I had watched this when I was in high school since I was a nerd, I would have been blown away by it.
Rym: Yeah, when I was in fourth grade and I saw Vampire Hunter D and I was blown away by it this would have blown me away the same way
Scott: but I might not have fully understood it and would have had to come back later with more anime knowledge much
Rym: like when I saw the first Tenchi movie.
Rym: I had no idea what was going on.
Scott: Clearly if you're already an anime fan, just watch it.
Scott: even if you don't like it, it's only 12 episodes, just do it right?
Scott: and you know, the only people who really shouldn't, probably should avoid it, are people who aren't anime fans yet and also aren't nerds.
Scott: They need to come into anime, you know, like the Kaveh Bebop Road and the Miyazaki Road Unless they're one of those people who remembers like, "Oh, as a kid I watched Sailor Moon".
Rym: you just tell them, "This is Sailor Moon for grown-ups".
Scott: Maybe, it might work, it might not.
Rym: I think it would work, because the show doesn't have all that build-up, it gets right into the thick of it, so you're pretty much.
Rym: it only takes a few minutes to get hooked in and I can't think of many people who, once they start watching it would at least not want to know what happens.
Scott: I've also seen so I've seen some people on the internet complaining they don't like the ending.
Scott: You're wrong.
Scott: They can all shut up.
Scott: They're probably the same people who don't like Eva.
Rym: Well, they hate this ending for the same reasons.
Rym: they hate the Eva ending, even though the endings are actually very different.
Scott: Yeah, but it doesn't matter, the point is all those people suck.
Rym: Yeah, you're seriously, if you're not satisfied with the end of the show suck it.
Rym: Get out of here.
Scott: Uh, there's something else, but whatever There's a lot else.
Rym: When we watched the show you know, saw the end and some shows, like I say, finish the show, and then I just turn it off.
Rym: but some shows, the credits just play all the way to the end and everyone sits in the room quiet until there is literally no more to see.
Scott: And then, oh, there's something after the final credits like 20 seconds worth, so you should watch that.
Rym: But, you know, you can tell when the show is an A anime.
Rym: I think my definition of an A anime, it makes that list.
Rym: if the majority of the people you show it to, when it ends, will sit in the room quietly until the last of the credits are gone.
Scott: That's one factor.
Scott: The other factors are you watch an episode and you just want to keep watching and you can't help yourself, and B, re-watching is good.
Scott: Like, if you can actually re-watch it and enjoy it again, if you get all those three things, it's an A anime.
Rym: Yes, and it does the Utena thing.
Rym: You watch it again.
Rym: everything you needed to know was there.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you watch the first episode after knowing the ending and people say things and you're like putting your hand over your mouth like, "Oh my god, they said that in episode one, I can't
Scott: believe!".
Rym: Hell, you watch this, every single episode has moments of, "Oh shit, oh really?
Rym: Oh, why didn't I notice that
Rym: before?".
Scott: "I can't believe.
Scott: they said that so early and I didn't notice
Scott: it.".
Scott: And there's only 12 episodes and they fit it all in.
Rym: This is one of the best anime I've seen in a long time.
Scott: Yeah, best.
Scott: I definitely call it best recent anime.
Rym: The last show that was as good as this that I watched was re-watching 2nd Gig Ghost in the Shell.
Scott: One more note just historically on the show, right?
Scott: The final episode of the show was delayed by the real earthquake.
Rym: Oh my god, I couldn't have dealt with that.
Scott: And then it came out in Japan much later and still got crazy ratings.
Rym: Well think about it, Scott, imagine if you had seen up to episode 11 and then you had to wait.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You would have been waiting as badly as we're waiting for the second season of Ponies.
Scott: That's why I don't wait, I just download the whole show at once and watch it all at once in one afternoon and one morning.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.