Rym: It's Wednesday April 13th 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: mocha fest 2011.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: I'm Finally catching up on Hokuto.
Rym: no Ken.
Rym: Oh really ever since PAX when we showed everyone Hokuto's on kai ken for the thousandth time.
Scott: I don't know how that's possible.
Scott: considering you are dead How could you watch TV if you are dead?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: there's something.
Rym: just suddenly I was inspired to start watching it again, and I'm blowing through like two or three episodes a day.
Rym: I finally it's sad, but I just met Toki.
Rym: Uh-huh, I got a ways to go.
Rym: all right, but we would do more shows on anime, but I watch so many animes you have no idea, so let's do a show on something.
Scott: well I watched these animes a while ago, and I don't think you watch the same ones.
Rym: I don't think you've watched anything.
Rym: I've watched.
Rym: we got a swap.
Rym: I think we should do a movie I think we should do like vampire hunter D or the slayers movies or something.
Scott: didn't we door to do slayers moving?
Rym: Uh we did the slayers movie.
Scott: We could only one.
Rym: we could do one of the other mini movies like the OAVs.
Scott: You're gonna tell about 30 minutes.
Scott: the things aren't even 30 minutes long.
Scott: We could watch it in the time.
Scott: It takes to talk about it.
Rym: I think I could do a show on one of those.
Scott: What would be the point?
Rym: what about vampire hunter D?
Rym: It's only an hour long, but it feels like four hours.
Rym: And I feel like we should do some old anime movies, maybe even some bad ones.
Scott: Legend of Lemnier.
Rym: I could watch that shit again.
Scott: Good you all on your own.
Rym: Here's what I remember about Legend of Lemnier.
Rym: There's a dude and a girl there's breasts, and then I fell asleep.
Rym: I woke up and the credits are rolling and nobody talked about it again except how bad it was.
Rym: there you go Yeah, all right one down done.
Rym: Yeah Next so is there any Anime related news?
Scott: no really all the news is totally lame.
Scott: and said about comics.
Rym: any comic news?
Scott: No, it's all really lame.
Rym: and said yeah, well the Comic Con in New York isn't until October.
Scott: Well a lot of thing is around this time of year.
Scott: all these you know these companies are not exactly Active companies that have things going on all the time.
Scott: right they're kind of slow.
Scott: They don't have a lot of stuff They're not big.
Scott: so it's not like they have news every week, or you know you can't have a blog.
Scott: It's it's you had a blog.
Scott: you'd have to have a blog about all the companies at once or to be able to Content.
Scott: so you know it's like.
Scott: well You know when it's when it comes time for San Diego Comic Con which is in July right leading up to it They save up all their news and their announcements.
Rym: Well, I think the trouble is more that what news will they ever had?
Rym: what news will the comic industry in America ever have other?
Rym: than Spider-man is continuing.
Rym: spider-man is now being drawn by this person instead of that person.
Rym: well They had has been added to a fourth team 10th team.
Scott: yeah, you know they have do have news that we could talk.
Scott: You know if you want to talk about that kind of stuff right.
Scott: for example lately DC every summer these companies usually Marvel and DC a big events.
Scott: right.
Scott: you know the big crossover of the crisis of infinite comic books The nerds have to buy right so that the nerds are actually complaining because DC's big event is Flashpoint.
Scott: it has something to do with the flash.
Scott: But apparently and I know this because they sent me a free copy of how does the flash not age?
Scott: Don't ask this like there's multiple different flashes.
Scott: It was the original.
Rym: Why are there more?
Rym: what happened to the old?
Rym: like what?
Rym: where's the oldest one?
Scott: there was the Golden Age flash?
Scott: I think he's dead.
Rym: so how?
Rym: whose is it?
Rym: It's a new guy.
Scott: Yeah, there was the Golden Age flash.
Scott: There's a new guy.
Scott: who's the Silver Age flash.
Rym: No the old guy.
Rym: Yeah, so they.
Rym: so they met each other.
Rym: How'd he pass on his power?
Scott: They didn't pass on the power.
Scott: They all have the same power separately, so Yeah, that sounds perfectly plausible the same way that a bunch of different people from planet Krypton.
Rym: if they all came to earth They're all Superman, but how did the flash get his power in the first place?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm not a flash expert.
Scott: This is like basic nerd.
Scott: I only know like the barest minimal information about the flash.
Scott: There was I don't know which.
Scott: I know that some of the names of the flash.
Scott: There's a there's a flash named Wally wood, and there's a flash named something else.
Scott: I Don't know, but there's a. there's like three different flashes basically right and there was the Golden Age flash.
Scott: Then there was the Silver Age flash and in Christ on Infinite Earths.
Scott: Oh god There's like six flashes on this Wikipedia page in Christ on Infinite Earths the second flash died and the kid flash Right became the flash flash, and now he's the fat kid flash is the flash flash, but there's a new kid flash.
Scott: So you know there's like the kid flash Wikipedia.
Rym: Thanks so much.
Rym: all incarnations of the flash possess super speed blah blah blah blah.
Rym: They all acquired it by some means.
Scott: yes, thanks something you do with the speed force.
Scott: The speed force it's something like they had some bullshit like that.
Rym: Is there red speed force as opposed to blue speed?
Rym: for no?
Scott: That's great for as green lanterns have this is this green lanterns and black lanterns and white lanterns and orange and blue.
Rym: Tonight also has that.
Scott: I know I bet the flash they won't flash.
Scott: Maybe that's a flash point is about.
Scott: but anyway the reason that the nerds are complaining wait How come bizarro flash is still fast.
Scott: That's a good question.
Rym: Why isn't he slow?
Scott: good point you win the winner is you?
Scott: Anyway, they're complaining about flash point.
Scott: because guess that get this right.
Scott: it has It's made up.
Scott: You know there is a core series.
Scott: That's like it's made up.
Scott: Well obviously There's that there's a core flash point series.
Scott: That's the flight.
Scott: you know the miniseries.
Scott: that is flashpoint, right?
Scott: But then of course is all these other books that cross so cross into it.
Scott: You know like if you read regular old issues of the flash well They're gonna have something to do with flashpoint.
Scott: But they have also started a bunch of miniseries just for flashpoint.
Scott: that are you know flashpoint miniseries?
Scott: They're all three issues.
Scott: guess how many miniseries they're making for flashpoint?
Rym: You wouldn't ask unless the number was really big or really small 40 16, so that's 16 times 3 issues of flashpoint miniseries Crossovers.
Scott: and the nerds are like complaining big.
Rym: the nerds are like you're taking my money.
Scott: Each of those is three dollars.
Scott: three dollars times 16 times 3 to get all these just Crossover less important flashpoint issues.
Scott: and the reason I know this is because the giant stupid catalog They sent me a free copy without me asking for it, so all right, but anyway.
Rym: Oh, I guess he doesn't kill anyone.
Rym: Whatever, I'm reading this article on the flash.
Rym: It's kind of Not interesting.
Scott: no kidding you don't say.
Scott: Anyways here is kind of a news you know for kids right.
Rym: ah for kids right.
Scott: so for kids It's sort of like.
Scott: it's sort of hard to understand What for kids is all about because it's sort of like.
Scott: well?
Scott: We're just for kids begin and funimation end.
Scott: basically for kids is you know one of those?
Scott: Programming blocks to see on TV, so if you watch certain kids channels.
Scott: I think CW at Saturday morning You'll see like a block of cartoons.
Rym: well remember cartoon cartoon Yeah, or Nicktoons.
Scott: Well.
Scott: This is different.
Scott: This is you know this is like a company You know puts together a block and then rents that block to the TV channel.
Scott: cartoon cartoon And Nicktoons was actually run by the.
Rym: it was but it was still a block of semi related programming either.
Scott: Really, it'd be like it'd be like if to Nami What when to Nami still existed was its own company and Cartoon Network paid to Nami to put to Nami on the Cartoon Network?
Rym: To Nami was great with its original host.
Scott: Yeah, that was the good days Anyway, so for kids You know they're responsible for bringing some shows to the u.s.
Scott: Like Yu-Gi-Oh and Pokemon and shaman king and a bunch of crap and ruining one piece in the ua.
Scott: you know stuff like that.
Scott: But basically you know they were recently sued by you know Japan because Apparently there was some question that they may have been Making money off of Yu-Gi-Oh and like hiding that money from the actual owners of Yu-Gi-Oh in Japan.
Rym: So they didn't have to give them royalties.
Scott: It's like you know.
Scott: they bought the Yu-Gi-Oh license, but then they made money off the Yu-Gi-Oh license.
Scott: They made like extra money off of it by selling DVDs.
Scott: and isn't there another lawsuit going on involving the Yu-Gi-Oh cards?
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I forgot about that.
Rym: the company that was making them that what may have been making bootlegs.
Rym: I barely remember.
Scott: Yeah, there's this weird stuff going on without with that too And that's not for kids as far as I can tell.
Scott: so there's all sorts of weird stuff with Yu-Gi-Oh.
Scott: Or maybe the fact maybe it's just the Japanese licensor Owner of Yu-Gi-Oh is getting all angry and wants to try to?
Scott: I don't know well.
Rym: I just I have this vision of a Dave and Joel style boardroom where they're sitting around.
Rym: They're like Tanaka.
Rym: We need you to rip off the stupid American.
Scott: go get all the Yu-Gi-Oh monies from America.
Scott: We didn't get enough from.
Scott: we're poor.
Scott: be Inscrutable right anyway, so for kids, right?
Scott: partially because that lawsuit and partially just because they suck.
Scott: Finally as you know they were on a downhill spiral for a long time.
Scott: I mean they were getting delisted and stuff right, but now they have declared the chapter 11 bankruptcy.
Scott: Ah good old chapter 11, which me chap for those you don't know this pretty much.
Scott: You know you think chapter 11.
Scott: Well now that's 11 different things you have to know really.
Scott: no you don't have to know 11 different things.
Scott: You know two different things right?
Scott: you know 11 and 7 because no one ever uses any other number besides 11 or 7.
Rym: I'll just gloss over that.
Rym: come on go moving on.
Scott: 7 is we are done We're going away.
Scott: Goodbye.
Scott: and 11 is we're gonna keep doing work even though We're out of money, and we don't have to pay people anymore.
Rym: Yeah, awesome Huh could have seen that one coming.
Scott: yep Actually, I'm surprised it took this long because why did I always wonder why people take so long?
Scott: It's like you're going.
Scott: Why?
Scott: it's like.
Scott: It's like if you're in the bathroom.
Scott: You don't have to declare bankruptcy yet, but once the toe is in the toilet you might as well You know what's good.
Rym: You're going down, but Scott here's the thing.
Scott: say I am on the no one escapes the toilet bowl.
Rym: say I'm on the board of a company and I am technically beholden to the shareholders.
Rym: if I know the company is going bankrupt and because of the Base product we make is shit, and there's no way to make the company profitable again.
Rym: It is a lost cause.
Rym: I cannot Tell them that I cannot run through this as though I know that because they can then claim that I am in fact not running the business in their best interests.
Scott: Why don't you tell them that?
Scott: and then they'll know that you're running the business in the best interest except There's no way.
Rym: because the moment it is revealed that I know Companies worth dick because no one's gonna buy it.
Rym: It's not worth anything so that good Yeah, so basically your company is we're dick if you're selling it to people for money when it's not we're Pretend that everything's fine until the last possible second when it's too late to get any money out of them.
Rym: once I've spent all my cash reserves Then I declare bankruptcy.
Rym: if I declare before they're gonna take all my cash to pay my debts What do you need that cash for?
Scott: you're just gonna spend it on poop anyway?
Rym: Yeah, I'm paying my employees longer.
Scott: Give give the all the money to the employees like everyone.
Scott: Here's all the money open for treasure chest.
Scott: They all empty the treasure now, and you leave now.
Rym: I'm legally liable to the shareholders for pissing away their money on.
Scott: no you tell them that the money was already gone and you Demonstrate that you know.
Scott: you tell the shareholders beforehand look we're gonna be out of business And then you give the money away, and then you leave.
Rym: now You know what.
Rym: there's really no easy way out or how does political and economic system?
Scott: You just say hey look this company's going down the shitter.
Scott: give the money back to the shareholders and then leave.
Rym: Yeah, I would just quit.
Scott: you're quitting is good - yeah The CEO in fact did quit.
Scott: according to this article The third quarter of 2010 the chairman and CEO Alfred Kahn resigned.
Scott: all right there you go.
Rym: Yeah, oh my god.
Rym: now I just have because you know we're doing that anime openers from around the world among other panels anime Boston next weekend.
Rym: So I was putting the finishing touches on it And I listened to the English opener to one piece several times one piece.
Rym: What's the line?
Rym: it's like he's sailing to find one piece in the grand line.
Rym: yeah in case he didn't know Oh, how do you get that way?
Rym: he ate the gum gum fruit?
Rym: Yep, anyway.
Rym: So there is some weird stuff going on in the manga world in Japan and a lot of people.
Rym: you've probably seen this so-called Jay Komi purify thing.
Scott: I never heard of this.
Rym: really it's all over the news.
Rym: people have been tweeting about it.
Rym: So basically the deal is that Jay Komi distributes manga legally.
Rym: Yep There is a lot of illegal manga out there as in stuff That's out of print But it's translated or not and you can just get scans of the whole thing.
Rym: I mean we have those scans of sanctuary that are Out there and such and it's illegal as in copyright or illegal as in.
Scott: they're showing the pink on your hand.
Scott: You're not a lot of copyright.
Rym: We're not talking about the pink.
Rym: okay I mean if we hey if we if pink were an issue We'd be all over this as would Daryl Surratt, but no pink.
Rym: It's just copyright.
Rym: So the deal is all right.
Rym: there is illegal you know copyright infringing manga out there on file-sharing networks.
Rym: What if you go to the creator and you say look or whoever owns the license who won't reprint it for whatever reason say look?
Rym: Rather than prosecuting these people over the thing that you're not distributing How about we take all the torrents and we put out better torrents?
Rym: We take the scans out there if we can we put out better scans And we put ads for all your new work in those torrents, and we still make the torrents free?
Rym: Yes, and then we bless the torrents by saying look total amnesty nobody's getting sued about sharing these all right And it's actually kind of a good idea now.
Scott: That's a great idea.
Scott: Yeah, now.
Rym: I don't want to get into all the details of it.
Scott: You can read it yourself, but and do they make like a nice accessible easily searchable website where these torrents are files are hosted?
Rym: I haven't looked into that too much.
Scott: Or are they just distributing them on the Pirate Bay with everything else?
Rym: It appears that that might be on the docket to actually distribute some of this stuff straight up through j-combing.
Scott: How about translating to English?
Rym: What the root of this is that?
Rym: remember that uproar among deviant art and artist alley types many years ago About how there was a clause in some new copyright law about orphaned works where if a work was orphaned then oh no you lose Your copyright and people who draw dog-headed girls were mad that they'd lose their copyright on the dog-headed girls.
Scott: Yeah, after like a zillion years.
Rym: So I feel like we need something like that.
Rym: But actually closer to this we need a sort of way for either creators or this isn't?
Scott: this isn't an orphaned work Situation.
Scott: an orphaned work is when I didn't say it was.
Rym: I'm saying it's like abandonware where but Scott have.
Scott: no I you can't contact the copyright holders.
Rym: I know I didn't say it was but it's a similar situation and that here We have work where we do know who made it, but there is no Legitimate way to get the work at all.
Scott: there is.
Scott: you have to contact the copyright holder And it's up to them and they refuse to all right for whatever reason they won't reprint it.
Rym: So what do you do now?
Rym: It's a work that can't be gotten.
Rym: yet under copyright law You can still sue people for distributing.
Rym: it hasn't been abandoned, but I didn't say it has been I know.
Scott: But they're refusing to distribute it or print it or make it available in any way.
Rym: So I think the genius here is that one Jake homie is going to the creators and saying look it would be illegal.
Rym: What do you say?
Rym: we get together and do this?
Rym: It's basically a way to get around the problems of copyright law.
Rym: if all the people who have a vested interest in the printing Play along all right I'm saying yeah, it's a great idea.
Rym: I think we need to do this more.
Scott: no yeah But I mean this is basically like you just said what do you do if they're not cooperating?
Scott: well this case they are cooperating.
Scott: So it's really not a change in any law or anything.
Rym: I didn't say it was a change in law.
Rym: But in this case I feel like people don't even think to go to the publishers and ask them.
Scott: they do they ask them all The time and they're always huge jerks.
Scott: It's this is actually rare.
Scott: I don't think as many people actually Disney We really really really want you to make Song of the South DVDs crickets.
Rym: Okay, so Disney giant faceless corporation.
Scott: Right those are the ones.
Scott: those are the ones that are holding all the cards essentially in the US.
Scott: This is only.
Scott: this is a rare case.
Scott: how many you know?
Scott: it's pretty much most.
Rym: There's tons of comics mangas even novels that are just out of print straight up.
Rym: Yeah, and there's a good chance that for many of these smaller things especially for imagine in the u.s.
Scott: All that I've seen this many times over many years my entire life many many works that you know it's like.
Scott: hey Does that a print?
Scott: I really wish it was in print.
Scott: Almost all of those cases are either a abandoned where you can't find the rights holder Or it's questionable or B. There is a rights holder, and they don't want to print it.
Rym: It's very rare that you'll have a case where there is It's a difference between not wanting to print it and being willing to bless Illegal distribution of it.
Scott: right that's you know.
Rym: all it is is that there are a few I don't people have gone to Especially in the US people who do own a work and don't want to republish it Which you might.
Rym: you can understand why someone might not want to.
Scott: maybe you have a work where it's not gonna sell.
Rym: Yeah, you don't think you'll make any money off.
Rym: well, but go to them and say hey Do you have anything new you're working on?
Rym: try to sell it to them like look this old property of yours is worth nothing.
Rym: But I see you're working on a new thing.
Rym: What if you let the old thing for free?
Rym: is advertising for the new thing?
Rym: try to sell it to the people who have us Bested interest in it.
Rym: you won't get Disney, but you'll get like the next level down.
Scott: here's here's the problem.
Scott: Let's say I start up a company right and I go around to people and I say hey I see you have this book.
Scott: It's out of print.
Scott: right why don't you let me make a free ebook and I'll put ads in it for whatever you're working on now.
Scott: and And then I mean well, I put that on my website as a torrent and everyone downloads it.
Scott: Yeah, they see these ads and Meanwhile I'm making money off other ads on the site that I'm selling and now those people who I you know Whoever works are being handed out are gonna want money from me, but they're gonna be like hey No, I don't want I'm done with this deal.
Scott: You're making a lot of money.
Scott: Well.
Rym: You know what that's just a contract Negotiation yeah That's.
Scott: but as the thing is most of them are gonna be jerks like that.
Rym: I don't know if they would necessarily a very few.
Scott: and if you know in Japan and that's nothing Why do you need it?
Scott: if you want to put torrents out of your own stuff that are blessed?
Scott: Why do you need someone to do it for you?
Scott: Just do it?
Rym: I think the problem is that people don't realize or think.
Rym: to do it.
Rym: You know first you don't need some.
Scott: if you own a work you don't need somebody to help you distribute it.
Scott: You know for free.
Rym: Saying I think there are people out there or companies out there that don't realize this is an option like they haven't you.
Rym: I mean Think about in technology how many times there's an obvious way to capitalize on something.
Scott: Hey, you got this don't do it.
Scott: Hey, you made this old movie.
Scott: You're never gonna put it on DVD.
Scott: Let me help you put it on YouTube.
Scott: It's like you can put it on YouTube on your own.
Rym: I don't think they realize they can't.
Rym: but anyway I feel like we should go further, and I think I've said this on other shows before especially for technology.
Rym: I feel like in the US at least we need of an eminent domain equivalent for copyright and patent.
Rym: yeah I do think that I feel like there should be extraordinary Situations where the government can step in and do the same thing they do when they take away some guys land to build a freeway To take away some guys IP to build an internet freeway.
Scott: Martin Luther King's speech.
Rym: But anyway, it's time for things of the day, so you know Banksy you're familiar with him Street artist and such.
Rym: well Banksy apparently backed a quote Scatological a Russian art collective all right called vonya mm-hmm.
Rym: vonya means war The war.
Scott: which war is that?
Scott: uh the war the vonya vonya all right.
Rym: so vonya likes to do Imagine improv everywhere coupled with Banksy style graffiti coupled with sometimes being gigantic douches.
Rym: One of their quote-unquote guerrilla art exhibits involved Surrounding for police cars in like st.
Rym: Petersburg and flipping them over okay.
Rym: Yeah So what they did and I've got some pictures of it.
Rym: It's pretty great.
Rym: This is very reminiscent of our old penis on the Parthenon.
Rym: But quote members members of vonya two of whom are awaiting trial on hooliganism charges Whitewashed the decoration on a bridge in st.
Rym: Petersburg.
Scott: Oh, I seen this when the very old.
Rym: well the news There's the news about this is what's cool, okay?
Rym: So when the bridge was raised because it was a drawbridge up an erect phallus ended up facing the local headquarters of the FSB.
Rym: We have this.
Scott: is that happened a long time ago.
Rym: I happen in June.
Scott: Yep the successor to the KGB.
Scott: So I was like area.
Rym: This is this huge graffiti, and it's a pretty great gigantic penis.
Rym: There are pictures of it everywhere is awesome.
Rym: Mostly because it would erect itself every time a boat wanted to go on.
Scott: I know right.
Rym: so do you know what the work was actually called?
Rym: a dick held prisoner At the FSB?
Rym: all right it was 65 meters tall.
Scott: now that that alone It's only a meter longer than mine.
Rym: that alone would not Qualify as a thing of the day because people draw dicks on stuff all the time and while I enjoy Dicks being drawn on things actually last night remember cock medias draw.
Rym: it came out of the vault so I watched it again but It won a gigantic art contest.
Rym: nice after a series of crazy Drama.
Rym: it won 400,000 rubles at the 2010 innovation prize by the National Center for Contemporary Arts in Moscow.
Scott: 400,000 rubles is like $4.
Scott: It's like 10 grand.
Rym: It's like 10 grand.
Rym: rubles are worth shit They're not that bad.
Rym: at least it wasn't rupees I'm thinking of Archer because it's 400,000 rubles and the article says which is the equivalent of eight thousand seven hundred pounds Like great.
Rym: What's that in real money?
Rym: Sorry so uh yeah?
Rym: They were arrested for that.
Rym: Banksy donated like 80,000 pounds to them To cover the costs of defending themselves or drawing this gigantic penis.
Rym: But they were disqualified from competition a couple of times and reinstated disqualified.
Rym: There's this crazy drama.
Scott: Why is this a drama?
Rym: because the police were like you can't count that as an entry They just spray-painted a penis on a bridge.
Scott: That's art.
Scott: It was vandalism and vandalism is also art at the same time.
Rym: Yes, they're not mutually exclusive and the fact that this one is Pretty great, and I I just find the whole.
Scott: I would have voted for it every time.
Scott: yeah to look at me that.
Rym: So the I got some Russia.
Rym: Lisa talking about the prize jury said that he is happy that they defeated the bureaucrats who tried to Deny the group the prize quote.
Rym: they are Professionals after all and some of them are brave people.
Scott: So I was gonna use something.
Scott: more annoying is my thing.
Rym: I have one last thing.
Rym: Vanya was not happy that they won the award for that work of art.
Rym: They had a better work of art that they thought should have won Which was a woman in the group was filmed stealing a chicken from a grocery store by inserting it into her vagina to quote the same guy from before now.
Scott: that was something I Would not would have picked the penis on the drawbridge.
Rym: Well.
Rym: You're partial to penises.
Rym: I can tell anyway.
Scott: I doubt you know Vagina's chickens inside of them is not Problem.
Scott: you go beak first.
Rym: Uh I've no idea.
Scott: done some damage It also.
Rym: I'm assuming it was a dead chicken.
Scott: Oh Okay, assuming Just put like one of the drumsticks in there.
Rym: now the picture on the website.
Rym: They wouldn't actually show the penis, but they did a prank where they just tossed a cat at like a McDonald's employee.
Scott: nice All right, so I was gonna use something more annoying as my thing of the day But instead I'm gonna use something that's you know maybe could be a news But isn't actually a news article what it is.
Scott: It's an article on Bloomberg, and you always hear about how rich people don't pay taxes.
Scott: Yeah, how they avoid taxes.
Scott: well this actually?
Scott: Specifically and in great detail lists ten or so actual Techniques and the specific things that rich people do to not pay taxes right.
Scott: and here is here's my favorite one of them.
Scott: So let's say an exec you're a rich, dude.
Scott: You have two hundred million dollars in shares of your company that you work for.
Scott: you're an executive.
Scott: you're on the board Right.
Scott: you got two hundred million dollars in shares.
Scott: you want cash, though You don't want these shares you got to sell those shares yeah to get cash right and if you do that You're gonna pay capital gains tax.
Scott: That's how it works right.
Scott: so if you sold today $200,000,000 of shares in your own company you would pay probably thirty million dollars in capital gains taxes.
Scott: How could you avoid those capital gains taxes?
Scott: I'm gonna tell you exactly how.
Scott: right now step one go to a bank and borrow 200 million dollars from the bank.
Scott: all right.
Scott: now you have a loan for 200 million dollars.
Scott: You've got 200 million in cash.
Rym: wait wait wait wait.
Rym: so let me guess use the shares as collateral now Yeah, back to loan.
Scott: well hold on.
Scott: use the shares as collateral Yeah.
Scott: But what happens if the value of the shares were to go up or down?
Scott: then your collateral would be sort of shaky Right.
Scott: so you need to.
Scott: you need to stiffen that collateral to make sure it stays worth 200 million dollars I'm still thinking about the bridge so that you can so that you can keep the loan ready.
Scott: So how do you make sure that the shares are gonna be worth 200 million dollars no matter what happens?
Rym: uh?
Rym: I'm not sure.
Rym: how do you?
Scott: you buy options on the put and the call so you have the right to buy shares at 200 and And also the right to sell them at 200 million dollars in the future.
Scott: Do a standard hedge yes, so now the you bought options in the same stock shares that you just put as collateral.
Scott: So now those basically the value of those shares as far as you're concerned is you can always Use those shares to get 200 million dollars no matter what the value of the stock.
Scott: even if the value of the stock goes down And if the value of the stock goes up well you can get more than 200 million dollars.
Rym: options do expire.
Scott: They've been buying them.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You have to keep.
Scott: you have to keep buying them over and over again.
Scott: all right Eventually right.
Scott: you can either Right give the cash back to the bank and repay the loan Which would just mean that you had 200 million dollars.
Scott: you took a loan and you gave it back.
Scott: You didn't paint.
Scott: you don't pay any taxes.
Scott: You just pay interest to the bank.
Scott: right.
Scott: or And hopefully if you borrow 200 million dollars I hope that you would be able to use it in a way to make more money than the interest.
Scott: otherwise that was stupid.
Scott: or You can just give the shares back.
Scott: right if you just get.
Scott: if you just pay the loan back Then you don't pay taxes because you.
Scott: all you did was take out a loan and pay it back.
Scott: You don't pay taxes on.
Scott: that sounds about right, and if you gave you let the collateral go to the bank And you keep the money.
Scott: I?
Scott: You do it get.
Scott: you do have to pay tax on that.
Scott: but the tax bill comes many many many years later many years later and During all those years you had 200 million dollars in cash that you could earn money with and hopefully you would earn enough money with To pay off that tax effectively paying no tax.
Scott: So you manage to turn 200 million dollars in shares into 200 million dollars in cash plus Without paying any capital gains tax.
Scott: what amazes me is that what's great is the greatest thing.
Scott: if those 200 million dollar shares?
Scott: go to the bank as Collateral if the bank tries to sell them won't the bank have to pay capital gains tax?
Scott: or will they not because they're a bank?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Well, I won't get into that or the bank just hold the share.
Rym: what I find interesting is that?
Rym: the Republicans are really fighting the fact that currently what one of the initiatives in the administration right now is to Close a lot of these loopholes and instead of raising taxes just enforce the existing tax.
Scott: I don't know why there are any loopholes, but here's the is the Scott I was about to tell you.
Rym: you know why there's loopholes there.
Rym: put there on purpose the Republicans no, but so there were loopholes.
Rym: I mean, it's pretty easy to have a loophole in an old law that you haven't updated.
Scott: Here's he has a lot.
Scott: if you make money no matter where the money comes from no matter What country you make it in mind is made in text.
Scott: did the amount of money that you have personal control over?
Rym: Oh, I don't know your possession I don't have control over it.
Rym: my friend of mine does.
Rym: he lives in the Bahamas.
Scott: if you tell him what to do is he?
Scott: Legally obligated to do it.
Rym: I don't tell him.
Scott: I just ask him and is he legally obligated to do it?
Rym: not by any US law.
Scott: If he if he takes that money and does and runs away with it and builds a mansion That's his mansion and lives in it guys fuck you not.
Scott: will you try to sue him or will it?
Scott: will that be considered?
Rym: Scott it's outside of the US.
Rym: No US laws don't matter.
Rym: so as far as the US is concerned yeah sure he can do whatever he wants with my money.
Rym: Bahamas laws different.
Scott: the US can just go ask the Bahamas hey that money whose money is that doesn't work.
Scott: that way Scott We'll blow up the Bahamas.
Rym: But the real reason people can get away with this bullshit is because the Republicans are basically preventing any reform saying that Reform of the tax code to prevent the loopholes is effectively raising taxes.
Scott: I got a new law.
Scott: you ready if you are in Congress.
Scott: We take away all your money.
Scott: You're not allowed to have any money.
Rym: I got a new law ready.
Scott: You want it.
Scott: You want it ready.
Scott: You ready carousel.
Scott: You want to be in charge of the government.
Scott: well You're you know you want to do it so badly.
Scott: you want power no money.
Scott: Take away all.
Scott: you must have zero dollars.
Scott: the government will provide you with food and shelter Just like you're in the military.
Scott: some.
Scott: you'll be a public servant.
Rym: I somehow feel that there may be a more subtle and elegant way to achieve our end.
Scott: I think that works though you want to be a public servant there You're a public servant.
Scott: is anyone gonna.
Rym: Give up all their rights to be the mayor of Podunk, Iowa?
Scott: We're talking about Congress federal Congress.
Scott: alright.
Rym: So the super-rich people control all the non federal Congress's and effectively then control the country The state Congress people.
Scott: they get exactly X dollars, or they live the local night.
Rym: Where do you where do you set X Scott?
Rym: You realize if you minimum wage No one can live on minimum wage.
Scott: they'll vote to graze the minimum wage real fast won't they?
Scott: All right, we can all get minimum wage here right minimum wage boom a million dollars a year says yes minimum wage There you go solved.
Rym: and of course before we get to the main coverage the meta moment We will be at anime Boston April 22nd 23rd and 24th.
Rym: not next weekend, but that well not this weekend But next weekend.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: We will be there doing I think four.
Scott: so panels I don't know which panels are doing.
Scott: we're supposed to get the itinerary today.
Rym: I've had it for a while.
Rym: I just haven't really shared.
Scott: I know some of them.
Scott: I just forget.
Rym: I'm pretty sure we're doing the hotter on a panel panel because yeah We're definitely doing that one because there was a. you know we did it as a throwaway panel last year.
Scott: Well, it's actually surprisingly fun to do even though we didn't know we were doing it till we showed up.
Rym: Well, I was also pleased that it.
Rym: we thought it was the throwaway.
Rym: right we walk into the room rooms packed.
Scott: It wasn't packed, but it was well.
Scott: No no there are a lot of people.
Rym: It was packed, but it was a tiny room.
Scott: It wasn't completely.
Scott: it was packed for first panel ever on Friday morning immediately as the con starts And it was in that itty-bitty little room like way around.
Scott: It was surprisingly fun to do
Rym: yeah
Scott: And without any preparation it went well especially
Rym: because I'm happy
Scott: to do it again
Rym: Especially talking about all the things that people do poorly in panels and then watching people who are at that panel at other panels Noticing those things as gold.
Scott: we should do it at Kinetic Con at 6 a.m.
Scott: Right before the con starts is mandatory for all other panelists.
Rym: and whoo a panelist, huh?
Scott: All panelists must be at the con at this time must attend one of these sessions for dick punchings Or you can't.
Rym: we're just gonna cancel your panels all right, so anyway We're definitely doing anime openers from around the world new and revised.
Scott: Oh snap We're doing Scott's who is Hatsune Miku panel, which is actually dated technology, but not really revised.
Rym: yes But it's a panel that I think anime fans need to see.
Scott: it's in big room.
Scott: I checked.
Scott: yeah, it's a big room at a big time, and it's a different color on the schedule.
Rym: Oh, well cuz you know why it's a different color.
Rym: We're not just panelists at anime Boston.
Rym: We are preferred panelists.
Rym: We're not guests we're not Vic.
Rym: So yes anime Boston we will be there, I think we're doing another panel.
Rym: My tool Derral Strad anime world order.
Rym: they'll all be there.
Scott: There's enough panels done by either us or people close to us or our friends that you could go to just those panels and probably Fill the whole weekend with awesomeness.
Rym: if you want to say hi to us We've had a lot of fans coming up to us at cons, and it's great.
Rym: the only word of advice I have is that don't try to talk to us after a panel.
Rym: That's pretty much the absolute worst time to talk to us cuz you have to leave the room because someone else is coming in the And usually we go to dinner right after our panels no matter when they are.
Scott: So dinner right after the first panel on Friday morning Maybe lunch.
Rym: so if you want to talk to us come to the tabletop gaming area.
Rym: And if we're not there And we're not doing a panel and we're not at one of Derral's panels or one of Mike's panels one of Gerald's panels one Of Clarissa's panels then what we're gonna be at is probably the lobby of our hotel playing games
Scott: or dinner or dinner.
Rym: But yeah, if you find us we might tell you where the good secret breakfast is.
Rym: no We're not gonna say it on the show.
Scott: I'll tell you to go to the Neptune to try it in cafe.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: in cafe is pretty much the second best breakfast in Boston.
Scott: That's the non secret best breakfast.
Scott: It's all great.
Scott: It's fantastic amazing breakfast, so you should go to it, and we're not gonna Tell you where the secret breakfast is.
Scott: you know what and we won't get you know what.
Rym: if you can beat me in advance wars I'll tell you where it is sure.
Rym: yeah Beat Megaman 2 faster than Scott will tell you where it is People who can do that.
Rym: yeah, how many of them are gonna be at anime Boston?
Scott: I don't know, but we don't.
Scott: we won't have a Megaman 2 available.
Rym: Oh, huh funny that The GeekNights book club book is Foundation.
Scott: It's actually I just got.
Scott: I bought the first three and the three separate volumes.
Scott: my parents have a hardcover for this old that has All three in one volume.
Scott: It's not actually that long volume one.
Scott: This should be kind of easy.
Scott: It'll probably be in like right next month or two.
Scott: We'll do the book club because it's gonna be pretty soon.
Rym: Yep, in case you didn't notice registration for Pax Prime hotels already went up and all the good hotels are probably already sold out.
Rym: But if you hear this and you do not have your packs hotel, you should go get it right now.
Scott: Yeah, like not.
Scott: we're not right now like tomorrow or the next day.
Scott: right now I was pause GeekNights and do it otherwise you did seriously dude.
Rym: You didn't pause it.
Scott: Where are you going to sleep?
Rym: Well the gutter the share mile away.
Rym: so advice Sheraton best bet because there's gaming there Thursday and Monday.
Scott: red lion 90% is good.
Rym: Red lion is I think my favorite.
Rym: non connected to the con hotel.
Rym: It's like right there.
Scott: There's only one connected to the con.
Rym: Yeah, but the red lion to be fair is you have to walk like that two blocks over But it's not far walk.
Rym: You'll be walking over there.
Rym: Anyway for the elephant castle.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I love that elephant castle.
Scott: It's pretty good place.
Rym: It's good like late night.
Rym: I'm tired.
Rym: food.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it, you know, it's typical It's it's basically like a Fridays but not Fridays.
Rym: It's the Boston equivalent of a Friday's Seattle.
Rym: Right, Seattle.
Rym: Yeah, right, right.
Scott: go to Boston next.
Scott: Yeah, go into Seattle in September and of course if you buy your book in your anime Boston hotel today godspeed.
Rym: Well, we know the dates for the next like ten years.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's I think that's definitely a cool move.
Scott: on anime Boston You know realizing it's something that a lot of companies and other conventions and people in general need to realize is a lot of times.
Scott: there's no reason to keep the secret just for the sake of keeping a secret.
Scott: if you have information and the information is finalized and There's not gonna be any harm by releasing the information.
Scott: It can only help.
Scott: you should release it.
Scott: You should be better.
Scott: You should release as much information as possible.
Scott: Not as little as possible.
Rym: The information was hidden, right?
Rym: No, it wasn't because you could just figure it out if you went to the Boston like convention website, exactly There was.
Scott: no really it was already public.
Scott: It was just hidden public.
Scott: So I looked into this at least now.
Rym: right now I looked into this and Otakon still keeps it secret.
Rym: Uh I think it's pretty trivial to know when every Otakon will be Yeah from the BCC website.
Rym: also because we still have access to the staff site.
Scott: I don't have access to stuff.
Scott: So I still do.
Scott: I haven't tried.
Rym: I'm listed as suspended but I can still log in and do everything.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: anyway I don't even remember user name or password of our forums rocking.
Rym: It's kind of an ivory tower even a lot of new people joining.
Rym: I think you'll like it.
Rym: follow the gig night.
Scott: It's an ivory tower, but no elephants were harmed.
Rym: If you would like only mammoths.
Rym: get all the tweets of our old things of the day and old good episodes.
Rym: And of course if you want to listen to as old episodes of GeekNights because all like 700 and whatever are online Every one of them is downloadable even the beta GeekNights if you can find it everything.
Rym: but the beta is Just on our website all the way back to the beginning every single episode.
Scott: and after I get some other work done.
Scott: after anime Boston I'm working on some other websites that are almost done and then I'm gonna do some big upgrades.
Scott: different recruiter.
Rym: Yep And the secret project I've been mentioning to people is coming along.
Rym: give it maybe a month and you might start seeing some.
Scott: yeah We're waiting for we're actually it's.
Scott: it sort of.
Scott: actually is a whole bunch done.
Scott: We're just waiting for certain events to happen to coincide to get the timing right?
Rym: Yep And I think it's.
Scott: but those events are scheduled so it's.
Scott: it's pretty much like Gonna happen guaranteed.
Rym: Yep, as long as I finished the editing which is actually really on track.
Rym: I'm learning premiere pretty well Yeah, in fact here.
Scott: I'll give you a sort of a real date.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: Oh shit Yeah, we can give like early May like May 7th.
Scott: It's something or sometime around early May.
Scott: Yeah, no first second week of May.
Rym: astute people may be able to figure out what it is Not the first but for early May.
Rym: well on the 1st of May I'll have something else for everybody but Some outdoor fucking.
Scott: perhaps I got something perhaps some half out the door fucking.
Rym: But we are like it like out the Museum of Comic and Cartoon Arts Festival the mocha festival 2011.
Rym: We were there as we always are.
Scott: how many mochas has this been in a row?
Scott: For us I Think I think I've been to the puck building three times and I think this is the third time at the.
Scott: I think at the armory, I think this is the depth.
Scott: This is definitely the third time at the armory at least.
Rym: Anyway, no, we also have a special guest.
Rym: Emily is on the show because she came with us to the mocha.
Emily: Yes, I figured it could be.
Emily: this could be the yearly Show that I'm on because I enjoy the indie comic.
Rym: It's also a good test of our technology.
Rym: We can actually have like eight people on the show.
Scott: Gaga also, you know we were gonna discuss pretty much.
Scott: All we're gonna talk about is the giant pile of comics that we have and we're doing it.
Rym: So I'm around.
Rym: usually, you know We go around and I interview like a hundred people and we have all those like just random interviews of like.
Rym: this is my comic.
Rym: Yeah I didn't bring the Marantz partly because I was lazy and I wanted to just enjoy the mocha and Partly because I wanted to get some video instead and we'll do some video later.
Rym: But we're just gonna talk about all the comics we got.
Emily: it was kind of funny because one of our friends came over.
Emily: She had to tutor during the mocha And so she came over for dinner that night and she walked in the door and all our comics were spread out in the floor.
Emily: She's like, oh my god.
Emily: How much did you guys spend?
Emily: Actually, it wasn't that much.
Emily: I've spent more in past years.
Rym: I spent less than a hundred dollars not knowing these surprisingly expensive but very awesome little miniature.
Rym: I didn't
Scott: actually count how much I spent but I definitely spent at least a hundred but other people spent more than me and other People like
Rym: credit our success and not spending money to the fact that by and large none of us bought anything We could just buy from a store.
Emily: About a couple things From like, you know verticals website or something like that.
Scott: I'm not vertical wasn't even there.
Scott: Top shelf was yeah, it's like if it's top shelf Fantagraphics first.
Emily: second you can use it was there.
Scott: it's weird because they're still indie publishers But at mocha they're big because they're the indie publishers and you think are Abrams, you know You can get their stuff
Emily: was there to where they
Scott: didn't see that but you can get their stuff on Amazon or you know from your comic book store usually.
Scott: so yeah, it's like why you know buying it at the mocha Doesn't really help you unless unless maybe the person is there and you wanted to sign it or something.
Emily: That's the thing if it's somebody who you're really a fan of.
Emily: I was this close to buying some Tov Janssen picture books some woman troll picture books But then I was like, no you can get that later.
Emily: You should buy zines that cost two dollars and are printed on a photocopy and you will never see again.
Scott: It's weird though cuz some of those you like I'll never see again.
Scott: But meanwhile you see them the next mocha they're there.
Scott: Yeah, if you want all of diary diaries, you can still get it.
Rym: I couldn't find prison comics.
Emily: I couldn't get poor poor angsty Hungarian anymore.
Scott: That's another thing.
Scott: is that for example the the torpedo code booth Perhaps the most popular booth of the longest lines.
Scott: or you can buy all that stuff at the pay to co comm even though it's Even.
Scott: let you know you can't get it on it.
Rym: But Kate Beaton isn't going to sign your thing.
Scott: if you wait in line for like an hour the beaten path.
Emily: Every time I see her and there's a line forever I got to say I always feel bad for like the people who are next to the really successful Indie artists.
Scott: Oh, it's like.
Scott: is it good?
Scott: or is it bad?
Emily: because happy at the line of Successful, but then everybody else it's ignore.
Scott: There's a line of people that is there's in front of you.
Scott: Then they'll probably look at your stuff while they're waiting but the foot traffic won't see you through the wall of people.
Rym: There's a secondary problem.
Rym: I think the way because I saw some people or I did feel bad for them there was a popular thing next to them and the people were crowded around that not really in a line just in a big crowd and Those people would kind of glance at the table next to it and just immediately glance back and never give it a second look Because it wasn't that good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, you know you at the mocha really quality rules, right?
Scott: If you've got some if you're good at setting up a table with attractive stuff that catches the eye You're gonna do all right.
Rym: Did you notice there was necessarily quality rules?
Emily: Sometimes it's like it's got to be quality in a wide variety of spectrums Like if it's very interesting or it's really funny But poorly drawn or the dude is weird.
Emily: at the table It's like 50 cents and you put the money in the mr.
Emily: T Bank or something.
Emily: You're gonna be interested in that that person.
Scott: plus there seems to be an explosion of things with anthropomorphized food Cute talking tiny robots of various sorts or What's the other thing?
Scott: I saw a whole bunch of things that are related to just other geekeries in general, you know.
Rym: No ponies, though, though.
Rym: I heard that a lot of people were asking for pony commissions of oh, you say there are no ponies But guess what?
Scott: I have some secret ponies secret ponies.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: In fact, I'll talk about this first Even though it's sort of riding.
Rym: Well that our friend gave you that little rainbow - that's true.
Scott: I want to talk about this book, right?
Scott: This book is actually the probably the best thing I got at the mochas and we're riding the tallest roller coaster first But whatever right.
Scott: so I saw this book called the 12 labors of gastrophobia by David Maguire.
Scott: It was $12 Right, so this I bought this based because it looked cute.
Scott: that's pretty much all I reason.
Scott: I bought it Right, and I read it last night and let me tell you this is fucking hysterical.
Emily: I want to read it.
Emily: I was looking like
Scott: I was lulling so much and what it's about is this Amazon who got pregnant but she doesn't know how her from who and She gets kicked out of Amazonia and So she's living in ancient Greece but it's mystical ancient Greece like this sphinxes that have and minotaurs and biclopses and all sorts of you know fantasy stuff.
Scott: and she has a son who's gastro and her name is phobia and They have wacky Adventures that are hilarious all over the place.
Scott: and there were my little ponies in this book Also cameos by a Kate Beaton pony and lots of other webcomics and all kind of Time-traveling and there's all sorts of stuff.
Scott: and the best part is I found out this is a webcomic.
Emily: The arts really cute.
Scott: So I went to the website and like apparently this collects like the first 12 Labors, but now they're on like the second set of labors.
Scott: on the website There's a whole bunch of them and it was so good.
Scott: I added it to my webcomics list because it was so hysterical, you know what that's referencing.
Scott: What do you mean neighbors?
Scott: No, oh, yeah, cuz it's Greek right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah It's a whole.
Scott: the thing is very.
Scott: it's got a lot of Greek ness going on all over the place But it is also fantasy and humor.
Scott: Yeah, and a lot.
Scott: there's a lot of anachronisms as well all over the place.
Rym: So I picked up.
Rym: there was this guy.
Rym: he had two little comics.
Rym: They had a much more but there one was called kanji for daily use and I got that one And the follow-up was flightless birds.
Rym: now kanji for daily use is what sold me because it's this panda and it's like oh I'll learn.
Rym: I thought it's a penguin But I just picked it up.
Rym: I think I picked it up from a table.
Rym: that wasn't the artist cuz I saw it in multiple tables Really?
Scott: I got.
Rym: I saw a lot of stuff in multiple tables.
Scott: There were for example another thing that I got that was at multiple tables that pinball zine, but let's see Kanji for daily use.
Rym: Let's see Akumu nightmare.
Scott: That's not the first page.
Rym: shippai Failure unrequited love unrequited alone regret alcohol.
Scott: He tells a story in just single words, right and you know next to each it.
Scott: on the left You see the kanji and the and the.
Scott: you know The romangi and the translate and what it means.
Scott: and on the right is an illustration and the illustrations in sequence tell a sad story.
Emily: On the back, you know what it says.
Emily: I can see the back.
Emily: Fuck you and the penguins like.
Emily: that's not Japanese.
Scott: And then in the bottom right you can is actually a little area where you can practice drawing the kanji.
Emily: Yeah, but it's basically the story told through a textbook of a penguins Horrible crushing depression and failure at life.
Rym: I was impressed enough to pick up flightless birds, which was just an actual comic.
Rym: And it's equally great.
Rym: It intersperses the sad penguin with Making penises in latte art.
Emily: Well, it's just about a any comic artist who lives in Brooklyn and sometimes she's really like kind of cynical in her Presentation of stuff but some of the stuff in the comic was kind of funny.
Rym: I was impressed.
Rym: It was a fun little thing and it was definitely the price was right.
Rym: This is the kind of stuff that you won't see except at the mocha.
Emily: Yeah.
Emily: Mm-hmm.
Emily: And of course We had.
Emily: we had to stop by the Scandinavian corner.
Rym: I bought a bunch of stuff over there.
Emily: I think we hit every every Nordic country We have.
Emily: we got one from Finland We got one from Norway and the one from Norway was great because it had no dialogue.
Emily: It was you know, I was like no translation problem.
Emily: I know it was like does so?
Emily: does it have a paper?
Scott: It's like Tezuka's.
Scott: what's it called tales of a street corner?
Emily: Yeah, and So that one was really cool.
Emily: I forget the name.
Emily: It was something about the canal.
Rym: I got that one.
Rym: That's in my pile.
Rym: I will pull it out right now.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: It was really cool.
Emily: It was den croquette canal in and don't don't eat and people don't hit us for our pronunciation by max Estes It's.
Rym: I don't even want to say anything about it because it's it's really good.
Emily: It's it's like it's way spoilable spy thriller kind of thing.
Rym: it's a spy drama with a dead drop.
Emily: and Well, it's all all told and very Stylized color.
Emily: No, no lines.
Emily: Really It's it's mostly with light and shadow and like lots of blues and and night tone Lots of people getting hit by cars and things - yeah.
Emily: And it has cats.
Rym: it's great just for the end where there's a cop who's like what the fuck It's what goes on in the streets by the canal at night.
Rym: I wish I could have a job where I'm paid by my government to go around the world promoting arts.
Scott: Oh my gosh Is that their full-time job?
Rym: Oh, it's but there are but they are paid for that.
Rym: I mean, hey go to it's science for a week and tell people about GeekNights.
Emily: It's not completely.
Emily: I I think it's not like they're paid by the government for everything but government sponsors it Exactly.
Emily: the Scandinavian countries have much better endowments for the arts and grants and stuff and they do sponsor this trip to promote cultural exchange Through the arts, you know and the u.s.
Emily: Has some programs like that, but not not nearly to the extent that That these other countries do and it's kind of a shame.
Emily: But of course at the same time you look at taxes and they nobody wants to pay taxes here That many more taxes than we do.
Emily: Nobody in the u.s If I was to say help me spread indie comics to the world All the Republicans and everything would be like.
Scott: well Mocha takes up one room for two days in a big city and you know It's like.
Scott: and it's not that it's only crowded like later in the day.
Scott: Yeah That's the amount of interest you're gonna get in this one part.
Scott: how much you know.
Scott: It's not like if you're in the.
Scott: you know, Northern Europe.
Scott: You got people normal people waiting in a huge line to see Don Rosa, right?
Scott: It's a completely different situation.
Rym: So at the same table, I picked up Otto non chalongelow little round dude who it's also a wordless one and it's just little four panels and He's kind of a dick and it's kind of funny in a way.
Emily: It's kind of like the anti Ziggy, you know You know this little dude who's very like round and and fat and he goes around.
Scott: he's round effect.
Emily: Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Emily: But he is kind of more not nice.
Scott: Well, he's nice.
Scott: Ziggy's usually just completely boring.
Emily: It's it's sappy and the other one is maybe not so sappy.
Scott: Ziggy's pretty much his greeting cards.
Emily: nowadays Ziggy actually come from overseas.
Emily: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know enough about it.
Emily: Anyway, so at the Finland table I was happy too because I was able to recognize some of the Finnish publications and it was Kannurva.
Emily: was Kannurva was the the one that Timo gave us.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: And then all the people at the table were like, oh crap.
Rym: I know who that is.
Emily: Oh, I was too embarrassed to say anything in Finnish.
Emily: besides my finish is really bad But we got Batuman.
Emily: Batuman is pretty great and we got a free comics newspaper Which had like a bunch of samplings of like.
Scott: oh, yeah They had a big stack that was.
Scott: that was something I saw.
Scott: more this year than ever was Things that were printed on newsprint that were big and I think I don't know if Wednesday comics which did come out Between these two mochas had any sort of influence on that, right?
Scott: You know the newsprint format.
Emily: This was like a collaboration between a Chicago Independent comic Collective and a Finnish independent comic collective and so it's kind of cool.
Emily: It was like half and a half.
Emily: but Batuman is.
Emily: this is a first issue called the sad issue and it's Adventures of the Batuman including bad friends hipsters and other depressing things.
Emily: It's basically, you know, it's Batman and he he the arts very cute is little Two-tone green and green and black and it's just Batman comes over to talk to Catwoman about stuff.
Emily: Cuz he's depressed.
Rym: So I thought they could only have sex in this in the space between the top of the Batpole and the bottom.
Scott: Anyway, so next to the the Scandinavian comic table right a little bit to the left was this this new NYU table Right, which was representing like this one group of this one major at NYU.
Scott: I forget what the majors called but basically it's like a pretty awesome major.
Scott: I kind of wish I would have done it or would have existed.
Scott: We're like you do all sorts of crazy stuff.
Scott: Like I heard this major people would like make video make, you know, quote video games using like asterisk servers and payphones.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Emily: it's like it's the new program at Tisch and it's like information.
Scott: It's like technology and art in the same major basically, right?
Scott: So they had this little comic that caught my eye because it was about Arduinos and basically all it is a little informational pamphlet.
Scott: That's also a comic that tells you what an Arduino is all about if you don't know.
Scott: Which is what caught my eye and I bought just bought that because but the thing that was really amazing at the table or something You couldn't buy which is sort of like they were just showing off the students work I think trying to convince people to you know, go to school.
Rym: that was burned by that over at the SVA table.
Rym: I was like, ooh, can I buy that?
Rym: and they're like now?
Scott: Yeah, but they had all these pop-up books The students had made.
Rym: Oh, I got a bunch of video those pop-up books.
Scott: It was like it was the Dune one, right?
Scott: There was one that was better than that.
Scott: Oh, I did doom doom Which is the best one.
Scott: and then they had dune.
Scott: But the doom one was just.
Scott: I was so awesome.
Scott: you open up and it's like the cyber demons in there.
Scott: It's like That was.
Rym: those are gonna love the art of a pop-up book.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, that was.
Scott: that was a high quality table.
Scott: I mean if I could go back in time That's what I would major in.
Emily: I see a lot of schools doing the advertising there SVA in particular.
Scott: you get well Half the frickin tables are SVA students.
Scott: I know right?
Emily: It's that's how I feel at my job.
Emily: It's like every other animator I meet their SVA and the quality of work that comes out.
Emily: There's a high quality pretty high caliber.
Emily: So I guess I don't think I've ever been SVA as an art school.
Scott: I've never.
Scott: well, I think what it is.
Scott: I think part of it is you can't get in unless you're already good and I think part of it is that's just a really Good school also.
Scott: So it's like you add the two together and I've never met someone who went to SVA who does not have mad art skills.
Emily: You know, or at least or at least some potential there, you know, of course, maybe they hide all that.
Rym: I I saw they don't bring them to the mocha.
Emily: I saw some pretty bad like at their.
Emily: at the I get all the inside dirt from my my co-workers.
Emily: But I saw a couple real stinkers in terms of computer animation.
Emily: those don't get put on the school demo.
Rym: Actually kind of a random aside, but did you guys notice that this year?
Rym: I think more so than other years there was a surprising amount of price disparities for similar works at different tables.
Rym: Yeah, like I saw like I got I picked up this little comic.
Rym: it was like 50 cents monster country just a cute little thing about Monster girl who eats legendary magical monsters to get their powers and it's kind of like curbing Like a lot just a little bit of asshole Astro boy, but in a different direction like more towards layers.
Rym: But it was like 50 cents or a dollar.
Rym: Similar quality works were at other tables that I looked at my goo.
Rym: This is great and the guys like yeah seven bucks.
Rym: I'm like seven bucks for a thing that you photocopied and stapled together.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you're shitting me.
Emily: I I usually Went for like the $2 ones if it was like more than five and it was just a monotone.
Scott: Yeah, the way I see it the way I see it Right, is that an actual comic book in the shitty floppy monthly format from Marvel or DC is three dollars, right?
Scott: So if you're gonna charge me and that's overpriced as far as I'm concerned now I'm gonna charge me three dollars.
Scott: It's got to be at least as good as an actual comic book.
Rym: Like if it's really great, I'll pay more for it, especially if it is still really Indian I'm not gonna find it or if you're bundling them together or via a lot of pages.
Scott: Yeah Something like that.
Scott: or for example, right?
Scott: I got this.
Scott: this you know.
Scott: What they did is this reminds me of the stuff that we've seen from the enforcer land.
Scott: Basically they took a Batman the Brave and the Bold coloring book, right and they photocopied it straight up complete.
Scott: They didn't give a shit really.
Scott: and then they went all over it and they changed it from Batman the Brave and the Bold to thrift store.
Rym: Batman Sounds pretty good.
Scott: Actually thrift store Batman come quick.
Scott: They're having a sale.
Scott: One more buy one get one free.
Scott: Oh, yeah Scandinavian comments.
Rym: Yep, it was a Danish one and we take.
Rym: the guy was telling us a lot about Danish comics.
Rym: very short very few words.
Rym: The Man of Glass by Martin Flink and it's about a boxer.
Rym: it involves a boxer.
Emily: It's really sad.
Emily: It could be like what's really good movie or something.
Emily: It would be.
Rym: it is really good like movie short.
Scott: They're already a bunch of movies that are just about a boxing and a guy's made of glass.
Rym: This guy is not made.
Rym: Well, it was more about one's heart than about the actual body.
Rym: It's told very well in a just alternating between present past and future.
Emily: Yeah, this is another wordless one.
Emily: See it.
Rym: There's a few words.
Emily: There's a few words, but it's really.
Emily: You know, most of the stuff gets across without any translation or anything.
Rym: So it's actually another.
Rym: look through.
Rym: there are no words really except for one tiny scene until the kind of the moral at the end.
Emily: Yeah, so I'm just gonna go through a quick a few of my my $2 selections.
Emily: For example, I got a very helpful guide to Gaga Because I am not gonna lie as in eight people or as in lady as in lady with the magic.
Scott: It's like a biography or what?
Emily: No, this is a Dissection of the music videos.
Emily: Okay, and it's here.
Emily: I was having Judith laugh and laugh cuz I was reading her Excerpts and it's illustrated right?
Emily: So telephone.
Emily: Gaga is not actually in a club nor is she sipping that bub.
Emily: She is in prison for bitches.
Emily: It is a rather sleazy place but Gaga digs it babe because she gets to make out with hot muscle dykes and watch lady fights.
Rym: I feel like this cover is kind of the same.
Emily: I got a surprise bailout on a telephone.
Emily: I see well.
Emily: Oh, well, she decides to celebrate anywhere by underwear dancing.
Rym: I Think that will serve the same purpose that the literal music videos do.
Emily: for me It's really funny because it's it's they just go through Shot by shot her more popular music videos and kind of highlight how crazy they are.
Emily: You know Gaga is straight chillin with her in with her house when she has this crazy vision.
Emily: Oh shoot She was born a freaky monster born from a bathhouse pod unapologetic queen of the pod monsters.
Emily: So it's just got little pictures to Show Lady Gaga.
Rym: we picked up this really little remember last year.
Rym: We talked about that the sugar spiders 24-hour comics.
Rym: so good Well, it was by Ira Rothwell and she was there again and she had a whole another 24-hour comic like this little water color Ething and it was pretty great Mm-hmm, and I got one called flashlight.
Emily: It's in full color by Megan bear and it's about kids.
Emily: Oh, actually the interior is not in full color.
Emily: I lied But they go down and Explore an abandoned subway track.
Emily: It's all about urban exploration with a flashlight.
Emily: And I got one about sisters.
Emily: go into the ice cream truck.
Emily: And one of the main reasons I got that is because the girls were really cute when they were selling it and they had these Little buttons where if you bought the comic they'd give you your favorite ice cream on a button.
Scott: And so they only had a few choices.
Emily: They made you choose like the girls in the comic should I get a rocket pop or should I get the chocolate eclair pop.
Emily: or Should I get ice cream sandwich?
Emily: Yeah, the ice cream sandwich Make the Decision like the girls are in the comic, but it was.
Emily: it was just really cute and very relatable as you know.
Emily: growing up in in the suburbs and getting ice cream with my sis, so there's that.
Emily: and And what's somebody?
Rym: oh Yeah, this is just a direct retelling of Swan Lake.
Scott: Oh really give me that shit.
Rym: It's really big format - and a lot of the faces room very reminiscent of But just the way like the boat when the swans are bored kind of just regarding the guy.
Rym: that just that's a very Kate beaten Face right there.
Rym: there the eyes are but yeah, I can see it's just a straight retelling.
Rym: That's actually very artful very good.
Rym: Well the story is very sad.
Emily: Yeah, I know.
Emily: and then you got another retelling of a folktale with animal transformation But not quite as seriously.
Emily: It's called derp the comic.
Scott: oh, all right because it was because it was called derp.
Emily: you bought it Derp and then it was.
Emily: it's the The frog Tsarina story from Russia where there's the enchanted frog and she turns into princess.
Rym: It's like you have to marry the frog cuz that's what happens.
Scott: Anyway, so I got this comic who is Amy amoeba And I bought it because it was an amoeba on the cover, and I was like alright Whatever it actually was a story about the amoeba who splits in half right and then it's like I'm Amy amoeba.
Scott: No, I'm Amy amoeba right.
Scott: and then as time goes on you know the it's it's all it gets like really philosophy Philosophical like you know and they they like when there's so many amoebas.
Scott: It's like they want to worship Amy amoeba But they're like which one's the original one and one of them claims to be that.
Scott: you know it's.
Scott: it got really Philosophical is actually quite surprising.
Scott: for a tiny little comic here I got this thing that was just.
Scott: it's basically like a few pieces of paper from you know stapled together Called no gods no kings only cheeseburgers.
Scott: It's from Michael Clayton at Michael Clayton illustration calm and You know I mean, it's just pretty much like black and white sort of just little you know But a mixed up bunch of comics that aren't really related to each other, but they were actually really hilarious Especially this one about spider-man.
Scott: when he gets a boner It's like spider-man takes down gang while holding book.
Scott: I didn't want to lose the book.
Scott: That's why I kept it so close to me I Got this thing called poop toast because it was called poop toast and it's about a piece of toast with poop on its head Aside from the cute little robots.
Emily: toast is toast.
Emily: I saw like at least four different comics that were like something something toast.
Emily: I was like what's with this hipster fascination with toast.
Rym: Yeah, I saw two hero.
Scott: I saw one comic that was about actual lettuce and another comic that had a character named lettuce.
Scott: That was a rabbit.
Emily: No, no there was a third one with lettuce.
Emily: Yeah, there was one called lettuce girl, and but it was about it.
Scott: That's the dentist the one with actual lettuce.
Emily: oh Was it actually like she?
Emily: but it's not anthropomorphic leathers.
Scott: No I guess not.
Scott: But yeah poop toast is about a piece of toast with poop on its head and there were actually three parts.
Scott: But you know what it's not done.
Scott: at the end of the day He actually is a continuing series and at the end of the third part It was like they got arrested, and then it was like to be continued.
Scott: I'm like are you shitting me?
Emily: Which was my favorite from the mocha last year?
Scott: and what?
Scott: what is up with?
Scott: like Like earthworms always being a sidekick of some sort right like Ollie or Richard scary You know.
Scott: or and then this.
Emily: it's like the earthworm is always the sidekick character Because you can make him cute, but you can't make him quite expressive enough to qualify for main character.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think we need something about a worm.
Scott: He's not a but these are like he's like.
Scott: You know earthworm Jim is a lot more going on.
Rym: No.
Rym: He's an actual earthworm.
Rym: He just happened to find a suit.
Scott: Anyway, I bought this.
Scott: it was called the three little gamers.
Scott: I got it cuz it was called the three little gamers.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically.
Scott: it seems like sort of one of those things.
Scott: they tell the stories of their own nerdiness you know.
Scott: and one guy's.
Scott: you know two guys think they're cooler than the other guy because he's a boffo weapon guy but they're video game guys and It's by.
Scott: let's see Maggie Siegel barely combo game fanboys calm.
Scott: March 2011.
Scott: I got something called similarly called controller And I bought that because the design of it is that the packaging of the comic was in an NES sleeve.
Scott: It looked the comic looks like an NES cartridge And it comes with a paper.
Scott: well construction paper NES sleeve to put it in.
Scott: Comic itself you know wasn't that exciting.
Scott: it was basically like You know remembering you know childhood and stuff like that and a guy Sort of being upset that he's like a big-time video game collector But doesn't really play video games anymore, and I wasn't that exciting.
Scott: But the packaging was too cool to not pass to not purchase.
Rym: I picked up this little.
Rym: it was a hardcover book of Japanese monsters of the bento bestiary.
Rym: Oh, that looks so awesome.
Rym: It got points because it had really good art and also really good text.
Rym: like there's a little Story from the perspective of each monster.
Rym: I think my favorite one.
Emily: I didn't know about.
Scott: yeah I didn't know about the big bestiary fan.
Rym: the one.
Rym: I really like was the one Yoda.
Scott: What does he do?
Rym: he rolls you to hell?
Scott: He's a flaming wheel jigoku.
Rym: He's a burning wheel, but I really I think my favorite one is the Umi bozo.
Rym: He's really cute like a giant sea monster and the text is the fishermen always want to play the same game But I don't mind.
Rym: first I'll pop up from under the sea and make the biggest of big waves.
Rym: Then they'll scream because they're so happy and they'll make the boat move really quick.
Rym: Then there's usually some splashing and I roar and laugh and a bit later They get really tired and they go into the sea for a sleep.
Rym: They must get tired really easy.
Rym: And he's just really cute.
Emily: Whales or weird kind of tsunami Effects or something.
Emily: I'm being a whale at the same time No, but it's like it was basically like this big water that would it's baby swamps.
Emily: Okay Come up under the boat and be like blue Get almost she.
Scott: she there at the baby swamps, you know, it would.
Emily: it would be weird.
Emily: I like the the person who was like a cad I forget.
Emily: anyway moving on I got a. you know my pick of the cute robot thing was actually this kind of sad and melancholic little comic called heaven all day and it's about the story of an inventor and a homeless robot.
Emily: and Well, their paths do not directly cross.
Emily: it's about the effects that you know Someone unrelated can have on somebody else's life, I guess.
Emily: But it's you know.
Emily: judging from the cover I thought it was going to be more of a light-hearted thing, but it was actually.
Emily: it was very good But it was.
Emily: it was kind of sad.
Scott: Mm-hmm I bought this thing just because it seemed pretty cool and because you know, there were so many robots going on.
Scott: I was like.
Scott: you will not tempt me with robots.
Scott: I'm gonna go classic and reward the person who has a dragon.
Scott: So this thing it was a little tiny book and it said you stupid dragon.
Emily: Oh, I love that.
Scott: Right, so it's like it's a book and you flip the page and as you turn the pages you're following There's a big.
Scott: it's a big long green dragon And as you turn the pages you're following, you know, the this dragon and there's all this sort of weird stuff all around him.
Rym: I love that style of you know children's books often had themes like that.
Scott: Yeah, and basically you get to the end and then you get to the beginning again.
Scott: and the thing it's really cool If you actually unfold it.
Scott: You'll see how he made it is.
Scott: he drew this big dragon on one big piece of paper and then cut it in a clever Way so that it folds into a book where you can turn the pages and follow the dragon.
Scott: It's it's pretty fun.
Scott: I also got these two things.
Scott: It's a it's a pinball zine.
Scott: These guys are starting and it was at two different tables.
Rym: I think I said that already because one of the guys at one table one of the guys at another table and I just remember the guy at the table at the time was dressed somewhat hipster ish Mm-hmm, and where I was like tell me about your deal.
Rym: and he's like he was like.
Rym: So we start talking and he's like man.
Rym: you want to play some pinball.
Rym: There's this place in Brooklyn.
Rym: You've probably never heard of it.
Scott: It's near Williamsburg But I do want to go check out that pinball, yeah Yeah, but anyway I started reading the first pinball zine and it's pretty good because it starts out for like complete beginners.
Scott: Like it tells you what all the parts of the pinball machine are and how they work And then it gets into some history stuff and both of these zines.
Scott: They actually have a lot of content in them for being the you know These small sort of inexpensively printed books and each one has a full-color design of a non-existent pinball table.
Scott: The first one has a quidditch Harry Potter pinball table, which I don't care about Harry Potter But it looks like a good table.
Scott: and the second one also has an avatar the last airbender table Which looks like an even better table, but I care even less about.
Rym: Though to spite all of our friends from our IT who Insisted to this day that safecracker is the best pinball machine ever they had heard of safecracker and they said it was good But it was not the best.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to go check out the zine, it's drop target zine dot blogspot.com.
Scott: I'm gonna try to get all the issues of this and read them all because it's really pretty interesting.
Emily: Speaking of hipsters in Brooklyn.
Emily: This is another one.
Emily: I got her free.
Emily: She was actually handing out these 20-page comics and is called Wizards and it's about this hipster girl who gets sucked into this vortex to a fantasy land.
Emily: and she says on the cover I think I messed up But it's wizards tumblr.com.
Emily: So I'm assuming it's a webcomic and I'm gonna have to check it out because it ends right when she gets into the magical world.
Emily: And after all these shenanigans happen in the real world, and so I'm like, why did you leave me at a cliffhanger?
Rym: Give free taste.
Scott: She's not getting away something for free.
Scott: that has closure true enough.
Rym: I picked up again.
Rym: I still have to read.
Rym: we have that play I bought at mocha last year.
Rym: I read it.
Emily: I read it.
Emily: I want to read it.
Emily: It was depressing and full of drama.
Emily: Well, I picked up again cuz it's drum.
Rym: I saw it would look like some Civil War drama comics.
Rym: I pick it up and it turns out that a brief rest in a shallow grave and other stories is short fiction.
Rym: As in just written fiction with a few illustrations.
Rym: I I just bought everything the guy had cuz.
Rym: it was super cheap and he seemed cool.
Rym: I haven't read it yet, but I don't know.
Rym: I'm really feeling short stories again.
Rym: That was something I was really into in like high school era of my life Like I just buy compendiums of short story short attention span theater.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, anyway, so I was trying to buy something else, you know, but I was sort of like whatever I was on my way out.
Scott: There was this table that I had passed by a couple times and it was a collective of Boston people right and they basically what they did is they put all their mini comics together into two bundles the red bundle and the Blue bundle.
Scott: the blue bundle was kid-friendly the red bundle.
Scott: It's not porn but not exactly kid-friendly Right and it had a little.
Scott: that's how I knew.
Scott: it was a Bostonian thing because it comes in a little cloth bag With a silkscreen of either red or blue.
Scott: Paul Revere on a horse on the front.
Emily: totally high quality.
Scott: So I got.
Scott: so I just picked.
Scott: I was like, yeah, I'll get the blue one.
Scott: So here's what was inside.
Scott: first of all bored angel was in there.
Scott: I was like, oh, I know bored angel I have bored angel have bored angel.
Scott: But anyway, I bored angels.
Scott: good There was one called Lumix which was actually probably the best one that was in there.
Scott: It's basically this big giant dude, right?
Scott: Who's an accidental superhero?
Scott: He's actually really clumsy and he just all hits the bad all his clubs.
Scott: all his clumsiness hits the bad guys And it's like it's pretty great.
Scott: How to grow a giant monster was literally how to grow a giant monster by Eric Boa car webcomics nation comm slash e boa car Higher ground.
Scott: Well, it's actually higher ground.
Scott: is this thing about like dinosaurs?
Scott: and It's the guys like trying to open an egg.
Scott: so he's trying to get to higher ground so he can drop it and It wasn't particularly that exciting.
Scott: It's by Shelley Parallon, but the art is really good.
Scott: It's like it's like yellow and then lighter yellow and then it's pretty cute.
Emily: Yeah, yellow.
Scott: There was this thing called el oso which was entirely in Spanish.
Scott: I don't really I could kind of follow it but kind of all right.
Rym: So speaking of Spanish that the only trade kind of things I picked up there bit their issues, but it was put out by archaea.
Rym: They're not terribly small feeding ground, which is it's six volumes.
Rym: Apparently I got the first four.
Rym: It's printed doubly to where it's in Spanish and English Mm-hmm, but it's a where the front is English in the back is Spanish.
Rym: It's actually where coyotes and It's all it's really.
Rym: it's like this werewolf story but set in Mexican culture near the border with the border crossings and the Border Patrol in the US and the towns and It's just an interesting take on the old werewolf story.
Rym: and the werewolves are actually cool.
Scott: speaking of werewolves like bought a new Jason comic werewolves of Montpellier and it's kind of sad because it's like I bought all the Jason comics and their individual forms, but now they're selling hardcovers that collect a whole bunch each.
Scott: So it's like you could just buy all these hardcovers.
Rym: I almost bought all the hardcovers at the moment.
Scott: It's like I bought all the individuals.
Scott: So now I was looking at him.
Rym: I was like, ah, there's Jason in here.
Rym: I haven't read and it's Jason and hardcover.
Scott: It's like I own all the Jason's anyway.
Scott: the last two things in the Boston book There was spider day night fever, which is just a whole bunch of Marvel characters drawn in hilarious dancing positions.
Scott: That's all that is I can never.
Scott: they were all spider-man characters.
Scott: and the last thing was actually Reggie and Brian and the lousy nickname.
Scott: And it's basically about this kid who lives in a fishing village and he's a fisherman with all the other fishermen, right?
Scott: Only he's young and they're all old and his.
Scott: they call him.
Scott: they give him a nickname which is Krusty because his boat always has all the barnacles on it, right and He basically tries to get rid of the barnacles so he can get his nickname change to something else.
Scott: So he goes and he really asked the mermaid and the mermaid.
Scott: Well, it's actually a mer dude wearing a sweater.
Scott: His mer dude friend is like, oh the barnacles.
Scott: They just like your boat because it's the most comfortable.
Scott: and he's like, ah shit.
Scott: Well, how do I get him off?
Scott: He's like, oh you just got to say the magic words, you know in Murph in barnacle language, which is Lulu Lulu Lulu Lulu Right.
Scott: So if he goes to get his boat inspected So he's hoping it he's right.
Scott: he says Lulu Lulu to get all the barnacles off and his boat is super clean.
Scott: So he's like, oh, I guess you can't call you Krusty anymore.
Scott: Your new nickname is Lulu.
Scott: He's like, ah shit It's pretty funny even though I just gave it all away.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of a lot of these.
Scott: it's comics comics dot Metro kitty calm.
Scott: They tend to be like a short like six-page.
Scott: It's like one joke.
Scott: Yeah, this thing is like if a comic is just one joke and I don't tell you the joke Then you're not gonna understand why it's worthwhile.
Scott: But it's like if I tell you the joke, then you're not gonna need to read that comic.
Scott: But the thing is all these people.
Scott: this is just like, you know, you can go to their websites and get more of their stuff.
Scott: Yeah, they get all the jokes.
Emily: stuff is available on line for the for the most part, you know A lot of times they'll just put their webcomic URL on it.
Emily: And so really what you're doing by buying these things?
Emily: It's not even that like half of them You won't ever see again and you can't find it.
Emily: and it's just like people making zines.
Emily: and the other half.
Emily: It's like support webcomic artists.
Scott: Hooray so I have one last thing.
Emily: I One of the things I picked up.
Emily: I want a geek bite this sometime but it's a really cute.
Rym: Oh, is that the learn kanji slash lesbians thing?
Emily: No, it's not learn kanji.
Rym: Assume that was a learning kanji.
Emily: She means kind of like Rica.
Emily: That's like kind of because it says the cut the kanji.
Rym: You thought it was a kanji book assumed that it taught you kanji.
Rym: I'd never looked inside of it.
Rym: No, I've seen it laying around.
Emily: it's this book I picked up back when the mocha was in the puck building and It's a Japanese indie comic.
Emily: but the author I think she either lives here part-time or Full-time now and cuz she really likes New York and she's been published in English by any lesbo.
Emily: come publishing.
Emily: But the cute thing is it's.
Emily: it's a very very different than your usual manga.
Emily: It's you know, like dot.
Emily: I is very very doodly kind of style and I dig data.
Emily: It was actually one of the first Like popular.
Emily: well for an indie comic Japanese comics that dealt with lesbian issues in a real way and wasn't all tragic or Wasn't all explicit.
Emily: It was just two college girls being like I like you and you know kind of getting on with their relationship and going to school and stuff and so The one I picked up this year.
Emily: I talked to Rika Takashima who was there and she signed it for me But it was the.
Emily: well, I picked it up partly because it's got what Vocaloid cosplay on the cover, but It's a little indie comic about one of the main characters from Rika Takashi Growing up Miho-chan and it's about her as a little kid.
Emily: She's very tomboyish.
Emily: It's not even so much about being a lesbian.
Emily: It's more like about being a girl who likes to run around and get into trouble.
Scott: Very cute 20% cooler.
Emily: That's exactly the phrase.
Rym: I'll have to read Rika's kanji.
Emily: Yeah, the only sad thing is this this new collection that I bought, you know, it's it's unfinished it's it's pencil sketches because the earthquake Like was very upsetting and she spent a lot of time like Contacting her friends and doing volunteer stuff and everything.
Emily: So she didn't have time to finish before the mocha.
Scott: She had time to print it.
Emily: Well, you know, it's like she took her sketches and put it together but it's like she.
Emily: she didn't concentrate full-time on the comic and I guess a lot of the Japanese people who I know, you know, if they're artists they tend to Be a little behind because of stuff that's been going on.
Emily: So anyway, I'd recommend that and especially the original Rika Takashi.
Rym: It's very cute Hmm and overall I'd say the mocha was as good as last year.
Rym: In fact, I say better than last year for one reason.
Rym: They only turned on half of the ceiling lights Yeah, and thank goodness.
Emily: They had some airflow in there a little bit.
Rym: I didn't realize how hot it was and it doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't really get hot until later in the afternoon when it gets crowded early In the day, it's actually pretty good.
Emily: you go into that one corner And it's like the corner with the door venting in and it's just like oh my god Over by the artists.
Emily: and so one more.
Scott: one more thing that I got there right was the thing that was getting a lot of people's attention because the Production value of it is just so incredibly high as the anthology project and the anthology projects actually been around.
Scott: I guess it's sort of like the same thing as flight only smaller and hardcovers.
Scott: It's the same idea.
Scott: Anyway, where I get really high quality arts into an anthology book.
Scott: That's that with high production value typically all They.
Emily: they're not actually comic artists they work in other aspects of it doesn't really?
Scott: I only read the first volume.
Scott: I didn't read the second one yet like it doesn't really say.
Scott: it's just like anthology project.
Scott: All right, here we go comics And they're all really really well drawn.
Scott: Like.
Scott: there's a whole wide range of art styles and the arts are all whether no matter what style it is They're all pretty amazing.
Scott: But I think I would totally believe that these are not comics people because a lot of the comics especially some of the wordless ones It's hard to follow.
Scott: like.
Scott: obviously the person has skills in drawing but not doing sequential flow in any way.
Scott: So it's like you can't tell what's going on unless you go really slowly and really try to think pretty hard about it.
Scott: And you know a lot of the.
Scott: a lot of the writing on some of them was you know Uninteresting but the art on all of them was amazing.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: volume two is thicker and is newer and the cover is cooler looking.
Scott: So maybe that'll be a different story.
Scott: But I mean the art is just as amazing.
Scott: and they had a special deal by both for 50 bucks.
Scott: That's 25 each.
Scott: It's a pretty good deal for such like.
Scott: it's like you should see them if you look at these things.
Scott: They're like a mate, you know, it's like the highest quality most expensive printing you can get.
Scott: so, you know You buy this the sort of the same reason.
Scott: you would buy something like robot or Apple, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, beautiful expensive high color printing of awesome arts.
Scott: that happens to be comics, you know.
Scott: and then maybe some of them are actually good comics, they're all really short and It's a lot of eye candy basically, so I guess last and not least we can't at least talk about that The Johnny Wonder crew finally had a table.
Scott: Yeah, they never had a table there even though they've gone there every year.
Rym: every year We're like, how come you guys don't get a table?
Scott: They're like It is expensive, but it's for charity.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: it's not like PAX or New York Comic Con where it's you know It's going into someone's wallet, right?
Scott: Reason the tables are so expensive because that's the fundraiser that keeps the mocha around.
Emily: Yay Anyway, okay.
Emily: Hooray.
Emily: It was a fun fest and We told you all about a bajillion comics and now we're gonna go.
Scott: Oh, and don't forget the funniest comic was 12 labors of gastrophobia.
Scott: So you should go to the website for it, which is I guess I don't remember I Will promote David McGuire.
Scott: it is so hilarious.
Scott: I'm not even joking.
Rym: I will stand by saying that you should probably check out the archaea for the feeding ground that coyote Mexican werewolf story.
Scott: Okay, a studio press also published because there's a mouse guard.
Rym: I read the first four and it was good enough to where I pretty much have to buy the next two to find out What's kind of hard to go wrong.
Scott: buying anything that's published by our can.
Rym: pretty much This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Rym: music can't leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night Because he looked at the cutie mark.
Rym: I'm waiting for the pony whose cutie mark is a pony so They're just gonna make babies.
Emily: That's like saying Scott being like my Damon is a little man.
Rym: Yeah, so mate.
Rym: What's that point?
Rym: Maybe that pony is just really into ponies.
Scott: It'd be a doctor.
Emily: I Wonder if people's cutie marks get old outmoded so like they could have the computer pony and then if they started computer in the 70s They'd have like a little tape.
Rym: Mr.. Breezy is way old and his cutie mark is that old style fan.
Scott: see see that's interesting like.
Emily: I wonder if when you get Your cutie well
Scott: granny smith has a granny pie, but
Rym: granny smith apples doesn't.
Rym: I mean maybe that's just why she's Doesn't go out of style.
Scott: What about?
Scott: there was like the ponies in Cloudsdale had like footballs and basketballs and stuff and Barton right.
Scott: so what if?
Scott: Well no, but like what?
Scott: if you know you're into football, and you're like a football star But then football goes away because no one cares about it anymore, but you still have a football.
Rym: you're sad pony.
Emily: That's like being a high school football star and then failing.
Rym: you know that's like having a Hartford Oilers tattoo you.