Rym: It's Wednesday, August 3rd, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, anime we should see.
Scott: We want to see.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Ah, it's so sad.
Rym: Second year in a row this past weekend was Otakon and we weren't there.
Rym: It was weird.
Rym: It was still, to this day, two years in a row, it is weird to not be at Otakon.
Rym: Even though almost no one I know went except for, like, you know, Anime World Order and Mike Tool and all them.
Rym: And, like, a tiny handful of the crew.
Rym: Almost everyone else also bailed on it, so.
Scott: People seem to follow us.
Scott: They're followers.
Scott: Plus, you know, most of the people, they're not into the, you know, the anime.
Scott: If you're not, you know, like us, doing a bunch of stuff at the anime convention, it doesn't really have anything for you as much, right?
Rym: The thing is, it could.
Rym: It just doesn't.
Scott: Otakon actually does.
Scott: If I didn't live in New York with no car anymore, you know, if I was still in Beacon with a car, or maybe even further south with a car, or something like that, I would probably still go to Otakon.
Rym: Would you stand in that line?
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: It's tough, right?
Scott: Because it also depends on the hotel and all that stuff.
Scott: But it's like, if Otakon was a little more convenient, I want to go because it's actually one of the only anime cons that has stuff I actually want to see.
Scott: Like, you know, the movies and the Japanese guests and whatever.
Rym: Of course, what saddens me is that the stuff I want to see currently is not what anyone else wants to see.
Rym: That's good!
Rym: I heard tell from multiple sources that after the Makoto Shinkai movie, there was a Makoto Shinkai-like panel.
Rym: And almost everybody walked out.
Rym: They didn't care about him.
Rym: They just wanted to see the premiere.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know, at least they saw his movie.
Scott: It's better than nothing.
Rym: Yeah, and the Trigun movie, people said it was okay.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see.
Scott: I wasn't there, so I don't know.
Rym: Yep, I don't know exactly.
Rym: At least Daryl got to run Anime as Crazy as Deaths.
Scott: I'm sure it was 100% packed house completely.
Rym: Yeah, absolutely.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I would have gone to that had I been there.
Scott: I would have attempted to as well.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I feel like it would take such a little effort to make Otakon almost twice as good.
Scott: Yeah, but here's the thing.
Scott: By my count, Otakon actually had a huge attendance jump this year.
Scott: To 31,000, they said?
Scott: Something like that?
Rym: Well, I didn't even check the official numbers yet, but they did.
Rym: Now that they have the Hilton, they have a much higher cap.
Scott: Yeah, they raised their number.
Scott: I think now, by my numbers, they might be bigger than the San Diego Comic-Con.
Scott: Because the San Diego Comic-Con has a number of like 140,000.
Scott: Some ungodly number, right?
Scott: But you don't realize, San Diego Comic-Con starts Wednesday night.
Scott: It's preview night.
Scott: Then it's Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
Rym: So, think about this.
Rym: They do turnstile.
Scott: They are multiplying that number.
Scott: That number divided by five is the real number.
Scott: Now, granted, when you look at videos of San Diego, the lines are way longer than Otakon lines.
Rym: But there are fewer headlining events that are concurrent.
Scott: And the crowds are packed much more densely.
Scott: But I think, I haven't been there, so I don't know.
Scott: San Diego is mostly one big room.
Scott: Imagine if everyone at Otakon was in the dealer's room the whole time.
Scott: Sure as fuck, even if that dealer's room was two or three times as big, you could be sure as hell that it would be as crowded as San Diego, right?
Scott: But the people at Otakon are spread out over a much wider space.
Scott: Also, you see those gigantic lines to see incredibly famous people in the infamous Hall H. Or there's a ballroom also.
Scott: that's like the second most popular room.
Scott: But Otakon has seven panel rooms, right?
Scott: I think there's some ungodly number of panel rooms and some seven video rooms.
Scott: And they're gigantic and there's so many of them.
Scott: From what I've never been to San Diego, I could be wrong.
Scott: From what I've heard other people talking about, it seems like they pretty much have the two gigantic panel rooms for famous shit and then a bunch of small ones.
Scott: So, I'm actually gonna say that by my count, as of now, Otakon is the biggest geek convention in the United States.
Scott: Possibly the world.
Rym: There's a reason why, when PAX was like, "Yeah, we're gonna have PAX
Rym: East."
Rym: And they were like,
Rym: "Boston?"
Rym: We were like,
Rym: "Eh.".
Scott: Yeah, and I would go to Otakon if I wasn't doing anything, if it was a little bit more convenient.
Scott: That's just my personal situation.
Rym: Yeah, but simultaneously, it's kind of like everything's going well for now.
Scott: It's like they could be even better with the smallest amount of effort.
Scott: It's so simple.
Rym: Just redo the screening rooms to have people actually talking about the stuff.
Scott: Mail badges.
Rym: Mail the badges and have a keynote.
Rym: Just have, you know, you've got Makoto Shinkai, get him to do a keynote.
Rym: Get Mike Toole to do a keynote.
Rym: Get someone.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: Get the first con chair of Otakon ever.
Scott: The person's not dead, right?
Rym: Jim Voll should do it, actually.
Rym: He's probably one of the more important- I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, he's a great guy, but I don't know what his public speaking skills are like.
Rym: I think he would do okay.
Scott: I'm sure he could do just fine, but, you know, it's like, is he, you know, an amazing public speaker?
Scott: I haven't heard him public speak.
Rym: Otakon gets the A-list of Japanese guests, and yet hardly anyone cares to even see them, except to get autographs signed.
Rym: Or if they're American voice actors.
Scott: I would just not bring the non-Japanese guests.
Rym: No, I would bring them anyway, but I'd bring a little bit less, and more importantly, I would do.
Rym: the one thing that the New York Anime Festival did well, if you forget the fact that they didn't actually have a translator, is, you know, they sell this big keynote thing, and they promoted the ever-living fuck out of the fact that they had Japanese guests,
Scott: and they
Rym: packed that room.
Scott: They sure did.
Rym: There is no excuse for Otakon not packing the room of at least Makoto Shinkai.
Scott: I think Otakon pushes a musical guest harder.
Scott: Wait, what was Otakon's musical guest this year?
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: Chemistry.
Scott: Who's chemistry?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'll be honest, I kind of stopped paying attention after- But the thing was, Otakon had huge musical guests for multiple years in a row.
Scott: TMR, right?
Scott: And then, you know, chemistry may or may not be big, but I haven't heard of them.
Rym: Of course, we're kind of disconnected from that scene.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: I mean, we used to be much more into the anime.
Scott: I imagine they did the opener to some anime that's really popular that we don't watch.
Rym: I mean, remember back in the day when the rumors, I'd always hear people, even at RIT, being like, "Yeah, I heard Otakon got 2 Mix next
Rym: year.".
Scott: Yeah, I'm still waiting for the 2 Mix Ayumi.
Rym: Oh my god, 2 Mix Ayumi Megumi.
Scott: I don't think one of those girl groups like AKB48 or Morning Musume or Girls' Generation or some shit.
Rym: That would probably generate a pretty big crowd.
Scott: That would explode.
Rym: And the thing is- It'd be like, "Yeah, guess what?
Scott: We're not bringing a musical guest like a band.
Scott: We're bringing 48 girlies.
Scott: Watch
Scott: out.".
Rym: They'd have to do a Japanese-style talk show, like have a room where it's them poking at cats or whatever it is they make them do on TV.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: But yeah, if you guys wanted us at Otakon, tell them.
Rym: If you were at Otakon and you saw good panels like Mike Tools or Daryl Sarats or Geralds or Clarissas, they have a forum where you can tell them what was a good panel.
Rym: And most importantly, the excuse that Otakon gave years in a row when we tried to get them to get Super Art Fight, which is one of the most amazing performance art.
Rym: that is competitive art.
Scott: Literal drawing, two-dimensional art I've ever seen.
Scott: It would be epic at Otakon or PAX.
Scott: Right now, it's epic at Kinetacon.
Scott: It's like, "Hey, there's a great reason to come to Kinetacon.
Scott: We've got Super Art Fight, which is the highest class event that isn't at the real
Scott: conventions.".
Rym: For years, before we were staff on Otakon, when we were staff on Otakon, and after we quit being staff on Otakon, we were like, "Get Super Art
Rym: Fight.".
Rym: It would be so ungodly popular.
Rym: It fills the Kinetacon main events, which is way big.
Rym: It's bigger than anime Bostons, I think.
Rym: Seating-wise, I think it is.
Scott: Equal-ish.
Rym: It depends on where that partition at the back goes.
Rym: I'd have to get some numbers.
Scott: Tough call.
Rym: Yeah, I'll try to figure out if they're the same.
Scott: It is close.
Rym: And it's getting bigger next year.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Then it will definitely be.
Rym: But their excuse was always, "Oh, we have Iron Artist.
Rym: We can't have two of the same kind of event.
Rym: We have a long working relationship with Iron
Rym: Artist.".
Scott: Well, we heard that Iron Artist was not at Otakon this year.
Rym: Yeah, in fact, Super Art Fight, I was talking to them and I was like,
Rym: "Yeah.".
Rym: They told us when we brought it up that it was because they had Iron Artist.
Rym: He was like, "Iron
Rym: Artist?".
Rym: And then he gets back to me and I was like, "That was definitely not on the
Rym: schedule.".
Scott: Dun dun dunnnnnn.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But, yeah, Super Art Fight, if you want to see them at ConnectiCon, they'll be there.
Rym: And if you want to see them at PAX, tell PAX.
Scott: Go to the PAX forums, make a thread.
Rym: Because we have told them, so hopefully we'll get them.
Scott: PAX East.
Scott: They're probably not going to West.
Scott: It's a little too close to the--.
Rym: I'll bet we could get them to go to West.
Rym: If the thing is West-- Not right now.
Rym: The problem is it'd be hard to fit them in because any West is already full to the brim-- East oh 12.
Scott: that's our pushing for central London and the cruise right anyway.
Scott: anyway speaking of conventions, right?
Scott: You know New York comic-con is coming up pretty soon and normally we don't care that much about what's going on.
Scott: It's your comic.
Rym: I mean with blue like our one or two panels.
Rym: Yeah, well do the walk around interview some people But there's actually.
Scott: there was just news someone's gonna be at the New York Comic Con.
Rym: I wonder who?
Scott: you wonder who?
Rym: I haven't looked at the Internet.
Scott: It's someone that I would wait in a long line to see.
Scott: I wouldn't pay to get the VIP badge to see them But I would wait in a long line huh, so we're gonna see how it goes down, and it's someone who?
Scott: They might go to other conventions, but I've never heard of them being at another convention at least not recently.
Rym: I know it's not but I'm gonna guess Lauren Faust because I can't imagine you being more excited about someone.
Scott: no yeah Yeah, you know who it is Rainbow Dash.
Rym: no I don't know who it is.
Rym: I haven't looked at the news.
Scott: It is Franklin Miller is going to be at the New York Comic Con.
Scott: Really, yes really I?
Rym: Want to go to a Q&A with him.
Rym: I know right what I I'd ask him something about whores.
Rym: I'd be like.
Rym: so do you really like the aesthetic of whores?
Scott: I don't know what his personality is like at all.
Scott: so it's gonna be.
Rym: I know if you go You don't want to ask first I mean what if he's an Alan Moore, but at the same time I mean it's hard to say I know very little about his non-professional life.
Scott: The only thing I know about him is I read Eisner Miller Which is just basically a book.
Scott: that is a conversate that is a that is basically a written-down Recording of a conversation between him and Will Eisner, and he seemed like a nice normal guy pretty much so I Couldn't really tell his personality.
Scott: It was just a guy who was a comic expert talking about comics, so it's it doesn't really tell me about him.
Scott: But if I had to ask him a question, I would definitely ask him Robocop questions Because those would be that you know there's people are gonna ask him plenty of bad.
Scott: You know what that is.
Rym: That's the equivalent of we need Daryl Saratian style questions at more non-anime events.
Rym: You got to basically go into any press thing find whatever that famous person's crystal triangle is and ask about nothing.
Scott: That's right, so There you go.
Rym: so things of the day.
Rym: a long time ago I Bought well bought.
Rym: I basically sent VHS tapes that were sent back to me.
Rym: all of Sailor Moon all of it all 200 episodes.
Rym: I watched all of it and some of my friends watched all of it, and we had an inside joke.
Rym: This is pre front row crew.
Rym: This is like back from the day of eight people gaga and the joke was Excuse me.
Rym: What time is it now?
Scott: It's for party.
Rym: I've never heard this and then the first person would say thank you It was this ritual.
Rym: I you know friend groups you have like that ritual eyes like weird greeting like hello.
Scott: Oh Yeah, I've never heard this one before because it was my old crew like a high school But it was in Sailor Moon.
Rym: There was.
Rym: this is random scene where this guy Randomly just starts speaking in English and are there three people speaking in English?
Rym: We're hitting critical mass here inside jokes.
Rym: but uh so Sailor Moon has a wealth of scenes where random motherfuckers speaks English but it's clearly just one of the Japanese voice actors and They're always awful, so I submit for your consideration One of those scenes from Sailor Moon also.
Rym: It's kind of a I don't know sort of an aside But you'll see this in a lot of anime like what was the old?
Rym: I hate the Japanese people.
Rym: all Japanese people are stupid.
Scott: I don't remember that was a dub of.
Rym: it was a sub of some show and a guy just says that in English Cracks an egg over another guy's head.
Rym: Anyway, so also if you haven't seen Sailor Moon at all ever It's kind of a trick to get you to look at a YouTube video that happens to kind of as the Sailor Moon looks like like for real People don't know it.
Rym: I don't think a lot of people who listen to GeekNights have actually seen Sailor Moon.
Scott: I haven't watched like a whole episode of it, but I've seen plenty of it.
Scott: I know what it looks like.
Scott: I can spot it from a mile away.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: plus you might have you probably only really recognized when she is Sailor Moon as she's Sailor Moon.
Scott: No, I know when she's not Sailor Moon.
Scott: Ah She looks the same only without a skirt jeans and a sweater.
Rym: Sometimes.
Rym: sometimes she wears other things.
Scott: was that your thing of the day?
Rym: that was my thing of the day.
Scott: So you know what you know.
Scott: sometimes I use the webcomic as a thing of the day, right?
Scott: Which is also always pretty good, but the thing a lot of people don't know is that I guess they do know.
Scott: Maybe I don't know whatever Webcomic artists they draw a lot more than just their webcomic, you know, they make lots of sketches and notebooks all the time.
Rym: Yeah, like remember a lot of people don't realize or at least didn't realize before Atomic Robo that a bit theater.
Scott: Yeah, that guy can draw What anyway, Brian clever could you can draw?
Scott: Yeah, I didn't know that he could draw.
Scott: we can.
Rym: I'll show you some his art really anyway.
Scott: So it's always good if you can go and find.
Scott: for example Some artists will put theirs they'll make sketches and put them on Twitter and they'll be on Twitter.
Scott: pick Yeah, and some of them they might be on.
Scott: why frog which is the same shit?
Scott: Some people might put him in like a Picasa or a deviant art or a something something, right?
Scott: Well, I found out today from some Twitter links that John Allison from scary-go-round Right.
Rym: Yeah, I forgot all about that comic.
Rym: Yeah, I really liked that comic.
Rym: I'm gonna start reading that comic again.
Scott: So he puts his on flicker and he drew some Thundercats that are At our epic hilarity.
Scott: Oh, like I can't even say hilarious because I mean, I mean just look at this fucking snarf.
Rym: Oh My god that That pushes all the same buttons that like Kate Beaton art does.
Scott: well I know.
Scott: in fact Kate beaten linked it and I thought it might have been Kate beaten in the first place.
Scott: But no, it wasn't.
Scott: so this is a quite the excellent, you know It's a whole.
Scott: you can look through his whole flicker account is my thing of the day.
Scott: Oh my god, Lee is you know, it's full of gems.
Rym: I can't believe.
Rym: I didn't know this existed.
Rym: I also guess 500.
Scott: I think is 519 things in his photo stream, but specifically these two Thundercats.
Scott: one I can't believe.
Rym: I forgot that webcomic existed.
Rym: I think when I built my new computer I just didn't like remake the bookmark and I just kind of forgot.
Scott: It's actually kind of weird because if you go to scary-go-round.com, it's a scary-go-round presents bad machinery.
Scott: I think the name of the comic is now bad machinery.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I'm not sure what the deal is.
Rym: Anyway, I was I never.
Scott: I actually never read the comic.
Scott: I just know who the guy is.
Rym: I am sure there are long archives from the point when I forgot about it and stopped reading that I can catch up on.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure man Skellington's.
Rym: So in the meta moment the Upcoming the next geek guys book club book is the ear the eye the arm.
Scott: You'll forget what order those are in probably leg and the foot and the toe and the toenail and the toe fungus under the tone.
Rym: It came highly recommended.
Rym: it's a short read.
Scott: you should read it By the end of the month because remember Bob is its own show now Which means we're not gonna be waiting for like an appropriate Thursday.
Scott: We're just gonna do one every month.
Rym: So if I can read the books quickly people and by the end of this week, I will have the foundation episode Which is done completely done.
Rym: I just got to type in the shit and put it online.
Rym: Mm-hmm I'm just kind of slow about stuff because I've been busy.
Rym: We put up another one of our PAX lectures a game mechanics and mechanism design.
Rym: due to popular demand The third one from PAX East 2011 how to win at games will be up I guess by the end of the day Sunday.
Rym: and then because you fuckers won't leave me alone about it I'm gonna put up another radio.
Scott: free Equestria Jesus aren't they don't?
Scott: we only have shitty ones though?
Rym: We have one.
Rym: we have one more Pilot, I'm not gonna put up the shitty ones.
Rym: So this weekend we got to record some more video for the real show.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, yeah people like why?
Scott: where's?
Scott: the RFE is like.
Scott: it's not a regular schedule.
Scott: It was pilots that we made.
Rym: Yes We know they were Testing the water.
Scott: like we dip our toe in the water and we take it out and we're like, oh that was good water Let's jump in.
Scott: and they're like, why haven't you jumped in?
Scott: Yeah, you're hanging from the toe.
Scott: I'm putting my bathing suit on.
Rym: I mean, I upload game mechanics and mechanism design.
Rym: One of the earliest posts is yo dawg That was cool and all.
Rym: but where's RFE?
Rym: Now I know how you go felt.
Rym: Yeah So we will be at the penny arcade expo prime in Seattle Which is the weekend before the holiday weekend this year.
Scott: Don't fuck that out.
Scott: It's not Labor Day weekend this year It's the week before.
Scott: if you bought the wrong plane ticket get ready to pay a fine.
Scott: It's a change the dates on your plane ticket.
Scott: And if you don't have a hotel reservation, I don't know.
Rym: tell you on Saturday at noon We are doing discover the Forgotten Masters.
Scott: You gotta prepare that.
Rym: Yeah, we do have to prepare that.
Scott: We're all.
Scott: we've already forgotten the master.
Rym: We're also doing at 6 p.m.
Rym: To 8 p.m.
Rym: I don't know what the room is going to be called.
Rym: There is a an experiment at this packs a workshop room for tabletop.
Rym: All right, we are going to be teaching people how to play.
Rym: I won't say the names of the games because we're that's not finalized yet some games probably Carcassonne.
Scott: We're not just gonna teach you how to play though.
Scott: That would be boring.
Scott: We're also you know I mean it would be useful to teach a whole room of people how to play at once Yeah, as opposed to teaching over and over again.
Rym: Yeah, that's well and good.
Rym: That's the Gonna.
Scott: tell you how to fucking win and With the secret strategies of masters then there's probably gonna be enough copies for all y'all to just play Immediately and we'll be around to help out to judge the rules clarify rules give people, you know tips.
Scott: It's like I need a hint of where to move to make the crab people.
Rym: I'll tell you this and if they yell at me for telling you this now, well, I'll eat that.
Rym: That's my fault.
Rym: We're starting to spot it because that's the sleeper hit of packs.
Scott: I think we need to get more spot.
Rym: It's Carcassonne seven wonders and then the fourth one in that session is secret.
Rym: It might be an indie RPG maybe might be we're not sure.
Scott: it takes a while though.
Scott: Okay, so spot it's are $12.
Scott: So we have to.
Rym: we at least have to get one to give to Robert coup.
Scott: Yeah, cuz he you know, he doesn't have one already Yeah, but he might have one already.
Scott: banana grams.
Rym: to our popular consciousness We need to return the favor with spot it unless of course knowing him He probably already has like a sack of spot.
Rym: It's probably if he doesn't.
Rym: well, you could beat someone with a sack of spot.
Scott: It's yeah, pretty effectively.
Scott: He'd be better with oranges that are frozen or doorknobs.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah But we may be doing a little more or not.
Rym: That's all up in the air.
Rym: We're finalizing details and We'll tell you more about our packs plans as we get closer to packs.
Scott: Do we have anything else?
Rym: New York Comic Con?
Rym: I'm not announcing anything yet on that because I can't confirm anything yet.
Rym: PAX East.
Rym: we'll be doing some stuff in about six and a half months.
Rym: Yeah It's April.
Rym: It's not that far.
Scott: We have a worst webcomic contest.
Scott: It's ongoing.
Scott: if you want to submit a worst webcomic You have to go to our website or the forum find the link that goes to the form to fill out.
Scott: It's a Google Docs form to fill out a submission.
Scott: We're probably gonna do this episode in two weeks for now because we need another Wednesday idea.
Scott: now That'll be it.
Scott: So two weeks you have a deadline of.
Scott: you know, I need time to read the comics.
Scott: So you got maybe a week or so left to submit a worst webcomic and we're gonna start checking them out to figure out Which one's the worst?
Rym: Yep, two observations on this one stop submitting control.
Scott: You say that every time cuz it's funny.
Rym:  I I Realized that many of you seem to have a surprising amount of furry Pornography at your fingertips and as soon as we said we have a contest.
Rym: How many furry porn webcomics can there be?
Scott: it's like.
Scott: I know that furry porn webcomics exists And I know there are many of them and I know some of them also combine lots of different You know sexual fetishes of sorts.
Scott: really dude I couldn't name a single one But the fact that people could you know did.
Scott: if you Google sir if I had there was a contest I wanted to win I Could Google search for and find some.
Rym: I could also.
Scott: I don't know any but it's like people submitting them.
Scott: It seemed like they know them.
Scott: It's like a good name.
Rym: How do you even?
Scott: how do you know these?
Rym: I could name comics that were technically furry but weren't porn like Sabrina was fairly famous among the fan crowds or Erotic in partial nature, but not porn.
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: There's a glove but that's actually right, but It's not just furry porn it's scary gratuitous poorly drawn furry porn.
Rym: and fuck you all for making me read this.
Scott: You don't have to read a lot of it.
Scott: We just read enough to figure out.
Scott: What's the world?
Rym: I believe the rule we post is that we have to read if available the first ten the last ten and Beyond that We're.
Scott: so more it's gonna be a completely subjective Judgment.
Scott: where it is we examine the website the art the writing that the if it's still going the craziness Factor we want to take into account and do account and it's up to us.
Rym: the craziness of the author Definitely comes into play.
Scott: anything you want can come into play.
Scott: and remember if you submit an entry to this I know let's do it since there's only two of us.
Scott: Let's do like a you know, an ebert thumbs up thumbs downs System, what does thumbs up mean?
Scott: that it's the worst the worst.
Scott: Yeah It's not exactly so.
Rym: thumbs down means is a good comic.
Scott: Yeah as in it's not the worst because it's the worst webcomic contest.
Rym: All right Might not have enough thumbs.
Scott: Use your toes big toes.
Rym: So Scott what to animate you looking forward to right now.
Rym: Like what are you watching every week when it comes out?
Scott: That number is I don't know.
Scott: I'm watching it every week as soon as it comes up But I did watch three episodes.
Scott: that number six show.
Rym: I watched one episode and I really like it.
Rym: It's the first show I've watched in a long time where I watched an episode and at no point during the episode Do I think when's this over?
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: when it's done I think is there another episode?
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I wasn't desperate to watch the next episode like I am with some shows, you know It's not like I'm dying to go home and see the next episode like, you know in ponies that this new pony episode I'm running home.
Rym: I'm for her like when I first watch eska flown air cowboy bebop like I'd finish that VHS tape and I'd sit there stewing on the fact that I had a goddamn month to wait.
Scott: and there are some shows like say Hokuto.
Scott: no can we're like.
Scott: I won't rush home be like I gotta watch the mocha dono can but when I was watching it before I finished it all you watch one and you just keep watching the next one the next one the next and you can't stop.
Rym: Yeah until eventually you stop those shows going waves like after a story arc ends.
Rym: It's like the spell breaks and I have like a three episode gap.
Scott: or I could stop watching or there's a recap episode.
Rym: Yep, but as soon as I get past that I'm done all night Yep.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: We'll do a fist of the North Star show soon.
Rym: I'm almost done with it.
Scott: You're really wet.
Scott: episode anyone.
Rym: Ah Fuck I forgot the number again.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: is it still?
Scott: is it still fist North Star one?
Scott: or you know?
Scott: It fits the North Star - I'm two different openings Oh, so you finish with the North Star one.
Scott: I'll just son like it actually says this the North Star - you know - at the at the beginning it's on and he's going to the island of Bob but not Ashra, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: You're already that where everybody is Surprisingly badass.
Scott: Yes, the island of bad Badass island where the real badasses were hiding this whole time.
Rym: Yeah, you look back at like King Sama like whatever dude King Sama your heart.
Rym: But it says to me that Every time I think about what there's a few exceptions like number six and even to the east started this way But then it kind of like I got less invested as it went on as it got less good.
Rym: Yeah, but All I want out of anime right now is Either a Satoshi koan movie.
Rym: Oh wait or coming kind of ghost in the shell stand-alone complex 3.
Scott: somebody Sent a link to something today.
Scott: I don't know much about it, but it's called H Plus.
Scott: it's live-action and basically is it goes in the shell ripoff.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: that's all I know.
Scott: I don't know anything else.
Scott: I think that I could look it up But I guess what is it?
Rym: Specifically about the anime that draws in like this like.
Rym: why do we like number six over the million other shows?
Rym: because we've watched A lot of similar ish shows where we watch the first episode.
Rym: We're like what the fuck was that?
Rym: who cares?
Rym: We never even felt like we forget the name of it.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: Why do I remember the name of the show?
Rym: Like what?
Rym: what's different?
Rym: I mean it starts out pretty generic like, you know, it's kind of like starts out like geo say like, okay You've got some characters kids school some sort of utopia science fiction, but oh wait, maybe it's a dystopia.
Scott: Well, it always is right.
Scott: It's that I've noticed there's certain things that are Stereotypical, you know reused cliche plots and anime over and over again, right?
Scott: There's the.
Scott: you know, you're inside the pretty and beautiful Perfect utopian city and then there's a. it has some sort of walls around it and if you leave it's Blair, right?
Scott: You see that sort of an apple seed definitely an ergo proxy definitely in Raza fon definitely in number six.
Scott: What other you know sort of even jellying doesn't have it straight up But it's like even jelly is definitely this city and the rest of the world are sort of you know, not the same, right?
Scott: But there's just so many animes where it's like there.
Scott: it's like the whole city is a Truman show almost.
Scott: Yep That's just you know, this is one example, but there's so many, you know It's the situation but yet I'm drawn in.
Rym: I actually kind of want to know what the deal is But we want there's also.
Scott: there's also the secret tower.
Scott: cliche.
Scott: number six also has what I'm getting at Promised.
Scott: has that?
Rym: was it darker than black or was that there was one show?
Rym: I remember we watched an episode of that started out kind of cool like this and Then it shows you like a straight-up.
Rym: Just here is the wall around the city.
Rym: What's the deal?
Rym: We're not gonna tell you and by the end of the episode I didn't give a shit Like I didn't care what was on the other side of that wall.
Scott: I always want to see someone.
Scott: just you know If you're gonna do cliches like this at least take them and turn them on their head.
Rym: So what if the story of ergo proxy is really yeah, it sucks outside.
Rym: The inside is a paradise.
Rym: The main character is just crazy.
Scott: That's not a bad one.
Rym: I would like to see a show like that.
Scott: I was thinking more like you're outside the city, right and The Oh big.
Scott: Oh, it was another one with city walls.
Rym: Well, well, well, well, it can't spoil right?
Scott: That's not a secret.
Scott: But you know you start outside the walls to begin with and you see that there's a city that's walled in and you have no Fucking clue what's in there?
Scott: until later.
Rym: Well, you get that a little bit.
Rym: remember in last exile when you finally get inside the the real people's stuff and you see what?
Rym: Their lives are like with their first water and their caviar.
Scott: Yeah, kind of.
Scott: but it's it's not.
Scott: it's not an it's specifically.
Scott: the enclosed city physical structure is always you know or the secret tower.
Scott: That's up to something a ziggurat of some kind like a metropolis or place promised, you know Yeah You know the same things over and over again in so many different shows and those always.
Scott: it seems like there are certain cliches that are That are usually in good shows now, but not always and certain ones that are usually in bad shows But not always I mean part of it is like.
Rym: I look at the moment when the show you have that moment of oh shit That's what this show is about.
Rym: like in bacchanal the first episode when you're like, alright gangsters Alright I can dig this and then motherfucker gets stabbed and you realize what the show is really about and you're like, ah That's another thing.
Scott: a lot of shows that turn out to be good do is the very beginning of the first episode is some Dark action scene.
Scott: maybe someone gets killed or someone's running and they get shot or something like that.
Scott: And then it goes la la opener and then la la la introducing characters And then it's not until maybe even the second or third episode They tie it back to that when they cried it.
Scott: third 32nd thing that happened at the beginning of the first episode.
Rym: remember when they cry opening scene the violent Murder with a baseball bat of someone and then moe happy opener and then moe happy school Like there was no link back to baseball bat murder.
Rym: Yep until later until later You can make a show where you never link back.
Scott: Well, did you have a thing that happens in before the opener that doesn't have anything to do with the real show at all?
Scott: I just never go back to that You know, what I would do is I would have Like 30 seconds before every opener.
Scott: that would make no sense individually, but could be shuffled and pasted in order to make sense But it's nothing to do with the actual show.
Rym: that's what you do in front of a kids show like case closed Because then the kids try to solve the mystery.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, so I guess let's put it this way What would make like right now Describe like the anime that you would just like lose your shit over like you would like Leave work early to get home and watch that shit?
Scott: Well, there's a lot of things that could fit that bill, right?
Scott: But I think what it would.
Scott: you know It really had to be a whole lineup because there's so many different kinds of anime I like I would need like one to fit every possible thing maybe even you know, and then again It's like well if I can have the world why don't I have five of every category of anime?
Scott: Why don't I have infinity of every category?
Scott: of this way?
Rym: then Let's look at the ghost in the shell kind of show cuz we've both talked at least why I guess give me goes to the shell Three.
Scott: Yeah, well, you don't need to change it.
Rym: movie or TV show.
Rym: TV show really not another movie not another four That wouldn't hurt either.
Rym: Yeah There's what I want.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I love you Mamoru.
Rym: She if I could change anything about a director other than bringing Satoshi come back from the dead.
Rym: I Was never allowed to make a live-action movie again because you would be forced to make comedy anime with action scenes.
Rym: That is all I want from you.
Scott: I think he doesn't want to do anymore.
Scott: I mean, Mamoru.
Scott: She make it a new Pat Lebois TV series.
Scott: There you go done comedy with comedy with action scenes.
Rym: actually, you know what I would like to see.
Rym: I'd like to see oh, she go pick up like her say at surah style shows.
Rym: Well, you already did that do it again do something like that.
Rym: Pat Lebois imagine Imagine this.
Rym: imagine if oh, she did the next key Taro.
Scott: I mean, I don't know if that's his style.
Rym: I think you could pull it off.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, the thing is I'd also like to see some team-ups right like if I like you get if you know.
Scott: You know, it's always like what if we get two amazing people together like lazy Matsumoto and Daft Punk?
Scott: But it's like, you know do those combos really work, you know that in anime at least in comic books They often work because you get the amazing writer and the amazing artist anime they can.
Rym: but I think it's more subtle It's more.
Rym: it's not the matter of what they both bring to the table.
Rym: It's more what like bullshit drama limitations did they bring to the table and look it's uh Utena, I mean Ikuhara and Chiyo Saito together made Something awesome that they couldn't have each made on their own.
Scott: so we can't just go out there and be like, you know, let's get Miyazaki and You know fucking Matsumoto together to work on the same thing.
Scott: It's like well that probably actually wouldn't turn out that well Right, but what you could do is you could say well, why don't we get lazy Matsumoto to do Lupin the third?
Scott: that's not bad because I heard.
Scott: but just to make say a Ghibli movie.
Scott: so he has Ghibli money and Ghibli animators and right working for Mike.
Rym: I just imagine that.
Scott: remember but he has.
Scott: he just writes and directs whatever he wants.
Rym: I glee ostro the Miyazaki Lupin the best like.
Rym: I love that movie.
Rym: It's one of my favorite movies of all time.
Rym: I Want to see the same take on the Matsumoto verse.
Scott: So Galaxy Express, yeah, we could do that.
Rym: I would love to see that.
Scott: That'd be awesome.
Scott: Oh my god I wonder what happened on the space train if if Miyazaki was right now, but the thing is Miyazaki You know, he hasn't been doing too much lately is most.
Rym: I just want more Lupin too.
Scott: cuz Daryl said he's on it.
Scott: He's on the downswing.
Scott: He's got an upswing with his pon.
Scott: Yo, I mean Panya was good But it wasn't it was.
Scott: no spirited away.
Rym: We need to get back to some Porco Rosso.
Scott: Yeah, I heard of Porco Rosso to rumor.
Scott: Yeah, we don't even need to make wishes.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I heard true.
Rym: I did hear from a semi legitimate source a standalone complex like for real three rumor.
Rym: But it was while it was from a pretty legitimate source that I would trust.
Rym: I'm so cynical of those kinds of rumors.
Scott: Yeah, I don't believe anything till I see it.
Rym: I mean Oh My god, I want that so much.
Scott: I know right I pay monies.
Rym: Yeah but I Heard from Daryl's this man in my world order cuz remember we used to watch like the Lupin Specials like after all the movies.
Scott: Yeah, but they tended to be just go downhill.
Rym: So apparently since we stopped watching him, you know what happened?
Scott: They suck.
Rym: They got even worse.
Scott: How could they get worse?
Rym: like everyone was worse than the last one and apparently the one that I was kind of excited about.
Rym: that I just kind of ignored.
Rym: I was waiting to hear a review where it was basically red versus green like different eras of Lupin.
Scott: Yeah, what about the detective Conan one?
Rym: Apparently?
Rym: No, apparently the red versus green one sucked balls.
Scott: What?
Rym: Yeah Like it was good concept poorly executed And apparently Lupin is not even like that big in the case closed one.
Scott: so eh What would happen if this summer Wars guy did Lupin me?
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: What do you think you do?
Rym: That would be no he would you know why?
Rym: cuz look at the kinds of characters that like The Lupin family as a giant group just to look at what was great about summer wars.
Rym: He could pull off that same kind of stuff.
Scott: Or if he got the Durara guy to do a movie Instead of doing a show cuz then he'd be forced to like bring it all in with a lot of money obviously.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, what would he do that?
Rym: What what story?
Rym: an original story maybe?
Scott: Yeah, it's something on its own.
Scott: Yeah, I don't want to Durara movie.
Rym: No, no, but I'm saying even.
Rym: but what about him doing his movie?
Rym: That's also a take on an existing thing.
Scott: No, it should just be it's his own movie.
Scott: Just something original I want to see.
Scott: you know, there's too many, you know as much as I want more Lupin's that don't suck.
Scott: or you know Another space train something, you know, even though nothing will ever be as good as it was right?
Scott: It's much better Just have more new original things, you know, Hollywood can give me all the sequels in the universe.
Scott: I don't need more.
Scott: I need more original something.
Scott: that doesn't.
Scott: I mean I'll ask ghost in the shell.
Scott: I'll take more but other things.
Scott: I want something new and original I would take your wood on because look at James Bond I mean like you wouldn't want Otomo to make a Kira - you'd want Otomo to make something fresh.
Scott: That's not freedom and cup noodle That all he did was design little.
Rym: what about manga?
Rym: because there's the easy answer here.
Rym: But what?
Scott: well, I mean, you know, obviously you want to bring Tezuka and such back from the dead.
Scott: Like you could do animes too if you came back from the dead.
Rym: the thing is I don't even need to say Oh, why don't they make a manga about this?
Rym: They're all done.
Rym: They're all in Japan.
Rym: None of them are in English.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much mostly.
Scott: Hey make more.
Scott: say things like sanctuary.
Scott: Yeah, I'd like to see a sanctuary though that took place in the US but had that same attitude, right?
Rym: So like it, you know like Frank Miller's sanctuary, you know you need you need Frank Miller to adapt sanctuary Heavily like heavily adapted don't stay too true to it to the real U.S.
Scott: Make it an HBO like one season to show or dirty 80s U.S This is all he likes.
Rym: dirty 80s punk shit, yeah You ever see Strange Days?
Scott: Never heard of it.
Rym: Really?
Rym: You should watch Strange Days.
Rym: It's in Netflix.
Rym: Is it strange?
Rym: It's you know the 80s like that 80s punk dystopia.
Rym: Yeah Strange Days is the 90s dystopia.
Rym: I've seen very few representations of the 90s dystopia.
Scott: The 90s are pretty good.
Rym: That's why yeah, exactly Strange Days is take the problems of the 90s and extend them into the future.
Rym: It's actually really good and the ending is the same ending as the difference engine.
Scott: So wouldn't that be like Back to the Future 2?
Rym: You know kind of similar except more race stuff Because you know Rodney King all that stuff.
Rym: It's kind of like that extension.
Rym: Ah, but yeah actually Back to the Future 2.
Rym: Similar in some ways but Strange Days has a little bit of a Ghost in the Shell element.
Rym: You'll like the movie.
Rym: It's up your alley.
Scott: Maybe I Don't know but yeah, I got a manga that doesn't exist, right?
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: well most of the manga is just like on go, you know It's.
Rym: it's so the ones that I want to read.
Rym: I just need someone to translate them and release them here.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's like I want more Phoenix.
Scott: That's not good, right?
Scott: I Don't know what kind of manga doesn't exist that I actually.
Rym: I think it all seems to exist as much as I want sanctuary to Be like.
Scott: I guess you know.
Scott: go back to anime.
Scott: I'll take a yotsuba anime.
Scott: I could watch that it's never gonna exist, but I want it.
Rym: I almost don't want it to be like.
Rym: I'd like it to be full episodes.
Rym: Like I was among Adil I would also like it to be shorts Like just little shorts.
Scott: I also don't want it to just be a direct adaptation of the manga.
Scott: I wanted to just be like make more yotsuba episodes that aren't in the manga.
Scott: So it's like.
Rym: Yeah, you had to see both.
Rym: You get you get Osmo to write it right?
Rym: Yeah, but with assistance from and direction from oshi.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: you do yotsuba very well.
Scott: He's good at comedy.
Scott: Just hates it.
Scott: No, no, I think there are other people who do better.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you just get the people did.
Scott: I was among a dad to do it.
Rym: Oh, yeah I don't even know who was on that project.
Rym: I don't know hand.
Rym: I have to look it up.
Scott: You know, there's also I kinda you know I do kind of like, you know the kind of.
Scott: there is some stuff they don't make anymore like Really stupid crazy racist stuff.
Scott: Like what was that?
Scott: That's that show with the school of full of bad kids.
Scott: Oh the one I Forget it was like even with the predecessor of chromardier.
Scott: Yeah, it's like yeah Oh to kojuku.
Rym: That was it.
Rym: Yeah, it's a show is pretty great.
Scott: I want stuff like that.
Scott: That doesn't exist anymore You know, they totally badass off-the-wall fucked up shit.
Scott: Well, there's probably shouldn't exist.
Rym: Before where there's the like there was the old style of zany anime comedy like Ron Mar or something Yeah, and then we moved into a newer style of zany comedy the Excel saga style.
Rym: Mmm, I heard someone made a pretty good edit of Excel saga.
Scott: Yeah, which Excel saga I think is just Pedro.
Scott: It's what leads into like, you know YouTube poop and those sorts of things that we have nowadays.
Rym: Anime world order said it best.
Rym: Was it them?
Rym: someone said this?
Rym: I don't remember who.
Rym: that Excel saga is the best anime in the world for anime fans.
Rym: So we're in this very narrow time window.
Rym: You have to have just seen enough anime to kind of get the jokes or at least get that they're referring to other anime You may not have seen and yet haven't seen enough anime to realize that the show is actually just random Family Guy bullshit Mmm like in that golden up like that golden window.
Rym: That is one of the funniest shows you will ever see.
Scott: Pretty funny when we were in that golden window.
Rym: Yeah But I think back at what I laughed at and it's not that funny to me now But I can see why I laughed at it back then.
Rym: Mmm.
Scott: I never did finish it me either.
Scott: Wasn't there something with like a the last episode porn basically or something?
Rym: It's porn in the same way that the second Wander not wanders, but El Hazzard OAV was kind of horny and stupid.
Rym: Mm-hmm, except I heard this was more porny.
Rym: I don't know if it was more stupid.
Scott: I have no idea.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I could actually go for another like El Hazzard style fantasy comedy.
Scott: Yeah, nobody, you know all the fantasy shows these days are just so.
Rym: slayers is good But slayers isn't really the same genre.
Rym: slayers is almost a fighting show Yeah, but like El Hazzard not the best show in the world but the kind of show that's a serious fantasy esque plot in an interesting original world and yet is just kind of Constant low-level comedy throughout the otherwise serious plot.
Scott: or you know, just even just go for the.
Scott: you know Something just in the old style right where you know, look at Genji.
Scott: Ken for example is like, you know Has the school plus the something right Haru?
Scott: He has the school plus the sci-fi weirdness, whatever.
Scott: I haven't even seen it, but I know that's what it has.
Scott: And in the same way Mahoutsukai tie has the school plus the Right, so give me the show that you know, too many of the shows nowadays are like, you know school plus something Crappy, you know.
Rym: So give me something good.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you're gonna bring in, you know The school part combine it with the awesome sci-fi part going back.
Scott: and well Remember even Evangelion is school plus sci-fi.
Rym: remember full metal panic, right?
Rym: But that originally was school funny Which is pretty funny even though kind of cliche and semi serious average robot action.
Rym: and what part of that was popular The school bullshit and they made fumafu.
Scott: Yeah, which is just the school part.
Rym: It was terrible.
Scott: Yeah Well, I think the thing was is that you know The the school part was so bleh and the military part because I did watch the entire first series back in the day.
Scott: That the military part.
Scott: I didn't read the comic though.
Scott: The military part was just so Average.
Scott: there was just nothing great about it.
Scott: Nothing bad.
Scott: It was it was like a. it was like a boring generic Plot of a video game where you piloted a mech or something like that.
Scott: It was literally like this.
Rym: bad Whoo now contrast it with remember Gasaraki.
Rym: Yeah, right same deal in that it's a boring slow Military.
Rym: but yet Gasaraki pulled me the fuck in.
Scott: I know we're the only people who like that show.
Rym: We got to watch that again and review it, but I think that's a good show.
Scott: We done a show.
Rym: No, we haven't.
Rym: Holy fuck.
Rym: We gotta go.
Rym: I'll get it.
Rym: We'll watch it.
Scott: We have a the V dubbed VHS tape.
Scott: then we got rid of those and not like we have a VHS player.
Rym: Anyway, I still do actually.
Scott: Oh, does it work?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I'm getting rid of it though.
Rym: Okay Hey anyone out there you want what was once a four thousand dollar top of the line VHS camcorder.
Scott: Oh the camcorder.
Rym: It's also a VCR.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but Gasaraki Was I like shows like that too?
Rym: Because it was very focused.
Scott: it Gasaraki perfect collection on Amazon 77 66.
Rym: I'll get it somewhere.
Scott: Let me check elsewhere.
Rym: I will get it somehow anyway, but What got me about Gasaraki is that a lot of anime and I think I've kind of pinpointed what it is that I like other than ghosts in the shell.
Rym: if you if I start watching a show and There's a moment like when you read a book you watch a movie or your brain like you suddenly see I know where this is Going there's gonna be drama about X. I don't give a shit.
Rym: Yeah, anytime I predict that like I feel like Now they're gonna have a misunderstanding About this and that's gonna be the driving plot point when I expect that and it doesn't happen Like the show totally goes a different direction.
Rym: That almost guarantees.
Rym: It's a show.
Rym: I'm gonna like.
Rym: Gasaraki was Surprisingly not stereotypical.
Scott: Yeah, I've never.
Scott: I'm sure there are other shows like that But I haven't.
Rym: parts of some Gundams are like that parts Pocket and less like more original Gundam.
Scott: see On Gundam seeds.
Scott: that shall not be named right, you know, give me the show.
Scott: Give me the Gundam show.
Scott: That's 50 episodes.
Scott: Keep you know has the good characters some comedy you had.
Rym: it was gonna proceed.
Scott: I know the.
Scott: give me another Gundam seed just like Gundam seed but not Gundam seed.
Scott: I know that's like they tried that with destiny and I know I'm asking for another sequel.
Scott: But it's like actually, you know what don't give me a Gundam, right?
Scott: Give me some other show doesn't need to be a robot show But just make it that 50 episode show with the characters and the you know Political evolving plotline with like four or five arcs.
Scott: that just keeps you hooked the whole time.
Scott: It doesn't have to even have to be robots.
Scott: Yeah, just something like that in with that structure.
Scott: I don't care even what you put in there as long as it's not moe or something.
Rym: Yeah, Scott.
Rym: There it is.
Scott: Mostly I just need the long-running show that I can come and watch a whole bunch of episodes schools plus moe.
Rym: There's a show.
Scott: great There's not enough of those out there already.
Rym: All right, I think I think we're done here Because now I'm kind of sad that I can't go watch all these shows we just talked about Except gassaraki.
Scott: Yeah, I could watch that again now.
Rym: Yeah I just remember we showed that was at the anime club and we showed the first four episodes and Afterward you and me and a couple other people were like, oh man, I wonder what happens.
Rym: Everyone else is like the fuck.
Rym: was that?
Rym: We watched the end of that you me Pete in the basement of one of the buildings at RIT like randomly We got the last VHS.
Rym: remember we broke into like one of the basement classrooms Turned on the projector and watched it instead of going to our wag one night.
Rym: Mm-hmm You don't remember do you I do?
Rym: Oh, okay.
Scott: That was the final DVD final DHS dub.
Rym: what's wrong you shiro?
Scott: They got some random guy from the recording room to do this Throw away no-name character on a boat for two seconds.
Rym: I'm such an okay dub But it's like if its score was 80 out of a hundred.
Rym: the final score was like 50 out of a hundred just for that one line.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.