Rym: It's Tuesday, January 25th, 2011, I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we bring you our coverage of Magfest 9.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So this is a bit of a departure from our normal GeekNights schedule.
Rym: We've got no things of the day.
Rym: This episode might sound a little odd, we didn't use our normal studio recording techniques because we actually did this show in front of some cameras.
Rym: It's nothing special, the video may or may not appear in the near future, but that will explain any audio discrepancies compared to our usual show.
Rym: If you're a new listener, this is a slightly atypical episode, we're just going to talk about Magfest, a rather awesome convention we attended recently, and that's about it.
Rym: I think I'll just get right into the meat of it because we talk about the con for quite a while.
Rym: So we heard about it for years, but we never actually went to Magfest.
Scott: Well it's because they were stupid, they had it on New Year's Eve, it's like who the hell is going to give up their New Year's Eve to go to almost any convention?
Scott: What convention could possibly be on New Year's Eve that you'd still go?
Rym: I would go to PAX.
Scott: I don't think I would go to New Year's Eve.
Rym: I would go to one New Year's PAX.
Scott: It depends on where the PAX was.
Rym: Seattle.
Scott: I don't know if I'd go to Seattle in New Year's Eve.
Rym: You wouldn't go to Seattle for PAX on New Year's Eve?
Rym: Imagine the craziness.
Scott: No, I don't know.
Scott: It'd be a close call.
Rym: So Magfest we ignored every year just because, well before I didn't even know it existed, like I vaguely heard.
Rym: oh there's something called Magfest.
Scott: I knew there was a convention called Magfest, I knew it was a gaming con, it was mostly video game oriented, and that it also had the video game music, but it wasn't large in my brain, it was just a convention I knew existed.
Scott: It was like 100 conventions, I know they exist.
Rym: I think what it really came to light was they had John St.
Rym: John in their ad.
Scott: That was one or two years ago, right?
Scott: They had John St.
Scott: John in the ad and they made that awesome YouTube video to promote it.
Rym: And I was like oh, Magfest.
Scott: What it was is that it wasn't that I thought the convention was somehow better, it's that that ad.
Scott: let me know that the people at that convention running it were very culturally similar to us.
Scott: They were our people.
Rym: What really got me though was when it was explained to me that there was an official yell of Magfest.
Rym: The colossus.
Scott: Well that was only apparently invented last year.
Scott: That was only invented last year.
Rym: But we heard about it last year and suddenly that seemed like the kind of thing that we would dig.
Rym: And that was correct.
Scott: It became very apparent in the past year or two that Magfest was our style.
Rym: So this year they actually came to us and said hey, you guys want to come to Magfest, be guests, do a panel, do your usual thing, the stuff you do at all the other cons?
Rym: And we said yes because it wasn't on New Years.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if it was on New Years again I would have said no, but we said yes.
Rym: Now many of you might be new listeners and you're trying to check out like alright, we're doing this review of Magfest.
Rym: I was at Magfest, I want to see what you have to say.
Rym: We're very harsh on conventions.
Rym: We often complain about all the things that go wrong with them because a lot of conventions do things very badly.
Scott: Because that's the only interesting thing to talk about a lot of the time is what went wrong.
Scott: If you talk about what went right, it's like well, this was fun, and this was fun, and Of course, it's a new con.
Rym: I mean how many Otakons did we cover?
Rym: How many times can you say the artist alley is this big and there's this many people in it?
Rym: So what we're going to do is start with all the bad parts of Magfest, get all the complaining out of the way so we can talk about the good stuff because there was some bad.
Rym: There was quite a bit of bad.
Rym: In fact, there was a portent.
Scott: There was indeed a quite smelly portent.
Rym: We're excited.
Rym: We don't know about the culture of this con.
Rym: We're ready to go.
Rym: We get on the bulk bus.
Scott: I had high expectations for Magfest.
Rym: Way high.
Rym: Way higher than zinc icon the first time we went.
Scott: I knew it relatively.
Scott: It was only a few thousand people which it was.
Scott: I knew it was four days and we were going, you know, in the afternoon on the first the Thursday.
Scott: So we're going to get a lot out of it and I knew that it was culturally similar to us.
Scott: So I was like, all right, this is going to be, this is going to be good.
Rym: Also, a hotel con very rarely for seven, you know, back before we did GeekNights or anything, we would go to a lot of hotel cons where 24/7 gaming, you know, they're kind of small.
Rym: Everything's crazy.
Rym: And now we only go to like Pax's and Otakons all the really big ones.
Rym: So it would be, it was interesting to go back to a hotel style con being this much older and weirder and, you know, doing panels and everything.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So we get on the Volt bus and there is immediately BO, like wicked gamer BO.
Scott: There was no way to a hundred percent know who had this BO.
Rym: It was probably that guy sitting right behind us.
Scott: Probably that guy sitting right behind us.
Scott: And I think it was a, it was a case of no hair washing.
Scott: That is what it seemed like.
Rym: He was wearing the kind of brown like gamer shirt with a gamer thing on it.
Scott: He was definitely going to Magfest because he's probably been worn a couple of times.
Scott: because he asked us at the end of the bus ride, Hey, you guys going to Magfest?
Scott: Do you want to, you know, ride over there together or whatever?
Scott: Cause he was taking the Metro, I think the bus was like half Magfest people.
Scott: We took an expensive, not yellow cab to get over there.
Rym: Basically the guy, if the guy, you out there, if you're watching this, you probably know who you are.
Rym: We're sorry, but you had some mad BO.
Rym: So when you said, Hey, you want to share a cab?
Rym: I said, yeah, we'll see.
Rym: We booked out of that.
Scott: We didn't know that, that we didn't know for sure that that was the BO guy, but I was pretty sure that was my, if I had to, if I had to bet on which guy on the bus had the BO, that's the guy I would have bet all my money on.
Scott: So Magfest number two is the old lady who's sitting in front of me who didn't move.
Rym: She could have had a BO.
Rym: She could have been dead.
Scott: She wasn't dead.
Rym: Though Magfest overall had a BO problem.
Rym: We cannot pretend that that was not there.
Scott: Ring, ring, ring, ring, ring.
Scott: Yeah, BO problem.
Scott: Do I have a BO problem?
Rym: I mean, we got back to Manhattan, I remember stepping off the bus and it was a breath of fresh air.
Rym: Jesus, Magfest, take a goddamn shower.
Scott: I even saw some Magfest staff who would wear the same shirt on one day.
Scott: And then I saw them the next day and they had the same shirt.
Scott: Not setting a good example.
Rym: Now if you wear the same shirt more than two days in a row, that's hobo territory.
Scott: That is indeed hobo territory.
Rym: Now I understand cons, like a lot of con staff only have one staff shirt.
Rym: You got to fix that.
Scott: I saw staff wearing non-staff shirts multiple days in a row.
Rym: I did wear my kilt three days, but you can go a long time with pants and non-bifurcated male garments.
Rym: Can't do that so much with a t-shirt.
Scott: No, not at all.
Rym: I don't know what to do about the BO problem.
Rym: I think it's because it was 24/7 con and because the hotel sold out, there were like seven or eight people in every room and I don't think people were taking showers.
Scott: I think also the elevator problem, this wasn't a problem for us.
Scott: We were in a hotel that was across, it was just like one street away from the actual hotel.
Rym: Too far to walk in the cold.
Scott: It was the official overflow hotel, but they had a shuttle bus, which is basically a big van.
Scott: take us over there every half hour back and forth.
Scott: And actually I was expecting to lose a lot of time with that shuttle bus.
Rym: Yeah, we really like that.
Rym: going into this, we're like, that's probably going to ruin our con and we have nothing to complain about.
Scott: The shuttle bus totally worked.
Scott: What was not good is that the main hotel was actually two hotels.
Scott: It was a big tall tower style and it was also a separate retreat style.
Scott: So there were two hotels in the main hotel that were connected physically to Magfest.
Scott: The big, you know, the wide out retreat one was totally cool.
Scott: That's where our friends were staying and they could just go to the room anytime.
Scott: And if I had to go back and it was in the same location, I would want to be in that retreat hotel.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Definitely.
Scott: To avoid the shuttle bus.
Scott: But the tower hotel was a credibly tall tower with not so many rooms on each floor with a lot of floors and poorly programmed elevators.
Scott: And even if those elevators are well programmed, there was no way to deal with that load.
Scott: There were not enough of them.
Scott: They were not designed to handle that much traffic going up and down constantly.
Rym: But a saving grace for us, the few times I tried to go up there and I failed many times cold guy had an awesome party on the eighth floor that I tried to go to like four times and I just couldn't make it.
Rym: No one there knew about the go down to go up or go up to go down trick.
Rym: Like no one was doing that.
Rym: Our bag of tricks, and this has got a running theme with us at Magfest.
Rym: Our bag of tricks was brand new here.
Rym: Like Otakon, all those big cons, everyone's figured that stuff out by now.
Rym: Magfest, no one there really goes to other cons.
Rym: Most of the people we talked to were like, this is not like this is my first Magfest.
Rym: They were like, this is the first convention I have ever been to.
Rym: I'd like someday to go to PAX.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't do a survey obviously, but of the people I talked to, right, the vast majority of the people either had never been to another convention or never been to a convention before ever.
Scott: And there were a few people obviously who are big convention goers like us.
Scott: But most of the people I talked to were not convention type people.
Scott: You know, I think there was maybe that was that one girl who knew tax.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And there was a girl with like a paxi scarf.
Rym: That was weird.
Rym: Small circles running into people who helped staff conventions.
Rym: we used to staff through a third person randomly in Virginia.
Scott: Yeah, it happens.
Rym: But the back to the
Rym: B.O.,
Rym: like the elevator thing, I think as a result, people just weren't taking showers because, you know, eight people in a room, they want to go play some games.
Rym: They take the elevator down, figure I'll shower later when everyone's done.
Scott: Can't go back up.
Scott: There's no way to get back up to the line at the elevator at all times, no matter when you pass by those elevators.
Scott: There were always people there waiting to get it on and off.
Scott: And also on YouTube, I didn't see this during the convention because, you know, it was like a whole areas of this convention that I missed out on because I just didn't get over there.
Scott: Even though it's a small con, there were just areas they didn't go to.
Scott: And, you know, part of that experience I saw on YouTube was the elevator party.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Apparently, if you go on YouTube and search for Magfest Elevator Party, there are people who got a boombox, got in those elevators and were just like, and you could hear the elevator party coming up in the elevator.
Rym: Right.
Rym: The trouble with that, though, that's not helping guys.
Scott: No, but it was a. you know, it was a cultural thing at the con that we missed out.
Rym: Well, remember back at RIT, the elevator party when I was a freshman, just that one day randomly all the elevators had a party at them.
Scott: Yeah, that was good.
Scott: We missed stuff like that.
Rym: But we got to do something about the BO because it's not like PAX, like every con.
Rym: There's that one guy with BO like you.
Rym: He walks through the room and everyone's like, oh, my God, that guy or, you know, small gaming con.
Rym: There's like the cluster, the fat Warhammer guys with their BO.
Scott: When that happens.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If there's a Warhammer room with BO or if there's a DDR machine with BO, just don't go near it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or go over there once.
Rym: You'll be like, that's my DDI.
Scott: You get away.
Scott: You just keep your eye on it.
Scott: Wait for it to clear out at a quiet moment because a 24 hour con, it's going to be cleared out at some point.
Scott: Go over there and do it while it's cleared out and get out.
Rym: And a lot of cons, like on Sunday, I'll have the BO because people just don't shower.
Rym: There's one to travel.
Rym: And you expect that.
Scott: But this was like constant and everywhere, like low level, no matter where you went, no matter where you went, there was a tiny bit of BO everywhere, except in a few places like the hotel restaurant and I or outside.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Where there was smoking by the engine.
Rym: The first time I walked outside, it was like, whoa, whoa.
Rym: Like suddenly I realized that I had become accustomed to BO.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: And then there were obviously, you know, every few minutes or so, if you were walking around or, you know, there would be a person with really bad, there'd be a peak, like there was a constant low level and peak.
Rym: So the average was pretty high.
Scott: So it's sort of like a bad guy in a video game who leaves like smoke behind him.
Scott: And there were a few of them and they were traveling around and eventually it was smoke everywhere.
Scott: And since it's four days, forget it.
Rym: And you might think we're being harsh, complaining about BO at a con.
Rym: No, you have.
Rym: no, you don't understand this was bad.
Rym: So wash everything.
Scott: So we talked a lot about BO.
Scott: It's been a lot of time on it.
Rym: So there's only one other thing that went wrong with Magfest big, Oh, big thing that went wrong.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Magfest nine had the worst registration I have ever seen in a decade of going to conventions.
Scott: I know we have ripped other conventions for the bad red lines.
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: Anime Boston.
Rym: I had to wait in line for two hours was that he ripped Otakon for not mailing the badges and those rippings were deserved rippings.
Scott: However, those rippings pale in comparison to the ripping that Magfest needs.
Rym: You might think like anime Boston, the year before we went was like famous for its bad red line.
Rym: Like it was just a disaster.
Scott: Even cuts.
Scott: There was a cards of con that we did not attend that.
Scott: Apparently the badges did not show up until like Friday night or Saturday or even not as bad penguin con back in the day.
Rym: The badges didn't show up until late Friday night.
Scott: Pango Condo wasn't a bad red.
Scott: He walked up to the coat check and it took a minute and you got a bad once they had the badges to sell.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Thing is they didn't check the badges until they could sell them.
Rym: So they, they fixed it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Magfest had not only a badge disaster, absolute disaster.
Rym: No staff did anything about it.
Scott: They didn't even try to fix this problem whatsoever.
Scott: Basically what they had is they had a little booth.
Scott: that was the same booth they were selling the merch at and it had maybe three or four laptops at it to which they were, what they would do is they would go up, they would look for you in the database cause it was sold out.
Scott: It was all pre-reg.
Scott: Then they would find your badge with your number on it.
Rym: Like four one nine seven.
Scott: Here you are.
Scott: Here is your number.
Scott: Four one nine seven.
Rym: And they'd make you sign this waiver.
Scott: I was watching their computers and the computers are very slow, very shitty software or whatever they were using.
Rym: They were also checking every single convention attendees ID to see how old they were and giving wristbands depending on your age.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All these factors meant about five minutes per person.
Rym: Minimum.
Rym: Five minutes per person.
Scott: And then they had a huge pile of like lanyards and stuff.
Scott: You had to rip one out of there.
Rym: So five minutes per person times 4,000 people is.
Scott: Even with only a few thousand people, right?
Scott: They only had like two or three laptops there.
Scott: And one of them was just for staff and guests and those sorts of vendors.
Scott: So we waited in a very short staff vendor guest line.
Rym: There were maybe 10 people in front of us in line.
Scott: It took us like over an hour and a half to get through that.
Rym: It was about an hour and 45 minutes.
Scott: But meanwhile, the normal registrant line was gigantic, right?
Scott: Not moving much faster wrapped around the hotel and it took like two hours to move like 100 feet in that line.
Scott: It was apparently there was.
Scott: the line was stacked up from when the convention opened on Thursday to when it closed on Thursday.
Scott: And I didn't really see that line being non disastrous until Friday.
Rym: some point Friday when there was a huge line in the morning, kind of slowly petered out.
Scott: But it's like they didn't try to add more stations, grab more laptops.
Rym: There was no sense of urgency at Otakon when they had a problem.
Rym: I mean, while I don't like the way Otakon does their badges, when there was a reg problem, they're like 10 staffers like, all right, how do we fix this?
Rym: What do we do?
Rym: Let's open up more reg over there.
Rym: Let's do something.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Even if there's something that you try doesn't work and you fail, at least you tried.
Scott: Magfest didn't even seem like it was a problem.
Scott: They were just like, yeah, Regen.
Scott: We're Regen.
Scott: We got three reg things.
Scott: We're going.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It was like they didn't even think there was something wrong with that.
Scott: Hello.
Scott: That was disastrous.
Scott: If I had to wait in that line, I might have just left and not if I showed up on Thursday, I would have charged back my credit card.
Scott: I would have charged my credit card, just left.
Rym: I wouldn't have left.
Rym: I would have because they didn't check badges anywhere except the video game room in the concert.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: I would have gone to Magfest anyway.
Scott: There were some people who were at Magfest, quite a few of them without badges.
Scott: Because they didn't go to concerts or they didn't go to the main video game console room, they didn't have a problem.
Scott: They just went without a badge.
Rym: I would not have dealt with it had I been an attendee.
Rym: But even as a guest, I had to wait an hour and 40 minutes to get 10 spaces through a.
Scott: Then they didn't even have us in their computer.
Rym: We do a lot of conventions.
Rym: Cons often screw stuff up.
Scott: I saw it coming a mile away.
Rym: One ConnectiCon.
Rym: we went to way back, they didn't have our schedule for us or tell us what panels we were doing.
Rym: We literally get there, get our badges, get a con book, open it up, find names of panels that we're pretty sure we submitted, and then we just showed up to them expecting to have to do them.
Rym: We were right.
Rym: That was the worst I'd ever dealt with until Magfest where we weren't on the list.
Scott: And the staff didn't have- We had to get the panels guy to come up and say, "Yes, these guys are
Scott: real.".
Rym: But even then, the panels guy was like, "These guys are for
Rym: real.".
Rym: And then he left, and then they still didn't know what to do.
Rym: And in the end, they never even gave us our guest badges.
Rym: They gave us normal badges.
Scott: Yeah, they just picked up normal badges.
Scott: Now here's how they could fix this, right?
Scott: Number one, you need more reg stations.
Scott: A lot more.
Rym: No, wait.
Rym: Mail the badges and it won't matter.
Rym: Wait, now what bothers me is that last year, apparently, there's this huge open area right next to the reg area.
Rym: They could have had like 30 people doing reg.
Rym: That area was empty, and the area they had for reg was smaller than the room we're recording the show in.
Scott: Yeah, apparently they had it right last year, and they got it wrong this year.
Scott: But anyway.
Scott: Mail the badges.
Rym: I heard of internal drama among the staff, but that's no excuse.
Scott: Even if you don't mail them, or even if you do mail them, there are still some people who got to pick them up at the con.
Scott: Pac still has a reg area, even though they mailed the badges, right?
Scott: Have a lot of stations that are dedicated to only reg.
Scott: Do not assign people numbers of badges beforehand.
Rym: How come you're looking up Joe Blow's 4192 badge?
Rym: Just hand him a random badge and write down the number you gave him.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It's like, you know, they write down when you pre-reg, you're now number 100, and then they got to find badge 100, which takes a bunch of time.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: Don't write any number.
Scott: And then when the guy shows up, give him the next badge.
Scott: Give him the order in which they show up to MAGFest.
Scott: Now there are, they do one thing that is kind of nice, I don't know how I feel about it, right?
Scott: Which is, if you decide to pay more money, you can get a better badge, right?
Rym: Those are real nice badges.
Scott: They're really nice.
Scott: You can get these big acrylic badges, and they also had these plastic ones.
Rym: I saw one guy with a wood one.
Rym: I don't know if he made it, or if that was- You pay more money, you get a better badge.
Scott: But the better badge, what was different about it was it doesn't get you anything except the better badge.
Scott: It's like, look, I paid a bunch of money to support MAGFest.
Rym: Now I'm, we're both way against, like, Comic-Con style, where, like, if you pay more, you just hit the line.
Scott: It's like, pay more.
Scott: You get to see Stan Lee no matter what, and you get a bunch of merch, and you get a t-shirt, and you get all this stuff.
Scott: It's like, well, it's not really fair.
Scott: Someone paid more money, they get to cut the line.
Rym: I mean, look at PAX.
Rym: It's super underpriced because everyone's got time, not everyone has money.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: But with MAGFest, the super supporters really don't seem to get much of anything except They don't get anything except a better badge.
Rym: They had to stand in that same line.
Scott: But that is, the thing is, the reason it's relevant is because that's how they look you up to see if you're a super supporter, regular supporter, and those people actually have their names already written on the badges, pre-engraved, right?
Scott: But I think the thing, what they could do- Well, have them check in like guests.
Scott: Exactly, right?
Scott: Or if you mailed them the badge.
Rym: Also, just how did it take an hour for you to deal with 10 people?
Rym: Because they didn't have any process for dealing with a problem.
Rym: We get up there and we're not on the list.
Rym: We're doing panels, and they had no way to resolve that situation.
Rym: They didn't have like, "Okay, if you have a problem, go over here to this one person who's only going to deal with
Rym: problems.".
Rym: Nothing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So that's most of what was bad at MAGFest.
Scott: I have no other major complaints- Bad reg, bad BO, general level of unprofessionalism that needs to be professionalized at the top as the convention grows.
Scott: Oh, one other thing that was bad was a panel scheduling.
Scott: They didn't leave any gaps between panels.
Rym: But Tim knows.
Rym: They know.
Rym: He was like, "Yeah, we wanted to do that.
Rym: Next year, we're doing
Rym: it.".
Scott: They know they're going to fix it, but it was a problem this year.
Scott: They had a panel that ended at three and a panel that started at three.
Rym: They also didn't do explicit room clears, because a couple of panels- I did see sometimes rooms got cleared- No, they cleared them, but they didn't have any policy about it.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: We're all pissed off now, because they thought they were going to see the next panel.
Rym: And then they had the shuffle of trying to force everyone out, force everyone in, and that was a little problematic.
Rym: I guess if we're going to complain, the projector was a teeny bit dark.
Scott: And the hotel- The tabletop library was meager.
Rym: Non-existent.
Rym: But we brought a library.
Scott: We brought a better library than they had.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: There weren't enough tables for tabletop gaming, but what are you going to do in that venue?
Rym: The hotel, this is kind of a weird aside.
Rym: I don't know how that hotel got away with it.
Rym: The fire marshal, like fire code numbers in those rooms were bullshit.
Rym: They were astronomical.
Scott: It's like I would go into a room, and if you asked me, "All right, I'm holding my hand over the numbers, right?
Scott: Scott, tell me how many people the fire marshal would allow in this
Scott: room.".
Rym: I'd be like what, 40 people?
Scott: With no chairs and no tables.
Rym: No chairs, no tables.
Scott: I'd be like 40.
Scott: I'd be like 40 or 50 max.
Scott: I was like, "That is bullshit.
Scott: If there were 95 people in here, we'd be
Scott: dead.".
Rym: Either that hotel bribed someone a long time ago, or Alexandria has way different laws from cities.
Scott: Yeah, Alexandria, Virginia.
Scott: I don't know what your fire marshal's up to, but he might be mad corrupt, or that hotel is corrupt or something, because that was not- I mean, the numbers were not only where the number is dangerous, but you could not fit that many people in the rooms.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like physically.
Rym: I don't know where.
Rym: Maybe they changed the walls.
Scott: I think they have a sardine law.
Scott: It's like if you can close it with a little piece of metal and twist a lid on it, then it's safe.
Rym: Now, it's not a complaint against MagFest.
Rym: There's nothing they could do about that other than moving venues, which they should.
Rym: That venue's terrible.
Scott: It was not good.
Rym: I mean, the concert space is itty bitty.
Rym: We didn't even go to the concerts, because there's no way.
Scott: I can't comment on the quality of the concerts.
Scott: I'm sure everyone who went to them was super excited about the bands they saw and whatever.
Scott: So I'm sure that the music was excellent.
Scott: But it was a tiny room.
Scott: When I looked into that room while it was being set up, it was a very small room.
Rym: It was smaller than some rooms with panels in them.
Scott: And they wouldn't let you bring a bag in there.
Scott: So I was like, I'm not leaving my bag anywhere, so I can't go in there.
Rym: But the reason I bring up the Fire Code stuff is that MagFest is used to this, because they're in Alexandria.
Rym: For whatever reason, it has this weird fire marshal la-la land.
Rym: Katsu-Kan and all the other Kansans we've been to in DC, they don't have that luxury of just ignoring fire safety.
Scott: I heard the story.
Scott: The fire marshal was there on Thursday or Friday, and Thursday, and walked around.
Rym: It was weird that we never saw him, though.
Rym: I mean, Kinetic can't even.
Rym: I see the fire marshal every day poking his head in every single room and counting numbers.
Rym: New York City?
Rym: Same way.
Rym: Katsu-Kan?
Rym: Virginia?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Alexandria?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I hope MagFest never burns down.
Scott: That'd be very bad.
Rym: So all that aside, MagFest was super crazy awesome.
Scott: Well, it was super crazy awesome.
Scott: It was pretty good.
Rym: It was the most fun I've had at a non-PEX convention in a long time.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But were those funds that you had, how much of those funds were MagFest-like?
Scott: MagFest's fault or your own fault?
Scott: Well, the trouble- Because if you can't attribute it to MagFest, if it's something that you could have done, say, just if you got a hotel room on your own.
Rym: The trouble with that, though, is that some of the things I could do on my own, but what MagFest provided was not the con or anything the con did, but the fact that a bunch of like-minded people all showed up in the same place.
Rym: Had there been no con and all the same people showed up, then yeah, I could have done almost all these things.
Rym: But MagFest and PAX are kind of polar opposites of the kind of cons we like.
Rym: PAX is definitely the, if you go to this con, there is stuff to do that the con is giving you things like these epic stadium concerts and this giant tabletop library.
Rym: MagFest is not that kind of con.
Rym: MagFest is a room party, hang out with your friends, meet new people con.
Scott: If you're not going to a concert or playing in the arcade, right, or going to a panel- You really don't need a badge.
Scott: Pretty much everything else, well, not only do you not need a badge, but you're not going to be able to, the con has nothing else to offer you except to make your own fun.
Scott: There are nerds here at the same time as you make your own fun.
Scott: Have a room party, get your own gaming going on in tabletop, do something on your own with these people to have fun.
Scott: I mean, people stopped to watch the football game, right?
Scott: Because we were very close to Baltimore.
Scott: So all the Ravens fans lined up for the game which they lost.
Rym: How many people would have walked out of PAX to go to bars and watch a football game?
Rym: If it was a Seahawks playoffs game, they would have- Even then, if it was an important game, how many people would leave PAX for that versus people who were just chilling in MagFest?
Scott: Well, the difference was if PAX was a hotel con and if the game was on in the hotel lobby in PAX and you could have watched it with all these PAX people.
Rym: While you're playing games and drinking.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Because we spent most of our con in either tabletop or in the lobby of the hotel.
Scott: Playing jungle speed mostly, but also many other tabletop games.
Scott: And because it was a four-day con, we actually had a lot of time to play tabletop RPGs.
Rym: We played a surprising number of like- we played a whole free market, but so the con is laid out.
Rym: You know, we don't really do this about other cons we go to because everyone knows how they're all laid out.
Rym: If you've been listening to GeekNights or going to these cons, not a lot of you have been to MagFest.
Rym: It's kind of small.
Rym: People aren't flying from Seattle.
Rym: So I think it's worth it to talk about the layout.
Rym: There's not much there.
Rym: There's- they had an artist alley vending area that- That was sort of mixed with the arcade.
Scott: Everything was sort of, you know, the area where all the, you know, the vendors and the tabletop games and all that stuff was all sort of squished into one space, sort of, you know, with some doors in between, right?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So they had a panel area like this long hallway and at the end were three tiny little panel rooms.
Scott: Tiny itty bitty!
Scott: But also the, uh, the jam space, the MagFest famous jam space was down there, which was sort of annoying because you could hear it in the adjacent panel rooms.
Rym: It was a little annoying, but it was also kind of this like background groove.
Scott: Well yeah, well it's like, it was like, okay, they put it over there because they wanted to keep it out of the way of everything else, which is what you should do because the jam space makes a lot of noise.
Rym: Now what they should have done, remember in the hotel right next to MagFest was this gigantic, like open bar area that they probably could have rented out or used that they didn't.
Scott: Yeah, that was in the retreat area.
Scott: They should have put it in the retreat area, but I guess they just didn't think of it.
Rym: In fact, had they had the, all the bands doing their jam space there and then paid the hotel to open that bar, that would have been a rocking room.
Scott: They could have made some awesome down in that room.
Rym: Apparently there were multiple parties that started in that room.
Rym: Like suddenly there'd be a party in that room and the hotel kept shutting them down.
Scott: I think part of the problem though, is that room is so close to hotel rooms that it would disturb hotel guests.
Rym: However, this hotel for the venue that it was, if MagFest were going to stay in this venue, they would have to get a contract with the hotel that basically literally rents out the entire hotel.
Rym: There were non-MagFest people, yet MagFest sold out and anyone who was not MagFest in that hotel was fucked.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Like badly.
Rym: I can't imagine them having enjoyed themselves and whatever they were trying to do.
Scott: But anyway, yeah.
Scott: So the vending area, you know, it had a mix.
Scott: It was just a bunch of tables all cramped up.
Scott: A surprising number though, were selling retro game stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: They were doing the hard sell.
Rym: One guy was like, check this out.
Rym: Gold, Zelda, gold, Zelda, 10 bucks, 10 bucks.
Rym: Come on, man.
Rym: And I was like, you know, you want it.
Scott: I was like, you know, it was, it was kind of weird because on the one hand it was fun to walk around and look at all this stuff, but I wasn't buying any of it.
Rym: But if you were a collector
Scott: of that sort of thing or an aspiring collector, then this was like the place for you because there was never, I don't think there's any place else in the U S that's going to have that sort of collection of, you know, retro game stuff all in the same place for sale.
Rym: And they were selling, like there was a dude who had a Lynx in an unopened, still string craft box.
Scott: There was all sorts of crazy stuff like that.
Scott: You know, if you could think of it, it was, if it wasn't ultra rare, you know, ultra, ultra rare, it was there.
Rym: What was cool though is that it was also kind of an artist alley and there were people selling the kind of stuff you see at like an anime con artist alley.
Rym: And they were really good.
Rym: I think the best guy was the one who had the like oil pixel paintings.
Scott: Yeah, that guy was the best.
Scott: We met him on the final day Sunday when we were just about to leave.
Scott: He was a cool guy.
Rym: What's weird is he was not the only one.
Rym: There were a couple of these people that we talked to and obviously not a representative sample, but enough to where I wonder this anecdotal, they never really went to other cons.
Rym: And we were like, man, if you went to an anime con and we explained like, yeah, Otakon is an order of magnitude bigger than this.
Rym: The artist alley is bigger than all of magfest, multiple orders of magnitude and your stuff is better than most of what we've seen there.
Rym: You could make money.
Scott: You could make money.
Rym: And he's like, tell me more about these anime cars.
Scott: I don't know how much money you would make at the, at the magfest, but whatever.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But there were stuff there.
Rym: I didn't buy anything, but I walked around.
Rym: There was a trouble that the alleys, like the alley itself, it was like this narrow.
Scott: You basically couldn't walk through it, but you could, you could walk through it very slowly, but it was never extremely crowded.
Scott: You know, it was never like, it wasn't like a Otakon dealer's room where people are packed in cause they really want some shit, right?
Scott: It was very, you know, there, it was cramped in space wise, but not so many people in that area.
Rym: It was a chill hangout.
Rym: Like some of the guests were hanging out there.
Scott: James Rolfe, who we never actually talked to was, yeah, one person we really wanted to see at the con.
Scott: We never saw.
Rym: Oh, well, well, cause we were going to go to his panel and I think we ordered Chinese food instead.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That happened a lot ordering food, but actually food delivery worked really well.
Rym: Unlike, unlike Connecticut, we got some slightly average, you know, okay.
Rym: Chinese food one night.
Rym: We got some okay.
Rym: Pizza one night.
Scott: Yeah, it was good.
Scott: It was okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So right next to the dealer vending area was, you know, the, pretty much the core of magfest, which is the arcade and also the console gaming room.
Rym: So it's very rare that we will say this.
Rym: packs could learn a lot from how magfest got their arcade set up.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: Pax has money and yet had the tiniest little arcade.
Scott: Well, I mean the arcade, but the packs, uh, free play console room was a little different, right?
Scott: Because the way the packs free play console is, is they have all these consoles and you to rent, you pick the game you want, right?
Scott: Whereas the magfest console was more the style of, you know, Otakon where it's like, these are the games that are set up.
Scott: Just go play.
Rym: I think there should be a mix.
Rym: I think it's a, it's, I like the idea of having, I check out Kaboom and I go play it with my friends, but also the common games, like a bunch of people are going to want to play game cube smash brothers, have a whole area dedicated to that in the corner.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And just have a whole bunch of chairs lined up with the right controllers and people just loser walks.
Scott: Keep going.
Rym: It was more than, I don't think the logistics of the game room were better than Pax's game rooms or Otakon's game rooms or anything, the culture was better.
Scott: I mean there were, there were certain items that were missing.
Scott: Like there was no rampart machine, which is, you know, personal, how much can we complain about that?
Rym: Katsu con is the only con that's ever gotten us around part machine.
Rym: But in terms of my request, nonetheless, we were like, you guys get a rampart machine and they got it.
Scott: But in terms of, you know, total quality of, you know, the, the whole collection of games there were to play in the arcade and the console, it was like a plus, right?
Scott: They had more arcade machines than Katsu con has ever had way more than Pax ever had much better selection.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: God plus.
Rym: they had a crane that you could play a crane game full of stuff.
Rym: Now they bricked up the end.
Rym: They're like, all right, you can't actually get the toys, but you can play this crane game for free.
Rym: And it was way fun.
Scott: They had some pinballs, but they kept breaking, but they still had pinballs and they kept fixing them.
Rym: They kept fixing them as much as they had that ice cold beer, this electro mechanical game that we'll, we'll talk about that in a separate show sometime, but it was a, you got to get this little ball bearing pass.
Rym: It's like labyrinth, but you're moving this bar instead of moving the labyrinth.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It was, it was pretty tricky.
Scott: Pete, I think was rocking that he got to four or five holes.
Rym: I got to three on the internet.
Scott: You can see someone beat the whole thing.
Rym: Daddy, three holes.
Rym: That's the best I could do.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But they had a lot of Japanese arcade cabinets, which was awesome.
Rym: Which are really nice.
Scott: And it makes, you know, the thing I really, I never really realized about, you know, I knew it, but I didn't know it was that, you know, you sit at them because they're meant for, instead of standing, you sit and it was just so comfortable because they were exactly the right height.
Scott: I guess they're supposed to be the right height for Japanese people who are small, but they were not that much bigger.
Scott: It was the right height for me.
Scott: And sitting at them was just so comfortable.
Scott: Like that we played the Tetris one and the sticks and buttons on them were so nice.
Rym: Japanese arcade cabinets.
Rym: Cause I haven't had a lot of experience with them are way just higher quality than anything I've ever seen in America.
Scott: It really makes me wonder though, because the sticks and buttons on them were so nice.
Scott: And but supposedly the street fighter sticks we have are the same buttons and sticks, but it's not quite the same.
Scott: But I think those are worn in, so I got to, I got to wear in my stick to make it nice like this.
Rym: Just sit there and play.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Rip your tapper for an hour.
Scott: I got to play something.
Scott: Black man.
Rym: It was like, we were playing some SNK, Capcom, all those kinds of games, games that I normally would never bother with at a convention.
Rym: And yet playing it on the Japanese arcade cabinet, I actually really liked those games now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I gave those games a short shrift and I'm now I'm doing plays some a shmup that had like some re.
Scott: you had ridiculous thing, right?
Scott: It was bullet hell, but you could also deliver bullet hell.
Rym: It was like Raiden, except you have 10 times as many bullets and they're 10 times bigger.
Scott: And then you also have to pay for any of these games.
Scott: Just push the button.
Rym: It was also, it was weird.
Rym: It was like cute pig girls.
Rym: Like everything was a pig girl.
Scott: I'm sure someone knows what the game is.
Rym: It was kind of the kind of just a little bit, but it wasn't, it wasn't super perverted.
Rym: But that arcade, I, I had a lot of fun.
Rym: I could spend my whole con in that RDR machines.
Scott: They had everything.
Scott: They had old school machines.
Scott: They had, uh, you know, they had those games, the all kinds of everything.
Rym: The only thing they didn't have were the like sixties, seventies, electro mechanical stuff.
Rym: Like the, uh, I mean, ice cold beers, ice cold beers, a relatively recent game.
Scott: It's not like pinballs, pinball games or old pinballs, but it didn't have like sub hunter.
Scott: No.
Scott: One thing they did have was this challenge area, right?
Scott: Basically they have a bunch of laptops set up with emulators and it's got, how many challenges did you beat?
Rym: One.
Rym: How many did I beat?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, you could have beaten two if you would've done the one I did.
Scott: So the way the challenge thing works, I think you can download the challenges.
Scott: I think I'm not sure.
Rym: If not, let's ask mag festival to give them to us.
Scott: But anyway, you get the challenges and it's a little menu and you can choose normal, hard, unfair.
Rym: There's different, very well put together.
Rym: And you're like, all right, I want to play any S unfair challenges.
Rym: It's like, all right, beat this bionic commando level under this time without dying with no health, whatever.
Rym: Or like crazy, what was it?
Rym: Beat one of the airships at the end of Mario three with a hammer suit without losing the hammer suit.
Scott: They were all really, really hard.
Scott: And many of them I could have beaten given enough time.
Rym: I could have done it.
Rym: I just didn't want to.
Scott: No, I mean like I could go and do it now, but it would take me half a day to practice and get it just right.
Rym: The point of this, I don't think is, can I practice all day and do it?
Rym: The point is, all right, who's got the biggest Nintendo balls, sit down right now, beat that level of bionic commando.
Rym: I don't know that.
Scott: if they put it online though, you might be able to practice before the con and then you just have to perform at the con to score, but then it's more of a performance art.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, the thing is you, you load out, you choose a selection, you push the load save state button and you play, it starts you right at the challenge.
Rym: Like it's perfect.
Scott: And there's people watching the whole time.
Scott: So if you beat a challenge, you say, did I beat it?
Scott: And they say, yup.
Scott: And they mark your badge number down.
Scott: Hello packs.
Scott: This is our badge number idea.
Scott: It's just, this is like the most meager use of the badge number.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But also packs, as we've learned, magfest printed the same kind of badges you print and they had individual serial numbers on each one.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It can't be that expensive.
Scott: Our code won't cost any more than that.
Scott: because you know, it's like, Hey, we got to do it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So they wrote down your badge number and if you won enough challenges, then you would get prizes.
Scott: And you know, there's a whole chart showing what you could get.
Scott: Like you beat three NES challenges.
Scott: You get the NES badge.
Rym: Cause you're going to beat three of those challenges.
Scott: Anyway, the challenge that I beat, I beat the capture Carmen Sandiego, they start you in the final.
Rym: It took you two tries.
Scott: No, it didn't.
Rym: I see you missed a lot of questions.
Rym: I recall.
Scott: No, I only missed one.
Scott: Only one.
Scott: I only missed one thing.
Scott: And then I corrected it immediately.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: They gave me that.
Scott: They marked my thing.
Scott: I'll go ask them for the record.
Scott: I beat the capture Carmen Sandiego.
Rym: It took me a lot of tries to beat bionic commando because I'm good at, bionic commando is my game.
Rym: I figured, all right, I'll do the bionic commando challenge.
Rym: Scott did do the mega man challenge.
Scott: The mega man two challenges.
Scott: It was like, okay, beat the big tank with bubble only.
Scott: And I, you know, I got it like halfway and I was like, man, if I sat here for two more hours, I could have this.
Rym: I'm not going to waste two hours of my convention.
Rym: It was what beat heat mans level without dying with no power ups, including heat man, no alternate weapons.
Scott: See, not only you had to do, basically what it comes down to is you have to do all the jumps in the middle without using the two rocket.
Rym: I think I could have done that.
Scott: I could have done that with enough tries, but then on the same try, cause you can't die right on that same try.
Scott: You also have to beat heat man, which means you have to make the jumps.
Scott: Don't lose any of your health or lose barely any health and beat heat man without a weapon.
Scott: without with a P.
Rym: I can't beat hardly any robot masters with, with the P.
Scott: I can beat like two or three robot masters with the P, but still I can be quick man with.
Scott: I can be, I can be a quick man, airman, flash, man, or a quick man, airman, flash, and metal man.
Scott: I could be any of those four with just the metal man, metal man first.
Scott: You don't have to show it's actually airman is considered the first whatever
Rym: metal metal
Scott: man is advanced first anyway, but yeah, I can be any of those with just the P probably without dying in a reasonable amount of time, but heat man, that would have taken quite a few tries.
Rym: So the one I beat was I sat there and I tried to beat the dark level in bionic commando, not just with no weapons or anything without dying, but without any leveling up.
Rym: I cheated.
Rym: I sat there and leveled up in the level.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: There was actually one that I almost kind of did, which is the Kirby one, which was Kirby's adventure beat the mini boss with the ball.
Rym: That was sad.
Rym: You finally beat the boss.
Rym: They're like, all right, and I'll beat the level.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you have to beat the hall.
Scott: It's the mini boss level where you fight all the mini bosses.
Scott: And I was like, I beat one of the mini bosses with the ball, but you have to beat all the mini bosses with the ball and you have to have the ball at the end.
Rym: But what the gist of this is that it was an awesome thing and other cons should take this model.
Rym: I mean, packs and a lot of cons have the, Oh, here's the tournament at a concert.
Rym: We ran like Rampart tournaments just out of nowhere.
Rym: They just had this kind of constantly going super hardcore, super old school skill based tournament.
Scott: 24 seven based skill based.
Scott: It is the important part of that.
Rym: That was kind of the culture of this on.
Rym: Magfest is really a more skill based con.
Rym: Like the omega is very much random until the end to a large degree, even at the end.
Rym: and and the gaming culture, people kind of they play games, but they're not really playing to win Magfest.
Rym: Everyone's sitting down and playing to win the goddamn game.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: Is that all?
Scott: It was mostly concentrating on skill games and hard games, right?
Scott: Fighting games or a lot of fighting games.
Scott: You know, they had the console FPS, which are games of low skill, but they're games of skill.
Rym: It was a separate discussion for another time.
Scott: They had old school, you know, Donkey Kong and all this anyway.
Scott: So video games at Magfest is like, you know, very important and very good, very, very good.
Rym: So except for the BO, the only things we like, our con was basically tabletop.
Rym: We spent almost the entire con short of running all the panels we did, sitting in tabletop, playing games with our friends and with strangers.
Rym: A lot of jungle speed.
Scott: We played jungle speed the most.
Scott: I think the reason we played it the most is because, you know, we got people hooked on it, right?
Scott: Mostly our friends were hooked on it because they'd never played it before.
Scott: And we had the, I had the brand new expansion, which really amped up the difficulty and also an asshole.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then on top of that, it's a game that you could just play.
Scott: You just whip it out and play it very quickly.
Scott: Unlike say, you know, Agricola, which I brought, we didn't play it because Agricola has a bunch of set up time and rules teaching.
Scott: Whereas jungle speed, we just like, all right, we just play it.
Scott: It's easy to start.
Rym: It's easy to go.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: I'm sad we only played modern art once towards the end of the convention.
Scott: I feel like if we would have played it early, we would have played it again.
Rym: But we ran that big Bonanza game that was really rockin'.
Scott: That was a really good Bonanza game to play.
Rym: Bonanza is such a good whip out at a con game.
Rym: because there's this weird, we praise the culture of Magfest so much, but again, as I keep saying, our mega tricks was brand new at this con.
Rym: People didn't have the German style board games rocking.
Rym: They didn't have any stuff like ready to go.
Rym: They weren't, there wasn't a culture of like, people are playing a game, Hey, I'll join you.
Rym: So we'd ask people like, we like, we need one more, Hey, you want to play jungle speed?
Rym: People were afraid.
Scott: It was weird.
Scott: We were playing banana grams at one point and there was a girl sitting there.
Scott: I was like, you want to play?
Scott: She's like, no, no, no.
Scott: I'm like, why not?
Rym: It's she was like, no, no, I can't play.
Scott: I was like, was the banana gonna bite you?
Rym: It's not my bite you, but not the banana.
Scott: What are you afraid of?
Scott: He's going to play banana grams.
Rym: And even if you just sit there and go, uh, or like, you know, we ran a bunch of action castles because you know, people never heard of it there.
Rym: They never heard of anything here, but we'll get to that.
Rym: So after our panel, we did the kind of thing we do at PAX, like, Hey, we got the room for another hour.
Rym: Who wants to play a game?
Rym: And at PAX a thousand people will be like, yeah, let's go here.
Rym: Everybody got the fuck out of that room except for five awesome people.
Rym: They were there.
Rym: Like people were like game.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: And they like, they made their way out of the room as quick as they could.
Rym: They didn't want anything to do with this game.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And then the five people who remain loved it and were like, was it awesome?
Rym: They're like, yeah, should you, was everyone who left this room stupid?
Rym: They're like, yeah, I don't know why they left.
Rym: They're stupid.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, apparently the people, even though they were culturally with us, they weren't, you know, let's play a game because we were a foreign culture.
Rym: We were, we were a little different.
Rym: So we're like, Hey, we're going to run a role-playing game.
Rym: You want to play?
Rym: And everyone else who was doing that at the con had already arranged ahead of time.
Rym: Like we're going to play this gamma world game at this time in this hotel room.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Cold guy had some rockin tabletop going, but it was up in his private room party.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Well, public room party there.
Rym: Apparently that was a lot of people were saying that was like the big fun tabletop in role-playing room party.
Rym: We just couldn't get up there cause the elevators whatever.
Rym: And I don't know, total random aside cause cold guy, he gave us at the con an Atari 2,600 that was modded to have S-video out.
Rym: We've been, it's sitting right there.
Rym: We've been playing this thing pretty much nonstop since we got back.
Scott: Totally.
Scott: It's great to have an Atari that actually works on a real modern television.
Scott: It's like, Whoa, you don't have to use any adapters and cables or anything weird.
Scott: You just pop in a game, you turn it on.
Scott: It works every time.
Rym: No blowing guys like that big.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Outlaw is the best.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: But I came to your room the last time on Saturday night, it was like two 30 in the morning and I knocked on the room party door.
Rym: I'm pretty sure you were asleep and I woke you guys up.
Rym: So I'm sorry.
Scott: But anyway, uh, we did some panels at magfest.
Scott: We did, we were on two panels that were intellectual panels.
Scott: It was actually, you know, we call everything.
Scott: We do a panel, but most of what we do is actually a lecture presentation.
Scott: We did two panels that were actually panels.
Scott: And I was, I was apprehensive going in cause.
Scott: I was like, all right, these people based on their emails seem smart, but we don't know them, but we don't know them.
Scott: And we don't know their personalities and we don't know their public speaking skills.
Scott: So is this really going to work out?
Rym: It worked out crazy.
Rym: Well, when we sit down, we're all introducing ourselves for the panel.
Rym: And I realized that we're the only ones without doctorates and like advanced game theory.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then dr hazard hung out with us like the whole con.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Hazard.
Rym: Everyone was awesome.
Rym: But dr hazard was kind of the most awesome.
Rym: I think we meshed pretty well.
Rym: That was fun.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All of us for a bunch of magfest staff, cause we were talking game theory over dinner and I think we got far too into the math.
Rym: So we turned to the magfest guys.
Rym: We're like, you want to play the dollar auction?
Rym: Two dollar auction.
Rym: In fact, it was two dollar auction anyway.
Scott: Um, so yeah, uh, the panels actually went really well in the second one.
Scott: I was good.
Scott: Amprehensive again, even though the first one went well because this guy was moderating.
Scott: Yeah, but he's our friend from a kinetic con, but I was still, I was like, all right, he's acting a little goofy right now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But then as soon as the panel started, he was for serious.
Rym: He was like, well, will the gentleman on the left answer gave us all titles?
Rym: I was the captain.
Scott: No, I was the admiral.
Scott: I don't know what I was.
Scott: I was hefe or something, but yeah, we just, you know, the panels, they both went great.
Scott: Even though the attendance was and no, the attendance was good.
Rym: It was okay.
Rym: I mean, for this kind of con, this is not a panel going con.
Rym: The people who are going to panels are the hardcore people who care about the thing or the people who want to go see the celebrity.
Rym: Like John St.
Rym: John does his panel, the rooms full of course.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Actually he was doing a whole bunch of stuff at the con bridge.
Scott: Anything you can do.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Well, we had to do like a separate segment on John St.
Rym: John at this time, but we did, you know, losing should be fun.
Rym: And we did this to other panels.
Rym: losing should be fun.
Rym: We actually had to kind of modify it like as we were going, because we went to a panel before we did anything else.
Rym: And it was this guy who was talking about like collaborative storytelling in role-playing games.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And we're like, all right, let's see what this guy's deal is.
Rym: Let's see if he knows.
Rym: And he's very articulate.
Rym: He knows his stuff.
Scott: He wasn't like the greatest presenter, but he was pretty good above average for a convention panel, especially a convention of that.
Rym: However, the panel, the gist of the panel was this is a world where only Dungeons and dragons exists.
Rym: So be that as that being the reality of the world, how do we make D and D a better role-playing game?
Rym: He basically did this great panel.
Rym: that is only great if you've never heard of any other role-playing game ever.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It was, it was similar to the way in which those we talked about in the forum, right?
Scott: These biologists who discovered calculus on their own.
Scott: It's like, they didn't know calculus.
Rym: At one point in the panel, the guy was like, so what if, what if?
Rym: now bear with me, suppose you at a little point, if a player rolled really well, you let them control the narrative.
Rym: Tell me what you found.
Rym: Like, let them have a little control of the story.
Scott: I was like, have you played any games invented?
Rym: since you might think this is going to break your game and it might, but if you just start introducing these little to give them a little bit of control, we're like, we, we all raise our hands simultaneously.
Rym: Like, have you ever heard of burning wheel inspectors, lacuna, we listed like a hundred games and he was like, no, I've never really heard any of those.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think this is the thing.
Rym: When he opened the panel, I felt bad.
Rym: He was like, so I, you know, I'm a really experienced role player.
Rym: I've been playing tabletop, you know, role-playing games like Dungeons and dragons since 1996.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And I was like, really only 96, huh?
Scott: But yeah, it's like, imagine if there was some guy who came in to talk about board games and everyone in the world, the only board game anyone played in the whole world was monopoly.
Scott: Nobody like 99% of people only play monopoly and very, very few people I've ever even heard of any other board game, but monopoly board game is synonymous with the word monopoly.
Rym: The culture of magfest is really rocking in many ways.
Rym: Like it really jived with us, but it was also very insular.
Rym: Like it's, it's the separate little thing.
Rym: Like a lot of the people there either only go to magfest and never any other cons or have, like, this is the first time they've ever been to, or there are people who go to all the DC area cons, like they go to katsu con and magfest and all these things in one of our panels, like monopoly came up.
Rym: And when we were like, you guys realize you're all playing monopoly wrong, right?
Rym: Free parking.
Rym: Isn't in the rules the way you think it is.
Rym: And you're supposed to be auctioning it off properties.
Rym: The whole room was like, what one guy, aren't you just like, no, it's in the rules.
Scott: One guy was like from the UK and he was like, you know, I'm not going to do the XA, but he's like, you know, everyone, he's like, everybody in the UK, he's like, that's not the rules.
Scott: Everyone in the UK plays with the money on free parking.
Scott: I'm like, yeah, everyone does.
Scott: Everyone's not following.
Rym: the one guy in the audience had his iPhone.
Rym: He's like, it's like the right.
Rym: It's not there.
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Scott: It's not there.
Rym: What do you think this is?
Rym: So we did.
Rym: losing should be fun, but we actually kind of, we went really short on some of the things we normally talk about.
Rym: losing should be fun as an excuse to talk about all the indie RPGs that no one at this con had ever heard of.
Rym: We were like, oh my God, inverting wheel.
Rym: If you lose, it's actually kind of awesome.
Rym: We talked about dread.
Rym: People lost it.
Scott: People always lose it when they hear about dread, even at the start of the con.
Rym: Yeah, but they're starting to, people know about it now.
Rym: This caused a little bit of a problem for us later because after doing all this, we were rocking the tabletop.
Scott: Scott ran a free market game, like a whole free market game early Sunday morning.
Rym: And we got people to sit down and commit to a four hour game of free market at a con.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I think our mercy was great.
Rym: Our whole sh*t was we want to shrink everybody else, like make shrinking cool because we want to be giants.
Scott: You could have just made yourselves bigger instead.
Rym: No, but we want to make everyone else smaller.
Scott: You could do that too.
Rym: Because it means more absolute space for us because I was playing colossus.
Rym: But we ran a bunch of swords, like the sword burning wheel because no one ever heard of this.
Rym: And once again, the people who have never played a role playing game before were the ones who rocked it the most.
Rym: There's this one girl, I forget your name.
Scott: She was definitely the best.
Rym: She was cute.
Rym: She sits down.
Rym: She's like, I've never played a role playing game before.
Rym: Can I play this with you?
Rym: And we're like, yeah.
Scott: Let's go for it.
Scott: We want you to play this.
Rym: Play it now.
Rym: I hand her the elf.
Rym: She's reading over the sheet.
Rym: I'm just starting to explain to everyone else what their characters are.
Rym: She's like, that dwarf's not getting the sword.
Rym: Can I argue with him about it?
Rym: Or should I just stab him?
Rym: Give me some dice.
Rym: What do I do?
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: She was very awesome.
Rym: She died weeping bitterly and alone after failing to tend the dwarf's mortal wounds.
Scott: Meanwhile, there are some D&D guys.
Scott: They had played D&D at least once before, right?
Scott: And then we're just like, all right, we'll go to the elven land and then we'll go to the dwarven land.
Rym: What is with you people always being like, we're going to compromise.
Rym: We're going to be nice and chill.
Scott: And I'm trying to egg him on.
Scott: It's like, come on.
Scott: Are you really going to let him get away with that?
Scott: It's like, that's the sword you needed.
Rym: One guy rage quit.
Rym: Well, he didn't rage quit.
Rym: He basically had really the sword.
Scott: He must quit.
Rym: He was like, you know what?
Rym: The whole time he's like, yeah, the elves can have the sword.
Rym: I don't care.
Scott: It's a new category of quitting.
Scott: I think it's like, I don't know, fade quit.
Rym: And then he just got quieter and quieter.
Rym: And then at one point he was like, yeah, I'm really not going to play this anymore.
Rym: And he's got up and walked away.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It didn't work.
Rym: So we were like the dwarf, we're like the dwarf just kind of has an epileptic fit and chokes to death.
Scott: I was like, he just, the dwarf wanders off into the darkness choking to death in the corner.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It was weird.
Rym: That was just weird.
Rym: He seemed to be having fun though.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know what was up with that guy.
Rym: I think he was in over his head.
Rym: I think he thought we were going to play this really short light game and we sit down and we're playing a short game, but it's burning a wheel.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, the only thing that in my life that it reminds me of is I was at a public speaking class in high school.
Scott: It was just called speech, but it was public speaking class.
Scott: And I had one friend and he had, you know, the stage fright, but he went up there.
Scott: He started giving a speech.
Scott: He was doing just fine.
Scott: He was doing great.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: I was like, yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: He's going.
Scott: And then just suddenly he stops.
Scott: He's like, I can't do it anymore.
Scott: I'm like, what?
Scott: It was like, it was that kind of, you know, someone's up there.
Scott: They're doing their thing.
Scott: And then just suddenly just like, they like, I give up.
Scott: It's like, it didn't even look nervous.
Scott: Normally you can tell someone's nervous.
Scott: They're stuttering or they're, they're going slow or they're shifty.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's totally just fine.
Scott: And then I quit.
Scott: I was like, what?
Rym: But I mean, the swords we rerun, I don't want to get, we can't have time obviously to talk about every sword we ran, but they were all pretty damn epic.
Rym: And Pete was running danger patrol.
Rym: People are really digging the danger patrol.
Rym: Everyone digs danger patrol, but as a result of the panel and talking about it at the end of the night, even when I was like, my throat's gone, my voice is dead.
Rym: Like I got to go to bed guys.
Rym: And all these kids come up, they're like, please, we heard about this game that you guys were running.
Rym: Can we play?
Rym: And I can't turn a guy down like that.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: He's like, we played D and D and nothing else.
Rym: I heard this is different.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: You're right.
Rym: Those kids, they, that was the blackest dwarf I've ever seen.
Rym: He walked in like Shat killed everybody.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Uh, what else went down in Magfest?
Rym: I mean, our con was pretty much doing our panels, playing tabletop and playing video games.
Rym: We didn't do a lot else.
Scott: I do want to point out though, uh, that at Magfest, right.
Scott: We kept score.
Rym: Uh, we did.
Rym: We had the league of hero legends, right?
Scott: Anytime somebody won a game at Magfest, any competitive game, right.
Scott: Or any challenge we set up like, all right, high score on this right now.
Scott: Let's go.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They got a point.
Scott: And, uh, the final score is Tim.
Scott: I got one point.
Scott: Uh, that's Tim McNeil, the head of panels.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Uh, George got a point.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, Pete got five points.
Rym: Well, cause Pete was rocking the ice cold beer, right?
Rym: He was also rocking the ice cold beer.
Scott: Wyatt got one point.
Scott: Uh, Rym got 13 points.
Scott: Not bad.
Scott: But Scott got 15 points.
Scott: However.
Scott: What do you mean however?
Scott: I beat you by two points.
Rym: You did beat me by two points.
Rym: That's legit.
Rym: What are you going to come up with?
Rym: The only thing I'm going to point out, I'm just going to, this is true information about one of the challenges.
Rym: Scott and I had a game of DDR and Scott failed in the second song and I was winning by an order of 93 points.
Rym: I didn't fail on any song.
Rym: You failed in the second song.
Scott: It didn't F. It didn't F kick me out.
Scott: I got, I got at least a D every time.
Rym: D because you failed, but you came back because your score is incrementing two points per step after you would hit the point of failure.
Rym: That's why your score was so low.
Scott: I didn't fail.
Scott: It didn't say failed.
Rym: However, in the third song, which I was wearing boots and I mistakenly thought I can do rhythm and police on maniac and boots.
Rym: Scott bumped it down to trick.
Rym: So he got a bunch of points.
Rym: I failed immediately on the song because I tripped on my boot and then I got a 300 combo on the rest of the song.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Technically though, the score, there was points.
Rym: Scott won.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So even if I give you the DDR, I'm still winning by two.
Rym: And if you give me the DDR, that means you lose a point and I get a point.
Scott: But on top of that, do you recall there was a game that I knowingly knew that you were an expert at this game, yet I agreed to challenge you to it and lost because I was ahead so much.
Rym: What game was that?
Scott: I forget.
Rym: But what game?
Scott: Huh?
Scott: What game?
Rym: In fact, I also point out that I played the Capcom versus SNK with you and I am the worst fighting game player in the world.
Scott: But there was a game that you were expert at that.
Rym: I also played Street Fighter two against you.
Rym: I did okay there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There was a game that you were expert at that.
Scott: I just said, all right, I'm going to give Rym one.
Scott: Let's play this expert game that he's awesome at.
Scott: Because I know that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What game was it?
Rym: Because I don't remember.
Scott: There was definitely one where I'm like, I know I'm going to lose.
Scott: Let's just go for it.
Rym: It was got plus.
Scott: No, it wasn't.
Scott: Anyway, I've been practicing my god plus.
Rym: A lot of those were jungle speeds, to be fair.
Scott: There were many of those 13 over jungle speed.
Rym: So jungle speed, as much as I like the the real wooden totem is probably a good thing with the dog toy totem, because at least five or six times we knock the totem like off into a crowd.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Scott: All right.
Scott: What else?
Rym: There was a bunch of random weird stuff like Scott, Pete, why not Pete, Scott, why didn't?
Rym: I were?
Rym: the only people at this con were in kilts.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But there was this one guy and he I think he stashed like Otakani, he's one of those guys who was like, I'm going to staff every con for the rest of my life.
Rym: Big beard, totally chill guy, old school wargamer, old school anime fan.
Rym: And he sees us and he's like, I feel stupid.
Rym: I have 12 kills, six of them are utility kills.
Rym: I didn't bring them because it was cold and I didn't get a lot of fucking kills.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: He's he's a killed guy.
Rym: He's a lifestyle.
Scott: Why did he with that many kills?
Scott: Why does he have any pants?
Scott: Yeti had pants and he had enough pants for a whole weekend.
Rym: But it was.
Rym: I just want to note that guy because that guy was actually pretty awesome.
Rym: I talked to him for a while about kills.
Rym: He told me there's a formal kill, like a real kill, real looking that's made out of like this polyester blend.
Rym: It's like 50 bucks, but it's a really has 12 kills.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: He's like, if you want to wear a real kill instead of a utility kill, like the ease of the utility kill.
Rym: I forget what it was called.
Rym: I got his phone number.
Rym: I'll talk to him at some point.
Rym: He was a chill guy.
Rym: John St.
Rym: John.
Rym: It's funny to see him because at PAX, we hung out with him for like all of Friday.
Rym: But we hung out like we went to a restaurant.
Rym: We walked around the con, but we didn't see him in his natural element.
Rym: His natural element is go to a hotel con.
Rym: Everybody is buying him drinks.
Scott: He went to 31 room parties, 31.
Rym: I thought I was hardcore when I went to bed at four thirty in the morning.
Rym: When I wake up, I see a tweet from him at like seven a.m He's like 16 room parties later.
Rym: I think it's time to go to bed on Friday.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But he was like on every panel, like any Magfest, any Magfest thing that he was the announcer doing his thing.
Rym: He was there.
Scott: He was there Sunday morning.
Rym: I saw him looking so good.
Rym: He had his sunglasses on.
Rym: He's sitting there like, yeah.
Rym: And then he'd like he'd muster it and say something and then he would go back to hang over there, though.
Scott: He was there the whole time.
Rym: He was there.
Scott: He was there.
Rym: He he had a good shtick going.
Rym: He would basically like gather an entourage of cool people who would follow him around and just crash room parties, like wander into someone's room party and be like, hey, guys, and do his shtick.
Rym: And people loved it.
Rym: He was the celebrity of the con hands down.
Scott: You know, he tried real hard and it totally worked.
Scott: That's that's his place, his place of power.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The hotel con.
Rym: And I can't imagine how much alcohol was bought for him by attendees at that con.
Scott: The only other things that I'm remembering now right are we did the Child's Play charity auction.
Rym: That was actually.
Rym: So the Child's Play charity auction started out real slow, like no one was bidding right away.
Rym: So Scott and I were like, oh, we got to do something.
Rym: So we started bidding it up.
Rym: We did not need to bid it up.
Rym: It bid bid up on its own pretty quickly after that.
Scott: But it's like people just started bringing stuff into the room to sell, like as it was going on.
Rym: So you might know this guy.
Rym: He dresses up as the Internet and all the.
Scott: I don't know his real name.
Scott: I don't know his story.
Scott: All I know is he's the guy who dresses up at the as the Internet and all the Northeast con.
Rym: We know him and he knows.
Rym: I see him at every con and he sees us and there's always.
Rym: every time I see him, I give the nod.
Rym: He gives the nod back at Connecticut, like he raised on some panels, like it runs panels.
Rym: He's just everywhere.
Rym: He has the rape clock.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's rape a clock on the Internet.
Rym: That's just his thing.
Rym: Like Jewish Wolf would.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: He walked into the room.
Rym: He'll have the rape clock and he put it for auction.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I was like, Dan, the whole room was like, I didn't see what it went for.
Scott: You know, I don't.
Scott: I wasn't.
Scott: I didn't stay that long.
Scott: I had to leave.
Scott: Catch the bus back to New York.
Scott: But he put the rape clock up for auction.
Scott: I would not be surprised if he bought it back himself.
Rym: Just as an excuse.
Scott: As a way to donate.
Scott: I mean, think about that.
Scott: You can put your own thing up there, you know, and then buy it back no matter how much you have to bid up.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: They had that scary Sonic the Hedgehog, like big.
Scott: The girl.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know what her name is.
Rym: Doll that apparently people have had sex with.
Rym: I can't quite tell what's going on with it.
Rym: You heard that story.
Rym: They were trying to tell if it ended up in different people's houses and it was.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know about that.
Rym: But when you when you bid on that thing, you don't get it.
Rym: You get to dictate what happens to it, which might be.
Rym: It got given to me.
Scott: OK.
Rym: There is a weird story there.
Rym: I feel like that's a magfest lore.
Rym: We got to talk more about the Colossus Roar.
Rym: All right.
Scott: What do you say about it?
Rym: The Colossus Roar.
Scott: People roar all the time and then everyone loses their voice because it's really dry.
Rym: So at Otakon.
Rym: Mutskacha.
Scott: Mutskacha.
Rym: There's everywhere.
Rym: The Colossus Roar has a lot more culture behind it, like it has more meaning, like when someone does it, they do it for a reason.
Rym: They're like, I just won this game.
Scott: All the Baltimore fans were using it anytime they had a good play.
Rym: We're all eating dinner, us and like a bunch of magfest staff and Dr.
Rym: Hazard were hanging out in the private room of the restaurant and outside we hear like suddenly.
Rym: Roar, roar, roar, roar.
Rym: And we look on Twitter and like, yeah, touchdown.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And also some people are really good at the Colossus Roar.
Rym: I can't do it for crap.
Scott: Sometimes I would heard people do it and I couldn't tell if it was a real person or if the game was just, you know, the volume on that game was cranked up all the way.
Rym: Or if Colossus himself had come to the con because he lives in New York, he could take the bolt bus down.
Rym: He could have.
Scott: Right?
Rym: I did not see any Colossus cosplayers though.
Scott: That was very strange.
Scott: You think there would be some.
Rym: Because there was a lot of cosplay.
Scott: Next year it's on you.
Scott: Colossus cosplay.
Rym: But the Colossus Roar is such like a fun, it didn't get annoying and I was really surprised.
Rym: I thought it was going to be really annoying.
Scott: But it doesn't, you know, the audio of it, it's audible properties, right?
Scott: It's not like butt scratch, which has a little annoyance and it's, you know, and no one can actually do it that loud to where it's painful or anything like that.
Scott: And since it's hard, it's relatively hard to do and people are losing their voice and getting dry.
Scott: They're not overusing it.
Scott: They use it like just the right amount.
Rym: Now the rule is if you hear it, you respond in kind if you feel that the moment is right.
Rym: And the moment, and it would kind of follow like when the con was the highest energy, the Roars would be pretty frequent.
Rym: 6 a.m.
Rym: the Roars are starting to die out because someone does it and everyone else is like, They're also a lot more on Thursday and Friday and less on Saturday and Sunday.
Rym: Though I think the reason it was awesome was that we were sitting there on like Saturday night, it's like three in the morning, catching the last shuttle bus back to our hotel.
Rym: I know 3 a.m.
Rym: at this con is the same energy level as 3 p.m The con doesn't die out until about 6 a.m It does have amping up periods, you know, obviously in the prime time hours.
Rym: But like 6 a.m.
Rym: to 10 a.m.
Rym: is the only quiet-ish time.
Rym: And even then, there are people playing games in the lobby.
Rym: But we're standing outside and in the hotel, there's like Roar Roar and you hear it through the doors and then off in the woods between us and the other hotel, you hear one guy just like, Whaaaat?
Rym: Off in the distance.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That was the moment.
Scott: That's pretty awesome right there.
Rym: That was like my moment at that con.
Scott: That was good.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I had a lot of fun at Magfest.
Scott: I did have quite a bit of fun there, but I don't know.
Scott: Is it worth two vacation days?
Scott: Maybe I go back, but I just go back Friday or later Thursday after work instead of taking Thursday off.
Rym: All Magfest brings to the table, to be perfectly honest, is the venue and the culture and the arcade room.
Rym: Everything else, I guess, and the concerts, but the concerts were impossible for us to go to because you couldn't bring a bag in, there's a wall of BO and the room was tiny.
Rym: But they simulcast the concerts on the hotel TV to anywhere that you wanted to watch it.
Rym: So every hotel room, that room party just had the concerts going on the TV.
Scott: That was very good and very clever.
Scott: But yeah, other than that, it's like Magfest itself doesn't bring anything else to the table, right?
Scott: So it's like, I already have two packets on my schedule, do I really need to go?
Scott: Well, I think if Magfest fixed itself, right, they fixed some of their logistical situations, professionalism.
Rym: Move to a real venue.
Scott: Yeah, I would be willing to go back if it improved and give it, you know, another shot just because it was a lot of fun going on there.
Scott: I don't know if I'd take Thursday off work, I might go Thursday after work.
Rym: Not maybe.
Scott: But yeah, I mean, you know, it was sort of, it's sort of on the borderline, right?
Scott: It wasn't, it had big problems, terrible reg, terrible BO.
Rym: But it gets a lot of points for just the fact that I don't go to any hotel cons.
Rym: I want one hotel con in my repertoire every year.
Scott: Yeah, so if, you know, if they keep upping their game, you know, I'll keep going back and helping them up their game.
Scott: But if it gets worse or stays the same, I don't think I can.
Scott: I can invest, you know, in it as much.
Rym: That red line was unforgivable.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I worry because they're at a point where their venue sucks.
Rym: They have to move.
Rym: They'll have to move into D.C.
Rym: where suddenly the laws are much more like real cities.
Rym: They can't get away with the B.S.
Rym: they got away with in Alexandria, Virginia.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We'll see if their professionalism is the is the doom of them or lack their lack of professional.
Rym: because we can say this.
Rym: Tim, the guy runs panels, knew what he was doing, like like every problem that we could have pointed out, he was already aware of and wanted to fix.
Rym: Yeah, but it's a kind of a Katsucon situation where like video Katsu, the guys we were with was like its own unit.
Rym: that itself was competent.
Rym: But much of the rest of Katsucon had serious problems that eventually exploded.
Scott: We definitely heard whisperings and mumblings of drama in the high level.
Rym: We will not get into the things that we know that we have learned from going to Magfest.
Rym: There is some crazy drama.
Scott: And also, you know, the number of staff.
Scott: I mean, the culture of staff wasn't like a bad culture, like the Otakon staff culture, but it wasn't a culture professionalism.
Scott: It's like they had the right attitude about gaming and all that stuff.
Scott: But they didn't.
Scott: they weren't like on top of the game in terms of, you know, let's work really hard to make everything the best.
Scott: It was more like, oh, man, we made a really good at making a funny commercial.
Scott: Yeah, they're not really good at managing a line.
Rym: But they had a lot of good staff who are new, like old Katsucon staff after the explosion.
Rym: A lot of the people we used to work with at Katsucon were now staff in this.
Rym: A lot of the really good people.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So we'll see how it goes.
Rym: It's hard to say.
Scott: To wait and see on the next Magfest.
Rym: What?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.