Rym: It's Tuesday, March 22nd, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, spot it and highlights from PAX East 2011.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: And we're back.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: God, two weekends in a row of conventions is almost too much for this pony.
Scott: That is definitely too much.
Scott: It wasn't just the conventions, right?
Scott: It was like almost every night I was out doing something after work.
Scott: I have not been home immediately after work since pre-Pax.
Rym: Since pre-Pax?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Damn, I actually have been home almost every day because I planned well.
Scott: I had all this stuff to do.
Rym: Yeah, I did all my stuff.
Scott: I had so much stuff to do, I couldn't do it all.
Scott: I opted to do the things that were out on the town and neglected laundry and groceries.
Rym: Ah, see, I've gotten around things on the town by never needing things on the town.
Rym: I mean, I needed new boots.
Rym: Got it at Ross.
Scott: I'm not talking about shopping.
Scott: It's like going to meetings with people and events of various sorts.
Rym: I got that hacker thing next week that I forgot about until I got a reminder about it.
Scott: Oh, you actually need to go to it?
Rym: Yeah, might as well.
Scott: The hacker town hall, the one we went to before?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I don't know if I'm going to go back.
Scott: The town hall...
Rym: This one supposedly is more structured and has stuff going on.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Alright, maybe I'll try it one more time.
Rym: I may or may not go.
Rym: I haven't decided 100%.
Scott: Yeah, because the hacker town hall I've been sort of disappointed in.
Scott: Not really the greatest expenditure of time.
Rym: It's only because they don't have enough structure and they don't actually do anything.
Rym: It seems to exist solely so that people who are desperate for venture capital can give business cards to other people who they think are venture capitalists.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: I mean, I got more business cards thrown in my face there than any place I've ever been short of an anime con.
Scott: That's what the tech things are all about.
Rym: Yeah, it kind of bothers me.
Scott: Apparently there's this thing that's called the New York Tech Meetup, right?
Scott: And you think that that's the biggest thing.
Scott: And it is the biggest thing.
Scott: There's a zillion people.
Scott: It fills the Skirball, which you went there to see Will Wright, remember?
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: And they fill it, I think, every month.
Scott: And you have to buy a ticket to it.
Scott: It's not free.
Scott: And apparently you have to be on... It's one of those things like Otakon Artist Alley where you have to buy the ticket right away before it sells out.
Scott: But supposedly, from what everyone says, I've never been to it, the vast majority of the people there are business people.
Scott: And there's a very small number of actual tech people there.
Scott: So it's like, if you're a tech person, it's just like everyone just wants to give you money and whatever, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, sounds about right.
Rym: I wouldn't mind them giving me money, except that usually when I get offers where someone says, "I will give you money to do something," it's not something fun.
Scott: No, but basically if I had a product that I wanted to demonstrate, I would go to it.
Scott: But otherwise, there's no reason for me to go there.
Rym: But anyway, since we're back, we're going to do normal GeekNights shows again.
Rym: This, I think, is the first gaming show since PAX.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes it's weird.
Scott: I don't realize it that often, but I think we need to be more conscious of it.
Scott: That because we do a show, any given day is once every other week.
Scott: If we miss one Tuesday show, that means a month goes by between Tuesday shows.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: That's too much, I think.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So...
Rym: Granted, every year convention season kind of hits us in the ass.
Scott: Uh, yeah.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: But yeah, we're going back on regular schedule.
Scott: Hurray.
Scott: Finally.
Scott: So, let's get to some regular old news.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: So, we were at the PAX.
Rym: We were at the PAX.
Scott: And usually, you know, we're the kind of people that like to ignore certain things that other people find really exciting, like waiting in line to play the latest and greatest thing.
Rym: Now, we've talked about this in our PAX shows.
Rym: I mean, there's nothing in the expo hall that you can't play on your own with no wait within a couple months at most.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, it's like, why would you wait two hours to play Duke Nukem 3D when you could just not go play a board game for two hours, then, in a month, buy Duke Nukem 3D?
Rym: Well, if you needed yet another reason to not wait in line in expo halls.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, we went and I was gonna make an exception to my not waiting in line rule because the 3DS was there.
Scott: And I'm like, "Oh, I gotta check that
Scott: out.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: That's just too, you know, that's just too big a thing not to check out.
Scott: And supposedly, the line looked really long, but people said the line only took 20 minutes, but whatever.
Rym: 20 PEX minutes, though, to be fair.
Scott: Yeah, those are valuable minutes.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: I have only a few of them twice a year.
Scott: The thing is, as soon as we got back to New York City, the Nintendo store around the corner from my office had 3DSs, and you could just walk up and use one.
Scott: And also, there's a huge display in Grand Central.
Scott: You can just walk up and use the 3DS not waiting.
Rym: Huh.
Rym: Literally across the street from my office.
Scott: So, I just went over and I tried one out for a significant, like, you know, 20 minutes.
Rym: What was extra funny is I went at, like, peak lunch hour.
Rym: You know, like, millions of people everywhere.
Scott: I wonder how many minutes they gave you at PEX.
Scott: And here's the thing.
Rym: Not only was I the only dude anywhere near the Nintendo display, I was the only guy, like, who even was interested, and the Nintendo employees were trying to get anyone to come over, and it seems like no one cared.
Rym: The fact that I walked over, they were, like, elated.
Rym: They were like, "Oh my god, they surrounded
Rym: me.".
Rym: They're like, "I'll play with you.
Rym: You want me to show you how it
Rym: works?".
Rym: "Oh my god, D-S-I, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
Rym: yeah.".
Scott: How much did they get paid to be that excited?
Rym: They, it was...
Scott: You gotta pay me a lot to, I mean, like, if you don't pay them a lot, they're just gonna stand there like, "Yup,
Scott: yup.".
Rym: So, you know why I think they were excited?
Rym: Boredom trumps all.
Rym: There was nobody there.
Rym: Nobody cares in the real world about video games.
Scott: Yeah, I'm, it's like I wanna bet against the 3DS, 'cause the signs are pointing south, but I can't possibly bet against the Nintendo handheld.
Scott: You just, that is the dumbest bet you can possibly make.
Rym: I'm gonna bet against, but not in the way you'd expect.
Rym: Here's my problem.
Rym: Go back to when the DS came out, when Nintendo was like, "Look, we have our Game Boy, it's number
Rym: one.".
Rym: "We have the Wii, you know, GameCube/Wii, that's number
Rym: two.".
Rym: The third pillar is gonna be the DS.
Rym: Now that was code speak for, "The DS is probably gonna fail, and we're hedging our
Rym: bets.".
Scott: That's right.
Scott: We can go, we can fall back on the GBA and just make, come out with a better GBA if the DS doesn't work.
Rym: And of course, we thought, Virtual Boy at worst, and both bought DSes the day it came out.
Scott: That was a good strategy.
Rym: Ah, it was a good strategy, except that there were no good games for the DS for some time after it came out.
Scott: Oh, there was Mario 64.
Rym: Which I'd already played.
Scott: Yeah, there were a few.
Rym: Name another one, name a game.
Scott: Advance Wars.
Rym: I had that, uh, when did the first DS Advance Wars come out, Scott?
Scott: The day after the DS came out.
Rym: Yeah, and I already had two Advance Warses on the GBA.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: But the thing is, there was, you know, at launch, there was something exciting, and then there was a big gap before anything else came out.
Scott: And the only thing about the DS, really, is that the third parties have been holding it up.
Scott: Big third parties on the DS, not on the Wii.
Rym: You can't blame the third parties anymore, because Nintendo, they never, like, even their own first party products don't innovate at nearly as much as they used to.
Rym: There was that one era where they were like, check it out, Crystal Chronicles, shared spaces, private spaces, four swords.
Scott: Of course, yeah, the era where they were the most innovative was the era when they were on the bottom with the GameCube, right?
Rym: Yup, because innovation is not how you make money.
Scott: 'Cause when they, you see, now they were at the bottom, so they tried to innovate and do lots of cool new stuff to get back on top.
Scott: And it worked, they innovated the Wii and the DS, and now they're on top, so they stopped innovating.
Rym: So, I guess my trouble is, I do not trust Nintendo anymore to buy anything they make sight unseen.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: There was a time when they would say, "Zelda
Rym: game?"
Rym: and I would say, "Give me one.
Rym: Sold.".
Rym: I mean, I'd already spent my money.
Scott: I'll probably buy the Wii Zelda game that's gonna come out.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, probably.
Scott: Whatever it is.
Rym: But I wouldn't buy it sight unseen.
Rym: I'm gonna look at a review first.
Scott: I'll probably pay 50 bucks for it.
Rym: I might.
Rym: I'm gonna wait, though, and see.
Scott: I'll pre-order on Amazon.
Rym: I don't pre-order any Nintendo anymore.
Scott: I'll pre-order a big Zelda game on Amazon.
Scott: That's a safe bet.
Rym: There's just, I don't trust Nintendo to make games I care about anymore, and while they may eventually, and there's gonna be this long, like, build-up until eventually, "Oh, snap!
Rym: The 3DS is the
Rym: console!".
Rym: Then, you know what?
Rym: I'll buy the 3DS Lite.
Scott: I. Yeah, I'm definitely, 3DS Lite is definitely something.
Scott: So anyway, I used the 3DS, I played Pilotwings, I played Street Fighter, and, uh...
Rym: I think it was like three or four years ago on GeekNights, I kept saying, "They gotta remake
Rym: Pilotwings!".
Rym: They did.
Scott: But yeah, you know, basically what it amounted to is the 3D actually works surprisingly well, and I'm pretty sure that my hypothesis of it's all about how good your vision is.
Scott: People with really good vision have less, far less problems with 3D stuff like this than people with less good vision.
Scott: Anyway, I have amazing vision, so the 3D worked just fine, but if you do tilt it, it becomes 2D, you know, if you got a bad viewing angle.
Rym: Now, the funny thing is, tilting it, you tilt it like one and a half degrees left or right, and it kinda, like, it messes it up.
Scott: Like, the depth just collapses, which is expected, I mean, obviously there's- But at least it doesn't become, like, unviewable, it just becomes flat.
Scott: You know, the 3D goes away, but you can still see what's going on, so you actually won't fuck up your game.
Scott: You'll still, like, win.
Rym: Also, Scott, I just have to, 'cause I knew you were wrong, but I wanted to have the exact evidence to crush you.
Rym: DS released in North America November 21st, 2004.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Advance Wars DS released in North America August 22nd, 2005.
Rym: What?
Rym: Six months, more than six months.
Rym: I remember- You're wrong, you're lying, you're making shit up.
Scott: What?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: 'Cause I remember we went to that GameStop in Wildwood, like, the day after.
Rym: Uh, Scott, we had DS's for a long time before that.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I bought my DS in the winter.
Scott: Anyway, it must be true if it's on Wikipedia.
Rym: So, alright, I could've waited six months, lost nothing, and then bought the DS.
Scott: True.
Scott: So, anyway, the 3DS, the 3D was way cool.
Scott: There is no denying that the 3D was totally awesome, unless, you know, it doesn't work for you.
Rym: Eh, one problem with the 3D.
Rym: It worked perfectly, but if you set it to the maximum 3D, though I do really like how you have a slider to control how 3D it is- The slider didn't really- it only made it, like, a little bit more deeper- Are you kidding?
Rym: When I slid it, it moved in like a foot worth of vision.
Scott: Really?
Scott: It only moved- you know, I didn't see that much movement.
Rym: When I put it to the max, it was way in there, but at the same time, when I had it at the max, about five minutes of play and my eyes started hurting.
Scott: No, my eyes didn't hurt at all.
Rym: But then when I moved it in a little bit from the max, it looked just as good, and no more eye hurt.
Scott: Really?
Scott: I had no eye hurt whatsoever, at any point.
Scott: But anyway, the thing was, is like, the Street Fighter game, it was actually- I was like, 'cause Street Fighter, any fighting game that's serious, you're like, no handheld can possibly do that.
Scott: But actually, because it has four face buttons and two LR, it actually kind of worked.
Rym: Oh, you got to play the Street Fighter.
Rym: They actually didn't have any DS games to play in Grand Central.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: They had this one bullshit game where the camera- so it shows the real world through the camera, and when you move it around, you see the real world.
Rym: And there's stuff you got to shoot.
Rym: It's like a real space first person shooter.
Scott: Oh, that could be cool.
Rym: It was cool, except it was like this stupid demo game that was obviously aimed at old people and little kids.
Scott: Yeah, there's no way you're going to pay for that.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's like, oh, this is cool.
Scott: I would never pay for it.
Rym: But it's interesting that in the World Store, they had real games, and then in the real world, where they're trying to demo it, they have the same kind of crap that they sell on the Wii.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but I also- you know, Pilotwings, you know, was Pilotwings.
Scott: It's like, fly through the rings.
Scott: And I was flying through the rings, and I flew through all the rings successfully, and then I landed.
Rym: Hey, Pilotwings was a pretty revolutionary game.
Scott: Yeah, but this is just Pilotwings.
Scott: It's like, so, it's like there's- the 3DS is cool, the 3D works, but there's no- there's nothing on it that I want to pay for.
Rym: Thus, why I said I'm betting against it for me.
Rym: I'm betting against it for the hardcore gamers.
Scott: If I get the 3DS Lite, I'm putting it on the same, you know, truck that I put my Pokemon on.
Scott: I'm not going to get Pokemon Black and White.
Scott: If they come out with Pokemon Gray, then I'll get it.
Scott: Now, think about what this means.
Scott: I'm not going to get- I'm not going to get a 3DS.
Scott: I'm going to wait for 3DS Lite.
Rym: Scott, NES, SNES, N64, GameCube, all the Game Boys for decades are, like, when we saw Nintendo, we thought, I'm buying whatever they make.
Scott: Go listen to old GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Nintendo, Nintendo, Nintendo.
Scott: PC gaming is dead.
Scott: Nintendo, Nintendo.
Rym: And I think it's a big sea change for me personally that in the new round of Nintendo, I don't trust them anymore.
Scott: Listen to new GeekNights, Xbox, Steam, Steam, Steam, Steam, Xbox.
Rym: Well, what it is is that Nintendo is no longer the "I'll buy it without looking at
Rym: it.".
Rym: Now, I'm not saying it's bad.
Rym: I'm saying that it has gone down to the level of everything else in my life.
Rym: I will look at it before I buy it.
Rym: I will hand the money after I've seen what they have to offer.
Scott: Yeah, I pre-ordered and purchased on release a Game Boy Color, a GBA, regular, and a DS Fat, and I'm not going to do that for a 3DS.
Rym: Yeah, big sea change.
Rym: I'm telling you.
Rym: So, we played this game at PAX, and it's kind of like brain jungle speed, because as you know, jungle speed kind of made the rounds in the front row crew, and now we've kind of created monsters.
Rym: Scott and I like the game, but I think everyone else in the crew likes it way more than we do.
Scott: But it is a good game.
Scott: It's like a good warm-up game.
Scott: It's not the game that you seek out.
Scott: It's just the warm-up.
Rym: Yeah, like you play that to get the blood pumping, and then Tiggers and Euphrates.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So, there was this dumb kid-looking game that for some reason, a bunch of people in our crew noticed it at PAX.
Rym: I think it was Pete or Nuri.
Rym: It's called Spot It.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: And all it is is little circular cards that have shapes on them, like snowflake, or dinosaur, or green shit.
Scott: Well, they're not just shapes.
Scott: They're like actual pictures.
Rym: Hand with an eyeball, lock, bomb, all this stuff.
Rym: And they're all different sizes, but the shapes and colors are the same.
Rym: And every card matches every other card in at least one way.
Scott: Yeah, so each card has a whole bunch of different pictures on it.
Scott: So, you got one card might have a really small snowman, and another card might have a really big snowman.
Scott: They're the same snowman, but they also have a whole bunch of other symbols, so it's like how you can even notice that snowman is there.
Rym: Now, the thing is, the game is actually a whole bunch of different games.
Rym: The baby mode, as we like to call it, there's a pile in the middle, everyone's got their card, and everyone looks.
Rym: And if you see the match between the card in the middle and your card, you say what the match is and grab it.
Scott: Yeah, because every card matches every other card, so it's not like a luck factor.
Scott: Everyone's got some kind of match.
Rym: Now what's great, you'll think, alright, we're all adults, this baby game, really, Rym and Scott, this baby game is the game you guys are going to talk about.
Rym: This game made me feel real fucking stupid sometimes.
Scott: Yeah, you'd be like eyeball, eyeball, eyeball, eyeball.
Rym: There'd be like four of us, four smart dudes, all of us 20 to 30 years old dudes and dudettes, sitting around looking at this thing.
Rym: We all know there is a match for every one of us, and yet none of us can match.
Rym: For like 30 seconds.
Scott: Well, because some cards, it's just all about coincidence, right?
Scott: You'll grab a card, and then the next card will have that same symbol again.
Rym: Oh, there you go, lightning bolt, lightning bolt, lightning bolt.
Scott: Right, but then sometimes your card will have like a whole bunch of blue symbols, and this card, the only match will be a green symbol, but that green symbol is really tiny on both cards.
Scott: It's like you're never going to notice it, and someone else, by the time you figure it out, someone else has got it.
Rym: Yep, but the end result is that it's actually a pretty great game.
Scott: It's definitely a game of complete skill based stuff, right?
Rym: It replaced jungle speed for one type of activity, because when we were in lines, playing games, you couldn't really whip out the jungle speed, because there was a lot more setup going on, we needed more space.
Scott: You need a table with a totem, you gotta be even around the totem.
Rym: There's the danger of hitting other people in line with that totem.
Scott: Yeah, spot it, you can pretty much play on any surface.
Scott: It doesn't have as many physical requirements as jungle speed.
Rym: But it has other modes, and they're actually all pretty great.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is the basic mode is like actually, while it's the baby mode, it's the most simplistic, it's also the highest, the one that's the most skill based, right?
Rym: Well, I would argue- The dick mode.
Rym: Dick mode is also high skill, but among low skilled players, it's also a low skilled game.
Scott: Yeah, the problem with dick mode is that there is skill to it, but there is a greater factor of it's also the vote who wins game.
Rym: Well here's the deal, when to play dick mode, you unzip your pants, and you whip it out, you put it on, and everyone- okay.
Rym: So, the pile is in the middle, and everyone has a card in front of them.
Rym: If you see a match with anyone else's card, you say lightning bolt or whatever and you put it on their pile, lowest pile wins.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like you have to try to match with the person who's not you that has the smallest pile to spread the damage around to make sure everyone else loses.
Rym: Now obviously, among low skilled players, the game is basically who doesn't get noticed.
Rym: The quietest people would win this every time.
Scott: Yeah, regardless of their spotting skill, right?
Scott: So the baby mode is the best at testing your spotting skill, where dick mode tests other skills as well.
Rym: But dick mode, the real thing, what it tests is the ability to not only keep track of that card up there, to keep track of all the other cards in real time, and to keep track of who's winning and who's losing.
Rym: And they have modes like everyone holds a card, then when you find a match between your card and someone else's, you give it to them, and then you keep going until there's one guy left with all the cards and he loses.
Scott: Is that a hot potato mode?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: We have our own vulgar names for every mode.
Scott: The thing is, this deck of cards with all these symbols on it is actually surprisingly versatile at playing a whole bunch of different games, and it's super cheap.
Scott: We paid 12, but on Sunday, they lowered the price to 9.
Rym: It's 10.08 on Amazon with free shipping right now.
Scott: You can't buy a better game for $10 a game.
Rym: Dude, it fits in the pocket of my kilt.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, a bottle of wine fits in there.
Scott: It fits in a jean pocket.
Scott: Tightly.
Rym: I think the highest endorsement I have for this game is that our friend bought it, and we were like, "Whatever," and we played it, and then we liked it.
Rym: I bought it, and everyone else bought it, and as far as I can tell, the dealer sold out of this game.
Scott: There was only one dealer selling it in the expo hall.
Rym: Nobody would have looked at this game twice otherwise, but it spread very quickly through packs.
Scott: Mad props to whoever started the slippery slope on the spot-its.
Rym: We've got a really good loadout now.
Rym: We've got the jungle speed, the banana grams, the spot-it.
Rym: We've got the whip-it-out-at-a-restaurant-games-down.
Scott: Yeah, we need more.
Scott: The thing is, we already have the long, awesome games with lots of wooden cubes down.
Scott: We just can't get people to play those.
Scott: People just want to keep playing the restaurant games over and over and over.
Scott: We've got to get people to migrate from the banana grams to the Le Havre or Le Genoa and such.
Rym: And so, without further ado, it's been a while.
Rym: We've got a long backlog of Things of the Day.
Scott: Oh, snap.
Scott: I don't actually have a Thing of the Day.
Scott: What?
Scott: Really?
Scott: I've got a Thing of the Day.
Rym: We just talked about this for like ever.
Rym: Alright, well, I'll stall for you a little bit.
Rym: By Thing of the Day, I'm going back to CollegeHumor, but not just some dumb video on their side, because they've actually... You know, we're big fans of CollegeHumor.
Rym: They're one of the best video content aggregators on the internet.
Rym: At least of fun video content.
Rym: I mean, I guess TEDx and TED could be arguably the best overall aggregators of actual worthwhile video content.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: Obviously, still stalling for time, as Scott not saying anything.
Rym: He's desperately trying to find a Thing of the Day.
Rym: So, CollegeHumor has done a lot of original shows that have actually been pretty damn good, and I think the best one right now is Troopers.
Rym: It's basically just kind of a Star Wars spoof about the stormtroopers living their normal lives.
Rym: You know, talking to each other, being dicks, guarding the princess, interrogating the princess, getting coffee for Darth Vader.
Rym: And stuff like this on the internet, if it were anywhere else, would usually be pretty lame.
Rym: And a lot of the early CollegeHumor original videos were pretty lame.
Rym: But this is top-notch, like A, production values, and it's like a solid B, comedy.
Rym: Like, I put it on the level of, I don't know, I'd say this is what I would call the baseline level for a modern, low-budget internet sitcom.
Rym: Like, it's the equivalent of what Seinfeld was on TV.
Scott: Alright, I do have a Thing of the Day.
Rym: So, that was enough stalling?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I was going to use this Thing of the Day on Monday, but you know what, it's okay to use on Tuesday, because it's also partially gaming-related.
Scott: And we haven't used it yet.
Scott: And it's one of those things that everyone on the internet has seen, because it exploded everywhere.
Scott: But it's gotta be a Thing of the Day, right?
Rym: The My Little Pony Epic AMV?
Scott: No, we used that already.
Scott: Yeah?
Scott: This is something we haven't used already.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: This guy upgraded from MS-DOS 5.0 all the way to every version of Windows, all the way up to Windows 7, right?
Scott: And it's surprising that actually, you know, from watching this, I have to believe he actually ended up with a better version of Windows at the end.
Scott: Because he actually had some of the Windows 3.1 apps that could possibly be useful, like the recorder.
Scott: Who knows if that would still actually work.
Rym: See, the tricky part is that some PCs, like if you switch to 64-bit or whatever, the upgrade path, the official one from Windows is, "Yeah, wipe all your shit out, start
Rym: over.".
Scott: Yeah, I think he did 32-bit only, which is the problem.
Rym: Which is fine, because otherwise this isn't nearly as cool.
Rym: I mean, yeah, I can upgrade from every version of anything to anything else by wiping out my hard drive between each step.
Scott: It was just sort of amazing how he put in Doom at the beginning, and Doom continued to work on almost every version.
Scott: And then for one version it stopped working, but then after he upgraded again, it started working again.
Rym: I didn't actually watch it.
Rym: Does he go the ME path, or does he just kind of skip that?
Scott: I don't remember if he does ME, but he does 95, 98, and then he either does ME 2000 or just straight to 2000.
Scott: It's a really good video.
Scott: It's totally worth watching, especially for people with the nostalgia of the old DOS days, playing games on the old DOS, this'll be awesome.
Scott: And for people who have never seen old Windows and old DOS, you'll learn a lot from this, of what it was like in those olden days.
Rym: Alright, so the meta moment, which for new listeners, this is where we try to cover all the stuff about GeekNights.
Rym: So if you are a new listener, we got a forum, it's rockin', you should go to it.
Rym: It's actually rockin', people will vouch for that.
Scott: And you should follow us on Twitters.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: If you saw us at the con and you thought we were cool, and Scott didn't want to take his picture with you, it's because he hates people and pictures and puppies.
Scott: I don't know why, the thing is I just don't know why anyone would want to take their picture with me.
Rym: It's always funny when, you know, you can see our two personalities, when a fan is like "Oh my god, I love Geek
Rym: Nights.".
Rym: I'll be like "Well, I'm glad you do, this is super
Rym: awesome.".
Rym: And I'm thinking "I'm so fuckin' awesome, aw
Rym: yeah.".
Rym: And Scott's like "Why the hell do you listen to GeekNights?
Rym: It
Rym: sucks.".
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: Do you have anything better to do?
Rym: I don't know, if I have any, if Scott has a pony name, it is henceforth Complainy Main.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Rym: After this weekend at Zenkai Con.
Rym: "Oh, there's no bagels in the morning and I can't get
Rym: breakfast.".
Scott: Did you not agree with that complaint?
Rym: I got a Philly cheesesteak for breakfast, so I was fine.
Scott: That is not breakfast.
Scott: Anyway, just, you know, some events coming up in the near future.
Scott: There's a Nerd NYC board game night, April 1st.
Rym: April 1st, I'll be bringing Candyland.
Scott: There's gonna be the MOCA Festival, the Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art Festival is on April 9th and 10th.
Scott: We're probably gonna go on the 9th all day.
Rym: We'll be there, so if you want to say hi, say hi.
Rym: We're not doing any panels or anything.
Scott: There's a convention in Long Island that we never go to and probably never will go to called ICON on the weekend following, the 15th, 16th, and 17th.
Rym: Much more important, April 22nd through 24th in Boston at the Heinz Convention Center.
Rym: We will be at, as we always are, except possibly next year, Anime Boston.
Scott: A real convention.
Scott: A big one.
Rym: And I'm looking forward to it primarily.
Rym: I love Anime Boston.
Rym: It's kind of replaced Otakon in many ways for me as an attendee and a fan.
Rym: But it's in the Heinz, which is a fairly crappy convention center that actually- No, actually I like the Heinz.
Scott: It's good, it just doesn't have the size necessary.
Rym: It's crappy if you want to be a big convention.
Scott: Well, I mean, you could be big in there.
Scott: You just can't be ultra big.
Rym: There's food over there.
Scott: Oh, there's the best food.
Rym: Oh my god, there's food over there.
Scott: King P.
Rym: Ah, the Trident, the secret place that I'm no longer ever gonna mention on the show.
Scott: 'Cause we ate there once and it was the best breakfast and we tried to eat there the next day and it was too full because everyone found out about it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So now we're not gonna tell anyone that it exists so we can go eat the awesome breakfast every day.
Rym: Oh my god, that vanilla french toast.
Scott: I can't even get over that.
Rym: God.
Rym: Yep, so we will be at Anime Boston doing a whole bunch of panels along with our friends Anime World Order and Mike Tool.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And the weekend following Anime Boston, we're probably not gonna go to it 'cause I really don't want to go back to Pennsylvania on such short notice.
Scott: But the Comic Geek Speak podcast is a podcast I listen to.
Scott: They got their own convention that they've been doing for a couple years now and it's gonna be on that weekend.
Rym: When are we gonna do the GeekNights convention?
Scott: April 30th and May 1st in Reading, Pennsylvania.
Scott: Huh?
Scott: The Comic Geek Speak Super Show.
Scott: You can not like that name.
Scott: That's a good name.
Rym: And of course if you saw any of our panels at Zank icon or PAX, look at the news on the site because we link to most of the slides.
Rym: So if you want to see like the list of board games we talked about.
Scott: Yeah, go to FrontRowCrew.com and then look in the bottom left and there'll be latest news or in the navigation bar.
Scott: just click news and you'll see it'll be like a blog.
Scott: suddenly that has news.
Rym: So two last pieces.
Rym: then we'll get on to our PAX highlights.
Rym: One, if you saw us at a convention or you would like us to go to a convention, tell the convention and tell them to ask for us because we are kind of, our cup already overflowed.
Rym: We're not really looking for new conventions to go to.
Rym: A convention has to come to us at this point.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Otherwise we won't know it exists.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And if it's in the New York area and there's not a bigger con at the same weekend, there's a chance it will come.
Scott: Yeah, there's sort of this equation, right?
Scott: Size of con versus hassle to get to the con.
Scott: So if the, you know, and so it's like, if it's far away, then it's a hassle, but if it's really big, it might be worth it.
Rym: Or if it's really awesome, like magfest.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But it also depends on the transportation, right?
Scott: So like, for example, we didn't go to generic con even though it was very close.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Because it was a pain in the ass to get to it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We didn't do panels really ever at Anime Next.
Rym: And it was small.
Rym: No one ever responds to our emails and eventually we gave up.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So anyway.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That and also the second point, we are, as many of you know, the directors of programming for panels and workshops at ConnectiCon every year.
Scott: And... Since last year?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Since last year.
Rym: And ConnectiCon is kind of an everything con, but unlike cons that call themselves everything cons, it really is a goddamn everything con.
Scott: It's an everything nerdy con.
Rym: It's like a steampunk anime gaming webcomic art con.
Scott: Regular comic, anime, board game, miniatures, video game, nerdy con, crafting, knitting.
Rym: We wanted to open panel submissions in October, but due to internal things over which we have no control in the convention, everyone else, not everyone else.
Rym: We haven't even yet opened registration for panels, despite the fact that the convention is in July.
Scott: And the convention is already, like, the period of which you could get your $40 badge has already passed.
Scott: Now the badge prices have already gone up.
Rym: But if you live anywhere near Hartford, Connecticut and you want to go to a 7,000 person con or a 21,000 person con if you count it the BS way PAX counts, then just wait for it.
Rym: We'll announce when we open submissions and if you're a listener who does cool stuff, we're in charge of panels.
Scott: And Kinetic Con may be small compared to PAX and other things, but the tabletop gaming there is worth the price of admission alone, not counting the awesome panels we're gonna have.
Rym: Tabletop at Kinetic Con is better than any gaming con I've ever been to except to PAX.
Scott: I think the thing is, like the tabletop room, the PAX now has bigger tabletop and perhaps more and better players, but the library at Kinetic Con is unmatched.
Rym: Oh my god, that library.
Scott: The PAX tabletop gaming library is not as good, not even half as good, as the Kinetic Con tabletop gaming library.
Rym: Alright, so, PAX.
Rym: We usually do these kind of very long-winded convention reviews, but I think we've been to enough PAXes to where we don't need to tell you that there's an expo hall.
Scott: Yeah, let's just stick to the things that were different about PAX East 2011 versus previous PAXes.
Rym: So, if you care about, like, the details of what it's like at PAX on a general level, like, oh, the concerts and the panels and the art, well, there is no artist alley yet, but the, like, all that stuff.
Rym: We've got, I don't know, like three or four other PAX episodes I'll link to.
Scott: Yeah, just go listen to those.
Rym: This year was exactly the same, except for the following.
Scott: And if you're one of those people who hates the convention shows, stop listening, because you know what, a lot of people tell us they do like the convention shows and it's pretty much equal and we don't have another idea for today.
Rym: However, I would say don't stop listening because we're not going to do the kind of review you seem to hate and you might want to hear some of this stuff.
Scott: Or your opinion might be reinforced.
Rym: Alright, so in no particular order, it was in the BCEC in the middle of fuck nowhere.
Scott: Yeah, we've never been to the BCEC before, new building for us.
Scott: It was a gigantic, basically I think Mike Tool had it right.
Scott: He said it's an airplane hangar that happens to be empty.
Rym: Now, it's relatively new, and that counts for more than you would think.
Rym: The BCC in Baltimore is, so far to this day, the best extremely large convention venue I have ever laid eyes upon.
Scott: Architecturally.
Scott: Yeah, forget the city, forget the cons, anything else.
Rym: The actual building, the layout of the convention center, the variety of spaces, the size of the spaces, the BCC.
Rym: The layout of the spaces.
Scott: The only flaw of the BCC is the road and bridge in the middle.
Scott: No other flaw does it have.
Rym: Like it is perfect, and it is actually way bigger than the BCEC in Boston.
Rym: And I'll just harken back to when they first announced there was going to be a Pax East.
Rym: When they said Boston, I said what?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But Boston's working out okay.
Scott: Except for the fact the problem with the BCC is, as he predicted, there's not much near it.
Scott: You gotta walk a distance to get to anything.
Rym: And even then, you'll walk a distance.
Scott: There's not much variety, and the stuff that's close is packed, because especially if you want to eat dinner at a reasonable hour, all the Pax people are already in there three hour wait to eat at this really good place.
Rym: So I think our mistake on every day other than Friday was that we tried to go to a nice restaurant.
Rym: You know what we should have done?
Rym: Ordered pizza every day.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Because that actually worked.
Scott: It did work.
Scott: The go to the Mexican place worked, but I wasn't going to eat there more than once.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But seriously, this venue, while smaller than the BCC, basically consists of three airplane hangers.
Rym: Like gigantic rooms.
Scott: Well, it's actually one.
Scott: They just had two dividers.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And only one of them was actually really, well I guess two of them were used.
Scott: Yeah, it was divided into four sections actually.
Rym: Yeah, I forgot.
Scott: Daddy four.
Scott: It was an airplane hanger divided into four pretty much sort of equal-ish sections.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The first section was expo hall, then tabletop, then the queue room, which they only use that queue room for the expo hall.
Scott: They actually put the main events queue up in the main events area, which is different.
Scott: And they only ever actually used half of that queue room at most.
Scott: And then there was a cafeteria area, which was secret.
Scott: tabletop number two.
Rym: Yeah, it was great.
Scott: It was tabletop number one was so crowded.
Rym: So it was pretty great on Friday night.
Rym: It was basically us and a whole bunch of bronies and listeners and crew hanging out.
Rym: So there's like 30, 40 of us in this room just kind of spread out.
Rym: The room is the size of a football field and we're the only ones in it except for the sleeping security guy.
Rym: There's this one PCEC security dude asleep on the far end, like passed out in a chair near the gigantic garage door that you could drive like a, you know, gigantic truck.
Rym: I really wanted to have all of us quietly walk over and just stand around him and wait for him to wake up.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think that would have been great.
Scott: That would have meant losing Paxman.
Rym: It might have been getting tased.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I don't think he had a taser.
Rym: But yeah, they actually didn't notice we were there because the con ended it too.
Rym: And we were still there and no one came to check on us.
Rym: And we didn't really run into many people on our way out.
Scott: But yeah, basically there are a bunch of smaller rooms on two different levels on the sort of, you know, the hallways on either side of the airplane.
Rym: Panel rooms are gigantic.
Rym: Now Pax has no problem with panel room size anymore.
Scott: Yeah, they don't fill up.
Scott: You don't really have to wait that long unless you want to sit close.
Scott: Or unless it's famous person panel, which was not our panel.
Scott: You know, we had one, our one panel had half attendance.
Scott: The other ones on Sunday filled up mostly, but not a hundred percent.
Scott: So you could have, you didn't have to wait in line.
Rym: Yeah, the room seated like twelve hundred or nine.
Rym: I forget.
Rym: I think it was twelve hundred in the big room and I, it might have been a thousand.
Rym: And we were like 90 percent full.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Friday's tough though, it was a constant concert.
Rym: But I mean, everything else about the venue is great, but I can't understate the value of having a new convention center.
Rym: Because while the layout kind of is like the Javits and that it's big and open and echoey, the sound and the loudness weren't nearly as bad as I expected just due to modern engineering.
Scott: My only, my only real problem was the surrounding area, which we knew about, and the fact that because it was a big airplane hangar, walking to anywhere took forever.
Rym: Oh my god, we were playing this game of Paranoia in the cafeteria area, and I was like, I'll be right back.
Rym: I'm gonna go get a drink from that drinking fountain that we could all see.
Rym: It took me more than ten minutes to walk to that drinking fountain, get a drink, and walk back.
Scott: Yeah, it's a long way.
Rym: I could see the Paranoia game that was on hold the entire time.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty impressively large.
Rym: Also, TableTop, there were so many thousands of people, like it was crazy to see that many people playing TableTop games.
Scott: They should have expanded the TableTop to take up half of the Q room and made the Q room half the size, and then they could have eliminated the cafeteria area entirely.
Rym: But anyway, there's really no trouble with the venue, other than the obvious stuff of it's in the middle of nowhere, and PAX ain't moving.
Rym: I have it on good authority.
Rym: now, the maximum capacity of the BCEC, as it stands, is 24,000 people, which is actually pretty small.
Scott: The true capacity has to be bigger than that.
Scott: That sounds like a stingy Fire Marshal.
Scott: But I've met the Fire Marshal of Boston, and he's an awesome dude, so I don't know why he'd do that.
Rym: So I looked into this a little bit.
Rym: I did some investigative journalism.
Rym: The BCEC and the city of Boston will not tell me what the maximum capacity is.
Rym: They outright refuse to tell me.
Rym: And when I said I have it on good authority from several other sources that your capacity is 24,000, they didn't respond.
Rym: They just stopped answering my emails.
Rym: And I even threatened them.
Rym: I was like, "Look, I'm going to go to press with the number of 24,000 and assume that is correct unless you tell me
Rym: otherwise.".
Rym: No responses.
Rym: I also learned, and I have this on pretty good authority, PAX is by far the biggest event that has ever been hosted in that center.
Scott: That's probably correct.
Scott: And I'm pretty sure they're building another hotel near the center.
Scott: There are plans.
Scott: They're trying to get 200 million dollars in state funds to build another hotel attached to that center.
Scott: To move Boston up the hierarchy of best convention cities.
Rym: Yes, if they built an extension like the BCC did in Baltimore, they could usurp the BCC completely.
Rym: They could kill Baltimore.
Rym: I keep almost saying Boston and Baltimore in the wrong spaces.
Rym: But yeah, it worked out pretty well.
Rym: keynote.
Rym: The keynote was fantastic.
Scott: I like how she didn't spend 100 years talking about her gaming history and instead actually talked about a topic.
Rym: Yeah, it was a great topic.
Rym: We played a bunch of games with her and the audience that were pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, and she taught us a lot of interesting things about chicken knee bowling or whatever you call it.
Rym: I kind of want to play barkball.
Scott: I don't want to play barkball.
Rym: You don't want to play barkball?
Scott: No.
Rym: It was a heartfelt, meaningful, awesome keynote.
Scott: Educational.
Scott: Much better than Wil Wheaton.
Scott: It was just pandering the whole time.
Rym: Yes, but at the same time...
Scott: But the thing is, I have a feeling that many people will not share that opinion with us.
Rym: Well, my opinion is complex.
Rym: When I say that Wil Wheaton did the worst keynote PAX has ever had, that's like saying that this 23 karat bar of gold is the worst bar of gold I've ever had.
Rym: I mean, it was a great keynote when...
Scott: It was okay.
Rym: Well, it was a rah rah rah.
Rym: It was a look at what gaming does to us.
Rym: We are who we are because of gaming and gaming is what it is because of us.
Rym: And the message was good, just the whole middle was basically the woo game.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Which, sometimes you need that.
Rym: Sometimes you need the rah rah rah.
Rym: I feel like PAX can alternate between serious business.
Rym: let's go and rah rah rah, we're so fucking awesome, look at us.
Scott: Well, whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I prefer the educational TED talk to a rah rah rah.
Rym: I like them both pretty much equally.
Rym: I can watch an entertaining thing and enjoy it independently of an educational thing.
Rym: Though, the things that do both are rated higher on my absolute scale of awesome.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: The Q&A, the famous Penny Arcade Q&A, East Coast, you kind of let me down.
Rym: There was no knuckle crack.
Scott: No knuckle crack.
Scott: I was like, what?
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: And all these people were tweeting like, I should ask about my little pony, blah blah blah.
Rym: Nobody fucking stepped up.
Rym: I went up there to ask about something else, but I had to do the ponies because clearly no one else was gonna.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think you had anything else.
Scott: I didn't have anything.
Rym: I did, but someone stole it.
Scott: Oh, right.
Rym: Yeah, so two years ago, well, I guess, yeah, at the first PAX East, you know, at the end of the show, Tycho was like, this is truly the real PAX.
Scott: And then at PAX West, you called him out.
Rym: Yep, I was like, so.
Scott: And then that's when he called PAX East the bitch PAX.
Rym: You, uh, there were, you know, we were very, emotions were running high at the end of PAX East last year.
Rym: And I believe someone, it might have been you, said that it was the real PAX.
Rym: And of course, boos.
Scott: Boos.
Scott: And then of course, right?
Scott: So some guy who wasn't us comes up on this Q&A and is like, so this is bitch PAX, huh?
Rym: And his reaction was priceless.
Rym: He's like, oh my God, look.
Scott: He's like, he knew that it was going to create a cycle and he did not want it to continue.
Scott: But apparently PAX West, PAX Prime is a den of thieves.
Rym: I like this trend.
Rym: I think what's going to happen now.
Scott: So a den of thieves, are we?
Rym: Every year he is going to denigrate the other one rather than propping up the one he's at because that is more entertaining.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: So speaking of fail.
Scott: The joke will get old.
Rym: There's one more very important fail.
Rym: East Coast, seriously, you're letting me down.
Rym: We talk up the East Coast to our West Coast posse and you guys totally don't stand and deliver.
Rym: At PAX East last year, Bohemian Rhapsody played and the line was moving into the Omegathon finale.
Rym: The line kept singing the song.
Scott: There is video evidence of this.
Rym: Long after no one could hear the original music.
Scott: Video evidence.
Scott: We made it through the instrumentals.
Scott: PAX West has never achieved such a feat.
Rym: Can you imagine an entire crowd singing Bohemian Rhapsody, including the instrumentals.
Scott: Thousands and thousands of people.
Rym: Just unending.
Rym: And then when it ended, people tried to start it again.
Rym: So we're in line for the Omegathon finale.
Rym: We play Bohemian Rhapsody.
Rym: Everyone can hear us.
Rym: We have like 10 people singing it as loud as we can.
Rym: I've got Fall Out Boy dancing.
Rym: No motherfucking person even considered joining in.
Rym: We sang the entire song to no avail.
Rym: It ended.
Scott: Only the security guard helped us out.
Rym: Okay, that security guard wins the prize for most epic burn.
Scott: It's actually security excellent at the BCEC.
Rym: Yup, in the tradition of Boston having really good security and Seattle having really good security.
Scott: What's up?
Scott: Well, Heinz had annoying security at points.
Rym: Wasn't that bad.
Rym: It was no Baltimore.
Scott: It was definitely no Baltimore.
Scott: And it was no Connecticut.
Scott: Yeah, Koo apparently knows how to hire good security firms.
Scott: He knows what to look for.
Scott: If I ever need to hire security guards, I'll ask him for advice.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: If I ever need anything, I would ask him for advice.
Scott: How do I brush my teeth, Robert Koo?
Rym: He's like an oracle for these dark days.
Rym: So this guard, right, we're singing Bohemian Rhapsody.
Rym: And he walks up with this look of, "Oh Jesus, you
Rym: kids.".
Rym: And then he starts conducting like, "Yeah, yeah, I'm with
Rym: you.".
Rym: And then he raises his hands and says, "Now just the
Rym: girls.".
Rym: And it gets quiet for a second.
Scott: Yeah, there are definitely, there are a lot.
Scott: It's like the absolute number of ladies at PAX is a high number, but the percentage is a low number.
Rym: Yep, at PAX Prime last year, Emily noted that there was a line for the men's bathroom, but not the ladies' bathroom.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: But that security guy gets the, I guess, the win of the con from me.
Scott: Zing.
Rym: There's one other guy who gets the win of the con.
Rym: So we did our panels, right?
Rym: And we got to our second panel pretty early.
Rym: So we let the audience in because there was this huge line, and we entertain them for a while.
Rym: We show some ponies, we talk, we did a shtick.
Rym: And while we're up there, we're like, "Yeah, man, we should, at other cons, why don't we just play the Blues Brothers music?
Rym: We're not on
Rym: stage.".
Rym: And we play that Blues Brothers theme, and then we run in from the back.
Rym: Oh, that tech guy.
Rym: And we high-five everyone like,
Rym: "Yeah!".
Rym: And so we say this, and we're like, "Huh,".
Rym: and the audience thinks that's funny.
Rym: And then we keep setting up, and then suddenly this music starts playing.
Rym: And I look up, and the tech guy gives us the thumbs up, and it's the Blues Brothers theme.
Scott: Yeah, the tech guy in the Wyvern Theater was the fucking man.
Rym: So we ran out of the audience, they were yelling and screaming and high-fives.
Scott: Yeah, the liveliers and everything.
Rym: That was epic.
Scott: Pax, you got to give the same level of technology to the far superior Naga Theater.
Scott: We didn't have any wireless in there.
Scott: Got to help out my bro, Chromatic Theory.
Rym: Because, Scott, I know you like some Hot Lamia action.
Rym: Naga's very similar.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Very close.
Rym: Of course, there's no Unicorn Theater, which is sad, but...
Scott: Unicorn Theater's at Prime.
Scott: Rainbow, how are you going to hit it up with some Twilight Sparkle next year?
Rym: I'm warming to rarity, actually.
Rym: Quite a bit.
Scott: Yeah, warming, but still, not as warm as anyone else.
Rym: But Wyvern Theater, dude, you've fucked things up for us now, because you realize I will have trouble getting my panel hard-on going unless someone plays the Blues Brothers theme and lets me run in and high-five the audience.
Rym: I guess we should talk about the Omegathon, because there was a big turnabout, unexpected.
Scott: Yes, our predictions for the Omegathon were along the lines of Rock 'Em Sock 'Em Robots and things of that nature.
Scott: Crossfire.
Rym: We were so sure, because one...
Scott: Well, here's the thing, right?
Scott: Last year, Pax East, the Omegathon was different because it was co-op.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: I looked at the list of Omegathon games for East of 2011, and none of them were co-op games.
Scott: Bananagrams, Jenga... I thought that they had abandoned the co-op nature of the East Omegathon.
Rym: Now, coupled with that, it was all tabletop stylin' for the most part.
Scott: There was one video game, I think.
Rym: So we were like, "Alright, what is a crazy, epic, two-player tabletop-ish
Rym: game?".
Rym: And Table Tennis doesn't work, obviously, because if one guy's good, it's just not gonna be fun.
Scott: Yes, we had all assumed that all games of skill were right out, because they make for boring finales if one person has any skill at all, and they make for double boring finales if everyone sucks.
Rym: Not just that, it can't be games that have a high barrier to entry, because Table Tennis, if they both suck, it's just gonna be out, out, with, out, with, for an hour.
Rym: So, we thought long and hard, and Rock 'Em Sock 'Em Robots, my prediction was Crossfire, knowing that, being epic, they could play the Crossfire music during every round.
Scott: Crossfire!
Scott: A great follow-up to Final Countdown.
Rym: My, uh, my secondary guess was Air Hockey.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: 'Cause tabletop, low barrier to entry, high skill cap, but not unreasonable, and nobody's good at Air Hockey.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway.
Rym: So, we, you know, we talked to, we go to the PAX staff, 'cause we're like, "Look, don't tell us, you probably don't even
Rym: know.".
Scott: But we wanna tell you our guesses, so that if we're correct, then it will be, you know, like, we're the man.
Rym: So I won't name names, 'cause I don't wanna reveal any secrets of who knows what and when, but there is a cool dude involved in PAX, whose game is to not know, for as long as possible, what it actually is.
Rym: So, we give this person our predictions, and he's like, "Well, I don't know, so I can't betray
Rym: anything.".
Rym: And this guy behind him, who I'm also not gonna name, starts laughing.
Rym: Hysterically.
Rym: So he leans over, and he tells him, he tells the guy who doesn't know what the games are.
Rym: He's not bothered to know.
Rym: And they look at us, and they just laugh.
Rym: So I was like, "Oh man, we're totally
Rym: right.".
Rym: We were so wrong, it was pitiful.
Scott: Right, so, against all of our, first of all, I did not realize that PAX East still is, and will probably be next year, a co-op omega-thon.
Rym: I like this.
Scott: I like this a lot.
Scott: Two, so I wasn't even thinking of co-op games.
Scott: Two, they chose a game of high skill.
Rym: Ika fuckin' Ruga?
Scott: And it was weird, because, like, I'm standing next to Dragon Master Lu, right?
Scott: They're like a Dreamcast game of reversing polarity, and I'm like, "They wouldn't pick Ika Ruga, that's a game of
Scott: skill.".
Scott: And Lu is like, "It's Ika
Scott: Ruga.".
Scott: And I'm like, "Yes, every clue they just said implies they might as well have just said Ika Ruga
Scott: already.".
Rym: It's like reading Arcane Runes, all of the words I've said make sense, but the message does not.
Scott: Even though they said it was Ika Ruga, and I'm like, "They just described Ika Ruga, that's what it's gonna
Scott: be.".
Scott: And remember, this is a matter of seconds we're talking about, so I'm thinking faster than they're talking.
Scott: I'm like, "They just said it was Ika Ruga, effectively, but there's no way it would be, because that is a game of high
Scott: skill.".
Rym: Before the word polarity, I was like, "Chu-Chu Rockets," because he was like-- Yeah, and he said Dreamcast, I was like, "Chu-Chu Rockets,".
Scott: but then he was like polarity, and I'm like, "Ika
Scott: Ruga.".
Rym: He was like complicated and visually stimulating, and I'm like, "Yeah, Chu-Chu
Rym: Rockets.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then Ika Ruga comes on, and I'm like, "Holy fuck, are you shitting
Scott: me?".
Rym: So here's what got me.
Rym: Both teams were surprisingly competent.
Scott: Well, one team was less competent than the other team by a significant amount.
Rym: Well, the left team won by an order of magnitude, as would have been obvious from the start, but it was still pretty goddamn epic to watch.
Scott: Yeah, because one of the guys on the right team actually managed--he had skill and held out to the end, but both players on the left team had skill.
Scott: Though I think if it was an individual competition, the good guy on the right team would have won.
Rym: The score he had, just him, was pretty fucking impressive.
Scott: Yeah, I was very surprised at the amount of skill laid down in a game that is not only a game of high skill, but also a game where memory is more important.
Rym: Also, I watched some clips of the operation round of the Omega-Thon.
Rym: I kind of wish I'd been there to see that.
Scott: Also, the Jenga round was a game of giant Jenga, not normal-sized Jenga.
Rym: I wish I'd been there to see that.
Rym: Had I known that, I would have gotten a line for the concert to see that live.
Scott: I definitely like the move they make where they put the Omega-Thon rounds at the beginnings of the concerts on Friday and Saturday.
Scott: Because when they make it just like Omega-Thon round in a panel room, people don't go and it's not as exciting.
Rym: But having it be that big event, it makes every round of the Omega-Thon feel just like the end of the wizard.
Scott: Yeah, it's a good move.
Rym: So, if we could change things about PAX, and there's always, you know, any con we go to, there's things we could change.
Rym: Luckily, for PAX, it's not like other cons we go to, I won't name any, where our changes are like "mail the badges" or "don't fuck up" or, I don't know, "check the badges at the door", "have panel rooms".
Rym: But we do have suggestions for PAX, and I think PAX East is in a position to experiment in a way that West will never be able to just because of this venue.
Rym: This venue was "full", they could easily fit 10-15,000 more people in that place.
Scott: But they couldn't enforce that many more people.
Scott: They need enforcers like "water needs hydrogen".
Rym: So, rather than say "well, let's just make it bigger and have tabletop twice as big", I think we could do something very simple.
Rym: One, they had an overflow room for the concerts and all the main events, including the keynote.
Rym: That was brilliant.
Rym: That room seats like 700 people.
Scott: Yep, totally worked.
Rym: But it was never even full, even though all the concerts were full, like no one got in.
Rym: People lined up, they shut the doors, no one else got in.
Scott: Well, I guess people just didn't want to watch the concert in a dark room on a big victim's screen.
Rym: You know what I think that is?
Rym: Look at all of our panels.
Rym: What question did we ask to every panel before we started?
Rym: How many of you were at your first PAX ever?
Rym: It was more than three quarters of the room at every panel.
Scott: That was true.
Rym: I think the majority of the people at this PAX had never been to a PAX before.
Rym: And many of them had never been to a convention before.
Rym: So that definitely skewed things.
Scott: Not possibly, probably.
Rym: Because remember, when we went to our first PAX, those concerts were some of the greatest things I'd ever seen.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like, I just couldn't shut up about those concerts.
Scott: In the immortal words of Big Mac,
Scott: "Yup.".
Rym: So, what I would do, because that overflow room is never going to fill, get rid of all the chairs in the back and put like three rows of tables and chairs so people can play games in there while they're watching.
Scott: That would be awesome.
Rym: Because there were a lot of people who thought they would play games in there and then they really just couldn't so they gave up.
Scott: Yeah, I do know some people who played games on the floor in there.
Scott: Yeah, but I think- But how awesome would it be to sit in tabletop and be able to watch the concerts?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And the main events.
Rym: I mean, you know, the Omega-thon.
Rym: I would have watched that Jenga in the overflow room.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Rym: Two, this is something we've suggested to every PAX.
Rym: PAX East now is the first time they've ever actually been in a position to do it.
Rym: PAX needs an art show.
Rym: Pretty much identical to Otakon's except all the auctions go to Child's Play.
Scott: Well, it doesn't need to be, you know, art show is good, but they definitely need an artist alley.
Scott: But it doesn't just have to be artist alley.
Rym: Well, I said art show because I think artist alley is kind of a separate thing.
Rym: They could do the art show independently of the BYOA.
Scott: Yeah, plus the art show shouldn't just be like art hanging on a wall.
Scott: It should just be a stuff show, right?
Scott: Any craft whatsoever.
Rym: The social currency something.
Scott: Sell something you made for Child's Play show.
Scott: The thing is they already have a separate event.
Scott: The Child's Play charity dinner and auction, you know, which they do every year.
Scott: So I don't know if they're thinking that it would be redundant with that.
Rym: Ah, but see, the thing is at PAX.
Rym: it'd be a different vibe.
Rym: If you do it, like imagine if they did it art show style, like the way Otakon does their art show.
Scott: And they do the bidding- Non-silent auction with non-silent auction at the end.
Rym: Yep, and also just the fact that people who want to show off their stuff would put things in.
Rym: They don't care about, well they care about the charity, but really they just want to show off their art.
Rym: And PAX is about a webcomic.
Rym: A webcomic is art.
Rym: A lot of people who go to PAX are way into Gabe's art.
Rym: I think there's a huge artist overlap between video games and penny arcade fans.
Rym: that would make an art show at PAX bloody fucking brilliantly amazing.
Scott: I mean the thing is, it's the penny arcade expo and there's a whole lot of gaming and not a whole lot of comics.
Scott: But penny arcade is a comic before it's a game.
Scott: And I think there just needs to be a lot more comic stuff.
Scott: And the people who go to PAX are looking, you know, these kinds of people are looking for more opportunities to show off their stuff, show what they can do.
Scott: And not just, you know, it's like.
Scott: the only people who get any play at PAX are the indie developers, basically us on up.
Scott: And the people who are us and below, they want a little table to show off.
Scott: They want a little, you know, to be able to put up their art somewhere.
Scott: And not just in a cosplay, you know, sort of form.
Scott: You know, maybe they make something else.
Scott: They want some sort of, you know, room or space at PAX to express themselves.
Scott: And PAX definitely has plenty of room, at least at least, they can do it.
Rym: Now the other thing is, look at how much crowding there was in tabletop, in the expo hall, in all these other places.
Rym: And yet there's all this empty space.
Rym: If they just had an art, like take the Q room, cut it in half.
Rym: They don't need more than half.
Rym: Turn the other half of that room into the show, the art show, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, cut the cafeteria in half, and then expand tabletop by that half, and then you're good.
Rym: And then make the other half of the cafeteria.
Scott: But also maybe the expo hall will get bigger too, you don't know.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: Well, or what they could do is, alright, so the Q room is half Q room, and then in the other half, that is half art show, half the BYOA hall.
Rym: Which is the, basically, like an artist alley, but it's the, you know, sub indie game developers and artists and people who just want to show stuff off or do weird stuff.
Rym: Like get a table, do whatever the hell you want, and maybe even no selling.
Scott: Yeah, bring your own awesome.
Scott: Any awesome...
Rym: I kind of think no selling.
Rym: It's just showing off.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you want to sell something that you're going to profit, you should probably buy an expo hall table.
Rym: Ah, so I think the other thing they could do...
Scott: And the thing is, they have an indie alley in the expo hall, and I'm pretty sure, 99% sure, that those indie alley tables are less expensive than the other tables.
Scott: Because that guy who made that little target shooting game had an expo hall table in indie alley.
Rym: So, I've already allocated basically all of what was the Q room into all this stuff.
Rym: If we turn the other room, the final room, into half like extra tabletop, the other half could be a dealer vending area separate, because the expo hall is mostly show off and demo.
Scott: So you want to take the, there are, you know, the expo hall does have vendors and also big showy booths.
Rym: I would separate vendors.
Scott: You want to separate the vendors into a vendor area that is separate from the showy booth area.
Rym: I don't know if it'd be a good idea, but I think it would really make people walk to the other side of the convention center and spread the crowd out a lot more.
Scott: Yeah, I don't really, you know, I don't know.
Rym: I don't know either.
Rym: That's one of my like, huh, I wonder if that would work ideas.
Scott: There's a lot of issues with hours and things like that.
Rym: Also enforcers.
Rym: But regardless of how they do it, and I think they should do it with the art show, the BYOA hall, which is basically the artist alley, but awesome.
Rym: And maybe the BYOA stage, the BYOP, bring your own panel.
Scott: Some other things I think they need to do is like the arcade was much better this year and it's still just the guys at Fun Spot.
Rym: Scott, turn half of one of those big rooms into just a gigantic fucking arcade.
Scott: I know, right?
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: Because it's still just Fun Spot bringing their stuff and, you know, their machines are quality, they work.
Rym: Pax, Magfest has a bigger arcade than you.
Scott: Yeah, they set up the room all fancy-like, you know, with the cool music and the atmosphere, but it's still a tiny room.
Scott: You need to make a big ass arcade with all generations of games.
Scott: Not just, you know, the centipede Atari generation.
Scott: You gotta bring in the Street Fighter machines of, you know, two through four.
Scott: You gotta bring in the racing machines.
Scott: You gotta bring in the rampart and the pinballs and the everything, you know.
Scott: We need an arcade with the DDR and, you know, the Tycho Drum Master and Initial D and everything.
Rym: But I think the end, if you take all this stuff, our main suggestion to Pax is that they've got, of their exhibit hall space, not counting panel rooms, they only actually used about half of it.
Scott: Yeah, they had all this space, they did not use it.
Scott: And I'm saying instead, you know, they could use the space more efficiently, which would mean get less space and just, you know.
Rym: Fuck that.
Scott: But I'm saying you got all this space, you gotta get more stuff to cram it and, you know, fill it in.
Scott: You know, if you got a pitcher that's half full, you could either use a mug instead of a pitcher or you could fill the pitcher with a lot more water.
Rym: Well, we do know next year, I mean, this year was the first year in the new venue.
Rym: You don't want to try anything weird with the first year when there's all these variables.
Rym: Next year, they've been in this venue before.
Rym: I think it's the time to experiment.
Scott: They just gotta get more enforcers.
Scott: So if you're thinking about it, enforce.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: In fact, if they want more enforcers than they had last year, and any of you listeners out there want to enforce, we can introduce you to people you can talk to.
Scott: Yeah, I know a lot of people are like, you know, they don't come to PAX because of money reasons.
Scott: Well, enforce then.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Also, most of the enforcers we know have a really good time enforcing.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And last, last, last idea.
Rym: I don't like to bring this up on the show.
Rym: As much as I love talking about myself, pretty much half the enforcers we talked to in panel rooms and everything basically said that we ran the best panels they had all day.
Scott: That's what they say.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I can't believe that that's true.
Rym: Now, here's the thing.
Rym: If that is true, that is fucked up because I think we're pretty good, but PAX has a right to much better content being its best content in the panel rooms than us.
Rym: Oh, yes.
Rym: So I think what PAX need to do is steal a line from MAGFest.
Rym: MAGFest has the MAG-9, nine gaming intellectuals.
Rym: They get nine people who know a lot about games and they put them on panels with a real moderator who has a real agenda and actually leads the discussion.
Rym: Because if you look at most panels of PAX, they're either a community panel that only applies to people in that community and is completely just meaningless to everyone else.
Scott: Are you a listener or viewer of X internet show or podcast or video thing?
Scott: Then come to this panel and all those people, the fans and the creators will be there.
Scott: Hooray.
Rym: Every year they're like, "Guys, do the GeekNights
Rym: panel.".
Rym: We're like, "No, that's
Rym: stupid.".
Rym: We should do the PAX panel.
Rym: So the rest of the panels are not lectures, they're panels.
Rym: But they're usually either the same panels as last year, meaning the same four game.
Scott: journalists get up and- They did that thing where it's like, "Vote on the top 10
Scott: games.".
Rym: But it's the same people and they have the same things to say.
Rym: They don't have an agenda.
Rym: And almost all of them just open it up to questions from the audience right away, which is pretty much a guaranteed recipe for a lame panel.
Scott: Also, don't forget the company selling something panel.
Scott: "Hey, we're id Software.
Scott: Check out Rage.
Scott: It's coming out.
Scott: We're going to show it to
Scott: you.".
Rym: Now those panels actually often fill up and actually that's a good use of panel space because that's a way people are interested in it.
Scott: I kind of wanted to go to that.
Rym: I only didn't because the Rage panel was full.
Rym: But I guess if Magfest, with its level of professionalism, I love you Magfest, but yeah.
Rym: If you can pull off professional, moderated panels with experts in games and game theory that everyone who's in that room finds really awesome, PAX can do the same.
Rym: PAX needs you to steal that formula straight up.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: If you can't get people to fill the panel rooms with stuff that people like, you need to go out and solicit it.
Scott: Go find people and say, "Hey, you would do an awesome panel at PAX.
Scott: Come and do
Scott: one.".
Scott: You know?
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Otherwise, we'll see you at the next PAX.
Rym: Wait.
Scott: One more thing.
Scott: Stop lying about the attendance.
Rym: Alright, PAX.
Rym: I'm warning you.
Rym: We're going to have to call you out at Prime.
Scott: Yeah, it's not gonna, it's like, I was gonna call it out at the Q&A, which is an inappropriate place to do it, because it's like, it's not, Gabe and Tycho, they have nothing to do with that.
Scott: They don't know or care, even.
Scott: But it's like, there's no other soapbox you can get, I can get on to bring this issue to the required amount of light.
Scott: And it isn't just PAX.
Scott: I would be very clear about that.
Rym: But we know why they do it, because basically, not doing it this way is the anomaly.
Rym: Only fan, super unprofessional conventions do it the right way, which is, number of people in the building.
Rym: But PAX, and the New York Comic Con, the New York Anime Festival, the San Diego Comic Con, and surprisingly, most of the anime cons on the west coast do it this way, too.
Rym: They're like, yeah, we're bigger than Otakon.
Rym: No, fuck you.
Rym: Otakon is so much bigger than you, it's laughable.
Scott: Otakon is probably bigger than PAX East, and PAX East is bigger than PAX West.
Rym: Otakon is bigger than PAX East, because Otakon's attendance is about 27,000 bodies, and the BCE can only- And that's not counting staff or anything.
Rym: The BCE, actually that is.
Rym: The BCE only holds 24,000 people at once.
Rym: And the total attendance of PAX East was, I do know the number, I won't say it because it was given to me in confidence, less than that.
Rym: So.
Scott: So.
Rym: I mean, if PAX is gonna say, you know, 24,000 people, then I can legitimately say that ConnectiCon, this dinky con that we're in charge of panels for- Is 21,000.
Rym: Eh, 20,000, because we don't get that many three day badges.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: So, you know, 18 to 20,000 is our convention.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, this is a pet peeve of mine, and I'm going to bring it to light if it is not rectified.
Scott: 'Cause it just needs to be known mostly by the journalists who keep reporting the number without understanding it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I feel like we need to make a tweet account, like one of those apps, that looks for anyone quoting attendance numbers of any convention, and if it's on the list of cons that do turnstile, it corrects them and tweets out.
Rym: Kinda like that Blood Elf account that yells at you for swearing all the time.
Scott: Really?
Scott: I never see that.
Rym: I saw it once and I banned it, but anyway.
Scott: I get an annoying Navi, and I also get, "I'll buy that for a
Scott: dollar."
Scott: All the time.
Scott: If you say Zelda, it goes, "Hey,
Scott: listen.".
Scott: And if you say Robocop, it says, "I'll buy that for a
Scott: dollar.".
Rym: I follow Duke Togo, though.
Rym: Dot dot dot.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.