Rym: Well, it's that time again for "The Ear, The Eye, The Arm" by Nancy Farmer.
Scott: Well, it's not time again for "The Ear, The Eye, The
Scott: Arm.".
Rym: Oh, you didn't let me finish.
Rym: On "The GeekNights Book
Rym: Club.".
Scott: No, it's time again for "The GeekNights Book Club" this month.
Scott: "The Ear, The Eye, The
Scott: Arm.".
Scott: No.
Rym: Regardless, we read "The Ear, The Eye, The Arm," which was recommended to me by Emily.
Scott: As a... I just can't help saying that.
Rym: "The Ear, The Eye, The
Rym: Arm.".
Scott: "The
Scott: Leg.".
Scott: Arm.".
Scott: "The
Scott: Foot.".
Scott: Dick.".
Scott: Can't help it.
Rym: You know, I was gonna say something other than dick, but I'm glad you went straight for dicks.
Scott: "The
Scott: Spleen.".
Rym: Dicks everywhere.
Rym: "The
Rym: Spleen.".
Rym: So, this was recommended by Emily, and the selling point, what sold me on reading it, was that it was short, kind of a young adult novel, and I didn't know the author, and it's sci-fi set in Africa.
Scott: Yeah, you would like the short books, 'cause you don't like doing hard work.
Rym: Alright, my next book's gonna be "The Count of Fucking
Rym: Motherfuckersto.".
Scott: I won't read it.
Rym: Actually, it's an awesome book.
Scott: I'll get the abridged edition.
Scott: It probably is awesome, but I'll get the abridged edition.
Rym: But anyway, it's sci-fi.
Scott: I just don't have time for this shit.
Rym: But it's set in Zimbabwe, in the year 2194.
Scott: It's already a pretty cool setting, I wanna play an RPG in that setting.
Rym: Yeah, and it is a pretty cool setting, it's a pretty futuristic Africa, and it has a lot of fun kind of references to the history we've missed in oblique ways, like, "Oh, he's from the English tribe, yeah, something happened to
Rym: them.".
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But, in case you have not listened to a book club episode before, we have already read the book.
Rym: This is the conclusion to the reading of "The Ear, The Eye, The
Rym: Arm.".
Rym: So, we're gonna spoil the ever-living crap out of this book, and we're going to talk about it, assuming that you know the plot and have already read it.
Scott: And as I say every time, there is scientific evidence to suggest that actually, books are more enjoyable when you know about them.
Scott: And not just books, anything.
Scott: Spoilers actually make things better, they don't make them worse.
Rym: Now granted, your scientific evidence is one study on a small sample size.
Scott: Contrary to what you would normally, to common sense, spoilers make things better.
Rym: In one study on a small sample.
Scott: Also, just logically, if something is good, that means that it's good multiple times, which means it's still good.
Scott: the second go when you already know everything's gonna happen.
Scott: "Empire Strikes Back," still good the second time.
Rym: But Scott, would you have enjoyed Monica as much had I, before you watch it, told you exactly what happens in episode 10?
Scott:  Yes.
Scott:  Really?
Scott:  I just don't think-- - Really?
Scott: You may not think you would, but you would have.
Rym: See, Scott, you say that, but I do kind of disagree, and that one study does not a coherent argument make.
Scott: I have no problem with anything being spoiled for me.
Scott:  That's all I'm saying.
Scott:  Okay.
Rym: Anyway, so, you might not want to listen if you haven't read the book, because you're not gonna know what we're talking about.
Scott: That's awesome, but, you know, maybe you'll catch on.
Rym:  I did like-- - Maybe you'll get interested "The Eye and The Arm" as characters, because it's weird.
Scott: They were actually my favorite characters.
Rym: Any time I read a new book, whenever there's-- There's certain kinds of characters that I expect them to be boring, and I expect to just like, "Oh, I just want to get past these guys and get to what I really care
Rym: about.".
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: A lot of books use that technique of having characters in different places.
Scott: They split the party as it goes, and they'll focus.
Scott: Each chapter will teleport between the different areas, and eventually the characters meet or interact in some way.
Scott: But so far, they've all been separate.
Scott: So you're going, it's like-- Let me think of a good example.
Scott: "Judging Eye" is like, "Momem, great ordeal," you know, and then "Skin
Scott: Eaters.".
Scott: "Momem, great ordeal, Skin
Scott: It goes-- Oh, my microphone's falling over.
Scott: It goes around in a little circle like that, you know?
Scott: So when that happens, quite often, there's only one or two of those you care about more than the others.
Scott: So when you're reading the other one that you don't care about as much, you're just, "Hurry up, I want to get back to the good part with the other guy that I care about
Scott: more.".
Rym: Actually, the only one I didn't care about there was the whole "White Luck Warrior" subset of
Rym: "Momem.".
Rym: 'Cause while I cared about it, I really just wanted to find out what was going on up north.
Scott: Yeah, right, well, north is where all the secrets are, right?
Scott: But yeah, you know, a lot of things will do that.
Scott: There'll be secret stuff, and there'll be less secret stuff, and it's like, you just want to go for the most secret stuff all the time.
Rym: But I really like "The Ear, the Eye, the Arm," because they were kind of incompetent, and they fought with each other, and they were kind of jerks, but then they ribbed each other the way real friends rib each other, kind of like in
Rym: "Ponies.".
Scott: Great, more ponies in the show.
Scott: But yeah, it's like, they're the detectives, they're trying to solve the mystery, they have superpowers, but their superpowers are actually just handicaps.
Rym: Their superpower is literally, "Show up five seconds after they should have showed
Rym: up.".
Scott: Right, and it's like, they were detectiving okay, but they never actually investigated in a Sherlock Holmes way.
Scott: It's like, they didn't have detective skills that much, they just sort of always ended up in the right place slightly before everyone else, but always after they needed to show up there.
Scott: And it was just like, are these guys even fucking helping?
Rym: They really weren't.
Rym: Until the very end, they had no impact on the kids.
Rym: All they did was basically reassure Mastika and his wife that they were alive.
Scott: So it's weird that the title of the book is named after them, when they're actually not the main characters.
Scott: They're not in the book really all that much, and they don't really play into it all that much.
Rym: Until the end, when they kinda deus ex machina their way to victory.
Scott: Yeah, and it's sort of like, they tried to pass it off as like, I was hoping for more detective action, but there really wasn't any at all.
Rym: But, they did do what you always want them to do, they worked with their feet, and their legs, and their ears, eyes, and arms.
Scott: Yeah, they definitely had the Odoro Daisou-Souzen Menta Daisou-Souzen.
Rym: When the kids just got out of Rest Haven and went into the subway stupidly, and ears like, "I hear something in the subway," and the other guy's like, "Shut up.
Scott: We got
Scott: this.".
Rym: But then later they're like, "Yeah, you were right, we were
Rym: stupid.".
Scott: Anyway, in case you haven't read it, just quickly, right?
Scott: Basically, you have some kids, their dad is mad rich, he's the general.
Scott: He's a super important person.
Scott: I get the impression he's kind of the dictator of Zimbabwe.
Scott: I think he's the sub-dictator.
Scott: I don't think he's the dictator-dictator.
Scott: He might be the dictator-dictator.
Scott: It didn't seem like it, though.
Scott: Regardless, he's either the dictator or one below the dictator.
Scott: He's super important.
Scott: These are his kids, he's uber protective of them, right?
Scott: So they haven't seen the world at all.
Scott: One day they escape, and he's so worried that they were kidnapped.
Scott: So I'm thinking, "Oh, they're not gonna get
Scott: kidnapped.".
Scott: But of course, they fucking do immediately.
Rym: I love how them getting kidnapped is actually just random bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, right?
Scott: It's sort of like, on the one hand, it's like, "Oh, really?
Scott: You're supporting all this parental worrying of kids going
Scott: out.".
Rym: Oh, but the world that is described in this book is fucking dangerous, and people do get robbed and kidnapped all the time, as far as I can tell.
Scott: So as the kids are kidnapped, they go from place to place, either by escaping or running away or getting double kidnapped from the kidnappers, right?
Scott: And they end up going to all these different places, and each of the different places they go has a different sort of moral lesson to teach to add up to the big moral lesson of the whole book.
Rym: Which is, immigrants ruin your country.
Scott: That's your moral lesson?
Rym: We'll get to that.
Rym: I was kind of disappointed in that at the end.
Rym: Yeah, so basically, I mean, look at Rest Haven.
Rym: It's kind of this, "Yeah, the old ways are traditional, and they're really good in some
Rym: ways.".
Scott: Well, the Rest Haven's the third place.
Rym: I just want to start it with, because it was such a stark... Like, every setting was presented in, "Hey, this place is great.
Rym: Oh, check out how different this place is from everything
Rym: else.".
Rym: Oh, look, it's all so shitty.
Rym: It's like, the past had problems, the future has problems, every time has problems.
Rym: There is this kind of moral that you have to just keep going forward, and there's no such thing as this perfect nostalgia for the past.
Rym: At no matter, any point in time was good and bad combined.
Scott: Yeah, that's my favorite thing about the whole book, is you look, and so many people in the world will always try to teach some kind of lesson.
Rym: In the '90s, anime was the best.
Scott: It's really popular right now for people to be like, "Natural things are great.
Scott: Unnatural things are not
Scott: great.".
Scott: Or, "The olden days, when men were men, was great, and nowadays
Scott: sucks.".
Rym: Back in the '50s, when women knew their place and made coffee.
Scott: Yeah, or even people would be like, "Modern times are great, and the olden times
Scott: sucked.".
Scott: You know, everyone is... Someone always is comparing one thing better than another thing.
Scott: Even great sci-fi novels, like Brave New World, will be like, "This is great, and this is not so
Scott: great.".
Scott: But here, the arm is like, "Look, everything has positives, and everything has
Scott: negatives.".
Scott: There is no great, and there is no...
Rym: Every one of these little settings, because they were kind of like settings, like individual stories within, and then there'd be like a link with the ear, the eye, and the arm showing up too late to save everybody.
Scott: It's almost like being transported between different separate worlds, and almost like a space train.
Scott: You go to the different planets, and each planet has a different lesson to tell you.
Scott: Only there's only three or four planets.
Scott: As opposed to like a zillion.
Rym: But each one also makes a lot of various points.
Rym: They're kind of all over the place about society in general.
Rym: Like, "Look at this kind of
Rym: place."
Rym: Like the stupid British lady at the end, who was all, "Oh, my dinner party outside would be ruined by you, all the
Rym: children!".
Rym: That one felt kind of snow-crashy, actually.
Scott: Yeah, it definitely felt like they were in some sort of weird, not real-world kind of place.
Rym: That one stood out as...
Scott: It was almost like a surreal VR kind of situation.
Scott: At least that's what I felt like.
Scott: It was very burbclave.
Scott: Yeah, like it was a scary, fake place they were in.
Rym: Granted, I can see it is interesting, because look at it from the perspective of, like, say you know African culture the way that we know our own white dude culture.
Rym: So, in that sense, imagine us describing a culture that we see from the outside, but don't get much insight into.
Rym: It's almost like that part was a... Like, that's how ridiculous this lifestyle looks to a complete outsider.
Rym: Mmm, that's true.
Rym: Like, I know something about this particular culture, but I see them doing the things, and it just seems really fucked up to me.
Rym: Like, I love how they describe that cradle as basically like.
Rym: they think it's a cage.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Kind of was a cage, though.
Scott: Well, no, actually I read it as being a literal cage.
Scott: I thought he was literally, like, in a cage.
Rym: There are things like that.
Scott: With metal and a lock on it and shit.
Scott: That's how I read it.
Scott: You thought it was just a cradle, and they interpreted it as a cage?
Rym: Well, it was a cradle with a cage cover to keep kids in.
Scott: Yeah, I thought it was a literal steel prison.
Rym: It was, but it was a cradle that was like... I think of it this way, these British people are like, "Yeah, that's what you do to a sick kid, to keep him in
Rym: bed.".
Rym: And the Zimbabweans are like, "What the fuck is wrong with you?
Rym: It's a
Rym: cage.".
Scott: So, how about the...
Rym: The Blay people?
Scott: No, the guy... The fuckin'... Freshman?
Scott: No, the praising guy.
Rym: Oh, the praise singer.
Rym: I like their religion.
Scott: Right, so this is praise singer.
Rym: He's such a wuss.
Rym: Like, his character was so awesome, and then it was so crap by the end.
Scott: Yeah, so basically the praise singer is sort of a kellis-ish kind of individual, right?
Scott: Basically, he has this skill, I guess he's practiced it or trained in it, where his job is to just sing praises.
Scott: So it's like, you know, they're sitting at the breakfast table, and this guy comes in, they pay him, he's an employee.
Scott: He's also sort of the kid's tutor, also, independent of praise singing.
Scott: And he comes in and says, "Oh, Rym, you are so great.
Scott: Oh, Scott, you are the
Scott: best.".
Scott: And he tells you why you're the best.
Scott: And he has such a great psychological effect that you almost lose yourself in the praise, and he just makes you feel great.
Scott: It's almost like drugs, but they go in your ears in the forms of words.
Scott: He's so good at it, he has such power.
Scott: So the family pays him to do this, and he uses his praising abilities, like hypnotize the dad, and that's what lets the kids leave the house and get you kidnapped.
Scott: So after that, the dad's like, "Yeah, praise singer, I don't like your shit
Scott: anymore.".
Rym: The thing is, I like the praise singer, but he was so cringing and just pathetic by the end that I gave up on him.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, on the one hand, I thought it was sort of a cool thing that they would do this, but it also had clearly that anti, you know, it's like, yeah, it's kind of cool to have this praise singing, but on the other hand, it's like, yeah, this psychological manipulation
Rym: is probably-- Well, platitudes can only get you so far.
Rym: And there's a line in the end, I think Ai says something like, "Praise is like a vitamin.
Rym: A little bit is necessary to survive, but too much
Rym: death.".
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But at least at the end, while the praise singer was sort of ruined, they were like, "Okay, you can stay, you just can't praise anymore with your psychologically manipulating
Scott: people.".
Rym: But he still goes and praises for Eri and Arm.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But they need it.
Rym: So, I mean, look at the Vlaie people, though.
Rym: That was kind of a, there's a whole story of like reclaiming the land that was fucked by the modern technology and this kind of like twilight life between the modern world and the ancient world.
Scott: Well, I mean, what was the name of the big fat, the elephant?
Scott: Oh, the elephant.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so the she-elephant was sort of like, you know, typical, they started off-- You know what she reminded me of?
Rym: A Lopta villain.
Rym: Like the Lopta pirates.
Rym: She's bad, but she's not that bad.
Scott: It felt just like a Miyazaki kidnapping, right?
Scott: It's like you're kidnapped, we're making you dig in the mines, but we're feeding you and we sort of, even though we're bad, evil kidnappers making you do slave labor, basically.
Scott: And at the end-- We're not all bad.
Rym: And at the end, she sells them to the masks and the masks are like, "We're gonna kill
Rym: 'em.".
Rym: And she's like, "Uh, that's not cool.
Rym: I'm gonna smash your stupid
Rym: mask.".
Rym: Right.
Scott: You know, it's sort of like, you know, while they were doing an evil thing, it's like they weren't just all bad people who were just straight up evil.
Rym: Look at the message at the end when the spirit of the land inhabits the arm to do all the, you know, the deus ex machina at the end.
Rym: Magic is real, gods are real.
Rym: I was kind of disappointed in that.
Scott: Kind of.
Scott: But anyway-- Especially in a sci-fi world.
Rym: But they make it very clear that he's like, when Tendai has kind of the vision of, you know, the spirit of the land and of this culture and the people, he looks at everyone in the room, even the she-elephant, and everyone in the city and the country and whatever, and realizes that there's one kind of bad that's just a part of society.
Rym: And then there's this other kind of bad that is dirty illegal immigrants.
Rym: I just, I can't, I was really bothered by that.
Rym: That message would have been cool except for the fact that the plot in the end was, everything was fine until these Gondwanans with their bad culture started moving into our town.
Rym: Yeah, you know, it's sort of like-- Especially because the mother, Matsika's wife, says at one point when she thinks, "Oh, it's the Gondwanans,".
Rym: she remembers a time in their past when some other tribe moved into their land and they were just as bad and they had to kick them out too and then it fixed everything.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like you had this, you know, thing where like there were the masks, like these unseen bad guys that everyone was always worried about.
Scott: I liked the masks.
Scott: They were the internal, you know, illegal criminal gang and you also had this external threat that they were always fighting with but, you know, they had managed to fend them off.
Scott: And then it turned out in the end, of course, that they were one and the same, right?
Scott: That the Gondwanans were waging an external war in the disguise of being an internal threat.
Rym: But they were just evil.
Scott: It would be like if there was an evil terrorist but they were the mafia.
Scott: Like the mafia turned out to be Islamic fundamentalist terrorist crazies.
Rym: But like I thought the masks were like big fire but it turned out they're just immigrants with different gods who are just straight up murdering, sacrificing evil.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like I would have been happier with the message.
Scott: more of like, you know, okay, look, you know, people from other countries are cool too.
Scott: They have the goods and their bads just like all the different places within your country have the goods and the bads.
Scott: The other country also has its goods and its bads.
Scott: There's probably some, you know, masks in Gondwana that are from your country, right?
Rym: Well, there was that little note at the end like the Gondwanans were sent back to their country and they all met unpleasant ends for having lost their masks.
Rym: But until we met the masks in the very end.
Scott: Well, there was that one scene where they jumped on the subway.
Rym: And when you first meet them and they're all like whispering and gibbering and like moving around and then when Tenai knocks the mask off, it's just a Shelby old man.
Rym: They were a lot like big fire.
Rym: But once the moral came out, they were just kind of, I don't know, I was disappointed in that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It could have been way cooler.
Rym: I love their graffiti.
Rym: That whole slogan of never look behind a mask.
Rym: That aesthetic was neat that you go down into the subway and it's kind of like, yeah, they own the subway and you see this just written everywhere.
Rym: Never look behind a mask.
Scott: But it's like I actually liked that.
Scott: It was like, you know, you have these evil, you know, criminal mafia kind of guys.
Scott: And they don't want money.
Rym: They'll murder a hundred people and leave their money on top of the bodies to remind you.
Scott: In a crazy cult.
Scott: And then the fact that they're just schlubby guys like everyone else, just like the KKK.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They take the hoods off and they're just schlubby guys.
Rym: But the fact that, no, they're also the government of Gondwana and they're actively trying to bring their objectively bad Gondwanian culture into Zimbabwe and ruin it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That was the step too far.
Scott: If they would have just stopped at schlubby guys, you know, the KKK is just schlubby guys and they don't have their hoods on.
Scott: That would have been cool with that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That was that was pretty good.
Rym: Or if these guys were just bad, not everyone from Gondwana is bad and everyone from every other tribe is bad, too.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, what else?
Scott: what else is there to say about this?
Rym: I like Maztika.
Rym: whenever we got to meet him.
Scott: I actually like the the who's the dumb guy's name?
Scott: It's actually a trash man was way cool.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because it's always cool when you have that character.
Scott: And it's sort of like, you know, they try to suggest he's got like mentally retarded in some way.
Scott: But he's not really right.
Scott: He's just one of those guys who doesn't say anything, really.
Rym: You know, he's kind of one of those mystical.
Rym: you don't know how he gets in and out.
Rym: Like he probably keeps like.
Rym: they say, oh, he's probably back in Rest Haven.
Rym: Like, how do you even get in there?
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know how we always say, like, you can't tell the difference between incompetence and evil.
Scott: This is like.
Scott: can't tell the indifference between incompetence in accidental, you know, being incompetent and accidentally being awesome.
Rym: Like that Bill Murray movie, The Man Who Knew Too Little.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or it's like your favorite captain.
Scott: What's his face?
Scott: Captain Tyler.
Rym: Captain Tyler.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Thing is, I'm pretty sure he was genius.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the point is, is it's sort of that same thing.
Scott: where it's like, you know, he I mean, he's acting way dumber than Tyler acted, of course.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He's acting like he has, you know, actual problems in his brain.
Rym: He probably does.
Scott: Probably does.
Scott: But, you know, he manages to get along and actually pull off a bunch of awesome.
Scott: Especially when he comes and saves and saves the day at the old bridge.
Scott: Like he says, yes, that was totally course.
Rym: He also ruined the day by sitting outside and letting the elephant know where they were.
Scott: Yeah, that was also a problem.
Rym: But, you know, I just I didn't like I wasn't sure where this book was going to go, but I think I really started enjoying it.
Rym: when after the kids get kidnapped and whatever and the ear, the eye, the arm go off to investigate.
Rym: And they always they show up late and they get injured every time.
Rym: And that one doctor's like, Jesus, you guys stop.
Scott: It's like they even went into rest haven with a pretty good plan of acting like the monster.
Scott: Their plan was great.
Scott: That was going to work to work.
Scott: You're right.
Scott: But the kids had already left.
Rym: It was too late.
Scott: But if they would have showed up when the kids were there, that would have been crazy awesome.
Rym: I love how their plan was literally ooga booga booga.
Scott: I actually kind of wish they reordered the book a little bit and had the rest haven be the last place and then actually have them save them with that monster strategy.
Scott: That would have been fun.
Scott: Totally fun.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I also very much enjoyed.
Rym: I want to start using this as a turn of phrase, because when in rest haven, when they're doing the traditional storytelling and that whole thing was really neat, like the cult, like you're like seeing the view of the culture of tend I like knew like when to do what and when to say what and put my fist like this and act like this or like.
Rym: All right.
Rym: That kid who doesn't know, you know, I've studied this culture, made two mounds that represent my mother's breast, and he knocked them down to thereby disrespect my mother.
Scott: Oh, the fight.
Rym: I don't care about that because that's kind of weird.
Scott: That's very West Side story.
Rym: But I know Kung Fu and this kid doesn't.
Scott: Sharks and Jets, baby.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But like, you know, he had karate lessons.
Rym: He knew he just kicked the kid's ass.
Scott: That's you know, that was showing like, look, even, you know, people so culturally, you know, far away from each other still have these like these similar things.
Scott: And you can tell what someone's going for at the same time, even though their style is different.
Rym: But at the same time, he didn't feel it.
Rym: He's like, this is really stupid.
Rym: I have to go through these motions with this old barbaric culture that talks about cows all the time.
Rym: I don't care about cows.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Cows.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, imagine if you wanted to play.
Rym: They're not curious about anything.
Scott: Imagine if you're going to play a board game with someone, but it's sort of like when you go to play Star Wars Jedi Knight and they bow and I just stab them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: We I loved.
Rym: you know, the only thing I enjoyed about that game was stabbing someone while they were trying to bow to me.
Rym: That was the only goal I had when I played online was to piss those people off.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I hate it.
Scott: when they voted to kick you, though.
Rym: And then I just joined the server right then because usually they couldn't get enough votes to ban me.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But the turn of phrase I want to steal is the storytelling.
Rym: where they're like, there was a man and the crowd says, go on.
Rym: The man was in Gondwana.
Rym: Go on.
Rym: The man did this.
Rym: And when you're done telling the story, you say, and that is when the storyteller died.
Rym: I just thought that was really funny.
Rym: I really like that.
Rym: I want to tell stories like that.
Scott: You could do it, but I'm not going to say go on that many times.
Rym: I'm eventually just like, I'm going to start ending every every anecdote where I tell with and that's where the storyteller died.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Go for it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Good luck with that.
Scott: So one thing I do want to talk about is the fact that, you know, this is a young adult novel.
Scott: It was really easy to read and didn't take much time at all.
Scott: And it's sort of like, you know, I've been I don't read that those kind of books that often.
Scott: Usually, you know, at least more recently I read books that are age appropriate or at my reading level.
Rym: The thing is, they're so like, for example, I'm not saying stuff is very accessible, but very good.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But I'm not saying that it's you know, it's bad that you shouldn't read books that are easy or whatever.
Scott: You know, there's still some value in plenty of books that are not.
Rym: And the writing was perfectly serviceable.
Rym: It wasn't great.
Rym: It wasn't like special.
Rym: The phrasing was not like a masterpiece, but at no point did the writing distract me from the story.
Scott: No, but what it is, is it's you know, it's.
Scott: I think it's unique to books.
Scott: Right.
Scott: For example, you could watch a TV show that is designed for children.
Scott: And enjoy it.
Scott: But it doesn't feel like it was easier or lighter because you're watching.
Scott: It's the same.
Rym: I disagree.
Rym: I think so when I watch children's movies, it's like, wow, made for kids.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: They keep saying the name of the things so the kids don't forget it.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: I don't I don't notice that.
Scott: Really?
Rym: I noticed that.
Scott: I mean, I guess I mean all ages stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: But, you know, when you're reading a book that is so, you know, meant for, you know, to be accessible to younger audiences, it necessarily is, you know, has less words, is less harder words, reads faster and more easy, you know.
Rym: So even if there was even if the common gobbledygook in here.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But I mean, even if the content is still valuable for, you know, someone who is older and wiser.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, which this that book definitely was, you know, they just feels sort of light as you're reading.
Scott: It has a different feeling as, you know, the work of reading is it feels different.
Rym: What made it feel light to me was only that one, I did not have to delve deeply into the language to, you know, find subtext.
Rym: There was very little subtext.
Rym: And two, there was no sacrifice made by any of the protagonists.
Rym: They they killed one character and then they brought him back with B.S.
Scott: That's yeah.
Rym: I mean, pretty much everyone turned up just fine.
Scott: With his magic circle on a string.
Rym: Yeah, the doro.
Scott: Yeah, doro.
Scott: Which is made?
Scott: it was made of real seashell as opposed to the other ones that are made of fucking ceramic.
Rym: I like how the the traditional like the elder in the village in Rest Haven was pissed off.
Rym: He's like, you got to go.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Like, imagine if you're like the master of, you know, I don't know what's something we like a lot.
Rym: Ah, board games.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: You're the master of some board game and some guy shows up who's never played.
Scott: He's not into board games, really.
Scott: He just sort of starting out and he's got like first printing settlers from Germany with the stiffy, stiffy guards.
Scott: And he doesn't even know what he's got.
Scott: It's like, oh, fuck you.
Scott: You know, meanwhile, you're sitting there with your brand new settlers with chintzy ass pieces.
Scott: You know, it's kind of like that.
Scott: So I can I could empathize with that guy, but just that there was no sacrifice.
Rym: He was a bad guy, though.
Rym: I mean, it was kind of a cop out that used the Nirvana guns.
Rym: But oh, those evil Gondwanans use the soul stealer.
Scott: The Nirvana guns reminded me totally of Hokuto.
Scott: no Ken.
Rym: But but I really liked how they've got the Nirvana guns.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And when they first go into their first business, the early eye in the arm, one of them's like, we don't have that many bullets or rounds.
Rym: So don't waste them.
Rym: And then the scene that is described is them firing constantly and with abandon for many minutes.
Scott: And pretty much every time the guns are involved, they're just like, pew, pew, pew, pew, pew, pew, pew, pew, pew.
Scott: I see.
Scott: It's weird that they had like.
Scott: on the one hand, I imagine the Nirvana guns being sort of like ray guns or something like that.
Scott: Batteries.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, I guess so.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: but then they talked about rounds.
Scott: I'm like, oh, I guess they shoot bullets or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's sort of I wasn't entirely sure.
Scott: Like a lot of the things, a lot of the physical things that were described, I didn't get a good feeling for.
Scott: Like they described the incredibly mile high tower.
Scott: What was it called?
Rym: The McElwain.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, this incredibly tall tower where all the cool stuff is and the fancy restaurant and the client, you know, where everything.
Scott: And I, you know, I sort of got the idea that, you know, they were in this gigantically tall tower, but I couldn't really get a good picture of it.
Scott: Like the cars are flying, but you couldn't really get it.
Scott: You know, it's like they didn't go into incredible detail about the shape of things.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: The descriptions and everything were very sparse.
Rym: Like there's one point like the Nirvana gun.
Scott: OK, I didn't really.
Scott: I couldn't really picture a Nirvana gun fully in my head.
Scott: I started to go with my own imagination, which is I think this book would feel very different depending who's reading it, just because so much is left to the imagination.
Rym: But I like how like when he describes a large woman, when one of them encounters a large woman, the elephant, the line is something like she was large.
Rym: No, majestic and majestic was italicized.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: how large do you imagine the elephant woman to be?
Rym: Oh, my goodness.
Rym: I imagine her not being because she could walk.
Rym: I imagine her not being fat and like horribly obese, like the people I often see waddling around downtown in the tourist district.
Rym: But I imagine her being like just this gigantic, slightly flabby woman who is stronger than anyone else you will ever meet.
Rym: I just I just imagine she picks the kids up like by their head and just like holds.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because of that, I imagined her as sort of like a fan.
Scott: You know, it's already a fantasy world, the Nirvana guns in the ear, eye and arm.
Scott: So I was sort of imagining her being more like the ear, the eye and the arm, like freakishly unnatural, could not exist in the real world.
Scott: Gigantic, like maybe half as big as an elephant.
Rym: No, I just pictured a normally gigantic woman.
Scott: I pictured her actually being just ginormous.
Rym: Scott, you forget how tiny kids the age of these main characters are.
Scott: Oh, that is also true.
Scott: They were very tiny.
Rym: Not that long ago, we rode school buses when we went to that Mets game, remember?
Scott: Yeah, I was on a school bus recently.
Rym: Yeah, we go in the school bus and I'm like, oh, wow, I used to sit three across.
Rym: And now, like, I don't even fit in one of these.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Kids are tiny.
Scott: But maybe that's another thing.
Scott: is that, you know, if you read this as a kid, then the imagination you put into is completely different.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In your because you imagine a bigger world and different sizes of things.
Rym: And, you know, I mean, really, it was a great book.
Rym: And the only things that annoy me are, oh, my God, the gods are real.
Rym: And the God just says, hey, arm, go here and do this.
Rym: And that's the answer.
Rym: Yeah, everything will work out.
Scott: I would have I would have to improve this book.
Scott: I would only put in more real detective work, you know, for reals.
Rym: And of course, you know, damn dirty immigrants.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And the idea in the arm, they had these powers that were mostly handicapped.
Rym: I liked how that was cool.
Scott: That was cool.
Scott: But I would have liked to see them also be beneficial more.
Rym: They were oogie boogie boogie.
Scott: Yeah, but if they were to use their powers to benefit like one.
Rym: Also, I totally heard them.
Scott: He totally did.
Scott: But it would have been cool if like one more time their powers actually helped instead of hurt or helped and hurt simultaneously.
Scott: Simultaneously.
Rym: Anyway, I do like our rest haven.
Rym: Like he heard them like rolling boulders up against the gates.
Rym: And the one taxi driver is like, hey, last time they did that, it was 15 years before I heard a peep out of him.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: Like, you know, this rest have in place and a taxi right outside of it.
Rym: Well, because right outside is like probably the equivalent of Alphabet City in New York, like the kind of low income, but not lowest income housing.
Scott: No, I think it was like a suburb, right?
Rym: Yeah, it was like a mid like middle lower middle class to middle class suburb.
Scott: It was weird.
Scott: The suburb, like the suburb was like on the edge of the scary desert where the she elephant lived.
Scott: I imagine like this like desert, desert, desert, suddenly white fences.
Rym: I gave up on any concept of the geography of this book pretty much right away.
Scott: Yeah, and I think, I don't know.
Rym: It's like vlay, vlay, vlay, cement line houses.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, really?
Scott: Okay, sure.
Scott: That's weird.
Rym: I like how two different bus drivers are like, fuck this shit.
Rym: And oh, and how every time, so many times the ear of the eye of the arm show up, they're like, we have a plan, must go quietly.
Rym: And then guns a blazing, they yell Mustika's name.
Rym: Everyone else hears it and flips the fuck out and it's just chaos.
Rym: And then the SWAT team comes in.
Scott: Yeah, good job, guys.
Rym: They were kind of incompetent, but they were funny enough to where I was okay with that.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: It would have been, I think it might have been better maybe if, you know, good balance, like if one of them was more competent and one of them was less competent and you had a Three Stooges situation.
Scott: Ah, the arm.
Scott: You know, you get a little straight man, funny man going.
Rym: The arm and the eye did a lot more than the ear, but that's partly because they didn't listen to the ear when they should have.
Rym: But then the eye passed out.
Scott: Definitely most of the focus was on the arm.
Scott: The ear and the eye really didn't do all that much.
Rym: Yeah, well the arm psychic stuff really overpowered everything else.
Scott: Yeah, it was mostly arm because he was the one who suffered the most and also did the most.
Scott: And he had the whole situation with like, you know, the baby and whatever.
Scott: It's like, you know, whatever.
Rym: That baby part could have not been in the book.
Rym: It didn't really, like.
Rym: it just was extra.
Rym: So, it's your turn to pick a book.
Scott: We're going to do double book.
Rym: Double book.
Scott: Double book.
Rym: Bear in mind the precedent you are setting, Scott, for I pick next.
Scott: Okay, well you know I wanted to do The Little Prince.
Scott: You did.
Scott: The problem is The Little Prince, you can read that shit in like a couple hours if you're not two years old, right?
Scott: So, that's probably one of the best books there ever was.
Scott: Which is why you're going to fucking read it, because I told you to.
Rym: But it takes you like- You're going to learn about the best tree in the world.
Scott: Sure are, and the snake too.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: But, you're going to read it in a day, so you don't need a month to read this shit.
Scott: We could do the book club on it friggin' next week.
Scott: So, I have to add an additional book to double it up to make the book a month worthwhile.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: So, I need an additional book that goes with The Little Prince.
Scott: Well, what could fucking go with it?
Scott: I'll tell you what goes with it.
Rym: Prince of Nothing?
Rym: No.
Scott: Wind, Sand, and Stars, also by Antoine de Saint-Ejuperi.
Rym: I have never read that.
Scott: Most people haven't, because, you know, a lot of people have read The Little Prince and know what it's about.
Scott: Very few people actually bother to pay any attention to the man who wrote it.
Scott: Antoine de Saint-Ejuperi is probably one of the greatest people to have ever lived in the history of the universe.
Rym: His Wikipedia article is worth a gander.
Scott: Yeah, so, just imagine if Porco Rosso was a real fucking person, and everything about him is absolutely true.
Scott: Like, dude, you know how he died?
Scott: He went out to fly on a plane mission and didn't return.
Rym: He's out there somewhere, still circling.
Scott: He literally was, like, delivering the mail by plane during the war.
Scott: He was a national treasure of ze France.
Scott: This dude was fucking epic.
Scott: So, you're gonna read this book about him being fucking epic right here.
Scott: Let us read the product description.
Scott: "Recipient of the Grand Prix of the Academie Francaise, wind, sand, and stars captures the grandeur, danger, and isolation of flight.
Scott: Its exciting account of air adventure, combined with lyrical prose and the spirit of a philosopher, makes it one of the most popular works ever written about flying, translated by Louis
Scott: Galantier.".
Scott: Right, so, basically you have one of the most badass, literally was an adventuring pilot, closest thing to, I guess he was sort of like an Indiana Jones, but he didn't archaeology.
Scott: He piloted, you know, planes, mostly.
Scott: Real person, not a made up person.
Scott: You'd think this dude was, like, from Arcadia of my Youth or some shit, but this is real fucking life.
Scott: It was all true.
Scott: Like, Red Baron kind of shit.
Scott: And, so read this book.
Scott: And also The Little Prince, which is what he's famous for.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.