Rym: It's Monday December 5th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is Dinosaur Knights.
Rym: Tonight we talk about the Alhambra.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I point out that the Alhambra was completely walled if you had an optimal score.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: That's one badass Alhambra right there.
Rym: We're talking about walled gardens.
Rym: I made an inside joke.
Scott: Thanks.
Scott: It wasn't inside.
Rym: It was inside.
Rym: It's Monday so we have some non-gamers here.
Rym: Speaking of games, this has happened to me enough times to where it's a problem now and I'm not sure what to do about it.
Rym: So Amazon, right?
Rym: You can buy stuff from Amazon or you can buy stuff through Amazon from other people.
Rym: The majority of board game tabletop game stuff that's on Amazon is through these other people.
Rym: That's just the way it is.
Rym: Three of my last four orders for board game stuff were through Amazon to some reseller.
Rym: All three of these orders were canceled by the person within a few days of me paying them money.
Scott: Yeah, do you know why this works?
Rym: I know exactly what happens.
Rym: These people list things they don't have and then they try to go buy them on the open market and discover that they in fact cannot buy it for a reasonable price compared to what I paid them for it.
Scott: That's not quite exactly what it is.
Scott: What it is is that they have computer programs set up and they select products and they automatically program this thing.
Scott: It's basically an automatic system that manages Amazon listings on its own and you tell it like, "Hey, you know, you find a website that's selling something that's not
Scott: Amazon.".
Scott: Let's say you go to, I don't know, Funagain.
Rym: I can summarize this.
Rym: They're trying, they're attempting ham-fistedly to perform arbitrage on the open internet market of stuff.
Scott: Yeah, you go to funagain.com and it says here, "Tickets arrived, Asia,
Scott: $18.".
Scott: I go to Amazon and I set the system to look at that page and meanwhile it manages an Amazon page that says, "Ticket to ride, Asia,
Scott: $19.".
Scott: When I find out that they're all sold out on Funagain.
Rym: I have two points though.
Rym: One, most of the people I've done business with where I ran into this problem do not seem terribly sophisticated.
Rym: I wonder if they're buying a package like a consultant sets this up for them or if they're doing it manually and just kind of trying to wing it.
Rym: But all that aside, I feel like Amazon should do something about this because it's a pain in the ass and I think the people who do this should be punished to prevent them or at least discourage them from doing such things.
Rym: For example, say you cancel more than, I don't know, 5% of your orders in a month's span.
Rym: You should be kicked off Amazon.
Scott: I think that what they should do is they should, it's real simple, is don't order things from someone unless it's obvious that they have it.
Scott: Like if it says, for example, once I bought something that was like a framed, a picture frame without anything in it and it was sold by Frames R Us or something along those lines which tells me, yeah, they've got the fucking frame.
Rym: Yeah, but I ordered this from a game store straight up.
Scott: Oh really?
Scott: Wow.
Rym: In fact, all of these, this is why I bring it up.
Rym: Every one of these failed orders was from a game reseller and if you look on their listing, they list a ton of games, one of each.
Rym: I suspect they don't have any of those games.
Scott: Yeah, that's a new one because usually when it's one of those generic sellers, it's like discount goodies or something along those lines.
Scott: It's a generic store name that could sell anything.
Scott: Or only buy things that are fulfilled by Amazon which means that they are paying to store the thing in Amazon's warehouse and Amazon is tracking the merchandise and quantities in their system automatically.
Scott: So you know you're definitely going to get it because as soon as you order it, Amazon will send it to you.
Rym: So even more worrisome is that I look on Amazon again and I see Jungle Speed for 20 bucks, says ship by Amazon, whatever.
Rym: So all right.
Scott: So that means it's in Amazon's warehouse.
Rym: That's what it says on the side.
Rym: But if I go to the email I got, it says, you know, your order from Robinson Game Store was canceled and there's a link to my order which links to that exact Amazon order page that I'm looking at right now.
Scott: It says ships from and sold by Amazon.com?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So either Amazon doesn't actually say who's fulfilling these orders until the end.
Rym: There's some shenanigans.
Scott: There is a shenanigans.
Scott: I think you got to email Amazon.
Rym: The thing is this has happened for every tabletop thing I've ordered from Amazon in a while.
Rym: So I'm wondering, there's something going on.
Rym: I'm going to do some investigative journalism.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Because Amazon, seriously, don't fuck with me here.
Rym: I'm a D level internet celebrity.
Rym: I will bring the rage of tens of people to your doorstep.
Scott: Except pretty much Amazon owns me at this point.
Rym: Yeah, I know.
Rym: I'm unable.
Rym: Did you see that article Fred Schott retweeted.
Rym: that was like, turns out the majority of people in bookstores buy things on Amazon.
Rym: after looking at them in bookstores.
Scott: There's a big surprise.
Rym: So what do you got for me?
Rym: It's Monday.
Rym: Talking about tech, not gaming.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you know how Mozilla, which is very important, right, makes all its money.
Scott: Eighty five percent of their monies come from Google.
Scott: People don't, most people don't know this, right.
Scott: And the way they get the money from Google is basically Google says, hey, Mozilla, we have a contract.
Scott: every time you send search traffic to Google through Firefox.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because Google is all up in Firefox.
Scott: Is the default search engine.
Scott: It's the.
Scott: if you just type something in the Firefox location bar and automatically Google, I'm feeling lucky, you know, it does all this stuff with Google.
Scott: So all the search traffic that gets sent to Google from Firefox, that is, you know, Mozilla gets some of the monies from those ads that are on those pages.
Scott: And that is where Mozilla gets almost all its monies.
Scott: And without that monies, Mozilla is in big trouble and Firefox is in big trouble.
Scott: So that contract is about to end.
Scott: It was a three year deal and they are negotiating to renew the deal.
Scott: So, you know, it might be renewed and everything will be cool and we won't lose Mozilla's.
Scott: But.
Scott: If, you know, something goes wrong, bad news could happen.
Scott: Very bad news, real bad.
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So there's a story on Slashdot and I'll link to the NPR one because there's no more information than what you already will see in these linked articles.
Rym: Like there hasn't been much, I guess, journalism beyond the basic story.
Rym: But the basic story is that in Mexico, there is a very bad gang, if you're unaware, the Zetas.
Rym: These are like the violent drug running paramilitary freaks down there who are murdering people using things like Facebook.
Rym: And then it'll come after me anyway.
Rym: So aside from the fact that it's interesting that on Slashdot, there is literally no discussion about the article from a technological side.
Rym: It's only either discussion of the drug war or prohibition.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Or Mexico, like politics in general, but nothing about the technology thing.
Rym: The technology thing is that a part, according to the DOD, Mexican Army found and dismantled a gigantic telecommunications network that Los Zetas had set up in Mexico for their private secret communications.
Rym: Fourteen hundred radios, twenty six hundred cell phones, one hundred and sixty seven antennas and one hundred and sixty six power supplies.
Scott: OK.
Rym: So I guess one of the antennas was on power.
Rym: Maybe it was a backup.
Rym: Maybe someone stole the power supply.
Rym: But it just goes to show that if you are evil and you want to get away with stuff, it's not that you have money.
Rym: It's not that hard to set up basically your own infrastructure.
Scott: Well, but think about it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They were they were mostly setting up a walkie talkie cell phone network.
Scott: Probably voice com.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it was probably really low traffic because it's just them.
Scott: It's not like we're trying to replace the.
Scott: you know, to replace the Internet.
Rym: You need tons and tons and tons of serious equipment.
Rym: You don't replace the Internet because here's the other thing.
Rym: If you're doing a relatively geographically defined thing, you have orders going out in different ways.
Rym: But then like the last mile use technology like this.
Rym: I'm pretty confident that even in the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: a small network like this turned up and used for very specific purposes would basically be uncatchable before it was too late.
Scott: The problem is if you do it in any highly populated area.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You got a lot.
Scott: The spectrum is hard to get.
Scott: You know, it's like that.
Scott: I'm obviously not going to get the spectrum legally.
Scott: You're pirate radio.
Scott: True, but you're just so much interference with the spectrum.
Scott: And then the FCC will find you very quickly.
Scott: You have to do it basically in the in the sticks in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: And then maybe it'll take them a while to find you if they even notice you.
Rym: I think it's more interesting.
Scott: What effect can you have on this from the perspective of IT?
Rym: Because I always wondered when I was a kid, like who does IT for the mob and who does IT for like the Yakuza?
Rym: And I wonder I wonder who ends up with those jobs.
Rym: And I would love, really love to even anonymously interview like the guy who does the computer support for like the mob boss.
Rym: I just think that'd be a really neat thing to look into.
Scott: He probably just calls up like the Geek Squad from Best Buy.
Scott: He probably doesn't have IT.
Scott: And they don't know he's a mob boss.
Scott: He's just some guy with a big fancy house and who needs his computer fixed.
Rym: Guys like, yeah, this people I'm going to kill dot CSV.
Rym: You couldn't import it because you were trying to import it as an XLS.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day, party frog.
Scott: This was pretty funny.
Rym: I just I like the way the party frog dances.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: You'll see.
Rym: It's party frog.
Scott: Check this out.
Scott: You ever gone to 8bitweapon.com with the number eight?
Rym: I have not.
Scott: I haven't either until recently.
Scott: So what they got is mostly I'm concerned with their store, right?
Scott: In their store, they sell some T-shirts and they sell some CDs of Chiptune music and their CDs are in these cool CD sleeves that look like five and a quarter floppies with little sleeves on them and then the CDs inside of there.
Scott: But the most important thing they sell is two different software products.
Scott: The Apple to DMS drummer and the Apple to DMS music.
Scott: I have an Apple to.
Scott: I feel like I should buy these Apple to Chiptune software that exists because I have an Apple to and that'd be kind of awesome to make it do something useful instead of sit in the closet.
Rym: So I'm going to actually do it.
Scott: It's 15 bucks.
Scott: I mean, maybe.
Rym: So anyway, the meta moment, which hopefully be pretty quickly book club book is two books, two books, two books.
Scott: You need to read Little Prince by Antoine de Saint-Ejouperi, which I'm still keep saying his name because I'm waiting for a French person to correct me or confirm that I think you're doing OK.
Scott: And that book will take you about like a minute to read.
Scott: And number two, you need to do to read Wind, Sand and Stars, also by the same person, which is a book that will take you more than an hour.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Also, very important, if you are fans of us and you don't go to our website or read the forum at all, you should at least go to our website once or twice, because we've actually got a lot of stuff going on that isn't actually an audio form.
Rym: For example, all our lectures from PAX East last year online in their entirety, as is a good chunk of our lecture from PAX Prime this year and a bunch of other videos from conventions and our other show, Radio Free Equestria.
Scott: And it's all on YouTube and also Twitter, Facebook and all the other places on the Internet.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: G+ we have a G+ thingy.
Rym: You can go and do your G+ thingies there if you have G+ thingies to do.
Rym: Our forum is an ivory tower up and above the rest.
Rym: I'm going to be straight with you.
Rym: If you can't write grammatically correctly, don't even bother trying to get into our forum because you'll get banned like that.
Rym: We are going to Magfest.
Rym: If you want a Bolt Bus ticket, they just went on sale, they're going to sell out, probably.
Scott: From New York for Thursday morning, at least.
Rym: Yeah, but if you don't live in New York.
Rym: We're going to be doing Beyond Dungeons and Dragons, second edition.
Rym: We're also going to be on two...
Scott: Why don't we do Advanced Beyond Dungeons and Dragons, not Beyond Advanced, Advance Beyond.
Rym: We're also going to be on two discussion panels.
Rym: One of them will have Dr.
Rym: Hazard to re-mus a new intellectual asshole.
Rym: So we'll be talking about money-making in games, and I forget what the other one is.
Rym: I can look into the details.
Rym: We will be at the Penny Arcade Expo East doing 2B announced panels.
Rym: We will be at Anime Boston doing 2B announced panels.
Rym: We will be this week, Thursday, December 8th, in New York City at Nerd Night NYC, which is in Dumbo.
Rym: If you don't know what Dumbo is, then you probably don't live close enough to go to this.
Scott: It costs money to go to it.
Rym: It's $14 to get in at 7PM.
Rym: To see us, but maybe you want to do nerd trivia, which not my bag, but some other people's bag.
Scott: The other two people talking are, let's see, Back to the Lectures at Hand, Cephalopods, Nature's Adorable, Amazing Abominations.
Scott: That could be maybe good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And after and then us.
Scott: And then after us, The Language of OkCupid by Bentley McBentleson.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: These are like flash lectures.
Rym: Twenty one minutes is the max we get.
Rym: For the lectures, doors open at $8.15, and that's only 10 bucks.
Rym: I'm not going to tell you to go because it's one thing, you know, you pay for a badge to PAX to see us, but it and also to get PAX.
Rym: So if Cephalopods, Adorable, Amazing Abominations and OkCupid and us seems worth 10 bucks, then go.
Rym: If it doesn't seem worth it, don't go.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I can tell you it should be fun.
Scott: It says on the website, losing should be fun.
Scott: Buy Rym to Koster.
Scott: But then in the bio, it says Rym and Scott.
Rym: Yeah, I wrote the bio.
Scott: OK, yeah.
Rym: Rym and Scott host GeekNights when they're not blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: It should be fun.
Rym: We haven't done a lot of local NYC sort of stuff, but it's pretty easy to do it.
Rym: So I started putting feelers out and we'll probably be doing more things like this in the coming future.
Scott: Brilliant.
Rym: Also, keep ConnectiCon in your hearts because it won't be that long before panel submissions go up.
Rym: And there's more announcements about ConnectiCon.
Rym: I shouldn't say yet, but they're coming.
Rym: They're coming.
Rym: So the walled garden, remember a long time ago before you had access to the Internet, you had access to a thing that was like the Internet.
Rym: Remember Prodigy, AOL, all those things?
Scott: Yeah, I had AOLs, but I had AOLs like in the 56K, well, 14.4 modem days.
Scott: I had a friend who had Prodigy on an IBM PS1, my first online experience, like maybe 2800 baud.
Scott: It was a weak ass modem.
Scott: Was with Prodigy.
Rym: And then I went to Prodigy Internet and I was on WOW for a while, but those were walled gardens.
Rym: And there is an era where, you know, other than super nerds, no one had access to the Internet.
Scott: Well, people in case people who aren't technological haven't heard the walled garden metaphor.
Scott: Basically, it's one of those metaphors that's so perfect that it sort of just become the terminology.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So a walled garden is any sort of computing environment.
Scott: That is cultivated and everything is beautiful and amazing and it's so great to be inside, but nothing goes in and nothing goes out.
Scott: So if you want to see the beautiful flowers, you have to come inside.
Scott: And if you want to take the beautiful flowers and show them to someone outside, you can't.
Scott: And, you know, AOL is a perfect example.
Scott: If you ever used AOL back in the day, right, that you could go on the Web with an AOL.
Scott: There was like IE was built into it.
Scott: But in AOL, there were keywords.
Scott: So you could go to AOL keyword something something.
Scott: And the only way to go to AOL keyword something something is if you were on AOL.
Scott: So people who didn't have AOL couldn't see anything that was posted in AOL.
Scott: And likewise, you couldn't say take a link to or some content out of an you know, that you saw on an AOL keyword page and share it outside of AOL.
Scott: It was a walled garden.
Scott: All these beautiful keyword interface thingies in AOL were only in AOL.
Scott: And there was no connection between that and the rest of the world.
Rym: Now, it's funny how some people you know, it's almost like the Berlin Wall fell and most people saw the outside and were like, oh, my God, there's an Internet.
Rym: History is nothing but Berlin Wall's falling repeatedly, but at the same time, much like if you take a chicken from a factory farm and put it free, it just kind of stands there.
Rym: How many of your grandparents and parents use the AOL icon?
Rym: And that's the Internet.
Rym: because they don't even know they they they don't realize that anything changed.
Rym: Now, the walled garden kind of had a resurgence after the Berlin Wall fell when Apple started releasing things through app stores, which I guess, according to all of Apple's lawsuits, is a shortcut for Apple and not application.
Rym: Yeah, but the metaphor still applies.
Rym: You've got this idea that you've got a locked platform and as a result, there's a curated collection of programs that run on this platform, which has a lot of pros and a lot of cons.
Rym: We're not getting into ideology yet.
Rym: We'll get to that.
Rym: But I mean, think about the cons.
Rym: I can install whatever I want.
Rym: Pro, I can't install broken bullshit that breaks my shit.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Cons, I can't install anything.
Rym: So the problem here is that Apple made the idea of the software walled garden, the app store, extremely palatable to the average person, because it is really great from the user experience perspective in most cases.
Rym: I mean, you're not going to get spyware on your iPhone.
Rym: Meanwhile, pretty much everyone I know over the age of 40 who is not a technologist has spyware on their PC, whether they know it or not.
Rym: In fact, most of the people I know who are under 40 have spyware on their PCs.
Rym: We were just at Scott Johnson's party and we identified lots of malware that appeared to be on that PC he had in the basement.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's just like, you know, every time the walled garden comes along, it's eventually destroyed and then another one comes up.
Scott: And it's weird because even though they're continually destroyed every time they appear, I don't think they are.
Scott: They're also continuously successful.
Scott: It's like AOL was wildly successful and then it failed.
Scott: And then the app store is wildly successful.
Scott: It's going to fail.
Rym: There's a big difference between those two.
Rym: back in the AOL days.
Rym: It was I mean, even I was into computers and I couldn't figure out how to get connected to the Internet.
Rym: So I got prodigy because I couldn't figure out anything else.
Rym: And I didn't know there was an Internet that was different from that.
Rym: And people, you know, were in the same boat.
Rym: But then when there were generic ISPs, people were kind of freed from these shackles.
Rym: There was the walled garden was an alternative to something that wasn't accessible to most people, which is the only reason they went to those walled gardens in the first place.
Rym: How many people outside of China willingly put themselves into an Internet walled garden today?
Rym: I mean, high schools force it on people.
Rym: Some bullshit.
Rym: colleges forces on students, by the way, never go to a college that restricts the way you use the Internet in any way.
Rym: No kidding.
Rym: It's not worth it.
Rym: RIT can do whatever you wanted on Internet.
Scott: You even had your own real real world static IP address, not like a static IP in the school.
Scott: on a on a on a land behind a net.
Rym: I missed that variable cornucopia of pirated goods.
Rym: I miss those days.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: It's basically our private piracy network.
Rym: But so now we've got this opposite situation where there are people who say, I can't deal with the freedom.
Rym: I choose to lock myself into this walled garden in hopes that the people who control the locks will let me out if I really need to get out.
Scott: Well, you know, it's people who don't go into a walled garden, right, unless it's beautiful to begin with.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's a lot of walled gardens out there that are just ugly.
Scott: So you walk in and you're like, oh, this place is all shit.
Scott: And they just leave immediately.
Rym: I mean, probably for people to go in basically like North Korea.
Rym: I was in this like horrible dingy place.
Rym: And then I looked out a window and I was like, oh, shit, there's pasture out there.
Rym: And I escaped.
Scott: But yeah, it's like, you know, so when you see a walled garden that's popular, that's because it has something in it that the rest of the world does not have.
Scott: There's some beautiful flower growing within.
Scott: that is so awesome that people are going to go in there and stay in there and love that flower so much.
Scott: You stay in that shit and be like, oh, this is the greatest.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, this flower doesn't exist outside of this garden.
Rym: And that's true.
Rym: Look at the iPhone that an interface that good doesn't exist outside of that garden.
Scott: Not on phones anyway.
Rym: Yeah, well, but just talk about phones first, because my the line where I think this is a problem is a problem is not phones, because phones as they currently stand.
Rym: I mean, there are people who buy a feature restricted or limited or weak ass phone by choice anyway in this day and age.
Rym: So I don't care if someone uses a walled garden on a device like that, because I feel like I could argue that the benefits outweigh the cons.
Rym: Everyone I know who has tried to hack their phone or has like rooted their iPhone to do something ends up breaking it.
Rym: And very few of them have done it for any benefit that I can fathom being worthwhile.
Rym: Right.
Scott: I mean, there are some benefits and there's a few little things that people do that.
Scott: I'm like, oh, that's neat.
Scott: I wish I could do that.
Scott: Like, you know, get an animated wallpaper on an iPhone, which doesn't have an animated wallpaper or more heavily customized ringtones and things of that nature, more so than you're allowed to normally change icons on things that you're normally not change icons for.
Scott: And, you know, they're just a lot of things, but it's not worth the effort.
Scott: It's not worth your phone fucking breaking.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It's like it's, you know, it would be nice if I could just have it.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not worth, you know, but
Rym: it also very elegantly, as long as the curation process of the garden, you know, the gardener is good at what they do and is willing to actually make sure that no malware gets in, that shitty apps don't get in, that it is managed in some way.
Scott: That's another thing, right?
Scott: A walled garden is not only, you know, keeping things from leaving and keeping other, you know, keeping outside things from getting in, but it's defending from the outside.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if you, you know, sometimes the world gets really dangerous and you just bombs falling from the sky and people taking analogies too far all over the place and you want to stay safe so you can hide in that walled garden while there are bombs dropping all over the motherfucker and wait until the war is over and then leave the walled garden.
Scott: And especially, you know, if the walled gardens way beautiful.
Scott: Maybe that's a good idea sometimes, but it's never good.
Scott: It's never a good long term idea.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, at the same time, the Internet, if you think bombs falling is a bad metaphor, the Internet has always been the Wild West there.
Rym: You basically even if you're savvy, you cannot be safe from malware on the Internet unless you are not only savvy, but also kind of lucky and you don't care about anything that's pop culture related.
Rym: I mean, as long as you never search for like lyrics to songs, you're probably safe from like 15 percent of the malware out there.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But so what do we do?
Rym: There are people for whom they currently do just for whatever societal problems we won't get into about education and technology don't have the ability to protect themselves from all the people out there with guns in the Wild West, the Internet.
Rym: So living in the castle, the walled castle that Steve Jobs built is probably actually the best alternative for them.
Scott: Well, it is good for them and it's also bad for them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's good for them and that it gets them something.
Scott: You know, as opposed to as opposed to just getting.
Rym: I mean, you're a peasant in the Middle Ages.
Rym: Your choices are die by bandit in the wilderness all alone and have all your stuff burned down or be a peasant shoveling shit around for some lord.
Rym: But you're not dead.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's Hokuto no Ken.
Scott: They could be a peasant and they could just get attacked by bandits all the time or they could stay in some sealed vault shelter where they're totally safe.
Scott: But, you know, it's not great living in a vault.
Scott: It kind of sucks.
Scott: Or but, you know, and living in that vault while they're safe.
Scott: And they have some food and shit.
Scott: So it's not the worst, but their potential to be the next Kenshiro is completely there's no chance.
Scott: At least if they were peasants, there's a chance for greatness.
Scott: Maybe they could be the ones who start the awesome town and, you know, are able to keep bandits at bay and have an awesome existence.
Scott: But you can't because you're in the walled garden.
Scott: You're stuck in the vault.
Rym: But anyway, let's hardware wise, cell phones are by and large fairly simple devices.
Rym: And there's very little complex functionality I want from a smartphone that I can't already get either on an iPhone, despite the fact that it's pretty closed or in my droid, which has a curated walled garden, but also has a door.
Rym: I can walk right out that fucking garden, do whatever the hell I want.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And I'm indifferent.
Rym: I don't care what people do and I don't think it's a problem.
Rym: And I'm actually kind of annoyed at the tech people who freak the fuck out that Apple is closed there, you know, not Monopoly phones, innards to people who aren't willing to go to extreme measures.
Scott: I just don't care because the thing is their garden is not so completely sealed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, the same way the AOL wasn't completely sealed.
Rym: I also don't care in that I don't care if, say, a toaster manufacturer documents the API for, you know, said confirming the firmware on the chip that toasts.
Scott: I would not mind if it was there.
Rym: I wouldn't mind if it was there.
Rym: I'm not going to not buy it if it's not there.
Rym: And if I really care, I'll probably reverse engineer that shit anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, there's there's a lot of situations where, you know, closedness is actually really awful.
Scott: So, Scott, you know, I don't want to say you are a maker in you and this and the software could have a bug, but it's closed source.
Scott: It's like I'm so I'm putting some mysterious thing in my body.
Scott: Great.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I feel like the closed source open source is a different argument, though, from the walled garden open garden.
Scott: Well, you know, but, you know, if your if your name is Richard Stallman.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's no difference.
Scott: It's like even if this is software is, you know, open and usable and you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: But the the source is closed.
Scott: Well, and it's might as well it's, you know.
Rym: But if the garden has a crack, if there's a way to write my own software, then theoretically, no matter how bad the stuff is in the garden, I can write open stuff to do the things I need.
Scott: Well, but you know what?
Scott: You can't change the dirt.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If it's open source, you can change it.
Rym: But at this point, if the dirt is your problem, if you know it's fundamental core, the dirt is your problem.
Rym: Your only real reasonable option is to find some other dirt somewhere else.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: It's called Android.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And that dirt's not that bad.
Rym: And honestly, it's pretty bad.
Rym: The only everyone I know who complains about Android, their complaints are mostly pretty fucking baseless.
Rym: They complain about things that they would like.
Rym: There are worse things on the iPhone that they don't complain about than like the tiny glitches that they run into on their heavily modded firmware hacked androids.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You can't complain about if you.
Scott: if you you know, it's like you can't complain on anything if you hacked it.
Rym: Also, half the problems I've heard people talk about Android are actually hardware problems because they brought a shitty handset.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: Here's I don't know about you, Scott, because I know you have rants about this.
Rym: We were arguing about this the other day.
Rym: But here's where I see a potential problem coming up.
Rym: It bothers me that this App Store model is moving to everything PCs that Apple computers and tablets now also have the App Store model.
Scott: Well, it's not just PCs, right?
Scott: It's even like sub.
Scott: it's like every thing has apps, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, and whether it's actually extensions or add ons or plugins, everyone's calling it apps.
Scott: So it's like Spotify is an app, but Spotify is also a platform that has apps.
Scott: It's just like calling everything an app and any, you know, and every.
Scott: every single thing is being modularized, you know, into an app.
Scott: And it's like every single thing that is an app is also a platform for apps, which is also a platform for apps.
Scott: And it's just like, you know, it's easy to think about if just the whole world, everything is an app.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you put apps and apps and normal people can sort of get that idea as opposed to where before it would be like a piece of software on an OS and the piece of software has plugins, which has configurations and extensions.
Scott: Now it's just apps and apps and apps.
Rym: Now, this is a noble goal, but my worries that, well, in a way, you know, a little too far.
Rym: All right, Scott, if I take it way too far, I can make it a noble.
Scott: So I get the Spotify app for Windows eight and then the Spotify app has apps on it.
Scott: And then, you know, next thing you know, one of those apps got what's an app.
Rym: I mean, I got I got I'm running a program and oh, it's got a class in it that does something.
Scott: Well, no, it's like a separate you know, it's like a DLC.
Rym: All the classes in a different file.
Scott: It's a DLC, basically, right.
Scott: And it presents itself user interface ways and, you know, financial buy it ways and download it ways as an application.
Rym: that doesn't bother me that much.
Rym: Now, here's why.
Rym: In my current iteration, like the biggest app store to use the generic term to further generify it, to prevent Apple from getting their stupid trademark bullshit on it is steam.
Rym: When I want to buy a game, I go to steam, I type in the name of the game and it's probably there and I pay for it and I get it right there through steam.
Rym: Steam manages all the updates, all the add ons later DLC, everything is through this thing.
Rym: But that walled garden is on my completely open garden, which is a Windows computer.
Rym: I can do whatever the fuck I want with.
Rym: My biggest fear is that if people get too used to apps, I'm not saying this will happen if they get too used to these walled gardens.
Rym: The things that we saw coming down the pipe from CBDPA a long time ago will seem impalatable to people and there might be a push toward locked down, basically destroying the idea, not of the PC, because I don't care if I have a physical PC here or wherever, anywhere, if the PC dies or not.
Rym: I care about having an open platform, whatever it may reside on, to do whatever the hell I want with.
Rym: The moment someone else can say you can't do X on that hardware, that is not, you know, that is general purpose.
Rym: We've lost a big battle when it comes to the future of technology.
Scott: Yeah, think about it.
Scott: It's like, OK, so the only apps you can install on your computer are ones that were approved by whoever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: OK, so on your phone, it doesn't really matter.
Scott: But what if it's on all computing devices?
Scott: Well, yeah, guess what?
Scott: You can't get any torrent clients.
Scott: You can't get IRC clients.
Scott: They don't install on modern computers and no one approves them.
Rym: Now, I envision a future where Apple computers by default only let you install approved apps through their app store and iTunes and whatever.
Rym: And maybe all Apple hardware.
Rym: Well, they were definitely going in that direction very slowly, which will be fine because Windows is still the majority desktop operating system.
Rym: And Windows isn't going down that road at all.
Rym: Even if they are no one, no user of Windows who actually matters, like corporate users, whatever, actually, at least in the near term, foreseeably let Windows lock it down to where they can install their proprietary bullshit, whatever it may be.
Rym: But what if in a far distant future, Apple becomes a majority or Microsoft gets dicked by some crazy legislation?
Scott: Apple's not going to become majority.
Rym: No, but what if they get such a majority of the desktop world that people stop making software that isn't business oriented for Windows?
Rym: I'm not saying it'll happen.
Rym: I'm not.
Scott: I think of anything.
Scott: Apple will only care about consumers and is basically is moving away from the like.
Scott: they don't even care about business or productivity or anything like that, which is good because they shouldn't compete over there.
Scott: They're just moving away from that.
Scott: Like they don't care.
Scott: They stop selling servers, you know, it's like they keep upgrading Xcode, but they really only want you to use Xcode to make software for Apple things.
Scott: And they want you to do, you know, office stuff.
Scott: I guess they have iWork and they want you to do media production, but they really just don't want you to do anything else with your Apple computer.
Scott: And they don't care about if it does anything else.
Scott: You know, it's like they'll sell you some games for your portable thingies, but they they're not selling you any games for OS X. They don't give a shit.
Rym: So I don't know.
Rym: I don't feel like it.
Rym: I guess the sum of this whole argument because this you know, this whole kind of meta argument and all these different levels is very important to people on the Internet right now.
Rym: Yet I don't actually see an end game in the reasonable near future.
Rym: that actually is bad.
Scott: I think you're just going to see history repeat.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Garden walls come up, then, you know, the people run inside the walls, garden walls come down, people come out, they go up, they go down.
Scott: It's over and over again.
Scott: Every bunch of years you'll see something go up and something come down.
Rym: But is there a pattern where cell phone is seen by many people?
Scott: It hasn't been going on long enough in technology to figure out what the pattern is.
Scott: All right.
Scott: We've only seen the walls go up and down a couple of times.
Rym: Here's a possible pattern.
Rym: Cell phones.
Rym: People see them as like appliances or purpose-built devices and they need them for specific things.
Rym: They need them to work reliably.
Rym: They don't need to customize them that much.
Rym: So they're cool with the walled garden there.
Rym: But they still have open computer platforms.
Rym: But what if that walled garden goes up, that little one, and no one ever leaves it because it's good enough?
Rym: Or at least the majority don't leave it.
Scott: The wall will come down eventually, always.
Rym: Will it?
Rym: What if, I mean, what are people going to be doing on their phones?
Rym: Oh, wait a minute.
Rym: What about when we have enough bandwidth and peer to peer ad hoc wireless whatever to where I'm torrenting from my phone to Scott's phone?
Scott: Because as long as...
Rym: No, Scott, I'm saying when we get to that point, then suddenly the hackers are going to open all this stuff up or people are going to leave the walled garden to do the things that Apple doesn't want them to be doing.
Scott: The reason the walled garden comes down is because eventually, right, because it's shut off from the outside world, it doesn't pollinate and evolve.
Scott: And eventually what happens is the outside world actually looks better than the garden.
Scott: And that's when people leave.
Rym: Well, Scott, but Apple had the Steve Jobs like, you know, internal development, that whole like closed system of designing things in a vacuum and and all that testing internally and the compartmentalization of development to the point that they're basically using the technique to write obscenities into the world.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Can obscenities made by the technique compete with evolution in the long term?
Rym: Like maybe it's possible.
Rym: So far they have.
Rym: So far, what Apple has created on its own has surpassed anything everyone else in the world has ever done in terms of phone interface.
Scott: If you wait until right now, the major problem is the fact that there there's this physical lockdown.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When it came to like AOL, there really wasn't this physical stranglehold.
Scott: So of the carriers.
Scott: So you're going to see eventually, you know, once, you know, right now Moore's law, the CPU speed doesn't matter.
Scott: What matters is, you know, the wireless, the spectrum and the antennas and stuff.
Scott: Eventually that will break when the technology is sufficiently advanced and people won't need carriers anymore.
Scott: And then, you know, the closed off carrier phones are just going to be hosed by the open phones would just be so amazing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And then and that's I think where we'll see the walled garden break.
Scott: That's only the phone walled garden.
Rym: I don't know, but I'm saying the phone walled garden would have been the most resistant one.
Scott: But it just happens to be the current one.
Rym: when technology enables behaviors that governments or large corporations don't want.
Rym: Like, for example, I'm torrenting and pirating between phones directly all the time.
Rym: That won't work through the app store.
Rym: But everyone who has an open phone is going to be doing it.
Rym: And eventually, you know, Joey Jojo, you know, the 14 year old goes to his friend and says, hey, how come I can't watch the ultra porn that you're streaming?
Rym: And you say, well, because you're using an Apple lockdown phone.
Rym: He says, oh, really?
Rym: How do I get a non lockdown phone?
Rym: Just like back in the day when I was a little kid.
Rym: and I said, hey, Billy, how are you downloading all these goddamn games for free?
Rym: And he said, see this?
Rym: This is a BBS.
Rym: Anything goes.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.