Rym: It's Monday, February 14th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, IBM's Watson.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Perhaps Dr.
Rym: Watson?
Scott: No.
Rym: No?
Rym: You sure?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You remember that on Windows 3.1?
Rym: I do remember that on Windows 3.1.
Scott: That didn't even do anything.
Scott: It was just like you would run it and a little doctor would appear and that didn't do anything.
Rym: Of course, actually the first version of Windows I ever had was Windows 3.1.1 with networking.
Scott: The first one I had was just 3.1.
Rym: Oh, did you upgrade?
Rym: No.
Scott: It's a 95.
Rym: Man, I stood in line and bought Windows 2000 like right when it came out.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't do that.
Rym: That was the last time I bought any software at a store, I think.
Scott: I bought Windows 98 SE at a store, but then I bought it online.
Rym: Well, that and Tribes 2 I bought in a store.
Scott: Yeah, but I've actually bought Tribes 2 online.
Rym: Yeah, I bought it in a store because I did not buy it.
Rym: I did not have the money when it came out and you got it.
Scott: In fact, you bought it for me and then you gave me the copy and then I gave you the money.
Rym: Yep, and then realizing the mistake of having not bought it, I forewent food in order to afford my own copy.
Scott: You had a meal plan by then.
Rym: Yeah, I had a meal plan, but it was all debit and I spent it all on coffee and ice cream.
Scott: Why didn't you spend it at Gracie's?
Rym: I was very happy to be done with Gracie's.
Scott: You needed food.
Rym: Plus, all debit.
Rym: A Gracie's dinner was like 20 bucks.
Scott: Well, with all debit it was.
Scott: I think it was 14.
Rym: I'm thinking about busting out the rollerblades, going back to work outside.
Scott: Do not do.
Scott: Do not, because as soon as you do that, the snow is going to just appear.
Rym: See, the thing is, the rollerblades are safe.
Rym: With a bike, if I commit to biking to work, I'm fucked if it gets cold.
Rym: If it gets cold, I can just take off the rollerblades and get on the subway.
Scott: That's not a bad strategy.
Rym: So I don't think winner.
Scott: I'm not, you know, while that might be a safe bet for you, like you test the weather in the morning and then blade to work real fast.
Scott: While it might be a safe bet, you may, you still, whether you can blade to work or not, you don't want to risk it being cold again.
Scott: So you don't want to tempt the weather guy.
Rym: Yeah, but I feel like rollerblades are not quite as prominent as a bike.
Rym: A woman might not see me.
Scott: No, they'll see.
Scott: They see everything.
Scott: It's like trying to hide.
Scott: If you try to set up a Tetris, the Tetris guy will be like,
Scott: "Oh.".
Rym: Line piece.
Scott: L.
Rym: Reverse squiggly.
Scott: Alright, he blocked it up.
Scott: Line piece.
Scott: The weather guy is the same evil guy.
Scott: The same pantheon of evil guys.
Rym: There's something up.
Rym: We've been referencing the Tetris guy a lot lately.
Scott: Because the pantheon of evil guys have been making their works lately.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: Though there's a, I know you're still the sheriff, but times they are a-changin'.
Scott: How are they changin'?
Rym: Let's see how today's combat goes.
Scott: We're not playing combat.
Rym: Combat in Outlaw.
Rym: What we do in Outlaw is in fact combat.
Scott: Combat has tanks.
Scott: Outlaw has pretzels.
Rym: It's the trouble with Atari games.
Rym: They have names like hockey, football, shooting.
Scott: They also have names like Solar Jetman.
Scott: Solar Fox.
Rym: Solar Jetman, however, was an awesome game.
Rym: Not that awesome of a game.
Rym: My grandpa really liked that one, though.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Rym: There's kind of big news, so I figure we can talk about that.
Rym: I believe it was your news.
Scott: Was it?
Scott: Alright, yeah.
Scott: The most gigantic-est tech news of the whole week that people are pooping all over because it affects things in like 30 different areas.
Scott: Almost as big as the Oracle Sun news.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: To this day, I can think of a few.
Rym: I mean, when the DMCA passed, when Oracle and Sun had sex, are some of the darkest days I can remember.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So now it's Nokia and Microsoft.
Rym: Together at last.
Scott: Right, so problem number one, right?
Scott: Well, step number one was Nokia was pretty much king of the world in cell phones.
Scott: Mostly because their candy bar phone took the world by storm.
Scott: Just regular old phones, right?
Scott: And they had Symbian phones and such out and about in the world before anyone else really had smartphones.
Rym: Yeah, they were basically like top of the line, super nice mobile phones.
Scott: It was pretty much, right?
Scott: You had Windows, the original Windows Mobile, which is terrible.
Scott: You had the original, you know, the Blackberries, and they were, you know, they haven't changed that much.
Scott: It's kind of funny that they haven't.
Scott: And you had Palm, the Trios, and those were the smartphones, right?
Scott: And just, you know, even though they were almost as functional as the ones we had the Androids and iPhones we have now, they really just, they didn't take the world by storm.
Scott: It was pretty much big time business users and nerds using them.
Scott: They weren't that much more expensive than they are now.
Rym: Yeah, but they were expensive compared to, you know, the landlines that most people had.
Scott: I guess, yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: I mean, when a cell phone itself is a luxury, the smart cell phone with the data is going to be a lot more, anyway.
Scott: And you had Symbian OS, right?
Scott: Which was, you know, probably the most open of them, except for maybe the Palm one, right?
Scott: And, you know, it actually worked pretty well in its day.
Scott: And you could get phones with it that weren't necessarily, you know, like crazy expensive phones.
Scott: You can get Symbian on sort of like weaker phones for reasonable prices.
Scott: So it was, you know, it had all the abilities of, you know, I guess to qualify as a smartphone.
Scott: It's pretty much just a phone that you can install software on, which is why Symbian counts as, I guess, a smartphone OS or whatever.
Scott: So Symbian was actually incredibly popular all around the world, not so much in the U.S.
Scott: where Nokia could never really get its phones carried by any of the carriers.
Scott: But everywhere else in the world, you know, Symbian was kind of huge.
Scott: I remember people were using like those, you know, Nokia like N97, whatever phones those were.
Scott: And they were doing like, you know, kick and streaming video and stuff, right?
Scott: You know, and Symbian was huge.
Scott: But now that it's been like two years or so with the iPhone, two or three years with the iPhone and, you know, Android for a couple of years, Nokia really fell off the bus and they didn't advance their shit.
Scott: They started making like the phones that had like ridiculous horsepower, but the software was poop.
Scott: And, you know, they just they weren't keeping up.
Scott: And there was, you know, even in the rest of the world where Nokia could, you know, was sold and popular, they were losing on the bottom end because some Chinese people were making, you know, better cheap phones.
Scott: And they were losing on the high end because Android phones were doing better than Nokia phones.
Rym: So what's a company to do?
Scott: Well, the CEO proved that he was not a moron.
Scott: I was quite impressed.
Scott: He sent out this letter.
Scott: that's on a gadget.
Scott: And the letter is basically like, look, we're on fire and we're throwing gas on the fire.
Scott: It's like, you know, we're basically years behind the competition.
Scott: We need to do something, right?
Scott: And Nokia was doing on paper some stuff that was looking good.
Scott: They were investing in this sort of, you know, Linux platform with like, you know, Migo, which is, you know, a Linux smartphone OS and stuff like that.
Scott: And they bought Trolltech, which makes QT, which is an open source GUI library that, you know, is used on KDE on the Linux desktop.
Scott: And, you know, they were.
Scott: they were, you know, pushing in that right direction, I guess philosophically with the open source Linuxness.
Scott: But the reality was that they totally failed to actually produce something that had, A, the functionality, B, the smooth hardware, and C, good interface or usable in any actual way.
Scott: It was just these horrible, you know, phones that weren't any cheaper and were many times actually more expensive.
Rym: I think what really hurt is that they weren't used to competing with the kinds of companies you have to compete with in the modern smartphone market.
Rym: I mean, they were used to competing with, you know, other crappy cell phone manufacturers.
Scott: Yeah, like Motorola and HTC.
Rym: And then now they've got to compete with, you know, Microsoft and Google and Apple.
Scott: Well, now HP, because inside news, HP's finally gotten rid of the word Palm forever, and it's now just HP.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Meanwhile, there are no updates to web OS and no apps.
Rym: So my pre is still pretty goddamn useless.
Scott: Anyway, the right.
Scott: So what Nokia has done here, right, is they said, all right, look, you know, we can't be like, you know, let's stop throwing gas on the fire.
Scott: What we'll do is Apple, obviously, we can't do anything with them.
Scott: They're not going to let us put iOS in a Nokia phone.
Scott: That's not going to happen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We could just install Android on Nokia phones.
Rym: And be, you know, one among many generic Android phones that no one would seek out.
Scott: So what, you know, so what we're going to do is we'll partner with Microsoft.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And we'll get the Windows Phone 7 on some Nokia phones.
Scott: So maybe if we, you know, can combine, you know, even though Microsoft's mobile OS isn't so popular, it's still got something going on.
Rym: I would call the Windows Phone 7 a huge kind of unpredictable dark horse in the cell phone market because it's the only one that's different.
Rym: But at the same time, no one seems to care about it.
Rym: And it's not doing anything different enough to make anyone say, oh, I want one of those.
Rym: It didn't penetrate the enterprise market because BlackBerry still got that locked down.
Rym: It's not penetrating the normal user because they're going to either get an Apple or whatever their cell phone company gives it.
Scott: And if the iPhone.
Scott: nano rumors are true, that's the end.
Scott: Game over.
Rym: Meanwhile, this weird aside that, you know, I've got my pre and my contracts running out and I'm looking at phones.
Rym: And I was poking at pretty much every Android phone that Verizon or Sprint has available.
Rym: And I was also poking at iPhones.
Rym: And WebOS has fucking ruined me.
Rym: I hate every other interface on every phone.
Scott: Really?
Scott: They just feel sluggish.
Scott: What's sluggish about the iPhone?
Rym: The iPhone doesn't feel sluggish.
Rym: The Androids all feel sluggish.
Rym: Yeah, they do.
Rym: The iPhone feels restricting, but I think part of it is that I have this visceral feel.
Rym: I'm so used to, I've got these cards all over the place and I just flick them off the top of the screen and flick them around.
Rym: And not being able to do that keeps messing me up in a big way.
Scott: Yeah, I guess, you know, you just got to double tap the home button and you slide on the bottom.
Rym: I guess it's hard to tell at this juncture how much of that is me being used to.
Scott: That's just a used to thing.
Rym: It's hard to tell if it's a used to thing or if it is just a clearly better interface.
Rym: Uh, whatever.
Rym: Because I do feel like there are things WebOS does that are better than everyone else.
Scott: Well, yeah, like integrating all the mails properly.
Rym: Oh my god, the fact that that just works still amazes me.
Rym: But I think Windows, you know, in my tradition of getting the phone that ends up being the minority shit phone, I think Windows 7 phone is going to be where I might go.
Rym: You know, to counterbalance.
Scott: It does some Xbox stuff.
Scott: Yeah, they might need that.
Scott: But I think, you know, if Nokia partners with Microsoft, well, they did partner with Microsoft, right?
Rym: I wouldn't bet any money on that partnership.
Scott: No, but if they can somehow get the magic of the software with, Microsoft has generally failed at hardware, with Nokia hardware that somehow makes, if they somehow make a not sucky hardware, they might go somewhere.
Scott: Especially in the rest of the world.
Scott: I think it could do well in places like India where Microsoft is still, you know, so powerful.
Scott: Or even South Korea.
Rym: I think what they should really gun for is the destroying the BlackBerry market.
Rym: Because BlackBerry is not, like, it's only powerful and existent today due to the fact that most enterprises are too afraid to drop it.
Rym: They've got too much invested in it.
Rym: Yet, most people hate their Blackberries unless they're people who never had a smartphone and the company gave them a BlackBerry.
Scott: Blackberries is one of the only ones who can attack.
Scott: You know, they pretty much eat, the BlackBerry stronghold has pretty much been eaten away at as much as it can be eaten away at.
Scott: To kill the rest, the only one who can kill the rest is Microsoft because they have Outlook.
Scott: And the companies aren't going to give up Outlook.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: So they're pretty much only choices are Blackberries or, right?
Rym: If Microsoft can come in with a Nokia phone and they have a huge kind of enterprise suite of, check it out, just turn this on, auto-migration from BlackBerry Enterprise server to an Outlook, Enterprise, Windows 7 phone, whatever server, they would destroy Rym almost overnight.
Scott: The thing is, iPhones and Androids can also do all that exchange stuff.
Rym: Yeah, but that doesn't matter.
Rym: The technological reality.
Scott: I see a lot of people who switch from BlackBerry to Android.
Rym: Yeah, that's such a tiny minority of the Enterprise market.
Rym: Because the only reason people use BlackBerry is that suits think that BlackBerry is safe, and they're right to a degree.
Rym: If Rym gets compromised, the entire industry, whatever your industry is, was compromised at the same time.
Rym: So you have no culpability.
Rym: But if you're using Android phones and you set up your own security, and there's a security problem, you're not going to get blamed.
Scott: No, because the thing is, BlackBerry actually has its own server, the BlackBerry Enterprise server that you have to install on your company's machine.
Scott: And the thing is, that goes next to the exchange server.
Scott: So now you've actually created two points of failure.
Scott: If you use Android or Apple or iPhone or Windows, they just connect directly to the exchange server with ActiveSync.
Scott: So actually, you're just removing the BlackBerry server entirely, and you have the same point of failure exchange that you had before.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not talking about point of failure.
Rym: I'm talking about, say there was a breach, like a user lost their phone.
Rym: And before you could wipe it out remotely from your server, delete all the data, encrypt it or whatever, someone got some data.
Rym: If you're using a BlackBerry, you can pretty much get away with saying, "We were using best of breed.
Rym: We used BlackBerry, and we got compromised
Rym: anyway.".
Rym: If you're not using that, people could come after you saying, "Why aren't you using what the rest of your sector is
Rym: using?".
Rym: That's the kind of bullshit that shareholders and suits will do.
Rym: Also, most people who are in the position to make the decisions don't realize that they can set things up like that.
Rym: They think that BlackBerry is the only way to have a phone.
Rym: that's a company phone that they can remotely wipe out if you lose it.
Scott: Sounds like they didn't hire any tech people.
Rym: No, it's because they don't listen to the tech people.
Rym: BlackBerry's got the market locked down, and they think BlackBerry is the market.
Rym: So Microsoft is the only one that has enough clout to say, "Look, we're enterprise.
Rym: You use Outlook.
Rym: We'll handle it just the same as Rym
Rym: does.".
Scott: The thing that really gets me about this Microsoft Nokia deal, and I'm not going to make any predictions or anything like that.
Scott: There were some deals with the Nokia employees who work on software getting pissed because they're basically throwing all their work away.
Rym: I predict non-newsworthy, mediocre success.
Scott: What I think is the real big issue here is something I think is a bigger issue in the world as a whole.
Scott: You look at this deal and look at the money behind this deal.
Scott: And basically the situation here is Nokia not to look so good.
Scott: So a bunch of money comes from Microsoft to Nokia, so now they look so good.
Scott: Because Microsoft paid them a bajillion dollars for this deal.
Scott: But that money doesn't come from customers.
Scott: It came from Microsoft.
Scott: And I think what's happening, I can see it at my company and a lot of other companies in the world.
Scott: They're sitting there doing their business.
Scott: And some other company comes along and says, "We will give you X dollars to do
Scott: this.".
Scott: But whatever this is, is not necessarily good for employees and/or customers.
Rym: Oh hell no!
Rym: It's good for the company that's paying for it.
Scott: But you look at the balance sheet and you say, "Okay, maybe somebody... Microsoft is going to pay us this much to use their OS.
Scott: That will lose us ex-customers.
Scott: The money they are paying us is more than the money we will lose by losing those
Scott: ex-customers.".
Scott: And it's good on the balance sheet.
Scott: So in a short term balance sheet decision, how could you not do that?
Scott: But in the long term, you're killing your brand.
Scott: You're doing all these other hard... You're making your software... You're doing something bad.
Rym: And thus the kind of endgame of large corporations and investment.
Rym: Where the real customers of a company in the end are the shareholders who want short to medium term gains.
Scott: Right, but look at companies such as Apple.
Scott: Apple doesn't do shit like that.
Scott: Apple's not going to be like, "Okay, you paid us two billion dollars so we're going to put your ugly ass icon on the
Scott: iPhone.".
Rym: Do you want to know why Apple doesn't do stuff like that?
Rym: Because they're already making money.
Rym: Successful companies don't do it.
Rym: The ones that are failing are the ones that end up in these situations.
Scott: Right, but it's basically a stupid move because all you're doing is prolonging your death.
Rym: Yes, which is exactly what you want to do.
Rym: That is the best interest for the shareholders.
Rym: You keep the company afloat and looking like it's profitable for as long as possible.
Scott: No, what you want to do is you want to actually start actually caring about the customers.
Scott: And then in the short term there might even be a loss, but in the long term you might actually compete and win out.
Rym: And Scott, in some cases shareholders can sue the board of directors and the company saying that you're not acting in their self-interest.
Scott: Which is why you shouldn't make a company public.
Scott: Ah, ding ding ding ding ding ding.
Scott: But anyway, right?
Rym: I would say there's one other thing going on here, and this is kind of a tangent so I won't dwell on it.
Rym: A lot of the things, the differences between the three or four cell platforms we have, especially in UI, are only different due to the fact that everyone has patent encumbering bullshit on their things.
Rym: And there's that huge clusterfuck of everybody can sue everybody at any time over everything.
Rym: So if one OS will have a good feature or a good thing and no one else can use that because there's a patent on it.
Rym: Even though it's a fairly obvious thing.
Rym: And if we really relaxed or broke down these software and UI patents, I feel like there would be a rapid convergence toward the good decisions.
Rym: And I think a lot of the fake innovation that's going on in the companies that are doing so well, not saying that what Nokia is doing is fake innovation, but the situations like that, is that because they can't attack directly because of patents, they basically have to go in all the directions that everyone else said will fail because that's all that's left.
Rym: So very briefly, talking about IPOs and companies doing things, Pandora is filing for an IPO for whatever reason.
Rym: What do they need the capital for?
Rym: What are they going to do?
Rym: Online radio is...
Scott: First of all, they're behind Last.fm technology-wise and music-wise.
Scott: But Last.fm is now charging for mobile access and some other things, so that kills them, right?
Rym: Ah, but mobile access means less and less for me, because I listen mostly when I'm sedentary at a computer.
Scott: Right, but Grooveshark is killing them both, and Spotify kills everybody.
Rym: Spotify is the second highest source of income for record labels in Europe, but Spotify isn't available in the U.S But at the same time, it's all the weird cyclical problem that TV has, too, where, like, how does Pandora make money?
Rym: They have to pay for everything they stream.
Rym: Last.fm, too.
Scott: They sell ads on Pandora.
Rym: Yes, they sell ads, but at the same time, do those ads even work?
Rym: Is it just another kind of advertising model propping up a dying industry?
Rym: What are they going to do?
Rym: What could they possibly use $100 million for to make Pandora better?
Scott: Maybe what they'll do is they'll just take the $100 million and then quit.
Rym: And then everyone's going to sell their stock and get the hell away.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, "Shit, Pandora's starting to lose money.
Scott: This is never going to be successful.
Scott: Let's get a bunch of money and
Scott: leave.".
Rym: Well, do you want to be a king or do you want to be rich?
Rym: And if you're in the online music industry, you pretty much want to be rich.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Spotify is already the king.
Rym: I mean, I used to use Pandora.
Rym: I stopped because they played ads.
Scott: And because it's the same music over and over again?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it'd be fine.
Rym: And then, like, one techno song would, like, break in.
Rym: Like, "Oh, it played a techno
Rym: song.".
Rym: And then it was nothing but Darude for, like, an hour.
Rym: Also, they played an ad.
Rym: And I was like, "What the fuck is
Rym: this?".
Rym: And I stopped using it and I started using Last.fm just because I never heard ads on Last.fm.
Scott: Well, Last.fm is actually owned by CVS, which is why they're starting to charge money.
Scott: It's a Hulu situation.
Rym: Ah, but while they charge money for the app, they don't charge money for the browser and ads.
Scott: Not yet.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: if they do?
Rym: I'm not going to use them anymore.
Scott: You know what I've been using is I've just been going to listen to traditional, like, shoutcast streaming music servers on my iPhone.
Scott: And on my computer.
Rym: I also dip into my substantial music collection and occasionally go to the Pirate Bay.
Rym: And if I really want to hear a specific song, like, right now, and it's not a song that needs the high quality, I just go to YouTube, listen to it, and then I'm good.
Rym: I'm set.
Rym: I heard the song, got it, out of my head.
Rym: So, I don't know where the online music streaming industry is going to go, but I feel like the whole thing is destined for this gigantic, long-term disaster.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It doesn't help that the law is not really helping them out, you know, making them pay royalties and other bullshit.
Rym: Oh, so they shouldn't pay royalties at all?
Scott: Huh?
Rym: No royalties at all?
Rym: What should they do?
Rym: What's bad about the law?
Scott: It's about the numbers in the law are the problem.
Rym: Oh, the statutory royalties, you mean?
Scott: Yeah, you know, every once in a while it comes around and it's like, you know, "Oh, they're trying to kill streaming music on the internet
Scott: again!".
Scott: And that's happened like two or three times so far.
Rym: The thing is, I hope they do kill streaming music on the internet, because then they will kill themselves, and you know what's going to be left?
Rym: Jamendo!
Rym: But anyway, things of the day!
Rym: You know what Detroit needs, according to the internet?
Scott: Uh, people.
Scott: To live there.
Rym: There was a tweet, and someone said something to the effect of, "You know what Detroit needs right now?
Rym: They need
Rym: Robocop.".
Rym: And apparently, Mer Bing responded to that tweet, saying that they had no plans to make a Robocop statue, you know, there's a little conversation.
Rym: And then a Kickstarter got started to build a life-size, ultra-realistic statue of Robocop in Detroit.
Rym: And in four days, they have raised over $18,000.
Scott: How much does it cost to make a Robocop statue?
Rym: That is 35% of the project.
Scott: What's the rest?
Rym: 35% of it is $18,000.
Rym: Whoa, what?
Scott: I thought you said that the statue would cost 35% of the $18,000.
Rym: No, they raised $18,000.
Rym: How much the fuck is a statue?
Rym: What's it made out of?
Rym: It's got metal.
Scott: You can definitely build multiple Robocop statues.
Rym: No, high quality statues that are going to last and look good are very expensive.
Rym: You need to get an artist to make it.
Scott: You can definitely do it for less than $18,000.
Rym: Also the land, the permanent maintenance, you know, all those things.
Rym: I mean, statues cost money.
Scott: It sits there in the park.
Rym: How much do you think the Sentinel cost at RIT?
Scott: Didn't cost RIT anything because other people paid for it.
Scott: And that's gigantic and it requires cranes and construction and shit.
Scott: A Robocop is the size of a person.
Scott: You can make it in your studio.
Scott: And then you have to pay for a truck to drive it to the park.
Rym: I don't think you understand what's actually involved in making a statue like that.
Rym: Anyway, I think this is cool and I actually donated some money to it.
Rym: Well, I pledged some money.
Rym: I'm part of it.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: And my favorite comment on this whole thing, someone on Twitter was like, "Yeah, I can kick that statue of Rocky Balboa's
Rym: ass.".
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: Philly sucks.
Rym: Plus Detroit, look, you've got a statue of Rocky Balboa.
Rym: You know what we have?
Rym: We have a statue of Joe Louis's fist.
Rym: Just his fist.
Rym: It's bigger than you can imagine.
Rym: It's just hanging with a fist and a little bit of a wrist coming off of it.
Scott: The Rocky statue's in Philly, not Detroit.
Rym: I know.
Scott: You said Detroit.
Rym: No.
Rym: Yeah, because in Detroit we have a statue of Joe Louis's fist.
Scott: No, before that you said Detroit.
Scott: What you got?
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So?
Scott: So what?
Rym: You've got a thing of the day?
Scott: Oh, that was a thing of the day?
Scott: I didn't realize you did things of the day already.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So last week on Monday night I went to this Hack and Tell thing, which I've been going to.
Scott: It's been going on for six months.
Scott: It's like a little, you know, there's one in New York and I think there's one in California now that just started.
Scott: Basically you meet there and some nerds spend five minutes showing you something they made and then it's like show and tell, but it's something you hacked, right?
Scott: So this one kid, he gets up there and he's like, here's Madden 2011 for the Xbox, right?
Scott: He plays it online against people and he doesn't win all the time.
Scott: He wins rarely.
Scott: His record was pretty bad.
Scott: So he found a way to cheat that won't get him kicked off Xbox Live.
Scott: And it's his little blog post that tells you exactly how to cheat and always win at Madden.
Scott: And here's what he does.
Scott: Apparently, when you're Xbox, right, once you're playing Madden against somebody, the packets actually go directly between your Xbox and their Xbox, right?
Scott: So he puts on the Wireshark on a computer, right?
Scott: And then he can see the IP address of his opponent by looking at the packets from the Xbox.
Rym: If this ends and you playing a game with a stranger online and while they're about to do something, you call their cell phone.
Scott: Right, no.
Scott: And then as soon as he plays and he tries to win, but if he's going to lose, what he does is...
Rym: Is he in flood?
Scott: Yeah, he just goes to a computer that he has on a hosting account.
Scott: So it's not coming from his IP, it's coming from out on the internet.
Scott: And he has a really simple, it's pretty much while true, send a UDP packet to...
Rym: I'm going to make an admission.
Rym: When I used to play Action Quake back in the day in high school, I would occasionally sin-flood the IPs of people that I was trying to beat.
Scott: Right, so basically what it does is it just destroys the other person's router or their Xbox directly and then they disconnect.
Scott: And then as soon as they've disconnected, Madden gives you a choice of... You know, they disconnected.
Scott: Either I win or the game doesn't count.
Scott: Because you're still connected, you get to choose.
Scott: So basically if he plays against someone who is a jerk, he's like, "I
Scott: win.".
Rym: Alright.
Scott: Right, so like one guy was running up the score on him and was winning by a whole lot and was pulling an onside kick and all sorts, you know, basically trying to run up the score before.
Scott: So he's just like, "Yeah, I
Scott: win.".
Scott: And he hasn't been banned or anything from Xbox because there's no way for them to know him.
Scott: Because there just happened to be a DOS coming from some other IP address.
Rym: See, the funny thing is that's the kind of bullshit you'd expect from PC gaming where people would also expect it, but using a technique like that against a console gamer is like punching a baby in the face.
Scott: Yeah, he says once, usually people don't have voice chats.
Scott: You know, most people don't, so you can't really hear their reaction.
Scott: But once he said the voice chat was on and he heard something sort of along the lines of, "Oh no!
Scott: Oh
Scott: no!"
Scott: Before it cut out, obviously.
Rym: But before we get to the main bit, of course, the meta moment, we are going to be at PAX East doing five panels in three panel rooms.
Rym: We will have our combined panel schedule of us and all the other good panels, at least the panels that are done by friends of ours.
Rym: And we'll put them online for your PAX planning, perusal pleasure.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: The weekend after that, we will be at Zenkai Con doing a whole bunch of panels on Saturday.
Rym: Surprisingly, we're doing a bunch of gaming panels.
Rym: In fact, we're doing the kind of gaming panels that we've done at previous PAXes and then retired.
Rym: So, if you can't make it to PAX, come to Zenkai Con.
Scott: Why don't you let us do our interesting new panels?
Scott: Always reprising the old panels.
Rym: Well, we're doing actually a new panel there because you might remember our first debut PAX panel many years ago was Beyond Dungeons & Dragons.
Rym: We've come a long way since then and despite the fact that we retired that panel years ago, it's probably the most requested thing we've ever done.
Rym: So, we've rewritten it and we have a new version that we're going to test out at Zenkai Con and we're probably going to do it at the next PAX Prime.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: Anyway, so other meta things.
Rym: The Book Club book is still Michio Kaku's hyperspace that Scott has to finish reading.
Scott: I'm going to start reading it.
Scott: I'm going to start with chapter two today.
Scott: Also, you should go to our website.
Scott: Also, you should go to the forum and the Twitter and there's an unofficial IRC and, you know, Facebook and every internet thing.
Scott: Look for us and friend us and join us and grab us.
Rym: Also, a shout out.
Rym: We go to these Nerd NYC board game nights once a month and due to our repeated calls, many awesome listeners have showed up and hung out and played games with us.
Rym: So, mad props to all of you.
Rym: Not one of you has smelled.
Scott: I also want to point out one thing, right?
Scott: Apparently, because any tweet on Twitter that has the word GeekNights in it, I see it, so I learn all about the Oxford GeekNights, which has nothing to do with us.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But also, it seems like there is some internet radio station, you know, just like I said in the beginning of the show, the old school shoutcast style, right?
Scott: Named Tune Radio.
Rym: I know them.
Rym: They've emailed us a million times asking for permission and things and I've always ignored them.
Scott: Right, so basically, they broadcast GeekNights at some time.
Scott: I don't even know when, but GeekNights, they put it up on their station, which is absolutely okay.
Rym: Yes, GeekNights is under a Creative Commons attribution license.
Scott: Yeah, so they put GeekNights on their radio station.
Rym: We're not even non-commercial.
Rym: You can do whatever the fuck you want with GeekNights.
Rym: Right.
Rym: As long as you say it's ours.
Scott: Right, so it doesn't look like they're not saying it's ours.
Rym: They cut out, it's like, "It's September 24th, 2011.
Rym: I'm
Rym: Joe.".
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I guess if you like shoutcast and you want to listen to GeekNights days after it comes out, you can listen to it on Tune Radio, but I just want to make sure that people know that it's not something we're doing.
Scott: There's no partnership between us.
Scott: It's just they're taking advantage of our liberal Creative Commons license.
Rym: I'll put it straight up.
Rym: If you ever run into any GeekNights thing that is not on frontrowcrew.com, it is not official and we don't care.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Well, I guess my Google checkout is not technically on frontrowcrew.com, but the e-commerce itself is.
Scott: If you want to make a GeekNights, you know, merchandise, if you want to make a GeekNights, you know...
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: The trademark for GeekNights, you will need a license from us if you want to use our trademark logos for things, but that's a separate issue.
Rym: Don't worry about that.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, you know, if you want to do GeekNights unofficial wiki or whatever, just go for it.
Rym: So tonight on that TV thing that none of us seem to have anymore.
Scott: Actually, I do have it because it's on network TV, isn't it?
Rym: I have no idea what channel Jeopardy is on.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's on ABC.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I've never in my life watched an entire episode of Jeopardy.
Rym: Really?
Scott: We used to have Jeopardy on on the tiny TV in the kitchen during dinner.
Rym: I guess part of it is that as a kid, I did Quiz Bowl in high school.
Rym: So whenever I watched Jeopardy, I just was amazed at the fact that you couldn't buzz in before he finished talking.
Rym: And it seems so arbitrary that, you know, you can't buzz in until he utters the last syllable.
Rym: And I don't know, that bothered me.
Scott: Well, that's actually from what everyone tells me and from what you read on the Internet, right?
Rym: It's because people watching would hate it otherwise.
Scott: Almost all the people on Jeopardy, right?
Scott: Almost all the contestants, at least the good ones, they know the answer to almost every clue, right?
Scott: Almost all the time, right?
Scott: You know, people like Ken Jennings, they just know every clue.
Scott: And winning and losing Jeopardy isn't about whether you know the clue or not.
Scott: It's about buzzing in.
Scott: And the way it works is there is a producer or someone that you can't see that manually activates the buzzers at a certain time.
Scott: So ringing in first, because you try to ring in early, it'll like disable you for a little bit.
Scott: So you can't just jam the button Nintendo finger, right?
Scott: So you basically have to either psychologically figure out when the producer is going to activate his buzzer and activate immediately after him and get a feel for the system.
Scott: That's how to win at.
Scott: Jeopardy is basically to figure out the buzzer system, which makes me wonder, right?
Scott: This Watson computer that's going to be playing Jeopardy, how does it buzz in?
Rym: I couldn't find anything on that, actually.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And not only how does it buzz in, but sometimes on Jeopardy, they'll be like, "Can you be more specific because you're almost
Scott: right?".
Scott: So they can't say no yet, you know?
Rym: I guess the real reason I'm pretty sure, at least for the buzzing in, is that TV audiences are not going to enjoy a show where it's like, "This drug found recently to cure...".
Rym: And someone buzzes in and is like thalidomide.
Scott: Especially because they can read it on the little screen in front of them, you know, the clue.
Scott: And I can read the clue faster than Alex Trebek reads it.
Rym: In fact, in Quiz Bowl, I remember this great moment when it was kind of down to this championship round.
Rym: We were in the semifinals or whatever, and the question was, "This Roman...".
Rym: And Arnold on my team buzzed in, and he was like, "Emperor
Rym: Claudius."
Rym: He just totally guessed a Roman emperor.
Rym: And it was right.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's not that many.
Scott: Odds are good.
Rym: Jeopardy always seemed kind of wussy to me as a result.
Rym: But anyway, the IBM Watson computer is going to be playing Jeopardy.
Rym: I don't know how I feel about that.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, on the one hand, it's like, "Well, it's just going to
Scott: win.".
Scott: Nobody can beat it, especially with the buzzing... Who knows what the buzzing in situation is like?
Scott: But I do wonder how it handles certain special cases, right?
Scott: Not only the "be more specific," but also like, "Okay, so it tries to ring in, and someone else rings in, so it knows not to try to ring in anymore.
Scott: But what if that person gets it
Scott: wrong?".
Scott: Then you have another opportunity to ring in, right?
Scott: And then how does it know what to wager when there's like a double Jeopardy or whatever?
Scott: it is where you can, you know... Or what does it do when there's one of those video questions where it's not just a regular question, but they have some celebrity on videos doing something?
Scott: Like, can it do that too?
Scott: Or can it handle the final Jeopardy, right?
Scott: It's like...
Rym: See, I feel like the way to make this legit, it should have to watch the videos through a camera.
Scott: Yeah, I think it should have to have a physical clamp on the buzzer, and it should have to have a camera, and it should have to have a microphone.
Rym: I couldn't find any info on this.
Rym: I'll bet a human handler's gonna ring in on its behalf, or some BS like that.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know how it works.
Scott: But at least the part that gets the answers, right?
Scott: It's basically just using the internet, right?
Rym: I mean, kind of a Wolfram, Alpha/Google.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, at least a human intelligence.
Rym: You can answer any question ever asked on Jeopardy within about five seconds of seeing it if you've got Google in front of you.
Rym: But the tricky part, I think, would not be finding where the answer is necessarily, but being able to, based on the question, figure out what noun it's actually asking for.
Scott: Yeah, it's like...
Rym: It's an interesting problem, actually, and I'm kind of ambivalent.
Rym: I think it'll win, but I think the only reason I think that is because I know that IBM would not put it forth if they had not tested it thoroughly internally and see it win.
Scott: Well, I mean, this thing isn't exactly the most expensive.
Scott: It's not like a super-duper computer, right?
Scott: It's just a bunch of Power7 servers, which are about a year old.
Rym: A real test would be three contestants -- Ken Jennings, me with Google, and Watson.
Scott: Well, it is Ken Jennings and another guy who's also the second best.
Rym: Yeah, but the other guy, no.
Rym: Replace it with just me or someone like me with a laptop and Google.
Scott: But you can't type into Google faster than they can, you know...
Rym: Yeah, but the way the buzzing is, someone's gonna buzz in an answer wrong, and then I'll have the answer, and I might notice that.
Scott: But you're not gonna win that way.
Scott: Basically, they'll buzz in and have it right immediately.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Almost certainly.
Rym: Or I'll just memorize all the answers like I used to do in Quiz Bowl.
Scott: But they don't know the questions, so how can you memorize them beforehand?
Rym: For one, I remember reading a thing on, like, what Jeopardy!
Rym: contestants get, and basically they're given areas of study and references to study, but then the questions and the topics are a small subset of everything they were given.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's not quite as spontaneous as everyone thinks it is.
Scott: Oh, I wonder, though, if the Watson -- Does the Watson get to pre-study like the contestants do?
Scott: 'Cause that would make it way easy.
Scott: That would make it way easy.
Scott: It'd be like, "All right, we know there's gonna be something about Rome.
Scott: Well, let's load the Rome database in, and we'll scan in this book on Rome with
Scott: OCR.".
Scott: It's, like, that's totally too easy if they do that.
Scott: It's got to be able to handle, you know, any arbitrary question at any time in order for it to really count.
Rym: One thing I am curious about is how, if this sort of research, you know, trying to make a computer that will parse the text and answer a question directly like this, I wonder if it is down the road of passing Turing tests or not.
Rym: I mean, one of the biggest problems with AI is that it really can't pass itself off for human.
Rym: No.
Rym: But at the same time, many humans cannot pass themselves off for human on the Internet anymore.
Scott: Well, I think, you know, what you've got, right, is we've managed to make a lot of computers that -- or systems that, you know, 'cause really what Watson is all about is the software, not so much the hardware, right -- is that, you know, do one human thing, right?
Scott: So, for example, have an AI that plays "Counter-Strike" like a human, or we'll have an AI that plays "Jeopardy" like a human, or we'll have something that converses like a human to try to pass the Turing test, or we'll have something, you know, a robot that flips pancakes like a human, right?
Scott: But what we haven't made is sort of the general case, right?
Scott: Give me the computer/robot software/hardware combination that can do all the things of a human, right?
Rym: Well, because that would be a human.
Scott: 'Cause a human -- It's almost like a ship of Theseus, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If it can do -- If it can see and hear and taste and touch and play "Jeopardy" and flip pancakes, you know, it can do all the things a human can do, but it doesn't have DNA.
Scott: Is it a human, or is it the ship of Theseus?
Rym: Well, that's the old question we have to go even further of what is human.
Rym: Does human mean species, or does human mean intelligence?
Rym: Because if we go the species route, the people with mutations and, you know, you can argue that there are people who aren't actually human.
Rym: Probably.
Rym: And also, what do you do about intelligences that eventually are more advanced than humans or when humans evolve?
Rym: If we go the intelligence route, I mean, there are chimps and dogs, and a lot of animals have the intelligence of small human children.
Scott: The thing is I want to see, right, is they've got Deep Blue, which plays chess, and they've got Watson, which plays "Jeopardy," right?
Scott: Show me a computer.
Scott: At least for starters, right, let's have something that can play any game, right?
Scott: You know, it's like if you obviously can't get the same --.
Rym: Because, Scott, that's clearly such an easy thing to do.
Rym: I mean, someone just has to think, "Oh, I'll make a computer that can play any
Rym: game.".
Scott: Football, chess, paper, rock, scissors.
Scott: Well, not sports necessarily, but any game where it's just, you know, decisions.
Rym: So, chess checkers and Starfarers of Catan.
Scott: You know, any game where you could -- You know, and what would be super cool, right, is if you actually went up to the computer, and it had, like, a camera and a microphone, and you pretty much -- you taught it the rules the same way you teach the rules to a person, right?
Scott: So, it'd be like, "Here, computer, this is Puerto Rico.
Scott: On your turn, if you're the governor, you select a
Scott: role.".
Scott: And it actually learned how to play, and then it could, like, watch a game of people playing and learn how to play based on that.
Scott: That would be -- I think that's the next step.
Rym: It would be an interesting step.
Rym: Basically, it'd almost be a logic processor, where all you do is give it a series of constraints, and then once it has all the known constraints, give it an outcome.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, we already have that, right?
Scott: We've got, like -- You can run a thing on your computer where it'll design, you know, a car based on, you know, genetic algorithms over time.
Rym: Well, genetic algorithms are a little different.
Rym: That's the, you know, discarding the least fit and enhancing the most fit.
Scott: Yeah, but a human puts in the fitness algorithm, you know?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We tell it what fitness is.
Rym: Yeah, but in a case like that, you'd be putting in different algorithms for beating a game, as opposed to just giving it the rules of the game.
Rym: The rules of the game are not the strategy to beat the game.
Rym: And I don't know if there's any way to have a computer now that, given only the rules, will come about to an algorithm that solves the game short of doing some sort of tedious genetic process.
Scott: Oh, that is sort of true.
Scott: Both the Deep Blue and the Watson, right, were sort of programmed for the specific game purpose.
Scott: So the algorithm to beat the game was basically typed in by people, right, who figured out what that algorithm was.
Rym: Yeah, we need an algorithm that generates an algorithm.
Scott: The computer didn't figure out how to win at
Scott: "Jeopardy!".
Scott: Pretty much someone who already knew how to win at
Scott: "Jeopardy!"
Scott: went in and said, "Okay, buzz in as soon as possible,".
Scott: right, as part of the program, you know?
Scott: So that's actually -- When you think about it that way, it's far less impressive, because pretty much someone went to the computer and typed in, "Here is how to win at
Scott: "Jeopardy!".
Scott: Do this, do this, do this, do this, do this, do
Scott: this.".
Scott: And the computer does that.
Rym: It's no different than writing the A.I.
Rym: to be good at, say, "Settlers," except that it's a much more complex problem with a much larger problem space.
Scott: Yeah, the impressive parts of the technology are pretty much only in the parts that understand, you know, the human language, the natural language processing.
Scott: It's really just natural language processing and the output.
Scott: And then the second part of looking up the answer and make sure you get the right one, you know?
Scott: That's pretty much the only interesting parts of Watson.
Scott: The rest of it is actually pretty lame.
Rym: What I will say is I will call bullshit on the whole scenario if it does not ring in first on every single question.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Because if it doesn't, that means that they're not actually -- You know, they didn't go full-on in this experiment.
Scott: I'd be really interested to see just exactly how it buzzes in, how it, you know, determines when -- You know, all this stuff.
Scott: If they wired up any extra inputs to it, that's bullshit.
Scott: How does it know how much to wager, right?
Scott: What did they program for that?
Rym: Obviously, if it knows the answer, all the money.
Rym: If it doesn't know the answer, $1.
Scott: You can wager zero.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You got to wager the $1.
Scott: But you also have to look at how much the other people have, right?
Scott: So if you wager zero and the other guy's got more than you right now, he could just wager zero and win even if he gets it wrong.
Scott: So you have to wager at least the difference between you and the lead guy if you're not in first.
Rym: You know what would be a much more interesting problem for me because it's a problem that I would -- It is easier to solve, I think, because the problem space is actually more constrained.
Rym: I would like to see a robot that competes at the price is right because it's constrained in one way.
Rym: It's got to just look up prices, MSRP.
Rym: But it's also difficult in that it's got to be able to beat all those crazy minigames.
Rym: It's got to be able to putt.
Scott: Play some Plinko.
Scott: It's got to climb up the Plinko stairs.
Rym: Oh, Plinko would be really easy for it to figure out, I think.
Scott: It'd have to climb up the stairs, though, to drop the Plinkos.
Rym: I would be okay with them carrying it up the stairs because you can't tell me that if someone in a wheelchair was on the price is right, they would not help them up.
Scott: No, the price is right.
Scott: is, I believe, ADA accessible.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: In fact, I think if you're in a wheelchair, though, I'm pretty sure they'll make you play a game that doesn't have stairs.
Rym: Yeah, they're not going to --.
Rym: Well, yeah.
Scott: You know, they'll let you play an easier game.
Rym: That would be much more impressive.
Rym: I want to see.
Rym: the price is right robot.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Scott: I mean, the thing is, right, price is right is about memory.
Scott: It's like, did you remember this piece of information, right?
Scott: So does Watson look things up on Google, or does it have its own database of information, right?
Scott: And then what was put in that database?
Scott: If I load -- I could take my computer and load it up with a list of price database on MySQL, and it could win.
Scott: the price is right, no problem.
Scott: That'd be really easy to do.
Scott: So it's like --.
Rym: Well, well, figuring out the prices part, but not, for example, the -- Because the showcase showdown is a lot more fuzzy.
Rym: There's too many -- There's almost a Fermi equation.
Scott: No, it just adds all the prices of all the different, separate things together.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time, there's no listed MSRP for a particular trip to a particular hotel.
Rym: You got to figure that out.
Rym: It orbits.
Scott: Yeah, it's all right.
Scott: But the thing is --.
Rym: And you got to putt.
Rym: How do you get to putt?
Scott: There's putting robots.
Scott: You got to putt.
Rym: Yeah, it's all got to be the same robot.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: Make a computer with legs.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: But, yeah, you know, it's --.
Scott: What was I trying to say?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's not necessarily any sort of fancy program you've written or fancy algorithm or algorithm-generating algorithm.
Scott: It's just data.
Scott: Was the data in the computer, or was it not?
Scott: Unless it has Internet access.
Scott: So how much data did they put in Watson?
Scott: You know, that could determine whether it wins or loses how much data was inserted beforehand.
Scott: And is it fair to insert some obscene amount of data on terabytes of hard drives?
Scott: that is more than, like, any nonautistic human can possibly remember?
Rym: Ah, but what if we have a human who just memorizes all that somehow?
Scott: Yeah, but that's -- You know, if it's a game of memory, you know, how fair --.
Scott: You know, because there are certain things a computer is better at than a person, and certain things a person is better at than a computer, right?
Scott: If you're talking about just memorizing a ton of information and looking it up, a computer is way better than humans, right?
Scott: But if you're talking about something like, "Walk down this crowded street without bumping into anyone,".
Scott: a computer is terrible at that, you know?
Scott: I mean, you'd have to have, like, some --.
Rym: Scott, I note that the majority of the people I see on the street on a daily basis are also terrible at that.
Scott: They're a lot better than a computer would be.
Rym: I almost disagree with you there.
Scott: But I'm just saying, you know, it's those kinds of --.
Rym: Well, let's zoom out.
Rym: We're talking about -- Because, you know, we can --.
Rym: From a practical perspective, a game versus a sport are very different.
Rym: But, really, they're not, because what's going on in a human brain is a physicality that is no different fundamentally from electrons moving around in a computer.
Rym: It's just a physicality, and we have these giant abstractions on top of it.
Rym: At its core, if I'm trying to figure out the answer to your question, there are chemical and electrical reactions going on in my brain.
Rym: Mm.
Rym: It's just a big physical thing.
Rym: So, why don't we make the baseball robot?
Rym: Is it fair for the baseball robot to compete against a human?
Scott: There was a baseball robot.
Scott: It's in "Bots
Scott: Masters."
Scott: [ Laughs ].
Scott: "Zib-Zoo" landing.
Rym: Now, I think the only reason we don't do this is because we can make a robot that bats better than any human could ever bat.
Rym: That same robot is not going to be able to run the bases.
Scott: Yeah, it's 'cause we keep making -- Yeah, if we keep making robots that are specialized at one task --.
Rym: I think it'd be much more fun to start having much more generic robots, even though they will fail miserably.
Rym: It'll be more interesting to watch.
Rym: Like, "Robot Wars," all those kind of competitions, were always boring as fuck because the problem space was so constrained, and the solutions would always come down to things like, "I have a robot that's really flat and just flips the other robots
Rym: over.".
Scott: Oh, you mean -- Oh, that's --.
Rym: Yeah, I want to see things that are like, "All right, your robot's got to just play goddamn baseball.
Rym: It's got to bet.
Rym: It's got to pitch.
Rym: It's got to run.
Scott: It's got to
Scott: catch.".
Scott: There's a soccer-playing-robot competition every year.
Rym: Yeah, I want to see baseball.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: I would like to see just, you know, the battle bots, but no restrictions.
Scott: You know, as long as it doesn't hurt the audience.
Scott: That's the only restriction.
Rym: No, you put it in some sort of cage.
Scott: It can't just be a bomb or a rocket launcher 'cause that would hurt the audience.
Rym: A bomb wouldn't work 'cause it would win the first round.
Rym: - No, it would get a draw in the first round and lose all the following rounds.
Scott: But, you know, it could throw the bomb at the enemy.
Rym: It better have enough bombs.
Rym: You want to put a machine gun in your robot?
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Don't run out of bullets.
Scott: As long as it doesn't hurt the audience.
Scott: You know, anything that doesn't hurt the audience, I think, should be allowed.
Rym: Bulletproof glass.
Scott: How about this?
Scott: Just no explosives or projectiles, right?
Scott: So, it would basically punch and kick and smash and do whatever in any shape and any size as long as it fits in the ring, you know?
Scott: And just go for it.
Scott: That, I think, would be interesting.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: I don't know how much else we can say about this.
Rym: I guess the TLDR version or the TLDL, I guess, in this case, is that this is actually not that interesting of an experiment.
Scott: Yeah, it's, like, it seems really interesting.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not actually that interesting under the hood.
Scott: It's a lot farther away from real AI than it appears.
Rym: Well, no, I guess it's more that it is a very, very interesting problem, and they're using a very unique --.
Scott: Well, the language-processing problem and the lookup problem.
Rym: Yeah, all the stuff that's interesting about it is really interesting.
Rym: But it's primarily only interesting to computer scientists, and all the media interest in it, you know, human-versus-computer aspect-wise, is actually kind of lame.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, watch.
Rym: Watch and learn.
Rym: If it does not buzz in itself and always buzz in first, bullshit.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, there's also, right, there's a game-theory aspect to it that I want to investigate, right, which is, you know, in game theory, right, game theory is all about you're making a decision, right, based -- and you have to take someone else's decision into account in your decision, right?
Scott: That's what it's all about.
Scott: And that's why a single-player game isn't really a game from a game-theorist's perspective, because in a single-player game is a puzzle.
Scott: There is an answer, and it's just all about figuring out that answer, right?
Scott: Now, you think of a single player when there's an AI, even if it's, you know, just the kind of simple AIs we have today, right?
Scott: Is that a single-player game, or are you actually making decisions against the decisions of the AI?
Scott: I mean, it's a pretty good simulation of a game against a real person, right?
Scott: But is it really?
Scott: Because there is still -- It's still a digital binary computer.
Scott: It's still an algorithm.
Scott: So the decisions it's making are already made.
Scott: Well, what it does -- -It's already deterministic.
Rym: What it has is a strategy, just like me playing Stratego.
Rym: I have a strategy.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So does it then not -- It's not -- While it looks, you know, like it is a player, it's actually just a part of the puzzle in the game, a very perhaps complex part, you know?
Rym: Scott, but the breakdown there is that me as a human, if I'm playing, say, "The Prisoner's Dilemma," I have a strategy.
Rym: Every decision that could possibly be made, I've already decided.
Rym: I am following an algorithm.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: So that doesn't make me less a part of the game.
Scott: There's also the trick -- But what if you're a deterministic computer instead of a biological computer?
Scott: Is your strategy not, you know, where they set algorithm for selecting a strategy?
Scott: Are you not now, you know, limited in some way, and now you are no longer -- You are now no longer a deciding party.
Rym: There's no fundamental difference because there's no way for you to justify saying that I have any more or less free will or determinism than the computer.
Scott: Ah, but there are quite significant differences between you and the computer.
Rym: But on a fundamental level, causality.
Scott: For example, in a dollar auction, for example, against a computer, right?
Scott: A human is probably gonna play, right?
Scott: But the computer doesn't find any value in money, so it doesn't give a shit.
Rym: Yeah, but me, as a human, if there's a dollar auction, I know better.
Rym: My strategy is don't bid.
Scott: Right, but other people don't know better.
Scott: Actually, yeah, because there's -- But a computer is yet a third way.
Rym: I would argue that it isn't actually a third way because you could program a computer whose algorithm is, "Hells yeah, dollar
Rym: auction.".
Rym: I mean, there's no difference between a human and a computer in that way.
Rym: If causality is true, then they're both equally deterministic machines, and their starting state --.
Rym: The only difference is that we can see the origin of the state machine that is the computer insofar as we created it.
Rym: What we cannot see is the state machine of the universe or the state machine that was our entire past leading up to us making the robot.
Rym: In fact, the robot is nothing more than an extension of us.
Scott: So isn't Watson, then, actually -- A human.
Rym: No, one step further.
Rym: Watson is an outgrowth of the humans, which themselves are nothing more than outgrowths of the causal chain leading back to the Big Bang.
Scott: Right, but no, the people who made Watson, at least, you know, right, isn't it actually sort of like a team playing Jeopardy, which is sort of unfair.
Scott: It's all those humans together playing Jeopardy on the same team.
Rym: But would it be any different if all those humans coached another human into a strategy?
Scott: Oh, would it be?
Rym: No, because there's no way to differentiate between the deterministic behavior of a machine and algorithm or a human.
Rym: Because we believe that causality exists and have no reason not to believe so.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Which also proves that we don't have free will, if that's true.
Rym: Ah, it all comes down to solipsism.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah, Watson is cheating.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: If he doesn't buzz in first, then he's playing suboptimally.
Rym: He's not playing to win the game.
Rym: Nah.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.