Rym: It's Wednesday March 30th 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: comics in digital form.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So on on Saturday going to see this show the the Book of Mormon right by the guys.
Rym: I sadly don't get to go.
Scott: I'll have to go next week sometime, but anyway well good luck with good luck getting tickets.
Rym: Yeah It's easy to get two tickets.
Scott: not really I had to get the Statler and Waldorf tickets.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: I don't plan to sit up close.
Rym: I save my.
Rym: I'm not sitting in the front row for an untested musical.
Scott: Yeah, no, but basically if people were the line basically because I didn't want to buy tickets You know the only way to get them pretty much is to go to the box office physically.
Scott: So I go to this box office Which is on the same street as my office how convenient.
Scott: and I wait in this line and the line is pretty much constant length.
Scott: They process people as fast as people get in line, and if the the light the line is the full length of the lobby in The theater.
Scott: right it's not a very big lobby, but still it's like a you know 15 20 foot long.
Scott: Yeah, the point is this line.
Scott: every single person in this line it deserved except for they got two guys behind me a Stabbing in the face.
Rym: What could they possibly be doing?
Rym: the line is moving what it is not.
Rym: Well, so there are two.
Scott: there are two ticket windows.
Scott: right all right.
Scott: when the time I walked in there was a lady at the left ticket window.
Scott: I don't know how long she was there before I got there But she was there at that ticket window at least 10 minutes after I got there And she just kept being like she couldn't figure out a date.
Scott: She was like no.
Scott: That's a Wednesday.
Scott: It's no good I can't go on Wednesday.
Scott: then like five minutes later.
Scott: She was like okay.
Scott: Oh, no wait That's a Wednesday, and I'm like oh my god old people die in a fire.
Rym: right the thing is the problem Here is that there's even a line.
Rym: It's just be online Online.
Scott: this is why Broadway.com where I work exists right.
Rym: but even even though the one who was like don't go to Broadway Com just buy it in person I would pay whatever it costs to not have to stand in this line.
Scott: now knowing the point is is that like even Broadway.com we have troubles because You know these theaters are just so old-fashioned.
Scott: You know but anyway Yeah, it's like.
Scott: and then another guy tried two different credit cards.
Scott: They were both denied and someone else was like I want to buy tickets for like November, and I'm like oh my god What the fuck people.
Scott: well, and I was just I was like give me can I get four tickets this weekend?
Scott: And then even me right I wasn't trying to get you know I was just like any date this weekend.
Scott: Give me four ticket.
Scott: You know the four tickets Right.
Rym: I think you're at the wrong booth for tickets.
Scott: Yeah, there's four shows this weekend.
Scott: I want four tickets.
Scott: right and he's like well, which of the four shows do you want?
Scott: I'm like I don't care, and he's like well You have to pick one, and I'm like you can't just search all four.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: What is what year is this 1970?
Scott: You know apparently yeah, it's like.
Scott: you know it wasn't just the people in line.
Scott: It was also the box-office people meanwhile.
Rym: date is that Broadway?
Rym: because people know Broadway like out in the wide world There's a lot of tourists, so they will sell out pretty much any popular.
Scott: Oh, it's actually bad for tourists.
Scott: how to tourists get the tickets?
Rym: I know I'm saying the tourists just get in that line because someone tells them to or They go through like their travel agency or whatever and they're like oh, we'll get you theater ticket.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: It's like it's this big thing.
Scott: if they would just put the tickets on I should know.
Rym: but here's the thing.
Rym: This is what I'm saying because they have this audience of people who aren't terribly savvy and who have money.
Rym: They don't have to upgrade shit.
Scott: meanwhile I think it's just because they're their theaters are relatively small and centrally located.
Rym: But then again right you think that you didn't let me finish because when I buy tickets to the symphony Not only is the fee basically negligible to order online, but it's not easy to do it in person online.
Rym: Not only can I see all the dates not only can I do crazy complex searches like you know?
Rym: I could search multiple days or multiple times or price levels or anything But once I finally settled on something and I pick my seats I can see a view from each individual seat.
Scott: Yep, someone needs to make a system.
Rym: You know the thing is God, but you're not listening to me.
Rym: There's no incentive to they make the same money.
Rym: either way it would cost more to improve it in any way.
Scott: That is where you're wrong right.
Scott: the fact is is that Broadway actually doesn't really make all that much money.
Scott: Cirque du Soleil makes as much money as all of Broadway multiplied many many times.
Rym: I know that we've had this before but I'm Broadway.
Scott: and the thing is a lot of Broadway shows except There's a few shows right that basically sell out forever.
Scott: right because they're the good shows.
Scott: they sell out forever because the theaters are small.
Scott: So right, but all the other shows basically just keep.
Scott: you got flops all over the place fail fail close.
Scott: You know how many shows just closed at a point?
Scott: recently there were more closed theaters on Broadway than like a long long time.
Rym: So here's the thing.
Rym: they're how.
Rym: how is online tickets that work going to get more people to go to shows They've never heard of?
Rym: Because right there are people argue the in-person one is better because you get you got to get tourists who don't even know what they Want to see have a line that's like I want to see a Broadway show.
Scott: Yeah, that's called the TKTS line where the tickets are half-price yet to buy them day of it exists.
Rym: Yeah, so that's it.
Rym: How are they gonna make more money?
Rym: How are they going to sell more seats to crappy shows?
Scott: Because they're a lot there are.
Scott: there's at least some people who don't go simply because it's inconvenient.
Rym: think so.
Scott: I don't think those all those shows that don't sell enough tickets and go out They would sell at least one more ticket.
Rym: by doing it properly It's got one more ticket is not worth any amount of effort.
Rym: You're gonna put in that much effort.
Scott: And I said at least one because obviously I don't have any actual numbers, but I I suspect it would be a good Disagree with this.
Rym: for one The popular shows meaning shows where people know the name of it who don't know anything about Broadway I probably do sell out most of the time.
Rym: I mean I even saw reports of spider-man selling out.
Scott: Well, that's just because you know because it has the proper noun.
Rym: Yeah, it's like a magic spell.
Rym: It's kind of like in Hollywood where every ticket to the Garfield movie was sold Before they made Garfield the movie was the least important part of the equation.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: but
Rym: there's no way they'll make enough money to warrant any reinvestment because at its core the shows are crappy and If they modernize everything all that means is after maybe an initial rush of people going to the theater who wouldn't otherwise they'll realize those shows are crappy and Most people just don't care.
Rym: There's no way that would make money.
Rym: They're better off.
Scott: In fact, I definitely make money.
Rym: I would make it even more of a pain in the ass to where people want to get show the tickets to say the Book of Mormon and they can't but they're already in line and I'm like Hey tell you what if you want to go on to a different show on the same day I can get your primo tickets at a discount.
Rym: blah blah blah.
Scott: They don't want someone else to go to a different show.
Rym: No, those people selling the tickets at the booths do that.
Rym: That's what I would do.
Rym: I would have like a tickets line.
Rym: I would upsell at the tickets line to just sell every goddamn ticket to every show in aggregate.
Scott: I understand the way the tickets line works, right?
Scott: Is that the box office is of the individual shows?
Scott: The day if it was the day of the show and they have X a bunch of extra tickets.
Scott: They physically take those tickets over to TKTS sell them to TKTS and then TKTS sells them for half price or whatever.
Scott: So Scott say I'm the basically discount, you know It's like buy a ticket for a show today that no one else was gonna say I'm the guy in charge of I don't know spider-man.
Rym: and spider-man sold out and some family of four tourists comes up to my box Office and it's like we want to see spider-man on this day and it's sold out.
Scott: What if I didn't go to the spider-man box office or the TKTS?
Rym: Let's say it's the spider-man box office.
Scott: Spider-man box office doesn't want any other Broadway show to make any money.
Rym: Ah, but here's the thing.
Rym: if their shows are already sold out Why don't they make a deal with some crappy show?
Rym: To where look?
Rym: we will also like they could upsell just that show.
Scott: anyone who comes who tries to buy a ticket to my spider-man They can't even search a whole weekend and you want them to cooperate with other shows.
Scott: remember This is a situation where it's old people being stupid.
Scott: I don't think it's that The whole thing is run by old people who are morons and old-fashioned he's got.
Rym: I agree with you.
Rym: But in this case, especially because of the limited size of the theaters and just the the scale of Broadway Which isn't as big as people think very small.
Rym: I just don't think modernization would help.
Rym: I think the problem Definitely.
Rym: Oh, I disagree with you extremely.
Rym: But anyway, it's not a Monday show.
Rym: So I guess I'll have to do a Monday show on why the person who works at Broadway calm Yeah, I work in the real money factory.
Rym: I can tell you that there's no money in it.
Rym: Otherwise it would have been done right but here but yet again, right?
Scott: So the money factory though if you were an old-fashioned money factory, how does that make money compared to the modernized money factory?
Scott: Yeah, but my eyes money factory is a lot better, isn't it?
Rym: But Scott that's because there's underlying money.
Rym: I don't think there's enough underlying money in some in theaters that can sell out at such low numbers.
Scott: I think they're definitely is.
Rym: they can't just raise the price or not enough people will go.
Rym: I mean the symphony gets away with that.
Rym: not that many tickets But it's like 400 bucks a seat and the rich people go and it still sells out.
Rym: So they make a lot more money.
Rym: if you're gonna try to charge 400 bucks a seat for most of the seats for spider-man It's not gonna happen.
Scott: No you charge less and you have more shows.
Scott: the symphony only has a few shows.
Rym: You realize how hard it is on the actors to do musicals.
Rym: There's a reason they don't do more show.
Scott: It's your job dude.
Rym: Uh Scott.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it's that's like saying yeah, ditch diggers.
Rym: Just dig twice as many ditches.
Scott: No, it's taking the same number of ditches per unit time.
Scott: You're just that you're just going on for more years.
Rym: You know why they don't?
Rym: because it stops making money.
Rym: or the actors get tired of it or they wear themselves out.
Rym: Actually a lot of shows have problems especially shows.
Rym: I was a fan of back in the day.
Rym: There's this one.
Rym: I forget the name of it, but it needed like three male leads.
Rym: So it would always only run for short times because even if they had understudies for all of them.
Rym: So six guys who are already like the rare male tenors that can do the parts and it's hard to get you know Multiple tenors in the same show because there aren't that many in the well that says for writing.
Scott: that's making the show purposely difficult.
Scott: That's like haha.
Scott: Come and see the torture chamber.
Scott: My point is this we stab the actors with spikes and flares.
Rym: my point is this you may know about the ticket selling.
Rym: I don't think you know anything about the rest of Broadway.
Rym: No, I don't think you know anything about what it takes to put out a show.
Rym: I know that Having stupid old-fashioned box offices, it's not Substantially, you know who it's hurting Scott you the same way that you got mad because you couldn't buy curtains online because Scott there's no money in it.
Rym: No one gives a shit.
Rym: if there's money would happen.
Rym: There's money There's no money.
Rym: didn't do it.
Scott: if there's so much money in it Yeah, the problem is is a cartel.
Rym: How is the?
Rym: so?
Rym: there's a cartel on curtains.
Scott: knows the cartel on tickets.
Rym: Why don't you just make?
Rym: I mean if it's so easy make a modern theater somewhere near Broadway Buy one of those warehouses.
Scott: on the west side is a cartel on theaters and digots.
Rym: So I'm saying make a new theater.
Scott: Yeah, where am I supposed to get this money?
Scott: So What?
Scott: what cartel is gonna sell me their theater?
Rym: Apparently if they're not making any money They'd gladly sell it.
Rym: if you paid enough and because you clearly have this magic money making if I had the money to begin with I wouldn't invest it in Broadway.
Scott: There's better places to invest it maybe because there's no money there.
Rym: The thing is Any comic or manga or animation related news.
Scott: You decided to hear my opening bit into this giant thing.
Rym: You're so wrong Disastrously wrong.
Scott: All right, so Rym we should.
Scott: they should hand.
Scott: they should study using tickets with you know barcodes on them.
Scott: They should.
Scott: they should actually have like hand written little notes that they scrawl.
Scott: They should hand them out only, you know on the second moon of the.
Rym: yes That's a real nice straw man that you're making right there.
Scott: nice Because they would sell the same number of tickets.
Scott: it doesn't matter how old-fashioned they are.
Rym: But Scott it took more effort to sell those tickets.
Rym: Anyway, the production of the tickets cost more.
Rym: your straw man is already burnt.
Scott: There is a. There's isn't much comic and anime news going down really I think.
Scott: but in a few months like July It's gonna.
Scott: are you kidding there?
Rym: Well, there's anime convention news Like what like the fact that anime Boston is gonna be at the same time as PAX East next year.
Scott: Well, that's not that big a news.
Scott: No, it's not news.
Rym: Even it's big news to half the people involved.
Scott: Yeah, what do we do about it?
Scott: just now?
Scott: I guess we're not gonna get a Boston which is sad.
Rym: that's not my news.
Rym: I was just saying that there's more news than you're letting on.
Rym: Yeah You started being argumentative.
Rym: I gotta finish the deal.
Rym: I got I can argue Bunch of anime in theaters trygun movie.
Rym: what happened to that?
Rym: There's a bunch of stuff we could talk about.
Scott: All right, like what was here was your anime news?
Rym: I'm gonna talk about a Star Trek convention.
Rym: So you go first All right.
Scott: Well, I don't have any news because I don't think there is any Star Trek convention.
Scott: Definitely isn't news.
Scott: So I got a geek bite right?
Scott: I read all three volumes of that people to thing that people talked about And you know you look at the cover and it's all booby and stuff and you're like, what's this gonna be?
Scott: Booby yeah, so I actually read the whole thing and I was you know I bought volume one just because I was like, you know, it was like a test of the waters, right?
Scott: It's like I can't you know.
Scott: I got to figure out what the deal is with this thing that is so much talk and so much sort of infamy.
Scott: So I got volume one and I was like, huh?
Scott: So then I got more two more volumes cuz only three volumes.
Scott: So why the hell not get the other two?
Scott: so I got the other two and I read the whole thing and it was actually.
Scott: It's weird cuz like.
Scott: it's not what you think it is.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I expected it to be one thing and it was another thing.
Scott: It's like a total disguise maneuver.
Rym: You know, what's interesting?
Rym: a lot of the a anime I can name or the b-plus anime even pull that shit.
Rym: I mean try gun Captain Tyler hold some of that.
Scott: I mean a lot of it is you know The otaku think Japan is like this.
Scott: Well, they're stupid.
Scott: Japan is normal people and Japanese people think America is like this.
Scott: Well, they're also stupid.
Scott: right and that was like one of the core messages of the thing.
Scott: But if you look at it, it's like, you know, it looks like it's gonna be a big perverted, you know thing.
Scott: But really it's not that perverted at all.
Scott: It didn't mean it has perverted parts But yeah, and it also, you know the way it goes it goes in a very not expected direction at many many points.
Scott: So it was totally worth reading and I don't want to give too much of it away.
Rym: But yeah Scott There's plenty of anime news.
Rym: It turns out that on Friday last week There was a really awesome cosplay of Umineko no naku karoni.
Rym: sure Great news and the Oxford English Dictionary added the word hentai to the dictionary.
Rym: All right, it means a sub-genre of the Japanese genres of manga and anime.
Rym: Uh-huh Plenty of news.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: Great.
Scott: Why don't you discuss this news in depth?
Rym: I just did.
Rym: Okay Alright, so a lot of people, you know anime cons have their pros and cons and there's the drama in some of them and not and whatever.
Rym: and For anyone who thinks that anime cons are this height of drama I just want to remind all of you kids that there are science fiction conventions and Star Trek conventions And those are the biggest drama there ever is but they're a different kind of drama.
Rym: They're like the.
Rym: this drama That is it's it's the.
Rym: I think anime cons are gonna go this road but in a long long time Like remember when we were at RIT There was like an amazement.
Rym: and all these like science fiction and such conventions in the area that get like 500 people.
Rym: They were in a hotel for a weekend.
Rym: Well many many of them their their sci-fi conventions all over the country and they all tend to Be run today by the same people who are running them 20 even 30 years ago.
Rym: Yep Imagine if 30 years from now the same people are running Pat.
Rym: Oh wait, that'd still be awesome.
Rym: Imagine if 30 years from now the same people running Otakon today We're still running Otakon and they'd had no new people join the staff for that entire time.
Rym: Yep that'd be a disaster.
Rym: and This is kind of an interesting thing that I don't think people think about when they think about the drama conventions.
Scott: Well, cuz the most of these other conventions, right?
Scott: The only only the conventions that we go to like, you know The taxes and the mag fests and some of the anime cons are actually social party events.
Scott: the vast majority of these conventions are Basically a room full of tables.
Rym: Scott you ever been to a sci-fi con Once or twice?
Rym: name them name one.
Scott: They were like, you know tiny hole in the wall where the crap and like you never went to an amazement with me.
Scott: I never went to an amazement.
Rym: No or the I can't.
Rym: not an amazement.
Rym: I know I keep saying an amazement God, I don't even remember the name of it.
Scott: Connecticut is Astronomicon not everyone's that either.
Scott: That's the one I'm gonna con technically is part sci-fi convention Yeah, but it's also part everything else.
Rym: It is also yes replace every mention of an amazement I don't know.
Rym: I kept saying that.
Rym: but anyway actually sci-fi cons are Party cons, they're primarily social.
Rym: They're not like.
Rym: you see you're thinking of comic cons Which are mostly or trading conventions like trading cards or baseball cards.
Rym: Where is just a bunch of tables.
Rym: a lot of the sci-fi cons are a bunch of nerds getting together semi in costume and Going to room parties and drinking.
Rym: It's just not as screechy But that's it.
Scott: But every convention even the comic cons right that are even the worst comic cons have room parties and drinking Yeah, and costumes right?
Scott: The fact is that the there's no socialization at the convention.
Rym: Yeah, there is like people hang out because they're a hotel convention.
Scott: So they're no but it's not an official.
Scott: there's no events at the convention itself does not have like, you know a rave or You know a game room or and none of the.
Scott: the programming of the convention is the social aspect.
Scott: Obviously no matter what convention you have a science, you know conference or whatever.
Scott: There's always drinking in the hotel in the lobby Conventions.
Rym: that just the fact that a bunch of like-minded people are in the same area is the primary.
Rym: But I'm saying the few rare conventions that have convention itself.
Scott: The content provided by the convention does not include socialization.
Scott: It may include, you know, some autograph tables and some vendors and maybe some at the same time.
Rym: without the convention itself The socialization would not occur.
Rym: this socialization is a direct result of the drawing of these people saying it's not a part of the of the Convention.
Rym: why not?
Rym: What if it happens at the convention in the convention only to people who bought bad?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not a sanctioned program of the convention.
Scott: So it doesn't count.
Scott: Completely different thing.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I disagree with you.
Scott: But anyway, uh Well, you all disagree today.
Scott: Did you uh, what did you eat today poison?
Rym: I disagree with you often.
Rym: I just don't always vocalize my opinions.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah, you're being all ornery today artery.
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: I think so.
Scott: What is a pony?
Scott: he was good at arguing.
Scott: what is a cutie mark even look like picture.
Rym: main rims face, so The Riverside Star Trek fest is in trouble and is probably going to go bankrupt.
Scott: All right, and what state is this?
Rym: You don't know anything about Star Trek.
Rym: Do you know?
Rym: James Tiberius Kirk was born.
Rym: do you know?
Scott: I do.
Scott: I do know that captain Kirk is the Star Trek captain.
Rym: So that much this convention has been going on for a long time.
Rym: How long really.
Rym: the only.
Scott: it can't be that long.
Scott: Star Trek's only a few decades old.
Rym: That's a long time.
Scott: It hasn't been going since the 50s.
Rym: No, it hasn't Okay anyway, so the only reason this convention has been going anyway, because it doesn't make money is because the city Gives it a whole bunch of money from this fund that it has to put on events that are useful to the community From the local hotel casino.
Scott: Oh hotel casino.
Scott: I thought it.
Scott: what state is this?
Scott: The casinos are legal?
Rym: Well, maybe you should look up where James Tiberius Kirk was born.
Rym: I think you don't know and that's why you're not saying anyway, so Apparently now the conventions like look we need money from the city to run the convention again.
Rym: And the city was like, yeah, you don't make any money.
Rym: We've give you $90,000 over the last three years.
Rym: We're probably not gonna give you any more money.
Scott: This makes me wonder though Is there cities that would be willing to pay us to run conventions that we could make into profitable conventions?
Scott: Very likely and then you know.
Scott: so we should try to find.
Rym: Look at how many cities fall into the scam of building a convention center to increase the profitability.
Rym: You saw that chart that showed that as awesome as packs and everything is the BC EC and the Hines are not quite driving Revenues for the city as much as people pretended it wouldn't know.
Scott: some conventions moved across town, but it has.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah We should find one of those cities to help us run our convention and then we can give the money back to that city That we profit with just to make them happy.
Rym: But basically there's this crazy drama.
Rym: and because Star Trek conventions tend to draw Older demographics who are not internet culture.
Rym: This is how I'm bringing it back to anime cons.
Rym: Yeah, there's no internet nerd outrage.
Rym: nobody Except the hardest of the hardest core.
Rym: Know anything about the Riverside Trek fest let alone the drama and the fact is probably gonna go away.
Scott: Can you imagine all the people who go to very Trekkies and Trekkers?
Rym: We're gonna be fighting with each other and God was like look We don't have enough money to do the con next year.
Rym: Well people pitch in.
Rym: they'd probably raise like hundreds of thousands of dollars.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gullible kids.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Hey if they got every attendee to give them a dollar.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it still wouldn't be enough to run over can know.
Rym: but Otakon is not nearly as expensive as you think it is.
Rym: No, it's an order of magnitude less than tax.
Scott: Yeah, but but but it's bigger.
Rym: but here's the interest the kind of where I'm getting at.
Rym: Convention culture is a huge part of modern youth internet II culture because Kids now socialize more online than they do in person at least in terms of like their true identity.
Rym: Like the gamer nerd in every town knows the one other gamer nerd in every other town Even if there aren't that many gamer nerds near them.
Rym: So for kids younger than us who are internet II the internet like conventions are basically The focal point is for nerds.
Scott: We're not nerds.
Scott: It's not a big deal nerds and geeks.
Rym: but non nerds and geeks have enough local culture to where they don't need to seek it Elsewhere.
Rym: Yeah, I mean if you're into generic pop culture stuff There's plenty of people who are into the same stuff nearby you like three and a half men or two and a half men Or whatever that show is.
Scott: Somebody nearby probably want to talk about TV.
Rym: in sports You don't need to go to a convention, but if you want to talk about James Tiberius Kirk's birthplace You got to go somewhere with other people and we don't have full-on virtual reality yet.
Scott: So what's the news about this convention?
Rym: That was the news.
Rym: it's going out.
Rym: It's going down.
Rym: There's no money.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Sure Yeah, great.
Rym: I'm just noting that Alright, never mind.
Rym: You don't care.
Rym: You don't care about Star Trek convention.
Scott: I don't really care about a Star Trek convention.
Rym: go the fact that the primary like convention culture I think is going to be one of the big moving forces of the upcoming generations of youth the yet born children.
Rym: and I think that the conventions that focus on having the dual aspects of user generated content coupled with Being a place for a whole bunch of nerds to get together who know each other online But don't know each other in person Cons of the twofold that are for-profit are going to make more money than big-box stores ever did
Scott: Probably and
Rym: that big-box stores could in fact.
Scott: but but big-box stores are open all day every day.
Scott: Conventions are gonna be once a year and for now, you can't have that many conventions You can't.
Scott: you can't like, you know You you know convention can run itself multiple times per year.
Scott: And if there were conventions every weekend Like let's say you live next to a convention center and there was a convention a nerdy convention in almost every weekend Somewhere within shooting distance.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: You couldn't go to all of them You could no one can handle it and they would all be diluted heavily the fact that they are.
Scott: You know that there's sort of actually at this sweet spot right now where if there are any more of them Then it would dilute the rest of them.
Scott: But if there are any less we could still probably use some more.
Rym: so you've headed toward my grand conclusion.
Rym: if you couple this with demographic movements showing that by and large young people are moving to the cities like in droves like young people are just they go to conventions because they don't have people right nearby them.
Rym: they're into their stuff and They're also all moving into cities.
Rym: So I think there's a rumbling rise in all the urban centers of nerdy stuff that happens at a low level all the time.
Rym: so I think the far out of that is that the large gigantic conventions of today are either they're all gonna disappear within the next 40 or 50 years or The big conventions that are established that don't fuck themselves over with internal drama and bullshit will be the only Conventions and we'll have like the Pax's the Otakons the whatever survives and Everything else is just going to be like our nerd nights where there's just constant nerdery everywhere Cities.
Scott: I think that the conventions scene will pretty much You know stay.
Scott: the same conventions will come and go but the numbers Sizes and geographic locations of them will just sort of correct to the market.
Scott: and you know They I don't think it's gonna be it will correct to the market.
Rym: I'm saying the markets gonna change rapidly in the next 30 40 years.
Scott: Well, I mean, yeah, okay everything everything in the whole universe will change in 30 40 years.
Scott: It's like, you know, come on anyway things of the day.
Rym: my guess was 34 and I was Way off.
Rym: you can guess if it was high or low.
Rym: But uh, this is just a mash-up of every bone that Steven Seagal Acting as Steven Seagal in a movie has broken in another character.
Scott: Well, they weren't really bones broken.
Scott: They were in movie.
Scott: bones broke because it was a movie right.
Scott: the thing you weren't real bone.
Scott: No the thing about this though that I wonder right is you watch a lot of these scenes and it's like he'll twist a guy's Arm and they'll make a cracking sound effect, but it's like Did he break the ulna and the radius should have counted that twice?
Rym: Maybe you should watch the video because they address that do they?
Rym: they address that very very specifically, uh-huh I also know there's one scene where he does something and a guy falls down, but there's no cracking noise.
Rym: I was about to say that's bullshit.
Rym: and then the guy on the ground yells and I quote But you don't just cuz he.
Scott: maybe his leg just really hurts.
Rym: I think he broke his leg.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Like I've seen people like stub their toes like I broke my toe.
Scott: I was like you stub your toe.
Scott: You're a wuss.
Rym: Ah, it was pretty much broken in this case.
Scott: How could you tell it was a movie?
Scott: It definitely wasn't broken.
Rym: Ah it in the movie universe.
Rym: It definitely was broken.
Rym: Maybe to quote.
Scott: keep in mind you're getting your Gandalf girth in these broken bones.
Rym: There are multiple bones in the forearm lower leg neck and hand.
Rym: each break in those areas will only be counted once Uh-huh.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Well, what if?
Scott: what if internet nitpickers?
Scott: What about this?
Scott: only I watched a video.
Scott: most of it is like him twisting and hitting and you know kicking, right?
Scott: What about when he shoots somebody?
Scott: now if you shoot someone in the head, is that not breaking the skull bone?
Rym: You could argue that.
Scott: but what about if I shoot someone wearing body armor Scott with a powerful enough weapon?
Scott: He would break their ribs.
Rym: why in the?
Rym: how many rims got broken Scott why in the ever-living fuck would Steven Seagal ever shoot Someone?
Rym: his fist is clearly more power.
Rym: He shoots people.
Scott: I've seen it in movies.
Scott: He doesn't really shoot.
Rym: This is only when he breaks bones with manual action.
Rym: No propellants.
Rym: Yeah, the real person seems like I was a peaceful man, but now it moves multiple bones on the same person Disparately like there's one guy where he breaks one knee then the other knee Elbow then the other elbow and a couple of ribs.
Rym: all those counted.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, so it's March.
Scott: Well, it's almost April and it's still fucking cold.
Scott: fuck.
Rym: Anyway, it was nice today.
Scott: March in the United States for people who don't know means March Madness Which nerds also don't know.
Scott: it's basically when the the the college basketball has a tournament.
Scott: No, I'm a sports fan, but not so much a basketball fan Huge fan of the last 40 seconds of any basketball match.
Scott: Yeah basketball is not my favorite sport I don't know.
Scott: I think it has many problems.
Scott: It shares many with soccer.
Rym: But anyway basketball better or worse than soccer Equal all right basketball better or worse than curling Equal.
Scott: I think curling is probably a better sport, but it's not fun to watch.
Scott: Fun to watch Basketball is a little more fun is more fun to watch.
Scott: if you know what's going on, maybe I mean while the sport of basketball may suck the NCAA basketball tournament is actually a thing of beauty because it is.
Scott: it is a single elimination Tournament with many many entrants now and it is quite often awesome How severe underdogs make it very close to the end or even win.
Rym: the NCAA tournament and the Stanley Cup are my two Favorite sports tournaments.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It is an excellent tournament for a bad sport.
Scott: Anyway, I somebody who comic mix calm Created a webcomics March Madness tournament, which webcomic is the best single elimination voting.
Scott: Oh, let's go.
Rym: That would be easy.
Rym: I was like penny arcade xkc.
Scott: penny arcade made it but it lost to kawaii Not.
Rym: what the hell is that?
Scott: I don't know that was in the that.
Scott: so that was in the Second, so if it would have been kawaii not went to the final four.
Scott: So if penny arcade had won It would have gone to the final four the final four.
Scott: So when was this going on?
Scott: How are they doing?
Scott: They finished it just now.
Rym: clearly None of us knew about it.
Scott: No, it just finished.
Rym: This is why I could something I've never heard of could win, right?
Scott: So kawaii not was against Gronk Which is Katie Cook's comic and they were up against the other two.
Scott: in the final four were earth world versus questionable content.
Rym: really questionable content is not that funny.
Rym: Yeah, and Earth worlds.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: I think it was just near the demographics of the people.
Rym: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: I'm saying was a heavily skewed turn.
Scott: It was skewed to the demographics of the readers of comic mix.
Rym: calm Of course this that would be the same as if I was like, alright, let's have a video game character mashup Who's better Mario or Sonic?
Rym: and I'm only gonna tell people on the Sega forums to vote.
Scott: Yeah Well, this is you know this whatever but the point is okay.
Rym: Kawaii knots not funny.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Scott: You never have you read it?
Rym: I'm reading it right now.
Rym: It's okay.
Rym: It's you know, what?
Scott: How many have you read?
Scott: You only learned about the webcomic less than a minute ago.
Scott: I read like 10.
Rym: Okay 11 They're cute.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: They are they're threadless shirt the comic.
Rym: Oh, all right I never actually I like it, but it's not better than penny arcade or xkcd.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: is xkcd even on here?
Scott: Yes It is Xkcd made it and also lost to Kawaii knot.
Scott: very early on Scott read Kawaii knot.
Rym: it is threadless the comic.
Rym: Every one of them is just a threadless shirt.
Scott: Anyway, the point is is that you should you know, go check out this little tournament.
Scott: It's it's kind of fun, even though we may disagree with the results.
Rym: Okay, this was pretty funny.
Rym: It's humble pie.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not the most important mathematical constant.
Scott: and the final battle is earthworld versus Gronk And the current revoked I'm voting for Gronk.
Scott: earthworld is winning 61% to 39%.
Scott: why is earthworld the winner?
Rym: I Call bullshit on that tournament.
Rym: Anyway, I call absolute bullshit earthworld.
Scott: Oh, actually this Kawaii knot is cute.
Rym: It is cute.
Rym: I like it, but it's not better than xkcd.
Scott: Uh, this birdcage.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's not better than xkcd, but I do like it.
Rym: Yeah ice cream Yeah, but you see what I mean?
Rym: It's like threadless made a comic.
Scott: Yep But I'll only cute.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh that milk one is good.
Scott: Okay, uh Jawbreaker.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I'm more of a threat.
Rym: Yeah Alright after having just read a whole bunch of Kawaii knot and while I call bullshit on the tournament Kawaii knot is an okay comic.
Scott: Oh, man, the yachts.
Scott: Did you read the yahtzee one?
Scott: Yes, I did.
Rym: I'm going to start reading Kawaii knot.
Rym: Yeah, but it's not better than xkcd or penny arcade or dr.
Scott: McNinja.
Scott: Yeah, but it's I don't even think dr McNinja was on here.
Scott: Oh, no, it lost to xkop early on.
Scott: Okay, that's not lost to earth world What?
Scott: Yeah, what earth world beat wonder mark - what.
Scott: and Johnny Wonder wasn't even on here.
Rym: Ah so anyway The meta moment if you saw us at a convention and you wanted to see these slides From a panel we did at that convention.
Rym: Look at the news on GeekNights the archive.
Rym: Yes on our website and the slides are up.
Rym: we also have video of one of our panels the triple threat from PAC.
Rym: so if you like any of our stuff and you didn't see that panel, you'll probably really like the panel.
Rym: and through the power of One HD camera and me zooming in and out on that one camera We've got an okay video probably the best video we've made ever.
Scott: The
Rym: secret is that I zoomed in on me every time Scott was the hypno toting and I zoomed in on Scott every time I was like poking at my face or picking my nose And between the two I could zoom in on one of us and if we were both picking our noses I cut to the slide.
Rym: nice The book club book.
Rym: when Scott finishes it is Michio Kaku's hyperspace.
Scott: The next book club book is We're gonna find out.
Rym: you don't want to announce it yet.
Scott: Wait till we're done with this book.
Rym: Gonna be done with this book.
Scott: We're getting next Thursday episode.
Rym: We're doing this book club and the next conventions we will be at.
Rym: we will not be doing any panels But we will be at the mocha festival in New York.
Rym: Not this weekend, but next weekend.
Rym: Yep Friday Well, yes Friday and Saturday.
Rym: Well Saturday and Sunday.
Rym: Actually, it doesn't actually start on Friday.
Scott: this Friday April 1st Goddamn fuck the internet is useless day.
Scott: Yeah, there will be a Board game night in New York City as usual.
Rym: I'll be there.
Rym: I have a mission.
Rym: I will be out of town, but Scott will be there.
Scott: I'll be there.
Rym: I think Scott should bring a game of Monopoly to play.
Scott: I will not be no fooling I'm just gonna.
Rym: it's gonna be real board game night And we will be at anime Boston in April doing a whole bunch of panels and hanging out and doing stuff And then we'll have a nice break until ConnectiCon and such.
Rym: Yep ConnectiCon the other packs maybe Otakon We I mean, I'm actually really looking forward to anime boss.
Rym: I'm really looking forward to any Boston to one get to hang out with Mike tool and Gerald and Daryl and all my anime con Friends.
Rym: if they go to I get to eat the real goddamn food of Boston on Newbury Street instead of the Non-existent food by the BC going to the secret breakfast every time.
Rym: Oh my god the secret breakfast.
Rym: Oh my god I want that food right now.
Rym: Hunger, those are the best French toasts I've ever had.
Scott: I don't know if ever but that was the one of the best French.
Rym: You know what I'm gonna say long Definitely in the top three because I don't want to commit absolutely top three.
Rym: I gotta think back to make sure there were pancakes I had.
Scott: that were definitely better.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I kind of want to go to Otakon.
Rym: actually, I'm feeling anime cons again after Zenkai County.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's up to Otakon.
Rym: Yeah, it's a hundred percent up to Otakon.
Rym: We submitted all our panels.
Scott: So Out I'm not gonna pay for a badge and I really don't want to wait in line.
Rym: But but I believe I'll even wait in the line.
Rym: I'm just saying if we don't appear at Otakon it has nothing to do with us not wishing to appear at Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, and I would I would go.
Rym: But I think what it is is at.
Scott: you know, every year wasn't too much of a pain in the ass.
Rym: I forget what conventions are like through the cold and horrid winter.
Rym: and Then we go to Zenkai Con and suddenly I remember that you know what?
Rym: I'm not here for me.
Rym: I'm here for all those kids who came to the beyond Naruto panel and walked out of that room thinking hokuto zankai ken That's right.
Rym: That's why we do this.
Scott: We do it.
Rym: So Scott.
Rym: Do you read any of the comics that you read digitally?
Rym: Yeah, which one's penny arcade?
Scott: dr.
Scott: McNinja Oh, you know all those.
Rym: so I guess digital comic distribution works just fine on the internet.
Scott: It sure does.
Rym: I mean granted people pirate penny arcade occasionally.
Scott: How did you pirate penny arcade?
Rym: I mean, I've read it through unauthorized distribution channels in the past.
Scott: I'm sure they're so worried.
Scott: They're coming after you.
Rym: Obviously, we're not gonna talk about web comics other than the fact that I don't know.
Scott: How could you not talk about web comics?
Rym: Well, what does web comics do?
Rym: I think people who do web comics do it primarily for the love of it and would do it Even if it wasn't profitable.
Rym: so as a result some of them Yeah, some of them most of them I think most of the good ones.
Rym: So as a result they do it and They don't worry so much about making money off of it.
Rym: And if they do make money, that's great.
Scott: I actually think it's.
Scott: it's weird though.
Scott: There are a significant number.
Scott: It's obviously not a majority by any stretch right but there are a significant number of the really good web comics.
Scott: right are either are done by people who do it for a living because their comic became popular and then they made money.
Scott: they make their living from merch and such or People who are really good artists who make money by doing art you know in other ways and they happen to also do a web comic.
Scott: that may make supplemental or A significant portion.
Rym: knowing that case it's much like not to name names.
Scott: But for example, we just talked about this tournament right.
Scott: the runner-up was Gronk by Katie Cook.
Scott: Katie Cook makes her money doing arts.
Scott: I don't think Gronk specifically makes her that much money, but you know, she still.
Scott: she makes her money as an artist.
Scott: You know drawing like trading cards and all sorts of stuff.
Rym: So yep, but I guess is that you can if you are an artist doing something You can have a community around yourself and use the webcomic that you do as a focal point for that community.
Rym: It kind of keeps everyone who discovered you at some point and is a fan of your work in a holding pattern around you.
Rym: So whenever you do something new you have this guaranteed audience ready to go.
Scott: Well take for example our friend the author of dr.
Scott: McNinja, right?
Scott: He is now writing Deadpool, which is totally the right move.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: So it's like hey, look at that.
Rym: or look at Brian Clevenger.
Scott: He learned the business making a bit they made a bit theater and now he's doing a Tom Grover.
Rym: Yeah, which is fucking awesome.
Scott: You can't go wrong.
Scott: But yeah, I want to.
Scott: I want to talk about.
Scott: you know digital comics themselves are sort of getting a resurgence now.
Scott: I mean You know we could talk about the same stuff We always talk about with the piracy and the DRM and the copyright and the companies.
Scott: companies don't want to up.
Scott: You know go digital.
Scott: They're so hesitant.
Scott: even it's like you think it's a new thing.
Scott: But really digital has been around for like over a decade.
Scott: It's already like they're already too late yada yada yada.
Rym: well, what I would propose that we do is Remember the last 15 years of arguing about software piracy and then music piracy and then movie piracy.
Rym: Just pretend we'd said all of those things about digital comics, right?
Scott: The only other the only thing to add to that argument right about digital comics Is that we already sort of talked about it a minute ago?
Scott: Is that you know while people sort of have questionable business models for the other mediums?
Scott: There is a business model for digital comics.
Scott: It's web comics.
Scott: It exists.
Rym: Yep, right and if you don't do it then But of course you do have to look at how web comics that do make money make money and it's always either like you We said they make money from alternate revenue streams that aren't even directly related to the car.
Scott: It's it's the same way a musician can make money from concerts as opposed to selling albums.
Rym: Yeah or merch or conventions?
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: Anyway, but digital comics, you know as a thing has been getting more attention than the other, you know did problems meet artistic mediums are having in the digital space recently because of Tablet computing.
Scott: right tablet computers have been around for a long time, but only recently have tablet devices.
Scott: I don't even know if I want to come, you know, I guess it's technically a computer.
Rym: but you know, yeah I'm starting to think however that our clients I think large tablets are not going to be Super popular within I think within five years.
Rym: It's gonna be a fad that dies out a little bit.
Scott: Well, we'll see.
Scott: but anyway because of the tablets iPad specifically digital comics are having a resurgence of sorts in in Attention and popularity and development.
Scott: so I you know there are a significant number of things to talk about in the digital comics realm that do not apply to the You know the general, you know digital art discussions that you have all the time.
Rym: Well, there is the tactile issue of their days and books have the same thing.
Rym: We could basically have this exact discussion about books or comics.
Scott: now It's all different for comics though.
Scott: comics for first of all they need color right and even if it's a black and white comic even if they're So few comics are straight black and white this grayscale and even it.
Scott: and even if it's grayscale you need higher resolution Right.
Scott: I mean I've seen some manga that looks pretty good in a Kindle or a Nook or whatever.
Scott: But really you need you know, it's been so much better on an iPad.
Scott: You know, it looks it, you know, you can't be reading it on I would not.
Scott: Reading a manga on a Kindle would not be acceptable for me.
Scott: I don't think it just wouldn't be.
Scott: it wouldn't be good enough.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: we're not quite there with the screen technology on the Kindle yet.
Scott: I mean, it's like, you know, it's.
Scott: it's sort of this same argument as like the bit rates of mp3s.
Scott: But it's like.
Rym: but Scott technology solved that.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: eventually we got to the point to where I can encode all my music in.
Rym: You know 356 whatever like maximum mp3.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like there is a bit space while you know I'll listen to 128 bit mp3.
Scott: That's just fine.
Scott: But there is a point at which it's like the bit rate is so low.
Scott: It's like unlistenable.
Scott: Well, it's got.
Rym: even I was listening to my old mp3s like from the early days when 128 was really the standard.
Rym: Yeah, they actually sound pretty god-awful compared to modern mp3s.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have much of a problem.
Rym: part of it's because remember the encoding was done differently too.
Scott: Now that is true coding has gotten better.
Rym: Yeah, 128 made with modern codecs probably sounds way better than a 128 made with the original front offer.
Scott: That's true, too.
Scott: But I'm just making an analogy there.
Scott: right there, you know comics on some devices right digitally It's just.
Scott: they're just not acceptable quality to where you can't even read them.
Scott: Right, especially a lot of scans lations are scanned at low-res Scott.
Rym: That's a current thing.
Rym: I mean that'll trivially be fixed by technology.
Rym: Yeah, kinda kind of like how look at movies.
Rym: I mean the two sides of the coin in movies.
Rym: at first it was the problem that there's no way to watch Movies on the go.
Rym: TVs are gigantic.
Rym: Yep, and then we got LCDs and I my game gear.
Rym: I could have bought the TV adapter and watch TV.
Scott: It had that at summer camp.
Scott: He couldn't tune shit.
Scott: We were in a valley in the middle of the woods.
Rym: No, no, but like the technology got better and better and now there are people who just watch movies on their iPhones.
Rym: Yep, and they don't complain at all.
Rym: But by the same token talk to some purists and you'll see arguments.
Rym: to the point of if you think this is a quote You can look up online who said it.
Rym: if you think you've seen a movie because you watched it on a phone You haven't seen the movie.
Scott: That's bullshit.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it is a different experience Eva on the phone on the train.
Rym: Yeah, but you could argue that it is a different experience But it's slightly time.
Rym: The technology has made it such that people don't care.
Rym: It's good enough for them.
Scott: Yep But yeah, but there there are you know, a lot of digital comics, you know, they might you know There's.
Scott: there is a level good enough for them, but there's a lot that are good enough for nobody.
Rym: Well for now, but imagine I mean someday we're gonna have possibly paper.
Rym: That's just like a paper like a comic and it's just digital.
Rym: every page shows whatever you want.
Rym: You just read through it.
Scott: Yeah, that'll be awesome.
Rym: Yeah, we'll have that someday and then it'll be a moot point.
Scott: Yep Anyway, the other problem with digital comics right is the interface of them, right?
Scott: So when you get comics in print, right?
Scott: They're the right size for reading, you know.
Scott: They're the size they were meant to be, you know.
Scott: But if you get them digitally You're only have.
Scott: your screen is only one size but comics come in all shapes guys.
Rym: Clearly I should make a Kindle device just for comics that is as big as the library collections of like Hellboy.
Scott: Okay, and then what?
Scott: if you want to read a death note on it it's way too big letterboxed.
Scott: So you got this giant thing to read a tiny tiny guy?
Scott: Yeah, that's great.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, you realize the real answer in the far future.
Rym: We'll just see it in our brain and won't matter.
Scott: Yes, but we're talking about right now, right?
Rym: I'm just saying technology will solve that problem, too.
Scott: Yes, technology will solve every problem.
Scott: You don't need to state it of everything.
Scott: The point is that right now there's a significant problem with digital comics and that the user interface is Incredibly far.
Rym: Well, actually I have a question then what could like design the device right now That you would just start reading the majority of your comics on if it existed?
Scott: if it existed like a minimum Like.
Rym: obviously you could say the mind thing, but what's like the the minimum?
Rym: like what is the first remember?
Rym: way back?
Rym: We did a show on, you know smartphones.
Rym: What is the minimum smartphone?
Rym: We would buy what is the you know?
Rym: Maximum smartphone we would buy.
Scott: I mean, I think you know, I would probably have no problem reading comics on an iPad to like device.
Scott: You know cuz even if I had to zoom some in or resize some, you know, it sucks, but it's not the worst It's that you know, but the main thing that stops me from doing that is no mostly the pricing and the business models.
Scott: You know It's like they charge so much money to get the comics digitally legally That and it's such a pain in the ass to get them illegally.
Scott: It's just not worth it.
Scott: It's easier Just order them all at his extreme discount in the old-fashioned way.
Rym: now, here's my trouble.
Rym: I would buy digital comics and even a reader for them just because of the convenience.
Rym: but Not only is there DRM?
Scott: Oh, yeah, of course the DRM, right?
Rym: But the quality is also worse like you noted and it's expensive.
Rym: now.
Rym: if they were dirt cheap with DRM and bad quality I might consider it for things.
Rym: I don't care about that much.
Rym: if they were expensive But there was no DRM and they were high quality.
Scott: I would probably pay for it.
Scott: The other thing is not just you know, even with the DRM is availability, right?
Scott: And you know, we're not reading superhero comics that much so it's not like we need.
Scott: you know I care that much if I get the spider-man comic on my iPad the day that the spider-man comic comes out.
Scott: Right because they actually don't do that.
Scott: The point is is like there's no.
Scott: Gary the comics that I want to read like fables I don't think is legally available to read on any digital place.
Scott: Is that there's two different demographic and there's no guarantee that it's always gonna continue to come out in that format.
Rym: it's got the Read and the comics that I read by and large are the ones that people who care about comics read not just superhero comics But comics in general.
Rym: people have a wide voracious appetite for comics and graphic novels manga things like that.
Rym: Those are the people for whom the quality doesn't matter and for whom they probably have Some sentimental or personal reasons for wanting to own the physical volumes for the art for display.
Rym: There's all this other stuff to where they would.
Rym: not enough of them would settle for the inferior digital versions to make it worthwhile to pursue.
Rym: Meanwhile on the opposite side of the coin the people who just care what happened to spider-man They will.
Rym: they'll just pirate it if they can.
Rym: so the that side of the coin is desperately afraid of having any digital version available.
Rym: There's an FDR.
Scott: Well, I think the comics that I would read digitally right would be the ones that basically right now I go through the order form and I'm like No, I mean there's a bunch.
Scott: It's like nope.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: Nope, not a chance in hell.
Scott: Nope, not worth a penny.
Scott: No poop poop poop, but there's a bunch that are like.
Scott: I would read that if it was like 25.
Rym: so Scott imagine you're at the mocha right?
Rym: Yeah, you own an iPad.
Rym: Yep, and you're walking.
Rym: you see a guy.
Rym: He's got something like Black bastard.
Rym: black bastard because like bastard was not the best comic in the world.
Rym: But you know what the concept was worth me paying the 50 cents to have it.
Scott: and there's only 50 cents for black bastard.
Rym: There was some ludicrously low price worth every penny.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: So, you know, we liked those weird like indie things like the weird crap that I would never see this anywhere else.
Rym: I'd never think to pick this up.
Rym: It's not even gonna be in my comic book order for most likely.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: now imagine if you see it and you like it like.
Rym: you see he's got just a picture of black bastard and he's like.
Rym: you want to read it and you're like, yeah and You just swipe your credit card on his little device and it charges you five cents.
Rym: and now black bastard is on your iPad.
Scott: That's awesome.
Rym: And if every time I would buy a lot more comics that things like the mocha if I didn't have to carry them All.
Scott: yeah, definitely last year.
Rym: I was limited by the fact that I ran out of space in my bag.
Scott: Not spit not space in the wallet.
Rym: Wallet is not the issue because they're like 50 cents half of those things.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's great.
Rym: But though I think you're.
Rym: but then again comics like that are almost the comics that could be a webcomic.
Scott: Yeah, that too I mean plus, you know if there were more webcomics that were.
Scott: I think there are ways to easily read webcomics on The iPad.
Scott: I think there's a few apps where you can add RSS feeds of comics and stuff like that to To easily, you know You could like turn it on every day and all your newest webcomics would be there and you could swipe through them.
Rym: Yeah, it's called Firefox.
Rym: It opens a bunch of tabs.
Scott: I'm just saying it's the Firefox isn't on the iPad, you know.
Scott: But yeah that you know, if I had that I would definitely be more convenient to to do that.
Rym: Yeah, because even now I have this problem lately if I carry books around to read them all the time and in New York You know, I'm eating over law.
Rym: I'm reading over lunch.
Rym: I'm reading books everywhere on the subway.
Rym: Books get dirty and wrinkled and I bump them into things.
Scott: cuz I'm carrying them everywhere with me But you can still read them.
Rym: Yeah, I can still read them But at the same time I would like to have the convenience of not having to carry books around everywhere.
Rym: Yeah, I'm actually real close to buying a Kindle or a note just because I don't want to carry physical books anymore.
Scott: So DRM, I know I know you know what I've been doing.
Scott: I've been using my the iBooks on the iPhone and you think oh, that's DRM, too.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: I don't buy any iBooks.
Scott: the iBooks app is actually you can have it read.
Scott: it can read text files and PDF.
Scott: so I got a project Gutenberg.
Scott: I get a text file or PDF and I can just read on my phone and it's actually incredibly readable.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I've been using that too on my palm Pre-running web OS.
Scott: if you got a new phone, that's proper then you could do the same thing.
Rym: I'm getting a new phone.
Rym: I probably will.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yep I don't know I. I feel like this is good.
Rym: digital comic distribution is going to explode on let's say within five years.
Scott: Well, I think digital I mean if you count web comics, I think digital, you know digital comics has exploded.
Scott: I think the problem here right is that you basically have like.
Scott: there's like comic readers are like segregated into all these different.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, I'm gonna go back to my Star Trek thing that no one cares about.
Rym: So the Star Trek convention?
Rym: there's no outrage and it's kind of like there's two separate worlds of conventions the gigantic Modern conventions run by youth who know about technology and the old-school conventions run by old-school people who didn't keep up with the times.
Rym: Yep the comic industry the superhero comic industry makes all its money on the people who haven't kept up with the times and those people are Extremely averse even if the digital things are perfected.
Scott: They're like, nope gotta have paper.
Rym: By catering to those people they also alienate new people who would probably love their superhero comics.
Scott: Yes, and they're afraid of.
Scott: you know This is a lot of the.
Scott: pretty much every business has this problem and I guess this is sort of the thing We were supposed to skip, you know, we said we were skipping right?
Scott: Is that every business that could move digital newspapers comics?
Scott: That right is there simultaneously?
Scott: they want to move because that's the way to go But they'll cannibalize the existing old business by making the move to full-on digital.
Scott: But so they dip their toe in the digital.
Scott: but dipping your toe doesn't work.
Scott: You can't swim if only your toes in the water.
Scott: You can only swim if your whole body's in the water, right?
Scott: There's a chance you may drown Right, but you can't get wet if it would only dip in the toe.
Scott: So they say oh digital failed.
Rym: I'm like Scott.
Rym: you by definition get wet.
Scott: If you dip your toe, you don't you won't get enough wet.
Scott: I'm just saying you don't get wet enough right to actually get anywhere, right?
Scott: So everyone is like dipping their toe in the digital world right as a result.
Scott: They're not swimming anywhere.
Scott: So they declare digital a failure.
Scott: and so they do digital stuff and they don't do it full-on.
Scott: So they abandon it.
Rym: and meanwhile Gabe and Tycho and all the webcomic artist if I was Marvel You know what?
Scott: I would do.
Scott: I would have the biggest balls in the world.
Scott: I would take right all that they have these Marvel and DC both They've got you know, the big ones spider-man Batman Superman x-men Avengers, right?
Scott: I would keep those going for at least a little while.
Scott: Yeah They have all these B and C Level comics that they put out right that are like the hero like the sub heroes the ones that normal people don't know who they Are like the Blue Beetle.
Scott: Yeah, like if you.
Scott: exactly right if you buy you all the superheroes that have their own comic books Where if you walk up to someone on the street and you say do you know who X is?
Scott: and they say I have no Idea who that is that is a B or C level comic, right?
Scott: The only ones I would keep going at least for the start are the a-level ones or everyone knows who they are.
Rym: So x-men stuff exactly see like Batman, right all those other ones spider-man I would make them web comics just like penny arcade.
Scott: Boom a page X times a week for free on the web.
Scott: You know, I'd be like moon night.
Scott: He's a web comic now.
Scott: It's just free at marvel.com.
Scott: I'd go one step further and I wouldn't put it.
Scott: they keep and like for example They have Marvel digital and stuff like that.
Scott: Marvel digital doesn't.
Scott: if you pay for it, you don't get every comic ever.
Scott: you only get the comics that are in the library right now and they put some in and they take some out and Deep in other people and it's in some weird format.
Scott: You can only read it with the Marvel reader.
Scott: It's not just like PDFs or whatever, you know, and people are paying for that.
Scott: So if they've just made I would be like screw that.
Scott: it's a web comic.
Scott: It's a JPEG on a plain old website with an RSS feed and everything.
Rym: I would go one step further and make available from maybe the c-list like the stuff that really isn't worth anything.
Rym: Yep, the entire archives just absolutely open, right?
Rym: but I'd watch and any one of those that started getting popular I Would consider having one making it an a title.
Scott: Well, no, I wouldn't you know, I would continue to let those things The old ones free but do a reboot.
Scott: No, I wouldn't reboot it.
Scott: What I would do is I would those are the ones you.
Scott: basically they're all these free web comics.
Scott: It doesn't cost you that much to have the web comic exist, right?
Scott: It's just a website with JPEGs.
Scott: Yeah, and if no one reads a webcomic just stop doing it because you have to pay the artist obviously, right?
Scott: So you stop paying the artist in that when you cancel it.
Scott: But if people are reading one of them you monitor very closely how many people are reading each one and if one starts to get Popular.
Scott: make sure they keep writing it.
Scott: maybe increase the number of pages per you know.
Scott: Maybe make it five pages a week instead of three or instead of one, you know.
Scott: And then start bringing out the merch and maybe you know Start putting it in print as in addition to being a webcomic and then maybe sell trades like on Amazon.
Scott: If
Rym: the Blue Beetle stuff suddenly is getting really popular then you just announce Hey, if anyone wants to just buy physical copies the Blue Beetle We're doing
Scott: one print run and sell them
Rym: on one time only
Scott: Sell them on the website that has the webcomic, you know Blue Beetle or DC.com slash Blue Beetle, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, you know that's what I'll be doing.
Scott: But there's like they you know, they had to you know Stop making the few thousands.
Scott: They make selling Blue Beetle paper comics in order to do this.
Rym: I also wonder how much money they'd save just on dead trees and distribution.
Scott: I don't know how much the dead trees actually cost.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: not that I know right.
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that I would.
Scott: my guess is that the most of the money they spend is on these artists salary.
Rym: So Scott, here's an argument that is going to be made that would destroy all comic book stores.
Rym: Shit well, you know what?
Rym: what happened to music?
Scott: stars gone.
Rym: Yeah, what happened to blockbuster gone?
Scott: Borders gone.
Rym: the thing is Tonight's doors.
Scott: If you yeah, it doesn't matter because whether you do this or not comic book stores They're going down to tie it back again, except for the really big ones They're going down.
Rym: if we have the situation where music stores and video stores and comic book stores and gaming stores None of them are viable as stores anymore.
Rym: But if the culture around these things grows due to the fact that distribution is free or cheap and people have a lot of access They'd like imagine if you know All this stuff is free and Superman is a ten times more popular because people who would never buy comics start just reading it.
Rym: You could probably then get away with having Cultural centers like instead of the old like Greek Patriots house in Queens You've got the Superman house where a bunch of nerds run the Superman Club
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and I think that could be the long tail of the kind of Generified diffuse geek and nerd culture centered in the cities where there's enough Superman fans to have critical mass of a low-level Constant Superman convention.
Scott: I think you could you could have like the PAX Clubhouse in New York City or Seattle And you could if one person's job to run the clubhouse and everyone out, you know It's just a hangout for those people who are members.
Scott: Oh Scott a membership.
Rym: I just imagined it the penny arcade in like Brooklyn It's just an arcade and a tabletop room and a store and that's it.
Scott: It sells penny arcade merch and some other stuff that's related like dice that you need.
Scott: I'd be there I'd be the ball.
Scott: I'd run the place.
Scott: I'll run the play the manager I'd be the owner founder, whatever.
Scott: It's my idea.
Scott: If you do it.
Scott: I'll sue you.
Scott: But Yeah, do we have a moral here?
Rym: we've gone on for about an hour.
Scott: the moral I think is you know It's a similar moral to all digital things, right?
Scott: It's been over a decade.
Scott: They've been way too slow and making a move.
Scott: the webcomic people have a business model has been proven to work.
Scott: Quality web comics will make money and become popular.
Scott: the print comics need to you know, not just dip their toe in a digital.
Scott: they need to jump in the pool with everybody else and I think you know, we still need though a lot of improvement in the user interface of reading digital comics.
Scott: that's I mean like even people like me who are the most digital are not reading digital comics and paying for paper comics because laws Give it time.
Scott: because I'm gonna take some time.
Rym: I remember years ago when we would both say things like I don't Carry around mp3 players everywhere because they're really expensive and they kind of suck.
Scott: Yeah, like the for the diamond Rio, yeah, I thought there was a time I bought an iPod mini.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah or gigabytes.
Scott: Yeah, and that was that was good.
Scott: That was when it was good.
Rym: We're not even at the iPod mini level of comic readers yet.
Rym: That's the argument.
Rym: I'm making.
Rym: we're barely like we're past the Rio.
Rym: The Rio is my laptop.
Rym: Yeah That's for sure, but we're not there yet.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.