Scott: It's Wednesday, March 2nd.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, My Little Pony with the magical friendships and such.
Scott: Yep, let's do this.
Rym: So I recall back in 2007.
Scott: That's a long time ago.
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Scott: That's, that's like, that's forever.
Rym: And yet we'd been doing GeekNights for a couple years before that.
Rym: But, uh, we reviewed El Hazzard, the original O.A.V.
Rym: and we didn't actually rewatch it.
Rym: We just kind of reviewed it from memory because we'd watched it in the last few years.
Scott: Well, I think I did actually rewatch part of it.
Rym: Yeah, part of it.
Scott: Well, maybe I don't remember.
Rym: We watched the whole thing.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't think we did.
Rym: So I'm actually kind of randomly watching it now.
Scott: The O.A.V.
Scott: or the TV?
Rym: Of course the O.A.V.
Rym: Watch the TV.
Rym: It seems like a trend like that.
Rym: In Mahou Tsukaitai and all those shows, Tenchi Moyo had the great, like condensed O.A.V that was good.
Rym: And then the TV, there was kind of like a watered down version of the O.A.V.
Scott: So I wonder what was, you know, what the cause of that was.
Scott: Was it because Pat LeVoir had a similar thing, but the TV was still good.
Scott: But it was also watered down a little.
Rym: There was definitely at least like some of the creators were, I don't know, too attached to the idea and were like, oh, I got to make more of this.
Rym: This is magic.
Rym: And they never quite recaptured that magic.
Rym: But anyway, El Hazzard holds up pretty damn well, having watched it now from 2011, almost 30 year old eyes.
Rym: I think what helps is that Emily's never seen it.
Rym: So I'm watching it with someone who has never seen El Hazzard.
Rym: You know, is it bad that to this day in that show, every single frame of animation that is in the Abba Abba Zoot Zoot music video stands out like a sore thumb in the actual show?
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: And whenever the any bug rooms appear whatsoever, just like up, even though what are they saying in the show?
Scott: The bug rooms only appearing depends dub or sub in the sub.
Scott: They say like they say something they say.
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: They make like a noise like hubbub.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's a pretty good show.
Rym: I'm enjoying it.
Rym: It.
Rym: it reminds me, though, that I loved that show when I was in a.
Scott: no, it's a bubble bubble bubble bubble.
Rym: That wasn't the bug room.
Rym: That was that little guy.
Rym: What little guy in the first episode, that little guy who kind of runs by them or whatever.
Scott: I always remember that guy.
Rym: I was like, fine, you know, they're in the magical world.
Rym: And Makoto is like, all right, Fujisawa, which way back home, Mr.
Rym: Fujisawa?
Rym: Since it's obviously no big deal.
Rym: And he's like, I'll just ask the next guy who comes by.
Rym: And that's when Bobo Bobo Bobo Bobo Bobo Bobo Bobo Bobo Bobo.
Scott: Yeah, but Cat Armor and Drunken Teachers.
Rym: You complained about what you thought was excessive fan service in Mahoud Skytie.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Elazzard times a million.
Scott: Really?
Scott: I thought I know how Elazzard had some because Elazzard has a scene where there's sort of like the three goddesses are hanging in some sort of spa.
Scott: And it's got a scene about 30 percent that it's got the lesbian princess, but that really only comes out all the time.
Rym: All the time.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: I mostly remember scenes of fighting because I just watched Mahoud Skytie and I was kind of watching it with a critical eye.
Rym: I noticed things I didn't notice as a kid.
Rym: The people are grabbing boobs in the background all the time.
Scott: Oh, in the background.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You mean the king's court?
Rym: No, no, just main characters.
Scott: Because I you know, if it's just the king's court in Elazzard, that's just realistic.
Scott: That's not I mean.
Rym: No, the T&A is off the charts compared to Mahoud Skytie.
Scott: I'll have to rewatch and compare.
Scott: Yeah, good show.
Scott: I believe it, though.
Scott: That show definitely had some T&A leanings.
Rym: The show is definitely very telegraphed, though.
Rym: Emily's pulling the thing that I pulled on you with Gundam Siege.
Rym: She's like, ah, Ifarita, that's probably that one, right?
Rym: Yeah, I got this shit.
Scott: Because they show you all the characters in the opener.
Scott: Except if I made an anime, the opener would not actually show like anything, any characters that weren't in the first episode or anything.
Scott: It would just be like, you know, be like the the Master Keaton opener with birds flying, you know, and the sun rising.
Rym: That's actually one of my favorite anime openers ever.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You know, so nobody will be able to say, oh, I see you put those two characters together in the opener.
Scott: They must be going to get it on.
Rym: Oh, I kind of want to watch Master Keaton again now.
Rym: Uh, that sucks.
Rym: Not all of it, though.
Rym: I want to watch individual episodes like Caliman of the Desert or the wine episode.
Rym: So there's not a lot of anime news.
Rym: And of course, we're kind of chomping at the bit to get to the main bit here.
Scott: So, oh, God.
Rym: Oh, now it starts.
Rym: So I want to talk briefly, just in case no one was aware.
Rym: You all realize that Thundercats is getting a reboot slash remake and Studio 4C is doing it, right?
Scott: Well, there's also going to be a CG movie, I think.
Rym: No, there isn't.
Scott: It looks off now.
Scott: There is.
Scott: It looks like it's the worst.
Rym: There's not going to happen.
Rym: It's a rumor.
Rym: Just like that Avatar movie that M. Night Shyamalan was going to make before.
Scott: Right.
Scott: OK, magic exit jokes.
Scott: Not funny.
Rym: Anyway, not a joke.
Rym: Have you seen Avatar?
Rym: It is not a joke.
Rym: I'm not laughing.
Rym: Anyway, the Warner Brothers is getting together Cartoon Network and Studio 4C to make a pretty badass looking Thundercats.
Scott: Well, badass looking so far.
Rym: Well, based on everything I've seen, it looks badass.
Rym: And one big point, Snarf is in it.
Rym: He does not talk.
Scott: You know, the thing is, there are many annoying characters like Jar Jar Binks, right?
Scott: And Snarf is sort of the Jar Jar Binks of Thundercats.
Scott: And many people view him as such, right?
Scott: They want him out of there.
Scott: But unlike Jar Jar Binks, who was like a late and out of place addition, Snarf was always there from the beginning.
Rym: I think the reason people don't like Snarf is actually pretty obvious.
Rym: If you think about it, people who care about Thundercats now are people who were kids when we were kids.
Rym: Now, being adults, they watch more hardcore, more real, cool stuff, but they still like Thundercats.
Rym: But every time Snarf comes out, it's a Tezuka situation where it kind of takes them out of there.
Rym: Yeah, this is so awesome.
Rym: And Snarf, Snarf, Snarf.
Scott: The thing is, Snarf is not anywhere nearly as annoying as those other annoying characters such as Jar Jar Binks.
Scott: So it's like, I'm down with Snarf.
Scott: It's not like I'm saying Snarf is my favorite.
Rym: It's a good thing they never made those prequels to Star Wars with Jar Jar Binks in it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: I don't really mind that Snarf is going to be quiet because he's still going to be there.
Scott: And he's actually, the design is really cute.
Rym: Yeah, he kind of looks like a cross between those body armor cats from El Hazzar and a Cabot from Tenchi Muyo.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, you know, I wouldn't have minded that much if he talked either, you know, it's all good.
Scott: But yeah, the thing is, when I think back to my childhood, you know, there were many things I liked.
Scott: I know you were the Mask guy.
Rym: Mask and Thundercats are my thing.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like for me, it was like, you know, there was He-Man and Transformers and Voltron.
Rym: I don't think, I don't know if I liked He-Man.
Rym: I don't have sentient memories of like He-Man.
Scott: I had a lot of He-Man toys.
Rym: But I had a lot of He-Man toys.
Rym: I had Battle Damage Skeletor.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I still have Battle Damage Skeletor.
Rym: His Battle Damage stopped working.
Scott: He-Man, Voltron, Transformers, Ninja Turtles, you know, but Thundercats was definitely the most of all of them that I was liking.
Rym: I think Mask was my most, but...
Scott: Not today.
Scott: Today would probably be like Macross or something, but, you know, it was...
Rym: Or maybe a certain other show we'll get today.
Scott: It's not the most.
Rym: No, not yet.
Rym: But also very important, the famous voice, the only voice of Lion-O is in fact going to be doing the voice.
Scott: Oh, thank God.
Rym: Yes, Larry Kenny.
Scott: Because if it wasn't him, it would just be like,
Scott: "Samoflange.".
Rym: What the fuck's a Samoflange?
Scott: Have those ever been a thing of the day?
Scott: Because those are from the year 2000 or perhaps even earlier.
Rym: I will check.
Rym: Maybe I will just link to them.
Scott: They're ancient.
Scott: Well, no, we could use them for a thing of the day.
Scott: Don't just link to them now.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: I got a thing of the day now.
Rym: And people are going to look for it anyway.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So have you got any anime related news, comics?
Scott: I got a comic related news.
Scott: It's an old news.
Scott: It's from some weeks ago.
Scott: It's from December, months ago.
Scott: But I don't think I talked about it on the show.
Scott: So I will do that now.
Scott: Haha.
Scott: Look at me bringing up this old news.
Scott: Apparently, right?
Scott: If we did a show on it a long time ago, Bone, one of the best comics there is.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Though, you know, you might want to listen to our review because it's a great comic, but it peters out toward the end.
Scott: Some people disagree.
Rym: But it's a petering out.
Rym: Kind of what I would say is it's a petering out where you go from a 10 to a nine.
Scott: So, yeah, Bone is an amazing comic.
Scott: You should read it.
Scott: And the best way to buy Bone right now is the one volume edition, which is a big, giant book that has the whole thing in it.
Scott: You're done.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Do not do because when you put it on the table, it makes a noise.
Scott: But it's black and white.
Scott: The one volume edition, which is good because it was originally done in black and white.
Scott: However, in order to sell more copies of Bone, especially in the Scholastic Book Club market, what they have done is they have been over the past years redoing each chapter of Bone one at a time in a colored format.
Scott: So you could buy Bone right today.
Scott: You could buy the whole thing in color in a bunch of separate volumes.
Scott: But now what they are going to be doing sometime in 2011 is releasing the one volume color Bone.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Scott: Hard to hard to make a team to make a two fourteen hundred page color, one volume edition that lays flat when you open it in a in a cardboard slip case.
Scott: It's probably going to be like one hundred dollars.
Scott: Who even fucking knows?
Rym: That's fine.
Scott: It's going to be nine and a quarter inches by seven.
Scott: And the spine is three inches.
Scott: So very similar to the current one volume edition.
Scott: It's approaching.
Rym: Grymore levels.
Rym: Grymore.
Scott: Anyway, but anyway, but yeah, probably going to buy this.
Scott: If anyone wants a black and white one volume edition, I got an extra.
Rym: We could sell it through the GeekNights merch store.
Scott: I could sell it on Amazon more or better than that.
Scott: But yeah, if you're if you haven't read Bone yet, you know, hold out till the end of the year and you could read the whole thing in color in one volume.
Rym: So the coloring job is actually pretty great.
Rym: Like, you might worry that it'd be like those old colorizations about, oh, no, because this is the original guy.
Scott: You know, he didn't do it himself.
Scott: He had this guy help him, but he was still, you know, but I mean, I guess you could consider the coloring canon.
Rym: by the way they did it.
Scott: Absolutely.
Rym: And it looks fucking fantastic.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So things of the day, I was reading anime news, Nina.
Rym: Well, I was looking for some anime news and I enjoy anime news, Nina.
Rym: But that's not my thing of the day.
Scott: Anime news is weird.
Scott: We've talked about it before, but just quickly.
Rym: It is surprisingly biting and realistic about anime fandom.
Scott: Usually when someone makes a comic for the purposes of marketing or advertising or, you know, something like that, it's usually terrible.
Scott: Anime news, Nina, is the only exception I've ever found.
Rym: But the current comic that's up there right now, I'll link to it, makes a joke about Family Circus, that terrible old comic that apparently has been running in newspapers for 51 fucking years.
Scott: Always by the same guy or at least credit to the same guy.
Rym: And I remember it as being terrible and insipid and not funny, not in any way funny, not even.
Rym: So I go to the Wikipedia and occasionally Jesus, because we wanted to see, oh, is it really been going for 51 years?
Rym: And yes, that's true.
Rym: But funnily enough, on the Wikipedia page, there's a picture of a Family Circus comic from like the 60s.
Rym: And it's actually funny.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And I guess that's.
Scott: I guess Family Circus is one of those things where it was originally actually good.
Scott: So it's quality lifted it up and it was in every newspaper and then it just became an institution.
Scott: And then once you're an institution, it's like you have tenure.
Scott: So you just suck and they'll keep printing it because it's fucking Family Circus.
Rym: Especially the whole newspaper comic thing where newspaper comics are the most inoffensive, bland, pathetic pablum I've ever seen.
Scott: Garfield is in the same department.
Scott: It's like because he has tenure, no newspaper will get rid of Garfield.
Scott: He doesn't have to actually make it funny anymore.
Scott: I'm pretty sure the oldest of old Garfields might be funny.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: And at least Garfield and Friends is, even if.
Rym: Yeah, but that's a separate thing.
Rym: We should review that.
Scott: You gotta watch them.
Rym: Thing is, Garfield is actually funniest if you remove Garfield.
Scott: Yeah, well, or rearrange panels randomly.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So there was this video that I watched just fine at work, but for some reason at Rims House, net neutrality prevented me from loading it with any great speed.
Rym: Yet every other, even though it's Fios.
Rym: Every other YouTube video I was watching at the same time was fine.
Scott: Anyway, this video loaded horrendously slowly.
Rym: I blame your laptop.
Scott: No, I don't think so.
Scott: I blame your files.
Scott: So it's called Valparaiso Polk 2011 GoPro HD.
Scott: So you're probably like, what the fuck is that?
Scott: Well, apparently in Valparaiso, which is pretty sure is in Mexico, but I could be wrong on that.
Scott: They have a downhill BMX race, which is basically don't die, don't die, don't die, don't die, don't die, don't die, don't die, don't die, don't die.
Scott: And then you get to the end.
Scott: But it's in a city on this incredibly narrow course that's roped off with just sort of like streamers.
Scott: And you have to go like on ramps and jumps and stairs.
Scott: And it's rough.
Scott: Like you would die if you were in this race or at the very least you would keep hitting obstacles and stopping.
Rym: I might.
Rym: I mean, parts of it watching it, I could do, but not the whole thing.
Rym: I would do them slowly.
Scott: So this is yeah, this is actually a qualifying runs.
Scott: The guy doing this, you know, is all alone and he does the whole thing on his own without stopping pretty fast.
Scott: It's it's and you got a first person view with the helmet cam is pretty exciting, especially the stairs.
Scott: You're like, oh, oh, it's like if you were sitting on the seat going down the stairs, the pole, the bike seat would just shove right up your.
Rym: So very briefly, the meta moment we will be not this weekend, but next weekend at the Penny Arcade Expo doing five panels and three panel rooms.
Rym: The first one is Friday night.
Rym: We will also be at Zanko Con the following weekend, 18th, 19th and 20th of March in King of Prussia, Pennsylvania.
Rym: It's a rockin' anime con.
Rym: Our friends run it and we're actually doing mostly gaming panels.
Scott: Exciting.
Rym: We're doing brand new PAX panels, actually.
Scott: In April, there's going to be a mocha festival.
Scott: There's going to be an anime Boston.
Rym: We'll be at both of them.
Scott: Yeah, there's some New York technology stuff going on.
Scott: I forget exactly what the calendar.
Rym: That's a fantastic news there.
Scott: Yes, I forgot.
Rym: Scott, I believe what you just said is something's happening in New York.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Then I forget it's on my calendar.
Rym: The book club book is still Michio Kaku's hyperspace.
Rym: We were still waiting for Scott to finish reading it.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: Hasn't been that long.
Rym: And if you want gig nights merchandise, we haven't talked about this in a while.
Rym: Our old Soviet Union shirt is almost out.
Scott: So if you want one of those, nobody's ordered one in a while, I think because we stopped mentioning it.
Rym: Yeah, so we have our shirt in the e-commerce store.
Rym: Supplies are very fucking limited.
Scott: If you get one, then you can wear it to any of these upcoming conventions and we'll see you.
Rym: Yeah, we'll be like, hey, thanks for giving me some money.
Scott: Yeah, and then as soon as we sell these out, then we'll probably have a greater incentive to make more new stuff and also reprint the current shirt.
Rym: Yes, new stuff first, though, because if we say we'll reprint these once they sell out, there's no incentive to buy one.
Scott: Yeah, we'll only print them, you know, print new ones if there's a strong demand for them.
Scott: Maybe we'll do preorders for a second printing or something like that to see if people even want them.
Rym: Also, join our forum.
Rym: It's pretty rocking.
Rym: I don't think we need to say anymore.
Rym: So we heard about to get right into it because people have been asking for an episode on this for a while.
Scott: We heard about my little, but it just hasn't been a Wednesday.
Rym: Friendship is magic from a multitude of sources over the course of some weeks.
Scott: I mean, it started out when I saw some buzz on Twitter among some anime fans like Gerald and such.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they were saying, hey, there is a new My Little Pony show.
Scott: It's actually good.
Scott: And I was like, oh, I'll make a note of that.
Scott: And I made a mental note like, oh, there's a new My Little Pony show.
Scott: It's good.
Rym: Scott was like, yeah, you see that tweet?
Rym: And I'm like, yeah, we should watch it at some point.
Rym: And then they say it's good.
Rym: Maybe we'll do a review.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And, you know, we just sort of I took a note and I put it aside.
Scott: And then I saw some other tweets and some other information that was like.
Scott: this show is made by Lauren Faust, who apparently Craig McCracken, who is a guy who worked at Cartoon Network on many shows like, I think he worked on Dexter's Lab and Samurai Jack and, you know, many other good Cartoon Network shows.
Scott: You know, he is the wife.
Scott: He's the husband of Lauren Faust.
Scott: Lauren Faust is the wife.
Scott: And she worked on Powerpuff Girls and also this other show that I never heard of called Something Imaginary Friends, according to Wikipedia, at least.
Rym: I also have an interest in Hasbro in general for various reasons.
Rym: So I knew that it was on their new network that they kind of launched with Discovery called The Hub.
Rym: And it's kind of one of the flagship products.
Scott: Well, My Little Pony is on the hub.
Scott: The shows I just mentioned were Cartoon Network shows.
Scott: Lauren Faust, you know, had a reputation for quality animation work.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So they came.
Scott: What happened is Hasbro bought half of Discovery Kids Network, which is, I guess, terrible.
Rym: Well, it's a joint venture to make this kind of.
Scott: they own.
Rym: they own half of their work designed to sell toys via animation.
Rym: They have a remake of like Pound Puppies.
Scott: They got a remake of Pound Puppies.
Scott: They got a Transformers show.
Scott: They got a whole bunch of stuff on this network.
Scott: And at night, they even have a show that they have a game shows that are themed after many board games like the Game of Life and shit.
Scott: And they got, you know, at night, it's sort of like a Nickelodeon format, like cartoons all day and like old TV shows all night.
Rym: But it's definitely like the original Nickelodeon 24/7 advertisement for their products.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: There was actually some buzz against it.
Rym: Like we shouldn't let a TV company be run by a toy company for children, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: But so we finally got around to it.
Rym: I got a torrent and YouTube and such.
Rym: And we watched the My Little Pony and it's all right.
Rym: It's OK.
Rym: It's fucking awesome.
Scott: I mean, it's not like, OK, it's not.
Rym: it's no cowboy bebop.
Scott: No, I mean, it's not a cowboy bebop or an Evangelion.
Scott: It's not an artistic masterpiece.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it has.
Scott: it has something special about it.
Scott: To where everyone basically can't stop discussing it.
Scott: They can't stop thinking about it.
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: it's like crack.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can.
Scott: you watch it and there are certain parts of the show where you groan or you don't like certain characters.
Scott: You don't like certain episodes or scenes.
Scott: You know, it has a lot of flaws, but there's just something about it to where you just want to watch it all the time.
Rym: And everybody is crazy about it and arguing about it has spread through our large circle of listeners and friends like a virus.
Rym: I mean, we get Scott and I watched it and we got into it.
Rym: So we made other people watch it.
Rym: I think it culminated.
Rym: we had a big party up in Albany with like our whole crew and a few of us, the ones who were in the know, were like, yeah, my little pony and the rest.
Rym: Everyone else like, what the fuck is wrong?
Scott: And at least 75 percent of all talking period was pony talking only among the people who knew.
Scott: And by the time we were done, everyone knew.
Scott: True.
Rym: But in the beginning, it was just us and certain other people who were talking about the ponies.
Rym: Everyone else is just like, Jesus, what's wrong with you guys?
Rym: Stop talking about the ponies.
Rym: And then we made them watch some ponies.
Rym: And with one exception, they were they were hooked.
Rym: Yeah, there's something to this show.
Rym: I really like it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I have some theories, like some sort of subliminal.
Rym: That's Emily's theory that that there's some sort of subliminal message that between every frame there are boobies and explosions and guns.
Scott: It's possible.
Scott: Bam, bam, bam.
Scott: I think there might be.
Scott: We had to slow that shit down.
Rym: Alternate hypothesis.
Rym: Rainbow Dash.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So so his is the deal with this show, right, is?
Scott: I did some investigating.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because, you know, we were earlier in this episode, we talked about Thundercats and He-Man and stuff like that.
Scott: And, you know, I liked He-Man when I was a kid.
Scott: But He-Man was terrible when I went back to watch it for recent years.
Scott: It's just awful.
Rym: And I did not watch My Little Pony as a kid.
Rym: I saw the movie in the theater.
Scott: I think I might have seen a movie in the theater, but it might have been a Care Bears movie.
Scott: And I don't remember at all.
Rym: But as a kid, I thought My Little Pony was stupid.
Scott: I thought it was stupid.
Scott: I mean, I saw I encountered some of the toys at girls houses and they were not exciting.
Scott: And I never saw the show on TV.
Scott: I just knew it existed because I saw commercials for it on TV when I was a kid.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: My Little Pony.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I knew My Little Pony existed.
Scott: But now that I like My Little Pony, I researched and all the old My Little Ponies.
Scott: This is G4, by the way.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, they talk about Generation 4.
Scott: Well, they talk about it the same way with Transformers, right?
Scott: Except, you know, this Transformers G1, G2, G3.
Rym: Now I point out, the way nerds are talking about this show is very indicative of its mass appeal to nerds.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Rym: I mean, people like us are using the lingo, kind of like how if Batman, the animated series, hadn't been great, like if it had been dumb, we would have called it the Batman cartoon.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But because it's good.
Scott: BTS.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It has an acronym, a canonical acronym among the fans.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So this is MLPFIM, which is an initialism, not an acronym.
Rym: Yes, it is.
Scott: Anyway, so...
Rym: But I said BTS.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So my research has determined that My Little Pony's G1 through 3 are awful.
Scott: And Generation 2 and 3 are actually kind of recent-ish.
Scott: Only one is really old, but they're all awful.
Scott: Like completely painful and awful.
Rym: And rebooting My Little Pony have been terrible because it was such just a saccharine, "Yay, little ponies, girls can brush their hair and oh my gosh...".
Rym: "Sell the toys, we don't care about making a good
Rym: show.".
Scott: But My Little Pony Generation 4, Friendship is Magic, is great.
Scott: And what's really scary is if you look on, for example, there's a GIF that's been going around.
Rym: Oh, the YouTube demographics?
Scott: Yeah, it shows the YouTube statistics for the episodes.
Scott: And it's like, you know, demographics watching this show.
Scott: This show, this video is most popular amongst girls, 13 through 17, men, 20 through 30, you know, 30, men, 30 through 40.
Scott: And it's like, what the fuck did they do?
Rym: So had it been older men, like one more generation up, you could have made the argument that it's parents with YouTube accounts showing it to their kids.
Scott: Possible.
Rym: But it is not that.
Rym: It is our generation.
Scott: If you go to any discussion forum that is related to anime, go to our forum.
Scott: How many pages is it now?
Scott: Oh my God.
Rym: There are like 700 posts in one of the My Little Pony threads in the GeekNights forum.
Scott: You go to 4chan, you go to 4chan.
Scott: had to like, there was a guy who went through and they had to have pony limiting rules added because there were too many ponies and people who, you know how the firefly people call themselves brown coats.
Scott: Apparently, if you like my little pony or a brony.
Scott: Yeah, at least if you're a dude, I don't know to the regular.
Scott: I mean, I don't know if you're a girl who likes middle pony bumps, whatever.
Rym: Also note that, you know, everything that gets popular among nerds has this kind of mash up fandom that happens.
Rym: But my little pony came to the table pretty quick with that one epic My Little Pony PMV.
Scott: Well, yeah, that was.
Scott: they even call it a PMV.
Scott: It's not an anime music video.
Scott: It's a pony music video.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like it's because the fandom is one of the best MVs I've ever seen.
Scott: It's a good MV.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like it's up there with the old Kevin Caldwell.
Scott: And, you know, on top of this, right, you have Lauren Faust, the creator on DeviantArt, like actually talking to people about the show.
Scott: And of course, on DeviantArt, plenty of people are posting arts, too.
Scott: So the fandom for this is usploding.
Rym: Now, what's interesting is that I have been emailed.
Rym: I'll keep names out of this, but I have talked to representatives from several companies, both directly and indirectly related to My Little Pony.
Rym: Also, people who run certain conventions we may or may not attend.
Rym: And pretty much at one point, I emailed someone and said, hey, My Little Pony fandom will be surprisingly and scarily popular at your convention.
Rym: I know you won't believe me and I know that sounds stupid, but trust me.
Rym: So and I had some suggestions for what they should do to take advantage of that.
Rym: The response was, oh, shit, yeah, My Little Pony.
Rym: The only people who don't seem to get it are the people in charge of Hasbro.
Rym: But I think all the production team of My Little Pony knows what's up.
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: Well, obviously they do have to talk to people on DeviantArt, right?
Scott: But I wonder how much they do or do not know, because here's some evidence that is going around.
Scott: Here's some things I've seen.
Scott: Number one, they're not taking it off YouTube.
Scott: People are posting it on YouTube, full episodes.
Scott: They're not sending takedown notices.
Scott: At least they haven't yet to.
Scott: they post full episodes like the most recent.
Scott: three or four episodes are just available on the My Little Pony website.
Scott: No problem.
Scott: Free.
Scott: Just watch them.
Scott: They don't care.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Honey Badger doesn't give a shit.
Scott: You know, in addition, like they you know, they're not so good at making toys, but they have put them out pretty quickly.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, what's said, I got a link to the video.
Rym: I still haven't uploaded it, but the toys look pretty piss poor, to be honest.
Rym: And it bothers me that they're awful.
Rym: I'm used to it.
Scott: Couldn't even like they couldn't even keep the princess white.
Scott: They had to make the princess pink.
Scott: Look at anime.
Rym: The crappiest PVC looks like the character, the crappiest one.
Rym: The one you get in a little ball from a gachapon machine looks better than what the Hasbro toys look like.
Rym: But our friend Natalie bought all the toys and just by doing their hair actually made them look ninety nine percent awesome.
Scott: All right.
Scott: How about that?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I feel.
Rym: but then again, think of it this way.
Rym: They probably didn't expect.
Rym: Here's my guess.
Rym: They did not expect this to happen at all.
Rym: So they made the show aimed at kids and the people doing the show.
Rym: You know, Lauren files.
Rym: They decided that, all right, we're given this property.
Rym: We have to do something with it.
Rym: Let's make it as awesome as we can.
Rym: God damn make it.
Rym: So as a result, because they're good people, it was awesome.
Rym: And it has this appeal that Hasbro did not anticipate.
Rym: And I would hazard that they're leaving the YouTube videos and all this Internet stuff untouched because they're not sure how to take advantage of it.
Scott: Well, because I mean, they're going to quash it.
Scott: They're smart.
Scott: You know, they should realize that their goal is to sell toys and they should make better toys.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: Here's the show to be free.
Rym: You didn't let me finish.
Rym: I think the reason the toys are pretty weak is that it's a long time from we should make a toy to a physical toys in stores everywhere.
Rym: I'm pretty sure these toys were long in a pipeline and they came out and it was far too late to do something different by the time they realized that people like me are watching My Little Pony, probably more so than eight year old girls.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: You know, there is.
Scott: there has been talk that there are some sort of executive pressures on the show.
Scott: Right.
Scott: She doesn't there isn't like this full creative control.
Scott: For example, the princess was supposed to be the queen, but they call her the princess.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Well, because, you know, Disney has made it so the princesses are good and queen are bad.
Scott: So you don't want to call her the queen.
Rym: As a result, it's the principality of Equestria, as far as we can tell, unless maybe it is a kingdom and there's a regency.
Scott: We don't know.
Rym: We don't know.
Scott: But you also get it going down that road.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, this show, one of the main reasons that I think it has, you know, so much interest from the nerds is that, you know, on the surface, right, there's sort of like, you know, this painful kind of stuff.
Scott: A lot of the things in the episodes are just sort of, you know, girly and sort of like, you know, like, oh, she's making dresses for everyone.
Rym: Oh, no.
Scott: And then at the end of the episode, it's like the like writes a letter to the princess.
Scott: That's like incredibly non-subtle moral lesson for children.
Rym: Today, I learned that racism is not a good idea.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, oh, really?
Scott: It's kind of painful for someone who's almost 30 years old to watch that.
Scott: But beneath the surface, just lurking there is like this mythology that is being built in an extremely nerdy way.
Rym: The show, we're calling this now, we've coined a term, it's Gandalf's girths, because we way back, we went to see Inception and me and Scott and a bunch of our friends were arguing about what actually happened at the end.
Rym: And at one point, Scott says something along the lines of, this is stupid.
Rym: This is like arguing how long Gandalf's dick is.
Rym: There's just no way to know.
Rym: And I immediately put forth that, no, his dick is seven inches long.
Rym: And we realized that nerds love to talk about Gandalf's dick.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, basically, when you have a world of fiction, right, there's going to be things, you know, when the world is being built, when there is, you know, a Forgotten Realms or any sort of any sort of world
Rym: building correctly,
Scott: any sort of world building, there's going to be things that you know about the world.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Baldur's Gate is here.
Scott: And, you know, look at the expanded Star Wars universe, this old and this many levels.
Rym: I mean, it's got income, I think, made the X-Wing.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Rym: Not in the movies.
Rym: Nope.
Scott: But there are certain things you do not know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like how many, you know, as long as Gandalf, how many horsepower does a speeder bike have on Endor after it gets broken a little bit?
Rym: You know, nerds will take that question and say, all right, well, if we see it in episode six, it's moving, you know, at this rate relative to the trees.
Rym: So it's good.
Scott: But then if you pull the thing down, it goes even faster.
Scott: Isn't this a higher speed that they don't use?
Scott: And then they, you know, he pulls on the throttle.
Rym: Look, the one stormtrooper that was knocked off of and hit the tree, he hit hard enough to crack his helmet.
Rym: So how strong are the helmets?
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, that kind of argument.
Scott: That's Gandalf's dick, right?
Scott: Because nowhere in the Lord of the Rings does it talk about Gandalf's dick.
Scott: It doesn't even say he has a dick.
Scott: He doesn't pee.
Scott: But he's a man.
Scott: He must have one.
Rym: So how long is it that it is seven inches long?
Rym: Because that is a solid length that is not excessive.
Rym: It's not crazy.
Rym: It's not like 40 feet.
Rym: You shall not pass.
Rym: But he wouldn't have a tiny one or even an average one.
Scott: Kidney stone, you shall not pass.
Rym: He's Gandalf.
Rym: He's not going to make it tiny.
Rym: So seven inches is kind of be like like the muscle car.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, so, yeah.
Scott: My Little Pony Friendship is Magic is loaded with Gandalf's girth questions, right?
Scott: Like, for example, the old palace is in the Everfree Forest.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What's the deal?
Scott: What's the deal with the Everfree Forest?
Scott: How come the ponies manage all the weather?
Scott: The princess has to make the sun go up and down.
Scott: But the place of the Everfree Forest is the clouds and the weather move on their own.
Scott: And the animals are wild animals.
Scott: But the animals who live in Equestria outside of the Everfree Forest, they have to wake the animals up from hibernation and feed them and take care of them because the animals can't manage themselves.
Scott: They're all domesticated.
Rym: I mean, look at the society.
Rym: There are clearly different like Twilight Sparkle is clearly of the nobility.
Rym: I mean, she lived in a lot and she moves to this kind of backwater town with all these kind of provincial people.
Rym: And yet she has magic.
Rym: She's a unicorn and unicorns and Pegasus and earth ponies all have different things.
Rym: But during the winter wrap up, they weren't allowed to use magic.
Rym: It's their old earth pony tradition.
Rym: I get this sense that the earth ponies were there maybe before Equestria.
Scott: Yeah, well, no, the earth ponies founded Ponyville a hundred years ago.
Scott: It said so Equestria is at least a thousand years old because that is how.
Scott: So we can already see the direction this is going in.
Scott: It's totally this crazy fantasy world.
Scott: And if you are a nerd, they drop these tidbits of information all over the place.
Scott: And little girls, I don't know if they notice it or not.
Scott: I hope they do.
Rym: But nerds notice immediately that Fluttershy is one year older than Pinkie Pie.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: They also are like, so where does Pinkie Pie live?
Scott: Oh, she lives in an apartment above the cakes bakery.
Scott: And she works for Mr.
Scott: and Mrs.
Scott: Cake baking, you know, and where Rainbow Dash lives in the little cloud palace she made for herself.
Rym: And only Pegasus ponies can stand on the clouds, which matters in the episode when they go to Cloudsdale.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You know, it's actually, you know, incredibly consistent.
Scott: There are some inconsistencies, but they are few.
Rym: And we have noticed all of that, like the carrot tops head was green in one episode.
Scott: It's like, did she just dyed her hair or there's another carrot girl?
Scott: But no, Cutie Mark makes you unique.
Scott: So there's not two people with the same Cutie Mark.
Rym: There's also.
Rym: some people have one Cutie Mark of like one symbol and some have three.
Rym: And it seems like there's different power.
Scott: I think the Derpy Hoops has like five bubbles or something like that.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Or seven bubbles.
Rym: Derpy Hoops.
Rym: But there's some weird ones like.
Rym: Twilight Sparkles is kind of different, too.
Rym: There's a bunch of stuff going on.
Scott: Well, Twilight Sparkles is in the same style as so.
Scott: So, yeah, the princess Luna.
Scott: No, the princess Luna has the moon.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And then Princess Celestia has the sun.
Rym: Now, Twilight Sparkles is a Pegasus unicorn pony.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: She's a Pegacorn.
Scott: No, the two princesses are Pegacorns.
Scott: But every other pony is either an earth pony, a Pegasus or a unicorn.
Rym: Now, I wonder, I mean, it's almost like if you look at this, like look at the Prince of Nothing with the non-men or something, maybe there's like they're likened unto the gods, the two princesses maybe descended from the gods.
Rym: And there were earth ponies that were already there because earth ponies have their shtick.
Rym: I mean, they're skilled or whatever.
Rym: I feel like through interbreeding over the years, if you have royal blood, you get either wings or horns, but for some reason, not both.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of stuff like that.
Scott: But another another thing related to that right is, remember, this is made by Hasbro, right?
Scott: Hasbro owns My Little Pony.
Scott: They own Transformers.
Scott: They own a lot of other nerdery things like that.
Rym: But let's see.
Rym: Let's see if they can guess the other thing they own.
Rym: Let's see if they can guess what has appeared in the show so far other than ponies.
Scott: Well, you know, plenty of things, but cockatrice, manticore, dragon, dragon.
Rym: Who owns Dungeons and Dragons?
Scott: Yeah, OK.
Scott: They own Wizards.
Scott: Hasbro owns Wizards of the Coast, which owns Magic the Gathering and also Dungeons and Dragons.
Scott: I do not think it is a coincidence that you are seeing, you know, sea serpents, hydras, griffins and all these sorts of fantasy monsters right appear.
Scott: I mean, manticore, specifically cockatrice, specifically in this show for little girls.
Rym: I will bet the chimera is the next one.
Scott: A chimera is a very likely pick for something to appear.
Rym: I did like how the hydra had one kind of dumb head.
Scott: It's a hydra.
Scott: That's how it works.
Rym: They always have one dumb head.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You know, I mean, most of the inconsistencies in the show are like, how come she didn't use her teleporting magic right there?
Rym: But there are good arguments to be made as to why she doesn't.
Rym: I mean, it clearly takes a lot of effort and she has trouble with it.
Rym: And remember, when she teleported under duress that one time with Spike, she burned him.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: But anyway, yeah.
Scott: So this show has a new episode every Friday, and it's strange that the episodes air at one thirty and ten thirty.
Scott: Not that I'm watching it on TV.
Rym: I'm watching it on YouTube.
Rym: One thirty.
Scott: Who's watching the show?
Scott: at one thirty or ten thirty?
Rym: Never in my life have I been home from school at any point from kindergarten through my senior year of high school by one thirty.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: Ever.
Rym: Now, maybe it's the DVR generation.
Rym: Maybe they expect parents to DVR it before the kids get home and they show it to the kids as soon as they get home.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe they just expect people to watch it on YouTube because they want to give the good time spot to the Transformers.
Rym: But then why the nine o'clock at night?
Scott: Nobody's talking about the Transformers show at all.
Rym: Or the pound puppies.
Scott: Oh, good God.
Scott: It doesn't look good at all.
Scott: I haven't watched it, but it doesn't look.
Scott: it's not a my guarantee.
Scott: It's not a my little.
Rym: I did like my pound puppies as a kid, though.
Rym: We'll see if I don't know if it's actually good.
Scott: You should try it out.
Scott: Go back and watch them.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: So, Scott, I have a really tough question for you.
Rym: Who is your favorite non rainbow dash pony?
Scott: A non rainbow dash pony?
Scott: Yeah, probably Twilight Sparkle because she is sciency and she is not crazy.
Rym: She's pretty level headed.
Scott: All the other ones are totally crazy in some way.
Rym: Big Macintosh.
Scott: Big Macintosh is cool, but I mean, he doesn't have enough screen time to be like a favorite or anything.
Rym: Yeah, I'm actually kind of warm into rarity, though.
Scott: Well, I mean, I'm warming on rarity, but I mean, she was so far down that a slight warming does not bring her up to above anybody.
Scott: Maybe she's above like, you know, Cutie Mark Crusaders.
Scott: That's about it.
Rym: I don't mind.
Rym: I don't know why you hate the Cutie Mark Crusaders.
Scott: They're just annoying.
Rym: The CMC is not that annoying.
Rym: It's pretty annoying.
Scott: They're just whiny little kids.
Rym: Only be annoying if they get too many episodes.
Scott: They've already got another episode coming next week.
Scott: This week.
Rym: I also think they could be saved if we have an episode where Rainbow Dash is taking care of them because she would not take care of them for shit.
Scott: Well, she tried to help out.
Scott: There was the pre Cutie Mark Crusader Apple Bloom episode where Rainbow Dash is trying to give her all sorts of training, trying to help her get her period as fast as possible.
Scott: Yeah, didn't work.
Rym: I there's the show also.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: It has moments that are funny no matter what age you are.
Scott: Yeah, it's like even if the plot of a particular episode is painful, it has legitimate comedy, usually coming from Pinkie Pie's department.
Rym: Pinkie Pie is the only pony who makes me laugh out loud contextually.
Scott: Yeah, she's supposed to.
Scott: It's intentional funny jokes.
Rym: But when they all got herpes and Twilight Sparkle had her and I didn't even do this.
Rym: This was Emily.
Rym: We were watching and she's there and her horns all limp and covered in pustules.
Rym: She's like, oh, my God, my horn.
Rym: And she's talking to Spike and it's kind of waggling around in his face.
Rym: And she cracked up long before I did at the obvious phallic reference that could be made to the floppy herpes infected horn on Twilight Sparkle's head.
Scott: I mean, it's a unicorn horn, right?
Scott: A lot of people say unicorn horns are originally a phallic thing, but not at least they are.
Scott: They aren't in the show, but you can make anything into a phallic thing.
Rym: But note how the fans are also obsessing over.
Rym: I mean, on the wiki, people have identified every single motherfucking pony that has been shown at any amount of time for any amount of time in the entire show.
Rym: Yeah, it's like she's for ponies that are in the background once.
Scott: You know, because think about you're making the show, right?
Scott: It's made in flash.
Scott: So what they do is they just like, OK, we need to have a background with a whole bunch of ponies in it because it's like the town hall meeting.
Scott: So what do they do?
Scott: They just make a whole bunch of ponies.
Scott: They color them all different and give them just a randomly generated cutie marks.
Scott: Like someone just sat there during like 30 cutie marks and slapped them on.
Rym: Yeah, but now because fans pay attention, notice how they are using the same like core set of side characters, almost Simpsons style all the time in the background.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, Derpy Hooves, they you know, there was the one they accidentally had her give her derp eyes.
Scott: So now she keeps reappearing with derp eyes and, you know, and at the same time, you've got like the guy with the hourglass on his ass.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Hooves.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Hooves.
Scott: You know, you've got who else is appearing frequently?
Rym: Carrot Top.
Scott: Yeah, the carrot pony.
Rym: Everyone likes the carrot pony.
Scott: I like the carrot pony.
Rym: I like the carrot pony, too.
Rym: I actually really like Cheerilee, the teacher, just because she shows that picture of herself from the 90s.
Scott: It's totally 80s.
Rym: Like late 80s, early 90s fashion.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's a good one.
Scott: Oh, there's also, you know, it's like, take for example, right, the episode where, you know, the episode where she makes all the dresses.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And it's like, OK, you know, the episode itself, you know, had the painful parts.
Scott: Like I didn't like the singing.
Rym: I like the singing.
Scott: I do not like the songs in the show.
Rym: I actually really like the songs.
Rym: The Winter Wrap Up song has been stuck in my head for weeks.
Scott: Winter Wrap Up song is probably the best song, but that's not saying.
Scott: that's not saying much.
Scott: That's like saying the least smelly poop.
Rym: I like Pinkie Pie songs.
Scott: I mean, some of them are funny, but they're not.
Scott: they're not songs.
Rym: I even like the Grand Galloping Gala one because it's just so spastic.
Rym: She's just kind of hopping around.
Rym: I enjoy it.
Rym: But I like Rarity's song, too.
Rym: I thought it was good.
Scott: Like half the episode is her singing the song twice.
Rym: It wasn't.
Rym: Yeah, it wasn't half the episode.
Scott: It was a great significant portion of the episode was her singing the song two times.
Rym: Besides, that episode was about tribes, too.
Scott: Well, that's what I'm saying.
Scott: That episode.
Scott: Right.
Scott: On the one hand was, you know, you know, on the surface level was just sort of like, all right.
Scott: But the message, you know, that an adult would get watching that show is like this twofold message.
Scott: On the one hand, you got the tribes to message, which is let the designer do what they do.
Scott: They know what's best.
Scott: If you listen to the community, you're just going to ruin your game.
Scott: tribes, too.
Scott: And also, if you're hiring a freelance designer, don't just, you know, it's basically you could tell that, you know, someone who had, you know, freelance design experience had written this episode.
Rym: Emily had a lot to say about that episode after we watched it, especially because we had moments in the past where she will show me a character design for something she's working on.
Rym: And she will say, how does it look?
Rym: And I'll say something like, I don't know, make it like 20 percent cooler.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Just needs to be cooler.
Scott: And it's like that is how non artists, you know, critique art.
Scott: It's like they don't know what's good, you know, and Fluttershy gets mad points for her rant, too.
Scott: Well, at least Fluttershy had some knowledge about sewing.
Rym: Yeah, but her dress was still awful.
Scott: Yeah, it was still awful.
Scott: But I guess it was well made.
Rym: And there's a lot.
Rym: I love the show for a lot of reasons.
Rym: But some of my favorite moments are surprisingly not the unintentional humors, like in the Zecora episode with the zebra.
Rym: I really like the intentional humor when Pinkie Pie tries to sing her song and she can't.
Rym: And she gets Fluttershy to do it.
Rym: But I also like the unintentional humor of the fact that Rarity is racist and does not become terribly disabused of her racism by the end.
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: I mean, she's like, oh, she's covered in stripes.
Rym: How awful.
Rym: And Twilight Sparkle's like, you realize that she was born that way.
Scott: And she's like, oh, my.
Rym: But yeah, he was born Japanese.
Scott: Yeah, I guess the other thing that I really like about the show, right, is that the animation quality is like the production quality as a whole.
Scott: Like I might not like the songs, but the singing is actually good and the voice acting is really good, which is really weird because a lot of the voice actors were also bad anime dub.
Rym: This is why I want to interview them, because I have a theory now.
Scott: All right.
Rym: No, none of these voice actors were in any way bad voice actors.
Rym: They were poorly directed and given shit scripts.
Scott: Also, maybe I have an additional hypothesis.
Scott: When they were doing the anime, they just didn't give a shit.
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: But when you see because it wasn't their character.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But now this is their character.
Scott: It's like they.
Scott: whoever it is is Rainbow Dash.
Scott: So they're going to own that.
Rym: It's hard to say, though, because like Lisa Ortiz fucking owned Lisa.
Rym: She fucking owned Lena inverse.
Rym: Yeah, like that was her character.
Rym: She loved that as far as I could tell.
Rym: And I don't think it.
Rym: I think that it's just going to come down to the fact that the production values and the direction in anime dubs is probably pretty poor because this day you play any anime dub other than Cowboy Bebop in another room and ask someone to tell you if it's an anime dub or not.
Rym: 100% accuracy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But My Little Pony sounds like people talking.
Scott: Yeah, it sounds great.
Scott: And, you know, the animation it's done with Flash and it's really, really good.
Scott: And the thing that I find being the most funny in the show aren't so aren't even the intentional jokes while those are good.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's usually I find myself most entertained by just very quick, you know, very short moments of a facial expression here or a quip there.
Scott: Just like it's like a whole bunch of really small things, but they're happening constantly and they're all like terrific.
Scott: You know what's funny?
Rym: You know, we said the same thing about just to make a point here.
Rym: Mahout Skytie.
Rym: That there were that the visual gags were very well executed.
Rym: The animation was very high quality and that the gags and the one offs and the snarks and the facial expressions were being done constantly, even in the background, which My Little Pony also does.
Scott: Well, I mean, the example that always comes to my mind is mostly, you know, Rainbow Dash because she's the best.
Scott: She is the best.
Scott: But it's like, OK, so when they end in the Sonic Rainboom episode where they pick her up at the end and she's like, oh, my gosh, oh, my gosh, oh, my gosh, oh, my gosh.
Scott: After she wins the contest and gets the little Greek feathery crown.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The way she sort of wiggles is just like it's like eye candy the way she's wiggling there, like, oh, my gosh, oh, my gosh.
Scott: And then there's also the time where she kicks the dragon in the face.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And the dragon's like the Rainbow One kicked me.
Scott: And then she just sort of smiles and nods.
Scott: And it's like, hells yeah.
Scott: Like the way she smiles and nods.
Scott: It's like a fraction of a second of animation.
Scott: But it's just.
Scott: it's just like so fun to look at.
Rym: Well, Rainbow Dash edges toward the Internet face very often.
Scott: I mean, how are you mad?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: A lot of the times, you know, it's like Rainbow Dash is the best because when, for example, when they're fighting over the grand galloping gala tickets, everyone's like, OK, you know, you can have my ticket.
Scott: I don't want to go.
Scott: If it's going to cause you so much trouble and everyone's like, all right, I'm giving up my ticket except for Rainbow Dash.
Scott: She's like, I got the day.
Scott: Yeah, it's mine now.
Scott: And then she's like, oh, all right.
Rym: There's a little bit of bender in Rainbow Dash.
Scott: Yeah, the benderness.
Rym: But Rarity has a lot of moments like that, too.
Rym: She has this face she makes when she's a guest at something where her eyes get really small like, oh, oh, or when they're having the sleepover and Applejack's dares her to go outside in the rain and ruin her hair.
Rym: And she just walks out and she's like, oh, oh, oh, the sea serpent, my moustache.
Rym: I note that the men in the show all have fascinations with moustaches.
Rym: The one sea serpent is fabulous.
Rym: Moustache like Spike really wants one snips and snails.
Scott: They liked it.
Rym: They like their moustache.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The only thing about this show that has me slightly, you know, scared is the fact that, right?
Scott: When was the last time any show like this was?
Scott: was capturing people to run to watch?
Scott: the next episode immediately was years ago, like 04, 03, perhaps.
Scott: I don't remember exactly the Full Metal Alchemist.
Rym: That was the last show that I was like, oh, shit, next episode.
Rym: Got to watch.
Scott: But where's Full Metal Alchemist now?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: However, is My Little Pony the next Full Metal Alchemist or does it have the staying power?
Rym: However, I have counterexamples.
Scott: Or is it a flash in the pan?
Scott: A bright flash in the pan, but a flash nonetheless.
Rym: When I was in high school, I watched, for example, Escaflowne and El Hazard.
Rym: And Lane and all these anime and one VHS tape would come out every month that had four episodes on it.
Rym: And you can bet that we would go to the store the day it came out, buy it, immediately run home and watch it.
Rym: Those shows hold up.
Scott: They do.
Rym: Also, I really think that Lauren Faust knows the deal and she definitely knows the deal.
Rym: if no one else, unless Hasbro cocks it up, she will be able to maintain this show.
Rym: And it's got a full twenty six.
Scott: It has twenty six episodes.
Scott: And, you know, it could be renewed forever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's possible.
Scott: I mean, I don't really know if it isn't.
Scott: It's like, all right.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: If it was plenty of shows out there to watch.
Rym: But if it wasn't, I would.
Rym: This is the kind of thing I would try to invest in to make happen again, because I think it could make a lot of money.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: They just we'll see.
Rym: I mean, what they need to do is, for example, if they sold Rainbow Dash T-shirts in like Hot Topic, those would sell like hot cakes.
Scott: Probably.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I would buy one Rainbow Dash T-shirt if it was high quality.
Rym: It'd have to be the same level of quality, though, as my shirt.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like that kind of styling.
Scott: Is there anything else to say about My Little Pony?
Rym: Other than Gandalf Gerthing.
Rym: I have a lot of Gandalf Gerthing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's basically it's a show that has a target audience of little girls.
Scott: that somehow magic.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, they didn't.
Scott: they tried to avoid being a stereotypical bad show, like one good example, Hasbro has a result.
Rym: Guys like Hasbro had one victim.
Rym: They're like, all right, we need to have a fashion pony.
Rym: We need to have a fashion element so we can do whatever marketing we're going to do.
Rym: So what did the studio do?
Rym: They made Rarity.
Rym: She's not an air headed shopper girl.
Rym: She is a professional world or at least equestria renowned dress designer.
Rym: They made her a maker and a doer and an expert.
Rym: And also in general, at least for us, I think, Scott, you're the one who said that watching them is like watching a pony front row crew, because if you notice the ponies that are the main characters are kind of like the leaders of everything in the town.
Scott: Well, I mean, well, the thing is, right, it's like the mayor is kind of incompetent.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And Twilight Sparkle, who's nobility.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's basically Twilight Sparkle went out to Bumblefuck.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Ponyville.
Scott: And she's nobility.
Scott: And she's actually educated because she's an academic.
Scott: So she actually knows things.
Rym: Except about Paris sprites.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Scott: And it's the only basically the few things that she doesn't know.
Scott: Pinkie Pie is a secret genius and knows every and in the town, even though everyone is much less educated than Twilight Sparkle.
Scott: So she can totally help.
Scott: You know, she can really run things, helping everybody.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Even though they're much less educated, at least, you know, quite a few of the ponies just have a particular skill or three that they are just incredibly they're like superhuman super ponies of that one thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the ponies, the main character ponies are definitely more highly skilled than the rest of the ponies on average.
Scott: Well, at least the other ponies don't demonstrate their skills on screen often, or at least they don't.
Scott: They also don't use their powers against D&D monsters.
Scott: Like true.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: And Mrs.
Scott: Cake are probably just as good at making cake as you're probably better at it than Pinkie Pie, because Pinkie Pie also is partying and has partying skills.
Rym: I saw a pretty good Andrew WK music video to Pinkie Pie.
Scott: Her baking skills are secondary to her partying skills, right?
Scott: So they're probably really good at that, but they're not baking cakes and feeding them to the dragon.
Rym: There are also incompetent ponies.
Rym: You know, what's his name?
Rym: The guy who lost the grass seeds.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Or the other guy who went south north to get the southern birds.
Rym: And don't forget derp and derp.
Scott: Derp and derp, snips and snails.
Scott: Or the barbell football and basketball ponies.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The show also cannot resist a horse related pun.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: But they do them.
Rym: I'm going to admit this.
Rym: I don't do it often.
Rym: Scott doesn't do it often, but it happens occasionally when someone in the front row crew will say some pony or every pony instead of somebody.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or there's like, you know, Philadelphia, cloudsdale, trottingham.
Scott: There's a lot of alliteration going on to plenty of this alliteration and horse related puns nonstop.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: It's weird because usually puns are just like, oh, puns.
Scott: They're just grown worthy to the max.
Scott: But these are actually good puns and they don't use them too much.
Rym: Not too much.
Scott: So it's tolerable.
Rym: So, I mean, the moral of all.
Rym: this week, we're going to we'll talk about the show again.
Rym: We've obviously tried to avoid the Gandalf questions, which are 90 percent of what I have to say.
Rym: The show is great for what it is.
Rym: I highly enjoy it.
Scott: And it's really enjoyable.
Scott: But it's like if I had to.
Scott: it's like, how much do I like it right now?
Scott: I like it a whole lot more than anything else.
Scott: It's on my mind because it's subliminal powers.
Scott: But how much do I like it compared to other things I like?
Scott: Not as much, you know, probably in the expand of my life.
Scott: So it's just hot right now.
Rym: How long between when the next episode is available and you watch it as fast as that guy gets it on YouTube?
Rym: It's also kind of a meta thing in the forum.
Rym: We weren't kidding.
Rym: My Little Pony thread is like 20 percent of the current activity in the forum right now.
Scott: And most of it Gandalf gurthing talk, but also plenty of meme generating talk.
Scott: You know, people making fan arts, fan mixes, you know, there's a pony in one fraction of a second in one episode.
Scott: It was a DJ.
Scott: So now DJ Pwn-E.
Scott: They gave it a name and there's plenty of YouTube videos of DJ Pwn-E DJing.
Scott: And it's like, OK, this is way out of control, which tells you that they're doing something right.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So if you care about My Little Pony and in particular.
Scott: And no matter how skeptical you are, some people probably haven't listened this far because they were skeptical.
Scott: But you know what?
Rym: Screw you.
Rym: Everybody we've shown it to with one exception has been turned.
Scott: If you are a skeptical anti pony type and you've managed to listen this far just because you wanted to be like, what the fuck, guys?
Scott: Really?
Scott: Are you serious?
Scott: We are serious.
Scott: It's not a joke.
Scott: It's a good show.
Scott: Just you know, we do not.
Scott: we at GeekNights do not knock it if we haven't tried it.
Scott: However, we try and then knock quite often.
Scott: So if you are knocking right now, just try watch episodes one and two and then knock all you want if you want.
Scott: But don't knock until then.
Rym: But as I was saying, if you care in particular about the fact that Rainbow Dash is in fact the best pony in Ponyville, you should go to the forum and vote in our which My Little Pony pony is the best pony thread.
Scott: There's only one right here.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.