Rym: It's Wednesday January 12th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights Tonight who framed Roger rabbit.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So a little context if I may this episode was actually recorded quite some time ago and we kind of kept it in the hopper until we had an occasion to use it and that occasion has Come upon us.
Rym: as by the time you're listening to this Scott And I are probably on our ways to magfest 9 and thus we wouldn't be around to do a show.
Rym: So some of the news is a little out of date and we may or may not have used one of these things of the day.
Rym: Again, I can't recall but it's a good show and we talk about Roger rabbit with a guest.
Rym: No, there's a show that we watch a long time ago that I'd forgotten about until randomly a little while ago.
Scott: I did not forget about it.
Rym: Well, I forgot about it in the way you forget about old anime.
Rym: you watch it and then you just don't like it doesn't come To mind.
Rym: it's not like I'd be walking down the street and suddenly.
Rym: Oh shit mahout sky time.
Scott: It's not a show that really anyone talks about but it was you know, it's in that same category as like, you know El Hazzard.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it was just I remembered being really cute and I remember the crew.
Rym: we all watched it.
Scott: It's actually similar to El Hazzard also structurally that there's no AV and a TV series.
Rym: Is it similar?
Rym: in the same way that the OAV is the only good part the TV series is?
Scott: I don't remember the TV series cuz you know, I never watched it.
Scott: Yeah, so anyway, we're gonna rewatch this and we're it's gonna be a show.
Rym: Yeah It's funny because I barely like I remembered the anime club fighting in the beginning and it was about magic and I remember this One scene where she's dumb and she makes this room like half on the roof on the ground.
Scott: I remembered that aliens with the black ball that rolls down the street.
Scott: Yeah, but that's that, you know, of course there.
Rym: I mean there's the similar weird stuff in gatekeepers With the red hats.
Rym: Yeah, but once I saw that opener with the little dot That suddenly everything clicked together I was like, oh yeah this show and it says something, you know Sometimes I rewatch an anime and I'm not bored.
Rym: It's more like I remember what's happening and I'm like, ah, I got to go through all this shit again But some shows like ghost in the shell watching them again.
Rym: It's like oh man.
Rym: I remember this.
Rym: This is awesome.
Rym: The show gives me more the latter than the former.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: I only watched one episode again.
Scott: So I got five more OAV episodes.
Scott: I watched.
Scott: I'm not gonna.
Scott: I'm not gonna rewatch the TV I'm not.
Rym: even I don't know if we ever did.
Rym: Well, I don't know.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: the TV's good bad different.
Scott: I don't think I ever watched it.
Rym: Well as a warning Ella's are the TV and the second OAV not worth watching?
Rym: Mmm, the TV show is basically the OAV done again, you know now that I think of it Like.
Scott: I'm not even a hundred percent positive.
Scott: There actually was a hosukai type TV.
Rym: I'm pretty sure there was.
Scott: I got to actually go check.
Rym: Yeah, I have to as well.
Scott: I Couldn't really find any exciting news nothing.
Scott: No, but I do.
Scott: I will do geek bite instead.
Scott: And the geek bite I will do is not actually a comic or an anime but is related and I watched the first episode of that Walking Dead TV.
Rym: Ah, I also have seen the first episode.
Rym: apparently my workers are watching it Like like they're watching it right along with the bittorrents.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it wasn't departed way away from the comic.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the first episode like as I don't really remember, you know the complete details of the early parts of the comic but the You know this first episode Definitely had the same tone and characterizations as the as the comic.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it definitely felt like oh, yeah This is definitely Walking Dead zombie world, you know.
Scott: Well, it felt it had that kind of gritty realism that most zombie things don't really and the characters act the way the characters act in Walking Dead and the zombies act the way they act in Walking Dead.
Scott: and They also sort of it seemed to me like they muted the colors to.
Scott: you know, it wasn't actually monochrome But the show definitely felt like it was sort of like they took half the color out.
Scott: You know a lot more like the comic which is monochrome.
Rym: randomly over the weekend.
Rym: I watched the machinist Just a movie that I hadn't watched.
Rym: I was bored.
Rym: It's Dostoevsky retold.
Rym: It's about a guy who hasn't slept in a year and is kind of going crazy.
Rym: and people you go crazy after three days Yeah, and people are leaving post-it notes in his apartment and they Know they're not.
Scott: he's just going crazy thinking this posted Clearly and it's basically Dostoevsky.
Rym: It's like crime and punishment kind of thing.
Rym: It's really good, but it did the same thing.
Rym: It was black and white but not really like it was black and white but every now and then like things would be almost color.
Scott: I mean the show wasn't actually black and white but at least it felt like there was some color that was removed.
Rym: You sure you have you watch anything else.
Rym: is your TVs fine?
Scott: Yeah TV is just fine.
Scott: But basically, yeah, I mean this wasn't a show where it's like, oh man, so I gotta watch every episode day comes out.
Scott: It's so awesome.
Rym: But I In the background, it's a show.
Scott: This is not a bad.
Scott: It is not one of those travesties where it's like, oh it ruins all the good from the original.
Scott: you know the beginning of The Walking Dead is probably the best part of the comic and This show is also good in the same way for the same reasons.
Rym: Well, like freaks and geeks or you know arrested development shows that I would never sit down and just watch but I'm hanging out Playing a game I could watch it like while I'm doing stuff.
Scott: Yeah, you know this is a show where it's like if I you know, it'll go somewhere in the middle of the queue.
Scott: It's like if I'm you know run out of like the best stuff to watch.
Rym: It's like oh kind of thing I put on the TV when I'm I don't know mopping or doing all my grown-up stuff.
Scott: if it turned bad in a later episode I would just well stop watching.
Rym: well bad in the way that the comic gets kind of dumb later.
Scott: Oh, well the comic gets dumb and then undumb and then you know It's a very switchy back and forth.
Scott: you think the comic also wasn't helped by the changing of artists.
Scott: You know, the original artist is much better than the artist they switched to.
Rym: Sorry - though Apparently artist they say I mean the TV show is short and it's gonna end and they already signed on.
Rym: They're going to make a sequel obviously a second season.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know, we'll see how it goes.
Rym: It seems to be really popular I'm pretty sure all those actors and be big at the New York Comic Con.
Scott: if you like a walking dead and you like a Zombie or both or you know, you should probably read the comic and watch this show.
Rym: I'll say this they're pretty much equal on the enjoyment level of all the zombie things other than Of the living dead the original zombie thing.
Rym: Well effectively the original zombie thing I don't you know, there's other zombie things that came before that but It's pretty much the best if you want realism and interesting characters.
Scott: How about Dawn of the Dead?
Rym: Dawn of the Dead was good It's right.
Rym: It's up there.
Rym: Close might be a tie but World War Z is nowhere near.
Scott: Anyway, anyway.
Rym: So our friend Mike tool, you know We write stuff for the anime news network among other awesome things and he does very amazing panels.
Rym: Have you ever had an anime convention and you see Mike tool doing anything?
Rym: Just go see it.
Rym: It doesn't matter what it is even if it doesn't look like.
Rym: you'll like it.
Rym: you'll like it trust us because if nothing else he'll just show you stuff that you Would never see.
Scott: that's generally the trick is people don't?
Scott: most people don't realize when you're deciding what panel to go to at a con Don't look at what the panels about right?
Scott: Look at who's doing it.
Rym: Yeah, Daryl Surratt It doesn't matter what he's talking about.
Scott: It's gonna be hilarious or us or Mike tool or any of the other awesome people.
Rym: Yeah Christian daily You know old RIT anime president, but speaking of old RIT anime Mike tool did a recent article that we're actually featured in a little bit.
Rym: He emailed us and a bunch of other people we know some time ago and he was like Hey, you guys were big in anime clubs.
Rym: Tell me a little bit about your old anime clubs.
Rym: I'm doing an article on him and the current state of him and everything.
Scott: So you said I'm like a fucking essay.
Scott: I said him like a five-page and he was like I expected like a paragraph.
Scott: you guys sent me an essay But it's like.
Scott: dude, you should know if you ask us anything We're gonna you know, we're gonna give you every piece of information that we've got.
Scott: We're not gonna hold anything back like Rym.
Rym: How long's your penis?
Scott: Well If we measure it in Cartesian coordinates Let us go down and discuss every molecule from the base to the tip by number of zip codes.
Scott: It will be point zero zero zero zero zero zero times ten to the six times ten to the negative.
Rym: It's not as big as Gandalf's zip codes the solid nine inches.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway.
Rym: So he did this article on anime clubs and it's really good.
Rym: he talks about the current state of them what they were in the past and if you don't if you're an anime fan and You're already on the right track.
Rym: like you're paying attention to directors and character designers And you're going to conventions and learning about anime and watching weird old stuff.
Rym: You're on the right track.
Rym: But the next step is to actually read articles about anime written by people who know what they're talking about.
Rym: You know the books the articles the lectures.
Rym: Fred showed all those people.
Rym: That's the next step.
Rym: So it's shot.
Rym: I had his shot.
Rym: I realized that I was hoping you would just be quiet.
Rym: Let me continue on.
Rym: then I was gonna edit it out later in post.
Rym: but now.
Rym: So this article is fascinating and as an aside Scott doesn't think you'd want to hear it?
Rym: I think you would.
Rym: we haven't done it a long time.
Rym: Should we do a show on r.i.t Anime, we already did the show.
Rym: I think we should do one.
Scott: We already did the show.
Rym: see listeners.
Scott: We don't have a shortage of Wednesday show listeners.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: They want whatever Scott doesn't want because I I am the candidate who is here for you.
Scott: Whatever you I just gonna have to figure out all the shows that I want to do that You don't want to do and then ask the listeners and they'll be like we don't want to do that.
Scott: About that we'll say zombies.
Rym: Zombies are constitutionally banned.
Scott: There's a constitution of geek names.
Rym: There is now.
Rym: But what this article really struck me when I read it and then when I thought about what I'd written.
Scott: I haven't read it yet.
Rym: So I got it and seeing other anime clubs Goddamn was the r.i.t.
Rym: Anime Club awesome.
Rym: Like I always thought in my head like yeah, that club was crazy Awesome, but it was my club.
Rym: I have a very skewed opinion.
Rym: Jesus Christ RIT anime is like the best anime club ever.
Scott: I don't know if it's a thing is like.
Scott: I don't know if it's still what it was, right?
Rym: It's like the last I heard it was.
Rym: we ran into the publicist I met.
Scott: I met the librarian and it sounded like, you know, they lost their club space But he was still keeping the library strong as best he could but I'd still.
Scott: I couldn't get any idea of like how many people Showing or if they were still doing as many less as bigly and awesome numbers I got.
Rym: as an aside if you look in the comments on Mike's thing more people mention r.i.t.
Rym: Anime than any other club.
Rym: So, uh-huh.
Rym: Well, you know, but and a lot of r.i.t.
Rym: Anime people are out and about doing.
Rym: you know big stuff running conventions and everything, but I Don't know.
Rym: I feel like r.i.t.
Rym: Anime is still pretty strong.
Rym: less numbers I heard where they're still pushing 150 or so people in meeting give or take.
Rym: Hmm I don't know how accurate that is.
Rym: If any r.i.t.
Scott: Anime people are listening You know, I know that we do have listeners at r.i.t.
Scott: At least one.
Rym: So if you're not going to the club go and go.
Scott: not go into the club go spy Just go to it once and tell me what's going on.
Scott: or you know Tell the president to email us or some shit because I don't let's get them on this.
Scott: Let's actually get the r.i.t.
Scott: We should get the r.i.t.
Scott: Anime club president on the show.
Scott: then we could do a show about anime club.
Rym: Actually, it would be a fun thing is try to get all the r.i.t.
Scott: Presidents As many r.i.t.
Scott: Anime club presidents as possible on the show.
Scott: at one time we could.
Rym: I could get six.
Scott: we could probably get.
Scott: Let's see you.
Scott: Scott Johnson Lisa Christian daily Luke Technically.
Rym: Mike Lynn was president for a little while.
Scott: Yeah, but how are we gonna contact Mike Lynn?
Rym: I I could get contact with.
Scott: we could get Jason or Saudi.
Scott: Yeah, and I guess Liz.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if we can get Liz.
Rym: I think we get Liz.
Scott: Well, we know like Yeah, the other guy named Scott that we don't really know.
Rym: I don't know him But the thing is Christian daily might be able to get him.
Scott: and if he can't Yeah, plus I think I think I mean that tells you something about the r.i.t.
Scott: Anime club.
Scott: right how many people did we just name?
Scott: like ten people and But you're only in college for four years.
Rym: So somehow the Hall of Kings was remembered.
Scott: It's like yeah, it's like There are kings from before we were even there and kings after we left and we still know them You know and they're all connected to each other.
Scott: That's that's you know, and some of these people had multi-year reigns.
Scott: This was not like.
Scott: everyone was in an in-and-out situation.
Scott: Some of these people had very short reigns though as well.
Rym: Yes, there was political drama There were there were kings and despots and revolutions and all king is dead and long live the king.
Rym: But anyway check this article out king and if you're at a convention keep an eye out for Mike tool.
Rym: He's.
Rym: he's on the good list in our opinion of anime and wearing MLS soccer trees.
Scott: That's how you know, Mike tool is Yeah, really big.
Rym: Yeah, like whoa, he's tall He could crush my head like a watermelon.
Rym: Anyway things of the day.
Rym: So I like anime openers like there was a time before I had access to a lot of anime and before there was YouTube Or bit tauren or anything like that.
Rym: I would go to sites and download Avi's or m pegs of the openers to anime that were not available in the u.s Yeah I mean there are still some shows where I've only ever seen the opener.
Scott: I've never seen the show and it was like that weird fucked up Pokemon ish thing.
Rym: Oh, right jeep baku.
Scott: Yeah, what the fuck was that?
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Scott: We could find out what it is.
Rym: I did.
Scott: I actually I do know what this story was with that or like Aaron's about you that we found out later was actually Shitty fighting game that had a different name in the u.s Yeah, they actually had a used copy of the GameStop that we didn't buy.
Scott: They see the shittiest fighting game in the world with the real the best opener and opening song in the world.
Rym: that opener I was like.
Rym: this anime is so of my.
Scott: I mean, it's a fighting anime, but goddamn was that a good opener?
Rym: I think the song was primarily what made it a good opener.
Scott: Yeah, that's kind of like most of what an opener is.
Rym: is the song kind of like a tenshi muyo gxp?
Scott: Yeah, that was the best opener to the worst show.
Scott: I mean if you took opener quality to show quality ratios Tenshi muyo gxp is the highest ever.
Rym: I mean the only thing that might possibly beat it is noir.
Scott: No, because noir is a much better show than tenshi muyo gxp.
Scott: Yeah, you're right.
Rym: You're right.
Scott: No opener is not as good as the tenshi muyo gxp opening.
Rym: nuns with guns lava No blood, you know one woman with a pistol takes out like 80 guys Open field.
Rym: that show wasn't stupid.
Rym: But tenshi muyo the worst I'd say.
Scott: noir is a good show.
Scott: I'm just saying who is better?
Scott: It's like comparing two poops, which is the least smelly poop, you know, what's great.
Rym: You know gxp was bad.
Rym: But the worst part is not only was it bad But none of the characters that the fanboys even wanted to see her in that goddamn thing for like the first half.
Scott: Is it better or worse than photon?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I put them in the same category of unwatchable.
Rym: It's like the untouchables.
Scott: They're basically the same.
Scott: They're easily the same thing, right?
Rym: They're yeah untouchable.
Scott: I Don't know they might be unlookable.
Rym: So anyway This is simply every.
Rym: well You know We have those things we show at anime cons or whenever we need to like fill a room or kill some time of every robot Anime opener in contiguous order.
Scott: I love that.
Scott: We should watch this.
Rym: is that for anime that aren't robot shows?
Rym: But interestingly enough some of them are robot.
Rym: It's really short and you'll see why because it's every anime opener ever.
Scott: It is every anime opener ever.
Rym: It's great Just like it was good the part when it just starts panning up to someone's face and then into the sky Like that was the best part The part where people are running to the left.
Scott: Yep, or the subtle one where the birds birds birds different birds more birds.
Rym: Well, there's two different kinds of birds.
Rym: There's like the one seagull flying out over the ocean and then there's the flock of birds.
Scott: There's a drop of water drop of water drop water drop water drop.
Rym: the teardrops go Sideways from a woman as she turns her head.
Scott: Yeah, or the head turning head head turn to look at the camera.
Scott: I don't look at the camera didn't?
Rym: the subtlest one was the zoom in shakily on an action scene.
Rym: Oh, that's a good reason.
Rym: not many old anime did that.
Scott: Anyway, so check this out, right?
Scott: some guy You know how some people would like take the shinning and then they would make it look like it was a feel-good movie Except between the hours of what?
Rym: two and four.
Rym: Yeah, that's Willis time really the most quotable episodes of The Simpsons ever, right?
Rym: basically Also a movie.
Scott: what these people did here or maybe one person did is they took?
Scott: Akira the movie.
Scott: All right, and they took some music.
Scott: I'm not sure exactly what music it is.
Scott: It's very is it?
Scott: yeah It's very familiar.
Scott: It's not Final Fantasy music.
Scott: yes, that's Lapta.
Scott: does?
Scott: I feel like there's a Final Fantasy song that's very similar.
Scott: Anyway, it's a little kind of similar But it's like the Lapta music and they took Akira and they put them together and it's Akira x Ghibli.
Scott: So it looks like Akira was a Ghibli movie.
Rym: You know what this gives me?
Rym: Ghibli Ghibli.
Scott: Anyway, it's it's pretty good and it serves many purposes like reminding you that Akira is amazing and lol Look at that.
Scott: They made Akira look like Ghibli and if you've seen Akira, it's like double lol.
Scott: You know what's actually going on in that scene versus what this sort of fake trailer would imply is going on in that scene Like Speaking of the Ghibli Ghiblis.
Rym: before we get to the meta moment I just want to point out you should go on YouTube and watch all the cutscenes from poker night of the inventory.
Rym: Yeah as a show it's basically like a half hour Animated show.
Scott: think of it as an anime.
Scott: don't think of it as a game, right?
Scott: I bought the game because it was like five bucks, right?
Rym: I watched it on YouTube.
Rym: Does that mean I pirated it?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: but basically right it's you play.
Scott: all you do in this game is play poker.
Rym: All you do in this game is watch the heavy.
Scott: you play the tiny heavy.
Scott: you play poker with strong bed the heavy Tycho from penny arcade.
Scott: and this is it max from Sam and Max?
Rym: I think you've never played a 7 max game.
Rym: Have you no idea?
Rym: actually he I think is the weakest link in this show.
Rym: Yeah He only has one trick, but they use the shik a little too much.
Scott: Yeah Basically you're playing poker with these four guys who are fictional characters and they're very funny.
Scott: They're very funny until they start repeating the same joke over and over again And then you're done and it's basically a single-player poker game that you you know.
Scott: He just goes on forever with nothing else really going on.
Scott: So you might as well.
Scott: the only reason to play it is for the joke.
Scott: So watch all the jokes on YouTube and then you're done just when heavy keeps calling strong bad tiny heavy.
Rym: There's something about that.
Scott: So without any further ado the meta Moment, let's try not to forget any things.
Rym: All right for anyone who hasn't paid attention the geek died store has one item for sale our original t-shirt.
Rym: We will have new stuff Relatively soon, but don't hold your breath cuz he'll die.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There was something to correct from a previous Wednesday episode.
Scott: I wanted to make a correction, but I forgot what we got wrong, but we did get something wrong and we will correct it.
Scott: Yeah, really really?
Rym: Just We're gonna be at mag fest.
Rym: We're part of the mag nine.
Rym: We're gonna be on to discussion panels with the mag nine other gaming intellectuals.
Rym: We're also gonna be doing a panel called I forget which panel we're doing.
Rym: losing should be fun.
Rym: I think is the one we're doing.
Scott: It's good panel, whatever Mag festival see a party.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Pax East will be at very likely will be at anime boss.
Scott: Max East is in a hundred days 99 days fuck.
Rym: we're gonna be at anime Boston most likely.
Rym: We'll see if we'll be at Otakon.
Rym: I'm gonna put this out there right now.
Rym: We've never been denied in like a decade panels at Otakon.
Rym: every year since 2002.
Rym: We've done one or more one year.
Rym: We did like seven.
Scott: we denied them last year just because they didn't get the schedule to us 2,000 2 3 4 5 6 7 8.
Rym: so they mine.
Scott: they might Legitimately deny us because we denied them and they're like, oh those guys are now unreliable.
Scott: So then we're gonna deny them.
Rym: I just want to get it out here now.
Rym: It'll be.
Rym: it'll be very telling as to how they can do.
Scott: if they want I don't care they can and if they don't then if they get the schedule out on time Then we'll go.
Rym: thing is it wasn't even the panel schedule.
Rym: It was our own staff schedule.
Rym: was what we were waiting on.
Rym: Yeah, right, but basically I just get this out here now because we're gonna you know if we're gonna submit our panels to Otakon like we do every year and Our panels have never failed to fill the room.
Rym: So we'll see if Otakon wants us to do panels or not.
Rym: if we don't appear at Otakon It is not because we are not willing to do panels.
Scott: No, it's you know, because something they did not, you know do enough.
Rym: Yeah, and if you have any strong feelings about that let appropriate people know I guess.
Scott: and if you if you want to say well, why should they do anything for you?
Scott: It's like well look at what Pax does for us.
Scott: Yeah, and so everyone else, you know Anime Boston does more for us than anyone else.
Scott: They do more for us than Pax.
Scott: So Otakon is just us to step up.
Rym: also as another kind of I'm curious listeners out there Let me know if you've been to like this comment whenever Katsucon happens again Because we stopped going to Katsucon when all the staff we knew quit and the con had a lot of trouble.
Scott: We're also gonna Zenkai con.
Scott: What's that?
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Fuck.
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: It's my calendar.
Rym: Yeah, we'll be a Zenkai con doing a bunch of panels.
Rym: I don't even know which ones will be fine.
Scott: Was it November?
Scott: I feel like we made.
Scott: do we miss it?
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I'm pretty sure.
Rym: if we missed it the staff would have said something like where are you guys?
Scott: I think they just remember it's supposed to be in November But I guess that's.
Rym: it has to be wrong if my phone starts ringing and someone's like guys your panels in like 20 minutes.
Rym: Where are you?
Rym: And I'll be like, New York.
Rym: That's pretty much it.
Scott: yeah, I don't remember any book club.
Scott: is World War Z.
Rym: World War Z was the book club.
Rym: We're gonna do that review as soon as we do a Thursday episode.
Rym: and the next book club book, which we've already announced I'll keep announcing is Michio Kaku's hyperspace, which is a book about reality.
Rym: great Good book.
Rym: what's wrong with you?
Scott: Not exactly fun.
Rym: Ah, actually it's really fun.
Rym: Yeah, you don't even know what it's about.
Scott: I'm gonna counter with some fun.
Rym: You're gonna counter with some fun because for every counter of fun you have I have a counter counter unfun.
Rym: Anyway, you keep pushing.
Rym: you're reading Ulysses.
Scott: You don't want to read that.
Rym: Okay, so So because it's her favorite movie and being an animator she has some expertise.
Scott: It's really a favorite movie Like a lot.
Rym: it is definitely on my list of movies that like.
Rym: it's in my top 50 of movies.
Scott: I think top hundred of movies.
Emily: and we were going to do this show together Like a way long time ago like a month ago, but because of a crashing Maya and various other problems I was way late and I only caught the tail end and then I had a phone meeting with Taiwan.
Emily: The show was Postponed until a later date because I said guys can't do it without me.
Rym: I have to be there for the work even now and it's postponed even later because we're recording this ahead of time while we're gonna be At magfest.
Emily: That's right.
Scott: Yes Well now they know the secret.
Rym: Oh no the magic of radio has been ruined.
Scott: At least they will not have any strange questions about like why is the news so?
Rym: It's pretty sure.
Scott: one of the things of the day is a repeat thing of the day.
Rym: We'll find out saying that but it is.
Rym: I mean what anime news did we even talk about?
Rym: I have to go find out and then make this post.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So what we're talking about?
Rym: a movie from 1988 an animated wealth path animated movie who framed Roger.
Scott: We were six years old, but Emily was what like.
Emily: I didn't see it in the theaters.
Scott: I think I didn't either.
Emily: I Must have been maybe about seven or eight and I saw it on VHS at my aunt's house And I remember.
Emily: you know It's.
Emily: it's very strange thinking back on my first impressions the movie because I remember it being a lot scarier Because I mean I was like seven.
Emily: I hadn't seen a ton of film noir Detective judge doom at the end and the dip scared Was awful.
Scott: it was a little bit scary.
Emily: It was this one part with a part where they're torturing the shoe with the dip and I was like, oh, this is awful It's like horrible acid shit, I hate it I hate.
Emily: I was so scared of that when I was a little kid and then like once I became older I realized that it was all a joke like that.
Emily: Yep was turpentine and that's what they used to clean the cells off.
Scott: Clean the cells off with.
Scott: but I'm like, why did?
Scott: why would you clean off the cell?
Scott: It's like you just drew the art on it and then they reuse them.
Rym: Yeah, it's From old Disney stuff.
Emily: If they wanted to save money Especially on low-budget productions, they would just keep using cells.
Scott: and actually how much is the cell cost?
Emily: I don't know, but they add up.
Emily: think of how many frames makes your typical animated movie.
Scott: and especially I mean I could understand Understand if you like, you know a race like the cell of the guy's really tiny and far away.
Scott: But if it's like the cell of like he's right up.
Rym: Wasn't it a lot like with old TV shows where they just thought they didn't think there was any value to the fact out Doctor who?
Emily: and so there's all these lost episodes.
Scott: I mean like live radio programs were not recorded in any way shape or form because They just broadcasted some guys with microphones.
Scott: and then that was it.
Emily: well back then I think they didn't even anticipate that there would be a secondary market for Things on on tape or on on digital media.
Emily: I mean there wasn't any digital media.
Emily: and so they figured well we'll have prints of the film, but we don't actually need to go back and Reshoot the film or scan it in because you know that hadn't been invented yet.
Emily: They couldn't have known Cells would turn out to be used.
Scott: Yeah, but even like, you know, regardless of you know, the technology that's available It's like, you know There was just no set.
Scott: It's like they hadn't learned the lessons of any of the previous centuries.
Scott: of that you must preserve.
Scott: put effort into preserving the art or That's a relatively recent movement and also I see beams are pretty old.
Emily: I think part of it is like television and animation and stuff.
Emily: It wasn't necessarily viewed as a fine art but as cheap entertainment, so it it was more an assembly line production than actually.
Emily: You know the feeling of a an artist before his canvas.
Rym: I mean look at like old comic books.
Rym: They they were.
Rym: I mean they were fighting comic books.
Rym: They weren't gonna put him in the museum.
Scott: At least nowadays we seem to have mostly at least not completely but mostly learn the lesson.
Scott: You know people are already trying to save the video game.
Emily: Well and and with the digital society Preservation is a lot easier.
Emily: Whereas back.
Scott: It's not as easy as you think.
Rym: it seems easier in the short term But in the long term it is much more difficult Mental effort and expertise but it doesn't require as much physical space and investment like film You know unrolling it in those long tubes.
Emily: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, sometimes let's talk about this movie.
Emily: Oh, yes, okay, but part of the thing talking about Roger Rabbit is very difficult If you leave out talking about animation history because what the movie is I mean on the surface level it functions as a really fun Mystery movie like, you know is definitely in the style of old black and white film noir Alcoholic hero who's kind of down and out.
Rym: and I have this with a lot like, you know project echo and a lot of things I've seen.
Rym: I thought like.
Rym: as a kid I didn't quite get that they were comedies.
Rym: They had funny moments, but I took him kind of straight up at face value and Roger Rabbit was the same way.
Rym: I remember just getting into it as a mystery movie and it didn't really dawn on me that this was Partly a comedy.
Scott: I mean, I didn't completely understand it, you know, and I was very young.
Rym: I didn't get any of those jokes about Jack Daniels.
Scott: I mean, yeah, there was.
Scott: so there's so many stuff in there.
Scott: That reminds me a lot of the same stuff that Powerpuff Girls used to do where you would tell dirty jokes But kids wouldn't get them.
Emily: Yeah, it's like all the all the more adult stuff.
Scott: It's like it's just right in there and so obvious It's.
Emily: it's called dual address and I learned about this in one of my classes when we were talking about Aladdin.
Emily: But dual address is when you have a thing that speaks to both children and adults But on different levels like when mojo Jojo was in jail and this big really big guy standing next to prison rape always the your go-to example.
Emily: What's the one?
Emily: Liberty Meadows?
Emily: it's like that guy, you know And luckily he ended up going into independent comics so he could draw the big-titted women He wanted without having to worry about newspaper censors.
Scott: He draws a fine.
Emily: He's really really good as
Scott: opposed to some of those fantasy artists Just
Rym: the woman straddling a story.
Emily: Anyway, like Frank Cho back when he was doing newspaper comics He'd always try to slip things in.
Emily: you know that were this strip was supposedly family-friendly, but sometimes it would get a little secretly raunchy, you know, but With with Roger Rabbit, it's funny.
Emily: Like I said, the dip was just one thing that I didn't understand because it was animation lingo And I thought it was just scary like some sort of scary acid.
Emily: Well, that's what I thought too, and I'm freaked out by acid scenes.
Emily: Anyway, I like good they killed us the poor shoe.
Rym: poor shoe didn't?
Scott: he was All right, we got to do a photoshop for that scene where it's crevo shoe that goes in the dip.
Rym: I'd feel too bad.
Rym: They're so rare.
Scott: Over and over again you get infinite crevo shoes.
Rym: So I'm gonna assume we don't really need to worry about spoilers because the movie came out in 1988.
Scott: Yeah, seriously, if you haven't watched it like what the hell?
Rym: I if you have not seen this movie God and watch it right now and then come back and listen to the rest of this.
Rym: Definitely you're about the 37 ish minute mark.
Rym: Yeah.
Emily: Yeah, but Some of the things that I always thought were really weird when I was a little kid and I mean, they're still really weird.
Emily: But the fact that the femme fatale is like married to Roger It's just kind of inexplicable.
Emily: but like, you know you expect You know, mrs.
Emily: Rabbit to be a rabbit and she's not a rabbit.
Emily: She's a very Alluring cartoon songstress.
Rym: I do love that scene where he's sitting there and he's all like Rabbit whatever.
Rym: then she comes out and he just kind of jaw drops.
Emily: Yeah But Patty cake scene Play in patty cake and they're actually playing.
Rym: I like how they animate the patty cake with the pictures.
Rym: I wonder if that was very much intentional.
Rym: I'm sure Come on you well well except for what was that scene?
Rym: Emily?
Rym: you were telling us about where he was looking at the wrong place.
Emily: That was funny.
Emily: that um Animation aside there's this book by Richard Williams called the animators survival kit.
Emily: And if you want to get into animation at all, that's like your primer.
Emily: That's the number one textbook.
Emily: you should get it.
Emily: it covers all the basics and he also has some really funny anecdotes because Richard Williams was the animation director on Roger rabbit.
Emily: and there's this one scene where the the actor who played.
Emily: what's the main character's name?
Emily: I forget but he was very good at maintaining the imagined eye contact with the cartoon because what they do is they'd film the actors and then This Print out every frame of the movie and then the animators would animate over it and then they'd photograph it like a background With a cell overlay like an animated film.
Rym: What's interesting is how like it really holds up.
Scott: Yeah In some ways like it's like whoa, that's you know, that's pretty good skills even for today, right?
Scott: Like in the scene we're like like Jessica.
Scott: I was pulling on his tie You know, yeah, it's pretty good Little mechanical gadgets and stuff like.
Scott: Like.
Scott: there was the scene where all the weasels bust into his office and this is his guns that are just comically floating around.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: did you like, you know take a sleep?
Scott: It was not as good as I mean.
Scott: overall the movie looks better than a lot of CG movies And I mean and while there were plenty of other movies before and since that have done the animation live-action combination It's like nobody's really done the same.
Scott: You know kind no one's done it.
Rym: Well cool world was like another attempt.
Rym: That doesn't really hold up.
Emily: No, no I've seen clips of cool world.
Emily: I didn't actually see it because my parents saw it and they were like It's okay.
Rym: But as a kid, I kind of want to watch it again because Brad Pitt's a really good actor It's.
Rym: I imagine he's really good in it.
Emily: Ralph Bakshi for me is really hot and cold like some of back.
Emily: She's stuff I like and some of it is just like really I don't know.
Emily: Smutty for the sake of being smutty I don't know.
Emily: Sometimes back.
Emily: She's stuff is kind of Lassie Nowadays, right?
Scott: I'm seeing a trend of like this sort of opposite, right?
Scott: Like I saw this trailer when I went to see Tron for this like Disney's Mars needs moms and it was like God.
Scott: It was like real people but in a whole CG animated world.
Scott: No, I guess that backwards people It looks like real motion capture.
Emily: I can't believe you thought those were real people.
Emily: I know they're creepy.
Scott: It looked like real people like at least real faces were used, you know for the Maybe you've made it past the uncanny valley and the rest of us have it.
Scott: But it said it was from the directors or the people who made Polar Express.
Scott: It wasn't Polar Express the same thing.
Emily: where it was Polar Express was like all animation and weird-looking It is Tom Hanks Mars needs moms is the exact same process the exact same Producers and actually strange as it is.
Emily: I believe it's the mekis, right?
Emily: Who did it?
Emily: it wasn't he involved with Roger Rabbit?
Emily: Yeah.
Rym: He was the director of the live-action part.
Emily: Yeah, so he's still around making you know live-action animation kind of Combinations, but they're not as cool and they're really creepy and strange.
Rym: But anyway, there's the scene that we were talking about.
Emily: Yeah, so anyway The the lead actor.
Emily: he was supposed to be making eye contact with Roger Rabbit who was shorter than he was but he he screwed up and they didn't catch it until they had sent the Footage over to the animation department.
Emily: They're like damn.
Emily: This is gonna.
Emily: Roger has to be up in the air if we're gonna have Eye contact in this scene.
Emily: So they like stretched him out against the wall like on his tippy toes for no reason.
Emily: They're like, well, he's neurotic it might work.
Emily: And so there's this one scene where Rogers just like inching up the wall and you're like, what is he doing?
Emily: But it was because they had a had a mistake.
Rym: They had to cover up so various little things But you don't notice it unless you know about him, you know, so they got Bob Hoskins to play Eddie Valiant But apparently, you know, the number one choice was Harrison Ford really just couldn't afford it.
Rym: Well, actually I think Bill Murray too, but he didn't respond.
Rym: I Think the casting worked out really well, I think I mean Eddie Valiant was a good character Yeah, though being an adult.
Rym: I did not notice how much they hammer down the point that he is an alcoholic He is drinking.
Scott: I didn't notice that at all until the most recent viewing.
Scott: I didn't notice that and it wasn't until two viewings ago after learning about it in college that I realized that it was about, you know, the you know, the All the cloverly thing.
Scott: Yeah the conspiracy to get rid of all the trains and the buses, right?
Scott: Because that's something that really happened, right?
Scott: I didn't know about that.
Scott: They bought all the streetcar.
Scott: That's the reason that we don't have trolleys, you know, except for tourist reasons in this country anymore is because you know GM whoever.
Scott: they bought all of them.
Scott: They shut them down They replaced them with buses and they purposefully made bus schedules shitty with shitty routes so that everyone would buy a car And that's why the United States is full of cars.
Rym: What's funny is think about the nice subtle social commentary of the crazy guy at the end Kind of avoiding spoilers, I guess who's like imagine it's a road with people driving a freeway.
Rym: I'll call it a freeway.
Emily: Well, the funniest value is like you're crazy.
Scott: Well, yeah, there's multiple scenes where they show him using the streetcar kids sitting on the back Of it.
Rym: Yeah and all that kind of stuff to show you like, you know, they Also notice how he gets a cigarette from that like 13 year old kid.
Emily: Also, it's kind of funny too because you know The evil guy is trying to make freeways and you realize it's set in LA.
Emily: so Everybody in LA hates the freeways because they're they're insane.
Scott: I mean Los Angeles, but everyone there is but everyone there drives.
Scott: and yeah A lot of LA people comes in New York insist on driving even if the subways.
Scott: Well, there's.
Emily: there's no alternatives in LA.
Emily: They don't have a Bus subway system.
Emily: They got rid of it thing Exactly.
Emily: and that's what the subplot of this movie is about.
Emily: It's about animation history It's a film noir and it's also social commentary about the history And I I like.
Emily: I like some of the Film noir tropes like some of the the lines where this is like Eddie Is that a rabbit in your pocket?
Emily: or are you just happy to see me instead of?
Emily: is that a gun in your pocket?
Rym: One of my favorite scenes is just that little shave and a haircut Do and they can't not do it.
Rym: It was really fun to watch was the Angry Video Game Nerd Cinematica review of Roger Rabbit.
Rym: That's what reminded me.
Emily: I didn't see that.
Scott: I only saw his review of the game because I was oh my god I actually played the game before I ever saw the movie.
Emily: Did you call the phone number?
Rym: No Well, the phone number now goes to a sex line.
Scott: No kidding I played the game with like a feck, you know, and it just went today.
Rym: I tried to play the game legit as a result.
Rym: I never beat it.
Scott: Yeah, I just played it with it with the fact that I happen to have you know.
Rym: Also, it was weird that as a kid.
Rym: I remembered like really not Understanding how they got Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck and Daffy Duck.
Scott: I didn't understand how they did that either when I was a kid.
Rym: I remember as a kid.
Rym: I was like so did it like?
Rym: who made this movie?
Emily: So what's the story behind that?
Emily: I actually don't know that aspect.
Emily: how they got Amazed me.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm like reading through IMDb in the Wikipedia.
Scott: So you still don't know you didn't?
Scott: you just tried to mention it without looking it up before.
Rym: I mean, I thought it was awesome like as a kid.
Rym: It really stood out.
Rym: that like Mickey Mouse and Bugs Bunny.
Scott: It makes me wonder like how come people can't figure this shit out?
Rym: Well, the best I can see is that you know They got Spielberg to do all this stuff and they basically they went into this movie thinking All right, this is our chance to make a super blockbuster.
Scott: Well, it wasn't a super block.
Rym: Well, they wanted it to be.
Emily: did they have to pay for the rights?
Emily: So did they get permission?
Emily: I mean, I understand that there must have been you know Some sort of legal powwow going on between the companies.
Rym: all the legal stuff I can find.
Rym: talk about the sequel that didn't happen and not paying the guy who wrote the book.
Emily: Yeah I was gonna say did you know it was based on a book?
Rym: Yeah, Gary K Wolf right never heard of.
Scott: so the book came first, yep.
Scott: Wow, what's the book?
Scott: the same story?
Emily: No, it's actually really different.
Emily: I haven't read it.
Emily: But I mean it.
Emily: it plays out like a mystery.
Emily: It's you know 1940s 1930s era and Other than that, I really don't know.
Emily: apparently it's a very strange book There.
Emily: but one point though Mickey Mouse kind of a dick, oh they're optics when The worst one is Tweety.
Emily: and Tweety I hate in the cartoons too, but Tweety when he's like
Scott: You know people you don't think about it too much when you're watching a lot of the old You know cartoons because some of them right give you a reason for someone to get the shit kicked out of them.
Scott: Like the you know, Wile E. Coyote doesn't fall off the cliff until he's trying to eat the roadrunner.
Emily: Yeah, it's kind of like karmic bugs buddies.
Scott: only, you know, most of the time is like Elmer Fudd tries to shoot him first.
Rym: Yeah, sometimes he just finds sometimes tortures.
Scott: Sometimes.
Scott: He's just an asshole but like for no reason I don't know.
Emily: most of the time with bugs It's like they cross him one time and then he spends the rest of the episode extracting his revenge, right?
Scott: But I mean sometimes they don't even cross him at all.
Scott: Sometimes it's just like oh you're singing opera.
Rym: All right Torture you have to death the the opera singer.
Emily: He hit him with the thing and and then bugs is always like.
Emily: this means war and then that happens sometimes.
Rym: Somebody should have just called the police and been like this guy hit me.
Emily: There were a couple with the with the thugs weren't there.
Scott: There was the one where he's hiding in the stove.
Rym: He's done it, but I know he's done it.
Emily: That's the other one and the the one where they're in the factory.
Emily: Is that that one?
Scott: Yeah There's one there in the house on the cliff and one there in the.
Scott: they're in a factory or something.
Emily: You know, which one I want to find again is the one where?
Emily: There's the dog who falls in love with the lawn ornament dog and then she gets turned into a bomb.
Rym: You don't remember that one.
Emily: It was one of those wartime cartoons and they used to play it on the cartoon.
Emily: now Vaguely Show the assembly line making a bomb and this lawn ornament dog gets melted down to be a missile anyway, so Roger rabbit like the end scenes are when the animators talent really shines through Where you've got so many different kinds of characters from all from the golden era of a lot
Rym: of them.
Rym: I didn't even recognize some of them like.
Rym: I saw some Looking stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I saw some stuff.
Scott: I didn't recognize like a weird cow, but there was some stuff I totally recognized like the totally hot harp.
Emily: I was like He was like, yeah, it's the harp but we're like you got a thing for that heart who doesn't have a thing for the heart.
Scott: Hey guys, that's who That's right.
Emily: Yep.
Emily: That's that harp.
Rym: Anyway, so currently they sell Charles Fleischer who did the voice of Roger rabbit.
Rym: for many of the scenes He would just dress up in a rabbit costume.
Rym: Just kind of bothering people.
Scott: and you hear my joke about the heart playing with it.
Rym: I'd love to see a video of that.
Emily: Tell us watching the heart play with and they had like the Some really early stuff like the the trees flowers in the trees.
Scott: Yeah, I never seen them.
Emily: I've seen.
Emily: I actually may not have seen it either.
Emily: I Know I've seen tons of clips of it.
Emily: So I recognized it, but I'm not sure if I've seen the whole thing.
Scott: but yeah, it's like there's this whole big parade of like hundred probably cartoon characters and Just because they're not really in it that much and I think that's part of the reason why you know It was allowed right?
Scott: Yeah to be in there is because like there they weren't like playing major roles.
Scott: It was like, you know, you could have even almost called it fair use.
Scott: They were in there for such a small.
Rym: It was definitely homage and not anything more direct.
Emily: Yeah Well, it's like.
Emily: none of the main characters were established cartoon characters, but they were very much based in The tradition of these cartoon characters like, you know, Roger rabbit has a lot of what's his name woody the woodpecker or whatever.
Emily: Yeah, kind of annoying Madcap adventures sort of personality A little bit of bugs, but he doesn't have.
Emily: he's a lot more wacky.
Emily: He doesn't have that kind of sardonic goofiness about him.
Rym: but There I mean it was a solid plot.
Rym: It's a great movie.
Rym: I love the opening cartoon and how it segues right into the.
Emily: oh, yeah, and people don't realize.
Emily: One cool thing about the opening cartoon that actually killed a lot of the budget for the movie
Scott: Is
Emily: If you actually look at it, it's like It's a nod to the old cartoons But it's got a lot of polish on it that an old Warner Brothers cartoon wouldn't have like those reflections in the floor and there's crazy like.
Rym: Either loved it that they got to work on something so awesome or hated it because they had to draw like.
Scott: that is like I think animators like it when they're given free rein to do Like a lot of animation in my days from many countries.
Scott: and it's like, you know in terms of the stuff that is done by hand It's like I guess Akira is better than that, but not much else.
Scott: Just the quality
Emily: just really showcases the potential of animation for crazy exaggeration like, you know, there's just a lot of You know crazy for shortening and squashing and stretching and all these dynamic effects which so just by showing you and reminding you this is what animation can do and then Putting these characters in the real world where these things don't necessarily apply.
Emily: It kind of highlights the differences.
Rym: Oh, I didn't even know this.
Rym: Mel Blanc.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: This was the last film he worked on.
Rym: he did the voices of all his characters No kidding in the movie And then he died the next year.
Rym: He didn't do Daffy Duck.
Rym: Apparently that was too physically exerting to do.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, which makes sense.
Emily: I like yeah, but there's like those scenes like there was Daffy Duck and Donald Duck playing the piano back to back.
Emily: that scene is brilliant and they're like bitching at each other and the Daffy's like I. I can't understand what this guy's saying, you know There's a lot of weird little scenes.
Rym: I forgot about that.
Rym: I'd kind of Suddenly remembered when we watch it again like all these littlest odds were cartoon characters.
Rym: They're just doing stuff in the background stuff in the background, right?
Emily: And like, you know, you'll walk outside the studio and then Dumbo flies across and the best thing is he works for peanuts.
Emily: But this is pretty good.
Emily: I I really do.
Emily: it's not my favorite movie But I really do like that movie and it's one of those films that I get really nostalgic about kind of like.
Scott: I think it.
Scott: You know, I think it's sort of been kind of forgotten.
Scott: ish Like.
Scott: it hasn't been completely forgotten, but it's not something that people think about often.
Scott: You know, is it like?
Scott: it was popular at the time popular enough to get a Nintendo game even.
Rym: But it's the highest grossing animated film ever in the world.
Scott: Yeah But then you know It's sort of faded Afterwards and it never really came back up or was reminded of or had any you know, big Merchandising or any of these.
Rym: there was a lot of talk.
Scott: They tried to make sequels and they all fell through Things like you know, like Aladdin we mentioned earlier right like Aladdin had a TV series at one point.
Rym: I like three direct-to-TV DVD
Emily: movies do like Like
Scott: a lot of these a lot of these other animated properties have these long tails and even you know Pretty much any huge movie sort of has a long tail to it either in the form of sequels or books or merchants or saw You know something right.
Scott: these big successful properties have long tails, but Roger Rabbit had no long tail.
Scott: Rabbit and the end Done.
Emily: He's a rabbit.
Emily: He has a short tail.
Scott: All right, but you know, so because of that, you know I mean people remember it exists, but I mean it was from the late 80s.
Scott: So a lot of people who are way younger than us never even saw it ever Right, man, even though it exists at all Yeah, and then even people, you know, if they didn't see it then they might.
Scott: you might say Oh, yeah, that was that thing that was animated and also live-action and that's all they remember.
Emily: Well at the same time maybe it's just the crowd I run with but I think that one people who have an interest in Like I don't know cinema history like the the famous movies over time.
Emily: That's one that's remembered kind of like Star Wars is remembered for for both technical expertise and that it did something different.
Emily: I mean other movies had combined live-action and animation before but not nearly to the effect you know to the with the quality that Roger Rabbit was able to achieve.
Emily: and Also, I think it's partly because I hang around with animators and they're always like gushing about Roger Rabbit.
Scott: So not not everybody's forgotten this film Yeah, but it's not something that your people talk about just in normal.
Rym: and though I think it's having a comeback just because after I Saw the Cinemasker thing.
Rym: I was like, oh I should watch this.
Rym: I didn't have it.
Rym: So, of course BitTorrent because it's not in the Netflix streaming and there were a ton of people seeding it.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know if it was due to that or just people are always seeding it.
Emily: Yeah I don't know.
Emily: I think a lot of stuff from the 80s and early 90s is starting to come back on a nostalgia wave, you know You know, we went through.
Scott: he met Ninja Turtles and Voltron rice and I were coming up to the later and soon the 90s stuff Will be come back again.
Scott: Yeah Ninja Turtles is actually.
Emily: I wonder if they'll have Captain Planet.
Scott: That's already Really.
Emily: that's what I remembered from my my little day.
Rym: Well, there's the new My Little Pony's show that apparently supposedly really good.
Emily: I saw part of it.
Emily: It really reminds me of those old cartoon cartoons.
Scott: It definitely does because like it's done by Craig McCracken's wife who worked on Powerpuff Girls and some other shows make sense.
Scott: It's a. it's a Cartoon Network kind of thing.
Emily: You know the the character designs just the general dynamic of the show.
Emily: it feels like those 90s cartoons is very fun.
Scott: But anyway, see if you haven't seen it You should probably go see Roger Rabbit.
Rym: If you've decided to keep listening to the show and haven't seen it yet go see it.
Rym: there are worse movies.
Rym: You could say definitely a lot worse movies.
Scott: You could sing be fun.
Rym: And even if you're old, you know This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: Whoo-whoo Giga.
Scott: Think that's the giga putty.
Scott: All right, mega Giga.
Scott: What's the Tara footy?