Rym: It's Thursday, March 17th, 2011, though in a moment we're going to say it's March 10th, because you see we recorded this episode before PAX, the Penny Arcade Expo East in Boston and one thing led to another, I never actually put the episode up.
Rym: So, because we're tired from PAX and because this upcoming weekend is Zenkai Con in King of Prussia we're a little busy and we're just totally copping out, didn't do any shows this week so I'm going to retroactively put this episode up on a brand new date but it's actually the show we recorded before PAX.
Rym: I will also say that the Penny Arcade Expo went very very well, we'll have a review of that coming soon, probably next week.
Rym: So if you saw us at the Con, you thought we were awesome, or you hated us.
Rym: have no fear, our review will be up soon and maybe we'll talk a little more about My Little Pony, I know it was very popular at PAX.
Rym: Without further ado, I'm going to let the music play and the episode we recorded somewhat haphazardly will begin.
Rym: It's Thursday, March 10th, I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, before we go to PAX, it's BK.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Scott, I got a problem.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: So, it's been a while since something like this has happened, but uh I think about the ponies.
Scott: Enough with the ponies!
Rym: A little bit more often than I think is healthy.
Scott: Listen, I know the ponies have infected all brains they have come in contact with.
Scott: The pony brain virus is an epidemic at this point, however I believe you mean the pony pox.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: We have managed to contain it to a single GeekNights episode.
Scott: It is quarantined, let us not let it spread, that is the end of the discussion of anything related to miniature horses in this episode.
Rym: Except you know you're thinking about them too.
Scott: Doesn't matter, we're done.
Scott: Alright, so moving on to something else that is not that because it must not leave the episode to which it is contained lest humanity become extinct and grow hooves.
Rym: I posit that the only reason we will be able to restrict it so is that we're doing another project.
Scott: You're still talking about it.
Scott: So let me go to some news here.
Rym: The news that you took forever to find because there's nothing you want to talk about?
Scott: Yeah, so a new Ted just happened, right?
Scott: The conference that makes all the awesome videos.
Rym: I feel like we should make a parody set of talks the Todd Talks and it's just bad ideas.
Scott: We could do that.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Scott: And there was apparently a lot of really awesome stuff shown yet again as is always.
Scott: But and I encourage everybody the Ted Talks are really good and when you get a chance watch them when they come out and look for people to tell you which ones are the good ones worth watching because some of them are like 15 minutes a lot of time.
Scott: The thing is, there are some people out there I've seen are starting to have some negative things to say about Ted and it's like what could you possibly say negative about Ted?
Rym: I can say one negative thing.
Rym: It is somewhat pricey for me to go.
Scott: Well, here's the thing, right?
Scott: Apparently it doesn't matter how much money you have if you want to go, right?
Scott: Here's the thing.
Scott: It's basically you know, while Ted does a lot of good stuff and they spread ideas with free videos and they have the TEDx which is pretty cool you know, and that kind of stuff, right?
Scott: and the fellowships and all these things the conference itself the Ted, the real Ted the main conference is pretty much make rich people feel really good about themselves for a couple days.
Rym: Ah, but think about what it's doing.
Rym: The rich people pay a lot of money to be involved, too, right?
Scott: Well, okay, so here's a story I read, I can't find the link again but you know, somebody whoever wrote the story was friends with somebody and that somebody got them into a Ted once, right?
Scott: Uh huh.
Scott: So that, once you're basically on the list then you can go.
Scott: So, a couple years later, this person right, wanted to go to Ted this year.
Scott: they wanted to go to 2011, they went previously another year.
Rym: Alright, so they want to go again and they should be able to, according to this rule.
Scott: so they bought a ticket for a shit ton of money, right?
Scott: with thousands of dollars, and they got a ticket.
Scott: but then, apparently, that person who I think they said was a former employer right, uh, it was a huge benefactor of Ted and that former employer pretty much told Ted they didn't want that person to go.
Scott: What?
Scott: So that person didn't go, they just took their ticket away and they don't have to tell you why.
Rym: I don't know, I'm leery of a story that you heard from some guy who heard it from a guy he knows.
Scott: No, this story was written by the person who had their ticket taken away.
Scott: I just can't find the link again, but I swear I am not making this shit up.
Rym: Huh, I'm, I don't know, I'm still slightly dubious, I mean, maybe I
Scott: am also slightly dubious, but it also doesn't sound that, you know, that I get the feeling that it's like also from what people have gone there, you know to the real Ted, is basically what happens at the real Ted is, as soon you know, when you're watching, uh the show, the talks right, basically all the famous and rich people are up front, and everyone else is in the peanut gallery in the back.
Rym: That's fine that's how everything is.
Scott: Right, so that way the peanut gallery doesn't get on TV and the rich people are in the videos, right, when they get audience shots, right but at the same time, basically what happens in between sessions, or when they're having dinner, or any of those sorts of things
Rym: is
Scott: all the rich and famous people talk on one side of the room and all the not famous people on the other side of the room.
Rym: Is there a rope?
Scott: No, but that's the thing, is basically everyone has sort of a social problem, trying to go across the room.
Rym: I'll tell you this, I would not have that problem, I would be right up in Bill Gates' grill, being like, "Hey
Rym: man!"
Rym: And he would basically brush you off big time.
Rym: Yeah, I've been brushed off by people before, I can deal with that.
Scott: But basically, you just go across the room, you get brushed off, because they don't want to have anything to do with you.
Rym: I would start a revolution, we'd all go over there, be real annoying.
Scott: Yeah, but that's what people seem to, you know.
Rym: Here's the reason I'm dubious about that story.
Rym: Why would someone care if some other person attended a conference to see speeches?
Scott: Because, I guess they were drama people, you know, the kind of people who have drama.
Rym: I just, I don't understand that kind of drama, I never have.
Scott: No, but we don't understand that drama, but we see it all the time.
Rym: Much like Pinkie Pie's tale, we see it all the time but we don't understand it.
Scott: I mean, I've never been to Ted, I don't know how true this is, for all I know you go to Ted and the rich people mostly want to talk to the normal people, because they talk to rich people anytime they want, who knows, right?
Scott: But, that's sort of believable, right?
Rym: But at the same time, consider this.
Rym: Alright, so maybe they cater to the rich people and they milk all the money out of them.
Rym: They then take that money and do good stuff with it.
Scott: Yeah, you know, I mean, Ted does plenty of good stuff.
Scott: It just, you know, it's like, okay here's a little, we're going to add a little taste of reality, right?
Scott: Ted isn't all beautiful and perfect like, you know, people seem to get the impression just from watching talks.
Rym: It doesn't matter though, because all that matters is the content of the talks, really, in the end.
Rym: Or most people.
Rym: And they're free on the internet.
Rym: So, humanity wins.
Rym: It's got, you know, if a Hitler does a good thing for bad reasons, a good thing was still done.
Rym: If a Hitler does a bad thing for a good reason, a bad thing was still done.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if, you know, how much of this is true or not.
Scott: It doesn't really matter.
Scott: The point is, is new Teds, they're coming.
Rym: Are you sure it was some guy on the internet?
Rym: Are you sure it wasn't nothing?
Scott: It was some guy on the internet.
Scott: Definitely.
Rym: So that's basically nothing.
Rym: So, really quickly, this is an article in the LA Times about fevers that children have.
Rym: And apparently there's a problem.
Scott: Disco fever?
Rym: That would fix everything.
Rym: So, parents apparently will give children fever reducers when they have a fever as low as 97.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Which is, by many definitions, not actually a fever.
Scott: There are some people who just natural body temperature is just higher.
Rym: My body temperature is almost a full degree above, you know, 96.7 most of the time.
Scott: Isn't it supposed to be 98.6?
Scott: Yeah, 98.
Rym: Whatever the number is, it's about a degree above it.
Scott: 96.7 is a radio station.
Rym: I was thinking about unrelated stuff, but I kind of have a high body temperature.
Rym: And when I was a kid, a lot of times I'd get my temperature taken at like a nurse's office or a temporary daycare or a kindergarten.
Rym: They'd be like...
Scott: It's like, I'm gonna go run around the track and take my temperature after I just set all of this food on fire.
Rym: But they'd always be like, "Oh, you've got kind of a fever.
Rym: Maybe we should send you
Rym: home.".
Rym: I'm like, "No, I'm
Rym: fine.".
Rym: But apparently...
Scott: I would've said, "Yeah,
Scott: sure.".
Scott: The
Rym: article's kind of talking about the fact that parents don't actually know what fevers are anymore, and the majority of people really don't realize that if you have a fever and it's not a fever that's high enough to cause, you know, the problems that high fevers cause, like
Scott: death... Like, 99 I think is my line.
Scott: Like, if it's over 99, it's like...
Rym: No, but even 100, 101, 102 for short amounts of time, that fever is actually helping your body fight it off.
Rym: That's your body reacting to the disease.
Scott: Well, yeah, so is sneezing and coughing.
Rym: Yes, those things are good.
Scott: You're still going to take Mucinex.
Rym: It depends on what kind of disease you have.
Scott: You're still going to take the halls of medicine.
Rym: No, it depends.
Rym: Like, for example, if I have a sinus infection, I want to take the Mucinex because my sinuses are blocked and bacteria are growing in there.
Rym: So I need to open it up to get them out.
Rym: But if I have 100, 101 fever because I'm sick, that fever is my body fighting off the illness.
Rym: And if I reduce the fever, I'm reducing my body's effectiveness and increasing the duration of the illness.
Scott: Yeah, but usually a fever reducer also has anti.
Scott: whatever it is you're sick with medicine in it.
Rym: No, most fever reducers just treat pain and fever.
Scott: Really?
Rym: What do you mean really?
Rym: So what causes fevers?
Rym: Mostly colds and flus.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: What treats colds and flus?
Scott: Medicine, Tylenol.
Rym: Tylenol does not in any way help you fight off a cold or flu.
Rym: It reduces the symptoms.
Scott: It helps you go to sleep and then your body will fight it while you're sleeping and thus you'll be a lot more comfortable.
Rym: And it's just kind of telling that people generally don't know much about, well, I don't know anything.
Scott: We just need a new thermometer that instead of telling you the degrees, says fever or not fever.
Scott: And if you have a fever, it plays Fever from Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Scott: And then you play Dr.
Scott: Mario instead of taking a fever reducer.
Scott: That way you'll be ignoring your discomfort.
Rym: It also needs to tell you what kind of fever.
Rym: Like, is it a normal fever?
Rym: A dangerous fever?
Scott: There's only three kinds.
Rym: Most dangerous fever?
Scott: Red, blue and yellow.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: I was born in Detroit.
Rym: I'm a Michigander by blood.
Rym: That's where I was born.
Rym: That's my kind of home grounds.
Rym: I still root for the red wings.
Rym: I still root for the pistons.
Rym: I still pray for the lions.
Rym: Detroit, it's not looking so good.
Rym: Detroit has had some trouble for, I don't know, the last 30, 40 years.
Rym: And one of the most important things about Detroit is its statues.
Rym: I mean, we have the Spirit of Detroit, which is this beautiful statue of, it's kind of like the Statue of Liberty, but it's the Spirit of Detroit.
Scott: It's not that big.
Scott: It's pretty big, actually.
Scott: It's not a Statue of Liberty big.
Rym: No, but it's pretty big.
Rym: And when we won, when the red wings won the Stanley Cup, I shouldn't say we, because I did not win the Stanley Cup.
Rym: When the red wings won the Stanley Cup in '96, someone made a gigantic jersey for the red wings and somehow put it on that statue.
Scott: Well, they also put tiger's jerseys on there, too.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But we also have my favorite statue in all the world, Joe Lewis's fist.
Rym: It's just a giant fist hanging down in front of the Joe Lewis Arena.
Rym: We've got statues, but there's one statue Detroit doesn't have, and I've talked about this, that Robocop, you know, people want to make a Robocop statue in Detroit.
Rym: There's a big project to get the money together to do it.
Rym: Peter Weller has stepped forward and made a pretty fucking awesome video advocating for the Robocop statue.
Rym: Peter Weller, if you don't know, played Robocop.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: He is to Robocop what John St.
Rym: John is to Duke Nukem.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, I recommend you watch this, and I donated some money.
Rym: Please donate a tiny amount of money, a couple of bucks, to make the life-size, realistic Robocop statue in Detroit.
Rym: I think it's a cool nerd internet thing, even though it is kind of a kick in the nuts to people who are living in Detroit.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's two ways.
Rym: Like, if you live there, or if I still live there, on one hand, you could see the statue of Robocop as being a very cynical, like, yeah, this city sucks idea.
Rym: You could also see it for what it is, as kind of a funny joke, like, you know, we do need to deal with this crime problem, and if only we had Robocop.
Rym: Like, you could take the good humor in it.
Scott: Maybe one day, like, Detroit will revive, and there'll be this Robocop statue, or maybe one day, Detroit will completely disintegrate, and it'll just be a Robocop statue, all alone.
Rym: Look ye mighty upon my works.
Scott: And then Joe Lewis will punch it.
Scott: Bam!
Rym: I think the most likely scenario is that the Robocop statue will be stolen.
Scott: Defaced?
Scott: No, you know what?
Scott: It'll be wearing a Red Wings jersey.
Rym: [laughter] So what do you got for me?
Scott: Uh, so, you know, you ever look out a window before?
Rym: Uh, on occasion.
Scott: What do you see out the window?
Rym: Right now, I see Manhattan.
Scott: So this means that there are photons coming from Manhattan.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And they're coming all the way to your house, across the air, and they're going through the air, and when they get to your window, they're actually going through the glass.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: That means there is well, sort of a particle/wave a photon, and it goes through something into your eyeball.
Rym: But, I mean, that's not that strange.
Rym: I mean, cosmic rays go through the Earth all the time.
Scott: Right, of course.
Rym: They go through Earth.
Rym: They go through metal, not just glass.
Scott: Right, but, so glass is a solid object.
Rym: So is metal.
Scott: Right, but a piece of metal, photons don't go through it.
Rym: Alright, but why do cosmic rays go through metal?
Scott: That's a very good question, and the answer to both these questions is probably the same answer.
Scott: And if you want to know this answer, this video gives a very good scientific explanation of exactly why glass is transparent, and it shows you experiments, it shows you pretty much everything you need to know.
Scott: for even a layperson who has knowledge of, if you understand atoms, electrons, protons, and neutrons, then you can understand why things are transparent or translucent.
Rym: You know, I wonder.
Scott: It is quite fascinating, actually.
Rym: I wonder, kind of an aside.
Scott: And sort of obvious, I probably should've been able to figure it out, but I didn't.
Rym: Not to sound cynical.
Rym: Maybe I'm just feeling cynical because I'm really, really tired.
Rym: But how many people, like, what percentage of people in the US do you think actually have a reasonable understanding of the classical notions of electrons and atoms?
Rym: Like, what percent?
Scott: A high estimate, 35%.
Rym: I think that's about right.
Scott: High.
Scott: That's conservatively high.
Scott: If I had to lowball it, I'd say, like, 25.
Rym: So, this episode was to get to the meta moment recorded in advance because we are, at this moment, on our way to the Penny Arcade Expo in Boston.
Scott: Bitch Pax.
Rym: Oh, shit.
Rym: Well, Pax East, Pax Boston.
Rym: I'll apologize one last time because I'm the one who accidentally caused it to be called Bitch Pax.
Rym: Remember my question?
Rym: I probably should've never asked that question.
Scott: That is, you know, it's all on you.
Rym: Yeah, it's all on me.
Rym: That's my fault.
Rym: You can blame me.
Rym: But, as a result, you know, we had to get some shows done ahead of time.
Rym: So, we are at the Penny Arcade Expo.
Rym: If you are listening to this, hopefully you are on your way and not at home being sad.
Rym: If you're at home being sad, just watch the My Little Pony.
Rym: You'll feel better.
Scott: Is that for the ponies?
Scott: Yeah, the ponies at the show.
Scott: Yeah, any other meta things?
Rym: The Book Club book is Michio Kaku's Hyperspace, which Scott has not yet read.
Rym: We're doing three panels of Pax, game mechanics and mechanism design, how to win at games, and the triple threats, short subjects in gaming.
Rym: And the other conventions are Zenkai Con is next weekend and King of Prussia in Pennsylvania near Philadelphia.
Rym: Friday, March 18th, 19th, and 20th.
Rym: We will be doing panels the 19th and the 20th.
Rym: We will not be there Fridays.
Rym: Don't come looking for us.
Scott: Are we doing a panel on the 20th?
Rym: Uh, yeah, one panel.
Rym: Then we're going home.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: I didn't know we were doing one.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: We're doing one.
Rym: We're doing Beyond Dungeons and Dragons, the remake.
Rym: Exciting.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: We are also going to be at Anime Boston.
Rym: We'll also be at the Mocha.
Rym: We're doing panels at Anime Boston.
Rym: We're just walking around and looking around at the Mocha.
Rym: And I'm talking really fast to try to counter the slow version of the meta moment that Scott usually does.
Scott: Except for the 10-1.
Rym: So BK.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So BK is this pirate dude and after you, you know, beat what's his name?
Rym: Nine pirates.
Scott: Nine pirates.
Scott: And what's the town?
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: I really don't remember.
Rym: It starts with a P. Provoca.
Rym: Provoca.
Scott: So after you go to Provoke Rym and his nine pirates, BK comes out of the booth.
Rym: I can't believe we've never done a throwaway show on fucking bikes.
Scott: I thought, you know, we must have because biking is pretty much our number one athletic activity here.
Rym: Well, it's the number one athletic activity that is shared between me and Scott because I run and ski and play tennis and rock climb and Scott bikes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, no, no.
Rym: You play FPSs and DDR.
Rym: Those are sports.
Rym: Jungle speed.
Rym: Athletics.
Rym: Jungle speed should be an Olympic event.
Scott: I mean, look, if the biathlon can be in the Olympics, jungle speed can be in the Olympics.
Rym: One thing that amazes me.
Rym: We'll get right into it.
Rym: We're talking about bikes.
Rym: I feel like most of the people I've known in my entire life who have ridden bikes or not ridden bikes have no idea how bikes actually work or how to ride them properly.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, a lot of people like when I was kids, it was pretty much you biked around the neighborhood.
Scott: That's what kids did.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But you biked around on a 10 speed.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, not at first.
Scott: I mean, not when I was way little, but as soon as I could fit on one right.
Scott: 24 inch or whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then even though it was like it was usually like a huffy or whatever because your parents are going to buy you something nice unless you're actually into biking.
Scott: But it didn't matter.
Scott: You can go around the neighborhood in the huffy.
Scott: No problem.
Scott: Didn't make you know.
Scott: And the thing is everybody knew how to ride a bike because we all did it every day to go to each other's houses in the neighborhood.
Scott: Some kids even rode their bikes to school.
Scott: It's just something everyone knew.
Scott: But now it's sort of weird that I'm an adult and there's a lot of people that I know who don't know how to ride a bike.
Scott: And it's like, what?
Scott: It's like every kid in my whole town who had to ride a bike.
Scott: So what town are you from?
Rym: Yeah, we won't name any names, but I could name a lot of people that I know and people I've met who like didn't realize how to brake, for example.
Rym: People don't realize that you're only supposed to use your front brake 99 percent of the time.
Rym: The rear brake is really only there to slow down around turns.
Rym: Maybe if you're going downhill, like a very steep downhill, and you don't want to flip over the handlebar.
Rym: Or if the front brake isn't enough, you can use it to augment the front brake.
Rym: You use it to control speed, like the rear brake you'll touch to like slow down a little bit if you need to.
Rym: But if you actually need to stop, you pretty much need to slam the front brake.
Scott: And I mean, especially if you go, you know, because it's like all the weight of you sitting on the bike is going to be on that front tire.
Scott: So if you, you know, it's either a friction against the ground is, you know, how much force is being pushed down on the ground and then the coat, depending on the material of the pavement under you or whatever it is, and the tire, right, that is what determines your stopping power.
Scott: So if your weight is on the front tire, there's not a lot of weight on the rear tire, there won't be a lot of friction on the rear tire.
Scott: So hitting the brakes on it isn't going to slow you down all that much.
Rym: Never mind the lever action of the bike that as you brake, you lean forward pulling weight off the rear tire.
Rym: That's why if you you can lock your rear brake, but you can't lock your front brake without flipping over the handlebars.
Rym: That's the other thing, I see a lot of people just holding down the rear brake and just skidding to a stop, ruining their tire.
Rym: Yeah, I mean an optimal brake in a bike is if you really need to stop in time your rear wheel should actually lift up off the ground about an inch.
Rym: That means that you have broken optimally.
Scott: The other thing is that, you know, cars have anti-lock brakes, right, and people I think have been, you know, anti-lock brakes have actually been around for a long time now.
Scott: And I think a lot of people, because even in cars, right, you basically just, you just slam on the brakes these days.
Scott: And that's what you should do in a car with anti-lock brakes.
Scott: It's pretty much just slam on them if you need to, right?
Scott: But in the olden days, before they had anti-lock brakes, people actually had to learn how to brake properly where if the tire is locked up, you let go of the brake because you want, you know, you want them basically to roll, but you want them to roll more slowly to stop.
Scott: If you just lock the tires up, then suddenly you can't control the turning of the car at all.
Scott: You're completely out of control.
Scott: It's just, whatever, you know, momentum you have and, you know, the friction of the tires against the road, that's pretty much all you got.
Rym: But bikes, people just, like, you gotta pulse them, just like you used to in old cars.
Scott: Yeah, the tires shouldn't stop rotating until you're actually stop-stopped.
Rym: I use a kind of pattern when I need to stop, where I slam on the front brake, and then I pulse it alternatingly with the rear brake as I slow down, like I tend to go and
Scott: I hold it down as hard as I need to hold it down, and if it's, you know, I can tell if it's about to lock up soon, and I let go, and then I go on it again, like, check it
Rym: out, check it out, check it out.
Scott: So I'm always trying to get the maximum braking power out of it without a lock up.
Rym: People don't seem to realize too, that if your brakes get wet, you need to, you know, tap them a little bit to clean them off so they'll be ready to go.
Rym: Like, if you go through a puddle of some mud, you gotta hold them down just a little bit to warm them up and get all the water on.
Scott: Well, unless you have, what's it called, disc brakes.
Rym: I actually didn't get disc brakes on my fancy bike.
Scott: Me either.
Rym: I could've, but they really, they're really only useful for mountain biking, I've decided.
Rym: They're not really useful for even pretty advanced street biking.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you don't see, like, who do you see using actual disc brakes for any actual, I always try to look at the professional biking people, not because I ever Mountain bikers.
Scott: Not because I'm ever going to be them, but just to see what equipment they're using.
Rym: Professional mountain bikers.
Scott: Because that's how you can tell between what's a gimmick thing, right, that's just something they're trying to sell you at the bike shop, and what's actually legitimately going to help you.
Rym: Well, the disc brakes won't let you stop faster, necessarily, on smooth ground.
Scott: All I'm saying, Lance Armstrong doesn't have disc brakes.
Scott: He has these, he has the brakes that are, they're much fancier than the brakes that I've got, but they're the same basic mechanisms.
Rym: But the difference is the main advantage of these brakes, and if I ever get a better mountain bike, I'll get disc brakes on it, is that if you go through a whole bunch of mud, their effectiveness is basically not diminished.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: And also, I mean, mud could, I guess, theoretically get in there, but that's not like...
Rym: More importantly, if your frame gets, you know, if the bike tires themselves get deformed, it won't hurt the braking ability either.
Rym: And, they disperse heat better, so say you need to, like mountain biking, a big thing you need to do is brake almost the whole time you're going down the hill.
Scott: Well, downhill, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, downhill mountain biking.
Scott: But it's also the uphill component.
Rym: Yeah, but downhill mountain biking, you need to use the brakes a lot.
Rym: And if you've ever been in a car, and you're using the brake to slow your car down down a hill, one, you're ruining your brakes.
Rym: Two, you're probably not going to be able to stop for a good like mile or two after you get to the bottom of the hill.
Rym: Bikes are the same way.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: If your brakes are too hot, they're made of rubber, they'll melt, and they'll get all liquidy, and they won't be any good at stopping.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: People also don't know how to shift.
Rym: They don't use their gears effectively.
Scott: Well, I think people don't even, because, you know, that's another thing.
Scott: In cars, people don't have manual transmissions anymore.
Scott: They have automatic transmissions since forever.
Rym: Never mind having two different clutches, like two different sets of gears.
Scott: Right, so you know, people don't even know how to, you know, the concept of gears isn't even something that they take into account in their everyday life because they don't, you know, have it in their cars.
Scott: So when it comes to bikes, only actual people who know and care about biking know how to use brakes.
Scott: I can't tell you how many times I'll be going over the bridge, which is the time when you're going to probably, even if you don't care about gear shifting or efficiency, that's the time to, you know, shift gears going over the big hill.
Scott: And you see people going over, and like, the biggest gear, and they just push really hard, or they'll just get off, or they'll be using some useless gear that's like, way too low, and they'll just be going as slow as molasses on a cold day, and they'll be pedaling like crazy.
Scott: And it's like, "What are you
Scott: doing?".
Scott: I'm like, "Dude, shift up.
Rym: Come
Rym: on.".
Rym: Yep, even worse, you couple that with the push-push.
Scott: Oh, the push-push.
Rym: Push-push is, most people when they ride bikes, they don't realize it's continuous motion, and they tend to just go push, push, push, like they're stepping on the front of each pedal as it comes around the top.
Scott: Yeah, the bike pedal, right, the gears are circles.
Scott: They're not ovals, right?
Scott: So, you need to, you know, when you're pedaling, you want to be pushing and/or pulling up with the other foot.
Scott: That's why people get the toe clips to make it...
Rym: I actually, I'm getting some toe clips in the spring.
Scott: To make it easier to pull up.
Scott: I'm not a big fan of the clips, just because it's hard to take your foot on and off the pedal.
Rym: Actually, what I'm gonna do, I'm not gonna get the, I'll get the clips.
Rym: You get the shoes that clip on?
Rym: I'm gonna get both.
Rym: I'm gonna get the clips for when I'm just like, if I want to take my bike, like, to the store, I can just use the clips.
Rym: Or the, yeah, the toe clips.
Scott: But then you gotta keep switching the clips with the foot thing.
Rym: Yeah, I'm only gonna use the boots if I'm going on, like, upper, like, I'm going to Beacon or something.
Scott: They sell the shoes on Zappos, actually.
Rym: Oh, do they?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, but anyway, so yeah, it's like, that makes it easier to pull up on the other pedal.
Scott: So this, what you want to have, ideally, you know, equal force rotating in a perfect circle at all times, right?
Scott: So the gear should be spinning at, you know, sort of a constant RPM.
Scott: So, you know, if you go push one side, then push the other side, it's basically RPM stop, RPM stop, rotate stop, rotate stop.
Scott: It's also really hard on your bike.
Scott: It's an oval shape, not a circle shape.
Rym: So, Scott, you're probably not aware, there are.
Scott: It's cycling.
Rym: There was a, this was a trend in the 90s, I think, and I don't know if it ever continued.
Scott: To make bikes with oval gears?
Scott: Yeah, every now and then you'll see.
Scott: It's possible.
Rym: Every now and then you'll see.
Scott: I don't know how you'd shift an elliptical gear.
Rym: Uh, they work just fine.
Scott: You could shift the rear gear.
Rym: Scott, you're not even letting me finish.
Rym: They made these bikes.
Rym: They were a gimmick for rich people, and basically they took advantage of the fact that most people push, push, and it was an elliptical gear that would basically use the extra force to round everything out.
Rym: So when your push, push happened was when you had more total torque.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: So as a result, you could actually, like it worked really well if you were a push, pusher.
Rym: But they were a little overly complex, and they were not easily rideable by people who know how to bike properly.
Rym: And people who buy a ten thousand dollar bike.
Scott: Anyone who goes to the store and is looking at a bunch of bikes and one of them has these weird oval gears, I don't think those are going to sell too well.
Rym: I think they would, but the people who are going to spend ten thousand dollars on a bike are people who already know how to bike.
Rym: Already care about biking.
Scott: Especially if they're more expensive than they're really not going to sell.
Rym: I don't know, I like biking.
Rym: We can stop ranting about people not knowing how to ride bikes.
Rym: You sure?
Scott: You want to rant about it some more?
Scott: I got to at least rant about the fact that in New York City, right, as you know, there's a lot of people who are like biketivists, right?
Scott: They're like big activists for biking.
Scott: They're like, you know, share the road.
Scott: and hey, people in cars, look out for the bikes, don't hit us with your cars, you assholes.
Rym: And I'm a hundred percent for that.
Scott: Yeah, I am also a hundred percent for that.
Scott: Bike lanes, sure, bring us some bike lanes.
Scott: Don't give bikes the proper right of way and leeway and all the things you need to give them, sure.
Scott: But the fact is this, last year I rode my bike to work, you know, all the days it was warm and after I get back from PAX it'll probably be warm again and I'll probably resume.
Scott: Most of the people I saw being assholes and not doing what they should be doing are the people on the bikes.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I rarely saw cars, you know, the cars really didn't want to hit the people on the bikes if they saw them, right?
Rym: I have been hit by more bicyclists than I have by any other thing in New York.
Scott: But in terms of, you know, people on bikes, I have seen tons of assholery.
Scott: Pretty much no one obeys red lights or stop signs or anything unless they definitely have to when there's a car coming.
Rym: The other day, another guy just slammed into me.
Rym: I was walking and he just hit me.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes even if they do respect the red light, instead of stopping, they'll sort of bike in a circle because they don't want to stop moving.
Scott: So they'll sort of circle around a bit until the green light comes, then they'll go instead of just stopping and putting their foot on the ground.
Scott: Is it like, is their bike too high for them to put their foot on the ground?
Scott: They can't stop?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Some, a lot of them will drive the stupid bikes without brakes.
Scott: I think I've complained about that on the show before.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: A lot of the people who circle, if you look, they're almost always fixies.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: Because it's hard for them to get going again because you know what, fixies suck.
Scott: They do.
Rym: There's no reason to use a fixie in the modern world.
Rym: They're not that much more reliable.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: I don't think it's about reliability.
Scott: I think for some people it's about style.
Rym: No, they always argue it is, though.
Rym: They always argue that, hey, my fixie never breaks.
Scott: My bike didn't break either.
Scott: But I've never actually argued with anyone who has a fixie, but I think they do it for style or they just don't care or don't know.
Scott: They just go and they buy a bike and they don't care about... People don't care about the under the hood stuff.
Scott: It's like the same reason you'd buy an Apple computer as opposed to... You look at the outside of it.
Scott: They don't look at the inside.
Scott: The gearing and that stuff is inside secret science-y stuff.
Scott: They're looking at the color of the paint job and whether there's a basket in the front.
Rym: One thing I can say, though, is that biking has pretty much been the sport that I have engaged in and the athleticism I have done more than anything else in my entire life.
Rym: I've been biking for pretty much as long as I've been able to bike.
Rym: I've had a litany of mountain bikes and road bikes and everything.
Scott: It might have been swimming, but I pretty much stopped swimming once I left my parents.
Rym: In high school, that was when it really peaked.
Rym: Every single day, I just get on my bike and ride off.
Rym: I'd ride 50, 60 miles just wherever.
Rym: I'd go down to Detroit and back.
Rym: I'd go out to the lakes.
Rym: A couple of times, I'd bike out and it'd be 11 o'clock on a Wednesday and I'd realize that I'm a couple hours from home.
Scott: For me, it was like biking and swimming with.
Scott: biking was ahead a bit, but then eventually another bike was stolen and then it was just like,
Scott: "Alright.".
Scott: I never got a new one until RIT, but then I stopped swimming when I went to college.
Scott: It was biking and then swimming took the lead and then biking again.
Scott: I haven't swimmed again.
Rym: Well, I started.
Rym: actually when I lived in the mountains, biking was nothing other than a hobby.
Rym: It was nothing but a way to have fun on a bike and exercise.
Scott: Once you're in the city, it can actually become legitimate transportation again.
Rym: Actually, in Beacon, it was legitimate transportation.
Rym: I'd go to the farmer's market.
Rym: I'd go to the train station.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, it's not like the city where you can go anywhere with it.
Rym: Yeah, I can bike anywhere in the city almost faster than the subway.
Rym: It'll get me there in many cases.
Scott: Yeah, I can get to work.
Scott: The thing is, it depends, right?
Scott: Can I go faster than the subway?
Scott: No, not really, but considering the fact that I can leave my house directly, take a shorter path than the subway, and I won't have to wait for the train to show up, you know, it sort of evens out depending on where you're going, especially if you're going somewhere that's a little bit far away from a station, because you can definitely make up for that walking time easily.
Scott: And you can take all sorts of paths that you would normally not be able to go.
Rym: I do have the advantage that my work is Grand Central, so I basically just bike.
Rym: It's like right there.
Scott: Yeah, mine is across town a bit.
Rym: I mean, I can rollerblade to work efficiently if I want to.
Rym: Of course, my building's being stupid and they won't let me bring my bike in.
Scott: Yeah, my building.
Rym: They found a loophole in the law and they're just being dicks about it.
Scott: Can't they let you in at the correct hours?
Rym: Yeah, at the correct hours, which they made sure were, basically the hours start after I get to work and end before I leave work.
Rym: And they're like, "If you have to stay late, well, you can't bring your bike down past your
Rym: elevator.".
Scott: Well, mine is the same way, except the hours are an hour before I get to work, and an hour ends at six.
Rym: Yeah, my hours are basically useless.
Scott: The thing is, if I stay there at six, I have to go get on the subway to go home.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: What I might do is, because I got my fancy road bike, which is, as much as I am into biking, it is way more aggressively geared than I am capable of taking advantage of.
Rym: That's one of the reasons why I need the tote clips, because I can't take advantage of the bike as it is.
Rym: I can't even use the highest gears.
Rym: I'm not strong enough.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: It's kind of amazing, but I love this bike.
Scott: I've never been on a bike where I couldn't pedal every gear in the right situation.
Scott: Obviously, I can't use the highest gear from a standstill on an uphill, but I've never been on a bike where I couldn't use the highest gear going downhill.
Rym: You should try riding my bike.
Scott: I got all those tiny, tiny little gears.
Scott: What is it, like the size of a dime?
Rym: The smallest one is like that.
Scott: If I'm going downhill on the bridge, I could use it.
Rym: Going downhill on the bridge, I was two gears away from that, and I was basically pedaling at my maximal capacity.
Rym: I couldn't push that other gear anymore.
Rym: Unless I push pushed.
Scott: You don't want to do that.
Rym: But I think what I'm going to do is I got that old mountain bike, that like 15 year old mountain bike that I got back.
Scott: That was stolen.
Rym: That was stolen.
Rym: I little macked it.
Rym: And basically I think I'm going to fix it up, and it's not the greatest bike anymore.
Rym: I would not take it for real mountain biking, because I think the suspension would just break.
Scott: I think you'd probably get hurt.
Rym: But I think what I'll do is I can ride it to work, and park it outside.
Rym: And if someone steals it in the city, alright.
Scott: You can pay to get a bike locker in Grand Central, I think.
Scott: This place is in there.
Rym: I'll have to look, but the thing is, this bike is 15 years old.
Rym: And it was already stolen.
Rym: I had already given up on having that bike.
Rym: The fact that I have it was just happenstance.
Rym: So if it gets stolen again, whatever.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is, alright, so you do that, it'll get stolen immediately, and then...
Rym: I don't think it will.
Rym: It looks pretty shitty at this point.
Rym: It does.
Scott: I mean, how often do people have the delivery guys get their bikes stolen?
Rym: I don't think they do that often.
Rym: I think people steal the nice bikes.
Scott: Speaking of bike thievery, right, in the city, bike locks become a big issue.
Scott: It's like, do you go with the big crazy chain situation?
Rym: Well, as I've learned, big crazy chain is about a five minute hacksaw job.
Scott: Right, but the other thing with the big crazy chain is that it's so heavy.
Scott: You gotta carry that if you're gonna use it.
Rym: I got a really nice, just kinda normal key lock with the cable and then the metal inside the cable.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I got one of those U things that has some sort of insurance and such like that.
Scott: And it, you know, it's like, you gotta make sure, though, that you, like, you put it through all the tires and all that.
Scott: And there's some people, like, they take their seats with them.
Rym: I would do that on my old bike, because remember, my new bike, like, the seat is just the default seat.
Rym: It's a generic seat.
Rym: On my mountain bike, the seat that that jackass who stole my bike cut up to try to disguise it, that was like a $180 bike seat.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: That was a really fancy, like, ergonomic seat that I really like.
Scott: So it's like you gotta take the front tire off, then you gotta put the lock through both tires and the frame, and then you gotta remove this.
Rym: You don't need to take the front tire off if you have a long enough chain to go through all the bits.
Scott: Yeah, if you're doing the chain mode, but if you're doing the U mode.
Rym: Yeah, that's why I don't like the U.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Actually, there's one guy, right, he, uh, if you have, like, a really crappy bike, what you could do is they make these tiny U's.
Scott: Like, the really, it's like the tiniest U. you can put it in your pocket.
Scott: So it's like, and what you can do is they also have these other things that are basically these wheel locks.
Scott: So the way they work is, you know how when you wanna, you know, on a quick take off your wheels, there's a little thing, the lever, you pull the lever and you spin the screw and you take your wheel off?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: You know, Emily's old bike doesn't have that.
Rym: I was, I was gonna change your tire the other day.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't have the quick release.
Rym: I reached out and I'm like, "What the
Rym: fuck?".
Rym: Then I look and it's just a bolt, and I'm like, "God damn
Rym: it.".
Rym: I had to go get, like, a wrench.
Scott: Old style.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But what they have is you can actually replace the quick release mechanism with this locking quick release mechanism.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: And I'm not, I don't know how well it works, but supposedly the way this thing works is that you can only, it's just normal, it looks like a normal quick release.
Scott: You don't notice anything, but it actually won't quick release at all unless you turn the bike upside down.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: So no one can, it basically prevents your tires from being removed if the bike is right side up.
Scott: So if you, if you trust in that system, then you can use the tiniest, tiniest U-lock and just lock the frame to something like a bar or anything, right?
Scott: Just get the frame on something, don't worry about the tires, take the seat with you, and I think they even have one for the seat quick release also.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So no one, if you get all three quick releases, the seat and the two tires with this thing and you lock your bike to something with a tiny U-lock right side up, then you can just carry around the tiniest lock, and if you trust it, then you're, and it works, then you're in business, right?
Scott: Without having to carry anything big nor heavy.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: I'm looking though, cause we're, cause no one can turn the bike upside down to take the things off.
Rym: What I might do.
Scott: You can't bust the tiny U.
Rym: It looks like for homeowners insurance, I can add on, basically, bike insurance.
Scott: My homeowner, my homeowner already covers the bicycle, or like, if I get a camera stolen on the subway, it covers all that.
Rym: Yeah, cause my bike is pretty, I got a really nice bike.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You didn't get like the really nice bike.
Rym: I got basically the highest end of the, like, I'm one step under where you start replacing like the front fork with carbon fiber.
Scott: Yeah, that's, that's really nice.
Scott: That's what I'm talking about.
Rym: I'm one step below that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm like persumer.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is that, you know, I gotta, I wanna go somewhere and like try out some of the actual street kinda bikes.
Rym: The racing bikes, they're not comfortable.
Rym: I don't enjoy them.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, I've never actually ridden one for any extended period of time.
Rym: Scott, if you wanna go long distances and you wanna upgrade your bike, get mine.
Scott: Eh.
Rym: My bike is comfortable like yours, but it's fast.
Scott: It's not significantly different.
Rym: Yeah, it is actually.
Rym: Scott, one, you have much wider tires than me and much bigger rims, like wider rims.
Scott: That doesn't make that much of a difference.
Rym: Actually, it makes a huge difference for long-term speed and energy efficiency.
Rym: If you're going a long distance, your tires are way too wide.
Scott: Yeah, but if I go get a street bike, the tires are gonna be way even thinner than yours.
Scott: Yours aren't that thin.
Rym: Yeah, 'cause mine's a hybrid.
Rym: It's between the two.
Scott: I can go, see the thing is, my gears are different.
Rym: My, like, the seat arrangement's a little different.
Scott: I'll go and I'll, you know, I'm gonna go test out those kind of bikes and if I can deal with it, you know, in maybe a year or two, I will go when this bike is sort of done.
Rym: Honestly, Scott, really, those street bikes, like street racing bikes are only worth it if you're going to race or if you are planning to, like, yeah, I'm gonna bike up to Albany this weekend.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Scott: You never know.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, you might, if you go down that road, yeah, you definitely want a street bike, but I'm just saying, unless you're doing that, you pretty much just want to get a better hybrid instead.
Scott: The thing is, I see most of the people in the city, right, they, they're all, like, the popular thing these days are like these, like, Euro pixies that everyone drives.
Scott: Oh, whatever.
Scott: You know, it's like, I always complain about the people with the track bikes, but actually the most popular bike are, like, these hipster, they get, like, these Bianchi frames with, like, it's like, oh, really?
Scott: It's like, everyone freaking rides these things.
Scott: I don't understand them.
Scott: But meanwhile, the delivery guys, right, what do they ride?
Scott: They ride basically, like, mountain bikes from Toys R Us.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That are all beat up in a mishmash of random pieces.
Rym: Well, I'll admit I miss, like, I like my bike because for riding in the city, like, it's way faster than a mountain bike.
Rym: But I miss having the tank capabilities of a mountain bike.
Rym: I miss the fact that on my mountain bike, I could just, like, ram into the curb if I wanted to with no effect, just, like, suddenly be on the sidewalk, run over, like, anything I run over doesn't even faze me.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: With this bike, like, a pothole.
Scott: You hit a bump, you're like, ah!
Rym: Yeah, a pothole on my bike is a big fucking deal.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I kind of actually, you know, after watching the videos of that downhill urban, uh, biking, you know.
Rym: You want to do that kind of mountain biking?
Scott: If I wasn't going to die.
Rym: We could rent mountain bikes and go out and do it.
Scott: Yeah, where are we going to find a place that's like that?
Rym: There's a ton of mountain biking trails up by Bear Mountain.
Scott: No, I'm not talking about a city on a hill.
Rym: There's got, just downhill, there's downhill courses in the woods that are the same basic thing.
Scott: Oh, that's nice in the woods.
Scott: I want to do it in the city with the stairs, and the street, and the, you know.
Scott: Do you know, have you ever done anything like that?
Scott: No.
Rym: Have you ever done, like, stunt biking?
Rym: Jumping?
Rym: Anything?
Rym: No.
Rym: You would die.
Scott: I know, that's why.
Scott: You would die.
Scott: I got to do, like, a little one first.
Rym: You got to at least ride on bikes with suspensions first to get used to that shit.
Scott: I had a bike with a suspension, but it was only the front suspension.
Rym: Yeah, you need the, a mountain bike, full body suspension is way different.
Rym: Like, some of the bikes I've tried, I didn't buy them because they cost more than my car.
Rym: You could basically jump out that window right there on the bike, land on the ground, and be fine.
Scott: Oh, I see guys do that on YouTube all the time.
Scott: Well, I guess if you land tires first.
Rym: Yeah, you got to land tires first.
Rym: Not head first.
Scott: You know, whether you, what part of the bike hits the ground first is up to your skill, and the bike, no bike, it doesn't matter what bike you're using, you're not going to be saved.
Rym: I do enjoy mountain biking, and it's one of the few hobbies that I love that I just stopped doing, and I really, I think this summer, I got to go up to, like, Hunter Mountain or something, just go mountain biking again.
Scott: Man, you know what I like?
Scott: Tricycles.
Scott: Tricycles are the shit.
Scott: You get your little red wagon, you pull it around.
Rym: I prefer bicycles.
Scott: You pull it around, your little red wagon, with your stuffed animals in it.
Rym: Monocycles.
Scott: Yeah, the monocycles was really popular at RIT, but I haven't really, uh...
Rym: Well, because the Juggling Club was really big with the Unicycle Club.
Rym: I think they were eventually the same club.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: There was always those guys that were taking unicycles.
Scott: There was a lot of crossover.
Rym: I saw a guy taking a unicycle over the bridge the other day.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Yeah, when I was rollerblading.
Scott: I haven't seen that many unicycles in the city.
Rym: Because they're not fast.
Rym: They're not practical for long distances.
Scott: I see a lot, what I do see is I see a lot of delivery guys of, like, the battery-powered bicycles, but they're not, like, fancy, they're, like, the ghettoist battery-powered bike you'll ever see.
Rym: Actually, my stepdad, he was really good at unicycles.
Rym: He had a whole bunch.
Rym: Like, little one, big one, he had one that was, like, ten feet tall.
Scott: What?
Scott: How could you even get on it?
Rym: A ladder?
Rym: Basically, you run with it like it's a pole vault.
Rym: You plant the tires sideways like it's a pole vault.
Scott: Oh, so because the thing the tire's on, you can bring it down and grab the seat because it swings all the way, yeah.
Rym: Well, the tires at the bottom, there's a long pole, there's a seat at the top, and there's a long chain thing and that, like, connects to the pedals which are way at the top.
Rym: So he pole vaults up and then jumps onto the seat and then starts going.
Rym: Or falls over.
Scott: Oh, so you don't just grab, so the seat, you don't bring the seat down to where you are?
Scott: No!
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: You pole vault up and then you start going.
Scott: I thought you would bring the seat down to where you are, sort of put it near the front of you, run, and as you're running, sort of put it under your butt and swing up there, like that.
Rym: Uh, Scott, try to picture what that would look like.
Rym: You basically are taking a pole vault, putting the nub of it in your junk and running full speed and planting it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's not a good idea.
Scott: You're more like jumping up, you know, ten feet while holding onto it.
Rym: Scott, can you jump ten feet?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: I like recumbent bikes, but I'd have no practical use for one.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, I like the idea of it.
Scott: I'm sure it's, I guarantee it's really comfortable.
Rym: If I was ever going to go bicycle touring, I would definitely rent one of those.
Scott: But the problem with it is, A, you know, you gotta have those stupid flags so you don't, you get seen and not killed.
Rym: Well, they're not, you don't use those for, like, normal riding.
Rym: You use those for, like, I'm gonna bike to PAX.
Rym: I'm leaving now.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: So you bike to PAX and you're on some road, but people still need to see you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Because you're way down on the ground.
Rym: Lights and flags.
Scott: You gotta have big lights and flags and it's pretty dorky.
Rym: Uh, dorkiness is not something I care about as a biker.
Scott: Dorky is pretty significant.
Scott: It's high dorkiness level.
Rym: One thing I got now that I never needed my entire life until I was in the city was the rear light.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I always had the front light because I'd bike through the woods at night.
Rym: Like, you know, middle of the night, middle of the woods, without a light, that's basically death waiting to happen.
Scott: Well, you know, there's two kinds of lights.
Scott: There's see and be seen.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And I, basically, in the city, I don't need to see.
Rym: No matter how dark it is.
Scott: Well, there's some places where the street lights are a little bleh, so you do need to see a little bit.
Rym: Where?
Rym: The light from the clouds from Manhattan is enough in most of the cities.
Scott: No, there's, like, a couple streets I go down on the way home sometimes that have, uh, heavy tree cover.
Rym: Oh, in Queens?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I can see that.
Scott: So, it's, like, this one place right next to a school, where if you go there at night, it's only, like, half a block.
Scott: But it is dark half a block because there are trees there.
Scott: And you can't see anything because the trees completely cover the street.
Rym: But I only need the lights now in the city.
Rym: They're the Annoy-a-trons.
Rym: They're the, "Please don't hit me with your car, you
Rym: jackasses.".
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You also get out of reflectors on, you know, some part of you because, you know.
Rym: Yeah, well, every bike comes with reflectors.
Scott: No, I mean, like, you know, like, on your bag or on your hat or something like that.
Scott: No, I don't do any of that.
Rym: I got the two Annoy-a-trons from the bag.
Scott: I got, like, because my Timbuk2 bag has reflectors built in.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I guess mine does, too.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I forgot about that.
Rym: But I got reflectors all over the bike.
Rym: I got a rear reflector and the Annoy-a-tron.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And that Annoy-a-tron, let me tell you, is really fucking annoying.
Rym: I got a really good one.
Rym: It blinks in this double irregular pattern of white, like, this white flash and then a whole bunch of red going, like, bit-a-bit-a-bit-a-bit-a.
Rym: And it's way bright.
Rym: Like, it hurts to look at it.
Scott: I just got a pretty cheap one.
Scott: It's still good, but it came in a set with also a little bike computer.
Scott: It's fun.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta get a bike computer.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: Just use your phone.
Rym: Yeah, well, my phone's GPS, if I leave it too long, will occasionally start jumping.
Scott: It'll be like... Well, you're gonna have a different phone soon.
Rym: Yeah, it's like, oh, he was...
Scott: And now what you do is you get a mount for your phone on your bike.
Rym: Like, one day, I biked around Metlas Central Park.
Rym: Like, I went over the bridge.
Rym: I did a whole lap around Central Park, and then I went, like, downtown and back home.
Rym: And I knew how far I went.
Rym: I looked, and it was like, you went 88 miles.
Rym: And I'm like, huh.
Rym: I went 88 miles, eh?
Rym: So I look at the map.
Scott: Wow, 88 miles an hour.
Scott: You can go back in time.
Rym: According to the map, I went halfway to Central Park, then I teleported to the Hudson, biked around there for a while, came back to Central Park.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Way to go, Palm.
Rym: Of course, now they're selling that watch.
Scott: What the hell watch?
Rym: The HP Metal.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It's some gimmick that links your pre to your laptop, to your computer, to the cloud.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I haven't even read the pig out of it yet.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So, do you want, like, seriously, do you want to go mountain biking at some point this summer?
Scott: Not really.
Rym: I mean, because we did.
Rym: Remember that one time when we lived in Beacon, we got in my car, we parked in that condo parking lot, and then we went to Red Oaks Mill with all the ticks and went mountain biking.
Scott: Yeah, that was not so exciting.
Rym: Really?
Rym: I thought it was really fun.
Rym: When we got to that gorge.
Scott: Yeah, like when you ran over my bike with your car.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That was actually pretty funny.
Rym: I forgot about that until just now.
Rym: We're like, are we all set?
Rym: Is everything mounted?
Rym: We're both like, yeah, we get in the car and we back up and we're like, what's that noise?
Rym: We get out and your bike, we just never put it on the car.
Rym: I just ran over it.
Scott: Well, no, it was a tire that was just left on there.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It caught my muffler, too, which fell off later, unrelatedly.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Scott: That bike is gone.
Scott: It exploded.
Rym: The other bike I used?
Rym: Still got it.
Rym: It's downstairs.
Scott: Well, that bike served me well at RIT.
Rym: Yeah, and then it filled with water and exploded.
Rym: Poor bike.
Scott: Oh, well.
Rym: I think we're petering out.
Rym: It's late.
Rym: We're tired.
Rym: We may or may not have recorded a lot of other unrelated things today.
Rym: Day?
Rym: Actually, it is night now.
Rym: But yeah, we recorded this a while ago and we needed a throwaway episode, so bikes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Bikes.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.