Rym: It's Thursday August 30th 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: I guess we talk about supermarkets.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: I don't think we said anything on the last show just cuz it wasn't really Jermaine, but the the gays can marry in New York.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Hooray Hooray, I actually stayed up to nominally.
Rym: to you know, we're like, oh we'll stay up and wait to see if they vote.
Rym: We'll be right like.
Rym: well no Watching really.
Rym: we're just watching New York's East Band.
Rym: We're just watching a movie and it was kind of funny like we're sitting there watching Billy Elliot about.
Rym: you ever seen that movie?
Scott: It's a Broadway show.
Rym: It's also a movie.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Rym: Yeah, the movie's really good.
Rym: It's on Netflix streaming.
Rym: You're just watching.
Scott: I know what it's about.
Rym: Yeah, so it's about.
Rym: for those of you who don't know a young boy in a poor, you know Northern British mining town during all the troubles and the strikes and everything and very kind of you know Blue-collar working-class people.
Rym: his dad wants him to do boxing, but he wants to do ballet So he sneaks away from boxing lessons and gets ballet lessons.
Rym: He's super good at it.
Rym: Yeah, and that causes havoc.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't think he's.
Scott: he's not gay though.
Scott: He just like he just likes ballet He's not.
Rym: he just really likes ballet like figure skaters.
Rym: So we're watching the movie and he has a friend who is gay and one thing leads to another and the movies like at its climax were like the super happy.
Rym: like everything is great music is playing and Just as that music starts.
Rym: We all get text messages from people that are like gay marriages past.
Rym: Yeah So we.
Rym: so we're standing there like turning on the news to see what's going on while the hurrah We won music is playing from Billy Elliot.
Rym: It was pretty funny.
Rym: Yeah, and Then we're like.
Rym: and then I saw someone on FARC said they just turned on pink lights on the Empire State Building and I was like bullshit.
Rym: So I went up on the roof like oh maybe.
Rym: and then there was foggy so I couldn't see.
Rym: so.
Rym: And then I was like, wait a minute.
Rym: It was foggy.
Rym: Then how would they see?
Scott: Actually, they had rainbow lights.
Scott: The rainbow lights were left over from something they did previously for something else.
Rym: On the next day - if you got him smoke him or light him.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that by now the Empire State Building is every possible conceivable light color configuration.
Scott: Yeah of red orange yellow.
Rym: I do very much enjoy whenever I see it up in colors and I don't recognize what the deal is.
Rym: I always like to look up and see like oh it's because of whatever.
Rym: well always something weird.
Scott: the problem is is I went to the website and Like once and I just went on the entire list because they have it scheduled in advance except for special.
Rym: I've done that but I've forgotten some of the things that they'll do it for.
Rym: then I remember when I see the colors like all right It's green because of st.
Rym: Patrick's Day or whatever.
Scott: Yeah I like it when it's sports teams winning except as long as it's not Yankees or Jets.
Scott: Yankees aren't that bad They're basically the evil team.
Rym: you ever seen damn Yankees.
Scott: you ever seen Shallon soccer, you know the?
Scott: you know, the evil is full of steroids That's the Yankees.
Rym: I point out that we went to our IT.
Rym: We were the evil team.
Scott: We rooted for the evil team over the evil team.
Scott: nor was I on the evil team.
Rym: RIT hockey was the evil team.
Scott: I was not Scott.
Rym: we were in the corner crew.
Rym: We were basically the stooges of the evil team.
Scott: Hey when you in Mighty Ducks, right?
Scott: No one no one's cheering for the evil team.
Rym: I was sharing to the evil team.
Scott: What the fuck.
Scott: because they way no one in the movie was cheering for the evil team except the evil team, right?
Rym: Of course, there was no cheering allowed in that evil team, but I'm just saying it's like evil teams don't have fans.
Rym: So if you so Yankees have fans, those aren't fans.
Scott: They're not even human.
Rym: I Don't know.
Rym: I always think of that one South Park where the Detroit Red Wings play against those kindergarteners.
Rym: I was rooting for the Red Wings in that game.
Scott: Did you're alone in that?
Rym: So it's Thursday, it's the lounge.
Scott: We can talk about whatever we want you and your lounge.
Rym: So Scott of all the things in the world any topic you could possibly use this fairly public.
Rym: Surprisingly, I don't know why popular forum.
Rym: you have thousands of people listening to your every word right now.
Rym: What is the one thing you want to talk about?
Rym: knowing that you can talk about any goddamn thing in the world?
Scott: Oh, I can talk about anything you can talk about my You know, yeah, you can talk about your dick.
Scott: Who do you think you said it?
Rym: No, what were you gonna say?
Scott: You don't know.
Rym: no, so why are you gonna say then you have something.
Scott: yeah barely barely.
Rym: I got two things.
Scott: so we'll daddy - So you're the one talking about dicks here not me.
Scott: it's on the record of audio record.
Rym: I said the word daddy and a number and somehow you can strew dicks.
Scott: Well, the joke is daddy to peepee It's the next word.
Rym: So you can tell we're punchy today for whatever is whatever.
Scott: so There's not much going on at least, you know, I do have stuff but it's mostly you got to save it for the other days.
Scott: This Google technology stuff this gaming stuff.
Rym: I got a lot to say about Google+ but it's not the time for that.
Scott: There's anime stuff.
Scott: I can't say anything about it cuz I haven't used it.
Rym: I've looked at it.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Scott: So, you know I'm gonna save that for the other days.
Scott: so what's there to talk about today?
Scott: Yeah, not much, but I did notice is a strange coincidence.
Scott: There seemed to be a lot of sales At the same time, huh?
Scott: Well threadless and I think it's related to the 4th of July Like they know that people are home on their computers.
Scott: So all the digital stores are having big discounts, right?
Scott: There's a big steam sale is a big threadless sale.
Rym: I'm sure that Had a sale because I've never bought anything on threadless unless they were doing their $10 sale or Anoth was buying me as many shirts.
Rym: I wanted for free.
Scott: Yeah But the point is this if you want to buy t-shirts and or vidya games now's the time.
Scott: Yeah, the biggest thing on steam I look through there's nothing I really wanted but There's a square Enix idos pack at 75 bucks for life.
Scott: Best deal ever if that's your thing, it's like I didn't want any of those games really.
Scott: But if you wanted those games not even those if you are saving like three you're getting basically getting over $300 worth of games for nothing.
Rym: Yeah, I put it this way if you want even one if you want more than one game That's in that pack.
Rym: You might as well.
Scott: Well, no because I mean it you're still paying $75.
Rym: if you want even one game in the pack, that means that you probably like the kinds of games they make.
Rym: Yeah, you're probably gonna play some of those.
Scott: let's let's look what's in this $75 pack.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: Let's see.
Rym: So man, there was a time when I paid $70 for Zelda 2, okay So there's that Batman game which a lot of people like I already own.
Scott: that All right.
Scott: So this deus ex which I already got both of those a long time ago for like five bucks.
Rym: Yeah, surprisingly that's kind of a forgotten game.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: I'm a month.
Rym: Oh, no not forgotten.
Rym: Let me put it this way It is a game that many people who would like would never have heard of it.
Scott: No, everyone knows about it.
Rym: Nah, you'd be surprised.
Scott: Anyway battle stations.
Scott: I don't even know what that is.
Scott: Conflict Flora's fruit farm.
Scott: Okay, there's a front mission evolved with a ton of expat pretty much every expansion.
Scott: So that's that's an okay game.
Scott: gyromancer.
Scott: I don't even know what that is.
Scott: hit man and hit man, too.
Scott: I played the demo of one of those whatever.
Scott: Oh, there's another.
Scott: there's three hit man's Infernal wouldn't it be hit man, I guess Just cause just cause.
Scott: two and a whole bunch of DLCs for just cause.
Scott: to Canaan Lynch - and a whole bunch of DLCs for that.
Scott: and Canaan Lynch one and a bunch of -.
Rym: so the moral here and a Bunch of bunch even more supreme commander and thief and all right supreme commander the game that was supposed to be the greatest RTS ever and promptly disappeared.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, that's a ton of games that are a lot of monies But you're only paying 75.
Rym: Yeah, I'll wait cuz you know what two years from now I'll buy a pack that has that and more for like ten bucks.
Scott: I know right But I don't even want.
Scott: I don't even want any of these games like.
Scott: even if I bought him when would I play them?
Rym: This is something that's been happening a lot to me.
Rym: Like it wasn't that long ago.
Rym: I was on Amazon.
Rym: I was looking for.
Rym: I wanted to buy like I was.
Rym: you know, whatever you finish an Amazon order You sit there like.
Rym: is there anything else I need?
Rym: Yep anything.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So I looked at anime and I sorted by price.
Rym: Yeah, and gonkotsuo, which is a fantastic like b-plus show It would have been an a-minus if the ending wasn't stupid Was like 18 bucks for the whole box set and a deal and I added to my cart and then I thought I was like, ah 18 bucks.
Scott: Well, it was.
Rym: that's like.
Scott: it's not so much the $18.
Scott: It's that I'm never going to watch this.
Rym: I would possibly watch it one more time at some point in the future.
Rym: and more importantly I only buy DVDs if I'm lending them to people and that's the show I could lend to people.
Rym: There are people I could think of who I'd be like, hey, you should watch this.
Rym: Here you go.
Rym: But then I imagined 18 bucks And I realized that's like one steak dinner and I just I didn't buy it.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I did buy an Amazon for a lot more than 18 bucks.
Rym: Happy steak dinner, but it's a steak dinner.
Scott: Finally, we've been waiting right?
Scott: Disco tech license both these movies and they're finally released.
Scott: Galaxy Express 3 9 movie and I do Galaxy Movie.
Rym: when we get this we're gonna watch him and do some shows on that Yep.
Scott: So I ordered both DVDs even though they were like 15 bucks each.
Rym: so Rose we never did a show on 3 9 Did we?
Scott: I don't know but it doesn't matter.
Rym: in the very least I want to do a show just on the 3 9 movie.
Rym: Yeah independent of the show Independent of any other.
Scott: lazy Matsumoto do plenty of Matsumoto in this in the future.
Rym: Yeah, of course We got a. I'm rocking through fist of the North Star.
Rym: I hit this point where I was like cuz you know when you watch a show that it like sometimes you watch a show any Show and or any media that you're consuming even games you get to a point where you almost feel like it's a chore Especially.
Scott: no, not really only if it sucks.
Scott: Yeah If it's good, I have a strong desire.
Scott: That's pretty much how I can tell us something I like or not is if I have a strong desire to keep going.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Well, I realized this like what was?
Rym: I was watching some show.
Rym: I think Oh cos they know you Jim.
Rym: But I was like, I'm gonna watch the show cuz it was pretty good and then we'll do a show on it.
Rym: I'll get Scott to watch it and I after like six episodes I'd like didn't really care about the seventh episode.
Rym: and then not that long after I watched like I think it was Ava again And I just remember watching one episode me like, oh, right I watched like the whole show in a couple days like you can't help yourself, right?
Scott: Yeah, like I started I was I've been watching.
Scott: oh, dude.
Scott: I saw something.
Scott: That's a short show - it's almost 11 episodes But they're long like selling movies.
Rym: I've only seen two movies and the first episode because cops who showed it to me way back.
Scott: I've seen now 11 episodes and the two movies.
Scott: But there's a third movie and is two or three TV specials and some side spin-off One of which is a Muroi special.
Rym: once I see the best character.
Rym: I have a strong suspicion that the first movie is the best of all of it.
Scott: I The TV shows pretty good.
Rym: It is but that movie is too but concentrated Lee.
Rym: Awesome Yeah, pretty.
Rym: remember that scene at the end where he's on the roof and the music's playing and smoke.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Oh my god, and it's a DS game, which I just got.
Scott: what you can't read.
Rym: Yeah, Scott hands me his DS.
Rym: He's like check this out.
Rym: I'm like, what is it?
Rym: He won't even tell me anything.
Rym: He's like just wait just wait and then I hear Man all right.
Scott: All right But yeah, it's.
Scott: I'm just saying that's an example of something where I watched one and I can't help but watch the next one.
Rym: Yeah, so fist of the North Star.
Rym: I was like that and then it petered out like in the middle of the fur.
Rym: the very first story arcs.
Rym: I was doing other stuff and I can't watch it while I'm doing something else.
Scott: and really for me a Peter the only time I was slow was After the first story arc ended and the second one began and everything went like back to like, you know with the base level I was sort of like,
Rym: uh, so see what got but
Scott: then it built up again.
Rym: It did this weird Peter out and then he got close to King Sama Like it was like alright He's actually gonna go get that bastard.
Rym: and then I just watched like every episode and then the next arc.
Scott: I was about to Peter out and then South Star swallow fist came and I was like, yeah Yes, that's the thing is that beginning of the second arc is a little bit slow But as soon as Ray shows up, you're like, yeah, BAM And then the toll show.
Scott: from then on there is no slowing down.
Scott: cuz you know Kenshiro has that no different recap episodes that you skip.
Rym: like there's the noise that happens when the guys about to explode.
Rym: I like how every power like different style has a different sound before a guy explodes or falls apart or whatever like that weird background like.
Rym: Anyway, it's not Wednesday, that's enough anime but stuff's on sale.
Scott: Yeah, bye.
Scott: It's time to empty your wallets people.
Scott: It's the economy's not doing too good.
Scott: Yeah, we got we have to shut down professional sports leagues possibly shut down government.
Scott: Everything's shutting down.
Scott: Yeah, luckily, so we don't want.
Rym: the thing is He's not shutting down.
Scott: That's right, but we'll be okay as long as steam doesn't shut down.
Scott: So bye games.
Scott: Oh my god We'll be alright if steam shut down.
Rym: Okay, because I just got Galaga yeah, and I have not played it out.
Scott: we Xbox live can't shut down either.
Scott: So by Xbox games like Galaga legions DX it just came out if you don't buy your fool.
Rym: So I'm gonna talk about an aspect of this problem that we haven't talked about Because we've already said a lot of the things that many of you will expect us to say on this issue.
Rym: So don't Scott don't interrupt me with uh, but we've already talked about this.
Rym: cuz I'm gonna skip all that bullshit.
Rym: There's an article here and there's a lot of follow-up articles about the fact that there's a skills gap in America where GV never discussed this before where unemployment is very high yet simultaneously Many many places that are desperate to hire.
Rym: people are unable to find anyone qualified.
Scott: Oh, yeah I thought you're talking about a gaming skills cap.
Rym: Oh Yeah before the show I was like, I'm gonna talk about the skills gap and Scott was like what the fuck We've talked about that.
Rym: Like it's like talking about the gaming skills cap like every Skills gap in the real world.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: You think it's related to the gaming skills cap.
Rym: No, I don't think so.
Scott: I'm sure there are some fundamental principles.
Rym: So here's the deal.
Rym: We already know that there's this problem of huge unemployment and we know that we have this problem where there's a very large unskilled workforce in the US and it's a big problem.
Scott: I wouldn't say it's unskilled I would just say it's.
Scott: I would say this some portion is on Some portion is low and some portion is maybe skilled but in areas that are not valuable.
Rym: No, no, no, that's not it Mm-hmm.
Rym: So according to this article and a couple other articles I found are these articles backed by studies or these just editorials?
Rym: Uh, it's anecdotes from people trying to hire and then demographic information and it's like a hodgepodge of research from places.
Scott: It's an article.
Rym: It's an angle.
Rym: I hadn't thought of before.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So the deal is that and I've had this I mean my company.
Rym: we were trying to hire people forever And it's it's hard to hire people that are.
Rym: when we interviewed was like.
Rym: it's like why'd you even come in?
Rym: Like I'd look at their resume.
Rym: I'd pick any word on it and be like.
Rym: so tell me about this and they just like be Daring headlights.
Scott: Yeah, I don't understand the lying on resumes.
Scott: That's a different issue entirely.
Scott: Well, but I mean in general it is really hard at least, you know.
Rym: If someone who say use the ticketing system put that on their resume like familiarity with.
Rym: but if I ask them About it and they can't tell me anything Yeah, anything at all, I mean there are people who literally apply to programming jobs.
Scott: You can't write fizzbuzz, which is a very simple program, you know Which you anyone any CS major who got went through cs1 should be able to trivially write fizzbuzz.
Rym: I've never heard of fizzbuzz.
Scott: fizzbuzz is pretty simple.
Scott: All you do is loop through numbers, you know X through Y and every single number.
Scott: you print out the number then you print a space.
Scott: Well, you print a space.
Rym: Okay, so far.
Scott: This is one line in Perl right if the number is evenly divisible by three so one line you print out the word fizz still one line.
Scott: and if it's divisible by five you print out the Word buzz.
Scott: and if it's divisible by three and five you print out fizzbuzz Still one line.
Scott: So this program basically forces you to do a iteration B modulus math C string formatting on output flow control Depending on you really.
Scott: but I mean that's basically the three things you have to know in order to write this program.
Scott: It's a trivial program.
Rym: this way It could be slow control in that you could write this in basic with a loop that has if if in it.
Scott: If you really wanted it's mostly about getting the string formatting exactly right with your print statements.
Rym: Yeah Really people couldn't.
Scott: there are people who apply for programming jobs who cannot write that program, you know I don't the line but let's skip past the lying and resumes go to the skill gap.
Rym: Okay, so the skill gap?
Rym: so we People who need highly skilled workers cannot find them.
Scott: That's why highly skilled workers are demanding even more and more money despite a shitty economy.
Rym: Simultaneously, there's this huge like Proportion of the economy that needs low skill work.
Rym: Yeah now as in people who aren't experts at any particular thing But they need people who can write an email with reasonable grammar and spelling keep track of a small number of simple tasks, maybe handle a calendar do trivial clerical work and Many people are not qualified to do this work either
Scott: Really?
Rym: so the problem is that we have the majority of the jobs that people are trying to hire right now.
Rym: if you forget the super High-skilled.
Rym: high-end are moderate to low-skilled jobs.
Rym: yet The majority of our education system does not prepare people for that.
Rym: It prepares people who have money for the high-end and it prepares people who don't have money for nothing.
Rym: It prepares them for no-skill jobs, which aren't in demand anymore.
Rym: So we've got the situation where there are people who literally have no marketable skills Yep, other than they're a warm body and there aren't enough jobs for those people.
Rym: yet simultaneously
Scott: The thing is if I needed a job that wasn't the highest skilled job, right if I need the calendar task managing guy And I can't find anyone who can already do it I'll just interview people to find someone who's nice
Rym: and then just train them
Scott: and train them.
Rym: Ah, so here's what's really going on.
Rym: first Companies are unwilling to train people anymore.
Scott: Well, you know we could the government could solve that if they've had some sort of tax incentive for training.
Scott: like all your tax money You spend on training is tax exempt or something like that.
Rym: Yeah Two people who are in school are basically told by everyone at every turn that if you don't get a degree from a university You're fucked.
Scott: They're lying.
Rym: Yes, they're lying but as a result There aren't people going into vocational programs and a lot of federal and state money that used to prop those programs up has been disappearing Quietly for a long time, you know what plumbers make mad money.
Scott: They make a lot more money than guy who you know manages a calendar.
Rym: Simultaneously a lot of people because they're told to have to get a degree Get huge student loans and get degrees and can't pay them off.
Rym: They get degrees in highly skilled arenas that are not in demand.
Rym: So on the job market they are qualified for jobs that don't exist Yep, and they are qualified for these middle and low skill job.
Scott: people go to college.
Scott: I don't know what I want to do.
Scott: I'll get a liberal arts degree.
Scott: You might as well have gotten no degree.
Rym: But these people are very qualified to do a lot of these middle and low skill jobs that aren't actually very high demand.
Rym: people are Having a lot of trouble hiring people for these positions, but because those people have crippling student loan debt They can't afford to work the low skill job because it doesn't pay enough.
Scott: But if they'd gone to but the thing is I don't understand, right?
Scott: So let's say I spent a lot and I went to a fancy school and I got a history degree.
Scott: Yep, and I'm not gonna be history professor and I can be a history teacher and I got a big-ass loan.
Scott: I need a job that can pay off this big.
Rym: I see you've already made the mistake of getting a big-ass loan mistake.
Scott: I can't Can't undo it, right?
Scott: I could go and get that job as an office clerk I think which I'm qualified for.
Scott: I think a lot of people for stupid reasons like pride don't do that Which is and it's probably that job would not be enough to pay off the student loan, but it's still more than zero, right?
Scott: It's either that job, which isn't enough or nothing.
Scott: It's like why would I choose the nothing?
Scott: I know I can't get.
Scott: I tried I would continue to try even while working that that subpar job to get a better job.
Scott: Well, here's to see if something opens up even if I can't get one It's better to.
Scott: at least it's better to work at Starbucks.
Rym: I make something even if all those people did that they are a tiny portion of the real economy and that there's this huge Just massive people who don't have any marketable skills.
Rym: No one is willing to train them or give them these skills.
Rym: the schooling system doesn't give them these heads for sure And there's really almost no recourse for them.
Rym: and yet simultaneously on the high-skill end No company can hire for crap.
Rym: I get job offers on a daily basis because people are desperate for anyone who knows IT.
Rym: Yeah, and yet I know IT people who can't get jobs.
Scott: This is why the next chance I get I'm gonna negotiate which I've never done before.
Scott: I'm too nice.
Rym: I'm also in the process of some of that that I probably won't talk about just yet.
Scott: So very briefly basically a lesson if you don't have skills get some Don't you know?
Scott: take whatever job you can get even if you have to work at a Home Depot or some shit Temporarily you get.
Scott: you get more than zero dollars.
Scott: do it.
Scott: I would do it and see.
Scott: if you have skills you can negotiate for more money.
Rym: Yep but if you're a young adult who is not yet decided if you're going to go to college if You do some research if you're not going to get a degree that will pay for your student loans You're better
Scott: off or unless if your parents are rich Yeah,
Rym: you're better off not going to college getting a job in one of these middle skill areas while simultaneously Fostering an expertise somewhere else.
Rym: This is a good example.
Rym: become a clerk at a hospital or a bank Because then you start accruing years of quote experience in the medical field or the financial field.
Rym: There's a huge demand for people who have basic skills You know reading writing simple math being an intelligent person and simultaneously who have some Experience with a very specialized industry even if they don't have degree related to said industry.
Scott: Listen to the TED talk with Mike Rowe and basically forget about.
Scott: you know What everyone's told you that you should.
Scott: you know, be what you want to be.
Scott: You can't be what you want to be.
Scott: You'll probably end up poor and start Hey, I wanted to be a rich IT guy.
Scott: Well, yeah, but I mean go, you know, go listen to that TED talk.
Scott: I'm sure it's I was think is the thing of the day.
Scott: once go get a job.
Scott: It'll probably be something you never thought you would do but you can make a lot of money at.
Scott: you Probably don't didn't grow up wanting to be a carpet installer, but you know what a carpet installers can make tons of money.
Scott: You know, you might not thought you would grow up to be a pig farmer But you know what?
Scott: You can make zillions being a big farmer.
Rym: the quote from the one of the articles that I read.
Rym: I think I'll link to this one because the quotes in it Quote we have held on too long to these low-wage low-skill industries and we didn't make a strategic long-term investment in education.
Scott: And he goes on it doesn't help that a lot of the no-skill jobs are outsourced to other countries.
Rym: Yeah, but he's saying that America has a huge demand for middle-skill jobs yet.
Rym: We don't prepare anyone for those jobs.
Rym: so there's a dichotomy between Super qualified people and people with effectively in terms of real-world marketable skills zero marketable skills.
Rym: They don't exist as far as recruiters are concerned because they literally have nothing to offer and no one's willing to train anyone.
Scott: Yep, it sucks.
Rym: So on a lighter note California told Amazon to fuck off.
Scott: Well, you know well Amazon told California to fuck off.
Rym: well, California basically played a bluff game where they said Yeah We're gonna Change the laws to make sure that you have to pay sales tax.
Scott: a lot of states have played this game and Amazon is so Far won every time.
Scott: so I don't know why California thought it was gonna be any different.
Rym: Well here well partly California as we were talking about for the show while Amazon did technically have a business presence there It was small enough to where they can say, you know, what fuck it?
Scott: Well, the only business present they had was affiliates which they have in every state except for states that piss Amazon off by That.
Rym: they had up one like small office in California to whatever but doesn't matter.
Scott: basically for those of you who don't know Amazon affiliates is a system where if you link to Amazon, let's say I link to the book club book on our website.
Rym: We need to do that.
Scott: By the way, if you click on that link and then you buy the book after clicking on that link Amazon gives us some money for basically being freelance salesmen for them.
Scott: We're selling you books.
Rym: Scott write a script that goes through every link we've ever made to Amazon in terms of the new affiliate link.
Scott: Right, but you know, that's that's how Amazon affiliates works.
Scott: So the way the Amazon only charges sales tax in states that require it.
Scott: You know if Amazon has a presence in that state, for example we pay sales tax and Amazon purchases in New York because Amazon has warehouses and distribution centers and other things in the state of New York, right?
Scott: Amazon did not physically have any of those things in the state of California For example the gig night star.
Rym: if you live in New York State You have to pay sales taxes that I then remit to the state of New York any other state?
Scott: Yeah, yeah, if you but technically if you live in say, Missouri, you are supposed to report that On your you know annual income tax report and pay that to the state.
Scott: Never it doesn't happen.
Rym: So Just give all the details of it.
Rym: Here's what I want to talk about.
Rym: Here's the problem.
Rym: I am we need a Either.
Rym: states have to all get together and make collectively an open trivial to interface with Universal system whereby all their sales tax laws Whatever they are are codified such that anyone who's selling anything online or interstate can Trivially do all the taxes automatically without having to research every individual states.
Scott: bullshit That's the federal government's responsibility because it's interstate comments.
Rym: But they won't because all the states manage their own sales tax Which I think they shouldn't be able to charge the people who are out of state because that would be interstate commerce.
Scott: And I don't think yes, it would be allowed.
Scott: It's interstate.
Scott: Well, the problem is though the federal government doesn't want to have federal sales tax.
Rym: Then if I buy something from Connecticut, it should be sales tax-free Yes, or we should have a federal sales tax or Federally administered state sales tax.
Rym: I would be fine with any of those.
Rym: what I'm not fine with this is current situation.
Scott: Where do to tell anyone's fine with the current situation is you know who is?
Rym: who really wants this situation to get worse?
Scott: No, I'm saying who likes it the way it is brick-and-mortar stores.
Rym: They are lobbying hand over fist to keep things the way they are They are and to make Amazon be forced to pay even if they don't have business presences.
Scott: Well, but that's not.
Scott: that's not.
Scott: I'm saying that's that that's a change they're fighting for.
Scott: I'm saying who wants to keep it the way It is right.
Rym: if they can't get their change They want to keep it the way it is because it at least forces online businesses who fall into these loopholes to have to pay.
Scott: yeah, and That amazing thing is it's not like I don't.
Scott: here's the one thing.
Rym: They seem to think that I'm only going to Amazon because I don't have to pay sales tax and that's what I do have to.
Rym: Somehow if I had to pay that trivial sales tax that suddenly I'm gonna go to Best Buy.
Scott: The only thing I don't understand is how does paying sales tax hurt Amazon, right?
Scott: Cuz it's like let's say Amazon sells on for a dollar.
Scott: Collect the sales tax from us and then remit it doesn't have them anything.
Rym: Yeah, it does.
Rym: Here's why it hurts.
Rym: If you say they had to do deal with every state sales tax, okay I say they did.
Rym: every state's laws are so completely different.
Rym: They would have to hire lawyers and do a huge amount of work to constantly make sure they're following all the laws of every state on every transaction.
Rym: Like some states like in New York, there's a sales tax on clothing in certain counties.
Scott: There's an administrative cost But it's not like but the sales tax itself.
Rym: It doesn't cost them anything No But the administrative costs are so high that I think it is Unconscious about conscionable to force Amazon or any online retail to deal with it.
Scott: But if you're like Walmart each individual Walmart store just worries about its own law and doesn't have to worry about the other one.
Rym: But if I'm a store in New York I only have to worry about New York sales tax and I charge it to everyone because they're in New York.
Scott: So, how about this?
Scott: Maybe right there could be some sort of system where it's like Do you want your sales tax to be collected?
Scott: then you must send your data in by this form?
Scott: Yeah, so it's the responsibility of each locale.
Rym: My argument is that in the modern world unless there is an API that does that unless I as a business can automate it and just hook into Arizona and Nevada and Wisconsin system and that handles all of it with like soap or something then I shouldn't know.
Scott: if I was Amazon I would set up a system and you know That would be like.
Scott: that would let them enter the data and be like alright if you want sales tax collected come in and type It in.
Rym: that would be fine except Amazon's in a very strong position to say fuck you.
Scott: Well, they should because it's still.
Scott: I still think it's interstate commerce and the state shouldn't be.
Rym: well The question is if I'm buying something online is the transaction occurring in the state I am in or in the state the service?
Scott: you buy something from Amazon.
Scott: Yeah, Amazon is a company in Seattle.
Scott: Yeah, you're in New York.
Scott: The money is going from your wallet in New York to a wallet in Washington.
Scott: Therefore it is interstate commerce because the money is traversing state boundaries Regardless of if the item you're buying is in a warehouse in New York.
Scott: It doesn't matter The money is going from one state to another.
Scott: it's interstate commerce.
Rym: end of story And I'm not a lawyer.
Scott: Ah You're in Washington State and you buy something from Amazon and the goods are not in Washington State.
Scott: It is still interstate commerce.
Scott: The only situation would be if you give you buy something on Amazon You're in Washington State and it comes from a Washington State warehouse.
Rym: What then?
Rym: it would be instant.
Rym: What if my order is?
Rym: Routed through the internet to other states just because the Internet is the way it is.
Scott: So the servers are not in the state of Washington.
Rym: Maybe they are but the traffic goes through Wisconsin.
Scott: just somehow The internet or the internet routing traffic.
Rym: Yes, because here's a weird example.
Rym: when the Berlin Wall went up there was a subway and They went beat or under the Berlin Wall.
Rym: So there if you rode like one of the West Germany subways papers these I forget which one was which you would technically enter East Germany for a while Because it looped through the territory.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Here's a question.
Scott: I I'm in New York.
Scott: I order something from a mail-order catalog in for in Detroit.
Scott: That's clearly interstate commerce.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The mail goes through Canada.
Scott: Is it international commerce?
Scott: I don't know the met not the actual goods.
Scott: the goods don't go through customs now.
Rym: Here's why I feel that you know, this is one of those situations I think the federal government should step in.
Rym: I think Should be heavily regulated by the feds and seriously fuck the states on this.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Scott: Oh A very old thing of the day that everyone in the world knows.
Scott: I'm gonna bring it back.
Rym: If you don't know don't tell anyone that Zombocom Welcome.
Rym: Welcome to Zombocom where anything is positive.
Rym: Zombocom is the most extensible website The world has ever seen.
Rym: it is the fact that it was made unattainable is attainable Like it was made so long ago and yet it does more than any single website.
Rym: web 2.0.
Scott: So much is possible that Zombocom could even be converted from flash to HTML 5.
Rym: The unattainable was attained.
Scott: It was attained.
Scott: HTML 5 Zombocom.
Rym: Oh So this is one of those.
Rym: this is the kind of thing that like morning zoo would talk about but this intrigues me.
Rym: This is one of those things where we're the internet not around.
Rym: I would never get to find out what the deal is.
Rym: There's a pool.
Rym: In this pool someone drowned a swimming pool large public swimming pool outdoors with many lifeguards.
Rym: Someone drowned.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: No one noticed the body for at least two days if not longer.
Scott: What was it?
Scott: a deep pool?
Scott: Yes, what was the color of the pool?
Rym: a blue?
Scott: Okay, so some pools aren't blue.
Rym: some of them are like gray cement, you know But like it's bluish cement or it's white cement and you know water is blue.
Scott: So this person was at the bottom of the deep pool, yes, what color was the bathing suit?
Rym: I don't know and it's.
Scott: but they sunk.
Scott: they didn't float.
Rym: They sunk and drowned and then days later Despite the fact that multiple news agencies had taken pictures of this pool for unrelated stories and no one noticed the body.
Scott: Well, it was in the bottom of the pool.
Scott: It's conceivable that no one would notice it.
Rym: Scott You can see to the bottom of any pool.
Scott: I'm just saying that you you could but if you weren't looking for it Scott lifeguards are obligated to look.
Rym: I know also they closed the pool at the end of the day.
Rym: You think someone might look in the pool also?
Rym: inspectors pool inspectors Inspected this pool twice while the body was there.
Rym: maybe more times, right?
Scott: But I mean you ever watch that video where it tells you count the number of times the guy bounces the basketball and there's a Dancing bear.
Rym: Yeah, but Scott's job is to look for drowned people.
Scott: Lifeguards job is look for people currently drowning.
Rym: No also drowned people.
Rym: there They're.
Rym: you're supposed to look at the bottom of the pool.
Rym: In fact, if you can't see the bottom of the pool because the pool is cloudy Then you have to get everyone out of the pool immediately.
Rym: That's like rules almost every pool.
Scott: No, I'm not an expert in lifeguarding.
Scott: The point is it I could conceive of looking at a pool.
Scott: They're being someone at the bottom and not physically seeing them.
Rym: But Scott if you're a lifeguard, that's your only job.
Scott: Regardless what I really don't there were three lifeguards what I really don't understand.
Rym: a kid Saw the person at the bottom of the pool Early on anything went to a lifeguard and said I think someone drowned.
Rym: nobody did anything.
Scott: Well, that's a problem.
Scott: But this is what I don't understand.
Scott: Did the person come to the pool unaccompanied?
Rym: Apparently they went with friends and left and no one noticed that the person was.
Rym: Understand is like a friend said after the fact that the person didn't know how to swim.
Rym: They didn't know why they went to the pool.
Scott: You go to the pool with your friends and you leave without them and you don't wonder what happened to them and you just leave.
Scott: That's what's really weird.
Rym: This is just like that and there's more crazy.
Scott: This is like a craziest and how could no one saw the person while they were drowning?
Rym: Well, cuz usually you don't you know, you know, we I think we talked about on the show how all right drowning People don't look like drowning people.
Rym: No, they look like perfectly fine and then they disappear.
Rym: Yeah, but Here's my guess.
Rym: I am pretty sure that the inspectors Weren't inspecting the pool and we're taking bribes to not have to inspect the pool and now they're fucked.
Scott: Well, I mean pool inspectors.
Scott: do they actually, you know, don't they usually just check the chemicals and stuff?
Rym: Yeah, and also other things for example turbidity if the pool is too cloudy.
Rym: They have shut it down.
Rym: Uh-huh, and they reported everything was fine.
Rym: Oh my god on far.
Rym: There's a picture of the pool from this news article.
Rym: someone uh, Pasted Waldo's face.
Rym: Oh That's clever, okay.
Rym: But this is just a really Sad and messed up story and I really want to know what the deal is.
Rym: The government stepped right in.
Rym: they're like What the fuck is this?
Rym: They put everybody involved on leave.
Rym: Well, yeah Every employee of the pool all the inspectors who inspected the pool and not only didn't see the body but didn't see the fact that The pool was cloudy and it's just like.
Rym: also Scott There were hundreds of people swimming in this pool every day and none of those people notice None of those people.
Rym: you think one kid with goggles would have been like there's a body down there.
Scott: Yeah, so why wasn't there?
Scott: Must have been something about the body or the bathing suit or something that made it hard to see it or the cloudiness.
Rym: Ah FARC when minorities drown in pools, it turns out they become transparent.
Scott: Oh, it was minority.
Rym: I don't know I mean, no, no, I stopped.
Rym: basically I'd already read enough crazy things that I didn't read the rest of the article.
Scott: this story sounds too crazy.
Scott: It's I'm waiting for Snopes report on this one.
Scott: It's looking pretty legit and it's yeah, I'm waiting for the Snopes report to get all the real details.
Scott: I can't you know, this is too crazy.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: So apparently her friends did say she was missing.
Scott: Okay?
Rym: investigators began looking for her after park personnel told them they found clothing a Cellphone and her identification card at the pool when they closed it, but they didn't investigate the pool or the facilities.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah Police were told the woman was missing and was last seen at the pool.
Rym: They apparently went to the place and didn't notice anything.
Scott: either There must have been something that you couldn't see it for some reason because the police the police would have seen it or There might be something else.
Rym: Here's the crazy.
Scott: There's no way there could be crazy that many people.
Rym: Here's a crazy guess.
Rym: Someone was murdered.
Rym: They broke into the pool While it was closed and slipped the body in and then people found it the next day But the body had.
Rym: they drowned the person.
Rym: so the coroner was like, yeah, they drowned two days ago.
Scott: The body was found eventually though, right?
Rym: It was found by kids who broke into the pool to swim after it was closed days after the body was in the ball.
Scott: Maybe the pool was just so crowded.
Scott: No one ever could see the bottom.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: What's the cloudiness?
Rym: This is just crazy and too crazy.
Scott: There has to be something else to it.
Rym: I Don't know.
Rym: We'll find out.
Rym: Fark is following this heavily.
Scott: I'm thinking about hitting up the pool pretty soon.
Rym: I'm thinking about going to that giant ass pool in Queens.
Scott: That's my pool.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah I bike near it once.
Scott: Yeah, really happening.
Scott: It wasn't that crowded and it was really nice looking.
Rym: It was really nice.
Scott: There's people like barbecue and all around as long as you don't go when there's like a bunch of kids going.
Rym: Oh Scott I was about to say let's go this weekend But this is probably the worst possible weekend to go to that.
Scott: I'm gonna go bike around near it pretty soon.
Rym: I tell you what that pool is chill this weekend and not super crowded.
Rym: We should you me Pete and Nuri and Emily should go over there swim and grill.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, anyway So in the meta moment the book club book, which I'm going to do.
Rym: Yeah, you did what you were going to do today, but we didn't because I got distracted and did not read foundation.
Rym: yet We're gonna have the book club book episode soon.
Scott: It's Isaac Asimov's foundation and What we're gonna do is book club, you know the problem with book club I think right now is that it does seem like people are actually reading and some people actually care a lot.
Scott: You know enough people care to make it worth it.
Rym: You got enough feedback to people.
Scott: is enough people to care?
Rym: I didn't think it was that popular but we got all this feedback suddenly.
Scott: But the thing is because we only do a Thursday episode every other week and it's like we don't want book club to be like Every other Thursday, that's too much.
Scott: Yeah, right, you know They would be half the Thursday episodes to be book club episodes if we did it monthly.
Scott: and also we're gonna make book club Its own show once a month.
Scott: So there'll be 12 book clubs a year.
Rym: because the trouble too is that if we do the book club You know normal geek 9s format we get all this other news and cruft on the episode.
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna do book club as its own episode once a month.
Scott: It's not gonna replace a Thursday episode anymore, which is means we really need Thursday episode ideas to send them in.
Rym: also I'm going to go find all the old book club episodes pull out the book club portions and put them in this feed Separate.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It'll be it's.
Scott: I'll make it on its own section on the website.
Rym: So anyway, if you have not yet finished Isaac Asimov's foundation, it's really short.
Scott: You only got a few we a week couple weeks to listen to get the very least.
Rym: Just read the Wikipedia that tells you what it's about.
Scott: Yeah, cuz that metamoment ConnectiCon is next week.
Rym: We are the directors of the panels department gasp and we're not doing that many panels.
Rym: We're doing a few because it's a lot of work to run a fucking panels department.
Scott: Let me tell you what, yep So we'll be there and then probably the week after that.
Scott: We'll do the episode of foundation.
Rym: Yep, and any other Unofficial book club book is all of our Scott backers Prince of Nothing books.
Rym: Just read them all because shit's going down with that.
Scott: We're out of merch.
Scott: We're absolutely out of murder.
Scott: gonna order more merch.
Scott: I'm working on that probably after ConnectiCon all right But it's been time for packs though.
Rym: Hopefully in the very least.
Rym: I'll try to order the same shirt again at PAX.
Scott: We need a new shirt.
Scott: Yep, send in shirt designs to Anything else.
Rym: oh that is pretty much it.
Rym: we will be at PAX Prime doing at least one panel possibly more Panel like things.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: PAX dev is a maybe we don't know.
Scott: Yeah That's it all right, so Thursday, this is your idea, yeah Supermarch How you say it in French?
Scott: Okay, supermarch.
Rym: All right I don't know.
Rym: It's kind of funny that Supermarkets when gives is the best episodes over matter to me a lot more now that I don't have access to them the way I once Did.
Scott: well Stu Leonard's is also the best Almost like an amusement park.
Scott: It's a difference.
Scott: It's not exact.
Scott: It's not quite the same, right?
Scott: It's like if you go to Wegmans, it's like a normal supermarket But the best Stu Leonard's is like its own kind of thing mostly for getting fresh produce dairy meats.
Scott: You don't really buy the stuff that comes in packages from Stu Leonard's.
Rym: It's something that despite being very regional is very Uniform throughout the entirety of the United States.
Rym: I mean, it's it's necessarily well generally uniform.
Rym: you walk into a real big deal non Walmart supermarket and there's produce on the right.
Scott: Well, I mean that's just because you know supermarket design has become such.
Scott: they figured out the maximum money makings.
Scott: Right is how do we arrange this store to make the most money and also meet the health codes?
Scott: and also, you know Do all these requirements.
Rym: but like my whole life I've had this whole like this ritual of going to the supermarket to buy groceries on a regular basis and it was this kind of steady Cornerstone of my mundane life Up in New York City and then everything changed.
Rym: like this is one of those places where everything's totally different.
Scott: Well, you have a doorman so you can order food online.
Rym: Yeah, also I live in a neighborhood where there aren't any supermarkets within a walking distance.
Scott: I still go to the supermarket.
Scott: In fact, they're opening up a supermarket on my block.
Scott: once it's ready I won't have to cross the street.
Rym: got to admit though New York supermarkets are not really the same as what we're used to.
Scott: Well, it's not a gigantic suburban supermarket that has everything in the goddamn universe, but has enough.
Scott: I'm just one person.
Scott: What the fuck do I need?
Rym: Well, it's also the fact that now that you know, you go to it more often with less carrying capacity.
Rym: It's not like the member in Beacon.
Rym: We'd be like, there's also less.
Scott: that's good less food spoilage.
Scott: Yeah, let's more money-saving.
Rym: Yeah, like I buy way more expensive food now than I ever bought but I buy a lot less of it.
Rym: Yep, even though I'm eating more.
Rym: Yep, but we used to have the ritual like it's been a week and a half.
Rym: We're out of food.
Rym: We'd like for core GeekNights than at 930 10 o'clock at night by a ton of food.
Rym: We'd go to the shop right and buy as much food as we possibly could so you wouldn't have to go back so soon Cuz it's far away.
Scott: take like I have a chore to go there to get it out of the car and get it like unpacked.
Rym: Yeah, oh my god, and I was always exhausted.
Rym: We'd.
Rym: I get up at like 5 a.m.
Rym: The next morning to catch a train for a but you had food.
Scott: I did have food And I have all these fun like weird.
Scott: and the thing is the only advantage of the bigger supermarket, right?
Scott: Like a Wegmans isn't that like it's any?
Scott: you know The reason it's better is not because it just has a more selection, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I don't necessarily need more selection.
Scott: it's just the particular things particular items that I greatly desire and Smaller supermarkets with less selection or less likely to have those particular not all gonna have the Nueva Cucina Exactly.
Scott: You can make a small supermarket and if I was the purchaser and I chose what would be on the shelves It would be the best supermarket ever because it's just a few, you know Each person has a few items that are like their brands their items that they need
Rym: Direct.
Rym: they do that.
Rym: I get figures it out.
Rym: So every time I log in it lists like here's all the shit you always buy and I'm like, yep one of those There's a humongous cereal aisle right and this you particularly like.
Scott: maybe three cereals boo berry, right?
Scott: So if there's?
Scott: if there was a tiny supermarket that only had those three cereals You don't care that all the other cereals are missing.
Scott: But the fact is odds are any supermarket is probably gonna have one of those cereals and the giant supermarket might have all three Amongst the mass of cereals.
Scott: Which is why you prefer the bigger supermarket because they're gonna have all the things you like just because they have so much selection.
Rym: so I Learned something very important when we were living in Beacon.
Rym: right one day one day I skipped work for whatever reason.
Rym: like I just didn't go to work.
Rym: It was like a Tuesday.
Scott: I thought I will buy groceries Now when I will be at the grocery store groceries during a weekday when all the old ladies are there.
Rym: and That was like another world.
Rym: it was like I was transported to a world of old people.
Rym: Yep, slow old people with carts blocking every aisle.
Rym: Yep It was like this disaster of untold proportions.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I ended up leaving and not buying anything.
Scott: Yeah, it's it.
Scott: that's a big problem in supermarkets, right?
Scott: Is that you know, they need to stock a lot of things no matter the size of the store.
Scott: They can't really have big wide aisles.
Scott: So the aisles are usually you know Wegmans has nice wide aisles.
Scott: Not even they're not, you know.
Scott: at best you can fit two carts side-by-side, right?
Rym: I've seen three.
Scott: I've never seen three.
Rym: I've seen three, you know Two letters you can do.
Rym: Leonard's is one five.
Scott: Yes, right soon as there's a one-way lane It goes through the store.
Scott: You do not stop you do not turn around you do not make any decision.
Rym: That's what we need.
Rym: that would fix that problem right quick.
Scott: You go from the beginning to the end.
Scott: you have to go through every section my whole life.
Rym: It's amazed me.
Rym: forget the old people just any time you go to the supermarket any hour.
Rym: And what do we do Scott?
Rym: we walk in we split up.
Rym: we go like Get everything we need as fast as possible get the fuck out.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I'll linger in a couple areas.
Rym: I'll linger in the meat-cheese area like all right.
Rym: I really like me.
Rym: I'll linger in the fresh vegetables area like oh I want to buy all of these but I shouldn't cuz I can't eat them all And that's it.
Rym: Otherwise, I get the fuck out but everyone like most people I ever see It's like they're walking.
Rym: they walk into the supermarket with purpose like I am going to buy X things and get out and get on with my life and then They like stop at the entrance and they're like days.
Scott: It's a psychological thing.
Rym: the same thing casinos do and then they like shuttle like up and down every aisle.
Scott: It's a well-studied science of coercion that is affecting you whether you realize it or not.
Scott: It's like you think you run in and run out But you know what you probably bought something that you weren't planning on.
Scott: thing is I run it even if you're consciously Forcing yourself not to do it.
Scott: You end up doing it.
Rym: I noticed when I started buying groceries online that I there are a lot of things I don't buy anymore.
Scott: Yeah, buying online is great.
Scott: Yeah Plus the best part of a buying online is that you never have to buy when you're hungry.
Scott: go into the store when you're hungry.
Scott: Is the worst I I did is you end up buying a bunch of shit You're not gonna use.
Rym: I usually when I go hungry.
Rym: I always buy a lot of like chips and salsa Yeah, and odds.
Rym: I'll buy a lot of odds.
Scott: It's you're not eating.
Rym: It's spots.
Rym: Yep I have weird fond memories of being in supermarkets like way late at night.
Scott: Yeah being supermarkets late nights fun is alright.
Rym: I hate it when markets aren't 24/7 even here like the food seller the only nice supermarket near me is closed at like 10 o'clock.
Scott: What the fuck.
Scott: what the fuck be open all the time.
Scott: I need food all the time.
Rym: Yeah, I Not anymore cuz I got delivery police.
Scott: the bodegas always open.
Rym: Yeah, but I guess Even though they were like five bucks for ice cream.
Scott: My bodega is expensive bodega guys made a new video.
Scott: They're actually Boeing Boeing's hooking up with them.
Rym: Oh, we should the Internet's Celebrities we should talk to those guys.
Scott: Those are the best guys.
Scott: They're still on the show.
Scott: They're still at it.
Rym: Yeah, those are good guys.
Rym: Those are my favorite guys, but it's something like when I was a kid.
Rym: You know when you're too young to go to a bar There's nothing to do in town.
Rym: I'd always end up with a bunch of friends every now and then randomly either at like the playground Behind one of the elementary school.
Scott: You can't go to a playground.
Scott: You'll get in trouble because you're not accompanied by a child.
Rym: Yeah, when I was a kid when I was a punk kid you go to a park but on a playground.
Rym: yeah, that's bullshit, but anyway or I'd go to with all my friends like Meyer like the supermarket at like 3 a.m.
Rym: Cuz that's one of the few places that kids can go and you can get stuff that might be fun.
Rym: They won't kick you out.
Scott: They've got like a tiny toy and game section.
Rym: Yeah, you can sit on like the one bicycle the Huffy that they built in the corner and you can get it around.
Rym: You can get a candy from the candy Tubs of the shittest ice cream in the world for like a dollar and get frozen pizza To put in the way.
Scott: you can get popcorn.
Scott: you can get a lot of stuff in the supermarket and you just hang out.
Rym: Yeah, you know until they kick you out because your punk kids they don't want you there.
Rym: Yeah, but and at RIT remember we used to have to take the bus to Wegmans.
Scott: Well, that's only because you're carrying so many groceries.
Scott: You couldn't walk back with them.
Scott: Well, it was also kind of far and we didn't have cars.
Rym: yet We take that one movie mall shuttle.
Rym: We'd always go.
Rym: It's like a ritual like we'd always go to the Wegmans and we'd buy all our stuff and then we'd miss the bus.
Rym: cuz we'd Walk over to one of those other stores cuz we were waiting for the boss.
Scott: There's like go to the borders and then you run back from the border.
Rym: See the boss like fuck.
Rym: Yep It was a good times.
Scott: Yeah, I wouldn't wanna go back to those times.
Rym: I you know, I kind of almost would cuz today.
Scott: there are aspects of those times clearly that are wanted but the time you know You mean no responsibility infinite free time, but the aspect of you know Going to the grocery store at a bus and carrying girl is not what I want.
Rym: But I have the fond memories of that.
Rym: cuz it was.
Rym: we're basically just hanging out.
Rym: It was basically GeekNights with three additional people for a couple hours, and then we got home with food.
Rym: Yeah, but you still don't want and we used to hang out in borders.
Rym: Yeah, cuz used to be bookstores.
Scott: Yeah, they used to be.
Scott: Yeah, yeah Supermarkets supermarkets is pretty much the only physical store that I still have to go to.
Rym: I don't anymore.
Rym: It's pretty great.
Rym: Actually.
Scott: Yeah, you know I could.
Scott: I think someone in my building does fresh direct But I just I'm not home to get it.
Scott: Well, you can schedule it for specific time Yeah, but that's you know, it's like okay.
Scott: I'll schedule for 10 at night.
Scott: These guys show up 10 at night with groceries like great.
Scott: Yeah, I don't really want to do that.
Rym: Why?
Scott: It's not my idea.
Rym: schedule it between like it's two-hour intervals schedule for like six o'clock.
Rym: Yeah They just bring it in.
Scott: That means I definitely have to be home.
Rym: I can't make a spontaneous plan Like if you're home, they take it into your kitchen for you.
Scott: not if yeah, but if I'm home That's the thing is I'm almost never home.
Rym: Yeah, you could live in a building with the doorman.
Scott: Yeah to move.
Rym: Yeah Yeah doorman.
Scott: But there's gonna be a grocery store opening up directly next to my house.
Scott: know what I plan to do when that happens.
Scott: Buy food and then eat it immediately and then only buy food.
Scott: I'm going to eat.
Scott: Oh shit, son immediately.
Rym: Now you gotta have some emergency food.
Rym: You know, obviously I was in piece of shit.
Scott: Well, obviously I would buy breakfast.
Scott: right cuz you need to get I'm not gonna wake up go to the shots of the store Come back in and eat the breakfast.
Scott: But you know, it's like I won't like stock up and a whole bunch of dinners.
Scott: I'll go out grab the ingredients for the dinner bring them in cook them.
Rym: one thing I stopped doing that I used to do a lot and I and now I kind of do it on fresh direct but not as much as When you're walking through the vegetable aisle, I'll see like artichokes or something.
Rym: I'm like, oh man, I should cook that.
Rym: Ah And then I make something I never would have made.
Scott: No, I do that.
Scott: I go on internet's I find recipes and then I buy the ingredients for the recipe that do not already I don't.
Scott: and the non parachute.
Rym: I buy stuff and I just cook with that stuff.
Rym: I just like alright, I got scallions eggs I'm not.
Scott: I do not have the skills of just taking random ingredients of cooking.
Rym: I'm getting there.
Rym: I can do that with certain things.
Rym: I can do that with egg and cheese based dishes.
Scott: Yeah, I could also do that with egg and cheese based the worst eggs ever.
Rym: Don't even talk to me about it, but I'm saying is if I had to I can combine What a dishes you like other than McDonald's egg, which is the only egg you ever make egg combined with pepper onion cheese And or so McDonald's omelet scallion.
Rym: Yeah So omelet do you actually flip the omelet?
Rym: Yeah, do you?
Scott: I need to get an omelet pan to make it easier?
Scott: Yeah, I do a real shitty job.
Rym: You don't make other egg dishes like frittata eggs over easy eggs benedict sunny-side egg a quiche.
Scott: I don't like you.
Rym: sunny-side is the only dangerous one.
Rym: You should need sunny-side, but I like it.
Rym: Anyway, I actually prefer over easy.
Scott: I like sunny-side.
Rym: just showing eggs.
Rym: Tell you yeah, I could talk about eggs for an hour.
Scott: They come out of chickens.
Scott: You open them up.
Scott: They taste good.
Scott: Cook them thoroughly.
Rym: The best egg ever is over easy French toast Where the yolk is liquid but the rest of it is not and you break it in half with toast and you shut dry toast And you shove that toast in that like egg yolk girls.
Scott: It's a girl scout.
Scott: We cut the hole in the middle of the in the bread and you put the egg in the middle.
Rym: No, that doesn't make the same thing.
Rym: It's got to be fried over easy in an obscene amount of butter.
Rym: Yeah, like an amount of butter.
Rym: That is ridiculous.
Scott: Nothing about New York grocery stores, right?
Scott: You know, not only do you have since you go less often you can buy less food at a time But they also offer smaller items, right?
Scott: So it's like in the suburbs.
Scott: They offer bigger ones.
Scott: Yeah, I can buy half a dozen eggs.
Scott: They cut the egg cartons in half and sell you six eggs.
Scott: Yep, and I can't get that at the big grocery stores There's also every region of the US and I'm sure other countries as well have different grocery stores, right?
Scott: So Wegmans is only available in certain places.
Scott: Yeah The stop and shop is only available in certain places.
Scott: shop right is only in.
Rym: Wondered what the fuck was with the people who went to tops in Rochester.
Scott: I don't know it was cheaper.
Rym: It wasn't cheaper.
Rym: I went there once.
Scott: I never went there.
Scott: but down south You can go to Publix or Winn-dixie right in Florida or Georgia or whatever.
Scott: And the thing is, you know each supermarket while they're mostly the same each one has you know Depending on its region and what store it is has its special things.
Scott: like Aldi the German supermarket place.
Scott: They sell like incredibly cheap computers Thing and people line up to buy them.
Scott: Meyer Publix in Florida, they make peanut butter.
Scott: in the deli section You can buy the peanut butter.
Scott: It's like Institution.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well Stu Leonard's is its own special things only like four of them I think like Myers in Michigan.
Rym: little note little weird aside if you're ever in Michigan or parts of the Midwest like that part like The the more affluent part of the Midwest almost any store name, especially if it's like a grocery kind of store.
Rym: They always they don't pluralize it but they add an S on the end because it's usually like like it's that Person's store like Kroger's or Meyers because I'm going to Walmart's Kmart's.
Rym: Actually, yeah people often will say things like Kmart's.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know this you know, while we don't do that so much in the Northeast right for you know, for example There are stores such as JC penny and people say I'm going to pennies or JC pennies.
Scott: But you know Macy's has an S at the end.
Rym: But in the Midwest just you'll know you'll notice you'll know people in the Midwest because they will say Grocery stores.
Scott: Yeah Min's has an S at the end and Stu Leonard's does too, but people don't say stop in shops.
Scott: They say stop and shop.
Scott: Yep You know Price right.
Rym: I remembered an ancient inside Joe shop, right?
Rym: I'm gonna go to Wegmans tonight.
Rym: I really need to get to Wegmans.
Rym: It's been a while.
Scott: It's been a while.
Rym: Yeah, actually hasn't.
Rym: But like Meyers in Michigan that like my big grocery store.
Rym: Imagine something like twice as big as one of those stupid Walmart's.
Rym: they sell fucking everything.
Rym: There's like a whole grocery store and then also like computer store car park.
Rym: Yeah, I don't understand.
Scott: people who buy groceries at like say Target, you know, it's like sure they do have a grocery section But it's like it's so sad.
Scott: Do they really have produce?
Rym: not as much as I hate Walmart super Walmart's have what is a facsimile of a real grocery store Target the fuck like.
Scott: really what the fuck it's like you can buy groceries there, but really really Why you even maybe if I was at Target for something else that I couldn't buy an Amazon for some weird reason.
Rym: Where is Target?
Rym: It's always connected to a mall or something.
Scott: There's a target.
Scott: Uh, let's connect to a mall.
Rym: They're all connected to malls.
Scott: There aren't really any in the city there.
Scott: Yeah nearest one I think isn't like Queens Boulevard, which is way east of here.
Scott: Yeah anyway Anyway, are we done with the show?
Rym: I think I think we're done.
Rym: What are you gonna say about grocery stores?
Scott: We like grocery stores kind of but I miss fucking Wegmans.
Scott: Yeah Wegmans is the best especially two-story Wegmans.
Rym: We'll be out of town in like another town And we'll we'll like think back to Wegmans like oh man if we see a Wegmans like we'll want to go to it like it's An event.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.