Rym: It's Tuesday, June 14th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we've outcored ourselves into a corner.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So did you go to the board game night on Friday?
Scott: No, I was at the Amazon Web Services Summit.
Scott: Ahh.
Scott: I actually could have gone to the board game night, but I sort of forgot until just as I was leaving the summit, and then I was like, "I don't want to
Scott: go.".
Scott: So I went home.
Rym: Yeah, I was on the beach, and I probably would have gone to the board games otherwise.
Scott: Wasn't the weather sort of...
Rym: No, it was perfect.
Scott: Because up here it was bleh.
Rym: The weather was basically like Saturday, you know, we get up and it rains.
Rym: Like, pours and rains, and nobody goes to the beach, and then like an hour later, it totally clears up, and the water's warm, and the beach is empty, and it was just perfect beach weather for two days.
Scott: It was gray and bleh here.
Rym: Yep, you should have come to the beach.
Scott: I was busy.
Rym: Yeah, you could have come to the beach instead.
Rym: What were you busy doing?
Scott: I went to the... There was a huge barbecue situation in Madison Square Park.
Rym: Yeah, I had some.
Rym: I could have had barbecue.
Rym: I chose not to.
Scott: This barbecue.
Scott: Okay, so, you know, you go and you expect the barbecue to be like amazing, because they're like, "Oh, the pitmaster.
Scott: The great pitmasters are here," right?
Scott: And basically the way it works is every place sets up a stand, and it's eight bucks for whatever they're serving, and you don't have a choice.
Scott: So it's like, if you want what one guy is serving, you go up, you pay eight bucks, he gives it to you, right?
Scott: And pretty much everyone gives you, like, a thing with a side in it, right?
Rym: See, as much as I would have, you know, enjoyed things like that, Rymn's Law of the Diminishing Returns of Crowds comes into effect.
Scott: Right, so it was...
Rym: The bigger an event is, the less fun individual people attending that event will have, on average.
Scott: But anyway, so it was, you know, it wasn't as crowded as it looked in the pictures on the internet.
Scott: And actually, when I was there, I went there pretty early on Saturday, it actually wasn't all that crowded, and you could eat at almost any of the places without waiting.
Scott: So there was a place that had, like, a middling line, like a five-minute line, so I'm like, "Aha, the place with this line.
Scott: This place must be better," which is, of course, what everyone else was thinking.
Scott: I was like, "Well, the line could just be longer because it had a momentum to it, and people think the same thing as me and got in the line because it had a
Scott: line.".
Rym: Could, but did they put that much thought into it?
Scott: Well, it doesn't matter, right?
Scott: So the place is called 17th Street Barbecue, right?
Scott: And they had baby vac ribs.
Scott: I think it was also because it had ribs.
Scott: A lot of the other places had things like pork shoulder or, you know, stuff like that, which would obviously be less popular than, I think, only one or two places had baby vac ribs, right?
Scott: So I got in that line, I waited five minutes, I paid eight bucks, I got some ribs and two scoops of beans, right?
Scott: So the ribs, they're pretty good.
Scott: It wasn't like, "Oh my God, the best ribs in the universe," like they were at, say, Soul Food Night, but they're pretty good.
Scott: But the beans, oh my God.
Scott: The best beans ever.
Scott: Those beans.
Rym: Notice how it's the same thing.
Rym: Like, we go to fancy steakhouses, and the steaks are always really good.
Scott: The mashed potatoes.
Rym: Yeah, it's rare for the steak to be, like, exceptional to a surprising degree, but somehow, the mashed potatoes at the Capitol Grill are way better than any mashed potatoes I have anywhere else.
Scott: Dude, I made a mashed potato.
Scott: I bought the heavy cream.
Scott: I added the, but it didn't matter.
Rym: I could not.
Rym: Heavy cream is good, but creme fraiche.
Scott: I didn't have a creme fraiche.
Rym: You should get some creme fraiche.
Scott: I'm gonna have to double it up next time.
Scott: But anyway, I went to another place that was, you know, had St.
Scott: Louis ribs and this sort of salad blob as the side dish, right?
Scott: And the, actually, I think I like, you know, the St.
Scott: Louis ribs, I think, were the same quality level as the baby back ribs, like pretty, you know, pretty good.
Scott: Not the best ever, but pretty damn good.
Scott: But I think I personally prefer St.
Scott: Louis style in general.
Rym: Ah, I was about to say I prefer the opposite.
Scott: But then, and the salad mush looked very unappetizing, like it looked like a blob of coleslaw.
Scott: But actually, it was very good.
Scott: I was like, oh.
Rym: See, I think your condition, too many years ago into diners where they give you coleslaw that you don't want.
Scott: Yeah, this wasn't coleslaw, though.
Scott: This was actually a salad that happened to be in a blob.
Scott: That happened to be cabbage, but it wasn't, there was no mayonnaise in sight.
Rym: Wait, so it happened to be a blob of shredded cabbage?
Scott: Yeah, there was also onions and peppers and other things in there.
Scott: And it had a dressing that was, you just couldn't see because it was clear mostly.
Scott: But it wasn't vinegar based, at least not that I could tell.
Scott: And it was, there was no mayonnaise at all.
Scott: And it tasted really good.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: And then there was this place in the way back that had this gigantic line.
Scott: It was the only place with a monstrous line, like a line that went all the way down the block.
Scott: And I was like, oh my gosh.
Scott: No, the beer was actually in the middle of the park.
Scott: And there were guards at every entrance to the circle in the park, so you couldn't leave that circle with beer.
Scott: You had to stay in there if you were drinking.
Scott: Because, you know, no drinking in the park.
Scott: But the place with the crazy long line, I was like, whoa, what the fuck is going on with this crazy long line?
Scott: I just ignored it.
Scott: I went to get a fried pie.
Scott: And there was a big line for the fried pie, but I get pretty close to the front.
Scott: And basically it seems like they can't make the fried pies as fast as people buy them.
Rym: So did they already have pie made and they were simply frying it?
Rym: Or were they making pies and then frying them?
Scott: No, it was, fried pie is this particular thing.
Scott: It's sort of like...
Rym: Plus a deep fryer.
Scott: No, it's sort of like, imagine if you had some sort of friedness that was halfway between funnel cake and pie crust.
Scott: And it was sort of in the shape of like, you know, a calzone, but flat, right?
Scott: So it was like a half circle, flat, fried stuff filled with fruit, right?
Scott: So it was sort of like a justice fruit pie, only hot and fried.
Scott: So they had all these different flavors.
Scott: And I noticed that, you know, people were basically waiting for pies to come out.
Scott: And people were ordering like apple and blackberry and whatever, right?
Scott: And I see some pies just sitting there and they're not being taken.
Scott: And I go up and I'm like, uh, apricot.
Scott: The guy just gives me one.
Scott: I'm like, hell, that's right.
Rym: What if people not know what apricot is?
Scott: People just didn't want...
Rym: Or apricot.
Scott: People were stupid.
Scott: They didn't order the apricot.
Rym: I think a lot of people don't know that they like apricot.
Scott: So I got the apricot and it was pretty good fried pie.
Scott: It was only four dollars.
Scott: So actually, I think the strategy for the barbecue thing is you... They have this fast pass thing, which is like, if you pay a zillion dollars and you order... They sell out of them really quickly.
Scott: So you need to get it in advance.
Scott: They actually... Every booth has registers on both sides.
Scott: So you can go to the registers on the back side if you have the fast pass.
Scott: You don't have to wait in any lines.
Scott: But I think you still have to pay.
Scott: Which is like, what?
Rym: Of course.
Scott: And who could eat that much barbecue?
Rym: Have you seen people?
Scott: Actually, the people with the fast passes.
Scott: I didn't see that many fat people.
Rym: It was early.
Scott: I think the strategy is you could do lunch dinner Saturday, lunch dinner Sunday.
Scott: And you can eat two meals at each one for sixteen bucks each.
Scott: And that can give you a maximum of eight barbecues with a reasonable stomach size.
Scott: I only ate the two and then I left.
Rym: So non-food related.
Rym: You know, Wildwood on the shore.
Rym: Our biggest thing at the shore, other than the beach, is always the arcades on the boardwalk.
Scott: Which decrease in quality drastically every single year.
Rym: For the last decade, every year, I've gone to Wildwood.
Rym: And Wildwood always had better arcades than any arcade I see anywhere else.
Rym: Sadly, it still has better arcades than I see in most places.
Scott: But there's still shit.
Scott: 99% cranes.
Rym: No, well, some arcades came and went.
Scott: Not as good as Fun Spot.
Rym: Fun Spot kind of sucked.
Scott: Compared to Wildwood?
Rym: Most of the games didn't work and I had a lot of trouble at Fun Spot.
Rym: I was not impressed.
Rym: I was much more impressed with other places I've been than Fun Spot.
Scott: And what place at Wildwood is even close?
Rym: Well, it just so happens that this year, you know, we were checking out all the arcades.
Rym: The one great arcade that used to have all those DDR machines in a row.
Rym: It's still that closed, busted ass haunted house now.
Rym: It's so sad.
Scott: What about my favorite underground, Ruhokuten?
Scott: no Ken used to be?
Rym: So, so, so.
Rym: Before I get to that, we go to where the one... Where's the good game last year?
Rym: What was the big game, the best game on the boardwalk?
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: Tanks, tanks, tanks?
Scott: I didn't play that that much.
Rym: You didn't play tanks?
Rym: That was like the best game.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So, tanks, tanks, tanks.
Rym: The only good new game was gone.
Rym: I don't know if it broke or what, but pretty much cranes everywhere.
Rym: Every arcade is just a disaster.
Rym: There's nothing left.
Scott: At least Fun Spot does have real games.
Rym: We're walking down into that underground mall and Scojo and I stop at the threshold because we see everything's missing.
Rym: It looks like it's just empty down there.
Scott: Really?
Scott: My favorite underground mall was ruined?
Rym: Well, it was ruined years ago when the Hokutona Ken machine stopped working.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: So we see it's empty and we hear carnival music.
Rym: and I see like in the far corner, it looks like they've set up like carny games with carnies like along the wall.
Rym: And there's carnival music.
Rym: We're like, "What?
Rym: What?
Rym: No, no,
Rym: no.".
Rym: And then I walk the rest of the way down and I see classic pinball.
Rym: And I see electro-mechanical games from the 40s and 50s.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Rym: Lined up all the fuck over the place.
Rym: And there's this dude standing.
Rym: There's a fence.
Rym: Like, I can't get to the games, but I can see them and they are glorious.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Somebody put it in the exact right spot.
Scott: My favorite spot.
Rym: So it's almost all classic pinball.
Rym: 40s, 50s, 60s.
Rym: Some of them are made out of all wood.
Rym: Some of them are almost entirely mechanical.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: It was pretty goddamn awesome.
Scott: So where did they come from?
Rym: So there's this guy.
Rym: It's this "remember when" entertainment or something.
Scott: Did you talk to him?
Rym: Uh, yeah, I talked to him.
Rym: And we'll probably have him on the show soon.
Rym: I don't know how much I can really reveal, but remember in Wildwood, whenever we'd go to eat at that Mexican place or go to the bookstore, there was that old Woolworths building.
Rym: And it was full of like just weird old 50s boardwalk stuff and buster.
Rym: The same guy owns that.
Scott: Oh.
Rym: And that was pegged to be a classic arcade museum.
Rym: And the permits are done.
Rym: Everything's all set.
Rym: The city council in fucking Wildwood doesn't want it to open.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Because they believe that having an arcade of any kind on that street will draw an undesirable element.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: An undesirable element to play old-timey pinball?
Scott: What, 40 and 50-year-old guys?
Rym: Now, somehow, the museum for classic games will draw an unhealthy, you know, quote, "undesirable audience,".
Rym: yet the bar next door that has $1.50 shots is fine?
Scott: Maybe, maybe that's the thing, right?
Scott: Maybe, you know, they say "undesirable element," right?
Rym: And we think that they mean, you know, being young kids-- No, they mean smart, rich people who won't go to crappy bars and buy $1.50 shots.
Scott: Exactly, right?
Scott: We think when old people say "undesirable element," that they mean punk kids who are going to cause trouble.
Scott: But the reality is, no, they want drunken college kids.
Scott: That's who they're looking for.
Scott: "Undesirable element" is reasonable, quiet people who are only going to spend a little bit of money putting quarters in the pinball machines.
Rym: Talking to the guy, though, it sounded like the people who are opposing it are just old and dumb enough to where they just equate arcades and pinball and all these things with the fights.
Scott: But not really lewd t-shirts and also with all the other nasty shit in the bottom.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: What are they thinking?
Rym: So there's this whole drama thing, but the dude, too, he was really cool.
Rym: We were talking to him, and the way he runs it is you pay five bucks a half hour and just all you can play.
Scott: Oh, my God, I give him $30.
Rym: We were there a while, all of us.
Rym: We just got in a line.
Rym: Me and Emily, we'd both play a game.
Scott: How does he time you?
Rym: He just does the honors system.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: I'm sure he might kick you out.
Rym: He gave us a bunch of extra time because he was cool and we were cool.
Scott: I just give him 20 bucks and play until I didn't feel like playing anymore and then give him 20 bucks every time.
Rym: The cool thing is a lot of these games are old enough to where they had multiplayer built in.
Scott: You take turns ball for ball.
Scott: Almost every pinball machine I've ever seen, almost all of them have built in multiplayer.
Rym: Most of the ones I've seen that had it would always be one guy plays, then the other guy plays.
Rym: This was alternating ball.
Scott: Yeah, alternating ball, yeah.
Rym: I haven't seen that on most modern pinball games I've played.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: The thing is, the problem is the modern ones do have it, but you can't really, because the old ones, for example, would have four different score spinners.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And then it would light up whose turn it was.
Scott: The modern ones are digital, so it's not as obvious.
Scott: The user interface doesn't let you really-- Yeah, you know what?
Rym: Having played a whole bunch of old-school pinball recently so it's fresh in my mind, fuck most modern pinball machines.
Rym: They kind of suck.
Scott: Well, you know, it's-- I played some great goddamn pinball.
Scott: I'm a fan-- The thing is the earliest of early pinballs, right?
Scott: A lot of them are too simplistic to actually be kind of interesting.
Scott: I like the ones that are sort of from the later mechanical era and then, of course, the early digital era, right?
Rym: Well, a lot of these had something-- you could see the different eras of pinball.
Rym: For a while, it was all the Gottfried whatever, the little flippers.
Rym: And then a lot of them had gimmicks, like the flippers will move on you, like they'll slide in or pull out.
Rym: And then you suddenly see a point where everybody has the big flippers instead of the little ones.
Rym: And then suddenly, oh, now all the pinball machines have the upper and the lower flippers.
Rym: And some of them, there were weird gimmicks that I'd never seen before.
Rym: The one, there were like spinners all over.
Scott: The cyclone?
Rym: It wasn't the cyclone.
Rym: It was way older than that.
Rym: Right.
Rym: But it had all these flat spinners that would like catch the ball and kind of like-- it would move it around.
Scott: Sometimes the ball would get stuck.
Rym: Like spin it around in the middle.
Rym: But in the middle of all that, there was this thing of balls.
Rym: And it would always tell you, like, knock all the balls into the left, knock all the balls into the right.
Rym: And you had to physically knock them.
Rym: And it was a really kind of neat mechanism as to how it worked.
Rym: So we'd play a lot of multiplayer.
Rym: And the one, like, big one, I did really well at this one pinball machine.
Scott: Actually, what you want to do is if you have two people, you play two machines multiplayer at the same time.
Rym: That's what we were trying to do.
Scott: You trade off.
Scott: The thing is, if one person dies right away, now what do they do?
Rym: I did really well.
Rym: Like, I wrecked it.
Rym: I thought I was doing awesome.
Rym: So I'm like, "Skull Joe, beat that fucking
Rym: score.".
Rym: He sits there and proceeds to roll the machine over.
Rym: I'm not super great at pinball.
Rym: So the dude, right?
Scott: It's hard to tell, right, when it comes to something, right?
Scott: It's like, if you're playing something like Counter-Strike, you know if you're doing well because you're at the top of this chart.
Scott: that's being made right then and there.
Scott: But if you're playing something like pinball, and the machine might have a built-in high score, but you don't know where that high score is from.
Scott: You don't really know what is a good score.
Rym: That's why single-player pinball, you really just have to keep playing the same machine and try to beat your previous score.
Scott: There's no way to gauge what is a good score.
Scott: Which is boring to me.
Rym: That's why I really like just how well integrated the multiplayer was in these old games.
Rym: Because they were literally like, "All right, direct competition for friends, go for
Rym: it."
Rym: And finally they all had notices on them that were like, "This is a game of
Rym: skill.".
Rym: Because remember all the old laws trying to outlaw pinball, saying it was the game of chance, no wagering.
Rym: So we talked to the guy and he's super cool.
Rym: And you didn't say I couldn't say this, so I'm just going to say it.
Rym: He had a whole bunch of video equipment all set up all over the place.
Rym: And we're like, "Hey, what's going on with
Rym: that?".
Rym: So he's going to be featured on that A&E show, Hoarders.
Rym: Which didn't really make sense to me because he, one, was articulate and cool, wasn't crazy.
Rym: Two, his machines are actually valuable.
Rym: He's not like an old lady keeping, I don't know, jars of poop.
Scott: Yeah, but who knows what other things he hoards, right?
Scott: No, just this.
Rym: Just old boardwalk stuff and pinball machines.
Rym: And he keeps all the machines in excellent condition and that collection is probably worth a fortune.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is, you think it's worth a fortune, but actually, you know, it's not that it's cheap, right?
Rym: Well, worth a fortune relative to the things that people tend to hoard.
Scott: Yeah, that's for sure.
Rym: I mean, a lady who's hoarding like Kewpie dolls, those are not worth so much.
Scott: No shit, really.
Rym: So the guy is totally cool and chill and I'm actually kind of curious to see how they portray him on Hoarders.
Rym: Because you know how TV shows are like that, where I really want to see...
Scott: Actually, I don't know what show this is, but I get everything I'm thinking about.
Scott: the show is based solely on the name.
Rym: You know, as much as I'm disconnected from pop culture, you never cease to amaze me sometimes.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So this place was pretty goddamn badass and that was my weekend.
Scott: Well, you had to go check that out.
Rym: The boardwalk was so disappointing, every other aspect other than, you know, food was the same.
Scott: But that one thing is enough to revive the whole thing.
Rym: Yeah, but it was such a rollercoaster of emotion as I'm walking down the boardwalk and everything sucked, everything sucked, everything sucked.
Scott: I'm telling you, there's something about that underground mall, it's like a magical secret mall.
Rym: And that's why the final moment I get down there and for a second, I thought it was gone.
Scott: I swear to God, you know what's in the back room is the wizard machine from Big.
Scott: I swear to God.
Rym: So, it's Tuesday.
Rym: Talk about some news.
Rym: I mean, E3 happened.
Scott: There's a billion gaming newses that we don't have time to talk about.
Scott: all of them.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So, do you have any non-E3 news before?
Rym: I talk about the only E3 news that I want to talk about right now?
Scott: Yeah, 'cause you know what?
Scott: 'Cause it's actually been a while since E3.
Scott: I sort of forget most of the newses except, you know, the gigantic ones.
Scott: There's just so many game announcements and it's like, well, you know, we'll talk about those games when they come out, I guess, if we care about them.
Scott: But there was a big news that has nothing to do with video games.
Scott: It has to do everything with role-playing games.
Scott: Announced as of, I guess, today?
Rym: Oh, right.
Rym: I guess that was actually officially announced.
Scott: Yeah, yesterday-ish, right?
Scott: Burning Wheel Gold.
Scott: It will be out sometime, I guess, July-ish?
Rym: Time to burn all my revised books.
Scott: Right, so basically, what is Burning Wheel Gold?
Scott: Well, whether you know or you don't know, there was Burning Wheel Classic, then Burning Wheel Revised, which is what we've been playing, and now there's Burning Wheel Gold.
Scott: It basically is a new version of Burning Wheel.
Rym: From the way it was described to me, it primarily tightens up and adds consistency to the rules.
Scott: Everything that I've read about what the improvements are, it is better.
Scott: At least, you know, in my opinion.
Rym: I think Luke said something like it was removing a lot of the sort of weird or specific exceptions that, while they might have been cool mechanically, really just added confusion and didn't actually help the game out that much.
Scott: Well, for example, right now, with Fight, right?
Scott: So Fight has been streamlined a great deal.
Scott: So one thing in Fight that was always sort of tricky was the positioning, right?
Scott: Do you close, do you steal, you know, retreat, or whatever?
Rym: Steal, retreat, and all that is range and cover.
Scott: Right, that's right.
Rym: You haven't really played much Fight, have you?
Scott: No, because I was a void Fight because it was complicated.
Scott: It's not that complicated!
Scott: But you know what, now Fight's even easier.
Scott: First of all, range and cover was changed, but Fight is also changed, right?
Scott: And you know what they did in Fight?
Scott: The positioning is just, you position.
Scott: And if, you know, let's say I've got long range and you've got a dagger, right?
Scott: And I've got a spear, and we position.
Scott: If I win, you're far away from me, and if you win, you're really close.
Scott: And that's pretty much all it comes down to.
Scott: It's just, whoever, if you win the positioning, you're at your best advantage and your opponent's at the worst advantage, and vice versa.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: What if you want to be at a disadvantage or something?
Scott: I'm sure you can do that if you want to.
Scott: I'm just curious, because it's one thing where-- What do you do if you want to fail a roll in Burning Wheel?
Rym: I'll just say that I honestly don't feel like the positioning was the complicated part of Fight.
Scott: No, it wasn't that it was complicated, right?
Scott: It's that you want to get to the good stuff and make it faster, right?
Scott: So it's like, you spend all this time positioning, and then roll the roll that really matters, the strike.
Scott: So this way, it's like you just get to the rolls that matter more quickly.
Scott: Actually, I never bothered with Strike.
Rym: I'd always be like Counter-Strike, Faint, or something.
Scott: And the other thing is, for Fight, you know how?
Scott: for Duel of Wits, there's the chart that says, "This does this when meeting up with this"?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Now there's that chart for Fight.
Scott: It's actually two pages.
Rym: I had a chart like that for Fight already.
Scott: Yeah, but now there's-- It's probably better.
Scott: It even has the weird things, like, "What if I Strike and he Sorceries?
Scott: What do you
Scott: do?".
Scott: You know, it has all that.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, Burning Wheel Gold, it combines the Burning Wheel and the Character Burner in one handy book.
Scott: The book has been much more streamlined, and the book itself is more useful.
Scott: The rules have been updated.
Scott: It's gonna be $25, I think.
Scott: The pre-orders are gonna go up, and I think he's got a plan to do, like, 50 pre-orders a day for five days or something along those lines.
Scott: You can get it even if you fail to pre-order, right?
Scott: You just won't get it immediately.
Rym: So, do you guys want us to get Luke on the show to talk about it?
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: 'Cause I feel like we could do a whole--.
Rym: We could put it up as an extra episode outside of the stream of GeekNights so we don't interrupt.
Scott: The other important thing, right, is that, you know, in Burning Wheel, the most important pages in the whole book are the first 75 pages.
Scott: That's really the hub and the spokes, 'cause that's all you really need to play.
Scott: You can play with that, right?
Scott: The rest is all the advanced rules, and also making characters, which is a lot.
Scott: It's gonna be hundreds and hundreds of pages, probably like 500 pages you're missing.
Scott: If you only get the--.
Scott: But that first part, the part that you can play with, is free PDF.
Scott: You can get it right now.
Scott: Finally, Luke.
Scott: Finally.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you should sell the whole book as PDF, but, I mean, first part of the book, enough to play the sword with the sword characters included for, you know, free, that's pretty damn good.
Rym: I'd go one step further if I were him.
Rym: I would take the old Burning Wheel, the revised one, and sell, like, a $1 PDF of the whole thing.
Scott: Well, I think he just-- He wants to make it go away completely.
Rym: Ah, he can't make it go away.
Scott: I don't understand why he always wants to, like, you know, hide these old things.
Scott: I'll never get it.
Scott: But I've given up trying to convince him because he'll never change his mind.
Rym: Does a cat not try to bury its poop?
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, you know, Michael Jackson doesn't stop selling Thriller.
Rym: Does a pyro not try to bury his poop?
Rym: The point is, right-- That was a joke from a long time ago.
Scott: You know, if you make a whole bunch of music, it's not like you don't sell the oldest album.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: I'll put it this way.
Rym: You guys can go onto our website and listen to GeekNights from October of 2005.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It kind of sucks.
Scott: It's awful.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: It's online.
Scott: It's gonna be there forever.
Scott: As long as I can keep it there.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So, you know, if I was him, you know, I would just make everything 100% free PDF and sell the books anyway.
Rym: That's all I would-- No, I'd sell the PDF for a few bucks.
Scott: I would sell the PDF also, but I would also make the PDF free.
Rym: Wait, so I'd sell the PDF and have the PDF for free?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: No.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Why bother?
Rym: The people who want it for free are gonna pirate it anyway, so I might as well just say, "Hey, five
Rym: bucks.".
Scott: No, because there are some people who will, you know, who will pay, even though-- Yeah, but I think you'd-- It's basically the equivalent of a donation box.
Rym: Yeah, but I think you'd make more money.
Rym: It's effectively a donation box if you sell it for five bucks, 'cause it's just a PDF.
Scott: No, I don't think so.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: It's the exact--.
Rym: There's the exact same mechanism design.
Rym: The only difference is the moral incentive.
Scott: You don't put the free PDF and the paid PDF in the same location.
Scott: That's the trick.
Scott: You don't put 'em right next to each other.
Rym: That's the Nessus strategy, and I think that's kind of a BS strategy.
Scott: But it works.
Rym: I think you should just sell a PDF of all the old Burning Wheel shit for, like, a dollar.
Scott: I'd do that too.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So, we'll see.
Rym: It's funny how we just started a Burning Wheel campaign.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: when we started it, I was like, "Let's ignore the new book.
Scott: Let's just play with these old
Scott: ones.".
Rym: I kinda still wanna ignore the new book, just because I wanna play a campaign with a small number of characters, for real, with the old system.
Scott: Yeah, we have our whole lives to do that.
Scott: It's not like he's setting our old books on fire.
Rym: I'll bet he would if he could.
Scott: He would if he could, but he can't.
Rym: He realized we're gonna wake up and he's gonna be in our apartment with, like, a lighter.
Scott: I think he's sort of resigned himself to that, but he's definitely not making more of the old ones.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So, remember a day a long time ago when, you know, flush off the success of the GameCube and, you know, Nintendo was still very high up on the Rym-and-scot scale of things that are awesome.
Rym: Nintendo was up there doing cool stuff 'cause they hadn't quite really given up on us kinda gamers yet.
Rym: And as far as we could see, the GameCube and the GBA link and all that was like, "Alright, they tried this.
Rym: It didn't go that well, but clearly there's potential here.
Rym: The Wii will make every dream come
Rym: true.".
Rym: Remember when the Wii was called the Revolution 'cause it was gonna revolutionize gaming and whatever?
Scott: Yeah, I believed in it at that time.
Rym: Remember when they had the press release?
Rym: They're like, "Yeah, it's called the
Rym: Wii.".
Rym: And everyone made fun of it for, like, a week, and then now it's just the Wii.
Scott: I waited in line to buy it.
Scott: Yeah, you did.
Scott: The first day.
Rym: And I remember sitting at home playing that WarioWare game, trying to like it, really wanting to like it, and then looking online 'cause I couldn't find the multiplayer only to discover that there was no multiplayer.
Scott: Though there was really awful non-multiplayer.
Rym: There effectively wasn't multiplayer.
Scott: There wasn't any simultaneous multiplayer.
Rym: Which was the only reason to ever play WarioWare.
Rym: So, we're older now, wiser, more mature, more experienced under our belts.
Rym: Carousel's coming up in like seven months for us.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And Nintendo has announced the Wii U.
Scott: Wii U. Wii U. Alright, there's enough Wii U jokes.
Scott: We're not gonna...
Rym: I can't even make fun of it.
Rym: It's, the funny thing is, what did we always complain about with the Wii?
Rym: That they didn't use the cool concepts they had of the shared spaces and the private spaces.
Rym: The GBA connected to the GameCube.
Rym: They didn't do that with the DS and the Wii.
Rym: They didn't use the primary potential of that console.
Rym: And we were fucked and we gave up on them.
Rym: Now suddenly, they're doing basically just that.
Scott: Well, you know what?
Scott: The thing is, they're actually not.
Rym: Well, I've learned a lot of things about this.
Rym: One, the new controller supposedly is not multitasking.
Rym: It's single touch.
Scott: I can't even imagine why.
Scott: It's the same as a DS screen.
Scott: So basically... Because Nintendo loves styluses.
Rym: That's why.
Rym: So basically, rather than using the Wii to its full potential and just having another five years of the Wii and having my DS or my DSi or my 3DS just connect to the Wii, which would be fine.
Rym: You could do everything that Nintendo had not done yet.
Rym: Fulfill all the potential.
Rym: Nintendo has never realized with that.
Rym: Instead, they're gonna sell me a console and then they're gonna sell me basically a crappy DS that only has one screen and really only works as a controller for my Wii U.
Scott: You wanna hear the worst thing ever?
Scott: Huh?
Scott: If you have a Wii U, right?
Scott: You can only have one of those controllers at a time.
Scott: What?
Rym: I didn't even know that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, Nintendo...
Scott: It's like, oh, so it's worthless.
Rym: So Nintendo...
Scott: The only good thing I have to say about it, right, is that you look at some of the other things that... Nintendo keeps adding new features and new elements with every console they release, right, whether it's handheld or for TV.
Rym: Well, simultaneously removing things.
Scott: Well, no, but the thing is, some of those things they add are used extensively.
Scott: This is why the DS was such a great success because every DS game used both screens.
Scott: Every DS game used stylus and touch in some way, right?
Scott: Those are the things they added to the DS and pretty much every DS game used them and almost every DS game used the wireless in some way.
Rym: Ah, but to make a counterpoint, the majority of games, especially early on, technically used the microphone and the stylus, but really...
Scott: Well, microphone was a fail.
Rym: It was hacked on bullshit.
Rym: Even the early Castlevania games.
Rym: Oh, the stylus was just added on bullshit that didn't even matter to the game.
Rym: Like, oh, touch the blue blocks to make it disappear.
Scott: But at least two screens was used in almost every single game.
Rym: Even though a lot of games just put a status screen up there and left it at that.
Scott: Right, but how about Phoenix Wright DS stylus?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Totally, totally good.
Scott: But anyway, those things actually got used.
Scott: is the point, right?
Scott: But on Wii, the motion stuff only really got used in Wii Sports and Wii Sports Plus.
Scott: No, it was used... Or Wii Sports Resort.
Rym: If you look at the average DS game, you know, take out the outliers.
Rym: So take out the absolute shovelware, like the bottom, and take out the great first party games.
Rym: The average middle of the road game, most of them, I would argue, use the stylus or the touch screen in a minimal gimmicky bullshit way and that was the end of it.
Scott: They definitely used the two screens though.
Rym: The Wii was the same way.
Rym: The waggle was used really well by a small number of games and was just an extra button that was kind of awkward to use for most games.
Scott: Right, but the point about the Wii U, right, is that the extra screen, the feature of screen in the controller, regardless of any other features they've got, that feature can be used very easily with pretty much every single game.
Scott: The same way that the two screens of the DS can be used in every single game.
Scott: So that's their problem, is they add these features that have potential, but developers or someone doesn't know how to use it or isn't created enough or it's too much effort, but that screen in the controller will be used with every single game in some sort of minimally effective way.
Scott: At very least, it'll be like an inventory screen or something.
Rym: So I have two things to say to that.
Rym: One, I realize now why that never happened.
Rym: Everyone who had actual cool ideas for how to use the weird things Nintendo added to their consoles were indie developers that Nintendo basically won't even talk to.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And locks out as much as they can.
Rym: And two, talking about the screen.
Rym: We don't need it.
Rym: The fact that the screen can only be on one of the controllers makes it less, it's not even a thing.
Scott: I know.
Scott: It's nothing.
Scott: Why don't they just let everyone use 3DSs?
Scott: because supposedly the Wii has the capability to connect 8DS lights simultaneously.
Scott: That's what I've heard.
Scott: But not once has anyone made a game that actually uses that feature.
Scott: The only time I've ever seen the DS connect to the Wii is if you get the Nintendo channel on the Wii, you can download demos to your DS over the Wi-Fi.
Scott: I've never seen anyone else use the DS Wii connection any other way than that.
Scott: Imagine the potential.
Scott: Even though it's theoretically possible.
Scott: Eight swords.
Rym: Just make fucking eight swords.
Scott: I don't know why they just don't do these obvious things like eight swords.
Scott: Even four swords two is enough for me.
Rym: Crystal Chronicles that's actually like the original and not those crappy remakes.
Scott: So on DSiWare, they put out for free the four swords.
Scott: But it's GBA four swords.
Scott: It's like, where's the GameCube four swords?
Rym: Hello?
Rym: It goes back to the fact that Nintendo recently has been very bad at understanding what it is that makes something popular.
Rym: I mean, look at that WarioWare game.
Rym: They're like, alright.
Rym: Clearly people loved WarioWare for the GameCube.
Rym: Clearly this was a fantastic game.
Rym: And clearly what they liked was the single player playing of the micro games.
Rym: They probably didn't care about that multiplayer.
Scott: Maybe the Japanese people like that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, we've said the same thing about Nintendo.
Scott: The Wii U is really just more of the same from them.
Scott: It hasn't changed anything.
Scott: We'll find out when it comes out for sure.
Scott: But the 3DS is definitely carrying the torch there.
Rym: I just have so little faith in this.
Rym: And it's funny because...
Scott: And the thing is, some of the games they announced I'm kind of interested in.
Scott: I wouldn't mind playing Luigi's Mansion 2 on 3DS.
Scott: But not for the amount of money it costs.
Scott: It's like a $10 game, not a $50 game.
Scott: But the price isn't going to drop forever.
Rym: Go back and listen to GeekNights when the Wii was coming out.
Rym: And we talked a lot about the potential.
Rym: Yeah, we'll get it.
Rym: Because they'll do cool stuff with this.
Rym: They're going to do the cool stuff like they tried with the GameCube on the Wii.
Rym: They're going to push the boundaries.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: They didn't do it.
Rym: I have no faith that Nintendo is going to do anything interesting with this console whatsoever.
Scott: It's like on the GameCube.
Scott: they were really trying with the software.
Scott: Pac-Man verse, right?
Scott: But then they just gave up on it.
Rym: Well, they were very sad during that time.
Rym: Because they learned that nobody actually wanted those good games.
Rym: Or they thought nobody wanted it.
Rym: Or they thought nobody was actually going to make those games.
Scott: But then they locked out all the people who would have made those games.
Scott: They're people.
Scott: They don't talk to anyone.
Scott: And you can't talk to them.
Scott: That's the other thing that the big companies get wrong.
Scott: Microsoft actually talks to people.
Rym: Yeah, Microsoft's community management is, bar none, the best of the three consoles.
Scott: They just don't talk to people.
Scott: They don't ask us what we want.
Scott: They're just Japanese people.
Scott: Apple doesn't need to ask people what they want.
Scott: They tell people what they want.
Scott: But Nintendo doesn't have that skill.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But the one thing that definitely has changed on our side is that we're not in college.
Scott: I feel like if I was in college, that the Nintendo stuff would still be...
Rym: I think that.
Rym: But then I look at what would we have played if we were today, if we were still in college, we could just get four people and sit down from the Wii.
Rym: We'd be playing Smash Brothers or the new Mario.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And nothing else.
Rym: Maybe the sports games.
Scott: They're coming out with Mario Party 9.
Scott: Eh.
Scott: There's Mario Sports Mix.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: There's quite a few games that are on the Wii that are the sort of simultaneous everyone-in-the-room games that you could play if you have a whole bunch of people that we can't really play because we don't have that kind of environment anymore.
Rym: We could.
Rym: We could get those people if we wanted to.
Rym: We just don't.
Scott: Plus, it does look like the Wii U, while you're only going to have one of the Wii U controllers at a time, there are still going to be some games along the lines of Pac-Man first where you only need one and the other three people will use Wiimotes or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, now how many of those games will actually be as good as Pac-Man first, which was to this day one of the best games ever released on the GameCube?
Scott: Maybe one.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's exactly what's going to happen.
Rym: I cannot express to you how little faith I have in this console.
Rym: So, we had a lot to talk about, so it took us a while to get to this, but we ran into a problem.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Probably like our senior year of RIT.
Scott: Well, a lot of it.
Scott: This problem has existed for quite a long time, well before we encountered it.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: We knew about it.
Rym: We call it in panels, for those of you who never get to see us live at conventions, the air hockey conundrum, because air hockey is perhaps the best example of this.
Scott: No, fighting games are the best example of this.
Rym: I think air hockey is a more universal, I think more people have the air hockey problem than the fighting game problem.
Scott: I think more people understand the fighting, gamers know the fighting game problem.
Rym: They're both the same.
Scott: Anyway, let's discuss the problem.
Rym: Alright, so for us specifically, this is kind of like a very personal show, we did not know about Euro games and hardcore board games and game theory and any of that until we got to RIT.
Rym: I mean, at RIT, as freshmen, one day some guy was like, "Hey, you want to play
Rym: Settlers?".
Rym: And I'm like, "What the fuck is
Scott: And I sat down.
Scott: For me, it was like people all around at RWAG talked about playing Settlers, and I just never played it because I was always playing RPGs instead, and then eventually everyone kept talking about the Settlers and playing the Settlers.
Rym: Yup, because they invited me to play once and I sat down.
Scott: One day I finally played the Settlers.
Rym: There's all these hexes and cubes and I played it and it was like this revelation.
Rym: I remember after the game was done, I was like, "That was the best game I've ever played.
Scott: Fuck
Scott: Monopoly.".
Rym: And it really set us off.
Rym: And for a long time, we were kind of in this perfect storm of gaming because our whole front row crew got into Euro gaming at the same time.
Rym: So we all progressed together.
Rym: I remember El Grande was one of the first games we got on our own.
Rym: I bought that shit when I couldn't even afford food.
Rym: I spent like 45 bucks on it.
Rym: Yeah, at RIT.
Rym: That was the first German board game I ever bought.
Scott: I don't know why you did it when you couldn't afford food.
Rym: Because I got more enjoyment out of El Grande than I did out of food.
Scott: Than steak on French bread?
Rym: Steak on French bread was like five bucks.
Scott: You could have gotten nine steak on French breads instead of one El Grande.
Rym: So we progressed and we played with our crew and with other people at RWAG.
Rym: And we played online.
Rym: And we started studying the game.
Rym: At one point I remember sitting there when I was bored playing the game idly online against myself to try to figure out strategy.
Rym: We started reading facts and learning about tripodting versus brickwood or grain sheep.
Rym: We got really into it.
Rym: So fast forward a couple of years having played these games almost every goddamn day for years.
Scott: Yeah, the summer where we played Puerto Rico three times a day almost every day.
Rym: The summer after our sophomore year of RIT Scott and I and our friend Alex a crew member, we all lived in apartments right next to each other on campus over the summer where rent was half back then.
Rym: I don't think they even let people do that anymore.
Rym: So we lived on campus in our apartment.
Rym: We had like, I had a job technically.
Rym: I went to that sub shop.
Scott: I was taking classes at the time.
Scott: But there were very few of them.
Rym: We pretty much had infinite free time and we would sit down almost every day and play Puerto Rico and play Puerto Rico.
Rym: And one day we played it like ten times just in a row, just nonstop.
Scott: Yeah, I sort of regret it.
Scott: Like if I could go back and tell myself I'd be like, "Don't waste the time, make something you
Scott: asshole.".
Rym: No, but had we not done that we wouldn't understand game theory like we do now.
Scott: I know, right?
Scott: It's such a difficult thing.
Rym: That's why you can't go back and relive college because now I'm older and wiser and I wouldn't spend my time dicking around.
Scott: I wouldn't have wasted my time if I had the time to waste now.
Rym: But the time I wasted was the only reason I have such a good memory of that time.
Rym: The wasted time was the best time.
Scott: I know, wasted youth.
Rym: Better by far than a wise and productive old age.
Rym: So that summer it really happened.
Rym: We played that game to death.
Rym: And then the next year we started mostly playing board games with our own kind of tight-knit crew because all the other people in the gaming club really weren't that good at the games anymore compared to us.
Rym: They'd take forever to take their turns.
Rym: And it was like Kellas going out among the world-born.
Rym: They'd just craft.
Rym: And I'm like, "Okay, captain.
Rym: Thanks.".
Scott: I think people understand the fighting game problem more.
Scott: So you have a group of people you all love to play Street Fighter.
Scott: But one guy goes and practices and he actually becomes really good at Street Fighter.
Rym: Doesn't take much.
Scott: Meanwhile, so now basically nobody ever beats him and you can't even hit him.
Scott: I practiced a little bit and at the height of my practicing I was beating my friends who had never practiced at all with just jab.
Scott: Literally I could just jab and I would win.
Scott: And there's still some people I know that are as good and better than me.
Scott: There's plenty of them because I'm not good at all.
Scott: Wyatt is way better.
Scott: He still plays, I think, all the time.
Scott: But the point is I'm still better than a lot of people and there's no even point in playing against them because the skill gap is so wide.
Scott: If you're Michael Jordan are you gonna play basketball with your family?
Rym: I would.
Rym: It'd be like that John Hodgkin's thing.
Rym: The Hodgkins.
Scott: The thing we went to.
Scott: But it's like, okay, you might get some fun out of it in some fashion but it's not like.
Scott: this doesn't give you that competitive gaming thing.
Scott: You have to play in the NBA if you're Michael Jordan.
Rym: So you get into the situation where you are better than most of your friends or you and your small circle of friends are all super good but none of you can play with anyone else.
Rym: Because everyone else is either the tiny minority of uber elite players who either you're to them what everyone else is to you.
Scott: Yeah, like, oh man, I just own all my friends at Quake and then you go to the Quake world and you don't even get one frag.
Scott: It's like, oh, you're in this sort of no zone in the middle.
Scott: And you can try to play online, but even then.
Rym: Now board games in particular, and this is where it really affects us, are the top is not that accessible especially because not many of these games yet are easily played online.
Scott: A lot of them are playable online.
Scott: That's changing rapidly, though.
Scott: Even though many of them are playable online.
Scott: there's that Brett Spielwelt site that's been around for a long time, and I know Days of Wonder has places you can play online but the communities online are rather small, and playing online is not the same experience as playing at a table and pretty much all of them universally have shitty user interfaces and I consider them to basically be so worthless as to be, might as well not even exist.
Rym: So, we're gonna sound a little bit full of ourselves for the next few minutes because basically, we left RIT which was like this den of geekery.
Rym: We're having that problem, but only a little bit, because I remember later on, we started going to Richmond's more elite board gaming night, where everyone was actually super skilled.
Rym: Imagine there's a gaming club and then there's a separate much more hardcore gaming club.
Rym: Imagine if there was a fighting game club in your college, and then a subset of that club was the "we are all the best at Street Fighter" club, and you just joined that.
Rym: So, we leave college, we go our separate ways and we all come back together in the Mid-Hudson Valley and, you know, we wanted to play some games, it was just me and Scott.
Rym: for a while and other than when people came down on weekends we really couldn't play any games.
Rym: So, we join a local gaming group and those guys were nice, it was fun times, good god could none of them play games.
Scott: No, it's just like they didn't know how to take their turn quickly right, so you would sit there and basically a game that would have taken us 90 minutes.
Scott: tops took not only 45 minutes, half hour to teach, but then there would be players that would just take forever on their turn, literally.
Scott: So you'd be sitting there basically wasting hours and you can't just leave the game and dick everyone over because then you're a dick.
Rym: The thing is you're going to win anyway.
Rym: I mean, I don't think we ever lost a game to those guys.
Scott: No, but it's like one of us always won, there were two other skilled guys, but there was always unskilled guys who would take forever and even if they didn't take forever they were just so low skilled they would just get rolled.
Rym: Which would have been fine if they learned and tried or if they learned from their mistakes and got better as we played games again, but instead they would argue, like we were playing that Timbuktu game, which the first round, I remember.
Rym: I sat there and I looked at it and I did a little bit of math and I realized exactly what the game was and I played perfectly optimally from round one.
Rym: you figured out what the game was immediately after the first round and played optimally for the whole rest of the game.
Rym: and you know what?
Rym: I beat you by one point at the end of the game.
Scott: Yeah, because I played a round to figure it out rather than just observing and trying to do math I played the round to figure it out.
Rym: So basically all the crew people who were there were within a point of each other.
Scott: It was me, you, Alex, one, two, three.
Rym: We dominated the game and everyone else, it wasn't that they were bad and that they took forever on their turn but that was true, but I remember when I said after the first round "Oh, I think I solved it" and Scott was like "Yeah, I think you're right".
Rym: and Alex was like "Yeah, I got it".
Rym: and they tried to argue that "What do you mean you can't solve a game?
Rym: What are you talking
Rym: about?".
Rym: and we proceeded to argue and show them "Look, here's the math.
Rym: We could even just stop playing.
Rym: I can tell you how the whole rest of the game is going to go right
Rym: now.".
Rym: So, maybe an outlier I mean, maybe we're just in the land of no Street Fighter players.
Scott: Well, I don't think there's that many people who are that good at board games particularly but there's plenty of other kinds of games that we're not so good at.
Rym: No, no, but the thing is it's a self-selected sample, like the people who seek out a fighting game club.
Scott: Yeah, if we went to those weird board game championships in Pennsylvania, how would we do?
Scott: Well, I'm starting to believe perfectly honestly that we would do really god damn well Yeah, I have no idea and those things are kind of weird and I really want to go to them.
Rym: I always want to do the board game tournaments at PAX but they always take way too long.
Scott: Yeah, that's another thing, right?
Scott: I could go in a tournament, but those tournaments are open to everyone and you're going to have to play, what, two or three games of Puerto Rico, which with good players will be 90 minutes times three maybe three hours, three, four, five hours at most, probably at least three, four, five hours and you might get a slow player in round one six hours, seven hours.
Rym: it's like, dude, seven hours, I could have played two RPGs, dude I mean, I played in some Settlers tournaments and they were just really boring, and then once it got to all skilled players it was random, because Settlers were random.
Scott: The thing is, we're going on so many PAXes already.
Scott: I'm thinking of, like, well it's another PAX, presumably I'm going to be going to tens of PAXes in my life, right?
Scott: I don't think I have a problem spending a day of PAX just playing a whole bunch of RPGs.
Scott: I think for the next PAX West I'm going to pick a day, once I see the schedule, and also our personal schedule, and I'm going to make a day of RPG and schedule.
Rym: Well, there might be things in the works for PAX East related to that Maybe, we'll see.
Rym: So, basically we're running into this problem, where now we're?
Rym: in New York, and we figured, alright, New York will find some gamers, and we hang out a lot with the NerdNYC crew, and they're a great crew, they're really into games, they're really dedicated, they're great guys.
Rym: I love hanging out with them.
Scott: Even there, I just Yeah, I mean, there are hardcore peoples in that group who we can play with, there's quite a few of them.
Scott: I played a really good game of Kalis actually two board game nights ago.
Scott: I didn't go to the most recent one, but the one two, yeah, a few ago I played an awesome game of Kalis, people were really good and I won, by a lot Of course.
Scott: But, because you're just going to get into a game with whoever happens to be there you know, it's kind of random.
Scott: you might end up playing a game with people who are not so skilled, also because a lot of people there have different taste in games, and are looking for different things.
Scott: most of the time, I don't play serious games there, a lot of times I'll end up playing some kind of light-hearted game that isn't so serious, it doesn't take so long that isn't hard to learn
Rym: Like jungle speed, or spotted
Scott: Yeah, things like that, things that
Rym: are
Scott: quick to learn and quick to play, and it's like well, that's fun and all, but I really lately just have a hankering to play this for serious, long games.
Rym: What doesn't help is that the venue.
Rym: I love the venue, but it's really where these board games, it's kind of like this raucous coffeehouse bar,
Scott: it's very loud
Rym: it's loud, and it's dark which is kind of like the death
Scott: of
Rym: a game like Puerto Rico
Scott: and cramped, yeah, it's like you need to have big tables, with lots of space, where it's relatively quiet you know, like a packed stable top room.
Scott: so it's very hard you know, even when there are people about to get a serious game going on, and there's also NerdNYC also has recess.
Rym: Now this is where, I mean, I'm gonna keep going to the board game nights but I've changed my idiom.
Rym: when I go to the board game night, I'm never gonna go into it thinking, I'm gonna play Puerto Rico, I'm gonna go into it thinking I'm gonna have a grilled cheese and a beer play a couple of light games and then go home.
Rym: Really?
Scott: I'm gonna bring one serious game every time that I wanna play.
Scott: I'm not gonna rely on anyone else, right and I'm gonna say, I need X people for this game.
Scott: we're playing it.
Rym: Well, here's what you need to do.
Rym: we need to post ahead of time what that game is every week every time we go.
Rym: Oh yeah, do more 4, that's a good idea That's really, we gotta get more in the forum and we find the other people who are just as stupid and hardcore about the games as we are, and just play serious games with them.
Scott: Let's do it.
Scott: But yeah, but recess, so we tell you to go to recess quite often and recess is this Saturday?
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah And you should totally go to it.
Rym: I'm going to stop going though.
Scott: Well, I don't know if I'm gonna stop going all together.
Rym: Well, I'm going to go if I ever remember to sign up to run a game in town.
Scott: Yeah, but basically here's the thing with recess, right, is that you can go and you pay $20.
Scott: if you're running a game, you pay zero dollars.
Scott: And then there's two sessions before lunch and after lunch, they're each four hours.
Rym: Now this is the trouble, some of the sessions are board games, and I've never finished a board game in the four hours because people don't take their goddamn turn.
Scott: Yeah, uh, because you're not gonna.
Scott: you know, because of the four hour session you're not gonna pick some lighthearted game.
Scott: it's always gonna be a serious game but some serious games take even more than four hours, especially when you have to spend time to teach it cause there's.
Scott: no, you can't just deny people entry to your game because they don't know how to play, right?
Rym: Well, if you look at old gaming cons usually there would be two ratings on any gaming event.
Rym: The first rating would be how difficult is this game?
Rym: Like how complicated is it?
Rym: The second rating would be how much foreknowledge must you have to be allowed to join this game?
Scott: I've seen a lot of cons still have that, where they say how much foreknowledge do you need?
Scott: But you know what, I've never seen any event ever that didn't say all welcome.
Rym: I have in fact, I've played in games, I've played in a D&D tournament at that.
Rym: you had to bring characters already made that followed certain requirements and you had to bring all your own materials and they just started you playing D&D.
Scott: I don't know if anyone does things like that anymore.
Rym: I feel like people do.
Scott: I've never seen it at any gaming cons.
Rym: But basically the recesses as great as they are, I usually end up I'm not willing to stand in line for like an hour.
Scott: Basically they put all the games up on the wall and you have to sign up and it's first come first serve.
Scott: so you have to wait in a line.
Scott: you basically have to fight and be aggressive and annoying to get to the front of the line.
Rym: And there's always like one game I want to be in.
Rym: It's always like oh there's one paranoia game or one lacuna game and that fills up immediately.
Scott: Yeah, so unless you're at the front of the line, you're not going to get in the game that you want to get in.
Scott: And then what do you do?
Scott: You're going to, you know, you spent 20 bucks so you're going to wait, are you going to sign up for a game that wasn't your, that you're not really that excited about and hope that it's good because you can't just bail on it if it sucks because then you're a jerk to everyone else.
Scott: So you're basically committing to four hours of being trapped, possibly being trapped in a game you don't want to play.
Rym: My experience has pretty much been the last few recesses.
Rym: The first session, I'll fight and I'll do the BS and I'll get into something pretty good.
Rym: And then the second session, I'm usually stuck not playing anything.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And usually the thing is, that's four hour, four hours, two four hour sessions with an hour lunch in the middle.
Scott: That's nine hours.
Scott: With the people that are good, if I could get together Dude, we could play Puerto Rico more than ten times.
Scott: Right, if I could get together a group of myself, Rym, and three other awesome people, we could play Puerto Rico, Le Havre, Calistini, like five or six games in that time period that are all hardcore and awesome.
Rym: Or we could play like two solid indie RPG, like one-offs.
Scott: Yeah, so I mean like I might go to recess just because even though it's not a great, you know, for me at least, it's not a great time.
Rym: Well that's the important thing.
Scott: Recess is great.
Scott: For other people it's still great.
Scott: But it's great.
Scott: Especially people who can't get their RPG on.
Rym: Well that's it.
Rym: Recess and board game nights are great for two kinds of people.
Rym: One, the people who don't have a large enough local crew who's into their games, which is a big problem for a lot of people.
Scott: Right, it's like you really want to play an RPG but, you know, you can't make it to a convention and you don't have any people locally.
Scott: Well you can go to recess, sign up for an RPG four hours and play it.
Scott: And if you're so RPG deprived, even if you don't get into your top choice of the really popular RPG, you'll probably still be thrilled with whatever one you get into.
Rym: But two, it's good for people who don't have space to play.
Rym: Like even if you have friends, like a lot of the Nerd NYC people are friends with us and with each other and, you know, it's a social group.
Rym: So, it's New York.
Rym: A lot of people have tiny apartments.
Rym: If you need a space to play, things like this are great for that.
Rym: But we have spaces to play.
Rym: We're really just.
Rym: basically we had this revelation a few weeks ago that we have everything we need to run our own kind of bi-weekly, like, hardcore gaming night.
Scott: Yeah, we just need to get, the problem is even our close friends who are really into games, they don't commit and be, they're not reliable.
Scott: They don't show up every single, you know, it's like, let's play serious, you know.
Rym: No, yeah they do.
Rym: The problem there is much more simple.
Rym: We can't do stuff like that on weekends because if you have a big gathering on a weekend everybody can show up.
Rym: Which then, you know, alright, twelve people showed up not playing board games.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you try to play a serious game when all those people are there.
Scott: Well, it's like, oh, these people don't want to play a serious game.
Rym: Well, no, it's everyone's social eyes.
Rym: I mean, I'm in that boat.
Rym: If I got a big crew, I want to hang out.
Scott: Yeah, but I want to play a serious game.
Rym: That's why we're making a dedicated serious gaming night.
Scott: Yeah, we got to do, you know, space, look, we plan this time for serious gaming.
Scott: Because a lot of times we'll get together and some people want a serious game and some people don't and it just doesn't happen.
Scott: But if we say, look, this is going to be serious gaming.
Scott: Don't show up if you're not into it.
Scott: Then it'll happen.
Rym: Yep, so basically what we've come down to doing is shutting, you know, all our hardcore gaming.
Rym: I'm pretty much just going to get from the people I already know, at least for a while.
Rym: Because the best gaming experiences I've ever had are still, you know, my tight-knit group of super hardcore gamers playing super hardcore games until we've solved them.
Rym: And I haven't had that experience since I left college.
Scott: Yeah, and you know, I've just been sort of really hankering for it lately.
Scott: So I think, you know, I might go, I'm not, you know, this recess, it's sort of like we took advantage of the fact that recess was there.
Scott: Because like, well, look, everyone was planning on playing games this day anyway.
Scott: Let's just divert them to our place, you know, a select few.
Scott: Because it happens to be a time that was set aside.
Scott: But I think for future recesses, I'll actually go to them.
Rym: Well, I'm going to go and run stuff.
Rym: I'm just going to keep an eye out and actually...
Scott: Because, you know, I'll consider it spreading of gaming and I won't be expecting to play gaming.
Scott: You know, and then we'll, maybe like the, you know, if it's not the double day recess, if it's the one day, we'll use the second day for our own gaming or, you know, I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, we'll figure it out.
Scott: But yeah, I mean, you know, if you're, you know, not in the same boat as us, right?
Scott: It's sort of tricky, right?
Scott: Let's say you're okay at some games.
Scott: Well, do you risk leveling up, right?
Scott: Do you want to self improve?
Rym: When we do that panel, How to Win in Games, we have this huge, you know, half joking but half serious disclaimer about how if you actually pay attention to games, like, you play a game like Puerto Rico or Calus, and you actually really pay attention and really try to win.
Rym: And learn from your mistakes.
Rym: You will very rapidly become so much better than everyone else around you at that one particular game.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you get Street Fighter and you like it, should you practice and improve your skills at it?
Scott: Because that is a rewarding task that is of self improvement, but at the same time, it can also be a great sacrifice of enjoyment if no one you know does the same thing and you can't find, you know, enough hardcore Street Fighter community to get involved in, you know?
Scott: It's like, unless you have like, say, Chinatown Arcade which is not open anymore, but I think it moved and I think they still have fighting games over there.
Scott: You know, what do you do?
Scott: You can play online, sure, but it's, you know, that's not really it.
Scott: Can you make it out to the tournament?
Scott: Are you tournament level?
Scott: Or are you just better than all your friends?
Rym: There's a secondary issue with space in that every gaming con I've ever been to, except for some very, like, tiny ones out of the way, has terrible space just because space is expensive.
Rym: Not just in New York, but anywhere.
Rym: So usually RPGs are in very loud rooms and even at recess, as great as the games are, the rooms are so loud that it's very tiring to play in the RPGs.
Rym: I'm very loud.
Rym: I have to lose my voice.
Rym: I'm sick of playing games in very loud rooms.
Rym: Even PAX has that problem.
Rym: Like PAX Tabletop at PAX East, it was a great experience.
Scott: Well, at East, I like the West better because it's a bunch of smaller rooms.
Rym: But like PAX East, it was something to see, such a big room, but at the same time, it was impossible to play games in there.
Scott: That's why we went to the other room.
Rym: Yeah, we had basically our private tabletop.
Scott: Well, anyway, anyone else could have come in there.
Rym: No one did.
Rym: It was just us.
Rym: So, we're not abandoning, you know, because we've said something about this.
Rym: No, we're not abandoning all the Nerd NYC events.
Rym: We're just, we've realized that what we want out of gaming, primarily, when we're players, is not something we can get from really any public venue.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, it's something no one can really get from any public venue, right?
Scott: If you're Michael Jordan, right, and you want to play competitive, hardcore basketball.
Rym: If you go to, say, MagFest, a gaming con, and you want to get your Street Fighter on, there are a bunch of hardcore people and it's really easy to get it on.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not the same level as the EVO tournament, which is the big Street Fighter tournament.
Rym: Yeah, but maybe you don't need that.
Scott: Maybe you don't need that.
Rym: RPGs just, you can't get away with, like, conventions tend to have large, loud spaces, and yet, RPGs specifically require out of the way quiet places.
Rym: And I think that's why a lot of the good RPGs that go on at cons happen outside of the con in hotel rooms.
Scott: Possibly.
Scott: But yeah, there's just, you know, should you sacrifice self-improvement to maintain enjoyment, or, you know, should you, like, is it worth it to put in the extra effort to find the community once you have self-improved?
Rym: No, no, no, I'll make a very, here's a simpler thing.
Rym: It's like a Counter-Strike server.
Rym: Do you play with your friends and with strangers on the pubs, because you can just do that, or do you give up on that and only play on your password-protected server?
Rym: that only the people you want to play with are there?
Scott: But then, even then, you play on your password-protected server with your clan, right?
Scott: And then you really want to play, but no one happens to be online right now.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So then what do you do?
Rym: Do you go to the public thing, or do you just not play?
Rym: There's also-- And then there's the third path of joining the clan.
Scott: There's also a reverse problem, though, that is, that we don't recognize often, which is a lot of people say, like, I know a lot of people have tried to play Counter-Strike, and they hate it because they just die instantly.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Even on pubs, they just get killed constantly.
Scott: They can't do anything.
Rym: That was me when I first started playing.
Scott: Yeah, because their skill level is too low to even play with the general population.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So, you know, what do you do in that sort of situation?
Rym: Well, that's why I'm going to still keep going.
Scott: A lot of those people, what they do is they just give up, rather than try to self-improve.
Rym: That's why I'm going to keep going to the NerdNYC recesses, but I'm going to only go to run games.
Rym: Because, one, if I'm running a game, I know exactly what it's going to be.
Rym: I'm not going to be stuck in a game I don't want to play.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And, two, I'm spreading the word.
Scott: What we can do is, plus, if you run, like, a board game-- It's the same thing that happens with conventions.
Rym: We don't really go to anime cons unless we're, you know, talent at them.
Rym: We don't go to-- PAX is the only con I'd go to if I wasn't, like, a guest.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, I mean, you know, if you're not running-- if you don't run an RPG, if you run a board game, you can just get it started, and then we can start a game at a different table.
Scott: Of just us.
Scott: Like, if four of us all run board games, we can all start up those games and then go to our own table and play.
Scott: This is also why-- Serious gamer, he says.
Rym: something I want to do at PAX East, and we have vague ideas, and we can't say if anything will happen or not, but what if we had a room, like, a panel room that was dedicated to this?
Rym: Where you would run, like, learn to play sessions, like, a lecture, a panel.
Rym: that's, like, 45 minutes long.
Rym: Everyone will learn how to play Puerto Rico right now.
Rym: We'll teach you all.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, at PAX West once, I taught, like, a whole room, like, three groups, like, 15 people how to play Agricola simultaneously.
Rym: So what if we institutionalize that?
Rym: We have a panel room where it's just-- it's got tables in it, even, and you-- for 45 minutes, you teach Puerto Rico, and then, look, there's 10 sets of Puerto Rico.
Scott: And there's a room full of people who know how to play it.
Rym: Oh, everybody play Puerto Rico.
Rym: And, oh, the moderator who ran the panel is there to help with rules questions.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Huh.
Rym: Because I really-- it's not-- you know, we're not special.
Rym: We're not that smart.
Rym: We just played a lot of goddamn games.
Rym: I mean, it's like the Street Fighter guy.
Rym: He's great.
Rym: It's an important skill.
Rym: Well, not an important skill, but it's a skill that he earned.
Rym: He'd be fought for.
Rym: But it doesn't take that much.
Rym: Very little practice at Street Fighter makes you way better than your friends.
Scott: Right, but it takes a whole lot of practice to become the best.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Around.
Rym: No one's gonna--.
Rym: So, I feel like our real strategy as we get older is we have to kind of make the culture that will make people become obsessed nerds like us about games so that we then have people to play with.
Scott: I think, also, you have to sort of pick and choose in your own life.
Scott: You know, choose only a few things to build your skills in, right?
Scott: Don't do Starcraft and Street Fighter and board games and-- Why not?
Rym: You'll just be better than everyone.
Scott: Right, but you gotta, you know, in some aspect, you have to, you know--.
Rym: Wait, are you saying I should strive for mediocrity?
Scott: No, I'm not saying strive for mediocrity.
Scott: I'm saying, you know, you should think about it.
Scott: If you try to practice all those things at once, you're never gonna be the huge master of any of them.
Scott: You'll become really good at a whole bunch of them.
Scott: You won't be god of any of them.
Rym: You could become a master, but not a professional.
Scott: Right, so pick something, one or two things to be god, like, as good, like, world class at.
Rym: Well, like you did with Pac-Man.
Rym: You were like, "I'm gonna be the best at
Rym: this.".
Scott: Yup, exactly.
Scott: And then, you know, pick a whole bunch of things to be as good as you can at, but then, you know, accept that you can't, you know, you really can't do everything in the world.
Rym: And when you can't find-- Like, you know what?
Rym: Street Fighter, I suck.
Rym: Like, I even try, and I'm just so bad, like, it's a joke.
Scott: Yeah, you also shmups.
Rym: Yeah, I'm terrible at shmups, too.
Scott: If you can't find anybody, then go and do some of those things that you enjoy that you haven't, you know, the things that you're good at, so you're really good at tennis, you can't find anyone to play tennis with, well, there's something else you enjoy that you probably haven't practiced as much, so go back and play that for a while, you know?
Scott: And then, maybe your tennis skills will rust, and you'll go back to it, but there's still gonna be that thing that you mastered, maybe golf, right?
Scott: And then, don't give up on that.
Scott: Keep practicing the golf, even if it's alone in the driving range, so you can be the master of something.
Scott: No studio, and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.