Rym: It's Thursday January 6th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight's oldness.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So remember way back we saw that movie or we saw a trailer for it that was the, like, a smart engineer becomes a terrorist and fucks everything up for everybody?
Scott: Uh, no, but...
Rym: We've talked about the movie.
Scott: We've talked about that idea.
Rym: Yeah, we talked about the movie, you know, we wondered if it would do it.
Rym: It was, uh, I forget what the movie was called.
Rym: I think it was Law Abiding Citizen.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: So I watched it the other day.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: That is what it was.
Rym: It was a smart guy who is an engineer becomes a terrorist.
Scott: How about that?
Rym: Not that good, though.
Scott: The thing is, I mean, it's actually a well-known fact that most real terrorists actually have engineering degrees, but they're not engineers.
Scott: They're not good at it.
Rym: Well, you're qualifying, though, because there's real terrorists as in the ones that plan big attacks and there's actual terrorists as in the guy that, like, their shoe was on fire or...
Scott: They attacked the local embassy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But basically the movie was, I don't know, it's not worth watching.
Rym: It starts out really good.
Rym: The guy does the kind of smart things you'd expect an engineer to do if he wanted to be a terrorist.
Rym: But step one, he got a little implausible at the end with the robot rocket launcher.
Scott: Alright, implausible.
Rym: And tunneling into solitary confinement.
Rym: Implausible.
Rym: And the fact that after he murders, like, a bunch of judges and things, the feds don't just step in and the CIA doesn't just, like, kill him.
Scott: Implausible.
Rym: Because they have him in jail.
Rym: They know who he is.
Rym: They could just kill him and they don't.
Scott: They would.
Rym: And it gets to the point where he's going to blow up, like, the entire city of Philadelphia.
Scott: That's not possible.
Rym: Well, possible, but who cares?
Scott: Incredibly.
Scott: Encouraged, but incredibly difficult.
Scott: That's like those guys, like, I'm going to poison the water supply.
Scott: It's like, yeah, no, you're not.
Rym: Like, it was obvious.
Rym: He puts car bombs everywhere and stuff like that.
Rym: But then it just gets a little dumb.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's no way one guy could put car bombs everywhere.
Rym: One guy, well, one guy could do a lot of what he did.
Rym: But the way the movie played out, real government people, because the shtick was, I'm spoiling this whole movie because it sucks, was that it turns out what he was, he was an engineer, right?
Rym: He was an engineer for the CIA.
Rym: And his job was low-touch assassinations, like tiny bomb and a cell phone kind of thing.
Rym: So the CIA tips off the cops, but the CIA doesn't just kill this guy after he's murdered, like, ten government officials.
Rym: So basically, it was plausible in every regard, except the fact that, one, nobody noticed the goddamn rocket launcher robot hanging out in the cemetery.
Scott: See, you know, the thing is, like, if someone like me, it would be a situation where, like, it was a terrorism.
Scott: They don't know who did it.
Scott: There was incredible amounts of damage.
Scott: You know, that's the kind of terrorism you would have of really smart people.
Scott: You would never know who it was.
Rym: Well, if they want to make a good movie along these lines, because basically the movie was trying to make this, like, a plausible reason for him to be that pissed off and also be a smart person.
Rym: And it really, basically his wife and his daughter get, like, raped and murdered in front of him, and then the people who do it get away with it.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, yeah, but I feel like someone should make the same movie, but it's basically anonymous that starts attacking people.
Scott: Eh, I don't know.
Scott: I don't think there's a good movie there at all.
Rym: I think there is, Smart Terrorist.
Scott: No.
Rym: You don't think there's a movie about smart terrorists?
Rym: This is James Bond, but you get to watch the bad guy?
Scott: That would be a different story.
Scott: Because at the end, James Bond comes in and blows him away.
Scott: Yeah, so I was at work today, and apparently he's doing construction on the floor above us.
Rym: You know, they're doing masonry work again on my building.
Scott: So, all I heard all day was sawing of wood.
Rym: Oh, every 20 minutes today, I hear...
Scott: And then, of course, a guy drops a whole bunch of two-by-fours on the floor.
Scott: And then... It's like, all day long, from the morning till the night.
Scott: It was the worst.
Rym: I can think of worse things.
Scott: Anyway, so I want to try something new for a Thursday, right?
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: Because I got no news.
Rym: I got something new, too.
Scott: I got news, but it's all Monday news because CES is going on right now.
Scott: But anyway, I was thinking, what if, right, you know, I geek-bited a book?
Scott: It's not a book that's ever going to be book club, but I read it, so it might as well geek-bite, right?
Scott: No.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Scott: So, I'm going to do that right now.
Scott: I read Lachlanra book two, which I know you have also read.
Rym: Let's not spoil it, but you know what?
Rym: It was more of the same.
Rym: I think he's a slightly better author in the second book.
Rym: Like, he's learned.
Scott: He definitely has more writing skills, but I think because you already know the characters and it's a sequel and the pirate part drags out a little bit long...
Rym: The pirate part becomes, basically, the book.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, I wish there was less pirate chapters, you know, even though...
Rym: He has a little too much of a tendency to kill every goddamn character.
Scott: Yeah, that too.
Scott: Well, I think he wants to, he's basically doing the superhero thing, right?
Scott: He wants to return to as much status quo as possible at the end, so he can start...
Rym: Except the status quo of the first book you can't go back to because he killed everybody.
Scott: No, no, no, but the status quo that was established at the end of the first book is the same status quo that was established at the end of the second book.
Scott: So, every book will end with the same status quo.
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: Maybe not the final final book, but every other book in between.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, you know, if you like the first one, the second one is more of the same.
Rym: It is way up your alley.
Scott: Also, if you didn't like the first one, then don't read the second one.
Rym: Nope, but if you did not read the first one yet, the second one, for me at least, is proof that the first one's worth reading because the second one might be worth reading for you.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's...
Rym: It's not a Hyperion situation.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: It's definitely not.
Scott: But yeah, you know, it's fun, thieving and pirating, and the whole time you're like, "What are they going to do?
Scott: What are they going to
Scott: do?".
Scott: And then, oh my God, you see what they do.
Rym: There's a pretty good moment of comeuppance.
Scott: It doesn't leave anything unresolved.
Scott: Once you finish the book, everything that was started in that book will end in that book.
Scott: You're not left hanging for a future book for any of the plot points.
Rym: I do.
Rym: The whole book, I was trying to figure out what their angle was, what the original heist was going to be, and I did not figure it out at any point.
Rym: I got hints with the rappelling thing.
Rym: I was like, "All right, I think they're going to go out the
Rym: window.".
Scott: I mean, I figured it out once they used the cement.
Scott: I was like, "All right, there's nothing to do except the only things that they have described that they could possibly be heisting are these
Scott: things.".
Scott: And then it was those things, and I was like, "Oh, really?
Scott: That's
Scott: lame.".
Rym: But then again, that's a pretty good con.
Scott: It's not the worst, but...
Rym: Just remember, they were in this for fun, mostly.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The thing is that they were in it for fun.
Scott: I don't know why they just didn't stick to their gambling situation, which was way more interesting than the pirate situation.
Rym: Well, I think they had the Lupin situation, where once you've stolen everything and you're rich, you're bored.
Rym: So what do you do?
Rym: Steal.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: That's basically it.
Scott: And of course, they also had the Kabi-Bewab situation, where you never actually get away with something big, so you always need money again.
Scott: It's like, "Why can't we get a story where the rich guy, the thief, actually makes off with the big gold, and he's super rich all the
Scott: time?".
Rym: I have a counter example.
Rym: In the first book, they're richer than probably anyone.
Scott: No, I think that you gotta look...
Rym: They already had all the money they could ever use.
Scott: Yeah, I think what we need is we need to go...
Rym: And they tried to steal more.
Scott: We gotta read about Lupin I. I have a feeling that Lupin I... Or Saint Lupin.
Scott: He was the one who was mad loaded all the time.
Scott: It's French.
Rym: I'm sure there's a translation.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: I got a feeling.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I feel like I get a lot of the same stuff I would get from our Saint Lupin book from watching the Layton movie.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Minus puzzles.
Rym: Minus thieving.
Scott: I didn't watch that Layton movie.
Rym: It was okay.
Rym: I think I geek-bit it.
Scott: Possibly.
Rym: So in homage and honor to the topic we're gonna do tonight, I found an article, tried my Thursday thing, related to that.
Rym: It turns out there is, of all the indicators of how long you have left to live once you're already old, like once you're 50/60, there's one that has been found, and this is one of many recent studies, but this one's pretty damn conclusive, that is the best indicator of how long you will live after you hit like 65/75.
Rym: How fast you walk.
Scott: I walk real fast.
Rym: If you just take an old person- Is faster better or worse?
Rym: The faster you walk, the longer you live.
Scott: Oh man, I'm gonna be like a zillion years old.
Rym: It's a straight linear thing.
Scott: Now is it just how fast you naturally walk, or can you intentionally speed up to live longer?
Rym: So the article, I recommend you all read it, and some follow-up stuff.
Scott: What if I have longer legs, but I take less steps per second?
Scott: Is it steps per second, or is it meters per second?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: That matters a lot.
Rym: So the deal is, specifically for people who are over 75, walking speed is a straight correlation.
Rym: Like a mile per hour is another X years of life, and it's pretty damn accurate.
Scott: I'm never gonna be in the walker, I'm just gonna keep walking fast as long as possible.
Rym: And canes, walkers, anything you've got doesn't matter.
Rym: It's just how fast you ambulate when you walk normally.
Scott: Walking is called ambulating?
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I did not know that.
Rym: Ambulation.
Scott: I thought ambulance.
Scott: For example- I thought ambulation was going to the doctor.
Rym: If you are ambulatory.
Scott: Yeah, I thought that meant that you were in transport to a doctor.
Rym: It means you can move yourself about under your own power.
Scott: Oh, well, that's new to me.
Scott: Guy in a walker, guy in a cane- I had the wrong definition of that word.
Rym: They didn't however use wheelchair people.
Rym: They didn't want to deal with that.
Scott: Yeah, what if a guy's way fast in his wheelchair?
Rym: But for example, from the article, blah, blah, blah, blah, those who walked one meter per second, about 2.25 miles an hour or faster, consistently and significantly lived longer than others of their age and sex who walked more slowly.
Rym: I wonder, this is just way out there.
Rym: speculation, I'm not going to argue there's any causation here, but New York City has, from many studies, the highest average walking speed in America, if not the world.
Rym: New York City has one of the highest life expectancies in America.
Rym: They said that there is a small correlation that if you walk slowly and you try to walk faster on a regular basis, that you will live longer.
Rym: But that is not nearly as strong and requires much more study to prove.
Rym: But they argued that if you're trying to walk faster, you're probably exercising, you're probably getting yourself into better health.
Rym: And there's all these side arguments that it might have to do with outlook.
Rym: People who walk faster tend to have places to go, they tend to not be in a lot of extreme pain or they're in extreme pain, but they want to be where they're going more than they want to deal with the pain.
Rym: They're willing to put up with it.
Rym: Also, just like hips and joints and heart, everything goes into walking.
Rym: So I thought it was a neat thing.
Rym: So today on the treadmill, I determined that my average walking pace, like out in the street if I'm just walking somewhere, is between 4.6 and 4.7 miles an hour.
Rym: My maximum walking speed, like if I'm in a hurry and I'm not going to run-.
Scott: Well, I walk the same as you because you don't get away from me.
Rym: Yeah, it's 5.1 miles an hour.
Rym: That is as fast as I walk unless I power walk, which I don't power walk down the street.
Scott: Yeah, power walking is dorky.
Rym: It's fast, but as we learned from Will He Run, you run when you got to go somewhere.
Scott: So this would normally be a Wednesday kind of thing of the day.
Scott: We're doing things of the day now, right?
Scott: No.
Rym: Okay, now we're doing things of the day.
Scott: All right, now we're doing things of the day.
Scott: So this would normally be a Wednesday thing of the day, right?
Scott: I don't know if you remember.
Scott: Probably one of the most ancient things of the day, if it was even a thing of the day, is the website miotd.com, which is mechaimageoftheday.com, which is actually- Ah, very good website.
Scott: A website that continues to go with a mecha image every single day.
Rym: Whoa, I haven't checked it in like two years.
Scott: You've probably got 720 some odd mecha images that you can observe.
Scott: This is a similar site, right?
Scott: It doesn't have one every day, right?
Scott: But it has quite a few in its archive.
Scott: It's only been going for a few months.
Scott: It's been going since late August, and each month it has quite a sampling.
Scott: So the website is Fe, Yes, Vintage Manga, and it's mostly single scanned.
Scott: It's not scans of the whole manga, right?
Scott: It's like, here's the cover, or here's an inside page of vintage shoujo mangas.
Scott: And you can see there are many pictures of crazy old mangas here.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I want to read every one of those as far as I can see.
Scott: I know, they're all girly mangas, but the point is- Yeah, yeah, you know what else was a girly manga?
Rym: Half the manga we like.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm just saying, I probably don't want to read all of these.
Scott: I didn't say I don't want to read any.
Scott: I said I don't want to read all.
Scott: Many.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, mad interesting pictures to be looking at.
Scott: And also here's something that appears to be somewhat Russian.
Scott: Disco Churin Potau.
Rym: That looks like a real person.
Scott: It is.
Scott: I don't know what's up with that.
Scott: I'm worried.
Scott: But yeah, lots of cool things to see here.
Scott: It's a thing of the day.
Rym: So the Commonwealth of Virginia has done something- You mean the state of Virginia?
Rym: They're a commonwealth.
Rym: Just like I think Ohio's a commonwealth, I forget.
Scott: So they're not, yeah, okay.
Rym: Basically, commonwealth means we're a state, but we call stuff different stuff for no good reason.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: But no, Ohio isn't actually a state, remember?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So- That's why you don't have to pay taxes.
Rym: The Commonwealth of Virginia's Department of Motor Vehicles are asshole killjoys.
Rym: They have ruined one of the two great wonders of the license plate world.
Rym: The first wonder of the license plate world, as you all know, is the famous Florida license plate that says, "Ass
Rym: Orgy."
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, it actually said A55RJY, but the new Florida license plate had a big circular orange in the middle, and someone clever made an epic license plate that made it past the censors, until one dude complained about it, and then they revoked it.
Scott: Assholes.
Rym: So Virginia, there's the second most famous license plate ever, of course not counting-.
Scott: How come someone hasn't tried to make a free speech case out of this?
Scott: I'm expressing myself through my license plate number.
Rym: So the argument is that you can do that with a bumper sticker, and that the state cannot condone on its own, it can choose not to condone obscene language.
Rym: But you're allowed to put a bumper sticker that says, "Fuck" or "Ass Orgy" on your car.
Rym: You just can't get the state to have a license plate.
Rym: that does that.
Rym: But why- And you know how they get around it?
Rym: They don't.
Rym: actually, while they say, "Oh, we'll revoke obscene ones," usually the code says, "We have the right to deny or revoke any license plate at any time for any
Rym: reason.".
Scott: So just someone decides arbitrarily.
Rym: Yeah, but really, they only do it when people complain, and they really avoid any- I mean, I was trying to get my vanity plate when I was a kid in high school.
Rym: They denied the first 20 things I told them.
Rym: Half of them were deemed obscene, and half of them, they wouldn't tell me why they denied them.
Rym: I ended up on Arcadia, because that was the bottom of my list, and I was running out of patience.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So I couldn't get Arboria, by the way.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: They wouldn't tell me why.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Because Arboria I figure is more fun than Arcadia.
Rym: Someone in Virginia had a famous license plate that is simply E-A-T-T-H-E, Eat The.
Rym: Have you ever seen a Virginia license plate?
Scott: Does it have a V in the middle?
Rym: So Eat The.
Rym: on this license plate, it says Virginia at the top in crayons.
Rym: On the left are two red, bloody-looking handprints, and on the bottom says, "Kids
Rym: first.".
Scott: Oh, Virginia, eat the kids first.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That sounds like, no, I think what that is, if it says kids first, that's probably one of those special ones.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Like in New York, you can get the pet swan.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You can get any, you can get Rangers or Mets or Giants.
Rym: But no, in Virginia here, we got eat the kids first with two bloody handprints.
Rym: And the DMV sent a letter to the guy who has it.
Rym: The letter is posted, basically saying, "Yeah, we received a complaint about your license plate, and it is hereby revoked.
Rym: Fuck
Rym: you.".
Scott: Just keep driving with it.
Scott: What are they going to do?
Rym: Suspend his license?
Scott: Only if he ever gets pulled over.
Rym: Basically, you realize cops look up every license plate they see all the time.
Scott: And then, well, I mean, you can at least keep it until your registration goes out, because they're going to- They can just take it right then.
Rym: They can demand he give it back.
Scott: They have to physically come and take it from you, though.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: All I would do if I were him is take a picture of me holding it to prove that it was mine.
Rym: I feel for you, dude.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: Fuck Virginia.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So we got a meta moment, really quick.
Rym: There will probably be one or two more GeekNights episodes before MAGFest.
Rym: I think one.
Rym: Maybe two.
Rym: We might have an episode to put up.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: MAGFest is next week, Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday, four days of insane awesomeness.
Rym: January 13th through 16th, 2011, Thursday through Sunday in Alexandria, Virginia, in the middle of fuck nowhere at a hotel.
Scott: But if you go to YouTube, to the MAGFest channel, you can see awesome commercials that will convince you to go to MAGFest.
Rym: You should go to MAGFest or- MAGFest!
Scott: I haven't even been there, but I already feel the MAGFest.
Rym: Not only that, many of our listeners see us at conventions, and you want to hang out with us.
Rym: Usually, we brush you off.
Rym: No offense to you.
Rym: It's basically we're busy.
Scott: Brim, we'll brush you off.
Rym: Yeah, you will also brush people off.
Scott: Although I brushed off that was not a fanboy or a fangirl.
Rym: Or a crowd.
Rym: The crowd's the biggest thing.
Rym: People don't know where we are, and then we do a panel.
Rym: All our listeners come to the panel or hang out outside the panel, and then we have a mob and we usually have to hide in the room until most of you go away.
Scott: If you want to actually talk to us, you're much better off coming up when there's no one else there and using your balls.
Rym: Of steel.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: But at MAGFest, we only have one lecture, and we're sitting on two additional panels in the MAG9.
Scott: Actual panel panels, not lectures or presentations.
Rym: The entire rest of this convention, I plan to alternate between drinking, sleeping, and playing board games.
Scott: I'm playing so many games.
Scott: Playing all the games.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Half the crew's going to be there.
Scott: If it's a game, I'm playing it.
Rym: Also, our friend John St.
Rym: John's going to be there, and James Rolf, who I've talked to once or twice.
Rym: Cool people.
Rym: The angry video game nerd and such.
Rym: Losing should be fun.
Rym: Technical changes in game design and achievements and metagaming.
Rym: MAGFest will also be at PAX East, but that's a ways away.
Rym: This weekend, actually tomorrow, Friday, NerdNYC board game night.
Rym: Next Friday and Saturday, NerdNYC recess.
Rym: Details online.
Rym: I will link to them.
Scott: Anything else can wait.
Scott: Oh, and the book club selection.
Rym: Michio Kaku's Hyperspace, a book about 10 dimensions and stuff.
Scott: Not 11 dimensions?
Rym: Well, 10 plus time, I think.
Rym: I think it's 10.
Scott: Not 9 dimensions?
Rym: As I recall, it is 10 spatial dimensions plus time.
Scott: Not 13 dimensions?
Scott: No, specifically 10.
Scott: How do you know exactly 10?
Rym: Because the math works.
Rym: With 9, the math doesn't work.
Rym: With 11, the math doesn't work.
Rym: With 10, it's predictive, theoretically.
Scott: Theoretically?
Rym: Basically, it is a layman's introduction to string theory in terms of what it actually implies if it's true and what the actual evidence is for it.
Rym: It's one of those things like, "All right, if this is true, then you know what?
Rym: There's all these universes and dimensions, and here's what that means.
Rym: Holy
Rym: shit.".
Scott: Check out this animated gif of a hockey guy eating a waffle and then drinking some syrup.
Rym: I've seen that.
Rym: That's a pretty good thing that the listeners cannot see.
Rym: In fact, we don't even have a Ustream anymore.
Rym: There's no way for them to see that.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, you know, I'm pushing 30.
Rym: I'm getting old.
Rym: You are old.
Rym: Scott's getting old.
Rym: We're both feeling the effects.
Rym: I'm not old.
Scott: Only you're old.
Rym: I'm getting old.
Scott: I'm not old.
Rym: You are less than a year younger than me.
Scott: I'm less old.
Rym: Captain 1982.
Scott: Am I not less old?
Rym: Do I not have ... Do I have to go low blow here?
Rym: I got more hair.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: Hair has nothing to do ... In all ...
Rym: In all places.
Scott: Babies.
Scott: Babies have no hair, but you know what?
Scott: They're less old.
Rym: Also, I posit ... I'm closer to baby.
Rym: I posit that, yes, you are very much closer to babydom.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: However, you have ... While you are not old of body, you are definitely old of attitude in some ways, Mr.
Rym: Crotchety old man.
Rym: Who is not?
Rym: Mr.
Rym: "Eh, I've done that before.
Rym: I don't need to do it
Rym: again.".
Scott: Who on this earth is not crotchety in a way or two or old-fashioned in a way or two?
Rym: Carl Sagan had no point in his life was crotchety.
Scott: Everybody inherits something from their parents, and because your parents are older from you than you, everyone is old-fashioned in some way.
Rym: Scott, for example, I inherited my dad's face.
Rym: I inherited my mom's eyes.
Rym: You apparently inherited your dad's, "Eh, Mila, get in the car.
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: Let's get out of here.
Scott: Yeah, it's because I walk so fast, I'm in a hurry.
Scott: That's why I'm going to live to be a lot older than you.
Rym: You inherited old.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Seriously, Scott's dad, his parents will come to visit us, and we'll be hanging out.
Scott: Is this show about being old, or is this show about Scott?
Rym: Five minutes.
Rym: His dad's like, "We're going to go yet.
Rym: We're going to have some food.
Scott: There's the game
Scott: on.".
Scott: All right.
Rym: Scott, you're the only one in the crew where when someone is mimicking the voice of someone else, it is pretty much just, "Eh, eh,
Rym: eh.".
Rym: Get off my metaphorical gaming lawn.
Scott: That's right, punk kids.
Rym: We are getting old though.
Rym: I mean, I realized that when I turn 30, I have at most everything.
Rym: I just did two more times, and then I'll die.
Scott: Pretty much, but you know what?
Scott: I'm betting on advanced technologies, because think about it, right?
Rym: I saw an article saying that one in five people who are alive today will reach 100.
Scott: Yeah, but think about this, right?
Scott: Our grandparents, when they were 30, it was like what?
Scott: The '50s maybe, the '40s of the '50s, and the life expectancy then was what?
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: I didn't look up any research for the show.
Scott: It was not much.
Scott: The life expectancy has gone way up over the course of their lifetime.
Rym: I've also read a lot of studies and things talking about the fact that the life expectancy of humans who survive, apparently from like 45, 50 to like 65, that's the danger zone where if you don't die then, you're probably going to make it to 80, maybe 90, but if you die right then, it's pretty much just genetics or bad lifestyle.
Rym: Even in the old days, a lot of people in ancient times would live to be 70, 80, but most people died when they were one, or when they were 20, or when they were 50.
Rym: Medicine only gets you so far if you're a fat ass, or if you just get bad genes, bad heart.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I go to the doctor, and the doctor say, "You are in the flawless health.
Scott: I predict I will be around very long.
Scott: There will be many geek
Scott: nights.".
Rym: That is the trouble.
Rym: You're pretty much guaranteed to have your doctor.
Scott: Although, it may eventually become GeekNights.
Rym: I think I'm going to outlive you.
Scott: Yeah, you wish.
Rym: Well, see, it's complicated by the fact that I'm much more- You don't walk as fast as me.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: We just agreed that we walk at the same speed.
Rym: And you- You can't run as fast as me.
Scott: You went to the doctor.
Scott: He's always got bad stuff to say.
Scott: Like what?
Scott: You got allergies and shit.
Scott: You're always coughing up nasty phlegm.
Rym: Yeah, I got allergies.
Scott: Yeah, you got all kinds of illnesses over there.
Rym: No, I've got allergies.
Rym: That doesn't correlate with life.
Scott: You'll be dead next year.
Scott: You'll be dead before the iPhone comes to Verizon.
Rym: I probably will be dead before the iPhone comes to Verizon.
Scott: Because it happens.
Rym: I'll bet you 500 bucks.
Rym: it's not within the next three weeks.
Scott: No way.
Scott: So now, you're only going three weeks.
Scott: You originally were saying 2012.
Scott: Why don't you extend that bet to be 365 days?
Scott: 500 bucks?
Scott: Yeah, 365 days.
Rym: No, but are you going to- because you never bet.
Rym: You never bet on anything.
Scott: There's very strong evidence this time.
Scott: I bet when I'm not sure.
Rym: Regardless, the thing that might fuck me is that I'm much more likely to die a catastrophic death than you are, I think.
Scott: Yeah, it's almost guaranteed.
Rym: I'm going skiing this weekend, most likely.
Scott: You'll get dead this weekend.
Scott: That's how it's going to happen.
Rym: Now, the first ski trip of the year is always the cautious ski trip.
Rym: Do I actually remember how to ski?
Rym: Because at the end of the year, it's like I've been skiing all year, so it's like, yeah, let's go.
Rym: The first time, it's like, yeah, the last time I skied, I stand there in the skis.
Rym: I'm like, how do I turn?
Rym: What do I do when I'm up there?
Scott: You fall, you crash into a tree and die.
Rym: I'm looking at the lift.
Rym: I'm like, how do I get on this fucking thing?
Scott: You don't.
Scott: You fall off like those people did.
Rym: I saw a snowboarder jump off at Hunter Mountain last year.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: Ski lift was stopped.
Rym: Yeah, he was like, fuck it, and he just jumped off.
Scott: Did he live?
Rym: Yeah, he store boarded down.
Rym: Well, he fell into a snowdrift, went, ah, dug himself out, and then he snowboarded down.
Rym: Or for snowboard lingo, that means you go 10 feet, then you sit down on the slope and smoke pot.
Rym: Fucking snowboarders.
Scott: Why does the ski people let them smoke pot?
Scott: Why don't the cops just come there and round them all up?
Rym: Because you realize snowboarders to me are little more than speed bumps in my way.
Rym: Anyway, not to get into that old thing.
Scott: Meanwhile, it's your idea to do a show about oldness, and so far you can't even stay on.
Rym: One of the reasons I picked up skiing as a sport is that when I'm skiing, I regularly see people who are in their 70s skiing better than I ski now.
Scott: Yeah, but they're either going as fast or they just go in steadily.
Rym: Faster and better.
Rym: They actually have a lot of skill.
Rym: I do not have that.
Scott: Well, the speed of skiing comes from gravity more so than it comes from pushing, right?
Scott: No, it comes from skill.
Scott: Right, but the skill is not ... It's not like running where you are providing the propulsion.
Scott: You are just providing the steadiness and the balance, right, which years and years of practice, if you're an old person, you've been skiing your whole life, then you got that down.
Scott: But if it was propulsion, like if it was bobsledding, the old people might be able to keep it inside the little tube, but they wouldn't be able to go as fast because at the running start, they would not have.
Rym: Yeah, but that's the same reason why I want to pick up racquetball again, because I see old ass dudes playing racquetball way better than I play now.
Rym: Because I remember as a kid, I was young, I was fast, but I was not skilled.
Rym: I could run all the way to the corner and get the ball.
Rym: My dad was not nearly as fast as me, but he knew where the ball was going to go.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: That's pretty much ... You look at all old people's sports, right?
Scott: It's like racquetball, shuffleboard, billiards isn't exclusively an old person sport, but old guys love to play it.
Rym: I realize almost no one we know plays pool.
Scott: Yeah, but I can't even hit the ball.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But those are all these sports where you don't need to have significant strength or speed.
Scott: You have to have enough, but it's all about the precision and the accuracy and these sorts of things.
Scott: Aiming and all these skills, but not aiming like in Counter-Strike, you're going to aim quickly.
Scott: It's just aiming.
Scott: So in shuffleboard, you can take all damn day and you push it with just the right amount.
Scott: It's all about control and these sorts of things.
Scott: that if you've lived a very long time and you practice a lot, then that is what you can be very good at.
Scott: Whereas opposed to, say, something like hockey, an old person is not very good.
Rym: But one thing I'm really fascinated with is the fact that there's a good chance we'll live to see the year 2040, 2050, 2060.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Well, I can't even imagine what the world is going to be like then.
Scott: No, it's not even bother.
Scott: I just worry about today.
Rym: I mean, think back 60 ... What was going on 60 years ago?
Rym: World War II.
Rym: Oh, the end of World War II.
Scott: World War II was over.
Rym: 1950, end of World War II, all the cleanup.
Scott: It was recently over.
Rym: But it was- That was a recent memory.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: You don't have anything to say about that, old man?
Scott: No.
Scott: When we're old, we're going to say, "Oh, man, what was happening 60 years
Scott: ago?".
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: Whoa, remember that?
Scott: Yeah, the cleanup.
Rym: The great Facebook wars of, I guess there's no more aughts.
Rym: I've got to say, they were out of the aughts years.
Rym: I like saying like 20 aughts five.
Scott: You never said that.
Scott: I did.
Scott: You rarely said it.
Rym: Well, I rarely ... Whenever I had occasion to say a year, I would use aughts.
Scott: No, you would say 2009.
Rym: Only on GeekNights.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: Because it didn't sound right to say, "I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Rym: January 4th, 20, aughts
Rym: five.".
Scott: But meanwhile, we should say, according to people who have studied this, during the aughts, you're supposed to say 2000 aughts, right?
Scott: But now that we're in the not aughts, you're supposed to say 2011.
Scott: Because remember we used to say, what year is it?
Scott: We didn't say 1998.
Scott: We said 1998.
Scott: So now we should say 2011.
Rym: See, I don't think it said we should.
Rym: I think that's just what people do.
Scott: I think that's what you're supposed to do.
Rym: Based on what?
Scott: Based on what linguists said on the internet.
Rym: What even linguists said.
Scott: There was someone talking about it on the internet in an academic article.
Rym: Are you sure it was someone on the internet talking about it?
Scott: It was an academic because the URL was the EDUs.
Rym: Are you sure it wasn't nothing?
Scott: I'm sure it was something.
Scott: This show is so far not about oldness.
Rym: We've talked a lot about oldness.
Rym: What I do wonder about is that- All you've done is bicker.
Rym: A big problem with the elderly today- Like an old person.
Rym: Is that they get bored.
Rym: Every time I see retirement homes, or I'm in a retirement home, and I saw a lot of this when I was working for the hospital, like all these ancillary facilities and things, everyone looked really bored.
Scott: Well, I see two extremes.
Scott: Of course, it's probably, in reality, a wide gray area with all people all along the scale, but from what I see, I see old people who are either incredibly active or old people who are incredibly not active.
Scott: For example, I got one grandma.
Scott: She's doing something every damn day.
Scott: You call her out, she is not there.
Scott: She's doing something with her ladies, or she's going to the gym, or she's doing something every day, going to a book club.
Scott: She is happening grandma, and then the other grandma sits in the house in Florida and doesn't do anything because I've watched TV, and only TV shows that involve police or detectives.
Scott: That's all she's doing, and she's very bored all the time.
Rym: Well, I've read, prior to this, what got me thinking about the show was that I read a whole bunch of articles recently talking about the problem of elderly loneliness, that pretty much from now- All your friends die.
Scott: You don't make new friends, and then your spouse dies, and then you're alone.
Rym: It's a huge problem.
Scott: Your family, even if you had children and grandchildren, they live far away.
Scott: Even if they don't, they're busy.
Scott: They're not there all day, so it's eight hours a day.
Scott: you're sitting there.
Scott: You don't have to go to work, so you don't have coworkers to keep you company, so you're just sitting there alone for at least eight hours a day, and maybe a nurse to keep you company or something.
Rym: I mean, there's a lot of outreach.
Rym: Look at all these programs of get young people to spend time with an old person.
Rym: I feel like that will not be a problem by the time we are old because we have the internet.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Scott: Us, we will definitely ... Our generation definitely seems to be able to occupy itself with MMOs, if nothing else.
Rym: Dude, if nothing else, if no more entertainment media were ever made from now until the day I die, and I live to be 100, I will never run out of books to read, movies to watch.
Scott: No, but you'll still be lonely.
Scott: You don't need people.
Scott: If you have the internet, though, then you kind of sort of have people.
Rym: Yes, but the internet will give me people for sure.
Rym: There's no way it won't.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: What I really ... I don't worry about it, but we complain a lot about old people on GeekNights, and in our normal lives for people who know us.
Rym: We complain about old people all the time.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's sort of like, you look at different cultures in the world approach old people differently, especially in the Eastern nations.
Scott: Old people are generally respected because they're old and wise, or at least stereotypically so.
Scott: Whereas in the West, we've sort of, especially in the US, we're sort of looking down on our old people.
Scott: They're a burden and a hassle, like, "Get out of here, old
Scott: people.".
Rym: I think both are true to a degree.
Scott: Yes, both are true, but I think what's happening is it is verily true that old people have wisdom from being alive so long.
Scott: They know things that young people do not know, right?
Scott: Anyone who's been around long- Dude, we're old enough.
Rym: Look at half our listeners in the forum who are like, "I have this really bullshit problem in college, blah, or high school, blah,
Rym: blah.".
Rym: We're like, "We're old.
Rym: We've been through that.
Rym: Here's what you
Rym: do.".
Rym: They're like, "Nah, nah, nah, nah, nah.
Rym: I'm not going to do that.
Rym: You guys don't know what you're talking
Rym: about.".
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: Yeah, we're old.
Rym: We know.
Scott: Yeah, old people know.
Scott: But at the same time, right, I would point out that recent Dilbert comic, right?
Rym: Don't hit me with your modem.
Scott: Don't hit me with your modem, right?
Scott: Is that the world is changing so quickly that even an old person who has wisdom of age and experience, that wisdom may no longer be correct or useful?
Scott: because just the world has changed so much that it's no longer true.
Scott: It's like if I told you, "Hey, yeah, at the beginning of Mario 1, you want to jump on that
Scott: Goomba.".
Scott: But then a new version of Mario comes out where it's a Spiky instead of a Goomba, and then I'm an old person.
Scott: I'm like, "Oh, you got to jump on the Goombas in Mario
Scott: 1.".
Scott: But the kids would be like, "All right, Grandpa, we got Mario 1 Super All-Stars Deluxe,".
Scott: and I jumped on it, but it was a Spiky.
Rym: "What?
Rym: What the fuck happened to my
Rym: world?".
Rym: That's not real, Mario.
Scott: I'll be a cranky old man.
Rym: Yeah, we'll be cranky and old.
Scott: about video games, I think.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Of course, I'm hoping that even as my body fails me, even if I can't get electronic immortality, I at least want VR.
Rym: I want to be able to sit in the catgirl machine for my remaining days.
Scott: All right, go for it.
Scott: It's all you.
Rym: I got plans.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, but it's like, you know, we complain about old people, but when we're complaining about old people, usually what we're complaining about- Well, it has very little to do with actual age in many cases.
Scott: It has to do with an old attitude of people who have wisdom or experience or knowledge or they're, you know, most people are versed to change for, you know, an older time or a previous thing, and the world has passed that by, right?
Scott: It's a different world now, and rather than update to the new world, they try to pull the world back to the way it used to be.
Rym: You mean like, why are you kids playing these stupid console FPSs?
Rym: We played real FPSs, like-.
Scott: Why do you listen to that jazz music?
Scott: Why do you listen to that rock and roll music?
Scott: Why do you listen to that rap music?
Scott: Why do you listen to that, you know, techno music, right?
Scott: It's like, hello.
Rym: I don't even know what the controversial music is right now.
Scott: There isn't any.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Thank God.
Scott: But anyway, the thing, you know, the point is, it's like, look, some people keep up with the times, and some people, regardless of their age, there are 30-year-old people who I consider to be old people because they have this attitude of, you know, the world, some older world is better, and we should bring back progress to a preview, you know, or, you know, they insist on holding these ideas that might have been good in a previous world, but the world has changed, and they still stick to their old ideas rather than updating to the new world, and that's what I'm talking about when I complain about most old people.
Rym: Well, this is why I think we'll be okay because I feel like a lot of people, when they get older, it's like they forget what it was like to be a kid, or they forget like- A kid isn't what it's like to be a kid now.
Scott: It's different.
Rym: But then some things are fundamentally the same, and they just forget, like, how many old people basically don't want kids to go out and have fun?
Scott: Yeah, right?
Scott: I mean, how many old people who say that were out- It's not that they don't want the kids to have fun, right?
Scott: It's like, "Oh, kids are having fun.
Scott: That's nice," until the kids make noise, which bothers them, but, you know, it's like they care about themselves before they care about the children, right?
Scott: When they were children, they would make noise, and those old people in those days would be bothered by the noise, but they didn't see that part because they were children at the time, and now the only part that they notice is the part where, "This noise is bothering me," and they don't recognize, "Look, these children need to play for their
Scott: health.".
Rym: But see, I think we straddle a kind of progressive middle ground in that I still prefer and can articulate why I think, like, for example, older PCFPSs and things like that are better, but at the same time, or like my experiences with old school gaming.
Rym: But you're not like- But I always qualify things by saying, "Yes, the experience I had playing DOS games and having to figure it all out made me a better person, but no way in hell should the world go back to that
Rym: BS.".
Scott: Hell no.
Scott: I mean, like, if someone wanted to learn about, you know, like, that was what they wanted, I would tell them, "All right, then go and do it,".
Scott: but I'm not saying, "Yeah, we should have DOS on every
Scott: computer.".
Scott: It's like, "What?
Scott: You're talking about?
Scott: everyone should drive stick
Scott: shift.".
Scott: It's like, "Fuck
Scott: no.".
Rym: I mean, of course, I wonder if we'll even be able to retire because it seems like retirement for as new an idea as it is, is already kind of obsolete.
Rym: Like very few people, I think, have the means to save for a real retirement, especially if, you know, you want to retire at 65 or 70 and you live 20 more years, how are you going to save money to live 20 years?
Scott: I mean, basically what happened, right, is we had a country where people weren't really that well off.
Scott: Everyone worked crazy hard.
Scott: There was a depression.
Scott: They worked crazy hard, right?
Scott: And because they worked crazy hard and kept working crazy hard for a couple of decades, they made so much monies and they were so good, you know, relatively speaking, it was never perfect, right, that they were able to afford things like pensions and these sorts of things.
Rym: Well, part of that was an old world structure of working at a company forever.
Scott: But then they tried to hold on to these things even as they could no longer afford them over over great periods of time.
Scott: And eventually, you know, because they tried to maintain or increase the standard of living, you know, when the economy would not really keep up and support it and, you know, people started buying things they couldn't afford and living in a big house when they had apartment money and having a pension when they had barely 401K money.
Rym: You know, now having a pension is a great thing as long as it continues to exist.
Rym: Yeah, pension problem is more just that the world of work has changed.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's basically right.
Scott: They spent all this money and now there isn't enough.
Scott: And the other thing is, on top of that, people lived longer and they were retiring at the same age.
Scott: So not only did we need to save more money and make more money, which we weren't doing, but it would cost even more money to pay for people to retire.
Scott: So the cost of the retirement was going up and mathematically is just not working out.
Rym: So, I mean, personally, I'm saving like I have a 401K.
Scott: Mine is actually doing real well.
Rym: I got three together and I'm putting money into it, a decent amount of money, but I'm not banking on it.
Scott: No, no, I'm not expecting to live off of that.
Scott: You know, basically the reason I do it is because it's easy.
Scott: I can, you know, you should.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And if you look at the numbers, it's totally working out.
Scott: But you can do cool stuff with it.
Scott: Like you can take a loan, you can loan that money to yourself, pay it back with interest, but you're paying the interest to yourself.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can do cool stuff like that, which is very useful.
Scott: And especially since I started it so early, you know, it has a pretty good chance of success unless it's hooked on a can, in which case doesn't matter.
Rym: I'm pretty much, though, assuming that there will be no Social Security when I'm 70.
Scott: Oh, hell no.
Rym: There's no way that will continue to exist.
Rym: My money is going into it, but I'm pretty much considering that.
Scott: By law, it's going into it.
Scott: I have no choice.
Scott: But yeah, I mean, that's, you know, the whole thing is a rough situation because it's like, OK, someone's an old person now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They are incapable of working.
Scott: Or, you know, even if they could work, it's like they couldn't work well.
Scott: You know, what job are they going to do?
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're not going to make really enough money.
Scott: So they can't work, but we're not going to kill them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And their kids aren't so rich that their kids can just pay to take care of them forever.
Scott: Or maybe they don't even have any children.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: So what does this person do?
Scott: Well, you know, they can, you know, live within their meager means.
Scott: If their Social Security goes away, they might not have, you know, any continued income.
Scott: They just have the money they have and that's it for the rest of their life.
Scott: And what if they live really long?
Scott: What if they need an expensive medical procedure?
Scott: What do they do?
Rym: I think we'll have socialized medicine by the time I'm 70.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: If we don't, this country is fucked.
Scott: But even if you have socialized medicine, it's like that's only going to pay for some things.
Scott: You can't pay for everything.
Scott: So, you know, if you got something normal like the flu, it's like, you're all right.
Scott: You got pneumonia.
Scott: You're all right.
Scott: You broke a leg.
Scott: Oh, you need like a whole hip replacement.
Scott: Well, maybe you got weird cancer in a weird place.
Scott: Well, now what?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But at the same time, I wouldn't have been able to save enough money to deal with that anyway.
Rym: So I basically can't do anything about it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Of course, we do have the advantage that we're both very well off.
Rym: And I feel like I worry that in the next 30, 40 years, retirement is going to move further and further into something that is only within reach of the upper middle class and the wealthy.
Scott: Well, no, it's pretty much, you know, anyone who's employed, I think, is going to be able to retire.
Rym: A lot of people who are employed, Scott, make, you know, forty thousand dollars or whatever a year and can live off of that, but can't afford to contribute enough to a 401(k) to actually retire 20 years of their life on it.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: What are you going to do?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What do you do?
Rym: And how easy will it be to get a job when I'm 70?
Scott: Oh, impossible.
Rym: That's why I'm not worrying about it at all.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, basically, there's nothing you can really do about it.
Scott: besides, you know, save some monies for yourself.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And I'll save enough money to where.
Rym: if like I think I'm going to live another 10 years, I'm running out of money.
Rym: I don't know, blaze of glory, wander off somewhere, go to Costa Rica, do something crazy.
Scott: Yeah, you know, that's the other thing.
Scott: It's like when we retire, it's like, well, now it's like the vacation we've been waiting for.
Scott: The thing is, I don't know, we should retire the beginning of the life, not the end of the life.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So you'd imagine this.
Rym: So you have to you get to live.
Rym: basically Logan's run Logan's run until you're 40.
Rym: And then you got to work the rest of your life.
Scott: I would just kill myself.
Scott: I think a lot of people would just kill themselves or not work and just be like, screw you.
Scott: I'm not doing it.
Rym: What are you going to do?
Scott: Make me put you in jail.
Rym: That's why I'm not focused so much on my old age.
Rym: I'm basically enjoying now and planning minimally and nominally for the next 60 years of my life.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I wonder what, you know, it's like, you know, I've talked to really old people, but like, what are the people who are like 60 something like now who are almost retiring, like, you know, or maybe like the people who are going to like the late 50s people, it's like they're going to retire soon.
Scott: Maybe it's like, what are they?
Rym: I mean, the retirement age is already pretty much going up to 70.
Scott: And they they got things to pay off, like, you know, they're paying off things like their kids, student loans or also there's the fact that the life expectancy in the US drops.
Rym: Oh, yeah, in the past cycle do almost entirely to obese people.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, it's getting to be, you know, that maybe that is maybe all the fat people from our generation will die young and then there will be enough money for the rest of us to retire on.
Scott: I just think the status quo of retirement is changing.
Scott: I think the change upsets old people and young people deal with it.
Rym: I don't even think it's that I think.
Rym: take it one step further.
Rym: I think by the time we're at retirement age, the world social order will be unrecognizable compared to what it is today, at least in terms of the economics of retirement.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, if we live to be 100, it definitely will be.
Scott: Think about what it was 100 years ago.
Scott: in 1910, the world social order was completely different.
Rym: Well, World War One.
Scott: Yeah, the world social order was completely different in 1910 than it was in 2010.
Scott: So if we live, you know, to let's see, we're born in 82, so in 20 in 2082, it's going to be completely different.
Scott: It's not even going to be even close to what it is now, especially.
Rym: I mean, the rate of change, I think, is faster now than it was then.
Scott: Yeah, it's going to be ridiculous.
Rym: I mean, look at how much the Internet changed.
Rym: I don't know, in the last two years.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Ten years ago, there was barely Internet.
Rym: Twenty years ago, there basically wasn't an Internet.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I do, at least I look forward nominally.
Rym: I don't look forward to getting old.
Rym: I still think aging is a disease that we should treat.
Scott: I don't, you know, I'm slower now than I used to be.
Scott: But then you have to worry about like, well, there's not enough resources on earth to support, you know, the number of people continuing to make new people if nobody dies.
Rym: So here's let's go crazy.
Rym: I would be OK, say we solved aging to where you age to twenty two and there is no degradation from that point ever.
Rym: This is perfect.
Rym: You will get one hundred and twenty years and then they kill you.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think that's OK.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: What do you mean, why not?
Rym: Because you can't.
Rym: or I mean, the other option is the ultra rich will live forever and they'll prevent anyone else from getting the resources to do so.
Scott: Repo, genetic opera.
Rym: But how about this?
Rym: So you get one hundred and twenty years no matter what.
Rym: As you know, and then at the end of one hundred and twenty years there and have some sort of thing like you only have one kid or some.
Rym: let's forget the specifics of that part.
Rym: China, when you're one hundred and twenty, you can appeal your death and it's just a worldwide referendum or some sort of system retarded.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: It's not going.
Rym: technology could make that happen.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Where you have to say the system is really going to work.
Rym: You have to make the case to a court to say, look, I think I deserve another hundred and twenty years.
Rym: and here's why.
Scott: Yeah, the system is not going to work.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Give me a system.
Scott: We don't let anyone be immortal.
Rym: So we have to deal with all the bullshit of aging.
Rym: that is just.
Rym: there's no reason to suffer through it.
Rym: We should suffer through the effects of age, even if we can prevent them.
Scott: Well, you know, it's either.
Scott: if it's you know, you're basically saying it's either one person or every person.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, well, we can all suffer a little.
Scott: Or everyone is aging sucks ass.
Rym: I would rather live the same amount of time that I'm going to live now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Aging sucks ass.
Scott: How does aging compare to hope?
Scott: Don't know, Ken.
Rym: But Scott, what if I'm going to live 80 years anyway, but I'm in perfect health for those entire 80 years?
Rym: Hey.
Rym: I would rather accept a time limit and live those years.
Scott: Also, when they come to kill you and you're 80, you just can be like, all right, maybe or I'll try to run and you know what?
Rym: I won't get away.
Rym: No one gets away from the runners.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: OK.
Scott: Your your plans will look crazy.
Rym: It's not that crazy.
Rym: We've got to be transhumanist.
Scott: You're crazy.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I hope it's not to keep it realistic.
Rym: We might be on the edge of not getting immortality, but we might see immortality.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Someone younger than us.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What if we're 90?
Rym: They're like, we've perfected.
Scott: At least no one had to be around to see them, you know, fill the world with too many people who can't eat anything because no food left because maybe they won't need to eat because they've done the Michio Kaku thing.
Scott: I'm glad to say I won't see a world with no delicious food.
Rym: Maybe they have infinite delicious food due to Diamond Age.
Scott: Then I would be living in that world.
Scott: Hooray.
Rym: And dying of old age.
Scott: No, I'd replace myself with a diamond person.
Rym: It'll be interesting to see how the crew maintains over the years, because when we're 80, I can imagine I'll still playing Counter-Strike.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Odds are not everyone will make it that far.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I think we got about 30 years is when we're going to see that, like the do or die time.
Scott: And the thing is, I don't know about playing Counter-Strike because while Counter-Strike has been around for a decade.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It is.
Scott: Think about how incredibly difficult it is for us to play tribes, too.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, if Steam is going to be here in 80 years.
Rym: We'll have to play tactical intervention instead.
Scott: I mean, how are we going to play Counter-Strike?
Rym: I imagine we'll be playing some sort of video game.
Scott: Something.
Rym: I mean, it'll be fair.
Rym: We're old men.
Scott: We're already seeing.
Scott: We're already seeing it.
Scott: CES, right?
Scott: They're talking about Windows 8 on ARM CPUs.
Scott: Counter-Strike will never run on an ARM CPU.
Scott: So ever.
Rym: But at the very least, we'll be able to play games fairly or board games.
Rym: Those don't go obsolete.
Rym: As long as I can move, I can play Puerto Rico.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And it's actually not that infeasible that we'll solve every German game we care about in our old age.
Scott: Possible.
Scott: Computers have become so advanced that they will solve them the way they solve checkers.
Rym: So if computers do that, would you still play German board games?
Scott: It depends.
Scott: I would have to make a better game.
Rym: What if every game you design, a computer gives you the answer before you finish it?
Scott: Depends if P equals NP or not.
Rym: What if it doesn't matter?
Scott: It does matter.
Rym: What if it doesn't matter somehow?
Rym: What if quantum mechanics like quantum computing just fixes that?
Rym: We just solve everything.
Scott: But if quantum computing is there, then that then we know the answer.
Scott: That P is NP.
Scott: Otherwise, if it doesn't matter, if P is not NP, a quantum computer can help you.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.