Rym: It's Tuesday, September 6th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're back from PAX Prime 2011.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: And we're back from PAX Prime 2011.
Scott: Which means going to work.
Rym: Six months until PAX is what that means.
Scott: That's all right.
Rym: And then, six months.
Scott: So at work, we're not- Maybe less.
Scott: I was tem- they were renovating the office, stupidly, but anyway.
Scott: Enough about that.
Scott: The point is, as it relates to me, that I was temporarily moved upstairs to where they subletted part of someone else's office.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That ended.
Scott: I'm back in our office in what used to be a conference room, which is now full of desks.
Scott: And the main problem I'm having is this room is a woman.
Scott: It doesn't matter if, you know, it's 90 degrees outside.
Scott: This room has four or five people in it and air conditioning and it might as well be fucking out of space in this room.
Rym: I have not had nice things to say about any building I've worked in in the city.
Scott: It seems like the hotter it gets outside- I was fine before all this renovating happened.
Rym: The hotter it gets outside, the colder it gets inside.
Scott: Anyway, so I need, you know, I'm like, well, I'll get me a hoodie to wear at work.
Rym: What hoodie are you gonna get?
Scott: Well, I mean, I have a Mets hoodie and a Giants hoodie.
Scott: Can't really wear a Mets hoodie.
Scott: That's kind of sad.
Scott: Giants hoodie?
Scott: Well, football is starting, so I wore it today, but A, it's a thin hoodie.
Scott: It's not, you know, one of those thick ones that will really keep me warm.
Scott: And two, Giants are gonna look like they're gonna be kind of sad.
Rym: So wait, wait, wait, wait, Scott.
Rym: You're what they call a fair weather fan.
Scott: What?
Scott: No.
Rym: You're not gonna show Mets pride unless they're winning?
Scott: Well, no, listen, I'm not changing what I'm a fan of.
Rym: But you're keeping it private.
Scott: No, I'm not hiding this information.
Rym: So why will you not wear the Mets hoodie?
Rym: I mean, it's just a hoodie.
Rym: You don't care what people think of you.
Scott: It's not about what people think.
Rym: All right, then what's it about?
Scott: It is about luck.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: It's like if you have a totem for, you know, the losing God, it doesn't help.
Rym: So wait, you wearing it will give the Mets bad luck or the Mets will give you bad luck?
Scott: Both ways.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Just like you can't buy someone's jersey because it means they're gonna get injured the next week.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I have a Sergei Fedorov jersey that I got way long time ago, and he never really got injured.
Scott: Well, the best way to go is to get a jersey of someone who is awesome and is long since retired because if you buy a jersey while someone's still playing or early in the career, something's gonna happen.
Scott: It's gonna make your money a waste of money.
Scott: Right, and it's like.
Scott: even then it's like, you know, you might get something and the guy might retire afterwards and have a long good career.
Scott: and you think, "Yeah, I got my money's worth out of this jersey," and then turns out to be a criminal or something later on.
Rym: I think the most likely bad outcome is autoerotic asphyxiation.
Rym: That's also a problem.
Rym: Seems to be the going thing.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway, so I go online to look for some hoodies.
Rym: There aren't really that many good nerdy hoodies.
Scott: I went to Threadless, I went to ThinkGeek, I went to Busted Tees, I went to those people who come to PAX all the time with the BitBoy shirt with the flying Game Boy, fun something, fan gamer.
Scott: I went to them.
Scott: I went to just about every purveyor.
Scott: I went to Topatico.
Scott: I went to every purveyor of nerdy apparel that is related to the nerdies that I have.
Scott: Animes, manga, comics, video games, everything.
Scott: I could not find one hoodie that, you know, there were plenty of hoodies that, for example, I fully endorse, such as Dr.
Scott: McNinja shark high-five.
Rym: So why not get that hoodie?
Scott: Because it's kind of dorky, right?
Rym: It's not dorky if you own it.
Rym: You got to own it.
Rym: You got to double down.
Scott: If I was in high school, that'd be awesome, but it is not stylin' for wearin' in the office.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I feel like it is retro stylin', as long as you own it.
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: You can't own things?
Rym: You own the kilt?
Scott: Too many of the hoodies out there, even if they had something on them that I endorsed, did not have a high-class visual style to them.
Rym: I should simply like a very, like if I had to buy a hoodie right now, what I want is a very subtle, very classy My Little Pony design.
Rym: Like some vector art, maybe a little, like a cutie mark, and that's it.
Scott: I may invest in a solid colored hoodie, because everything else seems to be fail, and that'll be that.
Rym: I would not mind a hoodie of my current desktop background in some fashion.
Scott: It's not too bad.
Rym: Of all the Rainbow Dashes, this is my favorite right now.
Scott: But you know how Penny Arcade has that first party, which is like polo shirts with a tiny little logo on them?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right?
Scott: We need like that, but with a hoodie.
Scott: They don't make a first party hoodie.
Rym: Well, you don't really put a polo mark on a hoodie.
Scott: I'm just saying you don't do that exactly, but I'm saying that same kind of, you know, high-class style.
Rym: Maybe, maybe.
Rym: High-class hoodie.
Rym: I don't know, I bet if I looked, I could find a nice high-class hoodie.
Rym: Or, Scott, you know what a high-class garment is that you wear when you're cold and you don't want to look like a doofus?
Rym: A suit.
Scott: Yeah, not wearing a suit to work.
Rym: I wear a suit every day.
Scott: Not biking in a suit.
Rym: Leave a suit at the office.
Scott: Not going in a suit in the rain, not wearing shoes.
Rym: Leave like five suits at the office.
Scott: Where am I going to leave them?
Rym: You don't have a giant closet just for suits?
Scott: There is no closet for anything.
Scott: No one has a closet.
Scott: There are no closets.
Rym: I've never worked anywhere in my life where I didn't have a closet.
Rym: If not a personal closet, at least a shared, safe closet in a communal area.
Scott: None closets.
Rym: So, in the video game news, I've done this a couple of times in the distant past.
Rym: I want to talk about something that isn't news, that people are pretending is news because it bothers me.
Scott: That happens all the time.
Scott: Usually I'm complaining about tech news.
Scott: that's actually business news.
Rym: So, here's the thing.
Rym: It's on Slashdot.
Rym: They made the rounds about some people who played Breakout on a building.
Rym: like has been done for over a decade.
Rym: Nothing special.
Rym: But, they did it by using a Kinect.
Scott: So, which part of your body did you move to move the paddle back and forth?
Rym: Whole body.
Scott: So, you had to run back and forth?
Rym: Yeah, you got to like move your body, like lean to the left, lean to the right.
Scott: Oh, just leaning, not running?
Rym: Yeah, because they can't see you if you run.
Scott: Oh, lame.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: What if you strung up a bunch of Kinects horizontal to each other?
Rym: You'd have to write some software to handle that.
Scott: Right, and basically each Kinect would pick you up and when you got to the left of one Kinect, it would put you in there.
Rym: That might have been news.
Rym: This is making the rounds.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: I mean, playing Breakout or Pac-Man or something on the side of the building, that happens all the time.
Rym: Like, people just did that at RIT more than once.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And the Kinect part, it's like alright, you did a kind of cool but derivative thing and you simultaneously used a really crappy controller for it.
Rym: I mean, how is this making the rounds?
Rym: Like, who is impressed by this as something new or interesting?
Scott: Non-technological people.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Unsophisticated people.
Rym: That's all I got.
Rym: That's my news.
Scott: So, there's this game coming out.
Scott: It's actually out already on Xbox.
Scott: It'll be out on September 7th.
Rym: How did I not know this game was coming?
Scott: I knew it was coming, I just didn't investigate it that much.
Rym: But, like, I didn't see it at PAX.
Rym: I figured it would be there.
Scott: I also didn't see it at PAX.
Scott: I think it was there, maybe, but I didn't, anyway.
Rym: I did not see it.
Scott: I didn't see it there either.
Scott: I saw it elsewhere.
Scott: But anyway, it's called Rock of Ages.
Scott: It's going to be out on Steam on the September 7th, which it's probably already September 7th, because right now I'm talking and it's 7 o'clock on September 6th.
Scott: And the trailer for this game is unbelievable.
Rym: I don't even know if we should really say what happens in this trailer.
Scott: This is like Terry Gilliam makes a video game.
Rym: I'll put it this way.
Scott: That's some combination of Marble Madness and Defense versus Marble Madness.
Scott: You have two options here.
Scott: I don't know how it works, but it's awesome.
Rym: You've got two options.
Rym: You can either watch the trailer and then buy the game, or just buy the game.
Scott: Yeah, don't get the trial, just buy the game.
Rym: I mean, how expensive can it be?
Rym: Even if it sucks, I feel like...
Scott: It's like 9 bucks on Steam, something like that.
Rym: I feel like playing this against other people, even if it only lasts a couple days.
Scott: I wonder if they let you play it against other people.
Rym: I saw a split screen they were showing.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I was in the trailer, you showed me.
Scott: It's 9 bucks on Steam, let me get the info's here.
Rym: Yeah, because seriously, this... It's one of those games where if there is a multiplayer component, I'm pretty sure there is, it will not be played too far out into the future, most likely.
Rym: Well, I doubt it will be the best game ever.
Scott: But... A rock solid combination of rock rolling action, deep strategy, and captivating art and music from different ages of history.
Scott: This is a game of crush or be crushed.
Scott: Two castles stand opposed, one is yours, the other is your enemies.
Scott: They're a jerk, and their castle sucks, so you're gonna try to smash it using an enormous boulder.
Scott: Huh.
Scott: Single player, multiplayer, Steam, Steam, Steam, Steam, Steam.
Rym: So, let me put it this way.
Rym: It's one of those games where it may or may not be good, but even if it's bad, the week or so we're gonna get of multiplayer on.
Rym: this bullshit is gonna be awesome.
Scott: I'm definitely getting it.
Scott: Actually, I already pre-ordered it, and I'm just waiting to download it tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, so kids in the forum, we're gonna be playing this this weekend.
Scott: Probably.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: I got a quickie, actually.
Rym: I have something horrible about deep-fried bubblegum, but I figured I should save that.
Rym: Also, it kinda makes me nauseous just to think about deep-fried bubblegum as a foodie.
Scott: Wait a minute, so dig the gum before it's been chewed.
Scott: You put the funnel cake on it, so you chew it and you get the immediate funnel cake flavor, and then after that, it's like a blow pop where you chew.
Rym: So apparently it's actually marshmallow with bubblegum flavoring in it, dipped in batter, fried, covered in icing, sprinkled with powdered sugar, and I believe fried again.
Scott: So no part of it is actually bubblegum, except for bubblegum flavoring on the marshmallow.
Scott: You just eat it, you don't chew it.
Rym: It won some Texas contest for most fucked up food at a fair.
Scott: Most fucked up, but not best tasting.
Rym: Also best.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: It won the contest, which nominally was the best, but I argue is the most fucked up.
Rym: Because somehow...
Scott: It probably tastes great.
Rym: But somehow the flapjack did not win.
Scott: Just the plain old flapjack?
Rym: The buffalo chicken in a flapjack is described as, quote, "A buffalo chicken strip, coated in flapjack batter, rolled in jalapeno breadcrumbs, deep-fried, skewered, served with a side of
Rym: syrup.".
Scott: I think that if it was...
Rym: Or, fried salsa, "spicy medley of jalapenos, roasted garlic, onion, tomato, and pepper, dipped in masa, covered in tortilla chips, served on a creamy
Rym: queso.".
Scott: Here's the problem with that flapjack, is that they used a buffalo chicken in there.
Scott: If they had used, say, the Korean fried spicy chicken, I might die.
Scott: Then they would have beaten the bubblegum, marshmallow, not bubblegum.
Rym: This raises an important point.
Rym: We have not been back to that Korean fried chicken place in quite some time.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: I think we should rectify this.
Rym: Conrad's back in town.
Scott: Let's go.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So anyway, fuck that.
Rym: My real thing of the day is a very important chart of evolution of something near and dear to all of you.
Rym: The humble video game controller.
Rym: Because, as I learned when I was playing some... I did the same thing you did.
Rym: I went through the Omegathon finale to see how I could do it, and I videoed it and recorded it.
Rym: And Xbox 360 controller, even the new one, its D-pad, does not quite make it compared to the original NES Plus.
Scott: Are you blaming me being doing better than you?
Rym: I don't know if you did better.
Rym: I don't know how...
Scott: I didn't watch your video.
Scott: I did basically perfect.
Rym: In fact, the only thing that I think is unfair is that we both saw the Omegathon, so if one of us did not actually remember the way to Aquamentis, we knew it then.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: I did have a slight memory refresh from watching the Omegathon.
Rym: Because had I gone into it, not having seen the Omegathon finale, I have a feeling I would have opened one of the wrong doors with the key first, but as soon as I got in there, "Oh, fuck," and gone back.
Scott: I also knew exactly how many keys I needed and where they all were.
Rym: I feel like I would not have remembered that had I not just watched the Omegathon.
Scott: Actually...
Rym: See, I don't know.
Rym: There's the thing.
Rym: I want to say I would, but I can't say for sure.
Scott: I'm going to err on the side of caution.
Scott: when I was watching the Omegathon, I knew where to go and what to do.
Rym: Yeah, as evidenced by the yelling.
Scott: Yes, anyway.
Scott: So I was going to use ponies as my thing of the day because I've been holding out and basically ponies keep building up, but you know what?
Scott: I, at the last second, found a thing of the day classic that was never used as a thing of the day.
Rym: What?
Rym: Are you sure?
Scott: A hundred percent sure.
Scott: So, way back in the day, RIT days, we liked to play Zelda 1.
Rym: We did.
Rym: Oh, you're using this?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Really?
Rym: I'm pretty sure we talked about this.
Scott: It was not a thing of the day.
Scott: I searched.
Rym: Huh.
Scott: So anyway, so yeah, we liked to play Zelda 1 and we beat it and we liked to play Zelda 2nd Quest and we beat that.
Rym: When did you beat it?
Scott: 2nd Quest?
Rym: Yeah, as a kid?
Rym: Uh... Or did you go back and beat it later?
Scott: No, when I was a kid, I could never find level fucking 8.
Rym: Ah, I found level 8.
Rym: What I could not find at the end of the game was the fucking silver arrows.
Rym: I wrote a letter to Nintendo Power and they sent me back a full color map showing where the silver arrows were.
Scott: Nice, where's that map at?
Rym: Uh, probably in the same place that my Zelda 1 cart and everything is in Arizona.
Scott: So I polished off level 8 and whatever after internets was better one summer.
Scott: I think this summer...
Rym: Better after internets existed as far as we were concerned.
Scott: Yeah, so I was able to search and figure out where level 8 was on the internets in like summer of '01, '02, something like that when I was home.
Scott: Anyway, uh... When was... I don't know.
Scott: I definitely was at home summer after college.
Scott: Anyway, there was a mod for Zelda 1.
Scott: Basically, the way this works is you download a legit rom of regular old Zelda 1. then you download this other thing and it patches the rom and it makes a new Zelda game called The Legend of Zelda Outlands AKA Zelda Sea AKA Zelda Challenge Outland.
Scott: AKA Fuck This Game Fuck This Game Fuck This Game, Fuck This Game.
Scott: So, we downloaded this game way back in the day when it first came out and we tried to play it at RIT on our emulators in like '02, '03 and you couldn't even get past like three screens of overworld.
Rym: I remember going into this at RIT, we were like "Yeah, we're good at video games.
Rym: Let's
Rym: go.".
Rym: And I go up and there's no old man to give me a sword and I didn't know what to do.
Rym: and then I wandered around dying until eventually I run into Zelda who says, and I quote "It's me, Zelda.
Rym: I found your
Rym: sword.".
Scott: I like it when you go to a Goron and he's like "We Gorons have rock bottom
Scott: prices.".
Scott: Ah, ah, ah, ah.
Scott: But yeah, no, it's a real... This game is basically...
Rym: This is a triumph of ROM hacking.
Scott: It's impossible Zelda.
Scott: They may... If you're out there thinking "Man, I wish there was... Nintendo would make a game just like Zelda 1 but, you know, was just a new Zelda 1.
Scott: Well, that game exists.
Scott: Zelda Sea.
Scott: It's hard as balls.
Rym: I would simply argue that while it's hard as balls and it is kind of fun Zelda 1 second quest was not as good a game as Zelda 1 first quest because there were more arbitrary bullshit secrets.
Scott: Walk into this wall.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now you didn't just have to bomb every wall.
Rym: You had to bomb every wall and walk into every wall.
Scott: It has the Wolfenstein 3D aspect of touch every wall.
Rym: Which...
Scott: At least in Zelda there's only four per room.
Rym: What amazes me is that now I think about that I'm like "Oh, really?
Rym: Uhhh.".
Rym: And I'm going around like pushing against every wall because I don't fucking remember the second quest worth anything.
Scott: Just bring a...
Rym: But... I'm not going to read a fact.
Rym: No.
Rym: Because I am playing the second quest right now.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: I got almost one piece of the Triforce.
Scott: Great.
Scott: It's easy to get one piece.
Rym: And not as easy as you'd think though.
Scott: It's not the one piece it's a one piece.
Rym: You walk into that one room and there's a bunch of staff flows.
Rym: staff
Rym: flows.".
Scott: And then the Gibdo in the first dungeon.
Rym: Does like four hearts of damage against my three hearts of life.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Nevermind the blue... Well, anyway.
Rym: But, uh, I don't know.
Rym: when I was a kid when I learned from a friend that you could just push through some walls and walk through them instead of getting angry I got excited and I went back home and gleefully for the next like seven hours pushed against every wall in every dungeon just to see.
Scott: But now it's like Ugh.
Rym: I don't know what trigger in my brain flipped from "This is awesome" to "Fuck
Rym: this."
Rym: To like...
Scott: I think what it is is that when you're a kid right the reward of discovery of secrets is like so great.
Scott: Like just discovering a hidden thing is just like so magical that you don't even notice the work you put in to finding it.
Scott: Whereas now it's not like it's totally demystified and there's no magic of discovery because we know it's there and it's just the manual labor that we had to put into.
Scott: it is so monotonous and mind-numbing right?
Scott: Because we were smarter that what, you know, that work as a kid.
Scott: I guess to a kid it doesn't feel as monotonous and mind-numbing because your mind isn't numbed yet.
Scott: To us it's like repetitive monotonous manual labor.
Rym: There's more to it than that.
Rym: It also just comes down to the fact that it was exploration and there was no other option.
Rym: I mean back then I'm searching around Zelda and there's no one to tell me where anything is.
Rym: There's no game facts.
Rym: So everything I discovered was like social currency.
Rym: You could go to friends when you were a kid when we were growing up and say things like "I found a fucking secret that you don't know about and they wouldn't believe
Rym: you."
Rym: And you'd take them home and you'd show it to them and they'd flip their shit.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Like I remember showing a kid that mine is world.
Scott: Kids now can't even do that.
Rym: There was this like legends would rise.
Rym: I mean remember like a classic example.
Rym: You can totally bring General Leo back from the dead.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: You can totally bring Parham and Parham back from the dead.
Rym: Totally bring Telos back from the dead.
Rym: Spoilers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean the mine is world was crazy enough, right?
Scott: People would talk about it and you'd have a friend who had read it in a Nintendo Power or something but then couldn't do it so you wouldn't believe him.
Rym: And kids would make shit up.
Rym: I had one friend who kept saying he jumped over the flagpole.
Scott: I had plenty of friends who would be like, "Yeah, Mortal Kombat 2.
Scott: I was in the arcade watching some dude play and you saw Sonya's tits.
Rym: Oh
Rym: man.".
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So Zelda C, I dare you to fucking play this shit.
Rym: I dare you to.
Rym: I don't even dare you to beat it because that's not fair.
Rym: That's like daring someone.
Rym: I dare you to even find the first dungeon.
Rym: It's telling that in the screenshots they got here it shows three games.
Rym: You know how?
Rym: in Zelda the number under your name is the number of times you've died?
Rym: It shows someone with some items who may have beaten the game.
Rym: He's died 93 times.
Rym: I in Zelda Second Quest am almost at the Triforce and I've died three times.
Rym: So very briefly the meta moment.
Rym: All you new listeners from PAX.
Rym: This is where we do all the announcements about the show and community shit that you might not care about.
Scott: You got any?
Rym: We do.
Rym: The book club book is The Ear, The Eye, The Arm.
Scott: Have you read it yet?
Rym: It hasn't arrived yet.
Rym: It shipped so I'll have it soon.
Rym: It's a short read.
Rym: I'll read it as soon as I get it.
Scott: We'll do the episode real soon because we plan to do one a month and it's already the second month.
Rym: We'll let it go a month and then we'll be good.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: We're doing a worst webcomic contest.
Scott: We're going to do that real soon.
Rym: It's pretty much over.
Scott: Like next week.
Rym: Unless there's a webcomic that you really really hate.
Rym: that isn't control alt delete because that's already been submitted a bunch of times.
Rym: Then there'll be a link to it.
Rym: Otherwise if you saw us at PAX and you wanted more of what you saw two of our lectures soon to be three from PAX East 2011 are up on YouTube and I will link to them.
Scott: All right.
Scott: You should go to our internets in general frontroadcrew.com, Facebook, Twitter, etc.
Rym: All that stuff.
Rym: Also if you were talking to us about ponies you might want to know that we did a pilot of a show called Radio Free Equestria and many of you have been bothering me.
Scott: understand that was a pilot and they're like where is there more episodes?
Rym: I get so much shit about that show every day.
Rym: When's it coming?
Rym: these people found my email address.
Scott: How do you know it's even coming?
Rym: So it's coming.
Rym: Just hold tight you bronies.
Rym: And last but not least many people relative to how many I expected which was zero came up to us at PAX and said oh my god you guys should have been at PAX dev.
Rym: So if you were one of those people you should tell the Penny Arcade people and then we will present at PAX dev.
Scott: And Rym do something about merch.
Rym: I got to make some more merch.
Rym: One of the constants in my life one of the most not the most important things but something that keeps me going every day that I always think about is that every six months at most I get to go to PAX.
Rym: Aww shit.
Rym: I really like you know we've been going to conventions for a long time.
Scott: It's like going to mecha only and twice as often.
Rym: I mean it's interesting that the newness twice is close.
Rym: The newness has faded like the first PAX we went to was kind of hard to replicate because it's like when you're a kid go to that first old account you walk into that dealer's room and you just have like.
Rym: you can't believe it.
Rym: And the first PAX was kind of like that.
Rym: and now we're older we've gone to many PAXes many PAXes and yet the wonder is still there.
Rym: it's just kind of shifted into different directions.
Scott: is it's like you know there?
Scott: it's like imagine that there was an amusement park with a bunch of roller coasters right and it opened.
Scott: and but it's only open for two three days.
Scott: So you go and you ride as many rides as you can.
Scott: then it closes.
Scott: next year it opens for exactly three days.
Scott: So you go back and you ride as many rides as you can but the rides you got enough of the first time you maybe don't pay much attention to.
Rym: But now you're riding the rides that were there last year that you didn't ride quite so much.
Scott: Right I mean even if there's an amusement park that's open every single day of the year most people only go to it once a year at most right usually less often than that.
Scott: So it's like you keep going back to the same amusement park every single year.
Scott: eventually it's like I've ridden all these before even though they're still pretty great.
Scott: maybe I'll ride it again if I haven't done it in a few years.
Rym: But you might go chill.
Rym: when I was a little kid and I go to Cedar Point I would see like the shows like I'd be walking I'd be running not walking on my way to get in line for a roller coaster and I'd see like oh there's some like live music in that restaurant.
Rym: who the fuck would go into that restaurant and waste five minutes when they could be in line for a roller coaster.
Scott: Someone who's ridden that roller coaster 20 times.
Rym: Yeah 10 years later I was in that restaurant watching the live show.
Rym: So if you want to hear you know the full review of PAX as a convention listen to all our other PAX episodes because all that stuff really doesn't change.
Rym: we're only going to talk about the things that were unique that we experienced at this PAX.
Scott: So the one thing I noticed overall at this PAX Prime 2011 right?
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Was it seemed like I don't want.
Scott: I'm not saying Penny Arcade sold out right?
Scott: I mean if you're going to say Penny Arcade sold out you'd have to say that when Robert Coop first came on and they started selling ads.
Rym: Well here, let's qualify this even broader and I said this to Aaron C. and a couple other people too because I think it's very apt.
Rym: Whenever we criticize PAX the criticisms added up kind of round down to zero compared to you know all the positives.
Rym: we don't always talk about because they're given like I very rarely think to say I played a thousand games because that's just a given like.
Rym: yeah of course it's PAX.
Rym: I played a bunch of games.
Rym: Instead I say I saw a star.
Rym: We'll talk about the stars in a bit.
Scott: So you know obviously you can't say Penny Arcade is sold out but PAX was sold a little bit more than it has been in the past right?
Rym: But the majority of it did not affect the convention.
Rym: it was all surface stuff like Firefall.
Rym: That game can't be good and my rationale for saying it's not good is that they I think spent more money on advertising at PAX than everybody else combined spent on advertising.
Scott: Pretty much it's like you know.
Scott: usually each per each company that wants to sell something sponsors one thing right?
Scott: So you know Dragon Age will get the hotel key cards and someone else will get the big banners hanging on the ceiling and someone else will get the bags and somebody else will get the stickers on the escalator and someone else will have the biggest booth
Rym: in the expo home.
Rym: stickers on escalators before.
Scott: Yeah someone you know each different company.
Scott: someone will have a car that drives around town advertising their game.
Rym: Firefall had the equivalent of one guy following every individual attendee around yelling Firefall!
Scott: Firefall!
Scott: Every single right?
Scott: Now on top of that you had Halo Fest which is an entire gigantic space of the convention devoted to one game series.
Rym: Here's the thing I can't.
Rym: I don't want to be down on it for the wrong reasons.
Scott: It was their anniversary and I doubt they'll do it again.
Rym: No but I'm saying I don't want to be down on it for the wrong reasons.
Rym: For example had that been Counter Strike Fest I would have thought it was awesome.
Rym: From the perspective of people who like Halo that was awesome.
Rym: My complaint about Halo Fest is only that Halo Fest itself did not do much.
Rym: If it was Counter Strike Fest and I went up to it and it had the equivalent content of Halo Fest it would have been.
Rym: it would have gotten like a six out of ten like all right.
Rym: that was cool.
Rym: It wasn't worth the amount of space it took up though.
Scott: Yeah that space could have been used for the convention but I'm sure Microsoft paid a lot of money for it.
Rym: Mainly because they had a private VIP party for much of Saturday night.
Rym: Or Friday night Friday night.
Scott: There were other you know just little things about for example the Penny Arcade merch booth.
Scott: right.
Scott: As every PAX have ever been to including East.
Scott: the way it's worked is they were always bundle deals right.
Scott: The way the bundle works is like t-shirt this much money.
Scott: poster this much money.
Scott: Hey if you get a t-shirt and a poster it's less than the price of both of those separately.
Scott: This year they changed that.
Scott: Now the way it worked was hey spend if you spent everything is the price it is.
Scott: if you spend at least 50 bucks we'll give you this patch.
Scott: If you spend 70 bucks we'll give you this other thing.
Scott: I sell you this hat five dollar.
Scott: The only thing I wanted was a twenty dollar shirt.
Rym: But you thought about buying something more.
Scott: Well I wanted the patch.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But I didn't want to spend any more money.
Scott: So I didn't get the patch.
Rym: You know what that's called?
Rym: It's called mechanism fucking design.
Rym: We've done panels on that.
Scott: But you know it's just.
Scott: it was a change that was you know in the money making department.
Rym: However that didn't bother me that much because I.
Scott: No I'm not saying it bothered me.
Scott: I'm just saying that that was.
Scott: one of the trends of this year's packs was a slight amount of outselling.
Rym: But we have to say again rounds down to zero for example New York Comic-Con.
Scott: They expanded the size of the expo hall in general.
Rym: Yeah the fact that there were two expo halls was a little much but there was actually a lot going on in the expo hall.
Rym: If you had removed all the Firefall content from the expo hall they would have only needed one.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Meanwhile if you had removed the halo first.
Rym: Alright so Firefall has like this gigantic booth.
Rym: up for?
Rym: Borderlands 2.
Rym: And Counter Strike Go.
Rym: That's where the line was.
Scott: Counter Strike Go, Borderlands 2 these were the kinds of things that had gigantic lines.
Scott: In the Zelda game on the Wii the Skyward Sword it had lines but not like the lines for the other things.
Scott: I think it's just because they had so many stations and I think part of it right is that some of these games what they do for example Counter Strike Go it's they bring in X number of people on two teams.
Scott: they play X rounds you know one or two how many rounds and then you leave and then new people come in.
Rym: Though we had an awesome moment.
Scott: Right where Zelda Skyward Sword they're these self running demo stations.
Scott: you walk up you play as long as you're gonna play and then you walk away.
Scott: So it's like some people walk up for two seconds and leave.
Scott: so you know.
Scott: that's why they don't need this big line up.
Scott: I think they'd be a lot better off the Counter Strike guys.
Scott: they wouldn't have this big line building up if you could just walk up play Counter Strike walk away.
Rym: Well what they need to do?
Rym: Spy Party.
Rym: they really know what's up.
Rym: they had three stations.
Rym: one was I've never played Spy Party before and I don't know what the deal is one was.
Scott: Well and I've read the manual the dead little blue manuals you had to read before you could play.
Rym: The second one was I know what's up.
Rym: and the third one was I somehow have played this game as much as someone who will buy this game has played it.
Scott: Yeah the thing has already signed up for the beta so I don't need to play it.
Rym: Yeah but once again just to point out the main person behind Spy Party knows what's up.
Scott: Yeah Chris Hecker is the smartest dude.
Rym: I actually talked to him this We talked to him just to be like look you're one of the few people we've ever seen on a panel at a convention like PAX who had any relation to game design and or journalism who knew what was up.
Scott: Yeah anything he does keep an eye on.
Rym: Like he's on the short list.
Scott: Just like you should keep an eye on the guy who does Space Chem.
Rym: Yup yup.
Rym: Or Monaco.
Rym: Monaco is up there.
Scott: The Monaco guy the Jason Rohrer guy.
Rym: Though we had a cool moment we were walking you know around in the expo hall.
Rym: we saw this guy with a really awesome like Counter Strike jersey kind of shirt.
Scott: Yeah it was like a bowling shirt but it said Counter Strike.
Rym: We're like what up awesome shirt.
Rym: where'd you get it?
Rym: and the guy's like I made Counter Strike.
Scott: He didn't make Counter Strike but he was a guy who.
Rym: That's what he said.
Rym: he's like I made Counter Strike but like what he's like.
Rym: well I you know.
Scott: He's been working on Counter Strike for a few years right?
Scott: so like he was cool.
Scott: He was a cool dude.
Scott: he was actually older like he must have been 40 or 50 something right.
Scott: But he worked on Counter Strike.
Scott: I was like damn thanks.
Scott: Counter Strike's awesome.
Rym: I didn't play Counter Strike at the Con we could have.
Scott: I looked over someone else's shoulder while they played it.
Rym: We were offered by multiple people.
Scott: An Xbox controller.
Rym: To skip to the front of the line.
Rym: but they only had Xbox controllers.
Rym: I don't really care.
Rym: The game looked like Counter Strike.
Rym: the only thing that didn't look right was that everybody playing was kind of the slow turret turn.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The I have an Xbox controller turn.
Scott: Yeah where it sort of has like this motion blur and there's like a little time.
Rym: People weren't really looking up and down so much.
Rym: They were kind of sweeping left and right at head level.
Scott: Yeah something like that.
Rym: Yeah there's one guy though.
Rym: I kept seeing him jump down from above and no one ever saw him because they never looked up and just stabbing people.
Rym: That guy knew what was up.
Scott: Yeah well he knew what was down the other guy.
Rym: The other guy didn't know what was up.
Scott: Yeah I saw some people who knew I talked to this guy.
Scott: I just you know I was standing there watching other people play Counter Strike you know just looking over their shoulder.
Scott: Yeah some guy next to me was doing the same thing.
Scott: You know we chatted up.
Scott: He was a nice guy just random con goer and he talked about like.
Scott: yeah he's been playing Counter Strike since source.
Scott: And I was like.
Rym: it's like we went to that panel at Magfest.
Rym: the guys like I've been playing D&D for a long time.
Rym: I started with you know third edition.
Scott: Man.
Rym: Ah we're old now.
Rym: We're those guys.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So I think the game I'm most excited about that I didn't know about pre packs was a game called Aramac.
Scott: I played Aramac for like a good 10 minutes while talking to one of the guys who worked on it.
Scott: And like it's.
Scott: basically it's an action robotron plus RTS.
Scott: It was.
Scott: it was great.
Scott: Only later and I was like comparing it to all these other games.
Scott: But only later did I realize that it's basically modern Herzog Zwee or Zwei or however he's supposed to say it.
Rym: I had heard I heard that word.
Rym: I'd seen those.
Scott: I knew that Herzog Zwei was a Genesis game but I didn't realize looking at Aramac that it was Herzog Zwei because I never played a lot of Herzog Zwei.
Scott: But now I do know.
Scott: But yeah Aramac looks hot.
Rym: It looks like it has.
Rym: everything I like about RTS is without all the stuff I hate about RTS.
Scott: I played it for a long time.
Scott: I'm sold.
Scott: when it comes out I'm gonna pay for it.
Rym: And actually World of Tanks despite my some issues I take with the business model and you know the design and everything.
Rym: It looks actually really fun.
Scott: I installed the demo disc that came in the goodie bag.
Scott: I'm going to try it out tonight.
Rym: They also had a German tank like a real one at the con and that was actually pretty cool.
Rym: It was cool.
Scott: Tank.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well they kept pointing it to people in the eye in the crowd like that that the gun they burned around.
Rym: There's a pretty great picture of me.
Rym: They gave me the shell to hold on to.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So you know the the the cornerstones of every packs.
Rym: There's three.
Rym: There's like three that you have to see.
Rym: One is the concerts which we don't have to see anymore.
Rym: Seen a million.
Rym: It starts with the keynote.
Rym: It ends with the omega finale and no offense to Jaffe.
Rym: This is the worst packs keynote I've ever seen.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean it started out.
Scott: you know like I David Jaffe.
Scott: All I knew about him was that he was an outspoken sort of Internet gaming personality and that he had worked on Twisted Metal which is the PlayStation game where you drive around in the clown car shooting other cars.
Scott: Great game.
Scott: It's like versus 3D spa.
Scott: Spy Hunter not spy party.
Scott: And I knew that he worked on God of War which is a Greek styling.
Scott: you know action puzzly game with the third person camera walk around and hit things.
Rym: But I tweeted about it.
Rym: I'm not going to wait.
Rym: But at one point I was just like is this going anywhere?
Rym: because basically he just swore a whole bunch and he had a message.
Rym: he actually had a couple of really good messages like they are inspiring important messages but they were buried in a sea of obscenity personal rants that no one cares about personal drama and name dropping.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like he pretty much told like his story of his career from his perspective you know and like what he went through to get from you know work.
Rym: He went on forever about a lawsuit that really was not relevant.
Scott: Yeah he like complained about the time he was sued a lot and he complained about like other people doubting him.
Rym: and he complained about everything.
Rym: And I don't know I was just.
Rym: it wasn't inspiring it was kind of rambly and ranty it was.
Rym: I was really underwhelmed.
Rym: It was the first time ever I've not been almost choked up by a keynote at PAX.
Rym: I mean you know even Will Wheaton got me a little choked up even though he played the woo game.
Rym: That's all he did.
Rym: Yeah but still it was a very.
Rym: it was kind of an inspiring talk.
Rym: He was like look this made us who we are.
Rym: gaming makes us who we are.
Rym: let's celebrate the shit out of this.
Scott: I still think the best one that I've seen so far that I was at was the guy who worked at Lucas Arts.
Rym: Oh yeah well he gave a really solid speech.
Scott: What was his name?
Rym: Also got me really choked up.
Rym: Jane McGonigal got me the most choked up.
Scott: Really choked up?
Scott: I think hers was great but I wasn't choked up.
Rym: No just I got a little like not choked up like not like watching Madoka but more like.
Rym: I was really like inspired and I just I thought about her speech a lot after I listened to it.
Rym: The only thing I remember from Jeffrey's speech is fuck shit fuck ass vagina.
Scott: I don't mind swearing swear away right.
Scott: But look at the Penny Arcade guys.
Scott: they swear but they're not just saying nothing but swears right.
Scott: It's like it wasn't?
Scott: it doesn't matter.
Scott: he could have been saying some other word he could have been saying fufu but he said that you know it's like if you use any word repeatedly too many times no matter if it's a swear word or not.
Scott: That's you know it's like what.
Rym: About the only thing he had right was that he talked about how he realized eventually like in the course of all his work and everything that the games that actually remembered and that are actually popular and that are really good games from any kind of reasonably objective standard are the ones that are actually games.
Scott: Yeah that was what.
Scott: the only thing that I was pleased about was how you know this is one of those guys who wanted to go and be a filmmaker right but ended up being a game maker instead and wanted to be a visual storyteller couldn't get that job you know but could get a game making job but ended up making games that were mostly movies you know full of FMV's and story and whatnot.
Scott: you know and that's you know the God of War and all that stuff.
Scott: So but the fact that that person realized that the games that are basically movies that you push buttons sometimes don't really have the staying power right and that the games of the staying power are the games that are games the Tetris the Sims.
Scott: you know you may not like some of these games but these are the staying power games.
Rym: Oh here it is.
Scott: The fact that he learned the lesson that we've been trying to teach people is reassuring.
Rym: So here's first I tweeted I'm like Jeff you said a new world record for the use of the word fuck vagina and fucking in a fax keynote and then a bunch of other stuff.
Rym: and finally I'm like fuck fucking mother fucker shit Sony vagina fuck lawsuit high concept.
Rym: he said that like a hundred times fucking game mechanics fuck and people were quoting that as a summary of the keynote which is a pretty accurate summary.
Scott: Yeah so I think you know pecs.
Scott: there's plenty of people out there that will write notes that will write here some.
Scott: whatever it takes to get well right here are some suggestions will write.
Rym: well right.
Scott: I don't know what kind of person he is.
Scott: You know what.
Rym: But what.
Rym: Get me a motto to do it.
Scott: He can't speak English.
Rym: Who cares?
Rym: translator?
Rym: I don't care.
Scott: Another good choice would be.
Scott: I don't know how you know how good his speaking skills are but you know in terms of accomplishments someone like Richard Garfield.
Rym: I'd like to hear what Richard Garfield has to say.
Scott: Who invented Magic the Gathering.
Rym: Among other things.
Rym: it's not his only claim to fame.
Scott: Right?
Scott: someone like the guy who made Outlaw and found that Activision made Pitfall that we talked about.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: What about Yoichi Arakawa aka Ko Shibuusawa.
Rym: I'd like to hear what he has to say.
Scott: If he's good at it.
Scott: You know there's plenty of people out there who have made you know great games and are very important people in the world of gaming that you didn't haven't had done keynotes that could go ahead of someone like David.
Rym: I didn't know anything about Jaffe other than what he'd made going in and sorry dude but I kind of see why a lot of people hate on you.
Rym: That was really uninspiring.
Scott: You should work on that.
Rym: But the Pinairgate Q&A is worth mentioning because one our friend Timo from Finland.
Scott: He scored an A+ at Q&A Ask.
Rym: He goes up there.
Rym: It's on YouTube.
Rym: But he basically is like.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I have the official Pax Candy.
Rym: He has this candy from Scandinavia.
Rym: This is Pax.
Scott: Finland.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well Scandinavia.
Rym: Where is Finland?
Rym: In Scandinavia.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: He also had some Salmiakki.
Rym: You can figure out on your own what that is.
Rym: And he made them play Paper, Rock, Scissors to see who got to eat which one.
Rym: And to their credit they followed through.
Rym: More importantly Mike and Jerry, Gabe and Taiko.
Rym: They've gone through a long journey I think of being.
Rym: You know the personalities that they are making the comic becoming kind of the rock stars of nerds.
Rym: It is really to their credit how good they have gotten at entertaining a crowd.
Scott: Mike's sort of the same as he always was.
Scott: But Jerry definitely you know I've seen he's leveled up like Jerry.
Scott: I've seen him Q&A a bunch of times in a row now twice a year.
Scott: I see him do this.
Scott: And this time he was at least one or two levels above the last time he did it.
Scott: Or any previous time I've seen him before.
Rym: To a degree that almost hurt on multiple occasions in the Q&A.
Scott: His A-ing skills at the Q-ing have increased greatly.
Scott: He is now you know epic level at the Q&A.
Scott: I can't wait to see if he maintains that epic level at East.
Rym: I don't think he can not maintain it.
Scott: Yeah he's definitely.
Scott: you know Mike's definitely got to up his game in some way.
Scott: You know he's Mike.
Scott: He's got a good game.
Scott: He is how he is.
Scott: He's still a good game.
Scott: But he's not.
Scott: He's got.
Scott: if he leveled up it would be so epic.
Rym: Mike's like.
Rym: he's got like a B6 at this but Jerry's just got.
Rym: he's got G now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know what to do about it.
Scott: I don't know either.
Rym: If he goes white shade everyone will just empty their bottles simultaneously.
Scott: Well you won't even need questions anymore.
Scott: He'll just stand there.
Rym: He'll just be stand up comedy for an hour.
Scott: He won't even be stand up comedy.
Scott: he'll just answer the questions that you were going to ask.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So you know last year I asked about ponies and I was like I should mess with him again.
Scott: Someone else did the ponies.
Rym: Yeah ponies were like.
Scott: There are a lot of ponies at PAX.
Rym: Usually.
Rym: Lots.
Rym: Last PAX.
Rym: Look how rapidly this has escalated.
Rym: Me and Scott were the only ones really pushing ponies.
Scott: At PAX East.
Rym: Like we played the PMV.
Rym: We mentioned ponies in the panel.
Rym: I asked about ponies in the Q&A.
Scott: Well it's just because we're ahead of the geek curve right.
Scott: We read the Internet almost every day.
Scott: We're so awesome.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And we look at the Internet and we see what's hot and we explore down every path and we explore in many different geekeries not just tech.
Scott: Dude by the time.
Scott: Not just gaming not just comics.
Scott: not you know.
Rym: we got by the time we covered it out.
Rym: We had already made a pilot of a show called Radio Free Equestria exactly on YouTube.
Scott: So it's like we're ahead of every curve.
Scott: But you know and it's like we were playing DDR and then everyone was playing DDR and we're watching ponies.
Scott: then everyone's playing.
Scott: If you want to make investment decisions just listen to whatever we talk about that isn't popular yet and assume it's going to be popular.
Rym: So apparently farts.
Scott: No.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: So big.
Rym: We're also really behind the curve or at least we're holders because we played Counter Strike before most people played it.
Rym: You still play it after most people don't play it anymore.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: But it's comeback.
Rym: We like the ponies were everywhere.
Rym: I didn't have to say a goddamn thing about ponies at this whole convention.
Rym: Ponies.
Rym: Someone brought an eight foot tall like Pinkie Pie just like at to the convention.
Scott: I didn't see it but I saw a video of it.
Scott: There are pony cosplayers.
Scott: There's a lot of button.
Scott: ears had pony buttons.
Rym: There was a derpy hooves in the maker strip.
Scott: That's two maker strips in a row where we've added ponies.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: What the fuck guys.
Rym: Two maker strips.
Rym: There's only two of these a year and we are now batting a thousand.
Scott: We need to.
Rym: And neither one of these was us.
Rym: It was not me or Scott getting this in there.
Rym: This is just unrelated.
Scott: We did not push any pony.
Scott: But meanwhile the Unicorn Theater had ponies outside of it.
Scott: So did the Manicourt Theater.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The enforcers were like pony fucking central.
Scott: Everybody pony in.
Scott: Every day they pony in.
Rym: I don't know what to do about it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: More hustling.
Scott: Less ponying.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Season two's coming.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'm not going to say anything else about that.
Rym: So we did one panel.
Rym: It was an okay panel.
Rym: It was an experiment.
Rym: And we tried it out.
Rym: I learned a lot about how to do that kind of panel.
Rym: And if we ever do.
Scott: I thought we would be spending a lot more time actually playing the games but.
Rym: I think we would have if we had fewer games to play.
Scott: I think if we actually would have been better off with more games to play.
Rym: I think it would have been fewer.
Rym: but we should have had a match or bring some of them to the audience.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: We could have brought people from the audience to actually play it.
Rym: Panel was okay.
Rym: But the thing I really want to talk about because this was an experiment for PEX.
Rym: They did the tabletop workshops and the GMing workshops area.
Rym: So we went up and for two hours we took over the room.
Rym: We videoed it.
Rym: And we taught everyone in there how to play Carcassonne, Puerto Rico and Seven Wonders.
Rym: And the people there loved it.
Rym: I think it was a great thing.
Scott: There were very few people.
Scott: And it was in a hidden room.
Scott: It was not in any schedule.
Scott: So I'm amazed.
Scott: anyone showed up.
Scott: But the fact that people showed up stayed and totally dug it.
Rym: Of course.
Scott: What was funny meant that our idea was actually a good idea.
Scott: It was a good test of our idea.
Rym: Prove that it was worthwhile.
Rym: together.
Rym: They really put all the effort in.
Rym: They did everything right.
Rym: And we're talking to help out.
Scott: They actually showed up with the games we needed.
Rym: We're talking to help them out and do this ten times over at PAX East if we can.
Rym: Hope so.
Rym: But the funny and sad part was that at the end of the session we're like, "Yeah, so how many of you know who we
Rym: are?"
Rym: And everyone's like,
Rym: "Yeah.".
Scott: That was kind of sad.
Scott: is that at our panel, which is a little more than half full, I was like, "Who knows who we
Scott: are?".
Scott: And most people knew who we were.
Rym: It was like,
Rym: "Ugh.".
Rym: I know.
Rym: It used to be like no one knew who we were and by the end they're like fawning over us.
Rym: Now it's like we got this GeekNights fan base at PAX.
Scott: We got to change the name of the panel to get people who don't know who we are to show up.
Rym: Well, I'm going to tell you guys a secret right now.
Rym: There's a good chance the panel we're going to do, at least our new panel at PAX East, I'm going to lay an egg out right now.
Rym: It's called Let's Play Money Making Game.
Scott: We should just, in the description, be like, "Come to this panel.
Scott: You might make
Scott: money.".
Rym: I think we should say, "Or pay me for the
Rym: door.".
Rym: That's the whole description.
Scott: Pay me for the door repair charge.
Scott: Come to this panel, pay for the door repair charge.
Scott: Maybe walk out with cash.
Rym: But so the table that works out there really well, but even at that, everyone there knew who he works with except one guy.
Rym: So we're like, "Yeah, so if you guys like this, check out Geek
Rym: Nights.".
Rym: Everyone's like, "Yeah, yeah, whatever,
Rym: blah.".
Rym: One guy's like,
Rym: "What?".
Rym: It was just kind of funny.
Rym: But our panel wasn't full.
Rym: The whole back of the room was Didn't feel like any of the panels were full.
Scott: People kept lining up for panels, but then the panel room would not be full once people went in.
Rym: I was talking to a lot of enforcers about this, and yeah, panel attendance is down except for the things that always fill up.
Rym: So all the Penny Arcade stuff.
Scott: Well, there are more panel rooms.
Rym: But the Penny Arcade stuff fills no matter what room they put it And the rooms are bigger.
Rym: The Penny Arcade-ish or related or like the same level stuff, like Wil Wheaton does a panel, it'll fill up.
Rym: Or they do like the D&D game they play.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That stuff is filled up.
Scott: That stuff all fills.
Rym: As are the panels for games that people really fucking care about.
Scott: Like, "Oh my God, this panel is where...".
Scott: What was that?
Scott: I think like Borderlands 2.
Scott: Didn't they give everyone like beta codes or something like that?
Rym: I heard the "Pitch Your Game" panel fills up and still fills up, but that's apparently really participatory and really funny and people enjoy it.
Rym: But most of the panels at PAX don't fill up anymore.
Rym: And I think, personally, this is my opinion, is because, one, most of the panels are kind of the same every year.
Rym: Like, "Oh, here's the panel about girls and
Rym: gaming.".
Rym: The panel goes like this, "Hey, there's girls who play games.
Rym: Don't be hating on us.
Rym: Don't be ragging on
Rym: us.".
Rym: Like, yeah.
Rym: Bring something else to the table.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: We've talked about that before.
Rym: We don't need to talk about it again.
Scott: No, one thing I do want to talk about, which I made a YouTube video talking about, was the Omegathon finale, right?
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: So the Omegathon is always awesome.
Scott: I'm going to keep my "Rock 'Em Suck 'Em Robots" guess until it happens.
Rym: I will maintain "Crossfire" just because.
Scott: You got to know
Scott: "Crossfire.".
Rym: If they play that song, people will lose their goddamn shit.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: But anyway.
Rym: Sorry, wait, wait.
Rym: To Jaffeize that.
Rym: Goddamn motherfucking vagina ass fuck shit.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So, Omegathon finale.
Scott: We line up.
Scott: We get in there.
Scott: We're sitting pretty high up.
Scott: We can see well enough.
Scott: The big reveal comes.
Scott: You know, final countdown.
Scott: Bring out two Omeganauts.
Scott: They look high quality.
Scott: Omeganauts.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Most of the Omegathon games that year were mostly skill-based.
Scott: Very, very good.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Bananagrams, yo.
Scott: Bananagrams, excellent choice.
Rym: Also, the Omegathon finale is in the Paramount Theater, which is nice.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: It is a choice venue.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So, reveal comes.
Scott: Not Rock 'Em Sock 'Em Robots.
Scott: Not Crossfire.
Rym: Zelda 1.
Rym: Now, at this point, you know, it's something very important.
Scott: Everyone, as soon as that music plays, everyone is just like, "Fuck
Scott: yes.".
Rym: The reason to be at the Omegathon finale is just for the way the crowd reacts.
Rym: You know, at the end of a tied hockey game for the Stanley Cup, the way the crowd is standing up and yelling, you get that about a video game.
Rym: So, Zelda 1.
Scott: Oh, shit, son.
Scott: It is on.
Scott: How do you win?
Scott: First person to get a Triforce fragment wins, which is understandable considering the time constraints, right?
Scott: So, but then, something else happened, right?
Scott: They were like, you know, before they revealed the game, they asked the Omeganauts to choose from amongst the failed Omeganauts.
Rym: For a spirit animal.
Scott: For a spirit animal, a spirit guide to assist them.
Scott: So, that was like, oh, is this gonna be co-op?
Scott: They gave these people-- It's gonna be doubles Mario Tennis.
Rym: They gave these people facts.
Scott: Well, after the reveal of Zelda 1, they said, so I'm like, well, if it's Zelda 1 and it's first to get a Triforce fragment-- Blindfolded?
Scott: What is the spirit animal for?
Scott: What is the spirit guide for?
Scott: And we're thinking, blindfolded Zelda 1, blindfolded Zelda 1, fuck yes, fuck yes, fuck.
Scott: yes.
Scott: It wasn't blindfolded.
Scott: They gave the spirit animal a fact to guide the player.
Scott: Now, this is understandable because let's say neither person knew Zelda 1.
Scott: They were nubs who'd never played it before, right?
Scott: In that case, we would've been there for hours.
Scott: What if they went left?
Scott: What if they went right?
Scott: So, Scott.
Scott: They would've died a hundred times.
Scott: They might never have found the first Triforce piece without that map that comes with the game.
Rym: This is why that's bullshit.
Rym: They shouldn't have given the people a fact.
Rym: them the Zelda 1 instruction book.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: Zelda 1 instruction book and the map that came with Zelda 1.
Rym: Because that would've been enough and that would've been cool.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I want to point out something.
Rym: The contest was get a piece of the Triforce.
Rym: I feel like had I been up there, this would've been a disaster.
Rym: done.
Rym: guy and said, "Dungeon
Rym: 2?".
Rym: And then I would've gotten it, but I would've gone to Dungeon 1 anyway.
Scott: Yeah, it's a trip to Japan is on the line.
Scott: You can't go to Dungeon 2.
Rym: Saying Dungeon 2 does not say I'm going to Dungeon 2.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, maybe the guy would agree to go to Dungeon 2.
Rym: Well then you got to do it.
Scott: You got to get bombs though.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or they could've been like, they could've just gone around buying and getting money.
Rym: They could've really.
Scott: Yeah, plus who knows what that fact said.
Scott: It could've been a speed run fact.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So they gave them a fact, which is understandable because if the players were not familiar with Zelda 1, we would've been there forever.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Number two, if one player was familiar and one player was not, it would've been incredibly unentertaining for the crowd to watch one person dominate and the other person get lost.
Rym: Kinda like why Dance.
Rym: Dance Revolution will never be the Omegathon finale because you either are awesome at DDR or it's not fun to watch you play DDR.
Rym: There's no middle ground there.
Scott: There's a huge component of.
Scott: they always want it to be really close, right?
Scott: They want it to be entertaining for the crowd.
Rym: I'm amazed at how close it is every year.
Scott: I am.
Scott: I think they do incredible amounts of testing, right?
Scott: They test the crane.
Scott: They test everything to make sure that it's going to be really close.
Scott: They change the rules just to make sure.
Scott: They maximize crowd entertainment.
Scott: They don't maximize fair competition or anything like that.
Scott: So in that regards, excellent job, you know, perfectly reasonable.
Scott: But if you don't know how to get the first piece of the Triforce in Zelda 1 as quickly as possible, how are you even in the Omegathon?
Rym: Scott and I, what's funny is, you know, the guy on the left.
Scott: How are you even at PAX?
Scott: How can you call yourself a gamer?
Scott: That's like, you know, people call themselves a lot of things, Like, you know, you identify yourself based on things you do.
Scott: You might say, oh, yes, I am a singer.
Scott: Well, what have you sung?
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: Oh, yes, I'm a big fan of Broadway.
Scott: Well, have you seen Phantom of the Opera?
Scott: No.
Scott: Have you seen Cats?
Scott: No, never.
Scott: Now, had this been like...
Rym: No.
Rym: Had they started them at Death Mountain and been like, Beganon?
Rym: Okay, I'd understand if people had some trouble.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But it's like, you call yourself a gamer and you identify yourself as a gamer enough such that, A, you go into PAX.
Scott: B, you're signing up for the Omegathon.
Scott: D, you're good enough to get to the end of the Omegathon.
Rym: And C.
Scott: And E, you've never played Zelda 1 and you need a pack.
Rym: No, no, no, Scott, to be fair, I can understand if someone, they knew where the first dungeon was, but they didn't remember exactly where Aquamentis was.
Rym: I can understand that.
Scott: That's fine, because then at least if you've at least played it, even if you weren't the master of it, which is understandable, it would still be pretty interesting to see you bump around in Dungeon 1.
Rym: But the guy on the right went right.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And wandered off and then his spirit animal was like, No, no, no, no, no, no.
Scott: And the spirit animal could not point at the screen.
Scott: They could only talk and read the pack, which is good.
Scott: But still very disappointed.
Scott: Very.
Rym: However, it was great because the competition was close anyway.
Rym: The person with better skill clearly won.
Rym: And more importantly, there's this moment where the guy on the left is in the dungeon and he's going toward the wrong door.
Rym: And Scott and I lost our shit.
Rym: I was yelling louder than I've ever let.
Scott: He was toward the door.
Scott: He went north.
Scott: Here's the thing on your right.
Scott: So he went north towards the bow, killed a few Staphloses, and then went south.
Scott: Now, I was told later that apparently he did this to get a heart.
Scott: But that is the most retarded thing ever, because number one, you shouldn't have gotten hit.
Scott: But you already hit.
Scott: So you need the heart to get full health.
Scott: Well, the guy on the right died outside of the dungeon.
Scott: You need the magic sword to shoot Aquamentus, because getting the bow takes too long.
Scott: And you know where you're going to get arrows anyway.
Scott: So it's understandable.
Rym: But arrows.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But but if you needed hearts, you could have killed the master hands in the room before The master hands was actually quite a tense moment.
Rym: because because the thing is, but you know, the guy needed the key, right?
Rym: The key ended up being in the bottom right and the hands.
Rym: that's where the cat kept coming out.
Scott: And the key is always in the bottom right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But the first guy got in like the hands, like you just avoided him right away.
Rym: The first guy just missed him.
Rym: And there was just like four hands in a row came up right on the key.
Scott: So I went yesterday.
Scott: I made a YouTube video.
Scott: You can watch it.
Scott: I did a test where I tried to do the Omega-Thon finale challenge of get the Triforce piece as quickly as possible.
Scott: I turned on an emulator.
Scott: I plugged an Xbox 360 controller.
Scott: I created a new game and I just went for it.
Scott: First try.
Scott: I didn't get hit once.
Scott: Not once at all.
Scott: I did it in about two minutes in a few seconds.
Scott: And in that room with the master hands, I just walked over, grabbed the key and walked right up without touching any of the master hands.
Scott: And, you know, I wasn't speed running or anything.
Scott: There's plenty of time.
Rym: So Scott, here's what I did.
Scott: There's plenty of times where I go slow, like I just walk into a tree for a few seconds.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, stuff like that that happens in Zelda one.
Rym: So here's what I would have done.
Rym: This is just what I would have done if I were Mike and Jerry.
Rym: So same exact competition with the same exact fact.
Rym: It would have been the second quest.
Rym: I wouldn't have said shit about that.
Scott: Fuck yeah.
Rym: Just imagine.
Rym: Everything would be fine until they get into that dungeon.
Scott: Well, you would have known because you would have seen the sword on the opening character select screen.
Rym: I would have come up with somewhere around that.
Rym: I would have started the game paused or something.
Scott: But then you couldn't have had the epic reveal where the music plays.
Rym: I could have had the reveal and then some save states.
Scott: But they weren't using emulators using real NES.
Rym: Which is dangerous.
Scott: It's the only fair way.
Rym: It's fair, but it's dangerous.
Scott: Not if you've tested the NES as thoroughly.
Rym: Yeah, but NES could glitch out of nowhere.
Scott: No, they get top loaders or in toasters or something.
Scott: Anyway, slight disappointment with gamers worldwide not playing Zelda one.
Scott: If you listening to this have not played and beaten Zelda one at least the first quest.
Rym: Stop right now.
Rym: Don't even listen anymore.
Rym: You are.
Scott: You do not count.
Scott: You are.
Scott: Instead, every you have no pride.
Scott: All your pride is erased.
Scott: Instead, you are covered in a mountain of shame.
Rym: You don't have to remove this mountain of shame.
Scott: You must beat Zelda one first quest.
Rym: You don't have to beat the second quest.
Scott: Do not use a fact.
Scott: You can only look at a map of the very beginning of the game that came with Zelda one.
Scott: If you need a JPEG of this map or the instruction manual, I'm sure you can find it on Google.
Scott: I think that's the only equipment you are allowed to use.
Rym: I wonder like I can't imagine how I found some of that stuff.
Rym: I think I just burned every fucking bush.
Scott: I burned every bush.
Rym: With a blue candle.
Scott: I burned a lot of bushes with a blue candle, but I got the red candle eventually.
Rym: I was so excited when I got that red fucking candle.
Scott: I burned so many goddamn bushes with the red candle.
Scott: If I was burning bushes in real life, I'd be like the most crazy arsonist ever.
Rym: Moses would be proud.
Scott: Is there any other pecs?
Rym: So there's one other thing we should talk about.
Rym: Con seemed a lot more crowded this year.
Rym: One thing is they may have sold more badges.
Rym: The other thing was that panel attendance is down.
Rym: And Halo Fest took up a whole bunch of space without a lot of content.
Rym: So it might have pushed more people into the gaming areas.
Rym: But there was some counterfeit badges.
Scott: I'm sure there were counterfeit badges in the past.
Scott: But this year there was a counterfeit badge epidemic.
Rym: I would guess there were 500 to 1,000 counterfeit badges.
Scott: There was a lot of counterfeit badges.
Rym: That's me guessing.
Rym: That's not based on anything Pags told us.
Rym: But Pags gave us as a gift.
Rym: We're calling them Zdars now.
Scott: If you don't know, in Mario Party, a negative star is a zdar.
Rym: Which is kind of famous for us because we were in -- this was the same time we had the bamboo and the vision.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: But we were playing Mario Party for the championship belt teams.
Rym: And we weren't doing that well.
Rym: We were doing okay.
Rym: We were holding our own.
Scott: It was tied.
Rym: In one round, the other team got a star.
Rym: Gave us a zdar.
Rym: We got another zdar because of a Bowser game.
Rym: And random bullshit gave us another zdar.
Scott: It was bullshit.
Rym: In one round we went from neck and neck to there is no hope.
Rym: There was no Obi-Wan.
Scott: And we lost.
Rym: And then the bamboo.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So these are zdars.
Rym: They're like -- it's like an anti-artifact.
Rym: But there were some pretty sophisticated counterfeit badges and I'm amazed.
Rym: This is one of the reasons why, you know, on the east coast a lot of the fan cons are really afraid of counterfeit badges.
Rym: But one, I've seen counterfeit badges on the east coast and they're like baby's first counterfeit.
Scott: They're jokes.
Rym: It's like, kid, you have a black and white photocopy and you put some tinfoil where the hologram is.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Or you've got last year's badge.
Rym: You thought that would work.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But at the same time, that does work.
Rym: At Otakon and Katsucon and all the east coast cons, seriously, baby's first counterfeit gets passed, baby's first convention security.
Rym: >> But the west coast has real security teams.
Rym: Like the people who do -- like the green shirts in the convention center, I want them to like come home and like just help me out with stuff because they're like the best people ever.
Rym: >> Yep.
Rym: >> They caught counterfeits to a degree that was amazing.
Scott: >> They didn't catch all of them.
Scott: That's impossible.
Scott: But they caught a significant number.
Scott: A very significant number.
Rym: >> Now, the thing is these counterfeits, the turnaround time on these things, I imagine, is pretty quick to the point that I feel like even if Pax did not mail out the badges, we'd have these things by Saturday.
Rym: >> Yep.
Rym: >> So we're not going to talk about what's going to be done about this.
Rym: We've heard some things.
Rym: We've talked to some people.
Rym: But we're going to let Pax handle all that because it's not our game.
Scott: >> It's not our game, but I do have some suggestions.
Scott: And a lot of people out there are making dumb suggestions.
Scott: And all you people making dumb suggestions.
Rym: >> First of all, all you people who said don't mail the badges, fuck you.
Scott: >> Shut the fuck up.
Rym: >> Shut the fuck up.
Rym: No.
Rym: We've been down that road.
Rym: Otakon has 15,000 people line up Thursday night.
Rym: That sucks.
Rym: >> Right.
Scott: So, you know, some people are just like, oh, slap a hologram on it.
Scott: That's really not good enough.
Scott: Some people like put a bar code on it.
Scott: It's like, dude, bar code works at a baseball game because there's no reentry.
Scott: They scan everything once and then you get in through a turnstile and you never leave.
Scott: That's why a bar code works.
Rym: >> So bar code works in one situation.
Rym: It works.
Rym: if they're not -- you see, everyone who says bar code or QR code or serial number seems to think that you're going to have people checking these as you go into the com.
Rym: No.
Rym: >> No.
Rym: >> The way you use that is you tie your name to a badge.
Rym: So when you buy a badge, your name is tied to that bar code.
Rym: And the badge, you can hit a thing and it's legit.
Rym: So maybe if you sell your badge to someone, you transfer the ownership on the PAC's website.
Rym: But there's no way to see who owns a badge unless you scan the bar code and you make it in such a way that it can't just be scanned by someone walking by.
Rym: You're like, here, check it out.
Rym: Like scan my badge.
Rym: One, you know, I'm sure they could make some deal where like booths scan badges and have raffles or whatever.
Rym: Two, you make an iPhone app and an Android app and if someone's scalping a badge, you scan it and you'd be like, all right, Joey Jojo Shabadoo, the website says that you don't own a badge, so what's this shit you're trying to sell me?
Scott: >> Yeah, or the website says this badge belongs to so and so.
Rym: >> But that's not your name.
Scott: >> What's your name?
Scott: >> Huh.
Rym: >> Of course, the easy way to tell the counterfeit is to grab someone's badge and rip it in two down the bottom.
Rym: They weren't plastic.
Rym: They were just cardboard with laminate.
Rym: >> Yeah.
Rym: >> They just tore right in half.
Scott: >> But really what it comes down to is, you know, obviously people who buy counterfeit badges are victims, right?
Scott: They didn't know they were buying counterfeit badges, especially when it's such a convincing badge.
Scott: But at the same time, you know, we need to -- we can't -- there's no way to stop counterfeiters altogether.
Rym: >> Let's put it this way.
Rym: >> The only thing you can do --.
Rym: >> If I bought -- this is the example you were using at the con.
Rym: If I bought a counterfeit ticket to a Red Wings game and I show up at the stadium, they're not letting me in.
Scott: >> I'm lucky they don't arrest me.
Scott: >> That's right.
Scott: So we nearly need to be like, look, people, if you're buying a badge from an unlegitimate source, it's up to you to verify if it's real or not.
Scott: And if you fail at that, well, you know, and that's the only way to prevent counterfeiting is to get the people who are buying the badges to be really, you know --.
Rym: >> Now, here's another thing I might do.
Rym: >> Sketchical.
Rym: >> Let's say -- because, you know, PAX's policy, I don't officially know what it is, and I'm not going to talk about what they may or may not have done.
Rym: Suppose that they took people who got counterfeit badges and made some sort of deal.
Rym: Like, they gave them a real badge instead.
Rym: >> You can't.
Scott: You already sold all your badges.
Scott: Fire marshal.
Scott: >> Ah.
Rym: So we can't do that.
Rym: Let's say we have a deal with the fire marshal or whatever where we have X capacity for more badges, which one cuts down on people who can get into PAX.
Rym: That sucks.
Rym: >> But at the same time, you use it where, all right, kid, you've got a counterfeit badge.
Rym: You can buy a real badge, but you got to pay full price right now.
Scott: >> Yeah, but then I'll just buy -- instead of it'll sell out, and then I'll just buy counterfeit and show up, and that way it won't matter that it's sold out.
Scott: I get in anyway.
Scott: That's --.
Rym: >> So there aren't good solutions.
Rym: You see what I'm getting at here.
Rym: There isn't really, like, every way to handle this.
Rym: >> Well, Scott, your solution is a little -- go on.
Scott: >> You should make the badge ridiculously awesome, perhaps even make it so awesome --.
Rym: >> Scott, make it like the magfest badges, the special ones.
Rym: >> Nope, the special magfest badges.
Scott: >> No, but like Def Con badges with electronics in them.
Scott: Make the badge so ludicrously advanced and expensive that the badge itself might be 30 bucks.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Like --.
Rym: >> And then raise the price -- here's the thing.
Rym: So it's got a USB port on it.
Rym: Raise the price of the badge by and sell space on that USB in the badge to vendors.
Scott: So you would -- both the badge would make money from people advertising in the badge, not on the badge, but in it.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And simultaneously, you know, PAX should be a flat rate or maybe, you know, it should be still accessible to people in terms of price.
Scott: But really, you need to raise the price a little bit.
Rym: >> A little bit, 10 bucks.
Scott: >> Make it 65, 75 at the most for the PAX badge instead of 50.
Scott: Right?
Rym: >> Yeah, because anime cons charge way more than you.
Scott: >> Also, only sell weekend badges.
Rym: >> Yeah, forget -- there's no reason to have single-day badges because I posit to you, almost anyone who buys a single-day badge has bought two or three of.
Scott: >> I mean, it's like you want PAX to be inclusive, you know, to make it as accessible as possible.
Scott: There are people who can only make it for one day.
Scott: There are people who don't have enough money for the three-day they want to -- you know, but if they can go for one day, that'll.
Scott: >> But nobody does that.
Rym: Everyone who buys a Friday and a Sunday badge did so because they were out of three-day and Saturday badges.
Scott: >> There are a lot of people who just buy one, two, three, and also, while I agree it should be accessible to -- you know, and inclusive, there's also the fact that, you know, some people are just more dedicated to PAX, and a dedicated person to PAX is going to go all three
Rym: days.
Rym: >> Yep, if you really want it.
Scott: >> The only sad thing is that somebody might buy a weekend pass and not use all three days, and then someone else might be denied a day that was available.
Rym: >> Ah, but if you're not using all three days, sell your badge to someone as you're leaving.
Scott: >> That's a good idea.
Rym: >> Yeah.
Rym: >> Anyway.
Rym: >> So imagine this.
Rym: You get your badge.
Rym: It's kind of thick and cool and light.
Rym: It's got a USB thing on it, and you know, like I was looking at this for GeekNights.
Rym: It's pretty cheap to in bulk buy tiny MP3 players with preloaded content, like tens of thousands of them.
Rym: Like it's surprisingly cheap.
Scott: >> Yeah, there's a lot of fancy electronic things, LEDs, RFIDs, full hologram, not a tiny hologram sticker.
Scott: >> But imagine this.
Rym: You get your badge in the mail, right?
Rym: What's on it?
Rym: >> An unreleased episode of PATV.
Rym: All the demos to games that the publishers paid to put on them.
Scott: >> Some --.
Rym: >> A League of Legends item.
Rym: >> Yep.
Scott: All that kind of crap can be on that USB stick when your badge comes in the mail.
Rym: >> Maybe a game that is part of some sort of like packs, like -- like -- I don't know.
Scott: >> Yeah, maybe you can put badges together and then do some sort of thing with them or get them scanned at different locations.
Scott: You know, and then what you do, right, is you don't have any particular badge checking spot, right?
Scott: You don't have like everyone here has to check badges and then there's a big clusterfuck of traffic.
Rym: What you do is -- already do at the entrances, they do.
Rym: That works fine.
Scott: >> Right, but what you do is, for example, there's a bunch of people waiting for a panel.
Scott: They're just sitting.
Scott: So you have an enforcer just casually walk down the line like just, hey, can I see everyone's badge?
Scott: Everyone hold your badge up.
Scott: And maybe he goes beep, beep, beep, beep, beep, just down the line of people who are waiting for the panel.
Scott: There's already people waiting there anyway.
Scott: They're already not moving.
Scott: The enforcer is already just sitting there waiting to open the door, right?
Scott: There's usually two or three of them at a panel door, right?
Scott: Any place like that in the convention, you know, a line to play a game, you know, any line or any waiting area, you know, people are waiting in line for the omegathon finale or the keynote.
Scott: Just have one enforcer go down the line.
Rym: >> If you just did that, that kind of sucks because that's like visible security or whatever.
Rym: You know, it's not a good thing for the vibe of the con.
Rym: So what you do is because we've got these serial numbers, every time you do that, you do a mini raffle right there for some tiny thing.
Scott: It's also --.
Scott: >> It's a combination security check in the guise of not just a raffle but also a check-in, right?
Scott: So you can go log into the pack site and see all the things you did and also Penny Arcade will have data about who checked in where for what events to see where the traffic is flowing, what's more popular, what's less popular, you know, what people like.
Scott: That's very valuable information that most conventions don't have.
Scott: There's so many benefits, you know, and of course, beep, beep, beep.
Scott: >> Dude, your badge ain't real.
Scott: Yeah, come with me.
Scott: Right?
Rym: >> Yep.
Scott: >> So that's what they need to do.
Scott: Make a fancy badge, get the money for it by increasing the con price and also selling badge stuff and then check it in places where people aren't doing anything and it wouldn't hurt to check.
Rym: >> I mean, beyond that, we played a lot of goddamn games, PAX was awesome.
Rym: I think I played more games at this PAX than any other PAX.
Scott: >> Yeah, but I didn't play a lot of games I never played before.
Rym: >> Which is fine because half the reason I go is to play new games like Marrakesh.
Scott: >> Yeah, this PAX --.
Rym: >> And half the reason I go is to play games.
Rym: I've already going to buy that shit.
Rym: >> I'm going to buy that shit.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: >> Is that I like to play games I know with people who also know those games who I normally don't get to play them with or I don't get to play these games that often.
Scott: >> There's definitely -- that was the most of this PAX.
Scott: Next PAX, though, I hope to do more of the games I never played before with maybe people I don't know.
Rym: >> Yeah, and sorry, magfest dudes, I actually kept like not having time to stop into your jam space and say hi.
Scott: >> Yeah, but now I have a mission, though.
Scott: I learned something.
Scott: this PAX is that, you know, I've sort of been experiencing the same part of PAX over and over again.
Scott: I think in the long run -- I'm going to go to tons and tons of PAXes, right?
Scott: I think I want to do every aspect of PAX.
Scott: So I think I'm going to be an enforcer once at least.
Scott: I think I'm going to try to be an omega naught once at least, right?
Scott: I'm going to try to do everything eventually.
Rym: >> I would go for omega naught at least, I think, because I kind of dig the co-op-y games.
Scott: >> Maybe I'll be X-ball Haul once, you know?
Scott: I'm going to try to do everything at PAX once in all the years of PAXes.
Scott: So we'll see.
Rym: >> Yep.
Rym: And on that note, we will see you at PAX.
Rym: It's not that far away.
Rym: >> Nope.
Rym: >> This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: >> Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: >> Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: >> GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.