Rym: It's Tuesday January 4th 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: super meat boy.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: See.
Rym: if I hadn't said the year people wouldn't have known.
Rym: I think they would know they would have no idea.
Rym: Especially you know 20 years from now when GeekNights is in the National Archives a national treasure, man They got to know.
Scott: I'm sure It'll be a a big problem for them.
Scott: They won't be able to look at the Dean.
Scott: you know the file the name of the file Maybe they won't or any of the ID in the far future.
Rym: They won't have files or the website.
Rym: They won't have file names.
Rym: the website long gone.
Rym: Well.
Scott: You know what.
Scott: whatever there will be in the future I will update it to you know because you're gonna be alive If I am two dead.
Scott: in that it is that I'm.
Rym: at least I'm hoping that GeekNights will outlive me.
Scott: if it's two days In the future and I die tomorrow then oh well So we had our crazies.
Rym: we might be a little low-energy tonight because we had our Annual New Year's Eve front row crew extravaganza, which this year was possibly the biggest one yet yet simultaneously in these smallest combined spaces No, no and it was the biggest.
Scott: we didn't count the bodies and a lot of the bodies are not simultaneous.
Rym: But there was one moment when everybody was simultaneous.
Rym: Almost yeah, everybody everybody who came to New York.
Rym: at least there are a few people who weren't here at all.
Rym: They didn't fly out for obvious reasons bums.
Rym: We had a big old party and a little tired played a lot of games.
Rym: It's amazing how much Super Meatball is kind of a spectator sport almost more so than a single-player game Because it's more.
Scott: what it more is when you have a whole bunch of people right like us playing it as a spectator sport.
Scott: It's like you suck.
Scott: Let's see you do it bitch.
Rym: Oh It's like here.
Scott: let me show you how it's done.
Scott: boom beaten.
Rym: A lot of people trash talk is surprising him out when they're not playing.
Rym: if you hand him the controller nothing happens.
Scott: Hey, listen, you know I got into that that.
Scott: what's that guy's name?
Rym: agmo agmo.
Scott: yeah, I was doing the agmo warp zone and we get to the final level of it and everyone was like looked at it and Was like ooh, and then I got up to the first Way up there right on the first go and they were like, oh snap.
Rym: It wasn't that hard though I was pretty easy to use.
Scott: Yeah, he's pretty good.
Scott: He's slow.
Rym: He's no good on any level.
Rym: Well, we'll talk about Super Meat Boy in a bit.
Rym: So I really briefly want a geek bite.
Rym: Cthulhu saves the world.
Scott: because I also played Cthulhu.
Rym: We all played the demo.
Rym: someone downloaded it on a box.
Rym: You did.
Rym: I played it a couple times.
Scott: I played it for lolz.
Rym: Uh, it is not worth any amount of money.
Scott: I would not pay any money and even if it were I would pay one penny if it's not ready.
Rym: It is not worth the time to play it.
Scott: That is all well, it does have.
Scott: It doesn't have two things that other JR cuz it's JRPG.
Scott: No question.
Rym: It's basically a Cthulhu JRPG.
Rym: You're Cthulhu.
Rym: He's on the Arlithotep or someone's taking away his power and to get it back.
Rym: He has to be a good guy.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is right it does.
Scott: it does have two things better than other JRPGs that make it maybe tolerable to beat the Whole thing.
Scott: Well number one number one, you can run really fast on the map.
Rym: That's okay.
Rym: I was talking more.
Rym: number two you once you have done 25 random encounters in an area.
Rym: They will never happen again.
Scott: Well, at least the first area.
Scott: the number is 25.
Scott: I don't know what the number is in other areas and it's you can turn them back on if you want but basically each area has a number of encounters.
Scott: that is the limit of Random encounters in that area which is genius right because that it's.
Scott: it's so perfect because look a lot of times You know, you don't know how what how much should I level up?
Scott: Well, this game is like here.
Scott: This is how much you should level up.
Scott: and the third thing it does which you probably didn't realize After you do a combat you get full HPs.
Scott: afterwards You only need to heal if you're gonna die in the combat.
Rym: Of course that doesn't remove one of the aspects of the JRPG which is often there the I'm running low on Supplies and need to make it out of here.
Scott: Mmm, who cares?
Rym: That depends.
Scott: The only reason to play this game is for the lulls.
Rym: It's okay lulls.
Rym: It's not great.
Scott: I thought it was good lulls.
Rym: It was okay.
Rym: The thing is it was a little predictable.
Rym: Yeah, the jokes were a little bit Obvious and ham-fisted.
Scott: I think they were lulls.
Rym: She's a groupie.
Rym: He could thoroughly gets a groupie.
Rym: She follows him around stuff like that.
Scott: Yeah, I think is the demo is one of the time limit demos.
Scott: So I ran really really fast to try to get to the To the you know to see as much content as possible.
Rym: I got to that other adventuring party.
Scott: Yeah, that's where I got.
Rym: beat them by holding a beat everything by holding a yep Everything by holding a. the combat is kind of a combo system.
Scott: That is that is.
Scott: one thing I didn't like though is that you None of the moves have really different animations.
Scott: That's one that you know, like a Pokemon you want to turn the animations off but not until you've seen them.
Scott: Yes Even in like Final Fantasy 4 all the spells had cool stuff going on at least one I never saw like a through who hit anyone with a sword or wrap his tentacles around anyone or anything like that.
Rym: Yeah, my insanity strike was just but oop, yep boring though you get points for being able to make monsters go insane.
Rym: I never figured out what that did because they died at the same time as that.
Rym: they went insane.
Scott: I think that's the point Is that you can make.
Scott: you can kill them by making them too insane and you can also kill them by killing them.
Rym: So two things that bother me.
Rym: one You get some good guy to join your party and she has powers that make people go insane just like Cthulhu does.
Rym: And two you rescue her from two monsters that are basically this game's equivalent of imps and She in your party is immediately powerful enough to take on infinity imps.
Rym: So what the hell game?
Rym: But Cthulhu does make this good face where he's kind of like, uh all the time.
Scott: It's not about making sense right?
Scott: and I you know, this is another thing that bothers me.
Scott: It's like we see in gaming as a whole this today, right?
Scott: A lot of people are taking this route where they find a genre of game and instead of You know fixing the fundamental problems of the genre which basically means making a fundamentally different game.
Scott: That's not in the genre.
Scott: What they do is they polish The problems of the genre so that they bother you as little as possible.
Scott: For example random encounters bother you in the JRPGs Oh like earthbound for example, right random encounters bother you.
Scott: well if the monsters too weak you just win Right.
Scott: or oh, it's.
Scott: it's really bothersome to organize all your equipment and to purchase the right equipment.
Scott: So we'll put in an auto buying button.
Scott: It automatically buys the best equipment It's.
Scott: why don't you just remove the equipment buying from the game?
Rym: Well, you see the slippery slope there is press a to play the game optimally and see all the cutscenes in order.
Scott: in other words Why the fuck did you make a video game just make a video on YouTube?
Scott: And that's I think a lot of the point-and-click adventure games that are pretty much trial and error until you see the next piece of Plot really should do that.
Scott: They should just be.
Scott: you know, here are you.
Scott: make interactive choose your own adventure book?
Rym: So Scott you've gotten very close to my point.
Rym: the reason I wanted to geek by Cthulhu saves the world is that it's a. I like the idea taking the piss out of a Genre and you know throwing in a geeky element.
Rym: I mean Charles Barkley shut up and jam guy Dan.
Rym: Oh, yeah I don't want to play that but I enjoy the idea of it so much.
Rym: I like saying the name of it Charles Barkley shut up and jam guy dad.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Hey dad but we have a problem now in the gaming industry with games like this where I am Pirating all of the games like this by watching other people play them on YouTube.
Rym: Mm-hmm now it's not necessarily I mean Is it Piracy to take a video of a game and put it online because it cannot replace the experience of playing.
Rym: Oh, wait, it can replace the experience of playing the game.
Rym: Some games I mean in a JRPG.
Rym: you can just sit there with the controller and hold a the whole time.
Rym: Yeah Or like poker night same thing.
Rym: I just watched it Cthulhu.
Rym: I'll probably watch some YouTube highlights to make sure I don't miss all the good jokes.
Rym: Maybe I'll read the game fat.
Scott: something I've been doing With the point-and-click adventure games is I haven't watched them on YouTube But I get the fact and I basically blow through it real fast You know without you know having to sit there for an hour Clicking on every single thing on the screen with every single other thing on the screen.
Scott: I did it with Machinarium and it basically took about the same amount of time You know to play it on YouTube as it did to You know.
Scott: just go with the fact and with the fact you get better resolution.
Rym: See at least the quest for glory games after the first one As point-and-click adventures or type and move around to the keyboard adventures.
Rym: It was mostly logical puzzles that you could just solve and they were actually interesting.
Rym: It wasn't the arbitrary walk into a room take every item and use that everything see all the deaths and eventually one of them Lets you go to the next room.
Scott: Yeah, there is this one I forget the name of it that I got in some steam sale.
Scott: That's basically this pirate dog.
Scott: and the thing was that one is actually funny.
Scott: I was like, oh man, so I've been.
Scott: I've been going through that slowly with the fact so it is.
Scott: it is pretty logical.
Scott: It doesn't have too many arbitrary bullshits.
Rym: But anyway, I do have an actual kind of gaming news that came up over the New Year's holiday.
Rym: That was kind of important As we always say mostly on Mondays because that's when the tech stuff comes up.
Rym: if you have to give The consumer access to the hardware at all as in they own the hardware or the hardware is in their house in any way You cannot have perfect DRM.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So the ps3 had DRM and it.
Rym: you could sign games and the ps3 will only play signed games.
Rym: and there's this whole system where if someone like They give a company a key that lets them sign games if they sign bad shit They could revoke those keys and force them to be reissued and they can update the ps3 firmware all sorts of stuff But there has to be somewhere a hardware master key and there is in fact a hardware master key and it has finally been Revealed.
Rym: so basically short of replacing ps3 hardware There is nothing Sony can do to prevent anyone from safely rooting their ps3s forever and you don't even need to root it.
Rym: You can just download whatever pirated stuff or homebrew stuff people make because they can sign stuff legitimately and Sony cannot revoke the master key.
Scott: Yep So it's like you can't.
Scott: this isn't even a situation where you need a mod chip, right?
Scott: Anyone can just make a blu-ray disc and the PlayStation will recognize it as legitimate.
Scott: and since it's the master master key Right.
Scott: It's like they can maybe update a firmware and put some sub master keys But they'd have to like redo their whole thing and then someone you know, it's it's pretty much doomsday for them in that department Yep, which has two primary uses.
Scott: It's not really a big change though.
Scott: They used to let you run Linux on there and stuff.
Scott: Not anymore though.
Rym: Yeah, well then they took it away and today I cannot fathom why they also took away the backward compatibility.
Rym: I just I don't get Sony the ps3 fee.
Rym: I feel like they're Japanese They don't get it, but it's it's languishing, but it's not failing the same as the PSP.
Rym: Yeah, the PSP is a solid second place, but it's second place Like hey guys, I'm still you know, any order the PSP go.
Scott: I mean everyone has the regular PSP.
Scott: No one has that PSP go.
Rym: I know less than two or three people who have even PSPs.
Rym: I know right and I've thought about buying one like ten times, but then I look at the game list again, and I think yeah It's sort of like the PSP.
Scott: for me It sort of has one of those game lists sort of like the Dreamcast does or like the Saturn right where there's some of these Quirky games that you're never gonna play anywhere else.
Scott: that it's like, oh man I'd really like to play one or two of those but it's I'm not gonna get a whole system to play like that Weird Megaman game that came out for the PSP.
Scott: Yeah or Bar man for the Saturn or any of those kinds of things.
Rym: the thing is most of the games I want to play like that Are old enough to wear emulation.
Scott: Well, you know the thing is, you know as I was talking about before when I was discussing the maim failures.
Scott: Right is in a previous episode Recent previous episode is that emulation is sort of failing for anything beyond like the ps1, you know Pretty much ps2 and on emulation is real weak.
Scott: and 64 emulation is there.
Rym: ish course that does make sense just because at least on Sony side with the cell processor and the way games work the Complexity of what needs to be emulated is Exponential.
Scott: it's a pretty much like everything ps1 and earlier.
Scott: you can emulate but anything after that and you know You pretty much.
Scott: you're better off getting a system and then getting a mod chip and then getting copied.
Rym: now Meanwhile on the Microsoft side you basically have to emulate a Windows computer.
Rym: Oh just run Windows.
Rym: Okay, it's got any news you got.
Scott: well, it's sort of news.
Scott: I mean this would normally be thing of the day material, but I'm gonna spin it as news Really?
Scott: It's very important right?
Rym: You want me to edit out that you're spinning it or you want the same to be a parent?
Scott: It's fine.
Scott: There's these guys right and they made a thing and that's the news that these guys have accomplished this feat right.
Scott: the feet they have Accomplished is they have beaten quake one with a hundred percent secrets.
Scott: They got every secret and they got a hundred percent kills.
Scott: they killed everything and it was a speed run.
Scott: So they did it crazy fast and it was a team of guys.
Scott: I'm not sure how much of it was like machine assisted.
Rym: I'm I've decided I don't care anymore.
Scott: It doesn't really matter right whether they did save and load or retry or whatever, right?
Scott: the fact is you do it whether you do it that way or not, you're still doing it and they you know they basically each guy was responsible for certain levels and they they Combined all their successes together and created a single speedrun video and you can.
Scott: it's on YouTube.
Scott: It's a quake one Done quickest.
Rym: it does remind me if nothing else how fast and how crazy the quake one engine was.
Scott: Yeah, that's you know.
Scott: The major reasons I want people to see this video are number one.
Scott: You can see quake one if you haven't, you know gotten it on Steam or played it anything.
Scott: it too You can see.
Scott: right, you know for many years.
Scott: We've been you know, having the constant debate has been ongoing of you know.
Scott: Oh, no console FPS is PC FPS is keyboard and mouse gamepad bla bla bla, right?
Scott: And here this video better than any other that I've ever seen in many years illustrates in.
Scott: You know for 40 minutes it illustrates.
Scott: Look, this is how a real, you know, you know Twitch hardcore FPS goes.
Scott: look how fast this is.
Scott: Look how fast they turn.
Scott: look at the maneuvers that are made.
Scott: look at the precision and the speed of the aiming, you know, and There is absolutely no way that this can be possible Using analog sticks because while they are analog the same as a mouse and while they have two axis the same as a mouse They are limited.
Scott: You can only push the stick so far to the left and then you will rotate to the left at the fastest speed Whereas with a mouse there is no limit.
Scott: you can slide your mouse all the way across the desk at the high sensitivity and spin around, you know now it's a billion degree analog stick on a computer with Effectively infinite control much like with a mouse.
Rym: Like if you can sit there and decide the sensitivity at every threshold you could make an equivalent But humans might not be able to use it.
Scott: Yeah, basically.
Rym: Yeah, so, you know, you have to move the stick like, you know, two It is possible I'm just arguing that but no console FPS has ever done anything like that.
Scott: No, I mean some of them do.
Scott: let you turn the sensitivity way up But it you know, just you know, the physicality of it makes it pretty impossible.
Scott: the other problem That I realized more recently with the console FPS is right is the twin stick, right?
Scott: so you got two thumbs on two sticks and you basically that leaves your You know index and ring and middle fingers to work.
Scott: the left button right button left trigger right trigger.
Scott: that gives you four buttons that you can press while simultaneously moving.
Rym: and Scott you can push in either of the sticks.
Scott: Okay, so six buttons you can do.
Rym: of course that does disrupt your aiming but I guess that is lighter in a console FPS.
Scott: Right, so you can move aim and push six buttons, you know simultaneously while moving and aiming.
Scott: But with the mouse and keyboard you can push every button on the keyboard simultaneously to moving and aiming.
Rym: What I would like like.
Rym: you can jump shoot use an item do a backflip at what I would like though.
Rym: now Imagine this I have my keyboard, but I only use the compete the keyboard because it's kind of a basic thing.
Rym: I just need a whole bunch of buttons in a grid.
Rym: Ideally, I'd have a whole bunch of buttons in a grid and where my thumb goes.
Rym: instead of buttons I would have an analog stick.
Rym: Uh-huh, we're moving in the two-dimensional plane.
Rym: And then the mouse is the aiming in the two-dimensional plane Mm-hmm.
Rym: I guess you could go crazy.
Rym: true because he double fisted with two mice One with an array of.
Scott: but that is true because you know for aiming you absolutely need the unlimited, you know Motion of a mouse.
Scott: but for moving every FPS I've ever played ever as a limit to the speed of moving so you can't move Any faster, right?
Scott: So an analog stick is just as good if not better for moving than a WASD.
Rym: No What I did do I have an aiming is far more.
Rym: I've made a video of it yet to put online.
Rym: But I've been experimenting with filming with a little HD camera.
Rym: what my hands are doing on the keyboard on my hands doing on The mouse?
Rym: what's going on on the screen when I play counter-strike?
Scott: Mm-hmm, and a lot of fighting games do videos like that, which is very helpful.
Rym: Yep It is.
Rym: it was kind of weird to watch myself because I feel you know when the APMs that Starcraft players talk about I see myself doing something similar when I play counter-strike when I'm like waiting for someone or I'm itching to shoot.
Rym: I'm kind of going straight just like I'm hitting the strafe bunches like pop up up up up up up up back and forth all the time weird.
Scott: Anyway, so yeah You should watch this video quake done 100% Quickest because a lot of the speed runs are all about just getting under the level.
Scott: It takes two seconds.
Scott: You're like what happened, but this one they actually kill all the bad guys.
Scott: So you can see a lot more aiming and shooting going on and that to avoid dying.
Rym: I do have a confession to make.
Rym: I never even played through more than like 10 levels in quake one single-player And I never played through most of quake 2 single-player.
Rym: I started playing them once I learned how to play.
Rym: I immediately went to online deathmatch and never looked back.
Rym: I basically had no like.
Rym: I hated the single-player game - was a little better.
Rym: There was more stuff going on.
Scott: But even then I think there's about they were pretty equal.
Rym: I skipped and beat the end of both of them, but yeah.
Rym: So things of the day, I know it's on College Humor But I found it pretty funny and everyone we know who isn't not scared of games found it desperately funny.
Rym: So I figure it's worth being a thing of the day.
Rym: It's a dude.
Rym: They sounds like he's vaguely like he's in the same archetype of Dave Riley, but Dave Riley's not a goddamn pussy like this guy is.
Rym: He's playing a recent scary video game and he's losing his shit as some people do when they play recent scary video games.
Rym: Mmm, I find it hilarious.
Scott: I don't think it's that funny.
Rym: I think it's pretty good.
Scott: You're sort of sad.
Rym: I Find it more funny than sad because he is enjoying himself.
Scott: I think so.
Rym: Maybe he wet himself.
Scott: that might be true and that is sad.
Rym: All right, what do you have?
Rym: What's better than that?
Scott: To check out this dude Right is a homeless dude in Columbus, Ohio the kind that stands on the higher side of the highway with a sign right and this guy goes up and pulls up next to him and this homeless dude somehow has Like a professional radio voice.
Scott: and basically the story is this guy.
Scott: he was growing up.
Scott: He got he like he met some radio guy and he fell in love with radio and he wanted to be a radio voice guy.
Scott: He went to school for radio voice.
Scott: He got the great radio voice.
Scott: His life was like, you know pretty good and then he got all druggy and it became a homeless bum.
Scott: but he says they do interview him and he does say that he's been clean for two years and he's not insane like most homeless people and he's just trying to you know, get by like a homeless person does.
Scott: and The one thing that I just don't understand is like if he's not insane and he has the radio voice Right.
Scott: This guy could be totally just fine.
Scott: It's like dude go take a shower cut off your homeless hair, right?
Scott: Yeah buy one pair of clothes, you know at at somewhere.
Scott: I'll wait now.
Rym: now.
Rym: now I can tell you exactly how to get this guy back on his feet.
Rym: step one go find Tay Zonday.
Rym: Step two get this guy.
Rym: step three put him in a recording studio Recorded chocolate rain duet.
Scott: sell a single, you know, I think this guy would be better for doing, you know, just voiceover stuff.
Rym: Hey, it's Q 107 for the meme side of it.
Rym: If you get those two guys together, that would make meme magic.
Scott: But I mean this guy, you know If the guy's not insane He can get a job at a McDonald's like boom instantly and even though he might not have a house yet He could save up, you know live in something.
Rym: if he lived nearby We could try to hire him to come to Connecticut and do all the announcements.
Scott: He's in Columbus, Ohio You know, another thing you could do is you go to any library where they have computers, right?
Scott: You get a cookie cutter website.
Scott: You know for zero dot a free cookie cutter crap website with some ads on it and then be like I will do Voiceovers for you five bucks, you know?
Scott: instead of a free PayPal account people send him five bucks.
Scott: He could record You know a voiceover with a shitty microphone on the library computer and email it to them as a wav file with audacity or some shit and you can start a little tiny business from the library computer until he gets a laptop and then he Could work out of Starbucks.
Rym: Where is he gonna record though?
Scott: in the library in the Starbucks in the Starbucks?
Rym: So I'm sitting there drinking my latte and then next to me suddenly.
Scott: Hey, it's Tuesday Yeah, so He's a homeless guy You know, he'd be a dad be his job and eventually, you know, if he saved up he could get.
Scott: he could get an apartment.
Scott: I'm sure you know, it's Columbus, Ohio.
Scott: It's not like New York.
Scott: You could live in an apartment for pretty cheap.
Scott: I'm sure there's a place with low rents.
Rym: I was gonna lean in to try to do the proper, you know Swallow the mic radio voice but my pop filters kind of in the way and then once he's that far easy He's looking pretty good.
Scott: So so go homeless.
Scott: guy with talents
Rym: met a moment kind of important because it might disrupt Geeknight's one last time before we're back on our you know, normal schedule coming up not this weekend but next weekend, January 13 14 15 and 16th in Alexandria, Virginia, we will be at mag
Scott: fest
Rym: The ninth mag fest doing nine panels.
Rym: now doing three panels We are doing losing should be fun, which is a panel.
Rym: We did it.
Rym: a bunch of packs is slightly redone.
Rym: We've updated it a little bit.
Scott: It needs update.
Rym: We might have an hour and a half instead of an hour Whoa, which means for the first time ever we could take questions that add Scott's rules of question asking.
Rym: Ah, they're already in there.
Rym: All right, and we are going to be on two panels with the mag nine nine gaming intellectuals.
Rym: I'm not sure if they counted me and Scott as one mag nine or two.
Rym: So there might be the mag ten For mag fest nine.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: we're not on the mag fest website and they don't have a schedule up But we know what we're doing.
Rym: Yes, there were.
Rym: there are long email threads about this But suffice it to say we will also in addition to losing should be fun beyond Technical changes in game design and we'll be on achievements and meta gaming.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that one's gonna be.
Rym: I hope someone disagrees with me throw down.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I hope someone's like what's wrong with Zynga.
Rym: They make great games.
Rym: Anyway, the I don't think that'll happen.
Scott: Yeah mag fest, you know, it's I don't think my.
Scott: you know The other cons we go to right like even packs where I play try to play a lot of games.
Scott: You know, the panels are still pretty significant at mag fest.
Scott: I'm feeling the panels less significant because it's four days of drunkenness in a hotel non-stop.
Scott: I'm definitely feeling in concerts a lot more gaming concert activity.
Rym: We have very few responsibilities at the con.
Rym: I mean packs.
Rym: we do a lot of stuff other than just our panels here.
Scott: Nothing Absolutely packs you also.
Scott: it's like well you have to go to the opening whatever and you have to go to the closing and you Have to write.
Scott: but at at mag fest is like what do I have to go to nothing?
Rym: Also my own stuff the con unlike packs well both packs is which are right near home.
Rym: I go to lunch.
Rym: I mean downtown Seattle pretty rockin.
Rym: downtown Boston pretty rockin.
Rym: There's nothing going on in Alexandria, Virginia by this hotel except mag fest.
Rym: I should also warn people who are attending.
Rym: if you are not aware parking at mag fest sucks balls According to other people.
Scott: I we don't know for sure.
Rym: Best website itself says hey our parking sucks.
Scott: I believe you basically cannot park here.
Rym: figure something out.
Rym: Try not to drive.
Scott: I believe it.
Rym: So, uh, look at the website.
Rym: They have a bunch of helpful hints, which basically boil down to don't park in the fire lane.
Rym: They towed like 12 dozen cars last year.
Rym: Don't park out on the street where they will tell you.
Rym: Don't park at the stores where they were told you.
Rym: don't park in front of the apartments across the street where they will tell you.
Rym: Also this weekend You can go even if you're going to mag fest.
Rym: on Friday is another nerd NYC game night.
Rym: I think coffee downtown willing to it will be.
Scott: the best weekend is a recess double recess Yes, and Sunday in New York City all gaming.
Rym: So if you are not going to mag fest because you are a sad loser, or maybe you can't get there.
Rym: I mean Then you can go to the recess which is basically two days of concentrated gaming And if you don't know what the nerd NYC gaming stuff is like this weekend on Friday You can go to their normal thing.
Rym: And if you don't live in New York well Loser one other meta item is you know our forum, right?
Scott: You know the way it works.
Scott: is you apply for you know to be registered and then we approve?
Rym: I've denied a bunch of people.
Scott: Yes, we have.
Scott: you know, we were originally approving anyone who typed any English.
Scott: now There is a section on the application.
Scott: pretty much you enter and you know username email address.
Scott: It's it's almost nothing right?
Scott: Password.
Scott: but there is one box where it says tell us why you want to join and a lot of people would type something in There like I want to discuss the podcast.
Scott: Well, that's you know, that's a complete sentence.
Scott: So I would you know, I could go for that.
Scott: I could approve that but a lot of people would write things like Discussion and I'm like up from now on.
Scott: I used to approve something like that.
Scott: You know what bothers me is and give them the benefit of the doubt and then reject them once they started spamming.
Rym: the time When I do I get someone who's like discussion or a penis or something.
Rym: They're a real person but half the time now they're a spam bot.
Scott: so basically when you type into that box Write something that proves you're not a spam should update the text to say basically type something to prove that you are human.
Scott: Yeah It's like write a complete sentence or write something that proves that you're a listener of the podcast Like I want to talk about last episode or something, you know That's not just a word like.
Scott: hey Cuz I'm just gonna reject that because there's been some spamming.
Rym: You just have to prove to us that you were human and if you got rejected at all You basically could.
Rym: you did not prove to me that you were actually human.
Scott: Yeah, if you're a human and you got rejected apply again and just type something more significant in that box.
Scott: Now if you type something more significant, I don't want to use a capture because someone could break a capture.
Scott: this I'm the judge of it, you know as opposed to the capture being the judge of it.
Rym: Yeah, I can approve or disprove a couple hundred of these a day if I need to.
Scott: it scales pretty well Yeah, and if we're getting so many we can't handle it approving and disproving.
Rym: I think at that point we'll be able to hire a moderate.
Scott: That means we're so popular that we're doing pretty good.
Rym: So Super Meat Boy SMB Super Mario Brothers Homage perhaps perhaps not really kind of if they call them Super Meat Boy 3.
Rym: I would have agreed because Mario 3 is pretty much one of the most tightest most rock-solid Platform 2d platformers the world has ever seen.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Indeed.
Scott: It is No, I'm a super meat boy, right?
Scott: I first actually saw the game being played at PAX West, right?
Scott: It was part of the PAX 10.
Rym: I believe yeah, I was pretty goddamn indifferent to it.
Scott: to be honest Yeah, I don't know what I saw being played there.
Scott: I basically what I saw was a guy who was doing wall jumps, right and he had to be just so precise So as not to die and everyone was like, oh, oh and I'm sitting there watching thinking.
Scott: Oh man, I could totally do it.
Scott: No, I would fail.
Scott: also right it's like is everyone there was you know had the platforming skills and everyone would.
Scott: you know You'd fail a whole bunch until you eventually hit it just right and that's the super meat boy is it's a. it's a platforming game And it's not a puzzle platformer, right?
Rym: You know, there are some nominal puzzles like figure like later in hell.
Rym: There'll be a whole bunch of portals and it's kind of a. can you figure out the way through followed by?
Rym: Can you actually do it now that you figured it out?
Scott: Yeah, I mean but there's not that much figuring.
Scott: I'm.
Scott: puzzle platformers are usually more along the lines of okay You know, there's a block puzzle.
Rym: pick up the block run with it drop it somewhere.
Scott: Yeah, that kind of stuff this is or you know, like braid.
Scott: braid is a puzzle platformer, right?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: can you jump?
Scott: It's can you figure out?
Rym: One definition of puzzle is just whether or not it's trivial to solve or not.
Rym: I mean if you're an intelligent person, I mean technically any single-player game is a puzzle, right?
Rym: I mean if you're playing tic-tac-toe against an AI and you're not that bright.
Rym: It's a puzzle.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But you know Mario vs.
Scott: Donkey Kong that is like the truth, you know, that's for me is like the classic.
Scott: What is a puzzle platformer that is a puzzle?
Rym: The thing with meat boy is that it?
Rym: it?
Rym: there are many of this so-called the genre of ultra hard precision platformers.
Scott: And yeah, there's like n-plus meat boy.
Scott: I want to be the guy is my favorite.
Rym: of all these.
Rym: I think they're all legitimate games.
Scott: Meat boy is the only one that is both harsh and fair Simultaneously that is you know, if you watch angry video game nerd you will see pretty much all of these incredibly old games that you know frustrate the angry video game nerd and make him so angry.
Scott: and the reason they make him so angry is because the design of These games is either you know is unfair or just broken.
Scott: right, you know, there'll be games where you die in one hit.
Scott: Okay, that could be fair, but you didn't get hit.
Scott: if you actually look at the pixels You did not get hit but it the game register to hit.
Scott: or there'll be games where?
Scott: You know, you'll have to make some ridiculous jump But the ridiculous jump is actually like one pixel too far or Ninja Turtles, right?
Scott: you know you try to make this jump but you fall through and You can actually walk across but it's not obvious that you can walk across.
Scott: the design of the game is busted.
Scott: It's that you're not totally sure.
Scott: you know that this is possible.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that was intentional possibly but Super Meat Boy right.
Scott: basically while it is hard as balls and while you will die a billion times It is 100% fair and perfectly designed, you know.
Scott: The first thing they did that was a work that was genius is they made the main character meat boy a square, right?
Scott: Because he's a square.
Scott: the game has absolutely perfect collision detection right to the pixel Right.
Scott: if meat boy touches a chainsaw blade, you know It detects perfectly whether that one pixel of chainsaw hit him.
Scott: and then he dies Instantly and you instantly retry.
Scott: you have to wait and you know to go.
Scott: it's just okay.
Scott: retry instant, right?
Scott: No frustrating waiting.
Scott: No suffering.
Rym: Just go at it again, but at the same time no waypoints.
Rym: So you still have to beat the level in a whole go?
Rym: But every level is kind of broken up in almost two parts and like you'll get past the first part and then you have to Deal with the second part you'll die a lot there.
Rym: but watching people play it's cool to see the the growth of mastery very quickly where a player will be Like.
Rym: they'll struggle with the first half and then they'll be able to do the first half without dying Trivially in the course of solving the second half.
Rym: It's kind of like all the old 90s NES games the experience of playing Mario 1 all the way through all the way through all the way through Compressed into an individual level.
Scott: Yeah, and this is what I like is, you know too many games nowadays, right?
Scott: they basically let you save all the time or You know, you're basically constant.
Scott: You never have to redo anything and there's no punishment for dying, right?
Rym: granted I don't want to go back to the old days where I would die at the end of ninja Gayden and have to start at the beginning of ninja gay.
Scott: fuck that.
Scott: but you know super meat boy is the exact right balance.
Scott: you Die, it was fair.
Scott: It didn't cheat you out of you know, it didn't?
Scott: you know, Rob you the design wasn't misleading.
Scott: You died.
Scott: fair and square right?
Scott: There is a fair and square way to beat every level, right?
Scott: You just didn't do it now.
Scott: So now you're gonna do this.
Scott: we save you know.
Scott: last level you beat.
Scott: it's cool.
Scott: Just do this level again and as a result your skill your the human skill you actually improve not some stat improving.
Scott: You improve.
Rym: now granted the cheap death is a good mechanic mostly for humor like those games like I want to be the guy I don't enjoy playing them, but I understand why people would.
Rym: that is a human game Watching other people play those games.
Rym: I love nothing more than seeing Mario hit the hidden coin block and fall into the pit.
Rym: Yep, but that'll never get old to me.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not fair.
Scott: nor is it good, right?
Scott: but super meat boy is way hard perhaps even harder than those games and Perfectly fair.
Rym: I'll argue those games are good.
Rym: They're just a different kind of game.
Rym: I don't like them and I can argue why I don't like them.
Scott: The other thing is that those games are often games of memory, right?
Scott: You have to memorize the way to get through the level much like Ikaruga Yes, whereas super meat boy is not a game of memory, right?
Scott: You can easily, you know see the way through the level at least most of the time, right?
Scott: Because there's usually you know, only one way to go.
Rym: So it's those goddamn laser eyes.
Scott: So 90% 99% of the game is execution, right?
Scott: Can you execute the path that you see before you you know?
Scott: And if you're gonna if you keep trying and stick to it You will be able to.
Scott: unless you're an old man with like a palsy, right?
Scott: You will succeed at getting through it eventually and even though the game gets harder You will improve and beat it.
Rym: I want to talk about the replay system because that is a stroke of brilliance.
Rym: I played games like this before but when I got to a really frustrating level, I'd play it for like 10-15 minutes.
Rym: You'll retry like a hundred times and then I would get to the point of fuck this and turn the game off with meat boy.
Rym: I want to see my dead meats.
Rym: I want to see the thousand times I failed.
Rym: so the longer you try and fail at one the more you want to not give up in this Current session until you beat it.
Scott: Yep, because then what happens is as soon as you beat the level it shows you every single Playthrough of the level you just played simultaneously.
Rym: So it's kind of like all the meat boys converge on the optimal solution.
Scott: Yep It's it's.
Scott: it's quite a thing It's so it just.
Rym: it's surprisingly satisfying and I really think it is the only reason a lot of people continue to play super meat boy.
Rym: perhaps if you beat one level and then you play the next one and it's like the number of deaths you have experienced is An inverse relationship to the likelihood you will stop before you beat that level.
Scott: The other thing I really like about this game is you look at a lot of other indie games lately and they're actually kind of Short, right like Machinarium with the fact was not a significant game, right?
Scott: But super meat boy.
Scott: at times this game has been like two dollars and change on Steam at times, right?
Scott: But meanwhile The game is really long.
Scott: It has a significant number of levels in a significant size.
Scott: and on top of that, right?
Scott: There are many many warp zones with additional levels to play and characters and a whole bunch of characters to play with and You can always replay a level to try to get the bandage.
Scott: if you didn't get the bandage fuck those bandages.
Scott: And if you didn't get an a-plus on the level by beating it fast enough You can replay it to get an a-plus and as soon as you get an a-plus on a level you can you can then play That level in Dark World mode, which is even harder.
Scott: So the game is just this incredible Amount of replay value that That you know is available to you.
Rym: So how do you orient yourself?
Rym: because I use my left thumb on the analog stick and I use the right trigger to run.
Scott: I've been used in switching between d-pad and analog stick.
Rym: I use the d-pad on when I'm if ever I'm walking like it's a precision thing where I'm actually walking and I've let go of Run always d-pad.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but the rest of the time I use the stick and I just it feels more I Don't.
Rym: I throw it back and forth pretty hard.
Scott: The thing is I wish that there was more.
Scott: If you know if I had the better d-pad than that one I'd probably use it all the time just because I'm a d-pad kind of guy, but it doesn't really matter I can switch it off.
Scott: and as for the you know, I used to just be holding down the you know The X button to go fast.
Rym: Well, you're used to playing a Mario game where you're always holding B.
Scott: Yeah, right, but I just you know, I've only found out that you could hold the right trigger to go fast.
Scott: You know and people were talking about it.
Scott: So now I'm experimenting with that, but I still think you know Just used to holding down.
Rym: You know the trigger is better for me cuz it free kind of like when I you play FPS as I have walk forward as My right mouse button, which is good in some FPS is but in other FPS is it kind of loads down my mouse hand when?
Rym: I'm aiming Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot going on there.
Rym: Oh, I also enjoy all the weird kind of Easter eggs Like.
Rym: the cutscenes are good.
Rym: They're short.
Rym: They're they're nice homage to old games like Castlevania Ninja.
Rym: Hey, then And the the - worlds that apparently you haven't found yet.
Scott: Well, the - world apparently is is a completely random thing, right?
Scott: Sometimes just randomly when a level loads a meat girl Right is is all glitched out and if you touch her if you actually win on that exact moment and touch her You will go to the - world which had never been to -
Rym: world's fun, but you only get three lives.
Rym: I've never beaten my hate that.
Scott: you know Some of the warp zones with the ones of the weird characters you can keep trying and I like those but the ones Where you're pixelated meat boy, and you only have three lives.
Scott: Ah, fuck those I can't beat.
Scott: like, you know, like some of those like I definitely could beat them.
Scott: Well, the trouble had infinite lives, you know.
Rym: That's the thing that you get the old 8-bit experience But in limited doses.
Rym: you can still have that because I like the limited lives.
Rym: it reminds me that I am relying on the crush of meat boy dies a thousand goddamn times because I Throw caution to the wind.
Rym: I've got two thousand some deaths and I'm only about most of the way through hell.
Scott: The other thing I really like about the game right is that you know a lot of games, you know, for example Borderlands, right?
Scott: These are games that blow their load early right, you know.
Scott: at the beginning of the game They'll have a whole bunch of interesting stuff.
Scott: They'll keep introducing you to and then once you get to the middle of the game They basically stretch the game out.
Rym: a castle crashers a castle crashers, right?
Scott: They'll stretch the game out with a whole bunch of regular stuff.
Scott: right castle crashers.
Scott: early in the game There's a whole bunch of exciting stuff gladiator fights, you know.
Scott: And then there's the level where you had to run away on when you're riding on the.
Rym: the animal also Just the design the music the sets and it all kind of gets standing after a few levels.
Scott: It's basically walk down the street and beat guys up in the snow walk down the street beat guys up in the desert walk down You know, it's like they stop making special stuff after a certain point, you know meat boy keeps it fresh even in later levels.
Scott: They're introducing new elements like the glowing pulsating bouncy things and then the the homing guns and then lasers.
Rym: And then, you know different ways to use the key holes for demon heads come out and then explode into six additional.
Scott: Do you know?
Scott: conveyor belts to go up and shoot you up into the sky?
Scott: The monster that sort of floats after you slowly like a beholder even though it has a lot more to two more eyes You know, but no eye stalks, you know.
Scott: They keep introducing new stuff and keeping it fresh and even though there's a lot of levels They were all.
Scott: it seems like they put the full effort into designing each level.
Scott: Wasn't like?
Rym: I can name it was not like.
Scott: there's some levels where that are designed Well and some levels that they just sort of did off the cuff right.
Scott: remember It's like Mario 3 or Mario 3 where they put the full design effort into every level.
Rym: the sky world that had both a bottom Part a tower and a top part.
Scott: That's the best guy.
Rym: I have some goods.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: sky world was good.
Rym: It's a very big shoe, but giant world was also pretty damn fine.
Scott: Yeah, they put the full design effort into every level and there's a lot of levels, you know And they didn't skimp out on anything.
Scott: So you actually want to keep going and keep going and there's a tiny plot to go with it.
Scott: That is some tiny humors.
Scott: that is, you know, also worthwhile.
Rym: I will admit though I love the game and I'm going to beat it for sure.
Scott: I'm definitely gonna beat it but I can only do like two levels a day.
Rym: when I say beating it I mean, I'm gonna beat the whole game normal and I'm gonna beat the whole game dark and Maybe the whole game doc.
Rym: I'm gonna go for it But I'm not gonna go after a hundred percent bandages or a hundred percent unlocks or any of that.
Scott: I don't go for a hundred percent and pretty much any any games, right?
Rym: The only game I have done in the last like decade a hundred percent was advanced Wars.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, I mean just I could do we should do a show about going a hundred percent in games.
Scott: But I mean, it seems like a lot of games these days.
Scott: what they'll do is they'll make a game You know and it's like you've seen every level.
Scott: you've got to the end boss you beat him, right?
Scott: But now this get like Mario 64 is like it's like okay you've beaten Mario 64. you went to every level.
Scott: You got at least one star.
Scott: in every level.
Scott: you beat King Koopa, but if you get all 120 stars Then you can you know, then you'll really beat it, but it's like You know all that process of getting the those hundred and twenty stars is not, you know It's.
Scott: it's more tedium than where is the before.
Scott: that point just beating the game feels like there was more substance to it.
Rym: Of course Super Meat Boy bothers me in one regard and a lot of games do this Remember like when Mario 2 was re-released on the DS or the Game Boy Advance or whatever Yep, and it was.
Rym: it was way easy like they gimped the hell out of it.
Rym: Yeah, but then they added those stupid Yoshi eggs.
Rym: You had to find the Yoshi eggs.
Rym: They're hidden everywhere.
Rym: It's basically impossible without a fact.
Rym: Yep, if you get them all you get jack and shit.
Rym: Yep, Super Meat Boy Rewards you with stuff playable characters.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean unlocking I don't you know, I'm not a fan.
Rym: No, I hate unlocking.
Rym: That's the thing.
Rym: My problem is that I'm not gonna hundred percent it and as a result, I'm not gonna get these characters.
Scott: They're neat.
Scott: The thing is I have high hopes that there's gonna be an editor for the PC version.
Scott: We're just gonna let people make their own levels, which is gonna be real good.
Scott: I foresee a lot of good stuff coming out of that that I'll probably play and get into that maybe a little bit.
Scott: cuz modding.
Scott: That will be a lot easier than modding say, you know, anything else is 2d.
Scott: and on top of that I have some high hopes that somebody will just make a hack or you just download a save file and then you have 100% on the PC and then you can play whatever parts that you didn't unlock that you wanted to check out.
Scott: You know try out all the characters once Separate show on unlocking.
Rym: cuz I I'm done with unlocking as a mechanic.
Scott: Yeah, it's bullshit.
Scott: It can
Rym: be there
Scott: But like I just beats I just beat Mario Galaxy 2 and then after you beat it It unlocks this extra world and it's like I started playing through the extra world because they're actually full levels in there like a rainbow Road and all this stuff and I was like, ooh, I actually want to play all these things and you know It's like okay get five more stars and then you can play this world.
Scott: Okay, you have five more stars You can play this world.
Scott: Okay get ten more and you can play this world.
Scott: Okay get ten more to put fuck you.
Scott: Yeah, there's only like two or three worlds left.
Rym: I haven't gotten to but it's And I see multiple characters that require more than 50.
Rym: Fuck you.
Scott: Yeah Well, I think the minecraft guy requires the most right cuz he can just cheat.
Scott: he can just like edit the levels.
Scott: You can just make.
Rym: I do like that how the meat boy is the real game.
Rym: But yet the other characters are just the weird fun stuff.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: Yeah Anything else to go.
Scott: use it on that weird note.