Scott: It's Wednesday, October 12th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is the GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we start to go through the 52.
Scott: Ah shit Let's do this.
Scott: So I was buying the book club book on Amazon wind sand and stars by Antoine de saju petty which I'm waiting for a French person to tell me if I'm pronouncing that in in properly or not.
Rym: But I was doing the same and I recently bought the brand new the newest newest cheapest cheapest Kindle Mm-hmm, so I thought oh I bought the Kindle because I don't want to carry physical books around.
Rym: I will buy the e-book.
Rym: Guess what book does not have any book?
Scott: This book.
Scott: so also if it did the Kindle version would probably be more expensive because a brand new copy is $11.
Scott: a used copy is way less.
Rym: So I look and I can't get a Kindle version.
Rym: so I click the button that says tell the publisher you want a Kindle version.
Rym: I know that's not gonna help me out.
Rym: Yeah in the short term.
Rym: I Go on the Pirate Bay.
Rym: I don't find it which is expected.
Rym: I don't expect there to be a brisk trade in piracy of just random books.
Scott: It's not random.
Rym: It's a very important popular Yeah But it's not a book that picked out at random.
Rym: The majority of people on the internet are seeing.
Scott: imagine there has to be little prints on Kindle.
Scott: at least write these.
Scott: the other book Double book, but anyway, we're not gonna mention again in the meta moment.
Rym: Not again.
Scott: No not gonna mention it ever Not in this meta moment of today because he mentioned in the opening bit anyway.
Rym: So I go on Google and I type name of the book space ebook First link PDF of the whole book.
Rym: Yep, and I now can say that on this Kindle I have 11 project Gutenberg books and one book that I pirated right.
Scott: so I was good.
Scott: I was thinking man.
Scott: I should get it.
Scott: You know, I need free shipping.
Rym: Let me get a second book right because you think of any book you wanted.
Scott: I was thinking you know because of the City massacres monster madness Which you should be watching every day of the month of October you should.
Scott: I was thinking hey, I've read the Frankenstein But I haven't read the Dracula Gutenberg.
Scott: so I'm going.
Scott: I look for a copy of Dracula and I as soon as I do the search I look at the results and I'm Oh, this is in the public domain, isn't it?
Scott: I went to project Gutenberg and I put it on my iPhone in the iBooks.
Rym: Emily recently read it and I was like Oh reading Dracula why and she's like Gutenberg.
Rym: Yeah, and I was like, oh and then I downloaded it.
Scott: So I'm like, well now I need something to fill this fucking cart and I had nothing.
Scott: So I just left it in the cart without buying it.
Scott: and then I got an email from Amazon That was like hey, you got an Amazon credit card and I'm like, yeah, that's why you sent me this email.
Scott: And they're like, you know what if you have an Amazon credit card and you buy some kitchen shit right now with this code 20% off even more off than the regular?
Scott: did you buy some Calphalon stuff?
Scott: I don't know not yet But I need to.
Scott: I need to buy a kitchen thing to fill up the cart and you if there's nothing you need I want a stayed like eight or nine inch Calphalon omelet pan omelet pan specific.
Scott: You know the ones are the curves that let you flip over the omelet.
Rym: Yes I don't need.
Rym: I already have a griddle.
Rym: I have an iron grill and I have a Calphalon kind of scary worn-out griddle Mm-hmm, and I got that gigantic like Calphalon serving dish broiling everything thing I actually kind of get it.
Scott: want to get a stainless steel pan that has these straight sides as opposed to the curved side.
Rym: Why?
Scott: because it's better for frying because the oil doesn't come out.
Rym: It comes out the same.
Rym: get the the shield instead.
Scott: Yeah, I kind of want to get one of those pans.
Rym: Okay, what you should get is the griddle that has the curvy bits to keep the bacon ever So slightly out of the.
Scott: I'm not taking for bacon I'm talking for like.
Scott: when you fill it with like, you know, a few millimeters of oil and go to town.
Rym: Yeah, I don't cook like that lately.
Scott: I've been doing more of that kind.
Rym: I tend to cook less with oil and more with butter a lot of sautee Partly because with Calphalon I don't need the oil for the nonstick.
Scott: Well you do.
Scott: if you're frying something I don't fry shit anymore.
Rym: Yeah, I'm beyond that.
Scott: I like to pray.
Rym: I do.
Scott: I like fried things But I see trying just regular frying pan fry.
Rym: I kind of want a deep fryer.
Scott: That's all you I had as a kid.
Rym: We had a fry daddy.
Rym: We just make potato, you know fried potatoes and that's all you.
Rym: Okay The only problem with it was kind of scary that when we were done.
Rym: frying the oil would cool down.
Rym: Congeal put a lid on it stick it in the cupboard.
Rym: a month later frying in the same oil.
Rym: That's nothing wrong with that no, but it was a little I don't know.
Rym: that oil I think was handed down for my great-grandparents.
Scott: I'm also.
Scott: I was also starting to look at.
Scott: you know, perhaps, you know food process II choppy bits Processor little circle ones that have a chopper chopper and also all the spinny blade also.
Scott: Yeah, maybe also the Cuisinart the big mix II.
Rym: I Don't need the mixing.
Scott: You know what now that's about the biggest one.
Scott: That's like the epic one.
Scott: I'm just thinking about the regular.
Rym: the majority of our listeners are in high school or college.
Rym: None of them.
Rym: Okay, our baking our cooking in any fashion.
Scott: I also started looking at perhaps, you know some crafts to do in the winter.
Rym: I watered my lawn the other day mowed it trim the grass did the edges.
Scott: No one cares Anyway, but we'll talk about that another time.
Scott: Okay, then maybe that could be a Thursday bit crafts.
Rym: So, of course the New York comic-con is this weekend as news not as a metabit because we're not Doing any panels at it.
Rym: if you want to see fan panels at it as far as I can or even most professional panels At least on our level of professional, you know D list celebrity are not in a panel room, but they're on a stage.
Scott: Well, the anime ones are in the anime ghetto, which is now on the top floor of the convention center.
Rym: now I recall remember we went to the auto show many years ago during that rainy ass day.
Rym: Yep I remember that that top floor which I rarely go to Was basically the equivalent of that like Sun annex at PAX next to the real expo hall Mmm, so that's even sadder than the anime ghetto last year.
Scott: Yeah, my ghetto is gonna be very sad this year.
Rym: I know it's talking about the New York anime festival at all But you have some.
Scott: they do have some top to your guests the Makoto shinkai and whatever how Anyway, but I'm gonna show.
Scott: I actually went through.
Scott: they have an iPhone app.
Scott: It's not so bad and I went through and made a schedule of stuff that I would go to see if I really if I Would really cared.
Scott: so they're screening all of my koto shinkai stuff.
Scott: So it's like well, why not go see voice of a distant star and five centimeters per second on a big screen in my house.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: indeed that's you know, and I'll basically all his stuff's gonna get screened.
Scott: There's gonna be an archaea entertainment panel.
Scott: I got so many press releases about that It was kind of ridiculous, but I guess David Peterson's gonna be on it, which is the only reason to go to it.
Scott: Mouse guard was mentioned in the press release But you think is you can just walk up to him at the archaea booth where Luke Crane will also be at certain times Hang selling their box set Mouse Guard RPGs.
Scott: So why not?
Scott: There's a Madoka screening on Friday night by anaplex Subbed first three episodes.
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: I know they're not going to annotate it or emcee it or anything.
Scott: There's gonna be some Miku stuff because you know Those guys are gonna be there again and because their panel crypt on future media their panel last year like most of the anime panels Filled the goddamn room.
Scott: Yeah, there's gonna be Makoto Shinkai in conversation with Roland Celts But he is the most important thing here our most important thing.
Scott: This is Saturday night.
Scott: This is if you go to one thing at comic-con One panel because most of the panels are worthless.
Scott: if you go to one panel go to this panel.
Scott: You ready.
Scott: Saturday, October 15th 815 at night, which might be a very inconvenient time.
Scott: Yes, indeed black dynamite ah Shit is an exciting new animated series going to adult swim.
Scott: in 2012. the series further chronicles blah blah blah.
Scott: Scott Sanders will host Q&A and show never before seen footage.
Rym: I might have to go to that That's right.
Scott: It's kind of our cast members Michael J. J white Byron mens Kim Whitey executive producer Carl Jones and producer Scott Sanders.
Scott: black dynamite and That's pretty.
Scott: I was gonna be.
Scott: Hasbro is gonna be there and it seems like they're mostly pushing transformers.
Scott: So we just.
Scott: I'm gonna go and be like what the fuck are you like sleeping?
Scott: No one gives a shit about your transformers.
Scott: Where are the ponies?
Scott: Yeah, I. why is Celestia white?
Scott: Why do you always give morning?
Rym: Why is she pink pink?
Rym: Why isn't she white, right?
Scott: Why do you always get boring corporate answers and keep secrets?
Scott: How come you're so bad at brand man?
Rym:  I probably can't say a lot But I have talked to people on the staff on the back end and most of this was personal conversations.
Rym: so I feel unethical.
Rym: comic-con staff or the read and Comic-con.
Scott: I thought you're some of Hasbro's dad.
Rym: No, no read side.
Rym: Okay now Hasbro My talks with them have been mostly from the perspective of I own your fucking stop.
Rym: Stop fucking up your property.
Rym: I own a several hundred actual percent of the shares.
Scott: is that?
Rym: oh very little almost nothing.
Rym: So don't give a shit about no, but I'm investor and I complain and I get these.
Rym: I get surprisingly The same answers that everyone else gets.
Rym: I guess that's not surprising.
Rym: No The answer to everything is we do not have any plans one way or the other for insert Whatever you fucking emailed us about.
Scott: that's right.
Rym: But anyway, uh With the best I can share in terms of My Little Pony is that I Warned.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: five or six different people throughout read exhibitions And the people who run the New York comic-con and said hey I know you're talking to the franchise people and I know you're talking to Hasbro.
Scott: Hasbro's got a big-ass booth on the map and they got a panel.
Rym: I said and I quote Trust me on this.
Rym: I know it sounds crazy.
Rym: add My Little Pony friendship is magic to the list of franchises.
Rym: You want talent merchandise and or Your product stuff from and I don't think anyone actually followed through on that.
Rym: Which is what's funny is that I told them this before ponies became internet crazy.
Rym: Yeah, this was a long time ago.
Rym: Yeah, so if there isn't the pony stuff you expected the con It's pretty much Hasbro and or the New York comic-con's fault and not any lack of people telling you They so dumb.
Scott: The thing is the people.
Scott: it's like if you it's like I'm digging in a mine I'm Hasbro mining for money by making toys and I find some gold and Everyone walks down is like gold gold and I'm just like yeah fuck that gold.
Rym: I'm mining.
Rym: I'm looking for silver.
Scott: Yeah, that's the ticket.
Scott: overs the ticket.
Scott: I haven't found any yet, but I'll let you know There's so much gold here.
Scott: dig it up and fuck that gold studio.
Scott: I don't like yellow.
Rym: It's funny because a year ago when I was talking to you know people in the industry about My Little Pony I'd basically present it on the lines of look I know this sounds crazy But people with money are interested in this franchise.
Rym: you could make some money off of them and I thought you know the rationalizations I gave to these people were pretty.
Rym: I was reaching a little bit.
Rym: I did not expect it to get as big as it got.
Scott: to be perfectly honest There's a handmade Fluttershy plushie going for six hundred and forty dollars on eBay.
Rym: You know, what's fucked up.
Rym: I clicked on that and when it was only six hundred thirty dollars for a second, I thought you know, I Didn't do it.
Scott: All right, let's move on let's get to this anyway your comic-con will be there.
Scott: stuff's going on right real quick.
Scott: This is article pretty interesting from the BBC about You know how people act when they're drunk and it basically it's an anthropologist and she talks about how look There's some things that are caused by alcohol directly narrowing a vision Short-term memory loss, you know worse coordination worse muscle control worse reaction time Inability to speak clearly etc, but alcohol does not cause.
Scott: cause you to break social rules such as Sleeping around with people or you know act in a fool going crazy getting into fights anything like that.
Scott: alcohol does not directly cause that chemically.
Scott: what causes that?
Scott: is Your cultural belief that alcohol causes that.
Rym: ah what I've said all along about Unsober, well, it's not except.
Scott: Oh, it's not.
Scott: that's not what it is at all.
Scott: It's that you're in a culture and your culture believes, you know Let's say American culture or Canadian culture believes that alcohol causes people to get violent.
Scott: If you're caught if you believe that then drinking alcohol Well will cause you to be violent because you believe that it will happen.
Rym: now We had a Scott.
Rym: will it still cause that if you tell someone about this study first?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm really curious if I mean what theoretically.
Scott: but the thing is if we believe that eating Twizzlers cause people to shit themselves, right?
Scott: Diarrhea that you know cause, you know people to lose bowel control then people would eat Twizzlers and shit themselves.
Scott: It would happen right if we culturally if everyone sort of believed that as a cultural thing.
Rym: That's my point.
Rym: I'm curious if there is an effect if people know about the effect because if that were true You could inoculate people against the effect.
Scott: the thing is I actually I would guess that it knowing wouldn't help you.
Scott: the same way that like knowing a Placebo is a placebo.
Rym: but what if for example you Show someone all this research about Russians and viewers of Russians being drunk and acting in their particular Russian way?
Rym: Could you change someone's social perception to where they act like a different kind of?
Scott: I think you'd have to have like You know to change the whole cultural belief which is farther deep down than the surface, but I wonder how deep it is.
Scott: But you know, but it's like they look and it's like well look Italians Don't get this way when they're drunk because they have a different kind of you know.
Scott: And basically what it comes down to is what we have is we have us and England.
Scott: We have an ambivalent drinking culture whereas other societies like Mediterranean ones and Latin ones they have a What is known as in?
Scott: where's the word?
Scott: Integrated drinking culture?
Scott: Right, which is why they act differently and in fact the integrated drinking cultures drink more than the ambivalent ones like us.
Scott: It's just we go crazy when we drink and they don't.
Rym: so things of the day.
Rym: This is just a Norwegian soldier because you know in Norway you pretty much have to be in the military for some time But we all get into all the details there.
Rym: You can read about it on the Wikipedia.
Rym: But this one particular Norwegian soldier Makes a face every time a cameras pointed at him and there's something about this face.
Scott: He's making the best of a situation.
Rym: There is something about this guy that I find utterly hilarious and I defy you To watch this entire video and not laugh out loud at some point.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So here's someone made a flash game called mega mash.
Scott: This is amazing.
Scott: This is a new kind of video game.
Scott: It's epic.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: You got to play this fucking thing.
Scott: Why is it like they could have made a ton of money if they would have made this like a downloadable steam Xbox Live game.
Scott: The fact that they made it a flash game that's free is crazy.
Scott: Somebody should take this concept and sort of make it bigger and HD and put it on steam and Xbox Live to make a killing.
Scott: Oh my god, this is the greatest Play this shit.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: This isn't a video game like no other video game that has existed that I've ever seen.
Rym: It's like alright it did that kind of cliche thing.
Rym: I see what they're doing.
Rym: I'm see what the oh, oh Yeah, yeah, I want someone to take this and embrace it extend it and make an expert for met a moment.
Scott: We already covered the book club in the upcoming con.
Scott: I just want to say check us out on the internets for our crew.
Scott: calm the GeekNights.
Scott: Rym YouTube account Facebook all the places Internet us.
Rym: our forum is an ivory tower for the elite intellectuals of the internet.
Scott: iTunes review Whatever internet place that you find that you want us to be or we are.
Scott: make it happen.
Scott: spread us around the internets.
Scott: that's how we roll and Along those lines.
Rym: if you want us to appear at a convention or school or whatever and money no No, no, don't tell us because too many people say oh you should go to X convention.
Rym: I'm not gonna put any effort into that.
Rym: tell the convention if an actual organization that's doing a thing approaches us.
Scott: We are much more likely to respond For transportation in hotel rooms If they can offer only badges, but they better be fucking close to us or badass.
Rym: I mean mag fest does not need to pay me to go there.
Rym: I would go there even if I was not a guest.
Scott: that's true.
Rym: All right X does not need to pay me to go there.
Scott: So what was your thing today?
Rym: I did it.
Scott: I forget what it was.
Rym: I forgot what it was already.
Rym: Yes, you really already forgot about the way, you know region.
Scott: All right Norwegian guy good Alright.
Scott: so to reiterate we've talked about this before on the show But you know something I've always complained about with superhero comics specifically the DC and the Marvel is that they are Incomprehensible to normal people who don't know anything about them.
Scott: I mean people have a surface level knowledge of say Batman Superman spider-man from comic from movies and TV, but that's about it.
Scott: So reading comics is something only for nerds and they make all these comics You know for a very small audience and it's this horrible thing.
Scott: and they should just fucking throw all their incomprehensible history out the window and restart from number one and from the beginning and Just make us any normal person can understand.
Scott: and not you know, Marvel did it with the ultimate comics But no do it with the real comics just go for it.
Scott: so DC announced this big relaunch that they were gonna undo all their comics and just start with number one of everything.
Scott: and So they did in the month of sip.
Scott: Well actually starting at the end of August they put out Justice League number one and all through the month of September They released 51 more comics for a total of 52 brand-new number one comics.
Scott: every single DC comic has been reset to number one will relaunched and It was a big deal really big deal.
Scott: So cuz it was such a big deal.
Scott: There was a special deal a Special value deal.
Scott: I could buy all of those number one comics for 80 bucks.
Scott: So I did.
Scott: for the good of GeekNights and for the good of you guys We will now begin going through them all 52 of the comics.
Scott: We'll see how long this takes.
Scott: It'll probably take multiple episodes.
Scott: Maybe to keep the Wednesday episodes free for other things You might have to put them in special episode might revisit the.
Rym: well We'll figure.
Scott: maybe we'll do Wednesday episodes every week until we got a board thing to know.
Rym: We've been especially made because you know me I tend to get Three panels into most underwear pervert comics and be like fuck this.
Scott: But we forced ourselves to read every word on every page of every one of these.
Scott: I even made a chart.
Scott: I counted the number of content pages ad pages house ad pages.
Scott: I. I wrote down the prices of all of them.
Scott: We did a full complete Investigation into this whole thing for you.
Rym: So before we get into the individual comics Let's talk about some trends like the general matter.
Rym: Uh, I mean I was thinking about talking about trends when I came to them But there are a lot of trends one very specifically because you brought it up on the ads and the non-comic content.
Rym: So My perception Reading these is that there were an infinite number of fucking ads.
Rym: there were so many that like I was kind of amazed.
Scott: Okay, the vast majority of the books according to my count had 21 content pages.
Scott: I counted the cover as a content page that I'll accept that.
Scott: Okay, so 20 pages of actual comic panels.
Scott: Usually you're getting a one or two two page spreads right going on in there.
Scott: They also had depending on what week as the weeks went on see I Separated the ads into ads and house ads.
Scott: house ads were ads for DC comics Which also included those final three pages at the end of every book where they sort of did like, you know The newsy crap going on back there.
Scott: All right, and also, you know, for example Here's an ad for Wonder Woman number one in Justice League number one.
Scott: That's a house ad but is an ad for onion news.
Scott: That is not a house ad.
Scott: The thing is even the house ads except for the deus ex one and the onion one actually included superheroes Like.
Scott: here's an ad for converse shoes.
Scott: That's not a house ad.
Scott: so it's got Batman all over it.
Rym: I had a problem with the converse as I wonder if you had the same thing that I knew they were there.
Rym: But every comic I was reading I'd be reading the panels and I hit the next page to my right and I'd be like Batman.
Rym: What's it?
Rym: Oh, it's the ad right every time it got me.
Rym: I'd be like Batman.
Scott: They do that on purpose Fuck you.
Scott: But anyway in there in the most of the books That were 20 pages of kind of 21 pages of content.
Scott: counting the cover there were about 15 ish ad pages.
Scott: So you are getting slightly more content than ad but Not that much.
Rym: That's a pretty bad ratio.
Rym: The other question I have for you is where are there more ads in the comics involving Batman?
Rym: or was that just my perception?
Scott: It depends on the book, right?
Scott: So some of the real some of the books cost four dollars, for example action comics, which we're gonna talk about real soon.
Rym: I didn't know they were different prices There were.
Scott: there were a handful of books that were four dollars instead of three dollars.
Scott: Those ones did have much more content pages.
Scott: For example All Star Western was a four dollar book.
Scott: It had 29 pages of content included.
Scott: It also had the same about the same number of ads 14 ads.
Scott: So when you paid more for a book you got more content without getting more ads.
Rym: All right.
Scott: The other thing is that books involving, you know, the bigger heroes right the more popular books tended to have More ad ads and less house ads.
Scott: for example plain old Batman Had actually less ads.
Scott: overall it still cost three dollars was 25 content pages including the cover eight ads But only three house ads.
Scott: so only 11 ad pages total in in the regular Batman book.
Scott: So they sacrificed.
Scott: but because they're more popular books, right the books with bigger characters in them They were able to have more regular ads and less house ads.
Scott: also books in later weeks once you got to week for you know week for a Lot less house ads because a lot of the house ads were for books in later weeks.
Scott: So the early weeks had more house ads to get you to buy the books for the rest of the month Whereas in the rest of the month They actually had a lot more regular ads for other things or a lot more pages of regular ads for other things,
Rym: huh?
Scott: So yeah, those are those are the general trends.
Scott: once we finish this spreadsheet I'll make it the public on the Google Docs so you can all enjoy.
Rym: Yeah, we have a ranking system.
Scott: We haven't quite worked out my rank my personal ranking system I guess before we begin.
Scott: it was good meh and bad.
Rym: mine was worth the time It took to read it worth the money.
Rym: It would have taken to buy it worth nothing.
Scott: So what I mean by Meg good and bad.
Scott: bad is I would not read it Even if you gave it to me for as a gift, it's so bad Meh is like.
Scott: well I would read it if it was just lying there for free and I really had nothing better to do.
Scott: and Good is I will buy the trade paperback at least the first one based on this one issue, right?
Scott: I would never buy under any circumstances.
Scott: Not a single one of these comics in this.
Rym: for oh my god Don't get me started.
Rym: So I always complain about the format of comics But I have to take it to a new level because I have never Had to read since I was a little kid many of them in a row.
Rym: Here's the problem.
Scott: There are people who will buy who are buying this stack of 52 comics every single month.
Scott: They so far I could have if I wanted to gotten Did all the twos all the threes and all the fours for the same price through DCB service?
Scott: We could have had an equivalent stack Every single my god, and there are people who get that stack every month and read through the whole thing.
Rym: So I'm where am I gonna read these?
Rym: mostly on the subway?
Rym: So it take you know, my subway ride.
Rym: I can read two or three of them So I need to carry at least like six with me.
Rym: Yep Holding more than one of these in my hand at the same time and trying to read one is a disaster waiting to happen.
Rym: Keep the other ones in your bag and swap them, but that's such a pain in the ass in a crowded ass subway.
Scott: I wish that they would just release one big.
Scott: if they released Even though I'm gonna be honest the majority of them the vast majority were bad and mad.
Rym: Oh, you want to release a Japanese style.
Scott: if they really compilation.
Rym: if it was one giant motherfucking book I would subscribe to that.
Scott: I would subscribe to that shit, even though the majority of that book would be bad or mad.
Scott: I would.
Scott: he probably paid 20 bucks a month for that.
Rym: I think I would do for this 52.
Scott: if for this 52 if I would have been one big-ass fucking book even Separate it into two big-ass fucking books.
Scott: put on the Batman books in one and all the other ones.
Rym: That's about accurate.
Scott: All right, and then you know just charge 15 bucks for each book.
Rym: I Might get just the Batman book at that point, but we'll see.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, I think we're gonna have quite differing opinions.
Scott: Let's go into it.
Scott: All right, so we'll get to the other trends.
Scott: when we come to them go right down the list.
Scott: Let's recap Justice League a little bit.
Scott: I already did.
Scott: we already talked about this on a show, but I do want to say the art was Jim Lee.
Scott: It was great.
Rym: I actually really liked the art.
Rym: I really liked that shot of Superman in the last panel.
Scott: I like the colors a lot too high because he had this look on his face.
Rym: I like how Superman's personality is kind of a fuck you.
Rym: I'm Superman.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I like that and I also liked how even this was a true Number one.
Scott: it starts off where like Batman doesn't even know Green Lantern at all Even though it says here five years ago Which is important because this Justice League now having read the other books Makes no sense if it's taking place at the same time as the other ones.
Scott: So this Justice League was actually five years ago Which actually kind of makes me want to read it more a little bit even though I still put it in the met category Because that you know.
Scott: it has nothing to do with these other ones you get sort of the five-year lead-up that go.
Scott: It's the prequel to all the other 51.
Rym: Yep, I also really like how it did not start with origin story.
Rym: It started in media res so that because I feel like cuz I don't want the origin story.
Rym: It's all these 52. imagine if every one of these was the origin story of some super.
Rym: be awful I couldn't have dealt with them.
Scott: No, I don't know.
Scott: So yeah So Justice League gets the met the high met even and probably the first Jeff John's book I've ever said is not bad.
Rym: I would read it if it was presented to me.
Rym: It is definitely worth the time to read because I enjoyed Superman.
Rym: I enjoyed Batman.
Rym: Okay, Green Lantern is still really stupid.
Scott: All right, so now let's go to week one Action.
Scott: action comics number one number one.
Scott: Actually, you're gonna be surprised.
Scott: action comics.
Scott: I put this in the good.
Scott: I'm gonna buy trade number one.
Rym: I actually kind of liked it to though.
Rym: I'm kind of angry about the art.
Scott: I don't know if I would buy trade number two, but I'll buy trade number one.
Rym: So the art was lazy.
Scott: The art was not amazing art.
Scott: There were many books in here, right?
Scott: That were.
Scott: the art blew me away.
Rym: Oh, no, but the art on this one pissed me off right away.
Scott: I didn't piss me off.
Rym: The first two panels pissed me off.
Scott: panel one is two guys in a kind of awkward pose Having conversation and the second panel is exact same panel with the Reds swoosh coming.
Rym: Yes, but they continued their conversation and Come on like that.
Rym: just the fact that they're having this kind of actual conversation They like they make a point like IT - I'm teetotal and their expressions literally don't change.
Rym: They're like their hands are still touching their faces in the same space.
Rym: Just it really looked like some kind of the lower rent comics.
Scott: I tend to read sometimes Yeah, I mean that this didn't.
Scott: I wouldn't say this is bad art But it's pretty much typical comic art completely average for what superhero comics are.
Scott: I also didn't blow me away.
Rym: I had a lot of trouble following what was going on in the action scenes Kind of not so much like you did.
Scott: the overall plot though Definitely made sense, which is good compared to a lot of these other books.
Rym: It mostly made sense.
Rym: I really liked Lex Luthor like the way he was drawn and the way he talked.
Rym: He was really fun.
Scott: What I most liked about this right was that Superman?
Scott: this really isn't a Superman book at least not the Superman That's been in a lot of other recent books.
Scott: This Superman is basically Robocop Right only without the restrictions that Robocop has.
Scott: he doesn't have any directives.
Scott: He's just like yeah, you're bad I'm gonna fuck you over.
Scott: I don't give back your shit about the police.
Scott: I'm coming to fuck you up.
Scott: Yeah, bad businessman.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: I'm gonna take you and drop you over fucking building.
Rym: That's right, and it's like they're like, ah, he broke his hip and Superman just like hey, I was Superman.
Scott: I would probably be pretty close to this Superman which is sort of a fantasy fulfillment sort of Mary Sue situation.
Scott: now It's but I don't give a fuck.
Scott: I like it.
Rym: No, no, cuz it leads into an interesting direction of Superman doesn't give a shit.
Rym: But what if you know the consequences of his actions?
Rym: cause right other?
Rym: Consequences.
Scott: the other thing I really like about it is that this seems to be a lot like the original Action comics, you know 1930 whatever Superman he can only jump.
Rym: he can't fly but he's getting stronger.
Rym: I think he's getting to the point where he will fly.
Scott: Yeah, he in all the other books I was sort of like oh he's flying.
Scott: this isn't the same I wish I was like every other book that had Superman in it.
Scott: I was wishing that it was the action comic Superman because this is the first one I read.
Scott: Well the second book I read right?
Scott: So I was hoping that the all the other books had action comic Superman.
Scott: But if you read the Superman book, it doesn't have action comic Superman.
Scott: Yeah, and I was like, ah, damn it, but actually While it was disappointing not to have the awesome vulnerable can only jump can't fly Just grabs rich people and throws them off buildings.
Scott: action comic Superman in the other books.
Scott: It gives me hope that maybe this action comics will be separate from those other books and it Itself will be much more readable Which is I think the thing that broke the camel's back and moved it over from mad to good.
Rym: the only Hope other than the kind of lazy art in some of the panels was that the the every part of the plot made sense But the way the train thing unfolded was a little weird.
Rym: Yeah, like the the panels didn't really make sense.
Rym: There was a little bit of Naito in there a little bit like it jumped back and forth.
Rym: I'm like, wait, who's he calling?
Rym: You just yelled two names of people and you're drawn kind of derpily Are you?
Rym: oh you're saying your own?
Rym: Okay, you said your own name there.
Rym: I see what's going on But anyway, why that guy have a gun and then like they just like everyone in the subway Just like or the train just like grabbed him.
Rym: But yet I thought was he gonna die on the train with why it didn't make sense.
Scott: I'm waiting for this book to get exciting when the kryptonite comes into play.
Rym: I just want to see Lex Luthor fuck shit up that too.
Rym: He was really funny like the way he's.
Scott: Hmm Yeah, he was definitely messing around with those government guys.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's written by Grant Morrison who is a notoriously Love or hate guy with the superhero fans.
Scott: I haven't really read too much by him even though he's still famous But I like this one and the art is by rags Morales.
Scott: So I know nothing about other than that is a name.
Scott: I have heard of someone who does comic art.
Scott: Apparently he's popular enough to do action comics number one, but the art was not so great.
Rym: Okay, so yeah for me to put it on you know, what worth the money, I think I want to.
Scott: I'm buying trade number one when it's listed.
Rym: I will read it.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Yes Now we move to animal man, which is notable because Jeff Lemire high hopes based on the Jeff Lemire name, but I never heard of Travel Foreman or Dan Green who did the art?
Scott: I did not research them at all either Yeah, but when I looked at this art, I kind of liked it.
Rym: I do too.
Scott: It's not like oh my god This is amazing art, but it was definitely different from all the other books.
Scott: Which is you know to just to do a different style makes me happy.
Rym: I also like how it had Watchmen style text at the beginning Yeah, and those black and white pages.
Rym: when you got to that part I was like, oh shit son though kids if you skipped that first page with just text from a newspaper You're reading comics wrong.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I think a lot of the ultra hardcore fans probably skip that page Maybe and I liked how it then it shows you on page two.
Scott: You know animal man is reading that page.
Scott: you just read which makes it even cooler, right?
Scott: Yep, imagine if like in Watchmen when you see like that, you know history of the Minuteman and then like our man was reading it Like in his you know, that'd be cool.
Rym: Anyway, but I I really like this one because that last panel I did not expect that to be where this was going.
Scott: That was let me remember what the last panel was.
Rym: She's like, I just wanted a pet dad.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't see that one coming along at all.
Rym: That was shit.
Rym: I am really this is straight-up worth the money.
Scott: I will read all of this until the thing about that the whole book as a whole that I like the most.
Scott: obviously It's the book has a mess, you know an animal a pro animal message to push.
Rym: But so what is the message though?
Rym: Because it seems to be partly that maybe like there's something primal and perhaps Morally ambivalent about it.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing that I liked about it the most was that it had the Normal family dynamic right.
Scott: a lot of books, you know when they got a family in there or something like that.
Scott: It's not normal.
Scott: But the animal man was totally acting like a normal dude and his family acted like normal people at the dialogue was.
Rym: it wasn't Dialogue it wasn't one-liners.
Scott: It wasn't Over dramaticized soap opera dialogue like, you know or melodramatic corny bullshit.
Scott: It was he was hanging with his family the way he would.
Scott: you would hang with a family if you were animal man and he was you know, the fact that he just acted like such, you know, a normal person would reasonably act in his Extraordinary circumstances was pretty cool.
Scott: And I'm really gonna be excited to see how he reacts to the extraordinary circumstances of that last battle.
Rym: I am also very happy that while it is clearly in the universe of the rest of this BS None of that BS appears to be ready to overlap.
Scott: Yeah There was no appearing of you know, Batman's or Superman's even though it's clearly in the DC Universe.
Scott: None of that came into the play.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: They paid lip service to it with Oh, yeah, all the other superheroes.
Scott: every book every single book.
Scott: in the whole 52 paid some amount of lip service to it.
Scott: There is none that had zero lip service.
Scott: Not that I could find.
Scott: But yeah animal man Jeff Lemire.
Scott: He did not disappoint at least not in this case.
Scott: Can't go wrong.
Rym: Okay, wait and not in this case.
Rym: you're thinking about Frankenstein.
Rym: We'll talk about that one.
Scott: Later the other Jeff Lemire book.
Scott: He did two books.
Scott: All right back girl also to 99.
Rym: So wasn't this supposed to be number one?
Rym: no Previous BS or anything yet?
Rym: It is clearly following on from Killing Joke the spinal injury her powers all that stuff and you know.
Scott: to give a credit though You don't have to know those things to understand the book, right?
Scott: There are some books where you have to know what came before to understand it at all like Green Lantern But don't get this.
Scott: but in this one you you know knowing about Killing Joke gives it more meaning gives you a bigger emotional Definitely.
Rym: I'll get.
Scott: it probably enhances the enjoyment.
Rym: say throw out to the fans like hey guys, but at the same time It's not necessary to know that to understand this book.
Rym: pretending I did not know that and reading this it was explained enough to be irrelevant as to why it is there.
Scott: But the thing is you do sort of have to know that there's a guy named Batman.
Scott: He's in Gotham City.
Scott: He's Batman and the coach the commissioners name is Commissioner Gordon.
Scott: If you don't know those things then you will not understand pretty much any bat book in the whole freaking.
Rym: I'm gonna say one thing I am really against you know, any of these not just being drop me in start reading.
Rym: I don't need to do anything, but I Almost want to give Batman a pass because I as everyone knows at least the basics of Batman.
Scott: He's Bruce Wayne, you know, his parents were killed.
Scott: these basic facts I mean at least if you're a nerd even if you're not a superhero nerd, you know those things Yeah, and even if you're not a superhero nerd my parents know who fucking Batman is.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: My parents know it, too.
Rym: They know who Commissioner Gordon is.
Rym: They might not know he has a daughter.
Rym: a lot of people don't know he has a daughter or any of that But they'll catch on when it's.
Rym: when they see Barbara Gordon is her name She'll be like, oh wonder if that's the daughter of the Commissioner.
Rym: Oh, there's the Commissioner.
Rym: He looks young Exactly.
Scott: Um, I actually put what.
Scott: did I give this?
Rym: I gave this one a worth the time.
Scott: I gave this a. oh I gave this bad.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The reason I called it bad.
Rym: I gave it man.
Scott: Yeah, the reason I is bad is first of all some of the art.
Rym: Oh it goes way off.
Rym: model her face exactly when she meets her roommate and she's in the background like looking and Her face is like scrunched back and her hair's in a ponytail.
Rym: I thought it was a different character.
Scott: Yeah, I mean some of the art, you know, it was like at these really weird angles.
Scott: That's what I wrote in my notes, right?
Scott: And now that yeah, so look at here.
Scott: Here's the example.
Scott: right.
Scott: you look at this Yeah, like.
Scott: her foot is like all in her leg.
Scott: It's like what's going on there.
Scott: is she Like let's don't go in that direction.
Rym: and her face is different all over the place.
Rym: Her eyes are big eyes are tiny nose is big noses.
Scott: I guess if it was this is a 3d page and the leg was actually coming out of the page and was a little more Inwards.
Scott: it might make sense.
Scott: Yeah, I did not like the half Chun Li thighs.
Scott: The other reason I didn't like it is that the plot was so superhero cookie cutter like oh There's a secret bad guy mask.
Scott: I wonder who he is.
Scott: I better fight them.
Scott: Oh, no, so I got hurt.
Scott: Let's see what happens.
Rym: I am pissed as well that the cops overreacted in the stereotypical way that cops overreact in all these stupid comics where you know The one cop is so mad at her that she wasn't able to save the one guy's life and pulls a gun on.
Scott: That's the that was actually.
Scott: the only interesting part of the whole book was that they show that she screws up not in terms of Vulnerability like Superman had physical vulnerability But the vulnerability.
Scott: if she's trying to save the guy and the dude goes out the window and he's dead It's like oh you didn't actually save the dude.
Scott: You're trying to save you failed at superheroing.
Scott: That was that was the only good part of this whole thing.
Scott: But yeah The reason it's not even gonna read it is Even if it was just lying.
Scott: there is cuz like look the plot is so cookie cutter, you know, what's gonna happen, right?
Scott: It's like you're gonna find out who the bad guy is ever so slowly.
Scott: It's gonna be some kind of surprise.
Scott: It's a character, you know, she's gonna fight them.
Rym: Also the fact that the bad to read it to know what's gonna happen murdered The first person by taking a garden hose and putting it in his mouth.
Rym: It was kind of yeah, okay.
Rym: Anyway, it's like it almost reeked of trying to like use the old Batman stereotypes, but make him grim and dark Like oh look totally killed that dude All right.
Scott: So let's move on bat wing.
Rym: I Don't know why but I actually really liked bat wing.
Scott: really I put this is bad.
Rym: I put it as worth the time and I almost it's close to me wanting to buy a Trade just to see what the deal is really.
Rym: I think it's partly because I love the scene where he's like people in Africa ain't afraid of a bat and Batman just like you've just got to sell it And how he's got like his own Analog of Alfred and how it's kind of like.
Rym: let's take Batman and put it in Africa where a lot of Batman's tricks.
Scott: Yeah, wouldn't work, you know, I don't want to start the whole, you know We could have whole episodes about racism in common and superhero comics, especially regardless of comic.
Rym: Oh, it is Stereotypical Africa, right but but but Gotham City is so stereotypical grimey 70s, New York City.
Scott: But I just want to say, you know, we can have all episodes about those two topics.
Scott: But I just want to say that as a whole almost as a whole The you know, it clearly they're trying it reeks of effort.
Scott: It's like they're trying not to be racist.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's almost like token black guy on purpose comes across to me.
Scott: So that's sort of like it's in my mind the whole time.
Scott: I'm reading it like yeah They're trying to make a black Batman just so they can have black Batman to say they're not racist.
Rym: Well, I guess here's I don't think that's the reason.
Rym: I think that's just you To it being a white upper-middle-class dude probably so I'll put it this way what I liked about it.
Rym: So maybe I can sell this to you.
Rym: Is that Unlike Bruce Wayne millionaire playboy and all that BS.
Rym: He's literally a cop.
Scott: That was that is cool.
Rym: I like that part and I like how he's investigating both things.
Rym: like the investigation side of Batman seems to be on the forefront.
Rym: figure out what's going on in this kind of Realistic ish, you know modern crime thing as opposed to the kind of like the Joker killed someone Let's go stop him and then fail to kill him because Batman's a pussy Mm-hmm.
Scott: I think you know, I didn't like about.
Rym: you know that forced racism part, but I don't know if that's really there though.
Scott: No, well, you can never say if it's really there cuz I did not feel that but that the majority of the book actually Right if you count the pages most of the pages is literally just I'm hitting you I'm Batwing up fight punch you guy with knife.
Scott: No now I'll stab you.
Rym: No, there were multiple scenes where he walks in on a pile of bodies.
Scott: now Yeah, that was the end of the book.
Rym: He walked in on the pilot now, but there's the other pile of bodies in the middle.
Scott: Yeah, two piles of bodies, but I mean most of the book is really just him.
Scott: You know coming up on a guy hitting them coming up on guy hit him also, right?
Scott: You know the art.
Scott: definitely it has a different style, which is good.
Rym: I don't like the art but it feels cook not cookie cutter.
Rym: It feels like this sort of generic superhero art that started appearing in the 2000s.
Rym: that I really I recognize.
Scott: I think this art is actually a much different style than what's typical.
Rym: It's very atypical but maybe not of Marvel DC superhero comics, but like this the independent superhero comics.
Rym: I've seen it like the mocha.
Rym: this really reminds me of that style.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing I don't like is that even though it's different from the other books It's just not a style that I like and it has sort of this digital fakeness to it.
Scott: Oh, yes That's the part that bothers almost like it's in an uncanny valley of like.
Scott: you can tell the same way that you can tell When someone's was made with it, right exactly.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I can tell you made this with the computer.
Scott: It looks like the.
Scott: you know Somebody copied and pasted this character onto the background and like this sort of like this flat Distance between them like a color form almost.
Rym: Yeah, it was really it was yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I think you said it best.
Scott: it's hard to describe because I'm not an illustrator Yeah, but it's got a fake digital miss to the art.
Scott: that made me not want to look at it Really, so I'm giving it a worth the time.
Rym: Yeah, I'm mad because I do want to know what's going on, but I'm not willing to put money toward finding out what's going on.
Scott: Yeah, I put it as bad.
Scott: Okay, it's it's it's a high bad.
Scott: It could go into med territory just cuz I like that.
Scott: He's a cop.
Rym: I feel like if you didn't have this hang up on the perceived races.
Scott: You know the racism and the sexism pretty much any book.
Scott: it's it's problem right because on the one hand Noticing it in any blue any any book where there are non-white people in it.
Scott: It's sort of like oh, there it is.
Rym: Well Scott, I'll put it this way I think I have that for the sexism because every time any time is comics The first thought is oh my god, don't draw them all stupid.
Rym: Oh my god, don't draw them all stupid.
Scott: It's the same exact thing.
Scott: anywhere you see boobs and anywhere you see non-white people It just sticks out.
Rym: but I don't get the non-white people thing.
Scott: I don't feel that Thing is in some books.
Scott: I felt it and other books I didn't cuz I. so I think there is something that some of the books are doing that other ones are not know the boobs Some of them are just outright sexist.
Rym: All right, so let's let's go Batman Detective Comics, so If anything is closest to my Batman aka Frank Miller Dark Knight Returns This one is in that Batman's actual past.
Scott: Yeah, this is.
Scott: this is way dark You know, it goes hardcore full-on.
Scott: what Batman is, you know Joker's all crazy doing his crazy shit.
Rym: I'm not the hero that Gotham wants.
Rym: I'm the hero that guy needs.
Scott: Yeah, you know Gotham City looks all you know art deco and stuff and you see that fucking train.
Scott: Oh my god That was great, right?
Scott: It's got the end where you know where the book is going.
Scott: right at the end You know Joker basically gets his face replaced by somebody in.
Rym: well We don't know if it was replaced or if he just doesn't have a face.
Scott: No, he definitely cuz.
Scott: he says tonight we'll both sell but a rebirth, right?
Scott: So he definitely has a new face.
Scott: So Joker is out there But he looks like Nicholas Cage.
Rym: and Nicolas Cage is out there and he looks like the Joker.
Scott: So that's gonna be really interesting right to see in issues two and three, right?
Scott: It's gonna be like, you know, hey, you know, you're gonna see maybe Commissioner Gordon or maybe what's that big fat cop?
Scott: Well, who's always there?
Rym: Oh, I forgot his name.
Scott: Yeah, I know that, you know You're gonna be looking at them and thinking that could be the Joker.
Scott: That's his new face.
Scott: So now he looks like that.
Scott: I just it's like if Joker was a skin spy.
Scott: It's like he could be anybody Right, you know, maybe Robin.
Scott: you see Robin there and like maybe Robin's a joker.
Scott: It could be he got that.
Scott: You got a joke.
Scott: You're Robin face.
Rym: I just I really like the art.
Rym: I like the way Joe.
Rym: I like the scene where Joker's in Arkham and they're all standing around him like is he in there?
Rym: I think he's bored.
Rym: I hope he's going to sleep one.
Scott: some things I got to say, you know The.
Scott: the plot was very.
Scott: it felt very much like a beat ass episode.
Scott: It did only of course way darker way darker way more gory and such.
Scott: Every time Joker talked I heard Course.
Scott: but for Batman, I didn't really hear either of the Batman voices.
Scott: I know neither the beat has one nor the.
Rym: you know what boys I heard.
Rym: I heard the same voice I hear in my head when I read Frank Miller's Dark Knight Returns, which is just a Badass that I can't describe in words.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't.
Scott: I tried to.
Rym: it's not this bad, right?
Scott: I could hear that Batman or the beat ass Batman if I tried on purpose.
Scott: But I only went trying on purpose and you know.
Scott: But the Mark Hamill one was always there whether I tried or not.
Rym: Well, because Mark Hamill is one of my favorite voice actors in his.
Scott: I also just want to say on that one page for the robot Oh, yeah, I couldn't think about anything except robust for Voltron Like robot robust.
Scott: Also, I want a robot.
Rym: I Want to buy the trade of this one.
Scott: I Put it as man because I would read it if you bought it But I wouldn't pay if like if it was on the list.
Scott: I wouldn't pay for if I rank.
Scott: the best is better things to pay for.
Rym: I like Batman is the story.
Rym: if I have to rank all the Batman things There's like two continuities.
Rym: one continuity ends with the Dark Knight Returns And this is the closest thing I've seen to something that would fit in my personal timeline before that because even Killing Joke, I didn't really like that much.
Rym: and The Dark Knight Returns whatever sequel I couldn't even finish that shit.
Rym: Yeah, but the other continuity of Batman's I've liked is Michael Keaton Batman.
Scott: Yeah, of course and beat ass.
Rym: So of all the Batman's this one is closest to one of the continuities.
Scott: I like Okay, let's move on Green arrow.
Rym: the green arrow is this is crap so bad.
Rym: Oh my god His arrows are so derpy.
Rym: Like I'm gonna shoot a flashbang Basically I'm gonna shoot an ice arrow.
Scott: So first of all, right green arrow is basically Iron Man who I hate.
Scott: so I already hate it.
Rym: Actually, I think it was Iron Man.
Rym: I like Iron Man.
Scott: I hate Iron Man.
Scott: I like how he's a prick Is the same as Iron Man?
Rym: No, he's more of a jackass than a prick.
Scott: It's a rich dude who's got no powers except He's got a lot of money and he goes around trying to be a hero.
Rym: Where does he keep all these arrows in his quiver?
Rym: How many arrows fit in that quiver?
Rym: How does he know to grab the ice arrow as opposed to the sonic arrow?
Rym: They don't even bother fucking explaining that I just it's such superhero bullshit.
Rym: But at least it didn't seem to rely on any other crap.
Rym: So if you like this sort of superhero underwear pervert bullshit, you can just start with this and go with it and never look back.
Rym: Yeah, so also right if you're into that sort of thing.
Scott: Yeah, the art was sort of consistent, but it looks like an old comic which I kind of liked.
Scott: actually I didn't like.
Rym: I liked how it almost reminded me of some 90s x-men.
Scott: Yeah, I guess like the penciling could be 90s But the way they colored it it sort of just looked like a bad 90s cartoon.
Rym: I guess I say that for someone who's a fan of superhero comics.
Rym: I am fine with this green arrow because it does not appear to pull in any other DC bullshit.
Rym: That's true That's true, but I personally have no patience for underwear pervert bullshit.
Scott: So also a lot of the dialogue was pretty corny, but I feel like I'm sorry It's about time you got put in your place.
Rym: That was definitely on purpose.
Scott: Why don't y'all just sign up for a reality show.
Scott: it'd be much easier to get the attention you want to be is obviously.
Scott: Here are the notes.
Rym: I wrote okay arrows are derpy.
Rym: green arrow is derpy.
Rym: The dialogue is campy WTF puns.
Scott: I wrote Iron Man cheesy dialogue Ultra-lame and unsubtle inclusion of current social issues.
Scott: I forgot about.
Rym: I forgot about.
Rym: I had something to say on that too But I had a note.
Scott: the art is dated and looks like a ten-year-old web guy.
Rym: Yeah But it's fine.
Rym: I can't you know to do an objective review.
Rym: This is great if you like campy superhero stuff.
Rym: But yeah, I'm not gonna recommend you read this other one.
Scott: No, I put in bad but worse than bad.
Rym: Hawk and Dove what?
Scott: so let me talk about Hawk and Dove.
Scott: I pick up Hawk and Dove and I look at it and I'm like, huh?
Scott: This sort of looks really 90s.
Rym: dove reminds me so much.
Rym: I read the tick sidekick.
Scott: I read a page and then I turn the page and I saw some pouches and I was like This really does look really 90s and I'm like, huh?
Scott: Let me go turn back to Rob life, but I was like.
Scott: No, it was.
Scott: it is Rob Liefeld.
Scott: It's like a self parody.
Scott: Look at the way Hawk Hawk looks on the fucking cover With his chat.
Scott: Oh, it's it Rob Liefeld at his best I mean.
Scott: for everything I've heard he's a good guy at conventions But he's still doing his bad feet and pouches and everything else He's known for.
Rym: why doesn't he put pouches on the feet so we don't have to see him?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: but yeah the art is typical.
Scott: awful Rob Liefeld not as bad.
Scott: It's not Rob Liefeld's worst, but it's still Rob Liefeld, which makes it bad in general From our taste.
Rym: Yeah, but here's what I wrote.
Rym: one.
Rym: Each character gets a power listing of.
Rym: here are all their powers and the fact that one of the powers was and I quote healing factor.
Rym: Do we that's?
Rym: Comic book bullshit.
Rym: Yeah, don't give me that.
Scott: Also, it was so just I don't know there was absolutely nothing interesting about the plot.
Scott: It was pretty much like I'm a superhero.
Scott: I'm stuck with his other superhero.
Scott: We're a pair.
Scott: the the guy who used to be the other superhero died and this new one showed up.
Scott: And I don't he was my brother.
Rym: I feel vague homoerotic tension there that I can't quite explain.
Scott: Yeah, it's almost like Wonder Twins hate each other.
Scott: kind of yeah or Wonder Twins tension.
Rym: And you know it didn't start with the origin story.
Rym: it flashed back to it immediately, and it was really dumb.
Rym: I wish I had power here you go.
Scott: Well that was exciting.
Rym: Yeah great alright.
Rym: Also, you know also, what's with this whole dead man thing this other character?
Scott: That was kind of their dead man's in a few of the other books.
Scott: I know I know I.
Rym: that's what I'm saying.
Rym: Don't I don't want the crossover crab.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: It's like is dead man that popular?
Scott: He's in a bunch of the book.
Rym: I'd never heard of him.
Scott: He was actually there was the dead man comic in Wednesday comics.
Scott: no okay alright That was the first time ever heard of dead man, but he's it.
Rym: dead man's in like four But at least bugs while it's intermingling these comics Which I don't like because that's what got me out of comics when I first started reading them when someone was like oh No, you got to read This is a number one.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: You don't have to know anything else to understand this but going forward You're gonna have to read all the other ones with dead man probably because he was just an offhand mention.
Rym: He's a big deal.
Scott: He matters in this in this comic at least yeah, but the thing is even though he matters.
Scott: What's the plot?
Scott: I mean the plot.
Scott: it was almost if this was a parody of Underwear perfect comics.
Scott: it would have been great because that's sort of what it was.
Scott: it was like.
Scott: it was so Stereotypical you it could have all.
Scott: it was going into the realm of making fun of itself or other books like itself But it wasn't.
Scott: I think it's actually trying to be a superhero comic.
Scott: I I'm not a parody of superhero.
Rym: I have nothing good to say about Hawken Dove.
Scott: none good.
Scott: Oh, I just want to point out one thing though at this point is what I noticed.
Scott: if you look on page one look at See these little things that are like telling you the place in time.
Scott: Yeah Yeah Those are the that.
Scott: that graphic design of the of the horizontal bar with these slight slant on the right with that font in the middle Was the same in every book.
Scott: if you look at there look at look at Justice League number zero.
Scott: Look, there's that same kind of bar.
Rym: You're right, right.
Scott: every book had that same graphic design for the parts where it told you You know five years ago or Washington DC or three days ago in New York Was always the same graphic design for those little narrative things.
Scott: in all 52 of the books They've got this uniform graphic design going on on the internals not just on the cover design.
Scott: I don't know that's good or bad.
Scott: I just noticed it.
Scott: Well.
Scott: That's all I had to say about it.
Rym: So bad bad Justice League International.
Rym: who the fuck is booster gold?
Rym: I what is?
Scott: I know.
Rym: I know who booster gold is Because I gotta say I don't know anything about booster gold at all.
Rym: I literally do not time travel.
Rym: Yeah, so reading this I Inferred that maybe he's from the future.
Scott: The deal is is he was like a teenager.
Scott: like I said I read booster gold like I have.
Scott: I had a big black-and-white Booster gold showcase that had all like the first issues of booster gold never had the whole thing.
Scott: And basically from what I remember which is probably slightly off because I tried to put it out of my mind He was like a teenager.
Scott: He got sent to the past or the future Where he's got some superheroes stuff, and then he went back to another.
Scott: all right No, he was in the future.
Scott: He went to like the hall of I think the maybe The legion of superheroes, and he got some superhero stuff, and then he went back in time with it something along those lines Whatever.
Rym: Here's my only complaint about this other than everything.
Rym: yep Batman looks that's not Batman.
Rym: what if there's a guy who looks like Batman?
Scott: It's almost like Adam West Batman or super.
Scott: It's I know it's super friends.
Scott: bad It is.
Rym: there's this other guy who looks like Batman is pretending to be a crab ass version of Batman flying the plane.
Scott: Yeah, and basically this book is basically super friends.
Scott: the book right it's pretty crap.
Rym: It's nothing but a series of one-liners while they fight generic lava monsters.
Scott: Yeah, the art.
Scott: I mean the coloring is okay But the rest of it is meh.
Scott: the thing that really bothers me is that this follows a plotline That it was in maybe 10 of the books and I'll mention it every time the plotline comes up.
Scott: It's pretty much Government organization gets together a whole bunch of superheroes to fight some unspecified threat.
Scott: That's coming up.
Scott: It's like how many different government organizations are out there forming together groups of superheroes like 20.
Scott: Oh, how many threats to the world can there be at the same time?
Rym: seriously the subplot of you know?
Rym: People are mad about this and are burning down.
Rym: the Hall of Justice didn't okay?
Scott: explain me this.
Scott: Justice League number one was five years ago, correct?
Rym: So maybe they were destroyed on the interim hold on face was five years ago.
Scott: Meanwhile the Hall of Justice that was apparently built less than five years ago Right because the Justice League didn't even exist five years ago
Rym: Yeah is
Scott: already abandoned and some sort of public park that people can enjoy and
Rym: simultaneously
Scott: Only lasted five years in the Hall of Justice lasted less than they might
Rym: be in space.
Scott: Well, I'm pretty sure the Justice League is in space.
Scott: But they went to.
Scott: they already gave out.
Scott: they built the Hall of Justice and gave up on it in the span of five years.
Scott: Are you kidding me really?
Scott: but really you know what that was quick.
Rym: all I got to say is this one's bad.
Rym: We're already issue ones.
Rym: There's too much entanglement that I can't keep it all straight in my head.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is that you do sort it.
Scott: to get the fullness of this book you do sort of need to know stuff.
Scott: There's a bunch of characters in here that it's like who the fuck are they?
Scott: It's like I don't you know.
Scott: If you don't know who all the different Green Lanterns are or like, you know Who's?
Scott: oh.
Scott: and the thing is even if you do pretend these characters are brand new.
Rym: Well, Green Lantern doesn't even exist until week two as far as I'm concerned, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: you don't even know like and who do you even care about these people?
Scott: Do I care about Tora?
Scott: Olives daughter ice from Norway?
Rym: are those real superheroes are made up for this?
Rym: and the other thing is like All of these characters got to.
Rym: all those characters exist otherwise like today.
Rym: were they in other comics or are they new?
Scott: I don't I'm sure.
Scott: some of the plastic man is definitely not new.
Rym: Okay?
Scott: I'm not sure which ones you're doing.
Scott: was apparently they all only a booster.
Scott: gold is not new that Green Lanterns not new.
Rym: The only power pretty sure Is to say a non-witty one-liner that is so stereotypical like Russian.
Scott: They're all punch-out jokes.
Scott: Justice League International is nothing but punch-out stereotypes of nationalities.
Scott: That's all it is.
Scott: And even though they're all stereotypes.
Scott: They don't really have personalities, right?
Scott: It's all they.
Scott: all the people ever say is like, you know, hey help us help me fight the thing.
Scott: do this attack Dude, it's like none of the carrot.
Scott: It's not you know, I'm looking for characters that have personalities, right?
Scott: I mean the way you can tell if A character has a real personality is if you can make jokes about them For example ponies.
Scott: not to bring it up again.
Scott: You can make jokes about every pony like you can do a Rainbow Dash impersonation like I'm rainbow Like.
Scott: what would Rainbow Dash do in situation X?
Scott: Right, you can answer that question because Rainbow Dash is a real personality.
Rym: So I thought you were going to say a real person.
Scott: no, but none of these characters Have any personality.
Scott: what to them?
Scott: They're just.
Scott: they're just all they.
Scott: all they are is Each character in this book is just a costume and a nationality.
Scott: That's all they are.
Scott: They have nothing else to them.
Rym: in the school of three of them have personalities.
Rym: Booster gold doesn't give a shit.
Rym: Yeah, and isn't Batman and Russian guy.
Rym: That man is derpy Batman and Now the Russian guy doesn't have any personality either.
Rym: the third person I was gonna say is the Green Lantern is surly Oh kind of yeah, but it's like they have no soul to them.
Scott: They're just costumes with nationalities attached to them.
Scott: This book is pretty bad bad.
Scott: Justice League international do not want.
Scott: if you gave me all the trades for free I would give them away.
Rym: so men of war people.
Rym: I hated the next one men of war which on the surface as far as I can tell is supposed to be just like Old-school comic style war stories.
Rym: Yeah one set in like a future with superhero crap.
Scott: Well, one of them is sergeant rock and the other one is something else.
Rym: Is it just me or was this really boring and filled with fanboy jargon and a whole bunch of like mini Shirot asms.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: I actually put this in the met category.
Scott: I kind of like this.
Rym: I put it in man, but I it's close to bad because It's.
Rym: it tries so hard to appeal to the American equivalent of the military fanboy By using all this jargon and all these acronyms and there's little bubbles everywhere.
Rym: being like.
Rym: that stands for the whatever Recoilist rifle stands for you know zone of engagement all this kind of idea.
Scott: I did notice that you feel like you're learning military stuff, but really you're not.
Scott: No, I mean what I liked about it.
Scott: first of all, it was a 399 book if you didn't notice I did not know.
Scott: it was more expensive and you got more pages Which is why I had the second story in it.
Scott: the art in the second story was stunning.
Scott: I just got to say that Oh my god, I love the art in the second story the second story.
Rym: I liked way more than the first story, right?
Scott: It seems like first of all, it's like there's a generic war always going on.
Scott: It's like what war is this?
Scott: Yeah, it's like this is just a war that's always happening.
Scott: And also it seems like this whole world is that it's like they just wars everywhere.
Scott: It's like it's the war planet.
Scott: this what this particular book men at war concentrates an actual full-on wars.
Scott: But it seems like this war is going on in every other book whenever some government needs to get a group of seer heroes to Fight an evil organization.
Scott: It's wars everywhere.
Rym: I guess what bothered me about the first story in this book is that it was such like cliche.
Rym: Check out our gritty realistic military story.
Scott: I thought it was a typical sergeant rock story and I tend to like Sergeant rock stories.
Scott: cuz sergeant rock is all about that military guy who will go against the military He's like, I don't want your promotions, you know fight, but it was just so cliche.
Scott: It was like Oh Shama as opposed to without Moroi.
Scott: Nah, that's what it was.
Scott: That's what sergeant rock is all about.
Scott: the other thing I did the other thing that boosted it a little bit that first story was that it mixed the The war story with the superhero story, right?
Scott: It put him together true and you know that it really only ever happens in like Captain America and stuff like that.
Scott: So, you know to be like well look his regular old soldiers in a world where there's a fucking flying dude who smashes shit.
Rym: It's like oh, I guess Military had been a little less storm ship Starship Troopers movie and a little more realistic and the characters were a little.
Rym: I mean They're a little too cliche and too archetypical for my taste.
Scott: Yeah, but I read the second story.
Scott: just the art was was so good.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: It was okay.
Rym: I wouldn't call it great.
Scott: That's my kind of arts.
Scott: I really like that style.
Rym: Yeah, I like it.
Rym: Okay That's why it's on the low end of math.
Scott: I've got a high man rims got a low man on the men-of-war.
Rym: Alright, let's talk about Oh Mac.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: What the fuck was that?
Scott: Oh Mac is definitely.
Rym: I have no idea what's going on or what happened or who these people are or I. Just I've almost nothing to say about it other than that WX and the gobbles and all the proper nouns were hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, so this is bad.
Rym: so bad what I wrote.
Rym: I wrote.
Rym: here's a note like reboot But WTF like reboot, huh?
Scott: That's what you think.
Scott: It's interesting.
Rym: That's the closest thing.
Rym: I was even remotely reminded of mmm, even though it's nothing like reboot.
Scott: No, not at all.
Rym: And I just I have no idea what the hell it is and I have no interest in reading.
Scott: So first of all, the art was so like Jack Kirby Throw up, you know, it was sort of like homage to Jack Kirby, but it wasn't a good one.
Scott: It was just like Okay, you're really making it look like Jack Kirby on purpose.
Scott: Maybe Jack Kirby invented this character.
Scott: That's why I'm guessing I have no idea.
Scott: It's probably it's likely Oh, how come Oh max an acronym - yeah, there were a lot of acronyms.
Scott: I want to say that now every book had tons of acronyms.
Scott: There were like five different evil organizations that were acronyms five different good organizations that were acronyms.
Scott: You know, it's like how many good and bad?
Scott: Organizations can there be with acronym names?
Scott: different technologies and weapon systems and heroes.
Scott: all these acronym names just all over the place.
Scott: It's like Marvel does the same thing too.
Scott: It's like stop it Not everything's a fucking acronym name and it's like and it always has to be clever too, right?
Scott: It can't ever be just talker shade.
Scott: Yes, dog urge God.
Scott: There's so many of them.
Scott: We'll get as we go through.
Scott: I'll bring up ones that we've already missed some.
Scott: The thing I hated most about Oh Mac I just don't want to give it so much time is that it was it had.
Scott: Perhaps it was in a lot of books.
Scott: But this one most of all.
Scott: I think I hit you you little guy syndrome Oh my god.
Scott: and that every panel there's someone doing something and Saying what they're doing it that you see them doing in the panel.
Scott: and most of the panels are action of a guy doing something.
Scott: but unlike Nightwing or at least the action was like almost all of all Mac's dialogue was like I am Oh Mac back away.
Scott: Get out of my way or I will hit you you little guy I will hit you and it like and oh, it's like, you know, what you need is a woman's touch.
Scott: I must always remind everybody.
Rym: Oh my god, not just another pretty face That I also noted that exact panel as yeah good.
Scott: God Good.
Scott: Yeah, it's just uh, and they did.
Scott: the bad guys were just generic evil science Organization, but he was Lord.
Rym: What's his name?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't care.
Scott: I will not be denied.
Scott: I smash you you little guy.
Rym: Oh Mac bad stay in hidden temple comic bad.
Scott: Wish Oh Mac would smash it.
Scott: So sorry, I'm done with that.
Scott: So and the cliffhanger at the?
Scott: Oh another thing on invention is a lot of the books tried Obviously to end in a cliffhanger.
Scott: if it's book number one Obviously you want to end in a cliffhanger to make the guy by number book book number two This one didn't end in a cliffhanger it I think it was just.
Scott: it did sort of end in a cliffhanger.
Scott: It was just a really stupid one.
Scott: It's like they were trying to make a cliffhanger by being like brother.
Scott: I is a space station.
Scott: Yeah, it was like they're trying to make that a cliffhanger.
Rym: It's like wow that would have worked on me in 1990.
Scott: yeah that it was ill.
Scott: it's weird.
Scott: like some books tried most of the books tried to do it.
Scott: a few succeeded and Only some of the ones that succeeded actually had me caring like even some of the ones that had a real cliffhanger.
Scott: I still didn't care.
Rym: Yep, like Batgirl didn't really care Animal Man is the only cliffhanger I cared about.
Rym: Yeah, other than maybe Detective Comics because I really want to know what Joker's plot.
Scott: that didn't make me care about the cliffhanger.
Scott: It just made me excited for the possibilities of who is Joker gonna masquerade as what's you know?
Rym: No, so Just to go back to that one Joker's a reaction to the way that all went and everything was really well written.
Rym: Yeah, if very creepy and disturbing, okay, so Static shock.
Rym: All right static shock bad for it's a good thing.
Rym: I had my deflector what you might call it up or else those.
Scott: Oh god, that's the exact same shit.
Scott: I'm complaining.
Rym: this whole comic is nothing but is nothing but that I'll use the samoflange on the bath madad.
Rym: Oh, no, the bath and I didn't work.
Rym: I gotta use the boof my fucker fuck right comic.
Scott: also Queensborough bridge has pedestrians.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Do your research?
Scott: I can see the fucking bridge out my window looking at it.
Scott: right now I'm looking at the real bridge not even like a picture of it.
Rym: There is the bridge like the.
Scott: It looks nothing like the bridge in the comic.
Scott: and he they even said there are no Pedestrians this fucking pedestrians on the goddamn bridge.
Scott: I see them.
Scott: I am them.
Rym: I bike over that bridge on a regular basis.
Scott: do your fucking research.
Scott: What the fuck like everything about this comic?
Rym: It could have been cool.
Rym: I like the main character.
Rym: He's snarky.
Rym: He's kind of like a.
Scott: I think it was it.
Scott: I think he was forced snark though I think it was also.
Scott: I had that same a little half as much as I had in the White guy guilt.
Rym: Yeah white guy, whatever You've got a weird like complex.
Scott: Also, the dude is basically like it's.
Scott: it's almost like they always draw him.
Scott: whenever they draw him They're looking at the Green Goblin in a spider-man book Right because he's standing and crouching on this flying disc Octagon hex thing.
Rym: He's so cool.
Scott: He's like Zack Morris.
Scott: It's like here.
Scott: It's like every pose that he ever has is stolen from spider-man Green Goblin in some spider-man comic.
Rym: But oh also electrocuted does not mean that.
Scott: Yeah It's just the half.
Scott: the comic is.
Scott: he's fighting a guy and just made up made up words about electricity that don't match real physics.
Scott: Oh, I must beat his made-up word with my made-up word.
Scott: I beat your and it's like.
Scott: it's the same as I like.
Rym: Tron level is over 9,000.
Scott: It's the same as I hate you little guy.
Scott: I'm casting this spell.
Scott: I'm casting this spell now on you.
Rym: Oh good guy, never mind that he everything he does also has some sort of positive slash negative electricity pun, right?
Scott: I mean last of all you get the family drama, which is kind of okay ish, but it's ham-fisted but Dude can fucking fly on a disc.
Scott: Why is he asking for a goddamn driver's license?
Rym: because he wants to be a normal?
Rym: no No, he doesn't though because his motivation is clearly I want to be a goddamn superhero.
Rym: This is fucking awesome.
Scott: Let's go, right?
Scott: It didn't makes no sense.
Scott: It's like they tried to give in the normal teen life But they completely ignored the fact of how the teen life would be modified by the superhero life.
Scott: It's like they just has the two separate lives and they're not intermingling.
Scott: You know except for the.
Scott: I need to get away from my family to do my superhero wing without them knowing Part.
Rym: Oh, I'm on the racism part.
Rym: while I do not feel your weird white guy guilt at least the misplaced part of it.
Rym: I Do find it somewhat?
Rym: Unnerving to me that oh, yeah.
Rym: I told them all you're some inner city whatever so they'd stay away from you.
Rym: Like really?
Rym: That's your excuse - yeah But no fuck this comic this comic alright, I wasn't that bad.
Scott: I think we'll make it through week one.
Scott: So we'll probably have to do a week per episode.
Rym: Alright storm watch I gotta.
Rym: I was the yes, here's what I wrote.
Scott: This was the epitome of acronym Good get an organization of superheroes together.
Scott: from here is what I versus an organization of bad guys.
Rym: first I've X'd out the name storm watch.
Rym: I drew a frowny face next to it.
Rym: I wrote see Superman number one in quotes because it does that shit.
Scott: Okay, we'll talk about that when we get to Superman number one.
Scott: Just forget that for now.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, it was like cuz did you read Superman number one?
Scott: I think I just gave it to you.
Rym: No, I didn't read it yet.
Rym: All I know is There's too many comics referencing each other in this kind of way like oh, that's not true.
Scott: Jad ready I'm gonna go off on that shit.
Scott: when we talk about Superman number ocean I'm ready for.
Rym: the other thing I wrote was and I quote what the fuck did I just read at a whole bunch of exclamation?
Rym: Points in question marks, right?
Rym: So I could not tell you what happened.
Rym: a bunch of like underwear.
Rym: perverts screamed at each other and random shit happened.
Rym: And then it ended.
Rym: and I don't know what's going on a bunch of underwear.
Scott: Someone's trying to get a bunch of underwear perverts together to form a team I think to fight some guys if you don't know who these heroes are already.
Scott: It doesn't make a lot of sense If you do it, you know, they don't introduce them.
Scott: There's something going on with a mountain and a horn.
Scott: None of the characters of any personalities.
Rym: They're just costumes with night hours around between a bunch of basically Unrelated scenes.
Rym: the angles are all weird.
Scott: It literally the art was not to my liking whatsoever.
Scott: I read it's.
Scott: the only thing is while I was not liking the art.
Scott: Sometimes it was least Interesting like there's that page where the the woman is like interesting facial expression No, but at the same time her face is kind of distorted and weird.
Rym: I like the plot the vague plot idea I get of.
Rym: yeah, the moon is threatening the earth somehow Yeah, but basically here's my notes ready.
Scott: There was a mention of slash fiction and it was like they were trying to be hip and cool by mentioning slash fiction.
Rym: Oh, they did that again in Superboy, they're like just totally not a Mary Sue.
Scott: art is sometimes interesting which I already talked about.
Scott: Yeah, how many things can threaten the entire world simultaneously?
Scott: How many hero teams can save it simultaneously even if it just in this one?
Rym: The fuck is going on.
Rym: I read every single word in every single panel twice because I try.
Rym: I could not tell you what the plot is other than that.
Rym: As far as I can tell the moon is trying to fucking kill everybody.
Scott: Yeah, I think the reason that this book is tied in with Superman is to give Nerds a reason to reason.
Scott: right because if it was just on its own no one would give a fuck.
Rym: I was waiting for bad news like show up.
Scott: Someone who really cares about Superman number one might be forced to read storm watch by tying them together because they're pretty much you know whatever.
Rym: so The last comic from week one was Swamp Thing, which oh, by the way, if it wasn't obvious storm watch is bad.
Scott: No kidding real bad.
Rym: I like Swamp Thing, but I put it man cuz I don't really care where it goes.
Scott: I also put it as a high man.
Rym: It is a high man.
Rym: I like fire.
Scott: I like this book, but I also don't care where it goes and I don't care about Swamp Thing.
Scott: Also a lot of the enjoyment I got from the book was because I had read Alan Moore's Swamp Thing so I still have to read which I knew.
Scott: so I know a lot about Swamp Thing and So I got a lot of stuff out of this that I definitely would not have gotten had I not read that.
Scott: Also the art in the swamp thing is sometimes stunning sometimes not right.
Scott: so and like this first page of the birds falling And the Superman oh my god the whole comic is like that right bye.
Scott: But the whole comic doesn't look like that over here when Superman is talking to the construction worker.
Scott: It just looks like a normal comic but over.
Rym: so it's like did you notice the Tyrannosaurus Rex about to kill Batman?
Scott: Yeah, that was pretty cool.
Rym: How come it has skin?
Rym: where did that come from?
Rym: I want to see the comic about the dinosaur that tries to kill Batman.
Scott: well That's the dinosaur that's next to the penny in the Batcave.
Rym: I know but I guess it came to life.
Scott: Yeah, but you can read those comics.
Scott: I could go find out what they are.
Scott: I forget which ones they are.
Scott: I think it's like Batman and the Outsiders or something like that Swamp Thing.
Rym: I would have had a much higher opinion of this if it did not have Superman and Batman and all this bullshit in it.
Scott: Well, you know having read the Alan Moore Swamp Thing.
Scott: that didn't bother me because the way Swamp Thing integrates with the world Even Frank Miller's Dark Knight Returns has another superhero or two in it.
Scott: But I recognize that as a negative quality.
Scott: if the Swamp Thing is truly number one You shouldn't get you shouldn't have to read the Alan Moore Swamp Thing to get the maximum enjoyment out of this one.
Rym: I mean look at if I hadn't read it.
Scott: I might have put this in the low mat or even bad Like.
Rym: maybe I pushed it into the low man like like we talked about the killing joke.
Rym: You might get an additional like oh if you knew about it, but if you don't know about it, it still works.
Rym: It's not detracting but here but you're it's you're.
Scott: it's not detracting.
Scott: You can get this book without having know anything about Swamp Thing, but it's a significant benefit, right?
Scott: You know what analogy.
Scott: that benefit was enough to boost it from low man, maybe even bad to sky man.
Rym: Though Imagine think about the difference between watching Galaxy Express 3 and I in the movie having or having not seen the TV show exactly.
Rym: It's the same kind of thing there.
Rym: You have to see both or you're really missing out on the real reason to watch it.
Scott: Yep also, I Just want to point out what about right here dinosaur the action.
Scott: remember I talked about how I like the action comic Superman.
Scott: So here was my first opportunity to see Superman since that action come.
Rym: why does he deliver a line?
Rym: So cliched that even penny arcades made.
Scott: well, and they're a hard-timed man to find mister doctor, right, but he's flying.
Scott: It's like oh god damn it.
Scott: Well, he can fly by that point but the thing is he's also appears much older than he does in action comic.
Scott: So is that action comics?
Scott: it didn't I couldn't find anywhere.
Scott: I didn't look that hard in action comics where it said ten years ago, whatever, you know.
Scott: But it seems like maybe that action comics is truly in another universe or in the past You know, but it has to be after Justice League before it doesn't make sense really.
Scott: But I don't like the Superman.
Scott: that's in this swamp thing, but I you know, I like.
Rym: I only like to Superman.
Rym: I like the Superman that we talked about at the way beginning in this episode Justice League and I like Superman in Frank Miller's Dark Knight Returns.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Those are the only two.
Rym: Superman I like.
Scott: I like the Lois and Clark TV show Superman.
Scott: I watched that show the way I watch ponies now that I was a kid.
Scott: No, it doesn't hold up.
Rym: I was gonna say have you seen it in the last decade when I was a kid?
Scott: I watched that thing every day every and whenever there's a new episode.
Scott: I'd be waiting for that shit to come on.
Rym: My brother - I think I was falling asleep as I was reading Swamp Thing because my nose Oh, we got to mess for Swamp Thing.
Rym: Yeah, cuz my notes go you're a hard man to find mister.
Rym: and then a scribble.
Rym: I wrote the word pecs maybe decks and then I wrote Superman that the man kind of fades off into a scribble and then it looks like drool.
Scott: So so we'll come back with another episode on the week.
Scott: two books.
Scott: I guess it takes about a week per episode here.
Scott: How long was that?
Scott: That was a while Okay, so yeah week per episode.
Scott: We got three more.
Rym: I want to give you a preview for next week because the next week's yeah Let's just go.
Scott: let me just go through a list.
Scott: the week next week includes Batman and Robin.
Rym: I got a lot to say about okay that woman.
Rym: I get a lot to say about yep deathstroke Demon Knights.
Scott: I got a lot to say about demon Knights Frankenstein a lot to say about that.
Scott: Oh Green Lantern got a lot to say.
Rym: so Green Lantern and Red Lantern DC.
Rym: what the fuck that's not a number one.
Scott: Yeah grifter.
Scott: I don't really have much to say about that.
Scott: I don't even remember it.
Rym: Legion loss.
Scott: I got a lot to say about Legion laws.
Scott: worst comic.
Rym: you're giving him a giving it away.
Scott: It's the worst.
Scott: It's it's awful.
Scott: It's awful.
Scott: All right, mr.
Rym: Like Justice League International was bad mr.
Scott: Terrific.
Scott: Red Lantern's Resurrection man and Suicide Squad all coming up and Superboy I kind of like Suicide Squad all coming up in a week to save it for week two.
Rym: It's coming.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.