Scott: It's Wednesday July 20th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: Galaxy Express 3 9 the first movie.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we did a show about nothing last week, and I remember the the impetus where that was not seinfeld.
Rym: It was that I thought oh, I know I'll read a dirty limerick And then I'll just go from there with random stuff.
Rym: And then I forgot about the limerick and we just talked about actually nothing for what an hour Because we couldn't come up with the show and we were lazy whatever.
Rym: so a little backstory.
Rym: We were at RIT and there was a book of limericks.
Rym: It's just called limericks, and it was like two dollars at the bookstore.
Rym: So we were like oh, yeah, we'll buy this turns out.
Rym: It wasn't just limericks.
Rym: It was primarily Dirty limericks or at least suppose if it's not dirty.
Scott: It's not a limerick.
Rym: So I have opened just now to a random page and every episode of GeekNights henceforth either in the beginning or during the meta moment I'm going to read a Random.
Rym: oh my god.
Scott: I'm sure this is really gonna increase the quality of the show my god, so This is number three hundred and welcome new listeners.
Rym: Well fucking one night dr.
Rym: Zuck his wife's nipples in his ears struck or stuck.
Rym: Then his thumb upper bum he could hear himself come thus inventing the radio fuck That was written in 1949.
Scott: I like how his name is conveniently dr.
Scott: Zuck.
Scott: Huh funny.
Rym: How it always works out that way.
Rym: yeah This was really spotted as many people from Nantucket as well.
Rym: yeah, cuz that a lot of them have.
Scott: no you know they like.
Scott: yeah We're gonna.
Scott: if you're gonna actually do this we're gonna meet a lot of these people.
Rym: So new listeners, I'm sorry I Had to be done.
Rym: It's Wednesday.
Rym: What can you?
Rym: what can I say?
Scott: you're getting your money's worth out of that discount rack.
Scott: Yeah, so if you go to a borders that's closing this week, and you see like you know something like that You know it's like a four dollar book of dirty limericks.
Scott: You're.
Scott: even if it's a horrible book you might get your money's worth if you buy it.
Rym: Yeah, and if you ever find yourself on the floor of the Senate, and you need to filibuster there you go.
Scott: Oh shit, son You know what.
Scott: maybe that's?
Scott: what we should do.
Scott: is we should send it to a congressman?
Scott: I should always.
Scott: only Anthony Wiener had not fucked up He could be in a limerick himself.
Rym: there once was a congressman Wiener.
Rym: So this weekend though we will not be there.
Rym: it is the San Diego Comic Con.
Rym: I kind of want to go some year.
Rym: It's just I'm always busy.
Rym: It's not really the kind of thing we like.
Rym: I always kind of forget to like say hope panels or lectures or whatever It's like in the one hand.
Scott: It's like the exact opposite of a convention that we want to go to.
Rym: yeah I mean, what do we go to?
Rym: we go to like really participatory conventions like PAX.
Rym: we go to super party.
Scott: San Diego comic-con is a big room of booths and waiting in line to see famous people.
Rym: now granted We go to that with the New York comic-con, but it's right there.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: It's like next door.
Scott: We don't have to fly to San Diego.
Scott: meanwhile the thing starts fucking Wednesday night.
Scott: Yeah If you want to go to it you have to buy tickets a year in advance and get your hotels here in advance and pay A zillion dollars and fly to San Diego.
Rym: or what.
Rym: we could get a professional badge or something.
Rym: I'm sure we could get a badge without having to do all that BS.
Scott: You'd be surprised.
Scott: This is like one level up from our usual convention because it's got real famous people Yeah, but at the same time a level famous while getting like guests and all that stuff at those conventions is difficult.
Rym: There's one thing that through this to this day is not that difficult and that is the press pass.
Scott: San Diego comic-con press pass is harder than you think but at the same time easier than you'd expect.
Rym: I'm sorry comic-con international So we will not be there but someday I'll go.
Rym: maybe we'll just go as attendees or something.
Scott: Yeah, but that one thing that I found weird right is like, you know, there's gonna be a bunch of stuff there But I don't actually need to be there for any of it, right?
Scott: The only thing you would actually need to be there for is like a panel that no one videos But they're always gonna video the funny part.
Scott: Yeah, right and they're always gonna sneak a camera into the you know premieres or whatever.
Scott: the sneak peek of course But it's the there is always.
Scott: the one thing you do have to be there for is the exclusive limited-edition swag.
Scott: But of course, we don't give a shit about exclusive limited-edition swag.
Scott: And if you do, you know what eBay Except when it's a limited to five thousand Special my little pony poster god damn it.
Rym: How did they know by Hasbro?
Scott: And if you look at this thing, it's definitely a fan Appeal.
Scott: it's got derpy.
Scott: It's got every fucking fan thing.
Scott: This is like for bronies specifically Yep.
Rym: Well, I got.
Rym: I got a lot to say about Hasbro and bronies and all that.
Rym: but give me Give me another two weeks until I no longer work for a company where I'm not able to talk about Stocks and companies and things.
Rym: and I got stuff to say anyway, so it's warm today.
Rym: It is the warmest so warm.
Rym: In the studio I have suffered through some goddamn heat.
Rym: we used to turn that AC off religiously.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: It is too hot to do that, you know, isn't there a way that you could?
Scott: I mean, I'm so much smog.
Rym: Look, I live we have a luxury apartment.
Rym: The studio has a window overlooking the East River and Manhattan at like 59th Street.
Rym: Like we can see Manhattan right now Manhattan is almost entirely obscured by smog.
Rym: I've never seen anything.
Scott: all the buildings are just silhouettes with no color and I can only see the first row of Buildings.
Scott: the second row of buildings is sort of like have gray and that is legit smog something.
Rym: I've never seen in person before.
Rym: It could be a really low cloud.
Scott: That's smog.
Rym: There is no way that is not smog.
Scott: It could be just haze.
Rym: I don't think it's haze.
Scott: Haze is not that thick It's.
Scott: it's super haze but it's not that humid double.
Rym: hey if that were haze it would be more humid.
Scott: It's pretty humid.
Scott: It's just hot.
Rym: It's not that humid good anyway.
Rym: So fucking hot.
Scott: it's real hot, but that's fine by me.
Scott: I'm fine with this hot.
Scott: I love it.
Scott: I'm all good.
Scott: You know, I love it one.
Scott: Let it be a hundred something.
Scott: I don't give a shit because you know what reasons got one.
Scott: I did not want it to be.
Scott: I just think back to when it was motherfucking cold.
Scott: You know fucking space nuts frozen off and I'm like this is.
Scott: I'm happy with this.
Rym: I can deal with many things.
Rym: I can deal with horrible fanboys.
Rym: everyone knows Scott would always be amazed at RIT way back in the day and how Polite and nice I could be to horrible fanboys.
Scott: I'm just gonna get out of my face man.
Rym: I can abide a lot of BS from people but I cannot abide someone who complains that it's too cold in the winter and Complains that it's too hot in the summer.
Rym: you get to complain about one season.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: That is all you get to complain about if you complain about both.
Scott: good No, cuz what these people?
Scott: let me let me be these stupid people.
Rym: They want it to be 74 degrees and boring.
Scott: They're like, oh, you know, I like the weather when it's kind of warm, but not too warm, but not too cold.
Scott: I like it to be 65 70.
Rym: I think they're the same people when they order food at a restaurant Want something very particular like can you replace my rice with this?
Rym: and I'd rather have this and I want it cooked exactly like this.
Scott: Yeah, shut the fuck up.
Rym: No, you don't Indian place or something.
Rym: I'm just like yeah That exactly.
Rym: if you bring me the wrong thing.
Rym: I won't even notice.
Scott: I mean if you're crazy rich and you know the people there you can do cool things like ordering off menu.
Rym: Yeah, that's that's Right by feelings about that.
Rym: cuz I just watched get shorty again.
Rym: cuz Emily never seen it and had been a while since I saw It.
Scott: remember when Martin where I never saw it.
Rym: really I would have sworn we watch art.
Rym: You should watch it.
Rym: It's in Netflix streaming.
Scott: All right, it's hilarious.
Rym: And it's John Travolta playing John Travolta.
Rym: It's kind of like a fanfic about John Travolta.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But anyway, the point is don't be complaining about hot and cold weather.
Scott: Otherwise you suck and be.
Scott: don't be being weird at restaurants.
Scott: Just fucking pick something on the menu.
Scott: Don't be all asking what's in this what's in that it wouldn't be Here?
Rym: are legitimate.
Scott: have an allergy.
Scott: you have an allergy.
Rym: you have celiac disease.
Rym: It is okay to be like is there?
Scott: celiac disease is an allergy.
Rym: No, it's an autoimmune thing.
Rym: It's distinct from allergies It's.
Scott: it's the same.
Rym: You have a food problem because celiac if you have a food allergy and you eat a food that you're allergic to throat swells up and shit hives.
Rym: Celiac doesn't have any of that thing instead.
Rym: It's just an autoimmune like attack in the gut.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know hives is an autoimmune attack in the skin, but they're distinct and EpiPens not gonna help you with celiac.
Rym: Anyway I'm sure Nuri is gonna be like you guys are both wrong, whatever.
Scott: So my news is that it's warm and here at the NOAA the National Oceanographic You don't know.
Rym: do you something?
Scott: American now atmospheric administration?
Scott: That's it.
Rym: That sounds like an organization that administers the atmosphere.
Scott: if you don't know about the NOAA It is paid for with federal tax money and there are people who are against it on the grounds that it's unfair competition with like the Weather Channel Except the Weather Channel gets their weather from the NOAA.
Rym: In fact, almost everyone who reports on weather just gets it from the NOAA.
Scott: So every weather you watch is just taking the weather from the NOAA and then reporting it except for weather underground Which has citizen weather stations.
Scott: Anyway, you should get your weather from there because it's you're you're paying for it And they have the best weathers and it's free.
Scott: and they made this little video Of a heat of the heat wave and it shows you day by day where the heat wave at and basically looks like full 1080p like Texas caught on fire and that fire spread.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a 1080p video of the heat wave from July 13th through tomorrow, but 105
Rym: degrees in the seven tunnel under Grand Central today
Scott: I heard there was somewhere that it was a hundred and seventeen like in Minneapolis or something in that at the Moat a Particular time it was the hottest and humidest place on earth
Rym: the hottest weather.
Scott: I guess short of short of a volcano.
Rym: I've been in a hundred and six degree heat.
Rym: That is the hottest outdoor temperature I've ever experienced.
Scott: I don't know what the hottest I've been in is.
Rym: I'm maybe it was hotter one day and I didn't know but Yeah, it's hot.
Rym: We can't stop talking about it cuz it's just so hot but it's good.
Scott: It's great.
Scott: I'll take it.
Rym: So anyway, so uh SDCC this weekend, we won't be there.
Rym: Otakon.
Scott: I'm sure there'll be a zillion news for next Wednesday.
Rym: We will also not be at Otakon.
Rym: so I'll just say this we're known we have no blood blood for Otakon But they do not like us so much.
Rym: Oh, well So if you want us to go to Otakon just tell Otakon that you want us to do our stuff at Otakon.
Rym: We'll do it if they ask us.
Rym: Yeah, but that aside You probably should be going to Otakon even if we're not there because as we've said Makoto Shinkai Is gonna be there.
Scott: if you don't know who Makoto Shinkai is you need to watch all his movies.
Rym: Such basically just watch him in order.
Scott: He is the guy who made an anime called Hoshino Koei voices of a distant star in his basement with his wife with his wife.
Scott: They voiced it then they got it re-voiced but later and it is like what five ten minutes.
Scott: It's short, but it's amazing.
Rym: It's I defy other than people who really fight it or who aren't human.
Rym: You're gonna cry, you know fucking cry.
Scott: but he pretty much draws clouds and Movies and well short animations about sad people in relationships separated by space and time.
Rym: space and time drama sad Longing distant love, right?
Scott: That's all he makes but he's going by.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with being a one-trick pony if you're awesome at that trick And it's not a trick anyone else has done and such and such.
Rym: so he also made The full-length movie Place Promised in our early days, which I really like.
Rym: Hoshino Koei, but I like Place Promised more But that seemed that way.
Rym: the place promised in our early days has some some of the most beautiful skyscapes I've ever seen.
Scott: Well, yeah, cuz he draws clouds.
Rym: Awesome plane with the two like propellers.
Rym: Yeah, and it has either the saddest happy ending or the happiest sad ending I've ever seen does have a terrible secret of space.
Scott: it does typical from animes the mysterious tower in the distance.
Rym: Yeah he did five centimeters per second, which is just a TV series of lovers separated by space and time.
Scott: and his.
Scott: what's the new thing called?
Rym: It is called Hoshi.
Rym: Oh Kodomo.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: But anyway, it's a new thing.
Scott: He made.
Scott: it's gonna be screened at Otakon premiered with no subtitles.
Rym: Children who chase lost voices from deep below.
Scott: I'm sure it will be stunning.
Rym: Yep I'm pretty sure that there's a picture.
Scott: if you don't understand what's going on.
Rym: There is a picture probably a movie poster in the article I'm going to link to.
Rym: and Yeah, I want to see that.
Scott: please videotape his panel.
Rym: Oh my god, if we were at Otakon with Emily She would just translate the whole thing for us while we were sitting there.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But please videotape the panel so I can see it.
Scott: Yes, and don't videotape the movie because Otakon will kick your ass out.
Scott: I can wait for that to be on DVD.
Rym: if you are at Otakon go to the Q&A People.
Rym: don't go to the guest panels.
Scott: They do.
Scott: they just go to like voice actors and other stupid shit.
Scott: They don't go to the Japanese people who came all the way from halfway around the world To see you and you and I'll like ten people show up and simultaneously.
Rym: the anime cons don't do anything about this.
Scott: They don't try.
Rym: I mean the New York Anime Festival did try when they got mr.
Rym: Gundam.
Rym: They were like, holy shit We got mr.
Scott: Gundam and then they fucked up.
Rym: Well, yeah, they fucked up the translator, but that room was packed.
Rym: It was indeed and I think more people went to see him at Otak at that New York Comic Con Anime Festival just because they pumped him up then.
Rym: anyone has ever seen anyone who was Japanese At any other anime con ever?
Scott: quite possibly except maybe yoko kano, maybe I don't know which was.
Scott: I had no to count But that was a concert.
Scott: a concert doesn't care.
Scott: We're talking about a panel not a concert.
Scott: concerts are different because here's someone talk Versus to hear someone sees them and perform.
Rym: Yeah just one of my saddest memories is going to the anime central and they're not anime central.
Rym: anime next and Just randomly walking into a big gigantic panel room.
Rym: There's only a few people sitting around and up front We're like, is that Rintaro?
Scott: It was oh my god, the director the director of the movie.
Rym: We'll discuss today Yes But before that we have of course things of the day.
Rym: so if you I'm living under a rock.
Rym: You might not realize that my little pony friendship is magic is legit more ponies.
Rym: I got it Before we did the show.
Rym: Scott is basically just going item by item down radio.
Scott: That doesn't mean I want to put it in GeekNights.
Rym: I needed a thing of the day and one thing that is very popular in Japan.
Rym: That does not happen.
Rym: as much in the?
Rym: u.s.
Rym: Is taking the opening to an anime or an animation or something and Reanimating it with characters from something else.
Scott: Yeah Americans Remixers tend to be lazier and they take paths of least resistance.
Scott: They like to edit videos They don't like to make new animation and or you know, because it's a lot of work.
Rym: So it's a very like Japanese fandom thing.
Rym: So that's why I'm using it today because this is someone did that sort of thing in flash to the.
Rym: my little pony.
Rym: friendship is magic opener, but they portrayed all the ponies as Girls like human girls.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: It's pretty cute.
Scott: Okay, so You know when it comes to webcomics, right?
Scott: There's a bunch of different categories of web comics.
Scott: I sort of realized.
Scott: right.
Scott: there's the pure webcomic.
Scott: It was a webcomic.
Scott: It always will be a webcomic like say a penny arcade or a dr.
Scott: McNinja, right or something like that Or boases, right.
Scott: then there's the.
Scott: it's a newspaper comic, but you can read it on the web, which is all the newspaper.
Rym: Thanks.
Scott: But then there's sort of the.
Scott: it's a comic book, but it's a webcomic at the same time, right?
Scott: So one of those was freak angels, which I was reading right?
Scott: So I just started reading that.
Scott: Oh, well, it's almost done.
Scott: Oh good gonna be done in like a chapter and they're gonna print the final trade.
Scott: I think it's gonna be seven By the trade.
Scott: then seven of them.
Scott: But yeah, so freak angels cuz I mean it was purely.
Scott: I mean, you know mechanically it was a webcomic, right?
Scott: It was you know, put on the web first collected into trades.
Scott: There were never any issues, but it was written by Warren Ellis a professional comic book writer, right?
Scott: He was coming who comes from comic book land.
Scott: so that's like saying if Alan Moore just you know started writing a webcomic and it happened to be that every page of the Webcomic was the same shape as a real normal comic book store comic.
Rym: Because with a webcomic, I mean if you post just one page you have to scroll.
Rym: imagine reading spider-man One page every few days.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, it's it's made by someone who comes from the real quote real comic world, right?
Scott: So anyway, freak angels is ending.
Scott: So I needed some new comic to replace it.
Scott: It's not done yet.
Scott: I think freak angels might have another few chapters or whatever.
Scott: But so I needed in a comic to replace it and I found one in the same category not ogloff Not ogloff, but I probably will add ogloff.
Scott: So there is a new Comic and it comes out every Monday and Thursday and it's steampunk pirates, which is really cliche.
Scott: It's lady saber and Pirates of the ineffable ether spelled a e th er, right?
Scott: So that's sort of like All right.
Scott: But the person who has created this comic Oh What the hell is his name is a comic creator that I much enjoy and his name is not on the front page.
Scott: Why did he not put Oh unprepared Unprepared.
Rym: I'm not gonna turn this off.
Rym: It's dead air.
Rym: There's gonna be dead air Scott.
Rym: Who's the author?
Scott: He I fucking know his name, but like he didn't put it on his own thing.
Scott: He's a. he's the guy who did whiteout and he did Gotham Central and he did Oh Greg Rucka Christ.
Scott: he didn't put his fucking name on his own fucking comic moron What the hell.
Scott: but anyway anyway, yeah So he wrote all those great comics that I like and bought all of.
Scott: so now he's writing a webcomic.
Scott: So I'm like, well even though this is cliche steampunk pirate ladies, and there's only three pages so far.
Scott: So I don't even know if it's good or bad.
Scott: yet Greg Rucka is been nothing but win in all the real comics.
Scott: He's written that I have read a queen and country.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: queen and country.
Scott: Gotham Central and whiteout are like his big winners.
Scott: So I like all those.
Scott: they're all great.
Scott: So I'm gonna trust him on this one, too.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So in the meta moment the next convention We will be at is of course the penny arcade expo.
Rym: Oh shit, we'll be doing stuff at it.
Rym: Stay tuned for that.
Rym: We will probably like we did at PAX East video it and put it online Shortly after that in New York Comic Con.
Rym: New York Comic Con New York anime festival.
Rym: We will be doing stuff at that too.
Scott: I would also like to remind you of the worst webcomic contest.
Rym: Yes submit to us the worst webcomic.
Scott: There is a thread in the forum And also if you go to from a comment click news You'll see a news article linking you to a form to fill out to nominate the worst webcomics.
Rym: Now one thing very important.
Rym: when it comes to a contest like this much like our someone it's gonna be a completely subjective Content.
Rym: our slightly infamous worst podcast pond contest which uh Anime pulse won pretty handily.
Scott: Well, did they?
Scott: I forget who won anime pulse one.
Rym: Okay, but here's the thing.
Rym: if you submit an entry to this that is fine.
Rym: You should submit one.
Rym: we have a prize.
Rym: submit whatever you want, but you Must agree and understand that if you do not yourself make your creative work If you are not yourself a webcomic artist a podcaster or something Look at what shit you just submitted.
Rym: that you're saying is terrible and realize that you are worse as a person than whoever Made the thing that you just because you didn't make anything.
Scott: So at least they made something.
Rym: Yep Something's better than nothing even making shit.
Scott: At least they're making something Unless they give up after like two strips.
Rym: that also also you can stop submitting control.
Rym: I'll delete you people.
Rym: We've got it.
Rym: We got that.
Scott: we got that one the first person submitted in the case of a duplicate submission because there's quite a few others Winning the one that was submitted earliest or has like the best.
Scott: I guess we'll subjectively decide who amongst denominators.
Rym: the only thing that's been submitted more than once is control alt Delete.
Scott: there are other things submitted more than one really.
Rym: Yes, cuz I haven't looked at it recently.
Rym: Anyway, control alt delete is pretty much it should win the.
Scott: it was submitted multiple.
Scott: It was definitely it wins the listeners choice award because I got the most nominations.
Rym: Oh my god I feel bad.
Scott: It remains to be seen whether it will win it.
Rym: our award Someone submitted xkcd.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, they can see.
Scott: you can you can submit penny arcade if you want But don't ever come and meet me in the hallway.
Rym: Also the book club will just say this now is its own show now a separate feed and everything.
Rym: So stay tuned for that appearing and hopefully once a month We'll be doing those.
Rym: the last book club book was foundation as a mob sci-fi.
Rym: We will talk about that.
Rym: Yep, and that's it for now in about six months and then another month will be packs for our PAX East.
Rym: Yeah, we'll be at that.
Scott: After that is New York comic-con at some point October, I think.
Rym: uh October is when the New York comic-con is.
Rym: we already mentioned that.
Scott: oh he did.
Scott: Okay I just want to add one more thing, you know, I know that we are shit talkers of the highest order.
Scott: Well the second highest order.
Scott: I mean we do make GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah But I have a new strategy.
Scott: it is the most obvious strategy.
Scott: it's not a new strategy it's a strategy.
Scott: Well, it's it's.
Scott: um, the fact that I'm following.
Scott: the strategy is new.
Scott: This is strategy to achieve V. Yes, the strategy itself is very old and I'm like, why was I so stupid not to ever actually use this strategy?
Rym: We've used it before we just forget.
Scott: So now I'm gonna follow this strategy for hopefully until the end of time when I die.
Scott: and that strategy is attack only one.
Rym: Dude why do you keep attacking me cuz I attack only one.
Scott: So The attack only one at this point in time is front crew calm.
Scott: So I've put all other projects aside and I am attacking only major improvements to front recruit calm.
Scott: So they will.
Scott: I've already made some of them and if I could just fucking get home instead of coming over here to play Games and make podcasts every day then I could get a lot more done.
Rym: But luckily Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday not doing Anything meanwhile, so you guys know well, I'll keep you know, this is the meta part of the show.
Rym: So I'll keep it on my attack.
Rym: Only one is now all the video content for GeekNights front row crew radio free Equestria all our lectures the uncle yo stuff I recorded.
Rym: I'm going to attack all the video projects that have been piling up on me Mm-hmm.
Scott: That doesn't sound like attacking only one.
Rym: Well one at a time in that I'm attacking that and inside of that I'm going to finish game mechanics and mechanism design.
Rym: get that online.
Rym: then how to win a games then uncle Yo, then radio free Equestria then all the other videos I've got Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah I'm sure that's just riveting to all you listeners.
Scott: It is There's one more thing I want to say August August 6th 13th and 20th, huh?
Rym: Three days that mean nothing to me.
Scott: on those three days the New York City Department of Transportation Will be having a program known as summer streets From 7 a.m.
Scott: To 1 p.m So that's a full 8 9 10 11 12 6 hours.
Scott: Right on those three days Park Avenue will be closed from 70 something Street to the Brooklyn Bridge.
Rym: I Want to go over there and do something.
Scott: I'm probably gonna bike all the way but that will probably take like 15 minutes.
Scott: I should walk it.
Scott: I'll probably do it 15 or like not 50.
Scott: I'll probably do it like back and forth four times because you can go so fast cuz no one there.
Scott: but they have like actually programming like you can go and like just do yoga and Exercises or you know shit and there's police everywhere, huh?
Rym: I wonder See we could say oh, we'll do a meet-up.
Rym: We'll say when we're gonna be there, but usually when you do meetups It's because we have a table and we're gonna play some board games.
Scott: Yeah, this is gonna be moving.
Scott: I'd see.
Scott: what I'm really wondering is you know in Park Avenue is a little tunnel.
Scott: Yep, right in front of grants.
Rym: Can we go into the tunnel?
Scott: Can we go in the tunnel cuz there won't be cars in there?
Scott: I really want that to be so will it?
Scott: but it thing is it's so dangerous, you know It's so dangerous to go in there under normal circumstances.
Rym: I know I'm always afraid It's one of my weird like one of the few things I'm actually like.
Scott: I like if you go near that tunnel.
Scott: it has all these signs like don't go the fuck in here unless you're A car.
Scott: stay the fuck out If you're a biking.
Scott: don't even go near this thing.
Rym: I'm always nervous when I'm biking that I'll just like Be stupid and not pay attention and go right into one of those tunnels.
Scott: the UN tunnels good of is the worst.
Scott: Yeah, really don't want to go in that one one time.
Rym: I went through that tunnel through Central Park Like that half tunnel that some like the cross.
Scott: those are just overpasses.
Scott: Where's there?
Scott: a tunnel there is.
Rym: there's one that's under Like it's down and it has some tunnels in it and there's really no room for.
Scott: you don't want to go in the transverse road?
Rym: No, you don't.
Rym: I was in I was on it.
Scott: take you want to take the park drive.
Scott: I think Emily was on a park drive - if you're on a bike you want to do park drive only no transverse road.
Rym: So anyway, we talked about rent aro earlier and a long time ago on the sci-fi channel.
Rym: You know, this is one of the things that got us into anime.
Scott: I was watching, you know I'd only seen you know a few animes and I didn't really you know.
Scott: I kind of knew like a cure was this cool anime that I hadn't seen it quite yet.
Scott: Yeah, I you know, I watched Voltron when I was a kid and I sort of knew Japanese.
Scott: ish, right?
Scott: But it was sort of like yeah, but I watched the whole week on sci-fi channel of Godzilla movies.
Scott: So I had gotten used to watching TV at that time slot the next week.
Scott: I sit down at the same time slot on Monday and it was anime week in the same time slot and they showed.
Scott: the first Night was Fatal Fury and Galaxy Express 3 9 and the second night was a do Galaxy Express 3 9 and I think something else.
Rym: I don't know if it may be fatal for you, too But I know Galaxy Express 3 9 was shown and so was earth.
Rym: say yet sir a to beautiful dreamer That I saw the end the very end of Galaxy Express and all I remember thinking was so what it's a train in space?
Scott: Yeah, but but of all those right.
Scott: so I said you like do I remember Fatal Fury fuck?
Scott: No, right, but Galaxy Express.
Scott: I fucking remember that shit, right?
Scott: That was like the first anime that I saw.
Rym: that was like About that like that kind of thing like when I first saw vampire hundred space adventure Like what's this hardcore vampire guy?
Rym: Like no none of the tropes of anime were known to me or the history of anime, you know.
Rym: So imagine seeing you know a Galaxy Express like it's so different from anything you'd see in America because it's so epic and melodramatic That you know.
Scott: just that was the thing, you know, I saw animes before it kind of sorta.
Scott: But that was the first anime that was like whoa.
Scott: I need to see everything that is like this that exists in the world.
Rym: So you Relatively recently in the last like year or two watched all of the TV show.
Scott: Well, yeah, I pretty much you know, I you know, I saw more.
Scott: Liji Matsumoto works over the years, right?
Scott: You know his properties the Yamato's and the Captain Harlock, but more recently I set him on fire.
Scott: I saw every episode of the Galaxy Express 3 9 TV show.
Scott: I was every episode of the Captain Harlock TV show.
Scott: I want to see all of the Queen millennia TV show, but it's really hard to get episode.
Scott: At least it's hard to get all of them.
Scott: You can get quite a few of them.
Scott: I saw Space Symphony meta.
Scott: I saw Almost everything Arcadia of my youth.
Scott: I saw that.
Rym: I think we reviewed that on GeekNights, right?
Scott: But just recently as in within the past month, right?
Scott: Discotech media has.
Scott: finally these people are awesome.
Scott: By the way, discotech is pretty much the best anime Company in the US right now, right prices good translation prices good translation subtitles high quality DVDs.
Scott: Everything's good.
Scott: You can buy it like a full season of Fist of the North Star for them for 30 bucks.
Scott: They also put out awesome, you know movies like attack the gas station and shit.
Scott: I'm pretty sure they do that one, but they you know those kinds of movies if not that one in particular All your awesome Asian cinema discotheque, so they put out Galaxy Express 3 9 and the sequel movie I do Galaxy Express 3 9 on DVD.
Scott: They just both came out.
Scott: They're like $17, but it's totally worth it.
Scott: I've never seen them before in this higher resolution with this high quality and audio with the subtitles and the whole thing.
Scott: It was way beautiful.
Scott: Yeah for something from like 1979. so basically the deal is for those of you who are not familiar with the Galaxy Express, right?
Scott: There is a kid who lives on earth.
Scott: earth has normal people Biological humans and they suck because they die and they're basically all poor.
Scott: but meanwhile There are also robot humans, right?
Scott: Anyone who has enough money goes and gets a machine body like Ghost in the Shell, right?
Scott: So why wouldn't you get a machine body?
Scott: machine bodies can live forever and you don't get sick or anything?
Rym: Ah, but what is the price of immortality?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: that may be the message and moral.
Scott: that might be What the show's about the overarching points that there is.
Scott: but regardless of that.
Scott: so there's a poor kid named Tetsuro, right and Hoshi no Tetsuro and he is in the TV show.
Scott: He's a potato head and The movie.
Scott: he has a much better character design and steady as the butt nose, but it is less funny.
Rym: There's a butt nose instead of a potato face.
Rym: Yeah, sometimes I love how the flashback in the movie is back to the potato head.
Scott: Yeah, that was pretty cool.
Scott: It's like as a kid He was Phil potato head But not later.
Rym: that is you know That is such a nod to the people watching the show.
Rym: right that was just lost on me as a kid.
Scott: So he was poor and walking around in the snow with his mom.
Rym: We're trying to get to the city with his mom.
Scott: right an evil count.
Scott: Mecca is basically a robot guy.
Scott: I met a you know mechanical person and he hunts human biological humans for sport because he can do that sort of thing.
Scott: so he freaking just blows Tetsuro's mom away with a laser right to have her mounted on his wall.
Scott: and Then you know Tetsuro goes on a journey to get his revenge.
Scott: and also he wants to get his own machine body because there's a Planet far away where you can get a machine body for free Even if you're poor.
Rym: all you have to do is get there.
Scott: He wants to have a long life to make up for the short life of his parents so that he wants to get to that Planet and the only way to get there is in the galaxy ray.
Scott: I've also watched galaxy railways all of it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I watch that.
Rym: It looks really fun.
Rym: It's okay.
Scott: So galaxy railways is basically this intergalactic train service.
Scott: It's like if the MTA went everywhere in the Milky Way and Andromeda galaxies and possibly other galaxies as well.
Rym: Now the interesting thing is the the design of the galaxy Express is nostalgic.
Rym: It looks like an old.
Scott: yeah, most of the galaxy railways trains look like fancy, you know, I guess at least bullet trains, right?
Scott: They would be futuristic for the 70s and let's the late 70s early 80s.
Scott: But you know, they look like bullet trains and all other fancy space trains.
Scott: But the galaxy Express is a high-tech train that looks like an old-fashioned steam train.
Scott: Right and the reason it's a special train because not only is it incredibly expensive to ride this train But it goes Express to Andromeda Which is a big deal.
Scott: because you know, most of the trains just go from solar system to solar system or planets a planet You know, there's like commuter trains that go from like, you know Saturn to earth or whatever, you know, like Titan to Mars But this is a train that goes all the way to fucking Andromeda, which is another galaxy.
Scott: You know what space there is between galaxies.
Rym: about over 200 episodes worth of plan.
Scott: Well, yeah, it's like.
Scott: so people question whether or not it's an Express and in the movie It doesn't stop at that many planets.
Scott: in the TV show It stops at every planet and I haven't read the manga.
Rym: Well, how many planets are in between the stops that it just doesn't bother with?
Scott: right the Express part of the galaxy Express is in between the Milky Way and Andromeda.
Scott: It doesn't stop cuz there's nowhere to stop.
Scott: That's the Express part, right?
Scott: There's no other train that's gonna get you all the way to.
Rym: and now we're not talking about the show But the show is primarily just this kind of show.
Rym: where they do episodic the train lands on a planet It's there for X hours or X days Tetsuro fucks up and gets into trouble and the planet has its existential crisis right at that moment.
Scott: Yep, so imagine if for you know, take for example cowboy bebop.
Scott: right in cowboy bebop There's some episodic episodes and there's also plot episodes.
Scott: But some of the non plot episodes have a little bit of plot in them like a tiny bit, right?
Rym: Or they have like some really important character development or something or something like that, right?
Scott: But there are episodes that are purely episodic.
Scott: now Imagine if cowboy bebop was hundreds of episodes long like a hundred and thirty something.
Scott: Well, you know Maybe ten twenty of the episodes would have some bit of plot in them and the rest would just be talking dinosaurs.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: So Galaxy Express the TV show a lot of the episodes are just you know, they're self-contained.
Scott: You don't need them.
Scott: The movie is a compilation that only focuses on the main plot Tetsuro getting his revenge getting to the robot planet.
Scott: What's the deal with?
Scott: may tell?
Scott: why does she want to help Tetsuro?
Scott: You know what's going on in the time Castle, you know all that sort of stuff right count Mecca is a bad guy.
Scott: It concentrates solely on that plot and also brings captain Harlock and emeraldus and friends into it more.
Scott: So yeah, right And it skips over a lot of the stop at a random planet and you know learn a lesson about something unrelated.
Rym: There's a more, you know, it's always some sort of like existential moral dilemma What is the meaning of fighting your own way or being a beggar?
Rym: or yeah, this is not listening to what mental who told you This is the.
Scott: this is the planet made of bolts, right?
Scott: All people do on this planet is make bolts, but there's an artist living on this planet.
Scott: Oh, so woe is this artist who is forced to make bolts but wants to make art, you know on this horrible planet?
Scott: Yeah, I can't afford to leave.
Rym: This is the planet where everyone's immortal, but they miss funerals So they fucking murder people so they have an excuse for funerals, right?
Scott: So, yeah, there's planets like that in the TV show But the movie just concentrates on the planets that have something to do with the plot.
Rym: So our review if it wasn't obvious, we're just gonna talk about the movie and we'll avoid spoilers though.
Rym: Sorry, I already talked about the movie a lot Yeah But bear in mind that the movie which spoils the end of the show was aired in Japan like shown Before the series ended.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not sure when the the timing of the manga release which I haven't read any of But yes, the movie was released before the TV show was done.
Scott: So you saw the ending of the TV show in the movie.
Scott: if you were Japanese before you saw the ending of the TV show.
Scott: But they are slightly different.
Scott: They're not exactly the same, right?
Scott: I mean, it's the same general idea with this spoiling ending that we won't actually spoil but They are quite different.
Scott: So just because you've seen the whole movie and you think you know Oh, I know what's gonna happen at the end of the TV show now It's not exactly the same.
Scott: It's still worth watching the TV show if you like.
Scott: Yes
Rym: now in terms of the movie, this is one of those things where even if you don't like it I know people who are anime fans who have seen it and who don't like it Even though they do understand a lot of what's going on and why it's the way it is.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: But much like citizen Kane if you want to have an opinion on anime and say that you care about anime You had better have seen this movie and at least know what the deal is.
Scott: Yeah It's like you don't have to watch the whole TV show Right, but if you haven't seen at least this first movie not even the second one Just if you haven't seen this first movie your opinion on anime really doesn't count.
Scott: It's also interesting not because it's that you know, I'm not gonna say, you know that it's the greatest movie ever.
Scott: There are plenty of anime movies that are significantly better than this movie.
Scott: many Miyazaki movies It's oshi khan movies.
Scott: Akira ghost in the shell does plenty of it.
Scott: I'd even say summer wars is better than this movie.
Scott: But this movie is important and it's still just because there are many anime movies better than it.
Scott: It is still great though It's interesting depending on when you watch it and in what atmosphere.
Scott: it could have a profound impact on you.
Scott: Oh my god, when I watched it in high school, it had a profound impact much less impact now But I still very much enjoy it.
Rym: Well, I think the difference is that when I first saw it, I didn't know any of those characters were.
Scott: that's true.
Rym: The whole all those like side plots and the bird and harlock and emeraldus and everything I I got the impression that I should know like kind of like when I saw the first tenchi movie.
Rym: as a kid I didn't know who these people were but the movie indicated to me that I should have known like they're a big deal.
Rym: So I went into that movie just thinking like oh that must be an important person.
Rym: Oh, I wonder what the deal is with that and it got me really interested in the Matsumoto verse.
Rym: Just cuz.
Rym: I wanted to know what the deal was.
Rym: Why'd that guy turn into a ship?
Rym: and what's the deal with the bird and the gun?
Rym: and why is?
Rym: why is that gone?
Rym: Like how did you get that fucking gun?
Scott: Yeah, why is the gun special right?
Rym: It's like Why is everyone so sad when so-and-so died?
Scott: There's even more of that in the second movie.
Scott: Yeah It's weird because the first time I saw it even though I didn't know who any of those people were and I didn't even realize it Was a universe of combined things or anything like that It sort of had this, you know, really melodramatic and sort of awe-inspiring mystic quality to it.
Scott: and now It's like I sort of have this, you know actual knowledge like oh, that's you know, you know Tochiro.
Scott: oh, yeah, man, that's so-and-so and oh my god, but you know, he's going into the Arcadia.
Scott: But it wasn't that same story told differently in you know, actually the actual captain Harlock show.
Scott: So which one is the right one answer?
Scott: There is no right one and there's a person doesn't go together.
Scott: It's a bunch of jigsaw puzzle pieces that look like they fit but they don't fucking.
Rym: we didn't even get the experience of imagine if We'd seen the whole show first and then the movie and we had and we had been people who had watched.
Scott: You know, we had been Japanese people who watched Yamato and Harlock already and not just all at once like we do.
Rym: But you know every week every week every week for your childhood one episode of the space train Yeah, and then there are a hundred something weeks and then way later a movie.
Rym: Yep, but watching it like you said movie from my modern perspective.
Rym: I Fan-service.
Rym: there isn't that movie a lot.
Rym: a lot of that movie is check it out.
Scott: It's hard.
Scott: Yeah, it still works.
Scott: Definitely if you do not know about the Leiji Matsumoto stuff may work better if you don't know.
Scott: I think so too.
Scott: cuz like once you know it you it's or it's weird, right?
Scott: It's like the what Marvel Comics and that often get wrong.
Scott: They sometimes do it right this way, right?
Scott: But they often get it wrong where they'll put stuff in like that.
Scott: So therefore their comic makes no sense to people who don't know it.
Scott: DC gets it wrong a lot more often, right?
Scott: Yep, but in this case, it's like if you're a fan There's a whole bunch of stuff there for you.
Scott: And if you're not a fan, then it's just okay.
Scott: There's a space pirate, you know, who's?
Scott: who's?
Scott: a great space pirate.
Scott: Okay, you know, he's just some guy You don't know you don't know.
Rym: real part of it too is that I was not used but it's like it's like it's.
Scott: he actually sort of even worse having the inside knowledge because now I Look at it as fan service as opposed to just looking at it as it.
Rym: there's the secondary thing of.
Rym: I was not used to Leiji Matsumoto level melodrama.
Rym: I had never seen anything like that before.
Rym: So the melodrama when I was a kid watching this movie late at night all alone Just made it feel probably more profound than it actually.
Scott: that's why I always watch Galaxy Express late at night in the dark in the quiet because it that's when it works best because it's outer space quiet Melodrama, right.
Scott: if you watch it during the daytime like when you get home from school, that's not gonna work.
Scott: You know when you get home from school or whatever or work watch Macross instead.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: then when the lights go out before bed, that's when you watch the galaxy Matsumoto and stuff.
Rym: you just got to sit down quietly and watch it and just really let the melodrama just take you away.
Scott: That's how I like to watch it.
Rym: Anyway, I think that's probably kind of like how I wonder what the original time A particular red wine should be drunk at a particular temperature a Matsumoto should be watched in a particular time in a particular mindset.
Scott: Yeah, right because it's like if you don't give it your full attention, you know And you're really you're focusing on it and it's quiet then you're not gonna really get.
Scott: you know, this, you know Extreme melodrama and you know sort of quiet space action is gonna come off.
Scott: sort of cheesy, I guess.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time the the actual message like the core moral structure of The Galaxy Express TV show and movie is I think extremely profound on its own.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I don't know It is a strong and quality message But I think what got me about it was that it's a message that is in so many sci-fis.
Scott: You know, it's a combination of me.
Scott: I'm play guy and You know token elves.
Scott: Yeah at the same time.
Scott: What was us?
Rym: Oh the non men.
Scott: Yeah, right It's like, you know, it was even when I originally saw it.
Scott: It was a message that I had seen already in multiple sci-fi works over and over.
Rym: But there's something about the way it's presented.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: So seeing it again.
Scott: It was like, oh man There's that sci-fi message that I've seen in so many works that I really liked.
Scott: I really like this one too.
Scott: In fact, it gives me this message.
Scott: I've seen and heard before better than those other ones Did.
Rym: well because for all the melodrama it's weird like but when I first saw the movies a kid Certain scenes felt much more profound to me than they are now.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time the message was actually like.
Rym: the core message was not presented directly in melodramatically.
Rym: throughout most of it.
Rym: it was very subtle.
Rym: you see people who die and people who live and You realize toward the end how much more moved you are by the people who died After a long and fulfilling life achieving their goals or failing at their goals Yeah, and how the people who live forever achieved more but yet it felt more hollow.
Scott: Yeah There's also the the fact, you know, you watch a lot of sci-fi things right even yeah even Matsumoto ones right and they always have lots of space battles.
Scott: It's always about the space battles, especially Yamato.
Scott: It's like, you know fire the wave motion cannon, but dude Right, but Galaxy Express doesn't have a lot of that.
Scott: I mean the TV show.
Scott: there's space battles But they don't go the same way.
Scott: Star Trek Star Wars or Yamato.
Scott: space battles do right?
Scott: It's either like the train is sitting there with shields on hoping it won't get no they won't die Or someone comes on the train and has like one gun, you know, or you know, it's always.
Scott: you know, sir It's it's much more Western in its its battle styling than in it than space styling, right?
Scott: It's like all the action is Western action, even though it's because it's all character driven.
Scott: There's no.
Scott: it's like instead of you know If they're gonna fight on the train, it'll be like a train robbery where you know Some bandits get on the train.
Rym: Well, that's it.
Rym: It's all character driven that the Matsumoto verse If anything could be said to be consistent throughout.
Rym: it's that a person fighting for what they believe Directly with just guts and will and determination is more powerful than any force in the universe.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like a lot of the planets they go to are Western in styling and space pirates are basically also Cowboys.
Rym: Well, they fight under their own flags in the sea of shining stars.
Scott: Yeah, of course Yeah, it's just and I mean come on gun frontier, right?
Scott: It's it's basically.
Scott: it's like Western in space And it's like people are like cowboy.
Scott: bebop was like Western Kung Fu movie in space like yeah.
Scott: Well, this is from the late 70s dude and the early 80s.
Scott: So it got beat Got beat big time.
Rym: I Still like the movie though.
Rym: I'm glad I watched it again.
Scott: I'm glad that I want to watch the second one again.
Rym: I haven't seen the second one.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: The second one is something special Something special.
Scott: Yeah, it's good But you know, but it's got stuff.
Rym: Yeah stuff.
Scott: I don't know how much I want to say about it.
Rym: Yeah, we'll hold on.
Scott: I want to hold off and do another episode.
Scott: Yeah Squeeze another episode out of it.
Rym: I mean we could go on and on about it.
Rym: I mean, I guess we could spoiler line, but there's not.
Rym: there's kind of one really important reveal and that's pretty much it.
Rym: And then that's it.
Rym: The end is just kind of all the denim all today.
Scott: It's pretty much all.
Scott: the whole end is the spoilers.
Scott: It's pretty much like this.
Scott: You can talk about the whole show right up until the end without spoiling anything.
Scott: Yeah, there are some slight differences in the plot.
Scott: I mean, you know, usually when there's a there's a Compilation in the TV show.
Rym: Tetsuro takes a fucking gun kicks in Count Mecca's door murders him and everybody in his household like right Away in episode one.
Rym: Yep, and I remember ConnectiCon way back We had that room late at night and we just had you know, we had to do something.
Scott: So we watched it.
Rym: We just watched that one episode and a crowd of people late at night.
Rym: We filled the room.
Rym: they're like 50 people sitting there and They were kind of like rowdy in the beginning.
Rym: and once the show started they were visibly moved by that scene because Tetsuro Fucking kills that guy.
Scott: It's like in the TV show.
Scott: in the very first episode in in the course of 20 minutes Count Mecca kills Tetsuro's mom and then Tetsuro goes and blows him away and all his friends right.
Rym: it gets his bloody revenge burns the mansion down Yeah, and then he comes back to Mattel and he's like, alright, let's go.
Scott: Yeah, I did it so in the movie.
Scott: in the TV show also There's a multi-part episode about the time palace Which is a castle where there's a fake captain Harlock who's making mischief distinct from the brain palace.
Scott: exactly in The movie right?
Scott: There's still a time palace because I mean that was such.
Scott: it was like a multi-part episode.
Scott: Of course, you got to bring that in
Rym: but
Scott: Count Mecca is in the time palace So Tetsuro actually has to go on the train Get to count Mecca and get his bloody revenge like halfway through the movie as opposed to at the end of the movie or at The very beginning.
Rym: count Mecca is is whiny and pathetic to the end in both.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But the other thing is most times when there's a compilation a movie a lot of times what you'll see the jerk.
Scott: the general pattern I've seen is you know, they'll take the original TV show They'll cut up they'll slice up the important parts and just squish them together and make a movie without actually and maybe the Animate a few new scenes, right?
Scott: This is actually all original animation new carat different character design for Tetsuro Much much higher quality animation than the TV show completely different music from the TV show, right?
Scott: It's a completely original animated movie.
Scott: They just happen to take the major plot points you know of a few planets from the TV show slash manga and Make those the story of the movies.
Rym: So it's like they wrote the movie using pieces of the writing from the TV show and It has because it has all these like the the whole Tochiro like side plot with getting the gun and everything is a good chunk of the movie.
Scott: Yeah, they do.
Scott: That's it's surprising like how much you know, cuz that is not in the TV show at all.
Scott: That is in the Harlock TV show and other Matsumoto works, but they squeezed it into that Galaxy Express Movie I guess to break.
Scott: maybe that was a Intentional thing.
Rym: Well, it did bring in more Harlock fan that whole thing with his mom and you know his fate.
Rym: And yeah tochiro's mom.
Scott: There's no way tojos.
Scott: Mom would have been alive at that.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Well, it was.
Scott: I got to just accept that.
Scott: you know the thing.
Scott: what does?
Scott: stuff doesn't fit Matsumoto.
Rym: stuff does fit But it only fits so much.
Rym: No It fits in this like the allegory and the moral and the feel is like deadlocked.
Scott: The Canon doesn't fit at all right cuz like if you watch one set of TV shows and movies It's like there's no way.
Scott: it's like tochiro came way the fuck after Harlock.
Scott: But then you watch this and it's like no they were at the same time.
Scott: Well, plus with I mean, I mean Tetsuro tochiro and Harlock were definitely the same.
Rym: Yeah But look at how the message of that whole tochiro thing.
Rym: It's exactly the same message as it was in every other portrayal of ah, but it's somewhat conflicted because you know his death Serving the purpose that it serves.
Rym: but at the same time Could he not had he been longer lived with a robot body?
Rym: He could have gone hot back home to his mother And at least said something.
Scott: also his daughter was completely absent from the movie.
Rym: But this is I think why the message feels so profound.
Rym: You know this over this kind of generic fantasy message of if you are immortal life loses all meaning.
Rym: that in the Matsumoto verse Oftentimes you see characters who really should have lived longer and how everything would have been better had they been immortal.
Scott: Well, then he didn't die.
Scott: He uploaded himself into his spaceship.
Scott: So it's like he didn't go for the robot body until he was already gonna die Anyway, but at the same time as opposed to just a lot of people just went for the robot body.
Rym: immediately You get the impression that it was not a clean like.
Rym: he is not still quite the same person.
Rym: He can't go back home.
Scott: He's basically part of a computer.
Rym: He can't go back and say just you know Anything to his mother can't resolve that whole situation.
Scott: He doesn't want to either.
Rym: Yeah, but she wanted him to know.
Scott: that's you know.
Rym: But in there's definitely this idea that the message is immortality bad.
Rym: yet The show is very conflicted on even that point and the movie is also somewhat conflicted on even that point Which is the main point.
Rym: the point is that it's conflicted that you could you could go both ways.
Rym: Yep, if I were a metal well, I don't want to spoil the end end, but I would do things differently And I wouldn't mind being immortal.
Scott: I might wait though wait for what you know for it to get the best possible robot body first.
Rym: Yeah, well, I think there are some good robot bodies one can get.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: They're also some not so good one.
Rym: Yeah So I don't know.
Rym: so we can say I mean it's a fantastic movie even if you don't like it.
Rym: It's one of the more important animated movies ever.
Scott: It's now easily available in high quality with subtitles for the first time.
Scott: do
Rym: it yourself a favor and just late at night some night Just put in the DVD with a couple of friends quietly watch it Maybe while sipping some wine
Scott: and if you like it watch all the Matsumoto show if you
Rym: like
Scott: Matos and I hope there's a hundred and something episodes on crunchyroll.
Scott: You can watch if you like it.
Rym: There is so much of it that you won't know what to do with yourself.
Scott: But yeah, if you do like it, I highly recommend the TV show.
Scott: Some episodes are better than others, but which is what's gonna happen with 100 plus episodes?
Scott: But if you like you'll notice how it's worried.
Rym: Oh head like morphs over time and it gets more and more potato with the eyes get more and more Derped until the very end.
Rym: when they under all at once because they put all their effort into the final They're like oh shit the I migrated too far.
Rym: We got to put it back.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.