Rym: It's Wednesday, August 17th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, the Borrower, Arietty.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Played some Burning Wheel last night, like we do.
Rym: And, you know, one trouble of the large game, even the small game of D&D or anything, is that you need food.
Rym: And it's not like the old days when we were punk kids.
Rym: You just, you know, buy an infinite amount of terrible snack food, like Sun Ships and stuff, and just...
Scott: And one guy eats them all?
Rym: Yeah, that one guy.
Rym: But those are like the 12-hour gaming sessions where, you know, maybe six hours of that was gaming, and the rest was just dicking around and attacking the darkness and all that crap.
Rym: But we're adults now.
Rym: We've got adult lives.
Rym: We're in a hurry.
Rym: So when we play a four-hour game, it's a four-hour game, and we don't have time to do anything else.
Rym: So I thought I'd make some chili.
Rym: Figured that's a nice way to have some food for everybody while we're playing the game.
Rym: that doesn't, like, get in the way, slow us down, don't have to, like, go out or order pizza or anything.
Rym: And I think it was pretty good chili.
Rym: Would you agree?
Scott: It was all right.
Scott: It was good.
Rym: It was pretty spicy.
Rym: It was the right level of spicy.
Rym: I think I did the spiciness correctly.
Rym: So I put in this thing, a third a cup of chili powder and a whole bunch of cayenne pepper and green peppers and jalapenos, and it was awesome.
Rym: But I washed the pot after everyone went home before I went to bed.
Rym: And then I went to play some Nintendo games.
Rym: And my hands are starting to, like, burn, like they're tingly, and I'm kind of wondering, like, what's going on?
Rym: Why are my hands tingly?
Rym: And it's getting worse and worse and worse.
Rym: And then they're starting to get hot, like they're on fire and I can't figure it out.
Rym: I'm just about to freak out.
Rym: And then I'm like, wait a minute.
Rym: And I think back to washing out the bottom of the pot.
Rym: And it was basically like the condensed scrape down pepper at the bottom.
Scott: This is why you wear gloves when you do dishes.
Rym: I usually don't do dishes.
Scott: It's just one of the reasons you wear gloves when you do dishes.
Scott: There are many other reasons.
Rym: Nah, you don't do enough dishes to warn gloves.
Scott: OK, if you're doing even one dish, gloves.
Rym: You're going to put on gloves to wash one water cup?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Really?
Rym: You really put on gloves to rinse out one water cup?
Scott: Yes, I do.
Rym: I don't believe you.
Rym: In fact, I'm going to wait with a camera and catch you not doing it.
Scott: Uh, sure.
Rym: So that sucked.
Rym: I wash my hands.
Rym: Obviously, that doesn't work.
Rym: It's too late.
Rym: So I give up and go to bed with my hands kind of on fire.
Rym: Woke up in the morning.
Scott: Hands still on fire.
Rym: Hands still on fire.
Rym: Took a shower.
Rym: Went to work.
Rym: Hands still on fire.
Rym: It was about noon that the hands were no longer on fire.
Scott: So you go.
Scott: You deserve.
Rym: It wasn't bad.
Rym: It was just kind of odd.
Rym: Like it was an odd sensation that I had not experienced before.
Scott: Some people pay for that.
Scott: You can go to the drug store and buy like capsicol or whatever.
Rym: So it's Wednesday.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There's lots happening in the anime world.
Rym: Tons of news.
Scott: Not really, no.
Rym: I mean, Otakon happened and eh.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Gotoshinkai will also be at the New York Comic-Con Anime Festival.
Rym: So we'll get him there.
Scott: Good.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: What was one of the best movies of recent years?
Rym: How recent do you qualify recent years?
Scott: I have to ask IMDb because I forget the year.
Rym: Because depending on the time span, my answer keeps changing.
Scott: So what is the top three movies of 2009?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Was Inception 2009?
Scott: I'm going to find out.
Rym: Or was that 2010?
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: I'll find out right now.
Scott: No, Inception was 2010.
Rym: Ah, crap.
Rym: What even came out in 2009?
Rym: I guess Avatar?
Scott: The blue one.
Scott: Yeah, that was 2009.
Rym: I put that on the list.
Rym: I thought that was a pretty solid sci-fi movie.
Scott: It was okay.
Rym: I enjoyed it.
Scott: Not as good as the movie I'm thinking of.
Rym: Ah, what movies did I see that were from 2009 that were good?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: How about Black Dynamite?
Rym: Oh, shit, son.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: Black Dynamite.
Scott: First of all, there's a comic book.
Scott: I already have issue one.
Scott: You got to get that shit.
Scott: Number two, there's going to be a cartoon.
Rym: I've seen the first episode.
Scott: The first episode, you can go watch an Adult Swim's website.
Scott: It's for real.
Rym: Well, it is very good at being exactly what it should be.
Scott: Which is awesome.
Rym: But it's hard for me to say that it's good.
Scott: It's got a lot of--.
Scott: How is it not good?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: There's something weird about it.
Rym: The whole time, part of my brain is saying, this is awful, thrown together, pablum.
Rym: And the other part of my brain is saying, shut the fuck up.
Scott: My entire brain just says, anyone who doesn't like this is a jive ass honky.
Rym: I think why I like it in the end, and why all the cons are outweighed by the pros, is that every time it makes a joke, it doubles down on that joke.
Rym: You got a stereotype, you double the fuck down on that stereotype.
Scott: That's why it's not just blacks.
Scott: It's blaxploitation.
Scott: This is what black bastards-- If you don't double and triple down, that's not sploitation.
Rym: This is what black bastards should have been.
Rym: But I don't know.
Rym: And also, once it doubles down, it'll make a joke.
Rym: It skips immediately to the set up for the next double down.
Rym: It moves quick, and it pretty much skips any sort of plot.
Rym: And it's really true to the movie, too.
Rym: I love the flashback, where he's like-- I used to be a children.
Rym: His dad is like, I'm leaving you to raise black dynamite as a single mother, because I'm going to go drinking.
Rym: You should all watch this.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Scott: You should watch this, and then when the show comes out, watch that, too.
Scott: And if you haven't watched the movie, what the fuck?
Rym: A warning on the movie.
Rym: The movie is great, but much like "Eden of the East," the movie starts out as an A, blaxploitation movie.
Scott: Yeah, the movie's like a little bit of a roller coaster.
Scott: It's like, so awesome, this part is a little bit boring.
Scott: Oh my god, it's awesome again.
Scott: And then this went on too long.
Rym: Tell you straight up, the so awesome peaks right before "Secret Chinese Lab" on Island.
Rym: And then it's way downhill, but then it has this huge uptick with one of my favorite lines in any movie ever.
Rym: I threw that shit before I came in here.
Scott: Oh, I threw that shit before I came in the room.
Scott: You don't even remember the line.
Rym: No, because the point is, he threw that shit before.
Scott: He came in the room.
Scott: He came before.
Scott: Yeah, sure did.
Rym: But then he fights Nick.
Rym: The movie's just like a half hour too long.
Rym: Kind of like how "Eden of the East" went from an A to a B by the end.
Rym: That's all right.
Rym: So the moment, once the thing comes back that he threw before, you can actually stop watching the movie.
Rym: There's nothing else to see that's worth seeing.
Scott: Anyway, "Black
Scott: Dynamite.".
Scott: Yeah, "Black
Scott: Dynamite."
Scott: Don't miss it.
Rym: I feel like I'm going to watch the entire cartoon.
Rym: It's right up there with Archer in terms of amount of actual physical laughter brought out of me.
Scott: I don't like that show.
Rym: I don't know what's wrong with you.
Rym: Archer is, in my opinion-- Not funny at all.
Rym: --the funniest cartoon to come out in many years.
Scott: "Ponies" is way funnier than that.
Rym: "Ponies" I like a lot, but it's the drama and the characters and the cuteness that draws me in more than the funny.
Scott: That's what I'm saying, is "Ponies" is not just humor, but Archer supposedly is.
Scott: But Archer has less humor than a show that is only partially humor.
Rym: I don't think it does-- here, I rate humor-- In fact, it has no humor.
Rym: It's not funny at all.
Rym: The way I rate humor in shows now is I use my own metric of me, because I will often see things that are funny.
Rym: But if I'm with people, you tend to laugh.
Rym: Even if something's not that funny, if there's a bunch of people around, at a stand-up comedian, there's this human vibe where you'll laugh more often, like you'll laugh at stuff.
Rym: I remember we'd watch, I don't know, like Dana Carvey together, like a bunch of the crew.
Rym: We'd laugh hysterically.
Rym: I can watch "Chopin' Rocket Lab" by myself, and my brain says, this is hilarious, but it does not force me to laugh out loud.
Rym: I don't just laugh in an empty room.
Scott: This is well-known psychology.
Rym: So "Archer" has made me laugh out loud by myself more times than any TV show I have seen in at least a few years.
Scott: It made me laugh zero times.
Rym: I don't know what's wrong with you.
Rym: It is some funny shit.
Scott: It's not funny at all.
Rym: How can you not find "Archer" funny?
Rym: It's kind of like how you don't like
Rym: "Firefly.".
Scott: It's just boring.
Rym: Or "Cowboy
Rym: Bebop."
Rym: And weird.
Rym: I like "Cowboy
Rym: Bebop."
Rym: But you don't like "Firefly" or "Archer"?
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: Anyway, so "Redline," we've talked about, well, I've talked about this off and on.
Rym: I've been excited about "Redline" pretty much from before it existed.
Rym: It's been in production forever.
Rym: And the fact that it actually came out kind of amazed me.
Rym: Like when we saw that trailer for it way back, it looked like the kind of thing you'd see from like a genius party.
Rym: Like I was amazed that it was actually a movie that was really coming out.
Rym: And I don't know if we talked about this before, but the date has finally passed because it was announced in April that "Redline," which was kind of botched in terms of release, like reviewers who have seen it have said surprisingly unqualified things like this is the greatest and most important animated movie to come out in the last decade.
Rym: - Uh-huh.
Rym: - Not a lot of people have been saying things of that level about
Rym: "Redline.".
Scott: - You realize a lot of anime movies have come out in the last decade that are better than that.
Rym: - Well, other than "Summer Wars" and "The Girl Who Left Her Time" and "Sort of a
Rym: Stranger.".
Scott: - But I mean, there's movies that came out in the last decade that are animated that it cannot possibly be better than.
Rym: - I don't know, 'cause what people have been saying is not so much best but most important because it's different and weird.
Rym: It's kind of like the cool 4C stuff.
Scott: - What year is it?
Rym: - It's 2011.
Scott: - So what year was it, 10 years ago?
Rym: - 2001.
Scott: - So a 2001 movie could qualify?
Rym: - Can you name 10 anime movies that came out in that time that you would consider good?
Scott: - I don't have to name 10.
Scott: I just didn't name one.
Scott: - "Spirited Away" came out in 2001.
Scott: Therefore, this cannot possibly be better.
Scott: - I didn't say better.
Scott: Nor, I didn't even say most important.
Scott: - It can't possibly be more important.
Rym: - I said that people are saying, I'm reporting on what those assholes are saying.
Scott: - I just proved that they're assholes.
Rym: - I have not seen
Rym: "Redline.".
Rym: I do not have an opinion on "Redline" yet, but much like when I saw that trailer to "Escaflowne" way back before it came out in the US, I've been mad excited about it, which is rare.
Rym: I rarely get excited about an anime movie that is coming.
Rym: And the release was kind of botched.
Rym: It didn't really have a good theatrical release either in the US or in Japan.
Scott: - What is up with everyone around the world, right?
Scott: It seems like everyone is botching releases of things, except for Valve.
Scott: When Valve makes a game, they release that game to the entire world simultaneously with great fanfare at the same price.
Scott: They've learned that lesson, and it's awesome.
Rym: - Because Valve doesn't have to rely on theaters playing a movie.
Scott: - Nintendo has these games, right?
Rym: - Nintendo's just stupid.
Rym: I'm not defending Nintendo.
Scott: - But two of those games, they're just gonna put out in Europe.
Rym: - Now, you know what's awesome?
Scott: - It's like, what the fuck?
Rym: - The whole "Nintendo, let me give you my money" thing.
Rym: As we'll talk about at PAX, they used to do that.
Rym: They brought out not just AeroBiz, but AeroBiz Supersonic, a game where you play the CEO of an airline and you have to increase profits and send Tanaka to business meetings in Hong Kong.
Scott: - I also wanna say Millennium Actress, Paprika, and Tokyo Godfathers all came out in the last decade.
Scott: - Yeah, and they're super good movies, but-- - There's no way, I would bet zero dollars that Red Line is better than any of those four movies.
Rym: I did not say-- - Or more important.
Rym: - I said one of the best, that it'll rank up there.
Rym: And two, the reason people are saying it's important is that it has a lot of the qualities that gave it that kind of general appeal that movies like Akira had when they were released in the U.S Like Akira, a lot of people who never saw any anime before and never saw any anime again saw Akira in the theater.
Scott: - They did.
Rym: - And the argument is that Red Line has all the qualities of an Akira to where.
Rym: had it not been botched, this would have been like another wave of people seeing anime.
Scott: - You know what quality Akira had was actually in theaters that people could go to?
Scott: That normal people went to.
Scott: - It's not just that, but it was an action-- - Was on the sci-fi channel and was much advertised that it was going to be on the sci-fi channel.
Rym: - But it was, very particularly, an action sci-fi, which, surprisingly, it's weird how Hollywood seems to be afraid of doing a real action sci-fi.
Scott: - I don't know why.
Rym: - I know.
Scott: And every now and then-- - They don't wanna be 290s.
Rym: - Every now and then, one comes out and even Inception, you could argue, is action sci-fi-esque.
Scott: - Pretty much, yeah.
Rym: - And yet, they didn't even wanna make Inception.
Rym: They didn't wanna release it.
Rym: The fact that it came out was a miracle, and then they're like, "How the fuck did it make "so much
Rym: money?".
Scott: - Avatar was.
Scott: - I know.
Scott: - The blue one you just mentioned.
Rym: - Yeah, Avatar is a great example.
Rym: It's like they forget that--.
Scott: - I like the thing.
Scott: that's annoying, you always get to see Avatar, the blue one.
Rym: (laughing) - Why?
Scott: - You can't just say Avatar, 'cause there's so many of them.
Rym: - It's not like there was any other Avatar movie.
Scott: - Yeah, Ultimate Quest for the Avatar.
Rym: - That wasn't a movie.
Scott: - I did, people get confused.
Scott: (laughing) There's too many things called Avatar.
Rym: - There's the new Avatar stuff coming out, but we'll talk about that later.
Rym: But anyway, it was announced that Redline will be released on Blu-ray in Japan.
Rym: There's no announcement of an American release or anything, but the Blu-ray will have English subtitles.
Scott: - Which means it'll be on the internet real soon.
Rym: - Well, it came out on August 10th, and it looks like the torrents are already making their way around the internet.
Rym: - Yeah, torrents.
Rym: - Go watch Redline and tell me if the people who are saying it is one of the most important anime ever are accurate.
Scott: - I doubt it.
Rym: - Dude, it's F-Zero the movie.
Rym: How can you not be pumped about that?
Scott: - There was an anime, it was F-Zero the anime that was on Cartoon Network, and it was, I forget what it was called, but it was awful and no one watched it.
Rym: - There was no F-Zero anime.
Scott: - It wasn't--.
Rym: - There was no Avatar movie.
Scott: - Actually, there was an F-Zero anime that was F-Zero, and there was another anime that wasn't actually F-Zero.
Rym: - You wanna know a weird F-Zero trivia that I found?
Rym: - Okay.
Rym: - I was researching emulators for the Peck stuff, right?
Rym: - Yep.
Rym: - And I found an emulator that only emulates the original F-Zero on the SNES.
Rym: - It can't play anything else.
Rym: You know why this exists?
Scott: - Because no emulator emulates F-Zero properly.
Rym: - No, it's not because of that.
Rym: It's no more accurate than like SNES 9x for F-Zero.
Scott: - Oh, okay.
Rym: - It hacked in six player online multiplayer simultaneous racing.
Scott: - Ah, shit son.
Rym: - It updates your position on everyone else's ROMs in memory and you race fucking the original SNES F1.
Rym: After PAX, I'm gonna get this shit going.
Scott: - No one's gonna play that.
Rym: - I'll play it like once and then I'll give up.
Scott: I'll talk about it.
Scott: - I'd be more excited if it was Game of Cube F-Zero.
Scott: - Game of Cube F-Zero was the best F-Zero.
Scott: - There was an anime called F-Zero GP Legend.
Scott: It was an anime that was F-Zero.
Scott: And there was also another anime, I forget what it was called, that was about racing of the similar sort.
Scott: I never saw it, but it was on Cartoon Network and no one cared about it.
Rym: - So things of the day, what do you got for me?
Scott: - You know, I know you don't like this game, but I like it, Wolfenstein 3D.
Rym: - It's, you know what, to say that I don't like the game is somewhat of a misnomer.
Rym: I do not terribly enjoy maze games, and Wolfenstein 3D--.
Scott: - What about Maze Craze?
Rym: - Maze Craze is different 'cause that's two player versus and it's just the maze.
Rym: - Whatever, the point is-- - If it was a two player versus race through a maze, then yeah, I would like it.
Scott: - I'm actually often disappointed that newer FPSs are so un-mazelike and they don't have as many just completely arbitrary secret passageways.
Scott: But the problem with the secret passageways in Wolfenstein is while I like them, they're sort of just, there's not often a clue to them.
Scott: It's pretty much brute force touching every wall.
Rym: - Well, they'll be like, oh, it'll be behind the swastika.
Scott: - Yeah, but it's usually it's just touch every wall, right?
Rym: - Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Rym: Wolfenstein was not a fun game from any perspective.
Scott: - It was fun if you just tried to beat it and didn't try to find all the secrets.
Rym: - It was also fun because we'd never seen a game like that before.
Scott: - But anyway, here's a great game, Wolfenstein 1D.
Rym: - Oh shit, son, is that in HD?
Scott: - It is HD 1D in your browser, totally free.
Rym: - 1080p?
Scott: - You can pay $35 for all three episodes if you send your money to Apogee Software in Tejas.
Scott: You can specify three and a half or five and a quarter inch disks when ordering.
Rym: - I love it when someone has a funny joke.
Rym: Like someone could say, yeah, Wolfenstein 1D.
Rym: And then someone actually makes the game.
Rym: that was the joke, demake style.
Scott: - I had an idea for a similar game today.
Scott: I don't know how, it might work, but I don't give it a good shot of working, but it's possible.
Scott: Ready for this idea?
Scott: - I'm ready.
Scott: - Turn-based Dota.
Rym: - That would actually probably work pretty well.
Scott: - Maybe.
Rym: - I want Dota text adventure.
Scott: - Yeah.
Rym: - You have to type obscenities as fast as possible.
Scott: - I think someone made a Dota roguelike already that was like, do you wanna go to lane one, two, or three?
Scott: One.
Rym: - So I'm a big fan, as Scott knows, of YouTube videos people make that are compilations of like the 10 greatest times.
Rym: Arnold Schwarzenegger goes ah, ah, ah.
Scott: - Tom Hanks peeing in every movie.
Rym: - Yep, or every death in Total Recall, stuff like that.
Rym: So this one is one that was actually pretty informative because I did not know.
Rym: most of these were improv.
Rym: 25 movies that have 25 scenes and those scenes, which are somewhat famous or well-known or iconic or a very big actor in them, were actually improvised and not in the script.
Scott: - Or at least some portion of them was improvised.
Scott: Some component.
Scott: - Yeah, some of them are like-- - Some of them are entirely improvised, some just have an improvised component.
Rym: - Yep, or like in one of them, a cab, a real cab, drove onto the set where they had blocked everything off for filming and the actor interacted with a cab that shouldn't have been there.
Rym: that ended up in the movie, stuff like that.
Rym: So in the meta moment, the book club book is the ear, the eye, the arm.
Scott: - The foot, the leg, the hand, the face.
Rym: - The joke that keeps getting made every show.
Scott: - Yeah, it's a great joke.
Rym: - It's okay.
Rym: It's kind of like the nine somethings, nine somethings, nine somethings game.
Rym: - We will be at, not this weekend, but next weekend at the Penny Arcade Expo in Seattle.
Scott: - Next to Walla Walla.
Rym: - We will be doing, on Saturday at noon, Discover the Forgotten Masters and Saturday evening, 6 p.m.
Rym: to 8 p.m.
Rym: in the tabletop workshop area, we'll be teaching people to play a whole bunch of games.
Rym: and in general, the bigger news, there is a gigantic, well, a gigantic new thing for PAX, the tabletop workshop room.
Rym: The experiment of it is this year.
Scott: - It's not that gigantic.
Rym: - But it's something new at PAX.
Rym: They haven't been adding new things for a while, they've just been kind of extending things they've got.
Rym: - Well, Penny Arcade in general, as we know-- - Well, they added that late show that we kind of obeyed.
Scott: - Yeah, that was horrible.
Scott: Penny Arcade in general has a policy of if you're not gonna do something awesome, don't do it at all.
Scott: That's why they stopped making their video game because they lost the ability to make it awesome.
Scott: So they just said, well, let's not do it.
Scott: We either do it awesome or not at all.
Scott: So whenever they do something new, they dip the toe.
Rym: - PAX Seattle, in Seattle, PAX Prime is pretty much for what it, like every part of it is run as perfectly as it could be run.
Scott: So now-- - And they're running out of space and the Halo Fest has taken up a lot of room.
Rym: - So they have to add more interesting things.
Rym: They got more tabletop space, obviously, 'cause that whole addendum area, the appendix this year-- - Is mostly taken up by Halo Fest.
Rym: - Yeah, but it's there at least.
Rym: So Halo Fest doesn't impact existing PAX.
Rym: - That's true.
Rym: - But they have a tabletop workshop area consisting of two workshop rooms.
Rym: And if this goes well, then we will hopefully be doing something with them and they will have a gigantic one at PAX East.
Rym: So my task to you, fellow PAXians, is to go to the tabletop workshop area content and make sure that goddamn room is full.
Rym: Make them realize that they need more content like this.
Rym: They're gonna have indie RPG creators running demos of their indie RPGs.
Rym: We'll be there playing games, teaching people how to play games.
Scott: - All right, I think you've gone on enough about this.
Scott: It's supposed to be the meta moment at the meta hour.
Rym: - All right, all right, you're gonna talk about how we have a website and Facebook and all that?
Scott: - Yeah, you should check us out on the internet, on all the internet places.
Rym: - Yep, our channels are online, all that stuff.
Rym: Tweeter, tweeter.
Scott: - Yep, search for GeekNights with the Googles.
Rym: - So it's not that often that an anime movie, a full feature length movie that isn't Pokemon, Bleach, One Piece, Naruto.
Scott: - It's mostly One Piece every year and Pokemon every year.
Rym: - Yep, but there aren't that many that come out.
Rym: Nevermind ones that get any manner of theatrical release in the US.
Scott: - Well, I mean, and even ones that do come out.
Scott: Some of them are compilation movies.
Scott: Some of them are like direct to DVD OVA type movies.
Scott: It's very rare that you get, and some of them are like part of an anime series, like even the East movie, right?
Scott: It's very rare that you get the standalone anime movie, even though when you first start out in anime, there's such a history of them.
Scott: There's a whole big pile of them you get to watch, but really in total, there aren't that many, and especially even fewer awesome ones, right?
Scott: But that, you know, and I think about it, how do you get into anime?
Scott: Almost exclusively just watching movies, not really watching TV series so much.
Rym: - Yeah, you'll see a movie.
Scott: - I think kids nowadays get into anime with TV series like the Naruto's and the DBZ's, but when I started, it was mostly movies that grabbed you.
Rym: - You'd see a movie, usually out of context, people would see like Project Aco or the Tenchi movie.
Scott: - Wasn't Project Aco an OVA?
Rym: - Yeah, but the first episode, the way it was shown on TV, I mean, you could treat it as a movie.
Rym: It's kind of a standalone thing.
Rym: Each episode of it is basically standalone, and plus there was Battle Gray and Battle Blue, which was the movie, which I think was actually also an OAV, but I digress.
Scott: - I'll look it up.
Rym: - So, well, it was originally porn, but people would see these things.
Rym: Like I remember I saw the Tenchi movie, and I was fascinated because the movie didn't make a lot of sense if you didn't know about the TV show or like what was going on.
Rym: So I'm just like, who are these characters?
Scott: - I know, it was a movie.
Rym: - Why does she have a tail?
Rym: - Project Aco movie.
Rym: - Why, is that Project Battle Gray, Battle Blue?
Scott: - It just says Project Aco movie.
Scott: Then there was Project Aco 2, which is an OAV, 3 was an OAV, 4 was an OAV, Aco the Versus was an OAV, and Aco the Manga was a manga.
Rym: - Versus kind of sucks.
Scott: - Okay, it was a movie, I was wrong.
Rym: - Yeah, all right.
Scott: - It's just 80 minutes, they're short.
Rym: - But anyway, so movies that are anime, if they come out, you know, we always talk about what anime you should see, you should pretty much see them all because it's not that hard to do.
Scott: - Yeah, even if they're not good ones, they're so rare, it doesn't take much time to watch them all.
Rym: - And a lot of them recently have been pretty good that we've been seeing.
Rym: I mean, Sword of a Stranger, I really enjoy.
Scott: - Yeah, I haven't seen any awful ones that are painful, but just at worst, they're average or slightly above average.
Rym: - The last bad anime movie I watched all the way through, I think, was Gundam F91.
Scott: - That's a very old movie from 1991.
Rym: - Well, there is also Goro's Earthsea.
Scott: - That wasn't, I mean, that was bad, but it wasn't, like, hideous.
Scott: Like, I'm dying, this is the worst thing ever.
Rym: - I don't know, though, it hurt because the animation was so good, but the rest of it was so stupid.
Scott: - Yeah, it's bad, but there's a lot worse things out there.
Rym: - Yeah, I guess I don't regret having seen Goro's movie.
Rym: - Goro, the good tournament.
Rym: - I almost regret seeing Gundam F91 'cause it was just so fucking boring and long and I had no idea what was going on and I kind of fell asleep, and then everyone was in an orange jumpsuit and their dads died and it was just stupid.
Scott: - Everyone had a dad, everyone's dad died.
Rym: - Yep, and every dad was in an orange jumpsuit.
Scott: - The problem with F91 is it seemed like a compilation movie that didn't leave out the small details, so it had a lot of small things that had very short scenes, so you didn't care about them 'cause they weren't there long enough to care, whatever.
Scott: We've done a show on that.
Rym: - Yep, so we did see, you know, there was, for those of you who weren't paying attention, another Ghibli movie.
Scott: - There was.
Rym: - Yes, and it was not by Miyazaki's.
Scott: - No.
Rym: - It's one of the non-Miyazaki Ghiblis.
Scott: - Yeah, I know, people always get these confused a lot, like they don't know which Studio Ghibli movies that were directed by Miyazaki and which ones weren't, and they get confused all the time.
Rym: - Yep, as long as they're not directed by Goro.
Rym: - Self-included.
Rym: - So The Borrowers was, it looks like there was a cartoon and a live action.
Scott: - Yeah, I knew that there was a thing called The Borrowers, and I didn't know anything else about it, and I got it confused slightly with The Rescuers for a time, but that was wrong.
Scott: - Really?
Scott: - Yeah.
Rym: - Ah, little people.
Scott: - Yeah, but basically The Borrowers is about little people, but it's not Lilliput, it's not, what's his name?
Scott: - Gulliver?
Scott: - Gulliver and his travels.
Scott: It's another little people, right?
Rym: - You realize only the first bit of Gulliver's travels is little people.
Scott: - I know.
Scott: - Okay.
Scott: - But whenever you see Gulliver's travels portrayed in any other medium besides book, it is just mostly focusing on little people.
Rym: - True, but The Borrowers, basically, this is a straight up adaptation of The Borrowers, which is the story of these little humanoid people who live in the walls of houses and out in the wilderness and borrow stuff that humans wouldn't miss and don't want to be seen.
Scott: - Yeah, so for example, rather than growing sugar cane, which they really can't do 'cause they're tiny and they don't live anywhere near sugar, they steal one cube of sugar from some humans at the middle of the night in their kitchen.
Scott: The humans won't know it was missing 'cause it was one cube.
Scott: But meanwhile, that one cube is enough sugar for fucking months and months for those little tiny people 'cause they're so tiny.
Scott: Ignore the science, it's a fantasy.
Rym: - And this is kind of like a slice of a story.
Rym: It kind of just picks up kind of in the middle of this life of the borrowers and there's this kind of underplot of how come there are so few of us?
Rym: The borrowers we follow in the story don't actually really know about any other borrowers out there anymore.
Rym: They've lost contact with everyone.
Scott: - Yeah, 'cause if you're so small and you can't move around quickly and you don't live in a big city of borrowers, your closest people, assuming there's a borrower in every house, the closest people are in the next house, which is a whole yard away, that's like a week-long trip to get over there.
Rym: - I don't think a week, they're not that small.
Scott: - No, I'm just saying.
Rym: - They're inches, they're not centimeters.
Scott: - If you can't ride an animal or a boat or a tiny plane, you're not getting over there.
Rym: - The next yard over is not that far.
Rym: if you're inches tall.
Rym: - It's far.
Rym: - No, it's not.
Scott: - It is, especially when you live in the middle of nowhere, like these people.
Rym: - Ah, well they live in the middle of nowhere, that's a different thing.
Scott: - That's what I'm saying.
Rym: - But the movie basically kind of picks up, there's this kind of little drama and then you follow this little story of the kid in this house who has anime heart, a very specific disease.
Scott: - It's the same disease from, oh, what was that very-- - Staring Up at the Half Moon.
Scott: - Yeah.
Rym: - I really like that, actually.
Scott: - I'm remembering, I just didn't remember the name of it, but yeah, I should watch that again.
Rym: - Anime heart is a very specific disease.
Rym: It causes you to be bedridden, but yet you can get up and do stuff whenever you need to.
Rym: You're not going to school, everyone's afraid you're gonna die.
Rym: If you exert yourself, things get dire and dramatic music plays and you start to sweat.
Rym: And you may die after the credits.
Scott: - Oh, you may die earlier than that.
Rym: - Usually anime heart only kills you after the credits.
Scott: - And you know, sometimes anime heart, it can only be cured by miracles.
Scott: If it is cured by miracles of some sort.
Rym: - The story, what it really picks up with is a family comes to their house.
Scott: - Anime heart usually only afflicts children.
Rym: - Yes.
Rym: And the young boy has anime heart, so he's kind of bedridden, and he sees a borrower and they're not supposed to be seen.
Rym: And then we kind of follow the story from there.
Scott: - Well, it's not that they're not supposed to be seen.
Scott: It's not like, you know--.
Rym: - Well, they don't want to be seen.
Scott: - Right, they don't want to be seen because they're basically afraid that humans will pull a King Kong situation, right?
Scott: Rightly so.
Rym: - Yes, because King Konging seems to happen.
Scott: - If you saw little people in your apartment, would you not King Kong?
Rym: - I don't know if I would King Kong, per se.
Scott: - At the very least, you would YouTube King Kong.
Rym: - And that would cause them trouble.
Rym: - But the story really, you know, Ariete from the title is just a young girl.
Rym: She's like the daughter of two of the borrowers, and she doesn't necessarily, she's really curious about this family, and the boy is kind of really nice to her and curious about her, and the parents are like, "No, we gotta leave, they've seen
Rym: us.".
Rym: And I'm obviously being very vague and kind of avoiding talking about the plot because it's a movie, you should just go see it.
Rym: There's no reason not to see this movie.
Rym: Nothing we say from this point forward should convince you to see the movie.
Rym: You should already be on your way to see it.
Scott: - It's a Studio Ghibli movie.
Scott: It is not directed by Miyazaki, but the guy who did direct it, what's his name?
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: - It is fantastic, and it's directed by Yone Bayashi.
Scott: - Yep, I wouldn't say it's fantastic, but it's very good.
Rym: It is great.
Rym: - I would say it's fantastic because it gave me that feeling after you watch a really good movie, just like, (sighs).
Scott: - Nah, it didn't give me the strong feeling of the top level of Ghibli movies.
Scott: - Really?
Scott: - Such as the Spirited Away or the-- - Well, Spirit, here's the difference though.
Rym: Spirited Away had a bit, and Lopita both had a more epic story.
Rym: I mean, Lopita ends--.
Scott: - Or the Whisper of the Heart.
Rym: - With the gigantic castle in the sky and the collapse and the pirates and everything.
Scott: - It's not on the same level as the Whisper of the Heart.
Rym: - And Spirited Away has the epic journey.
Rym: - Or the Castle of Cagliostro.
Rym: - This is like a slice.
Rym: It tells one tiny piece of this larger borrower's story.
Scott: - Yeah.
Scott: I would put it slightly above actually Howl's Moving Castle.
Scott: 'cause honestly, the only thing I really liked in Howl's Moving Castle was Talking Fire.
Rym: - Well, Howl's, I think, suffered from the fact that if you hadn't read the book, it was kind, like the plot didn't really make sense.
Scott: - Yeah, that was the main problem there.
Rym: - You're like, "What's all
Rym: this?".
Scott: - Yeah, but the Talking Fire really helped out.
Rym: - But no, I really liked the borrowers just because it had-- - I'm not saying I didn't like it.
Scott: I'm just saying it's like, "Oh,
Scott: fantastic.".
Scott: I'm like, "Fantastic is a level too high for
Scott: me.".
Rym: - No, I would call it fantastic 'cause it mainly-- - I would say great.
Rym: - It had the Ghibli atmosphere to a T.
Scott: - Well, 'cause the Ghibli animators went all out.
Rym: - It kind of followed in the, at least in the way I felt watching it, like the atmosphere from Ponyo and that it kind of had this slow, explore this setting and the people-- - I would definitely say it was equal to Ponyo.
Scott: - Lots of great animation.
Rym: I think the animation really sold it too.
Rym: Like the fact that right in the beginning, you notice that they animated the water tension, like the surface tension of water, relatively accurately to little people.
Rym: So like you're trying to pour tea and like one blob kind of just goes like plop into the cup.
Scott: - Yeah, that was really cool.
Scott: It's like they didn't pay attention to science so much 'cause obviously little people, not possible.
Scott: But a lot of other things that were somewhat scientific of like, what would it really be like if you were that small?
Scott: What kind of concerns would you have?
Scott: You know, what would be different?
Scott: They paid attention to some of those things, like you said, tension of liquids.
Rym: - Yep, and that just made a really neat atmosphere.
Rym: Like look at all the detail they put into the kind of environment the borrowers had built inside the house.
Rym: Like all the nails and the journeys and the sound too.
Rym: They really did a good job with the soundscape and you know, the fridge makes like horrible, distant death noises all the time when it's in scene.
Scott: - Yep, all right, so what else do you guys say about this besides watching?
Rym: - You don't have much to say about it, do you?
Scott: - I mean, it was 90 minutes.
Scott: It was a pretty good movie, I don't know.
Rym: - I mean, it had such great attention to detail.
Rym: The music was good, not great.
Rym: The music kind of just worked.
Rym: The song was interesting because the theme of the movie was actually in English.
Scott: - Oh yeah, that's right, it was.
Rym: - There's a whole story behind why they chose that artist and everything that I read, but I don't remember the details enough to impart it to you.
Rym: But I believe it was something to do with like the artist who is not Japanese had mailed a copy of her latest CD to the studio as a gift for something and then they liked it, they used it in the movie.
Scott: - Not really.
Rym: - I read something about that, but I don't remember it in detail.
Scott: - That's interesting 'cause usually that's the sort of thing that a scary fanboy would do and we'd get ignored.
Scott: One thing about the movie that was only slightly confusing was there was the housekeeping lady.
Rym: - I don't think it was confusing 'cause one, it is set up early on that she just doesn't know much about the outside world.
Scott: - No, clearly, but the thing is, it's like her motive, she's obviously the bad guy.
Scott: She's not evil, but she's the bad guy.
Rym: - No, I would argue that she is in fact evil.
Rym: She's a creeper.
Scott: - She is a creeper, but she's not--.
Scott: - She's not evil like friggin' Darth Vader evil, right?
Rym: - No, but she's a creeper, which is a side of evil.
Scott: - But anyway, but it's like she wants to get the borrowers, she sees them.
Rym: - No, think about it, her motivation's pretty simple.
Rym: She obviously, remember when they're talking about the little people earlier in the movie?
Rym: And the mother, the family is like, yay, the little people, the stories from our great uncles and the people in the past in the family and the dollhouse and everything.
Rym: And she, she probably has noticed things missing or has seen things and she thinks they exist and it bothers her and she wants to prove that they're real and she doesn't like the fact that everyone else kind of treats this as kind of like fairytale and they're very happy about it.
Rym: Like she wants to prove that they're there, to prove that she's not just going crazy.
Rym: - Yeah, it seems-- - Also, she's a creeper.
Scott: - Yeah, but it's like-- - She makes this great face.
Scott: - If she just wants to prove that they're there, it's like, but she could have done that immediately, but then she called like the exterminators to come and trap more of the-- - She wanted
Rym: to catch the rest of them probably and then like show it to the newspapers.
Scott: - Yeah, but she never, that motive of like, let's make money off these little people and do.
Scott: the King Kong was never explicitly stated, so it was sort of like-- - I don't think it needed to be.
Rym: It was pretty obvious.
Scott: - So like, what is she doing?
Rym: - 'Cause she didn't like, you know, vermin.
Rym: She was already like wanting exterminators early on.
Scott: - But it's like, if she wanted to just make, you know, do the King Kong thing, she had one already, you know, I don't know, whatever.
Rym: - Yeah, but she knew there were more.
Scott: - Yeah, whatever.
Rym: - And she wanted to get the rest of them right away.
Scott: - Anyway, so after we watched the movie, we went on YouTube and we searched for the borrowers and we found-- - Oh, there is a treasure trove of terrible old things.
Scott: - Apparently, there was a really old TV show and there was also a more recent live action movie in the US and we watched like trailers and previews and clips from all of these.
Rym: - There's a lot of stuff.
Scott: - They were all horrible and horrifying simultaneously.
Scott: So actually, this is kind of good because it gives you hope in a way, right?
Scott: There's a lot of things out there that-- - Scott, My Little Pony.
Scott: - That's another one, right?
Scott: There's a lot of things out there that either started in one medium of art and they were, you know, transferred to other mediums very poorly for, you know, such as My Little Pony, which I guess My Little Pony started as a TV show,
Rym: but-- - It started terrible, it maintained terribleness and then was rebooted.
Scott: - Right, but I mean, there's plenty of like books that were awesome and then had like a bunch of terrible movies made after them, right?
Scott: There are plenty of video games that are a bunch of horrible movies made out of them.
Rym: - All of them?
Scott: - All of them, right.
Scott: So there's still hope, though, that even though every attempt to translate something into another medium has done been a horrible failure, if the right person does it with the right attitude, you have another chance and people might not even remember the other bad ones if they're old enough, you know?
Rym: - If only we could get people to forget about previous G4 My Little Pony to make it disappear.
Scott: - You mean My Little Pony prior to G4?
Rym: - The pre-G4 is not, anyway, it's not the My Little Pony cast.
Scott: - G1, G1, two and three.
Rym: - But like all the little details, like Arietty, the main character, I really like her 'cause she has the good balance of, she's definitely a Ghibli heroine.
Scott: - No, no kidding.
Rym: - But she's the right amount of adventurous and defiant and cool and badass, all mixed in one.
Scott: - Yeah, but the other thing I liked about her more than some of the other Ghibli heroines is that she's actually somewhat more careful than the other ones.
Scott: A lot of the other ones are just so badass, like Nausicaa's just like, "I'm gonna fucking go out there and do it.
Scott: "We're going right in the fucking nasty, "horrible forest of death, fuck you," right?
Scott: Whereas Arietty's more like, "All right, yeah, I don't really wanna get seen "by the humans and get caught or eaten "by the cat or
Scott: anything.".
Rym: So she has a little more common sense and carefulness.
Rym: - Like she doesn't just take that sugar cube with a little note.
Scott: - Yeah, exactly.
Scott: She seems like a real person who's more intelligent and not just running into danger to make conflict for a movie, you know?
Scott: It's like she's more reasonable.
Rym: - Her with her cute sword and that little clip she puts in her hair, that's pretty great.
Rym: I like how the clip kinda looks like mouse ears from the right angle.
Rym: I think that was intentional.
Scott: - Maybe.
Rym: - Being a little person.
Rym: And the family's just great.
Rym: The moms, you know, the worried mom and the dad's just like--.
Scott: - Yeah, the mom was kind of annoying, but the dad was awesome.
Rym: - The dad's just like the badass, quiet Ghibli dad.
Scott: - Yeah, dad's cool.
Rym: - Yeah.
Scott: - I also like how, you know, you didn't have that sort, you know, there's those certain things like, oh, is this gonna go like, you know, dad dies kind of story?
Scott: And it doesn't really, it doesn't go that way.
Rym: - No, I didn't expect any of that.
Scott: - It just goes like, oh, you know, it's nice to see though, 'cause usually whenever there's a family thing, you know, 'cause when you have any kind of anime usually, they don't focus on characters' families unless they're gonna do something with them.
Scott: Like there'll be a show about a school, they'll only show you the parents of a kid if those parents are gonna do something like die or make trouble or become bad guys or something.
Scott: Otherwise, you never see the rest of the kid's family at all, you just, they don't exist at all and no one talks about them.
Scott: So, the fact that the parents are there, it's like, oh, something's gonna happen with them.
Rym: - Well, stuff did, but let's zoom out a little bit.
Scott: - Obviously, stuff did happen, but it wasn't-- -.
Rym: In the early part of the movie, there were tons of Chekov's rats and Chekov's swords and none of them Chekov, they were just atmosphere.
Rym: - They were.
Rym: - And it was actually kind of refreshing.
Scott: - Yeah, I was like-- - I thought the movie-- - When I saw those rats in the beginning, I was like, rats are gonna eat somebody, they never did.
Rym: in this one particular direction just based on all the Chekov's and then it really didn't at all.
Scott: - No, not at all.
Rym: - I was pleasantly surprised by that.
Rym: - Yeah, I like that.
Rym: - Like, right away, I expected there to be some sort of continuing camaraderie drama between that dumbass crow and the fat cat.
Scott: But then, really-- - The crow had his scene and never came back.
Rym: - Yeah, the crow had two scenes.
Rym: He attacks the cat for no good reason.
Scott: - And he gets stuck in the window.
Rym: - Which is actually a pretty great scene.
Scott: - Which is pretty, and then you never see him again.
Rym: - I love how the kid is just sitting there like, what the fuck do I do?
Rym: And he like, the crow's like trying to struggle and every time he tries to help the crow, the crow starts pecking him, so he backs off and then the crow starts struggling again and there's just.
Rym: - And I do enjoy the housekeeper because she, you know, we keep saying she's a creeper.
Rym: Just wait, watch this movie, you'll see.
Rym: There are like 10 scenes where someone's doing something and in the background, she's like, hey.
Rym: She makes this face.
Scott: - Well, a lot of Ghibli characters, you know, especially bad ones, sort of have that mouth open kind of heavy breathing kind of thing that happens once or twice in a movie.
Scott: You know, like.
Rym: - Yeah, but she does this every time nobody's looking.
Scott: - There's a lot of, you know, a lot of those typical Ghibli things, there's like some ball-like creatures in the very early scene that are, you know, they're always kind of hanging around.
Rym: - But like when she locks the kid in the room and the way she was creeping for so long, I have expected the maid to like try to murder the whole family.
Scott: - Yeah, get some sort of inherited, like what, you know, I didn't know what her motive was and so I was like, is she gonna like, hoping the kid dies?
Scott: Like what is she up to here?
Rym: - I feel like she is gonna murder the family, but that's after the credits.
Scott: - Maybe.
Rym: - Unless Anna My Heart gets the kid first.
Scott: - Yeah.
Rym: - But I mean, I don't wanna say anything else about this movie because-- - I assume Disney's gonna put it on DVD eventually, right?
Rym: - It's fantastic.
Rym: - Like they do.
Rym: - Or at least really good and there's no reason not to see it and there's no reason for us to spoil it or talk about the cool stuff that happens in it because you'll see it and it's awesome and we're just gonna say, oh
Scott: man, remember when-- - It's a Ghibli movie, how could you not watch it?
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: If you're any kind of anime fan, it's not, you know, it's not Earthsea, so why wouldn't you see it?
Scott: It takes 90 minutes of your life.
Rym: - You can see Earthsea, just don't turn on the subtitles.
Rym: And don't watch the scenes with the blob at the end.
Rym: - Just look at screenshots.
Rym: - Just skip from when the blob appears to when the dragon comes.
Scott: - Sure.
Rym: - This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: - Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: - Remember, GeekNights is not one but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: - GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: - It's Wednesday, August 17th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: - Uh, I accidentally opened a tab.
Rym: - It's Wednesday, August 17th, oh fuck.