Rym: It's July 26 2011 I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight half-minute hero.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Oh Man, not going to work all week.
Scott: Oh, you're going to work next week.
Rym: Yeah next week I got to start my new job.
Scott: Didn't you say you're gonna go to the work once to fill your HRs?
Rym: Oh, yeah on Thursday.
Rym: I'm gonna do some demo stuff but most of it'll be online.
Scott: No, that's good.
Scott: You wanna hear you wanna do some HR bullshit?
Scott: Nah, so, you know, I had a 401k.
Scott: then I had another job.
Rym: I had another 401k so I got to sort all that out.
Rym: because I have a 401k from the company.
Rym: I just quit.
Rym: Yeah, and I have a 403 B. I never rolled over from the last company.
Rym: I was.
Scott: I was in that situation.
Scott: I had two 401ks and two jobs.
Scott: I got a third job So I rolled them both over.
Rym: I'm not sure if I want to go into a 401k with the next company or if I wanted to do my own IRA and Make that my thing forever.
Scott: But anyway, I rolled everything over right?
Rym: I'm sure the gamer listeners are fascinated.
Rym: Oh my god, this is what 30 year olds talk.
Scott: So then they closed the 401k and started a new one.
Scott: I'd like roll over.
Scott: so Regardless, I got a letter the other day and it was like hey This is from the 401k that completely closed because the company, you know, my where I work now was bought by where I work now.
Scott: so, um, I mean where I just anyway, yeah, so They're like, hey the 401k is closing.
Scott: if you have any money You're getting a check whether you like it or not.
Scott: and I was like I rolled it all over.
Scott: I'll just ignore this letter.
Scott: check shows up in the mail for like almost $2,000.
Scott: I'm like what?
Scott: Did either?
Scott: did somebody give me money or?
Scott: Did Somebody not take all the money out even though I told them to I had to roll it over.
Rym: It's hard to say.
Scott: Regardless the check says, you know you get this much money and federal tax withheld zero.
Scott: So I'm looking at this check and I'm like, oh, oh If I just cash this well, it depends.
Rym: you're not doing Roth, right?
Rym: No tax as you put in.
Rym: so taking out you don't pay tax.
Scott: Roth is you know, but if you but if I if I This money was in a 401k.
Scott: So if you would draw it you pay a penalty.
Scott: Yeah, so this was taken out without penalty.
Scott: So if I roll it over to something else, that's fine.
Scott: If I cash this at the bank, I'm pretty sure.
Scott: if I don't pay the penalty.
Scott: No one will notice That's a very illegal but also No one will know.
Rym: here's my advice to you.
Rym: Don't talk about this publicly where anyone can hear you And just cash the check.
Scott: No, I'm gonna put it in the other one.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna go the HR person, but it's like.
Scott: the point is it's like what the fuck?
Scott: I told you to take out all the money and move it from A to B and you didn't move all the money or other People.
Scott: or did you give me free money?
Scott: What happened?
Rym: That's hard to say.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah But yeah this week I got nothing to do.
Rym: I've been editing some GeekNights videos hanging out even though I have a lot to do.
Scott: I've been working sleeping.
Rym: I was playing a game a little while ago called bouldering Mm-hmm, cuz Phil and she air out.
Rym: So we were actually, you know doing some rock climbing in Central Park and I've said this before to a lot of our friends.
Rym: I haven't really pointed out on the show.
Rym: Rock climbing is more game than a sport.
Rym: It's more intellectual than you would think.
Rym: So if any of you nerds out there Don't think you can do it.
Rym: I recommend trying to do it.
Scott: Yeah, like three-year-olds can do it.
Scott: Yeah Yeah Yeah, yeah, yeah they can.
Scott: So just like they could do jungle gym.
Scott: I bet you can't do a jungle gym as well as a three-year-old.
Rym: You know why I can't because my knees hit the ground.
Scott: I know.
Rym: So I downloaded, you know, I basically get almost every demo now on the Xbox because it only cost me time.
Scott: They only get demos of games that I actually want to.
Rym: I get demos of games that I expect to be bad just to see How bad they really are.
Rym: Mm-hmm I mean, I got that whatever that new D&D game is and I thought alright What's it gonna be a crappy walk around and hit things game?
Rym: Yep It was like.
Rym: it was amazing to me that despite expecting it to be a crappy walk around and hit things game It didn't even work that well as a crappy walk around and hit things game game.
Scott: See here's the thing is like.
Scott: I've actually been playing a lot of various demos and other games around lately.
Rym: Why is this the season of walk around and hit things?
Scott: and I'm saying almost every game that I've tried out that I you know Turned out to be a walk around and hit things game.
Scott: first I was in the dark spore beta walk around and hit things.
Scott: I tried out Dragon Age 2 demo walk around.
Rym: There's more to Dragon Age 2 than just walk around hit things as opposed to say this D&D game That is just walk around and hit things.
Scott: That Dragon Age 2 is mostly walk around and hit things.
Scott: What was this other one?
Scott: I played?
Scott: Oh, it was El Shaddai.
Scott: walk around and hit things.
Scott: Some.
Scott: It wasn't D&D.
Scott: It was like some other fantasy thing, but it was walk around and hit things.
Scott: But the one that I played was Bastion which was also walk around and hit things.
Scott: But it had this really clever narration mechanic where basically all it really is is there's things that you do that trigger wave files.
Scott: That's really all it is.
Scott: But the narrator was an excellent narrator like the voice actor they got for.
Scott: it does an excellent job like a James Earl Jones Ian High-quality like a Morgan Freeman exactly.
Scott: So it's like for example You start the game and you're laying in bed and you're just sitting there.
Scott: as soon as you move the stick your guy gets up and the narrator at that exact moment says he gets up and It's like you walk around and it's like there's an area where like you, you know, you get a weapon You know.
Scott: and he says oh man, and then he found this something something right.
Scott: and then you go the next area.
Scott: There's a bunch of stuff to smash.
Scott: You don't have to smash it You can just you're
Rym: gonna smash it,
Scott: but if you sit around and smash things long enough It's like, you know, eventually the narrator is like guy just rages for a while Right, and it's like, you know that mechanic kept me going through the demo So I bought it and I played a whole bunch of it.
Scott: The thing is it is walk around and hit things.
Scott: So eventually after like six seven eight levels.
Rym: I'm like Games like that do something cool, but all they have they're one trick pony.
Rym: You got like the one cool thing that they innovated and that's it.
Rym: then the genius games are gonna be the next games that take the few like really interesting mechanics that people use in these crap games and Actually combine them into a real game.
Scott: that isn't just a cool narrative or isn't just a gimmick Yeah, but yeah, it's cool though because the thing that really surprised me about the clever We called it reactive narration, which is really just triggered wave files that were well scripted to various activities.
Scott: Was that it didn't.
Scott: really it doesn't take that much.
Scott: It's so easy to program right?
Scott: It's all just getting the data, right?
Scott: It says it's another thing with clever program.
Scott: It's not like to our fortress where this sort of seemingly really awesome stuff happens because it's a complex system.
Rym: it's just as you said.
Scott: seemingly it's just a Wave file played if the player does a certain thing That's all and they just have a lot of wave files tied to a whole lot of events, you know, that could possibly happen.
Rym: It's even easy to do just dynamic music in games.
Rym: I mean look at even tribes to had that dynamic looping system where the music would like Ramp up as the action was ramping up around you.
Rym: everyone had different music.
Scott: But this is like you'll go into the weapon upgrade shop and you upgrade a weapon and then when you leave based on what weapon You upgrade it.
Scott: He'll say something different that's relevant to that weapon, you know stuff like that.
Rym: It's that almost goes along the lines of why I liked old adventure games like quest for glory because half the game was just Like.
Rym: you see something really dangerous and you're like, I wonder how that'll kill me.
Rym: It's like.
Scott: I wonder what he'll say if I do Yeah Imagine if shadow gate which had all the different texts for all the different deaths Which is basically what this had Morgan Freeman Exactly.
Scott: Oh my god the text didn't appear on the screen unless you enabled subtitles.
Rym: Oh, we got to get the license to shadow gate and then hire Morgan probably could.
Scott: the last shadow gate I'm was pretty sure with shadow gate 64, which was awful.
Scott: My brother rented it and played a ton of it, but It's it's.
Scott: that is an angry video game nerd fodder if I've ever seen one.
Rym: It might be too bad.
Scott: It's so bad.
Scott: It's super.
Scott: it's almost as bad as Superman 64.
Scott: Oh, don't say 64.
Rym: Don't say that.
Rym: That's not even like funny.
Scott: shadow gate 64 is so bad You have no idea.
Scott: You should get it played an emulator.
Rym: So the two games that stood out that I was playing demos of one was trenched Which was this kind of like World War one ask fight the aliens that are actually just people in TVs.
Rym: It gets a lot of points for style, but I worry that the game is just tanks tanks tanks Kind of just walk around.
Rym: ticket ticket ticket ticket ticket ticket, you know gate like it has this thing.
Scott: Alright, that's the one where you're sort of in the mech thing.
Rym: Yeah, it's called a trench Yeah, and the enemy is television, which I think we could.
Rym: we dig We jelly with that like that but Jelly means jealous.
Scott: Yeah, jelling as in.
Rym: Anyway, we're jealous of the ability to destroy TV.
Rym: They have the chance that we are.
Scott: we do not have the chance and We have a slight chance so credibly incredibly slight.
Rym: We had a better chance when we were young and planning that.
Rym: That's a story for another time.
Rym: But it's one of those games where it has the thing where if you hit each of the shoulder buttons Either your right machine gun or your left machine gun is shooting.
Rym: Why would you ever not be holding both of those down it you could?
Scott: Theoretically have a game where you could aim them in different directions, right or they have slightly different kinds of ammo.
Rym: I could actually order.
Rym: they spin down or like overheat at the same rate.
Rym: So maybe you let go of one to let it cool down to have a weapon while the other you know Some sort of mechanic.
Rym: It doesn't seem like this game had that.
Scott: No, the only there was never.
Scott: I couldn't figure out a reason not to hold both at the same time.
Scott: In fact, you know I was messed up and I kind of lost a little bit because I wasn't.
Scott: I didn't realize there were two.
Scott: The thing is I can envision a game that could be pretty cool.
Scott: It should be a stationary shooter.
Scott: You don't get to move around Where or maybe you someone else does the moving and you do the shooting?
Scott: Where you actually use the left stick to aim the left arm the right stick to aim the right arm and the two triggers to Shoot the two different arms to actually aim in two different places.
Scott: Simultaneous But in this game you can only aim in one spot at a time using only the right stick.
Scott: So there was no reason for that to be separate arms.
Rym: That is still such inside baseball that simultaneously.
Rym: But the other one that stood out was Catherine which Scott had mentioned and I just kind of ignored.
Scott: I've known about this game for a while and I knew that it was one of those freaky games from Japan That's probably never gonna get released in the US.
Scott: But oh my god, this is the one freaky game for Japan That's gonna get released in the US.
Scott: I should pay attention to it.
Scott: So I actually had it like, you know in the Amazon, you know, not your shopping cart like the saved shopping cart Just to remind, you know.
Scott: So every time I bought something the Amazon I would be reminded but it was like 50 60 bucks For this Xbox game and I'd really don't want to buy a disc game.
Scott: and then on top of that There's like a collector's box You can get.
Scott: that includes like a pair of boxers and a soundtrack CD and a bunch of ridiculous shit.
Scott: There's some YouTube videos.
Scott: You can see where they show you all the ridiculous shit That comes in the goodie box and I you know, so I'm like, I'm curious cuz you know Everyone likes it wouldn't be ridiculous game for Japan gets released in the US.
Scott: So the demo came out in the Xbox.
Scott: So I got it.
Rym: and Yeah, I just played through enough from the demo to know it has good parts and bad parts.
Rym: I was worried because it started out like really like the opening screen with the guy with the little ram's horns like hanging in the Barbed wire and the girl just kind of chillin next to him.
Rym: I was like, huh?
Rym: This is the kind of thing where if it was an anime I would be intrigued.
Scott: yeah exactly It's a very much.
Rym: it is an anime in a way.
Rym: It's really like.
Rym: there's a lot of animation in it There's a lot of like.
Scott: it's it's kind of like an interactive and it's very much in the speed graph or genre of anime.
Rym: Yeah, but speed graph or went a little too Still the same genre just it is but better better executed.
Rym: I would say I would say so but Independent of that it was weird because it starts.
Rym: I'm like, alright, what's the deal?
Rym: And then I play this weird kind of 3d Surprisingly difficult tower climbing puzzle.
Scott: Well, the first level wasn't difficult.
Rym: No, the second level was difficult though But it's not that it was difficult.
Scott: is that you could see how the as the puzzles could easily get more difficult and challenging.
Rym: Yes, that I couldn't just blow through it.
Rym: I had to actually like, uh, okay do this.
Scott: Yeah, and like there were parts, you know, it was like yeah, you know The boxes will will not fall down as long as they're touching by a corner and I'm like, that's great.
Scott: But it actually took a little while to figure out How to actually get the blocks into that configuration.
Scott: never mind do it quick even though I was trying to.
Scott: you know I was actively trying to figure out how that worked.
Scott: It's like oh you can make a staircase.
Scott: It's not supported by anything at all.
Scott: I was like that's the way to go.
Rym: But then after that ends I'm playing through that.
Rym: at first I'm like, alright It's some crappy like okay puzzle platformer that has like a weird plot around it whatever.
Rym: people often cover up a mediocre game with a plot.
Rym: and Then I got to the other part kind of like gameplay where you just hang out with your friends and get text messages from your girlfriend and Respond to them.
Scott: Yeah it's like the plot part is?
Scott: it's not like.
Scott: it's not as good as say half-life where the plot and The game are integrated or portal to write where they're intertwined.
Scott: They're the same thing, right?
Scott: This is like you do a puzzle game when you're sleeping and then when you're awake You go to the bar and you play this plot game.
Scott: But the plot game actually had some interesting stuff that wasn't necessarily straightforward.
Scott: take for example Those Knights of the Old Republic Star Wars games, right?
Scott: Yeah, I bought one of them cheap on Steam because they were so talked about and I'm not a fan.
Scott: But it's like, you know That's those are the ones you talk to people and depending on what you say and what quest you do you be.
Scott: You know dark side or light side those games have potential but never really every.
Scott: everything you really do It's same as fallout 3 right everything you do.
Scott: It's sort of like just obvious.
Scott: There's a dark side choice a light side choice and sort of a weird choice sometimes and that's it in this.
Scott: It's like you weren't always sure what the choice you were making was leaning towards.
Scott: It's like you.
Scott: there was this really quick good system.
Scott: remain text messages.
Scott: We push a and he'd write a line of the text message.
Scott: it's very it's Phoenix Wright style and you could either keep that line that he wrote or Erase it and press a again to get a different choice.
Scott: And so basically you press a B a B a B to see all the choices.
Scott: But it's like, you know you text someone.
Scott: it's like hey, baby What's up, or how are you doing?
Scott: And those are your three choices.
Scott: and you're like Okay, and then the next choice is like, you know the girl then the text you back and she's like Where are you?
Scott: and it's like you can see one of the choices of the truth at the bar drinking.
Scott: I'm at home at a movie, you know at work and it's like it's like which one do you choose?
Rym: Also, what are you going for like, I don't know if I wanted to be good or bad.
Scott: It's like you don't even know which choice was good or bad.
Scott: I mean obviously lying is probably worse than the truth But maybe not because where you are is not where she might want you to be.
Scott: It's like It's awesome and you didn't choose to be there.
Scott: It's like you don't get to control the whole plot.
Scott: It's like you're at the bar drink and there's a kind of like dream murder plot going on And it's obviously a metaphor about just you know commitment.
Scott: Yes And whatever.
Rym: but I love the artistic style.
Rym: I love how he's got the little horns and all the other sheep are there dying around him through this like dream And
Scott: the sheep is egging him on and like the hands are coming up from below to pull him into the yeah
Rym: Yeah, and the second tower it's the girl and then there's that other girl and I think I'm gonna buy it.
Scott: All right, let's you get a bite on disc.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think you know because if you buy it on disc you can just give it to me when you're done with it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I guess I could and save me 60 bucks.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's intriguing.
Scott: you can buy that.
Scott: you could buy the expensive one.
Rym: I'll say this of all the games we've talked about recently if you've got an Xbox just grab the demo of Catherine and Just check it out.
Scott: I want you to you know, I think it'll be on the ps3 - maybe I'm not sure if I like it I'm just interested.
Scott: I just want to see people buy it to prove to Japan.
Scott: yet again We fucking buy your games bitches.
Scott: There's no reason that every single game you make shouldn't be released in one to the second look from both me and Scott.
Rym: How rare is that?
Scott: Yeah So, you know when I was in sixth grade sixth grade which you were like 10 or 11 I was 11 12, right.
Scott: so There was this school.
Scott: basically every year the middle school did a magazine drive Which is basically go sell magazine subscriptions to all your family and friends and neighbors To get money for the school to do shit like keep the band around and whatever, right?
Scott: So I all I did was I said, huh?
Scott: These are cheap magazines descriptions.
Scott: So I got a search in a game pro and I kept that subscription through when I was at RIT.
Rym: Wow, I think I kept Nintendo power from 1 to 200.
Scott: I think I canceled it in like 2001 or 2 or something.
Rym: my brother kept Nintendo power But I gave up because I had the internet and I was playing PC games.
Scott: And you know, you can say whatever you want about game pro that pros and cons.
Rym: over the years It was no PC gamer game for it was like the weakest.
Scott: I bought some game of PC gamers in my day as well.
Rym: I subscribed once to PC gamer the whole year.
Rym: That was awesome.
Rym: I subscribed to computer shopper free cuz it came with those CDs or those floppies with games.
Rym: I know Raptor Call of the Shadows.
Rym: one must fall 2097.
Rym: Oh shit, son.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Rym: I would just oh my god that There's something for our packs panel Just to bring those games up.
Scott: I'm sure people know about those.
Rym: I don't think people do anyway.
Scott: the So so I you know, I was there when the scary Larry days by the way, he now works at Nintendo for Pokemon.
Scott: He works a Pokemon not for Nintendo, which I guess is sort of work.
Scott: It doesn't matter, right?
Scott: So, you know game pro after it was really sucky when I got rid of it in o2.
Scott: That was like the doldrums and you know by then internet had taken over.
Scott: video game magazines are dead.
Scott: Kotaku joystick destroy them.
Scott: There's no reason then to exist.
Scott: but just today Game pro announced something interesting which Sort of almost makes me want to subscribe Which is really weird.
Scott: and basically what they're doing is they're going to become a quarterly magazine.
Scott: Oh So they'll only be four game pros a year.
Scott: But if they're more if they if they do what the escapist should have been right, but it's gonna be 50 pages bigger Right and it's gonna be 10 bucks.
Scott: So maybe I think I might buy the first one of these on the newsstand.
Rym: just they do.
Rym: I don't want review I want like expert commentary.
Rym: I want like what Daryl and Mike and all them do with their magazine.
Scott: They can make a really highbrow gaming magazine.
Scott: that isn't you know, it's like look you're a magazine you're on print You can't get up-to-date news.
Scott: You can't beat the blogs in terms of speed.
Scott: But if you can beat them in content maybe.
Rym: and if you take maybe if you telly look at the state of video game journalism Stick at a piece of paper with ink on it and beat them.
Scott: if you take three months to put you know something That's only 15% bigger than what you normally do in one month, right?
Scott: So if they did it 300% bigger So it was three times as big as a normal game Pro.
Scott: It would be the same quality you imagine as a normal game pro.
Scott: They're only making it slightly percentage-wise bigger than an existing game pro and they're putting three months of effort into it.
Rym: So it should be at least twice as good as game pro is now Like when those GeekNights guys switch to two episodes a week instead of four.
Scott: Yeah, and the other thing is game pro unlike say game informer, which is owned by Gamestop or other Any other magazines still exist?
Scott: I don't even know, you know isn't you know directly tied to some other evil entity Even though I'm pretty sure there's plenty of bullshit, you know where companies pay for better review scores and all that crap?
Rym: Yeah, what would sell me a hundred percent is if they got rid of all scores and just had essay reviews on everything.
Scott: Yeah, they should just you know team up with like escapist or something to produce this quarterly or it's you know.
Scott: Just if it's it could potentially be good.
Scott: So I'm gonna check it out.
Scott: I'm gonna get the first one on the newsstands.
Rym: good What is this surprising wave of optimism on GeekNights?
Rym: Oh this new Catherine game might be worth looking at this magazine I might look at.
Scott: cuz we're still.
Scott: we're still hesitant.
Scott: when when we're saying dude This shit is awesome Then you can then you can.
Rym: what was the last thing we said that about except portal to portal to before that portal?
Scott: Yep, let me check the archive.
Rym: So we at least have to talk a little bit about the fact that EA bought PopCap for like over a billion dollars.
Rym: Yeah Why?
Rym: What?
Rym: well, I don't even understand like that came out of nowhere.
Rym: I'm sure if I'd been paying attention Maybe we could have seen it coming, but I ignore EA and I definitely ignore PopCap.
Scott: Apparently Zynga wanted to buy a PopCap and got turned down.
Rym: I could see that.
Rym: I wonder if Zynga lowballed though I don't like Zynga.
Rym: I think Zynga is bad.
Scott: Yeah, we like battle line.
Scott: That was the last thing we said.
Scott: good things.
Scott: Anyway Yeah, so it's like, you know The thing is it's kind of weird because EA is gigantic company and they make these gigantic games that sell a ton of copies.
Rym: I think they've realized that the big blockbuster high-budget game is at least for the near term.
Rym: I think that's gonna be on a huge downward spiral, right?
Scott: But it's like look how much money EA makes off Madden.
Scott: Compare that to how much money PopCap made off of peggle peggle probably made.
Scott: I don't have numbers I'm just guessing.
Scott: it probably made more money because it cost nothing to make exactly right it, you know It was so cheap to make peggle So afraid of a jillion of them for like a dollar.
Rym: the people who aren't Self-identified invested gamers aren't gonna be 50 bucks.
Rym: the peggle It's in and Zynga wouldn't really have been a good fit because I think it doesn't make games.
Rym: I Actually, honestly, I kind of want to do a panel of the next packs called Zynga doesn't make games.
Rym: Oh shit That would be the most I don't know inflammatory we've ever gone.
Scott: you can't target a specific anyway, but they are the worst.
Rym: They're the most evil.
Scott: They are Anyway, but PopCap isn't evil.
Rym: I can't call them.
Scott: I actually have a lot of pocket games on my phone because I bought them when they were on sale and they're kind of good.
Scott: They're good at what thank you birds is still better than their games, but it's in the same kind of genre.
Rym: Yeah We got to wait for a Rovio to make Different games that aren't just for birds and stuff.
Scott: actually the best game peggle hat PopCap has is the the bookworm adventuring one About bookworm.
Scott: Yeah, they have bookworm they you know, they have the rest of a bookworm at RIT The original.
Scott: the stupidest one they have is I think the aquarium.
Scott: do they do the aquarium one and say I got to check their Website, I don't even that's a game We're literally.
Scott: all you do is upgrade the aquarium and then you upgrade the aquarium in order to upgrade the aquarium.
Scott: Oh, and they have the plans for zombies.
Scott: isn't bad?
Scott: That's not really.
Rym: I don't understand what EA wants with PopCap.
Rym: unless they go into that market They don't own bejeweled.
Scott: Of course, they make all their money.
Rym: I mean, my guess is that they don't have like in-house.
Rym: some executive was like we don't have any inroads into that light casual gaming.
Rym: We got to get something.
Scott: Well, you also got to think of it long term, right?
Scott: You know, even if you know, you know EA could easily just make its own games in that genre and do the same business model.
Scott: Yeah, it's that's.
Scott: they don't need PopCap to do that.
Scott: What they do it though is PopCap has a proven track record of making multiple successful games in that genre, right?
Scott: So they're buying basically the talent that made peggle Zuma, you know What all these?
Scott: you know all these games?
Scott: Own those people any games that those people make in the future if they're as successful as plans for zombies, etc.
Scott: EA will make all the monies on that.
Rym: now I'm wondering if they're cuz the.
Rym: I don't know how much the money would matter to them Especially because they're paying a billion dollars for they need the money cuz I think weren't there.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't check their numbers, but I think they're down.
Scott: I don't think they're doing as well as they were.
Scott: so I mean if PopCaps on the way up They could boost the bottom line.
Rym: my money's in take two, but that's a separate thing.
Rym: but with EA I wonder if the real goal in the end is to Leverage popular cheap games like this.
Rym: They'll make money which is fine.
Rym: I think they're gonna try to use that sort of thing to feed into their big games with either micro transactions or oh You get a goodie.
Rym: if you play this PopCap like this little version like this.
Rym: I don't know a Major League Baseball like home run contest that they make the PopCap guys make and then oh if you've as you Level up in this you get goodies in the current.
Scott: There definitely is a lot of possibilities for integrating the Various PopCap games with the EA games and I think especially Right.
Scott: EA has made a bunch of mobile games, but they haven't been nearly as successful as the PopCap ones.
Scott: So for example, there is a mobile Madden.
Scott: Good luck with that shit.
Rym: Meanwhile, EA is looking into subscription services for their sports games.
Rym: I saw an article about that which is pretty much about time because that they already have a Subscription model except for the fact that a lot of people are more and more okay with having a game from two years ago.
Rym: Only the people who are nerds about they need to have the most up-to-date roster.
Rym: Only people who care about sports and video games care.
Scott: Well, there's people who actually care about sports.
Rym: video games Yeah, but I believe most of those people care to a degree about sports.
Rym: They want the game to match the current rosters because they care about that sort of thing.
Rym: Mm-hmm And a subscription model prevents the prop.
Rym: basically It'll get all the casual people who like play a Madden every now and then.
Rym: They're probably more likely to subscribe if the price is low enough than they are to Buy more than one Madden game every several years.
Scott: Yep So I just want to point out we're talking about PopCap.
Scott: the Make-A-Wish Foundation sent some kid over to PopCap because his wish was to make a video game.
Scott: He had the game all designed out and shit and the PopCap people made it and it's free on the App Store The iPhone iPad.
Scott: I did not know that the game is called Allied star police.
Scott: It's oh, it's you know, it is sort of a full game But it really only has you just play the same thing on three difficulties and then it's done.
Scott: It's not big but it's free and the way it works is sort of like a real.
Scott: it's actually pretty good.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's like amazingly good For what it is.
Scott: So the way it works is it's sort of like plans for zombies But it's real time plans for zombies.
Scott: So there's four columns and bad guys start coming down the columns and in real time You have to send tanks and different vehicles.
Scott: You spend money to buy them and send them down the different columns and they move.
Scott: So you it's like in plans for zombies you sit still while the zombies come at you.
Scott: This is more like if it were zombies for zombies.
Scott: So you're sending guys down the four columns and they're sending guys at you and as you kill their guys You get more money and you send more guys But your guys die and then you just send more guys to replace them and you have to destroy the other guys fort.
Scott: So I beat it on the first try and all three difficulties and you're supposed to just keep playing the same thing over and over.
Scott: We're gonna take a high score, but this is a pretty good game for some kid designed it and You know dad PopCap made it out of charity.
Rym: Well that dynamic miss - that's what we always say.
Rym: No one's really made a good versus tower defense.
Scott: This is definitely a. it's not versus No, but it's a computer.
Rym: I feel like the active participate like the way you play is more down the line of going that direction toward Straight up to towers versus each other.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, this is a you know, you should try it out because it's free.
Scott: and Actually, if you look here, it's kind of funny going iTunes and like almost every review on iTunes is like five stars.
Rym: So things of the day, I want to go back to my roots on things of the day.
Rym: college humor Basically more words that I realized I like things of the day.
Rym: They're interesting But a lot of times we'll be sitting like an out with the TV with a bunch of friends over and I need you know We need entertainment something to show them because the internet is TV now.
Rym: So I'm like, alright I go to.
Rym: I always used to go to you know The geeknight site and just go through like all the old things of the day because it was usually funny videos of shit.
Rym: But a lot lately I've been using a lot more articles or things that are really interesting But they're not something I could like show someone on a TV.
Rym: So for the next like several episodes, I'm gonna try to use things that someone could show someone else on a TV.
Rym: and I've had dogs in other words funny cat videos dogs in this case.
Rym: I had dogs my whole life till I went to college.
Rym: I love dogs and dogs are smart.
Scott: This bulldog is a college humor video or they appear to be smart But really they're just acting in a way that appears smart by random chance in the same way that people do.
Rym: Yes So this bulldog and his bulldog compatriot Really like the outdoor pool because it's hot.
Scott: Well, it's just a plastic kiddie pool.
Rym: Yeah, that's great.
Rym: If you're a dog Well, of course, it's dog size.
Scott: So it's like an Olympic dog pool.
Rym: They have a brilliant idea.
Rym: This pool is awesome, but it is hot outside.
Rym: What if we bring the pool inside and the video is them attempting to Pull off this master plan.
Rym: It's adorable.
Scott: Okay So I'm just gonna read the text straight from this website Which actually happens to be crunchyroll even though what I find strange is a crunchyroll I guess is the crunchyroll news posted this video with a YouTube in bed.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: couldn't they embed a crunchyroll in bed?
Scott: Anyway Alice in music land a project teased this past February by longtime Vocaloid artist Oster project is a new animated musical that matches up vocaloids with the familiar characters from Lewis and Carol's Alice in Wonderland Resulting in a work that is able to appeal not only to vocaloid fans But anyone with an appreciation for the happiness music and ring.
Scott: So this is a 12-minute Musical that is a hundred percent sung by Vocaloid characters a whole bunch of them and also an animation that is original and It's totally awesome times a billion.
Scott: and I wanted to bring it to Tuesday because usually I use vocaloid related things there Wednesday.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: Wednesday people already know vocaloid exists.
Scott: Tuesday people if they're not the same people I know we have a lot of people just listen every day.
Scott: They might not know.
Scott: so now, you know, and you're gonna see a vocaloid thing.
Rym: How about that?
Scott: All right This is this is actually like Ridiculously awesome.
Scott: You have no idea.
Scott: We're gonna watch it right after the show's over cuz I only watched it once so far.
Rym: I'm excited cuz I'm a huge fan of our virtual idols.
Rym: This is unbelievably good as long as they don't go all super macross on us.
Scott: You have no idea.
Scott: This is unbelievably good.
Rym: So in the meta moment, we are going to be at the penny arcade Expo doing a one panel at noon on Saturday.
Rym: Alert or discover the Forgotten Masters.
Rym: I don't want to say I know this one's discover as opposed to the other one which was steel which is separate and special.
Rym: Mm-hmm this one One piece of it.
Rym: I won't spoil the rest.
Rym: Scott and I are gonna play outlaw in front of the audience as we comment on outlaw Which I think is all you bring in the Atari out there one of the.
Scott: it's all you making it work at the projector one Of the better design games out there.
Rym: I know that I currently hold the GeekNights championship belt for outlaw because Scott could not win it.
Scott: I only lost by like one bullet.
Rym: Yeah one bullet.
Rym: It's all it takes.
Scott: Oh you shut up since you're not going to work.
Scott: You can try to get an Atari emulator to work.
Rym: It's fine Just in case the bringing the Atari proves to you just want an emulator because you want to practice to try and take the belt Away, but there's no chance.
Rym: Also in the meta moment, I'll let you know that because I have this week off I've been feverishly editing all the archival video I've got so two more of our panels are gonna go up.
Rym: Uncle yo stand up.
Rym: I'm gonna get up in our channel as soon as I put together on his channel Because our channel no longer has time restrictions like with the whole thing up in one video.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah That's pretty much it.
Rym: That's what I'm working.
Scott: I've been working on Upgrading front recruit.
Scott: calm significantly.
Scott: I'm doing a lot of stuff to upgrade it.
Scott: You can read about it in the forum.
Rym: It's pretty exciting.
Scott: If you can.
Scott: also right now the best thing you can do is if you're a Facebook person.
Scott: We have a Facebook page.
Scott: is facebook.com.
Scott: slash front recruit gasp.
Scott: Eventually once this new site goes up, which hopefully will be before packs, but maybe not depending but hopefully will be It will automatically post everything that we do to that Facebook page every day in a very high class and professional way.
Scott: So you could actually I basically gave up and trying to get people to come to front recruit calm.
Scott: So it's like I'm gonna make the website itself as rich as possible Like everything's gonna be there, but you know what why?
Scott: you know, if someone doesn't want to come to our website Why should I inconvenience them?
Rym: because we don't have ads.
Rym: so it's not like we need people to come.
Rym: in fact It's better.
Rym: if you don't come I'm just gonna and I'm just gonna take.
Scott: you know The only reason now, you know It's not like I actually wanted people to come for any reason other than I put all this work into it and no one sees It right.
Rym: I'm just gonna be so you know who sees it.
Rym: every time we get a new listener You're a con.
Rym: they wonder, you know, who the fuck were those guys trashing my dota game?
Rym: Yeah, right and they go online the Google for GeekNights.
Rym: They find the website.
Rym: they go.
Rym: Oh, those guys are some handsome individuals and I will listen to what they have to say.
Scott: It's there's gonna be a lot of fancy shit In general.
Scott: Yeah, so we ran what happened to the book club.
Rym: Uh, we didn't do it last week.
Rym: Cuz we're lazy.
Rym: We both read foundation.
Rym: We'll record it this week and put it up.
Rym: And you got to do the data entry on the book club for your book.
Scott: We also didn't do the data entry for Like the past one or two.
Rym: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: We can do it.
Scott: I did all the other ones.
Scott: Yeah, most of them are in there.
Scott: Yeah, where no one can see them yet, but you will see them zoom The book club is splitting off into its own thing the GeekNights book club.
Rym: So we'll try to do them at least once a month and they won't take up Thursday episodes Which means we need Thursday episode.
Rym: I do and I'm cutting all the audio of the book club out of the old Thursday episodes where there's all that like news and Crap in it so you can listen to just the book club.
Rym: book club.
Scott: I got to figure out how we're actually gonna post those.
Scott: Yeah, I think we just might have to leave those the way they are.
Rym: No, I'm gonna repost them in the new way.
Scott: Then there's gonna be double episodes, that's fine.
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: I'll note all the doubles.
Scott: I think it's because it's it's it's not.
Scott: I'll show you.
Scott: I don't know if it's gonna work cuz we'll go.
Rym: it'll be worth it to have doubles.
Rym: if I'll have to change the names or something.
Rym: It's worth it to have the audio there without the cruft audio.
Rym: no one needs the news.
Scott: you just fast forward.
Rym: They don't.
Rym: you know people.
Rym: hey, whatever.
Scott: They don't need it.
Scott: Oh, we've only actually done like a handful of book club episodes.
Scott: It won't be so bad.
Scott: Just leave the old ones the way they are.
Rym: I want to put them in the feed at least even if I don't redo the audio.
Scott: It's not good.
Rym: It's not.
Scott: Then you code the website to make it handle that.
Rym: I could.
Rym: I made a Django site before I quit my job.
Rym: Yeah, it's pretty.
Rym: It's pretty bare-bones.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: You know what though?
Rym: It's got a great admin interface sure.
Scott: well Yeah, cuz it's automatic.
Rym: yeah, and you know the actually that admin really starts to fail whenever you start doing The unofficial book club book is not one book But it is many books basically all of the Prince of Nothing series by our Scott backer.
Rym: Just read them all.
Rym: we're gonna be doing shows and shit on that stuff because it's having yet another Resurgence in the crew.
Rym: so we got to capitalize on that mm-hmm, and they're great books.
Rym: Otherwise New York comic-con anime festivals coming up doing stuff at that.
Rym: PAX East is coming up doing stuff at that.
Rym: So we only got 30 seconds, so I have been a hero is a game Where you play an entire JRPG and I had 30 seconds.
Scott: awesome because that's my number one problem with JRPGs.
Scott: They take two goddamn.
Rym: I never thought I'd play a game where grinding was fun.
Scott: Well.
Scott: You're not actually Grinding.
Scott: that's sort of.
Scott: you are at a time under the world.
Rym: It wasn't 30 seconds yet.
Scott: I'm just thinking guess, but when you are grinding.
Rym: It's kind of like it does all the work.
Rym: It's like all right.
Rym: I gotta level up now And takes like 10 seconds, maybe.
Rym: yeah, actually 10 seconds is a long time to spend grinding.
Scott: This is the interesting thing right.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: You know you look at it and mechanically it is a JRPG, but because of the way It's done.
Scott: It's actually not.
Scott: it's more of a dexterity.
Rym: You know it's like a dexterity puzzle game.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you need the same skills as a platformer But you also need to figure out the order to do the things in and it's dry.
Scott: you know Grinding is.
Scott: maybe you'll have to do it, but it'll only take you like 30 seconds.
Rym: It's part of a path like do you want to grind?
Rym: or maybe you can find an item that'll beat the boss even if you're Not more powerful than sometimes the.
Rym: you know the grinding is gonna fill axe.
Rym: you get her with that bugs water.
Scott: Yeah, and the grinding isn't just grinding.
Scott: It's like actually you're racing against the clock.
Scott: I don't know how far you've gotten.
Scott: there's a level where you have to beat this hermit.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I got the hermit And it's like you have to beat.
Scott: you have to get enough levels to beat him otherwise You can just beat the level the other way, so it's like once you get to level 30 or 40 He'll challenge you, but in order to actually beat him you need to get to level 50 plus.
Scott: But you can only get levels by fighting him.
Scott: So you actually know what you need to do is need to get to level 439 and then fight him and get 11 levels in that one battle so that in the next battle when he challenges you You're over 50, and you need to time it just just right.
Rym: so I love how the game the first time you play like It says like all right you got 30 seconds the fucking world ends, and it doesn't tell you what to do or anything.
Rym: Yeah, and you like right like.
Rym: you're like Oh crap, and you run into town, and then the clock keeps going down.
Rym: like you go to the menu clock keeps going You're like what and then you die, and it's like all right.
Rym: We're gonna scale it back a little bit.
Rym: mmm I like that whole like shake it to me.
Scott: So I just you know just some information right.
Scott: so this game was released in Japan known as Yusha 30 or Yusha Sanju Right hero 30 in Japan, and it was a real time.
Scott: It was like it's a. Wikipedia describes it as a hybrid real-time strategy action RPG.
Scott: shoot him up Alright, it was released on the PSP in May 28.
Scott: Oh 9.
Scott: It was released on the North American PSP October Oh 9. it was Reese.
Scott: the reason we know about it is because on June 29th It was released on Xbox Live Arcade in the US under the title half-minute heroes super nega Neo climax and half-minute hero 2 has been announced.
Scott: So the first I think the only part of the game you've probably played is hero 30.
Scott: I know there are other modes right so I've played some of evil Lord.
Rym: evil Lord 30 looks really fun Which is basically the same as hero 30.
Scott: only you're the your play.
Scott: as do you remember the evil Lord who is hot and had?
Scott: A bat for a girlfriend.
Scott: Yeah, you play as him.
Scott: Then this princess 30 mode which is a shoot-em-up game this night 30 mode Which is an action game which I assume is more like Zelda This hero 300 mode except you have 300 seconds to beat a level, but the time goddess is not there and Certain areas of the map become inaccessible every 60 seconds of the game.
Scott: I'm just reading this on Wikipedia because I haven't gotten past evil Lord 30.
Rym: Yeah, I've not played that much yet, but the game is.
Scott: and then this hero 3 mode Which is the same as hero 30, but you start with only 3 seconds, and there's only one mission.
Rym: That's Gotta be just a joke at the end.
Scott: I think it's probably the end end.
Rym: I don't there's a fun balance here of like.
Rym: the game is funny and cute like the goddess is like.
Rym: yeah I guess I could just roll back time, but I want money.
Scott: give me all the treasure and then I'll reset.
Scott: Yeah, if you give me enough money.
Scott: I'll reset time.
Rym: It's like why do you need money?
Rym: Yeah, don't worry about that I?
Rym: Also, like how you can change the graphics between like normal modern graphic mode Which is like this cute kind of scribbly like drawn in MS.
Scott: You know yeah, I like you know aesthetically be the Marty 16-bit.
Scott: You know final I play in 16-bit mode.
Scott: I like that mode better aesthetically But actually it's harder to play in that mode.
Rym: so I find it harder to play in the normal mode.
Scott: I play in the normal mode mostly even though.
Scott: I like the way the other mode looks But I think it's cuz.
Rym: I played the other mode first a whole bunch So maybe I'm used to.
Scott: it's really surprising cuz every single art asset in the game.
Scott: They did twice.
Scott: you know it's like everything is 16-bit and also not and you know It's really the sometimes kind of cutscenes, but they'll do the full screen splash.
Scott: Yeah, I was sort of a ninja guy dead in style ninja.
Scott: You're right ninja and in the 16-bit those look really great.
Scott: like you know the way they designed the characters It's gonna be really nostalgic.
Rym: I think that was the intent.
Scott: you should if you should definitely play the very first level of hero 30 twice in both modes So that you can see how the splash screens have completely different art in both different graphics modes.
Scott: Yeah, I wish though you could just switch between the graphics modes instantly.
Scott: now You got to go to the menu and change it and it loads and it's kind of slow.
Scott: That's a little.
Rym: no if I could just hit like a trigger and just switch it I just feel like that would be awesome all the time.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That'd be great.
Rym: be cool if that an 8-bit mode.
Scott: Yeah, it's also cool.
Scott: You know it's got to say a lot of stuff that other RPGs have like when you change your equipment It changes how your guy looks yeah, and all that kind of stuff.
Rym: There's a lot of characters, and they're all kind of fun.
Rym: It's one of those games like.
Rym: it's almost a big joke like the whole.
Scott: obviously half the game is a joke right It's like it's like they did a twist on the genre, but they actually made it better.
Scott: But they also made it sort of a joke like lol.
Scott: It's a JRPG Like oh you level up in like 10 seconds to level 50.
Rym: yep I think my favorite.
Rym: like early on you run into this bard and you need him like well But it really helps to have him to get across this bridge where there's a big mushroom monster to be.
Rym: yeah Cuz this dog helps.
Rym: he doesn't help.
Rym: he just stands there and sings.
Rym: the dog does all the work, but you're with him.
Rym: He's in your party for maybe Seven seconds.
Rym: yep as you run from one area to another area and halfway through he interrupts you.
Rym: He's like what a journey.
Rym: We are on and he says all this stuff.
Rym: You don't care about and then at the end He's like Our lives are changed for all the time.
Rym: We spent together and the many memories.
Rym: We have.
Scott: did you see him a second time?
Rym: I did not.
Scott: you didn't get to the level where you collect all the people you've been with.
Rym: I did not do that.
Scott: There's certain boss levels and basically I think there are two of them Boss levels where all you do in the level is go around Collecting all the previous helpers from the previous levels and then bringing them all to the boss in a giant army and most of them Die and you do all the work.
Scott: But it's still pretty awesome.
Rym: the game does have a good mechanic of time trials to like if you've played a level before it shows A shadow of what you did last time And it doesn't also items from future levels on a past level.
Rym: So if you know like oh, I level up and I go back and beat it faster.
Rym: It's just can you beat it faster?
Scott: Yeah, there's also if you have friends in Xbox Live like for example I was playing and it was like I was sort of taking the slow way to beat a level completely.
Scott: get all the items level Up a whole bunch and it said on the screen like fast karate has you know is fighting the evil Lord?
Scott: And I'm like what it was mean.
Scott: Dave obviously beat the level a lot faster than I did I was obsessed with.
Rym: I think was like the second or third level.
Rym: I saw you had a score and It was like like way over 30 seconds because he did the goddess thing And I was so close to doing it without having to go to the goddess like I'm like a second away from it.
Rym: But I just can't do it.
Rym: I wonder if it's even possible.
Scott: I've beaten levels with like a fraction of a second left.
Scott: I've gotten to the goddess of the fraction of a second left multiple times.
Scott: Yeah, I think once I actually went to the goddess statue with literally 1/100 of a second on the clock.
Rym: I Like that mechanic, but it makes me obsessed with not having to go to the gods.
Rym: if I can help you know.
Scott: That's another thing is you'll have five seconds left, and it's like well It'll take me two Seconds to fight a guy.
Scott: so you fight a guy and do this you get you get a little bit XP.
Scott: level up.
Scott: you got three Seconds left.
Scott: do you go out to fight another guy?
Scott: Do you risk it or do you just go and pull down because you want to get because you pay the goddess the same amount of Money no matter what foods cheap.
Rym: I'll usually go out and hold down B through the fight and hope I don't hands on the level.
Scott: some levels of expensive food.
Scott: some Levels have no food not true.
Scott: You know that's the thing is like you can't cover foods far away.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: early in the game.
Scott: You can use the same formula for beating the levels But then very quickly every level has something different about it.
Scott: that makes it So you can't just follow the same formula You've been using which is level up.
Scott: go to the goddess.
Scott: level up go to the goddess level.
Scott: go to the goddess fight the boss.
Scott: Some levels there just won't be bad guys out there.
Scott: You'll have to find some other way to level up some levels.
Scott: there Just won't be any money from fighting bad guys.
Scott: you have to get your money somewhere else.
Scott: And it's like if you don't have money you can't pay the goddess.
Scott: so even you really leveled up a whole bunch.
Scott: You know you can't level up enough to go fight the evil lord.
Scott: You need to pay the goddess at least once or twice.
Rym: you got to find the money somewhere Yep, and a lot of the levels have multiple ways to beat them.
Scott: That's another thing is usually I'm super anti getting a hundred percent on the games because I don't have time for that shit.
Scott: right But in this game It's very clear about showing you Visually what you need to do to get a hundred percent.
Scott: And it's not too hard to figure it out either.
Scott: like you'll go to a level and After you beat it the little dot on the map will still be gold which means you didn't get everything.
Scott: so you go over that And you put a and you see that there's a little symbol with a sword and shield and it's gray which means you think all The equipment.
Scott: so you go back in the level and you just do it slow buying every equipment You can find and you're like oh I got it and that equipment is you need it because in the next level you're really gonna need that shit.
Scott: Yeah, then you'll go back and there'll be a level.
Scott: It's you didn't beat that one either.
Scott: so you go and you'll see like this you know why with two arrows coming at me.
Scott: It's like aha There's another path to beat this level and you really want to get those because that opens up other levels.
Scott: I actually beat all of hero 30 in every single level.
Scott: in the only level I don't have a hundred percent Completion on.
Scott: it's a gold dot is the very last one and it's like.
Scott: it's weird because you know at the end of Megaman 2 There's two skulls.
Scott: Yeah, there's a second skull on the map.
Scott: I can't figure out how the fuck to get to it But I've cleared out every other level in the entire game except the very last one.
Scott: But There it's cool.
Scott: You definitely want to get the other paths because the other paths have a lot of stuff in them.
Scott: like my favorite path was the one where you make a deal with this evil devil.
Scott: and Basically, there's three or four levels.
Scott: you play and you have the power of like Satan and you're just.
Scott: you're like level of billion From the beginning of all these levels, but they're still hard.
Scott: It's like they still have a challenge to them and then after the fourth level the final one.
Scott: It's like the devil only gave you the power four times.
Scott: then he's gonna take your soul.
Scott: so if you don't beat that fourth level properly then the devil takes your soul and it's the end of the game.
Scott: and then you Have to like you have to beat the level a certain way in order for the time goddess to remove the.
Scott: you know The curse and protect your soul.
Scott: You got to give her all the treasure.
Scott: Basically you have to get extra treasures to give her.
Rym: That must be what Lena inverse turns into when she gets too much magic.
Scott: I definitely accept a different hair color.
Rym: Yeah That's what happens when you use high-powered magic a hair turns gray.
Scott: Yes So, I mean I bought a lot of games an Xbox Live arcade recently and you know the bastion one we talked about already and That's a demo.
Scott: yeah Galax, you know Galaga Legion's DX, which is all right.
Rym: It's not as good as pac-man, but it's way fun Yeah, but I think is it's not.
Scott: pac-man was a huge improvement over pac-man.
Scott: non DX Galaga Legion's.
Scott: DX is pretty equivalent to Galaga Legion's.
Rym: not but I had not played Galaga Legion.
Rym: So I played DX.
Rym: It's just like everything's awesome.
Scott: Yeah, but half-minute hero.
Scott: of all those I've been playing this one the most obviously because I beat it all with you know And it does.
Scott: the thing that really helps me play it all and get completion on it without Worrying is because it's so quick.
Rym: I can like knock out a round and you know in a couple minutes I can beat like two levels if I'm good.
Scott: Yeah, you can.
Scott: you can beat a whole lot of it really quick at you know, fill it in while something's cooking.
Rym: It's got the right level of being funny and everything.
Rym: Also the music is fantastic.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it's very strange.
Scott: It's a little game would have this big awesome music in it, but it does.
Rym: well the thing is the neo-climax.
Rym: It's got like.
Rym: the music is always like epic fantasy.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: Holy shit JRPG Mm-hmm.
Rym: It almost makes me want to play like Final Fantasy 4 again.
Scott: It's except you realize that the fighting the guys is not instant and you could die.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I don't know what else we can say.
Rym: It's a tiny game.
Rym: at least the levels are tiny.
Rym: the game feels tiny but it's actually pretty gigantic in terms of how much stuff?
Scott: Yeah, it's like you play.
Rym: it never gets old and every level is so different.
Scott: like Scott was pointing out it feels so quick But then you look back is like how many hours that I put into that?
Scott: Oh, fuck me It got me Pretty much with its instant gratification and quick battling.
Rym: There's no reason not to buy this game.
Rym: if you have an Xbox I think is.
Scott: I wish like you could get Final Fantasy 6 where the caught the random combat worked like this game genie.
Scott: Maybe I should.
Rym: Actually, yeah, I think that's the way to play old JRPG.
Scott: just, you know Get a game genie or emulator so that we love you billion.
Rym: I just go to the blue level.
Scott: a billion.
Scott: you push a button.
Scott: you just win every fight.
Scott: Turn off all random encounters.
Scott: It's effort and your level of billions.
Rym: You win all boss fights like where's The bad guy Galvez?
Rym: punch him in the face the end.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: Yeah, if only it animated.
Scott: you punch him in the.
Rym: yes There's a mod.
Rym: take every JRPG and it's just you put.
Rym: all you do is punch the big bad in the face and then the square.
Scott: Boss, you know, I don't think we actually did a description of what the this half-many hero is all about really.
Scott: So just to you know, cuz we completely missed the the this part the world's gonna end.
Scott: All right, so the work.
Scott: there's an evil lord.
Scott: You don't know who he is.
Scott: He's the big bad evil of all big bad evils and he he knows a spell to end the world.
Rym: But apparently this spell is like a third level spell like it's way fast to cast easy to learn.
Scott: He doesn't want to cast it himself.
Scott: So what he does is he goes around finding evil dudes who live in castles and he teaches them the evil spell.
Scott: And much like rezo, they're not stupid and all these people want the world to end.
Scott: So as soon as the big bad guy teaches them the spell to end the world It's our cast and they start casting it Immediately.
Scott: and you know what it takes exactly 30 seconds for this spell to work.
Scott: and after 30 seconds the world ends.
Rym: I love there's the one king who did.
Rym: the evil lord didn't even try to teach him.
Rym: He just overheard the evil lord teaching someone else the spell.
Rym: Yeah, that's how easy this shit is.
Scott: of that one bat cast it There's a bat trying to cast it.
Scott: there's all sorts of crazy.
Scott: all the great evil lords are the greatest.
Scott: I wish there was like a Mode where like you played as all the evil lords from all because some of them are just so great Like there's a guy made of rocks.
Scott: There's the insect queen and a phillax.
Scott: Yeah, there's all and they all funny names.
Scott: They all look funny and they have funny things to say.
Scott: all the evil lords are great so every you.
Scott: basically you're a hero and you show up at some place with the castle on a little map and The evil lord as soon as you get there starts casting the spell and you got to level up enough to kill him.
Scott: You'll not only level up but get to him and kill him in 30 seconds.
Rym: now in the first few levels It's easy.
Rym: like as soon as you are a high enough level to where with full health You are stronger than the evil lord this thing
Scott: pops up and tells you you greater than evil, which is like aha I know now that I'm stronger than the evil lord, but I wish RPGs did that.
Rym: But at the same time that's not like that formula doesn't help you later because I've beaten many bosses where I was not greater than The evil lord, that's true.
Scott: Well, you don't have.
Scott: you might have help or something.
Scott: You can beat the boss bucks water.
Scott: Yes, you also.
Scott: There are some levels where even if you're greater than the evil lord, you can't get to the evil lord.
Rym: You see you didn't figure out how to work the map proper or you're greater than him But you have to fight so many of his goons to get to him that you're not really.
Rym: you're only greater than him.
Scott: You might be able to get to the castle But you might not be able to get to the castle with enough time left on the clock.
Scott: So you have to figure out some way to get to like this hidden town near the castle so that you can reset the clock Close enough to the castle so you can get there with 30 seconds left.
Scott: and it's like a puzzle game even though it Visually and mathematically looks like grinding.
Scott: It's not grinding It's actually just part of the puzzle solving.
Scott: really how many guys do I need to kill before?
Scott: and then which town do I go?
Scott: To in order to be able to get to the boss.
Rym: There is no reason not to buy this game, right?
Scott: The rest of the plot is that there's this time princess.
Scott: What is she the god of time goddess?
Scott: She's the goddess of time and she's good, but she's greedy.
Scott: She wants treasure, right and there are statues of her all about the world and she basically comes to you and it's like hey Let's save the world, but I like money.
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: if you want me to reset the clock, you know, basically send you 30 seconds back in time.
Scott: You got to.
Scott: you know drop some money at a statue of me to fill up my coffers.
Rym: But she doubles the amount of money it costs every time she only adds 100.
Scott: I think only 100.
Rym: I've only ever done it once.
Scott: I don't really yeah.
Scott: Anyway, I've done a lot of times.
Scott: So you go to her statue and the first time in any given level the first time you go to the statue 100 then 200 that you keep giving her more and more money the more times you reset the clock per level So that when you go to the next level it'll start at 100 again.
Scott: So you think basically in those 30 seconds of playing you might just try to run around and do all the plot things.
Scott: But you have to do enough killing to get enough money to reset the clock in those 30 seconds No matter what else you do and get back to a statue.
Scott: Back to a statue also, right?
Scott: So it's kind of tricky.
Scott: The other thing is I forget.
Rym: Yeah, there's not that much to this game.
Scott: There's not that much.
Rym: You should buy it.
Rym: it's great.
Rym: It's awesome.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logo.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.