Rym: It's Tuesday, September 15th, 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: On Tuesday the 15th, we are talking about Rocket League, the hottest new esport.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Recorded in advance because I'm still in Australia or Singapore or whatever for a while.
Scott: Yup, which means I'm chilling out playing Rocket League.
Rym: Rocket League runs just fine on my laptop, so I bought a wired Xbox controller, which I wish I'd done before, so I'm bringing that on the planes.
Scott: To play solo?
Rym: I'm going to practice aerials and stuff solo on Rocket League.
Scott: Why don't you play in the AU region when you get over there?
Rym: Yeah, when I get over there, but I'm talking about on the flight.
Scott: See if they have different style.
Rym: Not that you would know.
Rym: Everything's backwards, they fly upside down.
Scott: No!
Rym: The joke that's in every Tumblr.
Scott: So does everyone.
Scott: Everyone flies upside down.
Scott: It's Rocket League.
Rym: If I fly upside down and I do something cool, that is literally 100% of the time not on purpose.
Rym: So yeah, we're back from PAX.
Rym: We played a bunch of games and we're going to talk about those in the next Tuesday show.
Rym: But something real big happened.
Scott: The biggest.
Scott: Well, not the biggest.
Scott: The biggest would be the thing we've always asked for.
Rym: The actual MMO.
Scott: The Pokemon MMO, but that is not happening.
Scott: What instead is happening is...
Rym: The Pokemon candy box.
Scott: Yes, the Ingress company, Niantic.
Rym: Which is now separate from Google due to all that stuff we talked about on a Monday.
Scott: Separate from Google, but apparently still very successful because Ingress was a successful game.
Scott: But they have teamed with the Nintendo to make Pokemon Go, which is the Pokemon Ingress.
Scott: You can now, once this game comes out early next year, safely delete all your other candy boxes, your Adventure Capitalists.
Scott: Delete all that garbage.
Rym: Never open your 3DS Streetpass again.
Scott: 3DS Streetpass in the trash.
Scott: Delete all the garbage games you've got and play this one garbage game above all others.
Rym: To rule them all and in the darkness bind them.
Scott: All the time you spend playing garbage games, play this one instead.
Scott: It will rule all.
Scott: I guess you're going to have to buy this weird Bluetooth thing that looks like a Pokeball.
Scott: Okay, fine.
Scott: I'll buy it.
Rym: That's already bought.
Rym: That's pre-ordered.
Rym: the day I can pre-order it.
Scott: Alright, we got that.
Scott: We good.
Scott: The end.
Rym: It's interesting though.
Rym: One, a clever person could have seen this coming.
Rym: Because there were a little... You could see business relationships and different people.
Scott: Yeah, they did a Pokemon Google Maps thing on some day last year.
Rym: Or this year.
Scott: I forget when it was.
Rym: It was about a year ago-ish.
Rym: I just remember it was warm out.
Rym: And it was at least a year ago because I remember I was walking to get lunch with someone for work.
Rym: Like a business thing.
Rym: And I zoom in on an area of Google Maps and I'd see a Pokemon on my Google Maps.
Rym: And I'm like, "What?
Rym: The
Rym: fuck?".
Rym: And I clicked on it and it said,
Rym: "Caught!".
Rym: And it turned into a Pokeball.
Rym: And I was like, "Uh...".
Rym: And I started scrolling around and I saw another Pokemon like downtown.
Rym: And yeah.
Scott: And then you went downtown.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But then nothing came of it and it eventually disappeared.
Rym: But obviously that was probably...
Scott: A temporary promotion but also clearly a test to see if there would be... You know, it was a precursor to Pokemon Go.
Rym: You know, it's also kind of smart that if you're... Pokemon is literally the perfect storm of a franchise to do any of this AR stuff with.
Scott: Pokemon is the franchise that can do anything.
Rym: Anything.
Rym: First person shooter.
Rym: We had that.
Rym: It was called Pokemon Snap.
Scott: You can make Pokemon Rocket League.
Scott: Pikachu driving a car.
Rym: But... So with Ingress... If you're going to make an AR game though like that, what better way to prototype it than to make a game that has basically no skin or a completely flimsy skin, like say Ingress, to figure out...
Scott: It has a skin.
Scott: Green and blue.
Scott: Go green.
Scott: Of course now it's going to be Go Dragonite.
Rym: Dragonite Spiritoom.
Rym: Spiritoom.
Scott: Man, am I going to find a fucking Spiritoom?
Scott: Am I going to have to go to some cavern somewhere to get a Spiritoom?
Rym: I better stay at the company I work for.
Scott: Or am I going to have to fly to Japan and find some ancient Spirit Stone to get a Spiritoom?
Rym: I've got to stay where I'm working just long enough because I travel the world a lot.
Rym: And let me tell you, if going to physical places matters, I'm going to be the fucking Pokemon master.
Scott: Well, you don't think there's anyone else who travels?
Rym: No, I'll travel more.
Rym: Like, oh, I'm in Australia?
Rym: Well, day trip to pick up that Pokemon in Tasmania.
Scott: I mean, in the preview video, they show a big capturing event in Times Square.
Scott: Oh, who happens to work right fucking there?
Scott: I guess I'm catching that Mewtwo.
Scott: Good luck, everyone who doesn't live here.
Rym: So, but yeah, with AR, no one's made good games really.
Rym: Like, Ingress was the best one.
Rym: that was a game that kept going.
Rym: People have made AR events.
Scott: It's still a candy box, but it was team... It is team candy box.
Rym: It also had game mechanics.
Rym: Like, it had stuff.
Rym: It was persistent.
Rym: All the AR things anyone talks about are like, I love bees.
Rym: They're events.
Rym: They start and they end, and they have a lot of Mechanical Turks making them happen.
Rym: Ingress actually kind of just worked, which was a big deal.
Rym: But obviously they probably learned a lot from Ingress, and they probably...
Scott: You can think of this, like, not just as Pokemon, but also as Ingress 2.0.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's no reason to play Ingress when Pokemon Go comes around.
Rym: Because, I mean, we saw people at expo halls who tried to make games like Ingress, and they obviously all looked stupid or bad.
Rym: Ingress is actually the first long-standing AR game, augmented reality, for those of you who aren't paying attention, that actually succeeded to some degree, and no one else has made one.
Rym: So, Niantic is the only company in the world that has actual data on how well AR games work with modern technology.
Scott: I'm waiting for some real game company to buy Niantic, right?
Scott: Nintendo could buy them, you know?
Rym: Well, they're owned by Alphabet, Google's parent company.
Scott: I thought that they weren't part of Alphabet at all anymore.
Rym: I'm not 100% sure.
Scott: I thought that they were completely separate.
Rym: Well, I'm not sure what is being split off completely independent, and what is just its own company.
Scott: Or maybe they are still on the Alphabet.
Rym: Yeah, that's technically owned by Alphabet.
Rym: I'm actually not clear on all that yet.
Scott: Alphabet's Google, by the way.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Listen to Monday GeekNights.
Rym: But it's kind of interesting, too, that way, way back... It's one of our lost panels.
Rym: We did this panel.
Rym: We called it "egregiously unrealized potential" at a PAX in, like, 2010.
Rym: Like, a long goddamn time ago.
Scott: And many of the things we asked for happened.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, this panel was so old that we had five or six slides dedicated to... Guys, there's this game called X-Com that none of you have played.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Scott: Reboot it.
Scott: Well, you can play X-Com pretty easily right now.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And the culmination... Oh, yeah, we talked about bringing Star Wars and Free Space Shooters back, and now we got to leave Dangerous, and there's probably going to be a bunch of Star Wars games.
Scott: Well, Star Wars is back.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But TIE Fighter came back on GOG.
Rym: That's often a precursor...
Scott: Yeah, but they're only going to make Rogue Squadrons.
Scott: They're not going to make new TIE Fighters.
Rym: You never know.
Rym: I hold out hope.
Scott: Other people have been making Free Space Shooters, though.
Rym: True.
Rym: But the entire panel culminated in the end.
Rym: Our only actual point was the Pokemon MMO would literally change and possibly destroy the world.
Scott: Maybe this will half destroy the world.
Rym: This is phase one.
Scott: It's a sign of the end.
Scott: It's not the end times.
Scott: It's not the final battle of Tarmen Gaiden.
Rym: I was about to say, we found the Horn of Valar, but no one blew it yet.
Scott: It's a sign of the end times.
Rym: This isn't the One Ring.
Scott: It's like you got the prophecies, and suddenly some things in the prophecies start happening, but it's not everything yet.
Scott: That's what this is.
Scott: It's like three goddamn false dragons.
Rym: All the babies on Earth were still born suddenly for some reason.
Scott: The room of Galv is empty, but we're still here.
Rym: No more crickets or cicadas?
Scott: Cicadas.
Rym: It's kind of an aside of the book club, but someone tweeted at me.
Rym: They said something very profound.
Rym: "The Prince of Nothing is better, but I feel better after reading The Wheel of
Rym: Time.".
Scott: Sure.
Scott: So yeah, of course.
Rym: This game is not going to be the Pokemon MMO, but it is going to be, I think, the best augmented reality game to have ever been released in the world to date.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's my guess.
Scott: I bet money's on that.
Scott: If I could invest in Niantic, I would.
Rym: Part of the reason I played Ingress was because it was the first one.
Scott: Maybe they're hiring.
Scott: Are they in New York?
Rym: I don't know where they're based.
Rym: Actually, yeah, are they hiring?
Rym: Because that's actually an area of games that I have a lot of domain knowledge and expertise.
Scott: I have a feeling that they're in the other side of the country.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's hard to say, though, because Google does have some offices down here.
Scott: I have a feeling they're in the other side of the country.
Rym: I will look that up.
Rym: A strong feeling.
Rym: I will find out while we're doing the show.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: Also, I have a feeling that you don't work very few hours there.
Rym: Yeah, but you know what?
Rym: I'd be willing to work a lot more hours if I was making big tier for real game stuff.
Scott: I wouldn't, even though there would be one huge benefit of working there, which is play Pokemon Go fucking today.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: There's another benefit, too.
Scott: Just give myself all the Pokemon.
Rym: I was going to say, right click, oppress, add Pokemon, Spiritomb.
Scott: Level 1,000 max stats.
Scott: Evie's maxed.
Scott: Six Spiritombs can't lose.
Scott: Ivy's maxed or whatever.
Scott: Oh, and then Rym, he levels himself up, but then I go to his account.
Scott: All Geodudes.
Scott: My only question now.
Scott: Rym captures a whole bunch of Pokemon.
Scott: Next day, he wakes up.
Scott: He looks.
Scott: He's got five Geodudes.
Scott: Can't lose.
Scott: He doesn't have the sixth Geodude.
Scott: I killed it.
Rym: My only question now is, will Dorkly/CollegeHumor continue Pokemon Rusty now?
Scott: Why wouldn't they?
Rym: Because they haven't in a while.
Scott: No, they haven't.
Scott: Oh, well.
Rym: But things of the day.
Rym: So, Gummergate is stupid, just in case, because apparently people who are fans of us didn't realize that that's the truth and we're mad a while ago and it was funny, but Jimmy Kimmel is like the second most mainstream, genero type of generic mainstream, boring humor in the world.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: The only talk show type entertainer person who is more mainstream is a guy that neither one of us can remember his name.
Scott: So mainstream.
Scott: The other Late Show guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But.
Scott: That's not Colbert, the third one.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, Gobert is special.
Rym: Anyway, so apparently he made fun of Gomergate because they're morons, which already says one thing.
Scott: I thought he was making fun of, I don't think this had anything to do with Gomergate.
Scott: I thought it was that he was making fun of people watching other people play video games.
Rym: Well, I think he also kind of made fun of gamer culture, which is, that's a mortal sin among the Gomergates.
Scott: It's like, yeah, he just doesn't understand why watching video games is interesting because he clearly doesn't play or understand video games, but yet he doesn't, you know, watching sports is okay.
Scott: We watch other people play football.
Scott: The end.
Scott: That's the end of the argument.
Scott: Done.
Rym: But irrespective of what, how, why Gomergate got mad and started sending him death threats and shit.
Rym: And he responded by reading all their death threats on the air.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: That's what you do.
Scott: That's what I would do.
Rym: Which infuriated them further.
Scott: Send me death threats to read on this podcast, please.
Rym: And the feedback loop is continuing to go, which says one thing.
Rym: Gomergate, you finally made it.
Rym: You're so mainstream that lame late night talk show people know what you are and are milking you for bits.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: That is the only thing that could make you more pathetic would be if grandma knows what you are.
Scott: I mean, it's sort of done at this point.
Scott: If you look, a lot of people like run the numbers on it and it's basically the number of people who are.
Scott: Gomergate is so few people.
Rym: I saw a great analysis of the accounts that tweeted about it, that all, you know, that you could kind of pick the accounts from the kinds of things they tweeted that were all new, you know, eggs and whatever with anime avatars.
Rym: They print.
Rym: like 90 percent of them have not tweeted in months.
Rym: It's pretty much dead.
Rym: So this is Stimpy rubbing his butt on the grave anyway.
Scott: So there's this guy, his YouTube account is called iBook guy.
Scott: I don't know why it's called iBook guy, but anyway, he's a pretty smart dude and makes good YouTube videos.
Scott: And he's got a series of YouTube videos that has two parts so far and he's making more parts.
Scott: And in these videos, he explains to you in great detail how old busted computers or old non-busted computers, depending on your point of view, you know, from like 70s, 80s level, you know, Apple twos, Atari, Commodores, even the NES, right?
Scott: How those computers with their limited capacity to process things were able to display fancy graphics on the screen.
Rym: These videos are amazing because...
Scott: For people who didn't already know how these computers worked, right?
Scott: This will make you perhaps appreciate old computers and maybe want to learn to program them because, you know, you might think, well, what's the point of learning to program some old computer?
Scott: Well, first of all, it's really much easier to understand.
Scott: And once you learn that, you'll realize, oh, a new computer really isn't that much different.
Scott: It's just got more bits available.
Rym: And like old computers, like you had so few colors, you know, count the number of pixels on the screen, which was a small enough number back then that you could count them by hand if you wanted to.
Scott: I mean, while I technically learned to program on an Apple two with like, you know, turtle graphics, logo, whatever, I really programmed, I guess, Mac L2C's with Pascal
Rym: and then I
Scott: even more really programmed on a TI-86 and a TI-86 is pretty much really similar to any of these things.
Rym: I learned all my actual programming.
Rym: It's got a Z80 chip, right?
Rym: Yeah, like I did Q-basic, but it wasn't real.
Rym: When I had to make shit work on my TI-85, which was faster, the memory was faster, but it had less of that slow memory.
Rym: I preferred the TI-85 in a lot of ways, but that was when I actually learned how to program.
Scott: Yes, I preferred my fixie to that geared bicycle.
Rym: I wonder if anyone in my old neighborhoods, because I wrote a pretty popular physics thing for high school physics classes, but it had my name all over it and if you fucked with it at all, I had a lot of really obfuscated bullshit hidden around in there.
Rym: If you fucked with it, all it did was make like half the equations subtly wrong.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, these videos are great though because I learned a lot from them actually.
Scott: I didn't know how all these computers work.
Scott: I knew some of the things he was talking about, but not all of them.
Scott: But it's explained at a level- Like, when have I ever done graphics programming on a Commodore?
Scott: My cousins had Commodores, I didn't have one.
Rym: The thing about that, Scott and I both learned stuff, and yet it's explained at a level that you will understand this if you have almost no knowledge of computers.
Scott: This is the kind of stuff where you'll realize, like if you're not sure if you like programming, if these videos interest you, then you probably will.
Rym: You'll love the shit out of programming if these are interesting to you.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Also, a sprite on an NES is actually a bunch of sprites.
Scott: And even if you just care about games only, you'll really appreciate what it took to program those old games.
Rym: But, again, just count the number of pixels on the screen, multiply that by the number of bits you need to determine one color versus the other.
Scott: Then go look at a game like Kirby's Adventure or Mario 3 and realize what they had to do to make that game happen, and look how perfect the game is.
Rym: In the meta moment, I gotta pick a new Book Plug book.
Rym: We just did the Book, well, we're doing the Book Club episode on Thursday this week.
Scott: Aren't we uploading that tonight, which is...
Rym: Why?
Rym: Because it was a Monday, Wednesday week.
Scott: Oh, it was.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: We're recording a lot of episodes way in advance because I'm in Singapore or Sydney.
Scott: We are recording this on Thursday, September 10th.
Scott: We're probably uploading it on Thursday, September 11, 12, 13, 15?
Rym: Yep, 15.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Dateline, of course.
Rym: So I haven't picked a new Book Club book, but we did the episode on The Wheel of Time.
Rym: The current book club is done and will be up on Thursday this week.
Rym: And I have not picked a new book yet because I'm going to keep reading The Wheel of Time for a while.
Rym: So...
Scott: The Wheel of Time goes ride and ride.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Moderate hiatus there.
Rym: We're back from PAX, obviously.
Rym: Hopefully, before I leave for Asia Pacific, I'll have at least one of the things we did at PAX.
Rym: Probably our lectures, sports, or games on YouTube.
Rym: Maybe it'll be done by the time this episode airs and then I'll link to it.
Rym: And if it isn't linked to, it means I didn't finish it by then.
Scott: Oops.
Rym: And otherwise, pretty much in October, GeekNights will resume like normal.
Rym: And once the weather gets too shitty to bike, videos are going to start coming out again.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: They better.
Rym: We got to make videos.
Rym: People are really gunning for more Utena.
Scott: Well, they can watch Utena.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I was going to get into Rocket League and Scott kept saying he refused to pay that much money for a game that might be a flash in the pan.
Scott: Yeah, kept saying.
Scott: I said it one time.
Rym: You said it several times.
Scott: I said, "Huh, this game's 20 bucks.
Scott: I don't
Scott: know.".
Rym: And I would say, "It's worth
Rym: it.".
Rym: And you'd say, "No, I'm not
Rym: paying.".
Scott: You said, "It's worth it," knowing nothing about the game whatsoever.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I was right.
Scott: Okay, so of course the game continued for another couple weeks and I said,
Scott: "Hmm.".
Scott: And Videoball did not appear.
Scott: and I watched some videos of Rocket League and I said, "You know, it's a basic 3D
Scott: Videoball.".
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Or one could say Videoball is a 2D Rocket League.
Rym: You know, I'm like- Except Videoball is shooting.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But it's like, "All right.
Scott: Well, this seems to be a thing.
Scott: Let is my duty to see this
Scott: thing.".
Scott: And then, "Yeah, it's a real deal thing.
Scott: Get in on it now.
Scott: It's still the early times
Scott: yet.".
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If you join a matchmaking game, Rando, right now, actually, there are enough people who suck at this game to where you can play and have fun and learn to get better.
Rym: It's not like MOBAs.
Scott: Well, I mean, yeah.
Scott: It's like, imagine if you started playing MOBAs when Dota was just a Warcraft 3 mod.
Scott: That's would be the same thing as if you started playing this now.
Scott: I mean, yes.
Scott: This has been around for a while.
Scott: There was a predecessor game made by the same company that was like something something battle cars.
Scott: And then Rocket League's been around for- Right.
Scott: So Rocket League's been around for a little while yet.
Scott: But even so, this game is still young.
Scott: But it's like the fuse has been ignited and it's getting very close to the dynamite.
Scott: But it hasn't quite touched the dynamite.
Scott: It's like it's getting real close to the dynamite.
Scott: You can get in and be a part of the explosion if you start playing now.
Rym: And you know, actually, the game is because it's a dexterity, physical sport kind of game, as opposed to a MOBA, which is a lot more about knowledge.
Rym: You can actually just get better at it by practicing without anyone telling you what to do.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And the game has good tutorials.
Rym: So you can actually just play.
Scott: Well, tutorials are good at what they do teach you, but they leave a lot of stuff out.
Rym: But anyway, so what is to tell you if you don't know what Rocket League is, which scarily a lot of our listeners didn't like, I streamed it and half the people were like, whoa, what's this game?
Rym: So guys, come on.
Scott: Rocket League is the hot new game.
Scott: The way the game works is pretty simple.
Scott: There is soccer, a ball and nets.
Scott: But the nets are at the edge of the field, just like soccer.
Scott: However, there's no out of bounds because the entire field is encased with walls, even a ceiling.
Scott: So you can't leave the field.
Scott: So you don't worry about out of bounds.
Scott: The game doesn't stop playing.
Rym: And you play three on three.
Rym: There are other options.
Scott: Three on three soccer because the field is so big.
Scott: And, you know, if you have a full set of soccer players like winning eleven, it's like you watch a soccer match.
Scott: Most of the soccer players just standing like at midfield while the ball is like near the net.
Scott: You know, it's like they don't have anything to do with the play over there.
Scott: They're in their position was three on three.
Scott: Everyone's got, you know, a relative amount of action all the time.
Scott: You know, you can still like pass center it to your teammate in the middle and go for the goal and whatnot.
Scott: But, you know, it is not so many players on the field that it's too crazy.
Scott: But there's not not enough players that it's like.
Scott: you're just two people.
Scott: You can play one on one, but it sucks.
Rym: Two on two is pretty fun.
Scott: Two on two is OK.
Scott: I like three on three.
Scott: The real mode.
Rym: One on one.
Rym: I'd like to see two pros play one on one just to see if there's anything because other than just get past the guy, like, I don't know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, it could be real like clever duel of wits.
Scott: It definitely could be.
Scott: But so the catch in Rocket League is, of course, the rocket aspect.
Scott: You are not a person playing soccer.
Scott: You're a car playing soccer, like an RC cars.
Scott: Well, there are arguments as to question whether are they full sized cars with a giant ball or are they tiny cars like RC cars with a normal sized ball?
Rym: And the game gives you no context to figure that out.
Scott: Well, you can see like the stands, right?
Scott: I like the only real world size reference are like the audience, the crowds.
Scott: But they're so far away from the stadium.
Scott: You can't tell if they're like, you know what?
Rym: They're not far away.
Rym: You're just tiny.
Scott: Or is it a tiny car?
Rym: It's hard to say.
Scott: Or is it a bit a full sized car?
Rym: It'll be interesting when the world gets to the point to where Rocket League is a physical game.
Scott: Well, think about the rules of physics.
Scott: If you had a rocket on a tiny car, you just go so far so fast, you just like explode immediately.
Scott: The car has to have some amount of... No, it doesn't.
Rym: I did model rocketry.
Rym: You can put rockets on little things like that just fine to be easier.
Rym: Bigger rockets can't accelerate quickly.
Rym: If you have a big ass rocket, it can't go from nothing to into the air.
Rym: It'll sit there for a long time.
Scott: Anyway, it's a tiny.
Scott: So you're in a car.
Scott: So you're like, well, how do you play soccer in a car?
Rym: Well, I can crash into that ball.
Scott: You just crash into the ball, punch it, basically.
Scott: You can sort of dribble it, right?
Scott: If you drive into it slowly, it'll go bump, bump, bump.
Scott: You can smash it against the wall.
Scott: You can also... There's a jump button so you can jump.
Scott: And then once you've jumped, you have three seconds, if you're still in the air, to jump again.
Scott: And if you jump again, you could just do a double jump, but you can also point in a direction from your second jump.
Rym: Back to the side.
Scott: Forward, back, side, diagonal.
Scott: And that second jump has some oomph to it.
Scott: It's called a dodge.
Scott: So you can get some oomph on the ball.
Scott: And you can also use this like lunge down the field very quickly to go backwards while still facing forwards.
Scott: Like if you need to get back in your net to defend, you could just do a backwards dodge, get right back in your net, but you're still facing forward.
Rym: Or half the time because you're panicking, jumping the wrong direction.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: The game is very precise with the controls on the gamepad.
Rym: So it gives you a lot.
Rym: It's a lot of physics play.
Scott: A lot of analog control of the throttle forward and reverse and your angles and everything.
Rym: You can rotate in full six degrees of freedom at any point.
Rym: And you also have a rocket boost that you can activate.
Scott: That's why it's rocket league.
Scott: So you have this rocket.
Scott: So the thing with the rocket is that you could just press the rocket button to go fast.
Scott: But just doing that isn't really always the greatest idea because you can just use the dodge to go basically just as fast if you're just trying to get down the field or whatever.
Scott: Uh, so it's very, it's only has limited use on the ground, but you really use it.
Scott: for is you jump and then you use the analog stick to aim your car up and then you press rocket.
Scott: And now you're a rocket.
Scott: It's not flying like a plane or like a helicopter or anything like that.
Scott: It's like flying a rocket, like an Apollo five rock, you know, if you spiral out of control, you look like a rocket that spirals out of control is going to land in the ocean and explode.
Rym: Now, this is what pushes the game into an upper tier.
Rym: that makes it really viable as a sport that if you play without the boost and the boost isn't there, the game is already a really good, really fun, really skill based game.
Scott: And when you play with people who are of a low skill level, when you're first starting out, people aren't using the rocket to go in the air very much because as difficult as the game is on the ground, going into the air and being able to hit the ball while it's in the air, moving precisely, you're just going to miss the ball 99.9% of the time.
Scott: And even if you hit it, it's going to go not where you want it to go 100% of the time, 100% of the time, it's going to go where you don't want it to go.
Rym: So
Scott: going up into the air and in the game and being effective at doing so is so such a even the most basic thing of get in the air, hit the ball that's in the air towards the just in the direction of the other enemy's goal, not even not even a shot on the goal, but just towards their end of the field is so difficult that in low level play, people don't even attempt that most basic aerial maneuver very often.
Scott: So that non rocket fun game is the game you're going to play when you're first starting out because no one's going up in the air.
Rym: So the end of the sum of all this is that the game is actually just really stupid fun.
Rym: And what I found once I went through the tutorials and got reasonably competent, Scott's about 10 times better than me right now.
Scott: And I'm still.
Scott: I'm still garbage.
Rym: Scott's plays about 10 times more than I'm 10 times better than him.
Scott: And I'm garbage, which means Rym is poop.
Scott: You and when we both started, we were both worse than poop.
Rym: The streaming I did was literally the third time I'd ever played the game and it shows.
Scott: But go watch some pros play and it's like it looks like a completely different game because they're so good.
Scott: They can just go up in the air whenever they want, hit the ball exactly where they want, when they want all the time.
Scott: It's ridiculous.
Rym: The game is perfectly fair.
Rym: It has a bunch of DLC and stuff, but none of it affects gameplay in any way.
Scott: Everything that you know, this DLC is purely cosmetic.
Scott: There is no gameplay affecting anything.
Scott: Everyone's on a perfectly even playing field.
Scott: No matter what your car looks like.
Scott: As far as I can tell, the hitbox is the same.
Scott: The speed is the same.
Scott: The jump is the same.
Scott: Everything's the same.
Scott: So it doesn't matter.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And I just like.
Rym: it's really quick that you start playing and you're just join a match, immediately play.
Scott: It's really easy to match last five minutes.
Scott: You can forfeit if you're losing.
Scott: No problem.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Overtime is just golden goal.
Scott: It's it's real simple.
Scott: It's crazy fun.
Scott: You get crazy excitement.
Scott: You know, everything is exciting about sports plays that like replays that look astonishing because some guy did some amazing save or an amazing shot.
Scott: You know, the excitement of just playing any kind of game where you put a ball on a net, but it's fast paced, unlike soccer.
Scott: So it's not boring ever.
Scott: And there's no penalties or play stoppages because you can't commit a penalty because it's a video game.
Rym: And unlike a lot of other esports, like MOBAs are bullshit.
Rym: The game actually has a pretty good spectation.
Rym: Like the spectation was built in.
Scott: It's not perfect yet, but they vastly improved it.
Scott: There's a patch today.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you look at every video game ever and go to the sub Reddit for that video game and you'll see there's usually like common complaints with the game.
Scott: I mean, this goes back for as long as there have been online forums, typical complaints about a game.
Scott: But usually those complaints go unaddressed.
Scott: Hearthstone does not have extra deck slots or counter strike.
Scott: still has the AWP.
Rym: Well, there's the side thing of sometimes those complaints are stupid, but they get addressed running the game.
Rym: Like tribes two.
Scott: In this, there were pretty much not very many complaints that people had with Rocket League and they were all perfectly reasonable.
Scott: Right.
Scott: People wanted to be able to join a new game immediately after finishing one without having to go exit to the main menu and join again.
Rym: There's always one jackass who doesn't say keep playing.
Scott: So you sit there and wait, you know, and things of small things of that nature.
Scott: Right.
Scott: People wanted and there were some bugs like there's a map where you could like get outside the wall.
Scott: They released a patch today of this as of this recording, which is September 10th.
Scott: They addressed every one of these perfectly reasonable issues that people wanted fixed and they're all fixed now.
Rym: They also let me block PS4 people because the game's also on the PlayStation.
Scott: Yes, you can play on PlayStation four or PC.
Scott: It's apparently twenty bucks on steam.
Scott: You can wait for a steam sale.
Scott: But why?
Rym: Yeah, they are apparently going to release it for OS X and Linux as well via steam.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But here's why I say pay 20 bucks for this.
Scott: And even if it's a steam sale later, don't regret it, because what you're going to do to make up for that money you spent on Rocket League is be is not by Fallout four until it comes out with a complete game of the year edition.
Scott: All DLC is 10 bucks steam sale.
Scott: And then that 40 bucks you save or even more on Fallout four will be the money you spent on Rocket League with money left over because, you know, and your money will go to this, you know, poor Rocket League game company instead of just OK for themselves.
Scott: Sure, but not as well as, say, the fallout guys, but I don't need your money, guys.
Rym: Fallout can wait.
Rym: Rocket League is a multiplayer game.
Scott: That's exactly right.
Scott: That's why you're doing this decision that I just told you to do.
Rym: Even if it dies amid a hoggy death, which it won't, I don't think.
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: I think this is going to always be not always.
Rym: It will.
Rym: it'll eventually get on.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: I don't think that this is guaranteed to be a huge mega game, but it's going to be a big, important type e-sport.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It'll have a long run.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It'll have a much longer run than, say, natural selection to did isn't right or anything like that.
Scott: And that's still alive.
Rym: Yeah, barely.
Rym: But it's on life support.
Rym: It's hanging in.
Scott: It's there.
Scott: Is there.
Scott: And this has, you know, thousands of players at all times or as NS2 did not.
Rym: Rocket League is the cool kid who just came to town and is actually really cool.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Like you're actually getting along with him.
Scott: You're hanging out, you know, and you build your skills over time.
Scott: But it's much.
Scott: it's weird in that it's a ridiculously difficult game.
Scott: To, you know, reach the top tiers, the skill cap is so high, but you just keep playing.
Scott: And even though I'm an old man and can't possibly get to that max skill cap, I keep getting better like and I as like every game I play, I jump a little higher and still accurately hit the ball.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or, you know, score or contribute more to my team every single game I play.
Scott: Whereas you play something like Street Fighter and you're going to hit a wall at some point where it's like, oh, I guess I can't execute this combo by pushing these buttons fast enough.
Scott: Yeah, but it doesn't happen in Rocket League because you're just you know, you're driving this little car around.
Scott: It's natural video game skills.
Rym: Well, it has building them.
Rym: It has good feedback.
Rym: Like when you mess up, you really kind of you start to understand why it has a good loop of like learning the rumble and all the side stuff and the ball cam.
Rym: The fact that you can switch between looking straight ahead and a camera that floats a little back from your car and always points at the ball no matter where it is.
Scott: The original game that is based off the battle cars thing had so many modes.
Scott: And like while they develop that along the way, they develop like the Rocket League sort of mode.
Scott: And then they realize, like, this is the fun part here.
Scott: This is way fun.
Scott: And they just took that out and made it its own thing.
Scott: And they worked on less stuff and polished it more, which is why Rocket League.
Scott: It's like you're like, I'm paying all that 20 bucks just this one like mode of another game.
Scott: And it's like, yes, but this mode has been polished so shinally right that it's so perfected.
Scott: It's not some janky thing, right?
Scott: Like it was originally.
Scott: This is like the real deal.
Rym: Scott and I are going to play it enough.
Rym: We just need a third person for our team and we're going to play competitively.
Scott: Yeah, we don't have to win to play competitively.
Scott: I mean, I don't win that often in a runner, but I play that competitively if I can be in the top third someday.
Scott: I mean, we're still in the bronze ranks, the silver and gold ranks.
Rym: We got to get our way up, but I'm going to try to be competent at this game.
Scott: I want to.
Scott: if I can get into the silver ranks, I would be satisfied and be like, I am good enough at the Rocket League.
Scott: If I got to the gold ranks, I'd be like, well, I guess I kept playing Rocket League way too much.
Rym: And I will commit to if you guys get into this game to form teams and will play with you.
Rym: And I'd even be more than happy to set up a ladder or something in the Geek Knights forums.
Scott: I mean, there are even, you know, for big games, you know, like the Dodas and whatever of the world.
Scott: Yeah, this is the real championship.
Scott: So you can't possibly hope to compete in because it's not your job.
Scott: But there are other tournaments all over the place like this, the recreational for DOTA that I know, like.
Scott: I think it's like a game journalist tournament.
Scott: Like they're not.
Scott: they're good, but they're not, you know, anywhere near professional good.
Scott: But they still there are tournaments out there for people of lower skill levels that we can join with our team or set up or whatever.
Scott: And I would be happy to get involved.
Scott: Then I would have a video game and I have a tabletop game for a competitive play and I'll be set.
Rym: Yep, because video ball hasn't come out yet.
Scott: I have my Rocket League in my video games when I'm home and nothing to do.
Scott: And then I'd have my net runners for when I'm out and about and there's someone to play net runner with.
Rym: It's been a long time since I sat down to play a game and just didn't notice how long I had been playing it.
Rym: That's that's what I can say about Rocket League.
Scott: is you just keep joining another one.
Scott: And now you can play even faster because you have to exit to the main menu.
Rym: Yeah, I'm a I'm really feeling this game like I'm having a lot of fun with this game.
Rym: It reminded me what it feels like to play that kind of mastery action game.
Scott: It's like I could have just gone back to Counter Strike and it would have been which I was doing until Rocket League.
Scott: But I'm you know, I'm getting better at Rocket League.
Scott: At Counter Strike, I think I'm as good as I'm going to get, which is not good enough.
Rym: You were never that good.
Rym: I mean, I'm not good at Counter Strike, but I'm easily like I'm more better than you at Counter Strike than you were better than me at Rocket League.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I haven't played Counter Strike in so long.
Rym: That's your problem.
Rym: You don't.
Rym: you don't even know like the corners or anything in new Counter Strike.
Rym: No, you don't know the maps.
Scott: Maybe if I go back and play 1-6 or 1-0 the Counter Strike when I was good.
Rym: Yeah, the only people who still play 1-6 are all invincible Neos.
Scott: Oh, well, that sucks.
Scott: Or cheaters.
Rym: And no one plays Source because Source is the worst Counter Strike.
Rym: Yeah, like play Rocket League.
Rym: It's legit.
Rym: And we're going to stream and play a whole bunch of it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.