Rym: It's some time in 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is a Tuesday GeekNights.
Rym: This is a go up at some point cuz I'm still in Singapore.
Scott: in Australia We don't have any news because who knows what day this is or what news has happened.
Rym: Yep, and while I got some gigabytes and things those can wait.
Rym: and yeah, so we're just gonna talk about the games.
Rym: We play two packs.
Scott: Yeah, cuz they were packs.
Scott: prime was very recent.
Scott: It was the week before Labor Day this year a little bit early and we played Lot of new board game.
Scott: like.
Scott: I had a whole list of like board games on and play that I had not played yet And I played them all pretty much.
Scott: There's no board games right now that I know of maybe one that one with the Sort of Hanabi ish spell casting game.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but anyway, I played that game that games really good.
Scott: I didn't play it and won that game But we played pretty much all the other games We wanted to play and learned a whole bunch of new stuff.
Scott: so we can talk about all these games.
Rym: So we're gonna talk about a bunch that were pretty good and then as the main bit We're gonna review the one that was actually good, right?
Scott: And I think there's some other ones that deserve a full episode as well like camel up cup.
Rym: Oh camel ups getting its own episode right and camel cup can eat a dick.
Scott: that game sucks But camel up camel up is the real deal right.
Rym: so also our friends who own camel up.
Rym: might we'll see what happens to them.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so tumbling dice Kind of broke out in the sense that we played it a lot at the end of every day before we'd all go to bed Because you could kind of just like you could teach a stranger how to play this.
Scott: You don't need to teach anyone how to play tumbledice.
Scott: They look at the tumbling dice and they immediately understand how to play the game without any instructions whatsoever.
Rym: Strangers stood back and tried to throw their dice at it.
Rym: You did have to explain to them.
Scott: Well, I mean, that's just like playground rules, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, alright guys, you know.
Scott: But basically the way tumbling dice works is much like the title you have dice and you tumble them.
Scott: Everyone gets 46 and you take turns tumbling them on this apparatus Which is pretty much a set of terraces and at the bottom There are these tiny terraces that say x4 on them.
Scott: So obviously zero.
Rym: x1 x2 x3 x4.
Rym: there's.
Scott: Obviously if your dice lands on say the x2 terrace
Rym: and you roll and
Scott: the number five is on it You have scored ten points and you take turns throwing one die at a time much like shuffleboard dice can bump other dice Usually moving them to lower tiers or off the board entirely.
Scott: and when all the dice have been tossed by all players you add up the scores of the dice remaining on the board and you try to get the highest score you can which would be Six times four because you got a six on your die on the four terrace and then you got four of those 24 times for the best possible score
Rym: this game.
Rym: We're score Zero, that is literally it the game.
Scott: That's all there is to.
Scott: it is so simple dexterity game.
Scott: throw dice.
Rym: now It matters this luck.
Scott: and there's also skill.
Scott: The skill is where does the dice end up?
Scott: Can you get the die to land on the little tiny four terraces through to those bumpers and around everyone else's?
Rym: the answer is?
Rym: Yes, I'm actually really fucking good at this game.
Scott: knock your enemy's dice off the board at the same time.
Scott: Can you do that skill wise and also luck wise?
Scott: What face does your die show up on?
Scott: because guess what?
Scott: You get all the way down onto the four tier with a high skill toss and it's facing one up.
Scott: That's four Garbage point great.
Scott: I think you get a grid if you get like a five on the two terrace Which is really easy to do.
Scott: that's ten points.
Rym: Well, the trick is the real strategy.
Rym: the real skill at least is you put it on the five probably or the four depend.
Rym: Like I had a pretty good People.
Scott: I see.
Scott: I was thinking that too.
Scott: when I first started reliably I was able to get the no I was watching other people who were and were not doing that.
Scott: Yeah, I'd obviously didn't calculate with a calculator, but it did not seem to be that there was any consistent.
Rym: Well, a lot of those people were bouncing flicking or throwing.
Rym: I would do a straight simple slide.
Rym: I was very very careful.
Scott: you'd as far.
Scott: I was watching you as well.
Scott: I did not notice you getting consistently higher results on your die face.
Scott: I definitely was got plenty of ones and twos just like everyone else.
Scott: Well, usually because I got knocked into a place and the die rolled over I would have well Maybe if you had gotten a one to begin with.
Scott: then he got knocked.
Scott: it would have ended up as a five.
Scott: Yeah, baby is a lot so that there is a. you know Regardless of how much jigaboo jones you have the fact that you don't throw all your dice at once Last and other people get to throw after you even if you can jigaboo jones and get the face up that you want.
Scott: There is a luck element, which is the facing of the die.
Scott: The skill element is where the die goes.
Rym: Yeah, it's.
Rym: it's also just kind of shuffleboard.
Rym: Like what order the players go in matters a fuck ton.
Scott: It creates a lot of excitement.
Rym: I think we could fix a bit a problem with the game by instead of doing round robin turn order doing some other like snake Or some other form of player turn order.
Scott: We've also you had the obvious idea of don't just use d6 use all kinds of other die use different die Maybe bigger ones maybe smaller ones.
Rym: We experimented.
Scott: actually the other dice did not work that well No, I think you know, there's a lot going on here.
Scott: You can make different terraces with different bumpers.
Rym: Well, no, you can't with the game by default the game.
Scott: No, but I mean you could make a time.
Rym: Yeah, I was getting to that.
Rym: So this game and tumbling die is basically like one of those Toys R Us Milton Bradley style games that it's been re-released a million times.
Rym: Yeah, I think you've seen a normal toy store much like crocodile.
Scott: You should make one.
Scott: I suggest not so.
Rym: Yeah, if you go to board game geek you see all these different additions.
Rym: even the official ones are all slightly different.
Rym: But then people posted pictures of the custom sets.
Scott: They made that is a real tumbling dice, right?
Scott: Yeah, that is the highest quality tumbling dice.
Scott: Look at this.
Scott: Oh, that's like a. that's the god of tumbling die.
Rym: That is for tumbling dies.
Rym: and look it goes one, two, three four one Two three four and there's a zero hanging out each one of these places.
Scott: Whoa, they just stack tumbling dices on top of each other.
Rym: four sets of tumbling dice that they call it Niagara Falls, that is incredible.
Scott: How many but do you throw for 16 die?
Rym: Oh, it's those comments here.
Rym: So is this for real?
Rym: And the response is we played one game.
Rym: No, it doesn't work.
Rym: I guess if I were to put them on the sides instead blah blah blah blah.
Scott: Yeah, cuz as dice get further from you They're gonna spread out sideways.
Scott: trying to get him go straight down a bowling alley is pretty difficult.
Rym: I think it would work better.
Rym: I think they just were low skill.
Rym: We'll see we'll see We won't see it.
Scott: let's begin again for tumbling dice and stack them up.
Rym: but tumbling dice is.
Rym: it's in this class of games I'll actually aside from the dexterity component It's in this other like meta class of games that are good at Attracting strangers and getting them to play a game with you.
Scott: much like you can walk up to a tumbled nice Throw your four dice and I get a minute and then leave and know exactly what your score was and cheer or whatever.
Scott: and you're Good,
Rym: but we met a bunch of cool people just because like we had it out and strangers would be like, hey What do you like to walk over to watch and when you can turn to someone and be like you see this really weird thing We're doing you
Scott: want to do until you hand them for d6 and be like, you're green.
Scott: Oh, you're not green.
Scott: cuz I'm green.
Scott: Yeah, take the red dice.
Scott: Okay, then they play.
Scott: they don't need to know anything.
Rym: It's like zendo does the same thing.
Rym: You have a game that's weird and has a weird crowd around it and people are attracted to it even more than that.
Scott: Cuz the zendo and set and those sorts of things that need some sort of instruction.
Scott: tumbling dice needs nothing other than Intelligence and looking at it for a minute not even a minute less than a minute.
Rym: Yeah even the get the first packs.
Rym: we went to an oh wait in Seattle.
Rym: the game that attracted a huge crowd where he met a bunch of cool people and then had like friends for the rest of The packs was via Paletti which still required like rules and explanation but had a spectacle.
Rym: Yeah, this is the spectacle that requires no rules or explanation.
Scott: Anyway, someone dies.
Rym: Yeah, tumbling dies pretty good.
Scott: What other game do you want to talk about for?
Scott: so Viticulture viticulture is a worker placement game with a really good theme and it's not a great worker placement game.
Rym: Yep, it relies too much on cards and fiddly actions.
Rym: the cards It's imagine It's so.
Rym: it has all these mechanics.
Rym: like you get grapes and the grapes age which doesn't happen in the real world But nonetheless the grapes can age and get better over time.
Scott: You can turn them into wine which also ages.
Scott: Yeah Independently you turn and then you fill orders and you can fill orders with better wine than they asked for but you can just fill The orders and get points.
Scott: and we played it once And it was yeah, I mean, I can't make you a whole episode.
Scott: something played once but first of all We played with six players.
Scott: big mistake.
Scott: Play with four or less players because it takes forever if you play with the people who like the game.
Rym: We're like, no, no, no.
Rym: six players is bullshit.
Scott: Yeah The car.
Scott: in a curricula you start the game with a hand of cards and that's it.
Scott: in this game You basically can take actions to get different kinds of cards But then the cards are multiple actions and the cards are all over the place.
Scott: They range cards were useless garbage and some cards were ridiculously powerful.
Scott: Fuck over everyone else.
Scott: get a million points.
Rym: Yeah, like you think a potato dibber was overpowered in a curricula?
Rym: No, no, no, no.
Rym: That potato dibber is a little bit over.
Scott: the theme of the game though is ridiculously fun.
Scott: I started the game with a tasting room and every time I went with the tasting room.
Rym: I'm like, oh Yeah, I did really well despite bitten fuck by the fact that one the rules were taught slightly incorrectly because Much-like ground floor and all those other Kickstarter kind of games.
Rym: This game has some like fiddly not intuitive mechanics along the way.
Scott: But as all these custom wooden bits to represent the tasting room and my favorite the truss truss you like trusses What about?
Scott: has little has little grapes?
Scott: Hey, hey, can't hang in from it.
Scott: Yeah, that's the most useless thing.
Scott: No one built it.
Rym: No, someone used.
Rym: someone built it because they it was a mistake.
Rym: They used it to harvest once mistake.
Scott: Yeah anyway, but yeah the You know, you get all these little wooden things to represent all the like upgrades you make to your vintner facilities Which were kind of fun getting a tasting room and a truss because he's like you get to put the little wooden thing.
Scott: that has Wouldn't great, but my initial read is that I don't think it was play tested very closely like very well No, and they just took work replacement added a theme and they're like I. well they added
Rym: theme and I think I'm pretty sure the game designers Jamie Stag Meyer and Alan Stone They my guess I don't know them I don't anything about them is that they had a cool idea about a game where you get grapes and wine and the wine can Age and they kind of just and they
Scott: made the mechanics fit the theme.
Rym: they used mechanics that were you know Tried and true and they came up with clever mechanics along the way Like there's all these things and every one of them can be upgraded.
Rym: That's cool.
Scott: Yeah, they made it really match the theme and as a result the game suffers.
Rym: Yeah I'll play.
Rym: we got to play it a couple more times because it's moderately I don't need.
Scott: I mean I could play it a couple more times, but it's like I'm gonna do it.
Scott: I had enough worker placement games.
Scott: I don't need to play anymore.
Rym: so I'll say this if you trust our first impressions you can skip this one.
Scott: if You don't trust our first you really like worker placement that much that you want to play.
Rym: like every worker placement I'll play Kayla's first if you and then a curricula and then play kverna.
Scott: It's like you really have.
Scott: you have those like me.
Scott: if you have that many worker placements You really need another one.
Scott: Yeah Lord, you must really really really fucking like wine and really want to get off on the fantasy of growing what grapes and playing with A little wooden truss also, you don't make.
Rym: well Anyway, the theme actually is pretty broken if you actually know a lot about wine, so it's a little yeah.
Rym: But I mean, you know, it at least feels like wine making, you know, you get the stomping things you step on the grave Yeah, and then you can stop immediately but keep them forever and they never go bad and they get better over time after you stomp.
Scott: Yes Older is always better.
Scott: It might not actually be better, but you can sell it for more.
Rym: But if I played a few more times, I guess they could if they really wanted to be thematic There should be some more vinegar in this game Like the vinegar would be the equivalent of the brown peppers in Scoville.
Rym: Oh Yeah But it's just.
Rym: it's in that classic games that unless you're hurting for a game It's not that good.
Scott: And if you've got this game, you're so into board games.
Scott: You definitely have another worker placement game on hand.
Scott: Yeah you definitely do and you're not telling me that you're gonna in a worker placement mood and this in Viticulture is the only worker placement game that you have with you.
Rym: Like if you play this game more than four or five times period you're gonna have a really clear Specific path through this game and hope that you get the cards.
Rym: I suspect there are several degenerate strategies than like Scott hit and at the cards are literally all that matter which is also true for.
Rym: But it takes a lot longer to get to that and the cards are all pretty equally powered except the overpowered potato-dibber.
Rym: Seriously every time I draw the potato-dibber I win like every time.
Rym: So we also played each of us once in two separate games.
Rym: Elysium, okay, which had a. it had a clever mechanic.
Scott: Well, the mechanic was explained to me incorrectly Correctly as well and then it was corrected midway through the game and I still managed to win.
Rym: I came in second place because I had a ridiculous fucking combo.
Rym: I had a card that gave you you know, the classic one victory point for every three victory points Mm-hmm.
Rym: I had a way to that twice in a row at the end of the game.
Rym: Yeah, so basically the way the game where he beat me because he happened to have a card.
Rym: Oh, you don't be zillion points.
Scott: You didn't win.
Rym: He had a card that pushed him past me Okay.
Scott: But anyway, so the way the game works is you've got these four sticks of different colors and on your turn There's a whole bunch of cards out in the field.
Scott: You can basically or and there's also like these plates you can take and you spend one of your sticks to take some of the Stuff.
Scott: take something from the field, right?
Rym: But you have to have a stick on the spent of the color of the thing But you don't have to spend that one to take the thing.
Rym: so if I have a red and a green I can take something that has a red or Something that has a green on it or something that has a red or green and a colorless one showing you have to have at least two.
Rym: But then I give up any one of my sticks.
Scott: see I was told incorrectly.
Scott: the incorrect part that I was told was okay.
Scott: Look, you want to use your red to take that card.
Scott: You still have to have your red and discard one of the different non red stick.
Rym: That's what I was told too.
Scott: And that's not correct.
Scott: What you can discard the red stick and take the red card.
Rym: Oh, I was told that you could discard whatever you wanted and take the red card.
Scott: Yes, so you were told correct.
Scott: Okay, so I was told incorrectly.
Scott: I thought if I wanted to take the red card, I had to still have my red stick after Discarding one of my sticks.
Scott: so that right which was incorrect.
Scott: So I was like, you know really restricting myself early in the game.
Scott: but anyway, all the all the cards you get are Part of different Greek gods or whatever right and shit like that and actually much like viticulture.
Rym: they're all the fuck.
Rym: take seven wonders right and Expand the scope of what a card could do like ten times over right?
Rym: So basically every card was like the crazy victory point cards at the end of the game.
Scott: The way it works is when you get a card it goes on top in front of your sort of play area And when it's in front of your play area the text on the card is active.
Scott: It's like you.
Scott: it's like a building you've built in glory to Rome, right?
Scott: It does.
Scott: or a creature you summon in magic?
Scott: It does stuff.
Scott: So one strategy in the game is to get a bunch of cards out in front and use their powers combined To get a lot of points.
Scott: The other thing you can do is if you get all the cards have numbers and colors because the color goes to the god It goes with and they're numbered like one two, three four.
Scott: You can get cards in sets and like gin rummy sets like no, you know, one two, three all same.
Rym: That stuff was actually all explained to me incorrectly.
Scott: Explain to me incorrectly at all.
Rym: Yeah that part so I thought I was making a set that turned out was not a set.
Scott: Yeah, there's a little helper card that I kept looking at.
Rym: I still almost won though.
Scott: Yeah, there's a little helper card that tells you what sets you can make.
Scott: So if you build up in front of your area enough cards to make one of these sort of, you know runs You can then spend an action or there's different.
Rym: You could put them down at any time.
Rym: You can only put down another card that might like.
Rym: you have to put it into the set or make it its own set.
Rym: Cards in the front of your thing Also have a power you can do once you pull them into the back.
Rym: They can't do their powers and I pulled it But they're worth victory.
Rym: points cards in the front or with bupkis at the end of the game, right?
Scott: So it's like you when a card is in the front you use its ability To get points and do things to help you.
Scott: so like a card is on the bottom The card is disabled, but you've made a set that is now worth victory.
Rym: Here's the best way I can describe it.
Scott: And if you're the first person to make a particular kind of set you get a fuck ton of it.
Scott: Bonus points from the side.
Rym: So here's the best way I'll describe it because it's GeekNights.
Rym: You guys have played magic.
Rym: probably say I've got my land war elves.
Rym: Yeah I can give.
Rym: I have to have my green Forest stick out still to take the land where elves and I discard any stick you including that you could be the green one.
Rym: Yes, it could be anything right now.
Rym: I've got the land where elves in front of me.
Rym: I can tap them to get that mana at any point.
Rym: I have some power now.
Rym: It's a power I can just use on my turn or if you get two more elves At any point on my turns I can use my power to pull the land war elves back.
Rym: Once they're pulled back I can never tap them again.
Scott: I don't think it's any time.
Scott: I don't only played it once and I remember that well.
Scott: But I thought you could like only move a certain number of things according to.
Scott: yeah, you have a.
Rym: it's like a Dominion You know, I don't know.
Scott: I didn't think it was any time on your turn either.
Rym: I thought oh, it's when you have that action right there.
Rym: I'm skipping a lot of those fiddly.
Scott: So there's a limit to how many things you can pull.
Rym: there is an economy, you know what it's like.
Rym: It's like the merchant and glory to Rome.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Scott: You have to take that action to move stuff down.
Rym: Sometimes you get two of that action or three Exactly and the game actually goes really quick and you have very few turns.
Rym: Yeah, you pretty much gotta pull something back every turn.
Rym: You're fucked Yep, but so the land where elves are out in front of you at the end of the game.
Rym: You could have tapped them on that last turn but you get zero points for them if they're pulled back by the end of the Game, they couldn't be tapped once they have pulled back But they're worth a victory point.
Rym: if you got three land where elves they're worth like nine victory points.
Rym: and if you got a land where elf and something that caused two and a war elephant and What I'm trying to think of creatures with those Then it'll be worth another set of points and at the end of the game most points wins.
Rym: I Don't think it's a good game.
Scott: I don't think it's good either.
Rym: It's got a lot of clever mechanics, but they're not intuitive.
Rym: there's too many of them and just like Viticulture like it like it's a lot like when you play it seven wonders But seven wonders.
Rym: the card colors have a pretty constrained set of things they can do Such that they can be represented by a relatively simple system of icons.
Scott: This that you have to look up every time you play true, but at least that gives you some parameters.
Rym: this game Imagine one cards like get three gold and another card is a paragraph of bullshit.
Rym: You can do.
Rym: Yeah, it's So all over the place that unless you have memorized every single card in the game.
Rym: You cannot have a strategy.
Scott: So what I did is I basically found a card and I won the game.
Scott: by the way The one I played.
Scott: I found a card that was like hey take a card that's out in front of you throw it away and take a random card from the deck and Put it in front of you to replace.
Rym: I got that same car.
Scott: I basically took all my other cards and made perfect sets and kept putting them behind as quickly as possible.
Scott: Cuz that's the direct path to victory points, right?
Scott: I kept getting the bonus shits.
Scott: cuz I was the first one to do so and then I kept that one card out there and kept using it once a turn cuz that's as much as I could use it.
Scott: and You get these guys that are like wild cards if you move them back, but they're also negative victory points.
Rym: Oh, yeah, the citizens.
Scott: I kept discarding the citizens with that power to go and get new cards that weren't citizens.
Scott: and You know, it's like I'm just getting free cards all over the place.
Rym: Oh, I did it.
Rym: I did a thing that basically I could tap these guys.
Scott: I basically scored like six points by throwing away three citizens and then scored another set of points.
Scott: cuz that got me a set of Cards, I got like 20 or 30 points for my bullshit combo of.
Rym: I got some cards that I could keep tapping.
Rym: Just keep getting victory points.
Scott: I had 15 points just from bonus each.
Rym: It's I had like 40 from bonus each.
Rym: It's Yeah at the end of the game I had like 60 something from bonus chits because I don't nobody else's getting any points.
Rym: I did I basically did things to get a ton of bonus chits Because I got a card that gave me a point for every three bonus point.
Scott: Oh, no, I'm talking about those ones.
Scott: I'm talking about the ones where like the first one to get a black set.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: I got two of those.
Scott: Yeah, those the regular victory point shits.
Scott: I only had a moderate number of.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I didn't go hard on that.
Rym: There's so many other mechanics in this game that I Unless I showed you a bunch of examples.
Rym: I could not teach this to you without visual aids.
Scott: I do think though that you could take the stick mechanic.
Scott: Yeah and apply that to a different game.
Scott: That would be interesting.
Rym: stick mechanic was extra good because it had the.
Rym: if you get fucked and can't take anything You have to take a citizen they kind of suck and it also sort of forced you into like not it.
Scott: You couldn't just pick the thing you wanted right.
Scott: a lot of worker placement games.
Scott: It's like you have a worker.
Scott: put it on one of the workplaces here.
Scott: It's like you have a red or green a blue and a yellow and they're all different and if you use you know You can.
Scott: if you have the red one You can still do red actions But you're gonna give up the right to do a green yellow every turn you say this this set of the cards out there I cannot take.
Scott: yeah So and as you take more and more actions The number of actions still available to you is more and more limited which it does.
Rym: this power like this mechanic Heavily reduces analysis paralysis because every choice you take closes a whole bunch of doors.
Scott: And it's just it's not even like you.
Scott: the doors are actually closed.
Scott: You just don't realize it.
Scott: It's like no they are closed.
Scott: You cannot do that.
Rym: So you get in a situation of like I want I want to take I want to discard my red one but if I do Scott could do.
Rym: take the red the one of the other actions like the final action.
Rym: You know the thing that you have to take one of the adventure or whatever Fucking me and forcing me to not be able to take one.
Scott: All right, let's talk about let's not Let's talk about.
Rym: not I know you're gonna talk about the other mechanics.
Scott: No, let's be done with Elysium.
Rym: Yeah, Elysium I think is the worst of the games.
Rym: we talked about a lot of clever ideas.
Scott: It's not a game.
Scott: I want to play.
Scott: I have no desire to ever play Elysium again once again.
Rym: I don't hate it But I don't have a desire to design a game and the core of your and it has a bunch of clear specific simple or interesting mechanics.
Rym: But you have a side mechanic of a lot of cards with a lot of paragraphs of text on them.
Rym: Your game is probably poorly designed.
Scott: It better be.
Scott: it better be a card game Yep, and you don't realize it's poorly designed because the like Dominion or something.
Rym: Yep all that text on the cards is Obfuscating the bad design.
Rym: seven wonders is just that.
Rym: like that is the game.
Rym: those cards.
Scott: sushi goes even better.
Rym: sushi goes great anyway.
Rym: things of the day.
Scott: I think I used this as a thing of the day already, but Rym says I did not.
Rym: I don't think you did.
Scott: I think I did but I'll do it again.
Rym: Anyway, so I forgot what my thing of the day was.
Rym: you do your thing?
Rym: Oh, I remember I remember.
Scott: here is a video of some Russian gentlemen and They found while fishing or something or I don't know what the hell they're doing.
Scott: They found a can of rations from the war as in 1940 something Soviet rations in a can.
Rym: Is this like that guy who found that beer in his gutter?
Scott: and they open that can and they dig right in these happy old Russian dudes.
Rym: There's some sort of meat like material in this can Watch at your own risk Alright that this sounds a lot like that video the guy who found a buy a can of beer in his gutter from the 80s And tried to chug it.
Scott: I think that one is actually worse than this one, but that one though is the least funny because of how immediate.
Rym: So that video spoilers not Scott's video projectile.
Scott: vomiting.
Rym: The guy throws the his head back to drink the beer and vomits so fast That it's almost a violation of the speed of light and causality.
Scott: Like the vomit comes out like as soon as the beer like it's near his face It's whole stomach just turns Back.
Rym: that before the beer even got into his mouth.
Rym: The brain was like, whoa, whoa, whoa, what the hell are you doing?
Scott: Everything from digestive system in both directions.
Rym: So if you're ever in New York City It had there's a thing in a few streets aren't that many of these that very few cities in the world have Let alone in New York where they're super rare.
Rym: Sometimes you'll see it's really really tall building and There'll be another really really tall building and there will be a sky bridge connecting the two of them.
Scott: If you sky bridges around this guy.
Scott: some of them are like clothes like you can actually get into them Even if you're in the building, it's just too hard to tear them down.
Rym: There's a few that are used out there Yeah, but not many because in cities like there are a lot of sky bridges.
Rym: in mid-tier cities like in Boston You'll see him because they connect like a mall to another mall and stuff like that Yeah, or a hotel to the office building next to it.
Rym: but in New York the few of these things that remain are usually connecting like Private building to private building that are not both owned by the same people anymore And there's no public way in the world to get into these things and you probably wouldn't want to anyway.
Rym: So there's one that I'd seen often like I passed by this thing a lot and I recognized it.
Rym: I saw that I saw a picture of it.
Rym: There's article in Gothamist about it.
Rym: Apparently it connected an apartment To a fashion studio because the guy who lived in the apartment ran the fashion studio.
Rym: Okay, and it's really big and cool and old.
Rym: By coincidence right now The fashion studio was turned into an apartment.
Rym: So it's two apartments on my two totally different sets of people.
Rym: They're both for sale.
Scott: So you could buy both.
Rym: if you buy both you get the sky bridge Sure, and apparently the sky you only buy one.
Scott: you get half the sky bridge.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I guess that one.
Rym: I guess one building owns it so you just don't get it like the door.
Rym: Okay, like I don't know how that works.
Rym: But yeah You could buy these two apartments and you get an extra room above the street in New York City.
Scott: I mean you can afford that.
Scott: call me I would buy this apartment if I could because if I could afford one of them I would buy it and someone else could buy the other one like you and then we'd have the sky bridge.
Rym: Yeah a sky bridge.
Rym: Do you know what I could do with the sky bridge?
Scott: one shot walk across the street without getting hit by a car.
Rym: That would be just an egg one.
Rym: I've got.
Rym: I live in two buildings.
Rym: That's cool enough to you get.
Scott: you could have mail sent to here or there.
Scott: Wouldn't be hard to get the mail what I do.
Scott: You could have delivery to either one if you.
Scott: oh, I'm in the kitchen now.
Scott: I really like delivery to come here.
Scott: Oh, I'm in the bedroom.
Scott: I'll just send the delivery to a different address.
Rym: Oh There's an update The so date line.
Rym: according to the listing the units are exclusively off for sale together.
Rym: If the first time I've been over 30 years the residence is six thousand three hundred square feet Combined.
Scott: Okay, that's It's pretty York plenty.
Rym: You'd live in that.
Scott: I'm good.
Scott: I'll take it.
Rym: Yeah third floor level stable street.
Scott: So yeah, who's got the monies?
Scott: bring it up.
Rym: Let's do it.
Rym: guys You want us to do more.
Rym: ten of videos, right?
Scott: Yeah Buy us this antenna like living situation.
Rym: if you buy us this apartment I will make videos for you 40 hours a week for the next 20 years with good sky bridge lighting.
Rym: Yeah, we'll make the videos in the sky bridge.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: So the best game we played Apax Was another Friedman freeze game.
Scott: who's actually one of our Friedman freeze if you don't know is the power grid.
Scott: guy Yep, and all his games come in a green box and all his games are have a name.
Scott: That is two words that begin with F.
Rym: Power grid was translated for German.
Scott: the German name of power grid is two words that begin with F. Don't get on me about this non German speakers.
Rym: Yeah, I'll cast elk fast, right?
Scott: We played a Friedman freeze game that is not new, but we hadn't played it before.
Scott: We played it maybe three or four times at packs.
Scott: Yep, and that game is fresh fish fresh fish.
Rym: Our joke at PAX was saying it increasingly like that just as the weekend went on, right?
Scott: So the way fresh fish works, it's pretty simple game On the board.
Scott: There are these four.
Rym: well, it's simple.
Rym: But
Scott: yes there are four food trucks and You are have four carts one cart per truck and you want to get your fish cart as close to the fish truck as you Can and you want to get your soda truck your soda cart as close to the soda truck as you can.
Scott: that way?
Scott: you know the food delivery comes in the truck.
Scott: you sell the food out of your cart and The food that you sell be fresher than the food other people sell because the delivery took less time to get to your store theme than other people's stores.
Rym: barely even Comes close to making sense.
Scott: No, it makes no sense whatsoever.
Rym: But especially when you see the game who would be?
Scott: I really like the art.
Scott: The art is good.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Scott: It's that kind of.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's almost like a garbage pail kids style but cuter and kid.
Rym: Yeah, like the.
Scott: I know what the name for it is, but I've seen it around that I really like it Particularly like the fish.
Rym: actually the fish is okay, but the your score at the end is How the combined total of how many spaces away from each cart or from each truck?
Scott: Your respective cart is now due to the rules of the game You have to be at least one space away.
Scott: So like you could get a four because each you masterfully got every cart one space away from every truck.
Rym: Yeah, so that already is a pretty solid mechanic for like a simple but complex game.
Rym: to add to that The way you play is you put Reservation tokens out on your turn.
Rym: you either draw tile from the bag Which we'll talk about or you put a reservation token out.
Rym: The reality is you put reservation tokens out for a long time.
Rym: You've got six of them and you just keep putting them out.
Scott: You could go really risky and go to the bag early if someone but if you go to the bag when you don't have a lot Of tokens out you're pretty much just hurting yourself.
Scott: So it really they get the rules of the games sometimes But usually if you don't have a lot of tokens on the board you're almost definitely going to hurt yourself, so there's not a lot of incentive to just go straight for the bag and Hoping you'll fuck someone else instead of and luckily not fuck yourself.
Rym: Like you'll know when with people who've played this game before if someone goes to the bag early a hush falls over the crowd.
Rym: It's like oh, you're going in that bag with like two tokens.
Rym: I'm gonna put that card.
Rym: We're gonna write that car.
Scott: It's like you don't have any reservation token anywhere near the fish.
Scott: What if you pull the fish out of that bag?
Scott: You are just fuck.
Rym: Yep So here's the other main mechanic.
Rym: you have 14 chips or 15 chips some number of chips that you want their money.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and you want a low score.
Scott: obviously It's golf low store.
Rym: The chips are negative points and you bid them When a cart of a particular type comes up, right?
Scott: So someone reaches in the bag and pulls out the fish card Which means it's time for somebody to put out a fish cart.
Rym: closed fist auction Whoever bid the most puts their cart out, right?
Scott: So you everyone's got reservation tokens near the fish.
Scott: everyone does a closed fist auction.
Scott: See who bids the most and then that person gets to put their replace one of their reservation tokens with the fish cart.
Rym: That is theirs now because we're all pro.
Rym: I mean Chris and Anthony who are pretty pro.
Scott: They owe the game.
Rym: Yeah, they're literally.
Rym: they weren't playing nothing But they played mostly Friedman Freese games because they also had familiar with them.
Rym: but so in pro mode what you'll see if someone fucks up is Everybody bid zero because the person who drew the tile wins because they break a tie that way and that's why it's very dangerous.
Scott: And they're all yours.
Rym: Oh the tile out Your fish cart.
Rym: you only have one token up.
Rym: Oh, I guess you're getting max score on the fish car, right?
Scott: It's like so Rym goes in the bag thinking.
Scott: Hey, hey, hey, I'll pull out a card and screw these guys.
Scott: I don't have a lot of tokens out, but I'll screw them over.
Scott: you pull out the fish cart.
Scott: Everyone sees that your token is like on the other side of the board far away from the fish.
Scott: Everyone bid zero.
Scott: Rym now must put his fish cart on that faraway token and it's worth a million points.
Rym: yeah, Scott might be like seven eight nine away from one, but you max out at like 14 if you can't get there.
Rym: Mm-hmm and Basically the way it works Mechanically.
Rym: other than that auction thing is what you place these little reservation things and when something comes out There's areas of the board numbers of squares.
Rym: They're sort of surrounded and they have a one or two next to them.
Rym: That means there can only be one or two things in that space.
Rym: so if Scott puts a Blocking tile on one of the spaces in a two area because he had a reservation thing there and I put my cart on Another one in that area Everything else in that entire area becomes roads and anyone else who had a reservation token there just gets kicked the fuck out.
Scott: So me and Rym we both put our reservation tokens in this area really close to the cheese.
Scott: I win the cheese auction to put my cheese down.
Scott: It's a one area.
Scott: Now Rym loses his reservation token.
Scott: if another cheese auction happens that can be bad news bears for Rym who doesn't have any reservation tokens near the cheese now.
Scott: and If I lost the auction, oh bad for me.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So to make matters even worse the carts you put out or the blocking tiles you put out block.
Rym: you have to follow a road.
Rym: So we kind of played bastard mode where we had carts that were kind of trucks that were near each other Many games in a row a cart got entirely walled off from the entire board And you know what?
Rym: The answer is in this game max score.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: Yeah the the answer to any question What if I do this is you're fucked?
Scott: Yeah, you can.
Scott: it's like what?
Scott: if I can't I can connect But I have to go off the edge of the board.
Scott: It's like oh you can actually do that.
Scott: Yeah, it's two spaces for every edge of board space you use so that costs you like.
Scott: oh, it's max score.
Scott: You're too far away.
Rym: this game Looks really simple like a light fun game.
Rym: It is one of the most brutal like short multi It is I've ever played.
Scott: cutthroat ist of Placing carts and picnic flea market stand.
Rym: This is a. this is a game where four or five people will do a closed Fix fist auction.
Scott: everyone opens and everyone immediately closes all their fingers, but one yeah After seeing what the other people had in their hand.
Rym: the game has two phases effectively the posturing phase and the fucking phase.
Rym: There's really nothing else to this game.
Scott: fresh fish fuck.
Scott: So the thing about this game that I noticed though, is that I won.
Rym: every time I played I think I won a few times But I want to be times - I think I played twice in one.
Scott: twice every time you played I wanna I want.
Scott: you did win more often than me anyway, but what I was doing to that made a difference was When I was putting my reservation tokens.
Scott: I was trying to put them in such a way to where no auction result could fuck me and As long as I eventually got the auction which is gonna happen eventually at the end of the game every cart will have been placed.
Scott: No matter what I would have my cart in a good position.
Scott: So that way I didn't have to bid a lot in the auctions.
Scott: like a cheese auction would come up And I'd be like you know what if I won this cheese auction.
Scott: Yeah, that would be a good thing.
Scott: however If I lose the cheese auction It's not really gonna hurt me at all because I placed my marker in such a clever place that it's gonna get a good score.
Scott: However, I can't really be bumped out easily.
Rym: I saw you with that strategy, and it worked very well.
Scott: times.
Rym: Anthony found a pretty good counter to that strategy by bagging earlier and putting markets out Blockers and just knocking my backup guy also off the board before the end of the game
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and then I have got max score on two carts and lost by a lot instead of winning by a lot.
Scott: Yeah So I was able to with my strategy Not have to bid a lot in the auctions and usually there would be one auction during the game where I couldn't avoid bidding a lot and I would bid a lot and I'd win that important auction and Then all of my carts would be like one two three not a lot of points at all And I just had a ridiculously good score.
Rym: Yeah, I'm the first time I played which I did win.
Rym: my strategy was well.
Rym: I've got these tokens if not now than when my goal is to spend all of them And it works really well.
Scott: It's yeah.
Scott: I mean if you spend all your tokens and you don't care about bidding a lot you're gonna have great placements and you usually Getting great placements.
Scott: your score is gonna be like less than five six something like that, but I have seen negative scores sure But you know that's a. that's a terrific score though in a four player game.
Scott: Right where someone's getting like a 15 on something in a five player game.
Rym: I saw one where someone won with like 13 like right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like you're gonna have one bad car is gives you ruin everything.
Scott: So, you know if you spend all your tokens you get four get all your carts in good positions.
Scott: That's a good score.
Scott: if you get one bad position, but you didn't spend anything in the auctions That's also gonna be a good score.
Scott: All right, so there's a lot of different ways You can approach it and still turn out well.
Rym: But the real the game is real quick to teach real quick to play Really really satisfying.
Rym: there's some randomness elements to it.
Rym: Well
Scott: turn order matters a lot forgetting the good positions
Rym: but it is really
Scott: fun like the turn order actually helped me quite a bit because every time I had at the beginning of the game every time like a Position in mind like for my marker and every time I got to my turn 90% of the time that position was still open.
Scott: because turn order.
Rym: Yep But the game has a very high fun economy as in the amount of fun per minutes It takes to play is a very high value.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: And there's also so it's a Friedman freeze game.
Rym: So it actually has two versions of the rules.
Rym: We were playing the like newer updated version, but there is an older version more streamlined version.
Rym: Yeah The difference between the two is basically in the version that we were playing the one that most people would play When you fill a place then the roads go in.
Rym: but in the original weird rules It's kind of like battle line.
Rym: you only fill in roads by deduction By fruit like all places have to be connected to all places.
Rym: So once you show that they're like you have to place a road here or that breaks.
Rym: then roads start appearing and stuff starts happening.
Rym: Yeah, we did not actually play that way because the proper way is great.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So also the former way is kind of more diggish because in the in the ease in the older way in the very least Everything's connected.
Rym: But the way we were playing with the newer rules You could very easily entirely wall something off and make the game horror.
Scott: very intentionally people would get picked flea market stands and line them up in a diagonal impossible to cross by any means so that it's like.
Scott: well the people on this Side of these flea market stands can have good scores on cheese.
Scott: Everyone who's done who isn't already on this side your cheese scores at minimum gonna be like eight And that's if you get that one spot there everyone else 15 get fine.
Rym: You're gonna look those other people in the eye as you place that cart Flipping them off and high-fiving the person who's on the good side with you.
Scott: I frequently.
Scott: another part of my strategy was to specifically put markers and places.
Scott: I wanted a flea market stands Yeah, and then go in the bag and actively try to get flea market stands to fuck people up and it worked.
Rym: It's a super fun game If I would highly like.
Rym: it's also really tiny if you're a board gamer at all.
Rym: Just own it.
Rym: It's a perfect game to have in your repertoire like keeping and it's not like it doesn't?
Scott: it's not like any other game.
Scott: The closest game I can think to this would be Through the desert.
Scott: No.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not.
Rym: it actually takes a long time, right?
Scott: It's not really even it's.
Scott: it's similar to through the desert, but it's not.
Scott: it's not close enough to where they're like displacing each other Right.
Scott: It's like there's no other game that you have.
Scott: that is like this game where you wouldn't want this on your shelf But through the desert takes.
Rym: so it takes twice as long to play as this game and it's not as good.
Rym: Yeah, so like this is a kind of game that I would just carry in my backpack at a convention right alongside Like elk fest and those other little games that I carry around and wizard.
Scott: Mm-hmm There you go.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: fresh fish fresh fish.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.