Rym: It's Thursday January 8th 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We gonna have us some fun with predator.
Scott: the Predator really got the deer.
Rym: the predator Let's do this Got a wave of what someone in a group of friends of ours has not seen.
Rym: a perhaps important movie like a Robocop a Predator a Terminator 2 had a wave of it's cold.
Scott: Holy shit is all today.
Rym: Yeah, so I know there's a guy I know who biked to work a couple days ago What's up, and then he couldn't bike home because it was too cold so his bikes just sitting at his office.
Scott: Yeah, I saw a guy today.
Scott: I was like how to bike to work in the snow, and I was like all right.
Scott: What are you doing?
Rym: It's like zero degrees out and the answer is stay home or spend a lot of money.
Scott: also part of the advice was leave Your eyes for dead, and I was like nope.
Rym: Yeah Well the thing is you just got to go slow and you gotta have special tires most.
Scott: It's not how about we just use a subway.
Scott: Yeah, I had a bike to work.
Scott: carry your bike onto the subway.
Rym: Subway has been kind of shitty lately.
Rym: It's fine for me.
Rym: It's yeah, cuz you don't go anywhere you go like right across on going to work.
Scott: Can I go home?
Rym: yep?
Rym: But going downtown has been getting pretty bad because it all the people are gonna go there or whatever.
Rym: They're all taking the subway now, and it's cold.
Rym: It's all the people like me.
Scott: you're also taking the subway And so you are the problem.
Rym: yes I am and you know what all those other people need to get fired.
Rym: Oh, the people who are the same as you because if they all got fired You know what the people who don't bike in the summer Should not be allowed to ride the subway the way you get to ride the subway for six months out of the air max.
Rym: How's that?
Rym: Whatever you say I can live with that.
Rym: I could do that.
Rym: So yeah, anyway got any news being Thursday being the lounge.
Scott: It's not lunch anyway, so I'm lounging.
Scott: we're not going to magfest.
Rym: ah no we are not.
Rym: it's the first magfest since we realized magfest was awesome.
Rym: that was worth going to.
Rym: and The only reason we're not is because Pac South is Literally the same weekend in all honesty.
Scott: It looks like magfest is gonna be better Yeah, but then again in terms of what the convention provides.
Rym: It's like the first packs.
Rym: Australia like it was kind of The first pack.
Scott: south is gonna be small.
Scott: yo
Rym: yep, I mean I saw how many panel rooms they have and I was like okay Yeah, we'll just do one right and but at the same time the smallest panel room It packs out is still bigger than the panel rooms at magfest, so it's kind of a wash.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, so I just want to talk about magfest.
Scott: not you know while it's an awesome convention Does not really have their shit together, and they didn't announce their musical lineup until just now.
Rym: yeah The panels were just recently scheduled to.
Scott: So I just want to point out the awesomest thing in the schedule besides the return of machine supremacy Which gives me hope they'll just return again next year, and they should just move here.
Scott: sure You know the typical guys you always see on there like power glove the Megas DJ cut man.
Scott: It's a you know all the all.
Scott: the usual crowd is there, but the headlining featured performer About at the top of the list.
Scott: the guest of honor is you Miyake?
Scott: Do you know whom you Miyake is?
Rym: I actually do not.
Scott: you Miyake is the DJ and composer of the?
Scott: Katamari series.
Rym: oh Yeah, that's pretty awesome right there were I not going to PAX South.
Rym: I would be at that concert.
Rym: Fact I know some people who might suddenly decide to go to magfest because of that.
Scott: I Say I saw the the only person who could beat that I already saw at magfest which was I forget your name Streets of Rage composer.
Scott: oh yeah best video game music except for Megaman 2 music.
Rym: So yeah if you want to go to PAX South I guess it's sold out.
Rym: if you want to go to magfest I don't think it's sold out yet packs.
Scott: east also is very very soon after pack and it is also sold out.
Rym: so Oh my god.
Rym: all these conventions the ConnectiCon is coming up in July.
Rym: Let's not do the meta moment at the news But I was just talking about conventions didn't mean about us doing things at those conventions.
Scott: My news is just this Headlining magfest act.
Rym: yeah, all right, so I got some news.
Rym: I was gonna do this on a Monday, but I kind of wanted so much CES news.
Scott: now We got tons of money exactly.
Rym: so I'm pulling this in because it's also relevant to a Thursday.
Rym: It's relevant to the lounge your mom.
Rym: so the other day I was I went on LinkedIn because in the kind of job that I do.
Rym: I actually have to like go to LinkedIn and like I see an email from a person go look up to figure out like what?
Rym: It is that they do.
Scott: and like I do get emails and people you don't know and use LinkedIn to find out who the fuck They are exactly like.
Rym: yeah I actually know this person.
Rym: my ways of what I do is first I flip through my business cards that I scan and be like Okay, have I ever met this person?
Rym: as the answer is no I look him up on LinkedIn and see if their picture rings a bell.
Rym: if I don't know who they are then I have a Picture.
Rym: yeah, believe it.
Rym: but and then I saw that it was telling me like it always does in that Ridiculous stupid news feed that I can't believe.
Rym: people use where it's like a social network for people who have nothing better I can't believe people do.
Rym: now granted.
Rym: You know what's fucked up.
Rym: I post stuff in there all the time like whenever I'd post a geek dies episode or anything.
Rym: I just copy/paste it in there too because whatever and I get a lot of like Emails and a lot of like messages and things about like GeekNights and things.
Rym: It's really weird like people who uh like board game fans a couple of like Video game journalists editor types of message me a couple times.
Scott: They follow you on LinkedIn.
Rym: Well, I find LinkedIn with people that I know okay.
Rym: Yeah, so anyway, I see one of those ridiculous messages.
Rym: Hey, why don't you say happy work anniversary to your good friend who just started work?
Rym: Just worked x-years on today's date CJ Henderson.
Rym: Oh yeah, CJ Henderson died some time ago actually and that was a Slightly depressing moment to see that they're like, oh, hey LinkedIn doesn't know.
Rym: you're dead and everyone, you know on LinkedIn just got reminded that you're dead in a kind of funny but also sad way.
Rym: internet so independently.
Rym: Facebook just recently Apologized.
Scott: I don't mean the same goddamn thing.
Rym: So yeah fate.
Rym: no Facebook did something even more interesting.
Rym: It was a great idea what Facebook did.
Rym: Facebook basically for people who had taken photos and things like, you know throughout the year For every individual person on Facebook where it had enough stuff it sent you like.
Rym: hey Here's your year in review.
Rym: and for someone like me like awesome.
Rym: That's that convention.
Rym: I went to.
Rym: that's that picture my dick I took by accident.
Rym: That's that wedding.
Rym: But for some people yeah, that's when my son or daughter a significant other died.
Rym: Oh, that's my pet who isn't around anymore here in review is horrifying.
Rym: Yeah, so People were really traumatized by Basically technology showing them what actually happened in their life for the last year in 2014.
Scott: Well, it started off that time.
Scott: He got sick.
Scott: Yeah, and that vacation that was really bad.
Scott: The person you broke up with and then You know all this horribleness and then the horribleness in the news that you read tweeted or whatever that horrible photos associated with it.
Rym: and Yeah, one of the examples here is pretty tragic Eric Meyer web design.
Scott: You went to see this movie.
Rym: a web designer consultant writer is one of the people.
Rym: earlier this year He lost his daughter to brain cancer on her birthday.
Rym: She was six.
Rym: for that reason He had actively avoided looking at previews of his own automatically generated summarized summary posts.
Rym: But Facebook put a personalized prompt advertising a feature in his newsfeed which prominently featured his dead daughter and a happy birthday.
Rym: It added clip art figures to the picture like it was a birthday like it would it was.
Rym: I looked at a page kind of Like.
Rym: it looks like the kind of thing that a an asshole would do as a mean thing to another person But it's just automatic.
Scott: It looks at the date.
Scott: It has a photo associated with the date It was written in there.
Scott: as it goes up exactly hurt this person's birthday.
Scott: I have a photo of them.
Scott: They're associated with this person.
Scott: The problem is why don't these systems just have a way to mark someone as dead?
Scott: then it was.
Rym: that's why I wanted to Everything on Monday.
Rym: I wanted to talk about how Technology and the Internet and society have moved so fast that Nothing we have in place nothing modern all the new stuff we use almost everything in our lives has no way to deal with us Dying like right now.
Rym: It was the computer doesn't care.
Rym: computers never gonna die exactly so like weird stuff.
Scott: So I think no one wants to install that.
Scott: because imagine going into your like You know settings and it says click here if this person is dead and seeing that there Everyone no one believes they're gonna die even though they know they're gonna die.
Scott: I mean even us are hoping for our ghost in the shell brain uploads.
Scott: We're like no We don't need to have a death option on tweets.
Scott: I'm gonna upload my brain.
Rym: I know there's a moment of the venture.
Rym: brothers were a guy.
Rym: There's a there's a wizard guy And he says something like like what would you like?
Rym: What do you want to do if you want to really hurt someone?
Rym: he's like I'll tell me the exact moment of their death And then later on like way later another episode a guy's being kind of a dick, and he just turns to him.
Rym: He's like Three years eight months one day from now of an aneurysm, and the guy's like what?
Scott: Mm-hmm but Great next week skiing.
Rym: Yeah, actually.
Rym: I'm skiing on Saturday.
Scott: That's I'm saying so
Rym: that I Don't know really what to say or do about this issue because I don't think it should be an issue In the sense that if you have social media Your own media being reflected back at you is something that you have to sort of expect.
Rym: I Mean if you're if tragedy happens in your life And you've uploaded pictures to flicker do you just not go to your own flicker for the next year or two?
Rym: Maybe you do, but then you also shouldn't have gone to Facebook like I don't could.
Scott: I could just be like hey Ram go my flicker and delete any photos of so-and-so.
Rym: But isn't that even asking someone to do that could be pretty traumatic.
Rym: in fact that might even say worse like hey Go delete all the pictures of my dead daughter.
Rym: Oh wait like deleting her.
Rym: oh no sadness feels.
Rym: so It's weird to me that people are so mad about this.
Rym: But is that just the privilege of having a tragedy for not having a daughter or one who is dead?
Rym: Yes, having no tragedy in my life Just do people just have to Adapt to the fact that their lives up to this point in social media will be pretty much Constantly reflected back at them like a mirror for the rest of eternity.
Rym: Do we just have to evolve that out of ourselves like?
Rym: I don't know what to do about it?
Scott: Just wait until you face some tragedy, and then bring it up again.
Rym: Yeah, well I could talk about my stepdad.
Rym: There was some tragedy.
Scott: Yeah, he's alive though.
Rym: He is alive, but that's that's still some tragedy.
Scott: Yeah Maybe I was a long time ago already.
Rym: Yeah, it was still kickin.
Rym: It's actually impressive for a lot for lying in the desert for an unknown number of hours with his brain leaking out of his skull bleeding in the desert and Then like being found and then hours later still helicopters, and yeah, it's basically a miracle.
Rym: That is the doctor was like.
Rym: that's crazy.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So yeah, I thought that was an interesting issue that a lot of people don't think about.
Rym: so Considering that it was just recently said comic week on cyanide and happiness my advice to you is Every time you take a picture, and you post it to Facebook Imagine how you'll feel when that picture is the subject of tragedy.
Rym: I'm sure that will make you completely immune to actual tragedy.
Rym: That's also probably terrible advice stoicism.
Rym: I approve But anyway things of the day while ago.
Rym: I tweeted I don't think I made this a thing of the day, but it was just.
Rym: it's a very internet video And I'm just gonna describe it because describing it almost makes it seem weirder.
Rym: So it's Luna or the Celestia though the main pony the powerful pony for ponies.
Scott: I've made a comeback.
Scott: When's that season for coming?
Rym: Oh my god?
Rym: I think spring it's coming soon.
Scott: There's also you know I completely forgot ponies exist.
Rym: Yeah, because there hasn't been any ponies, and I really want nothing to do with most of the fandom anymore.
Rym: So I gotta just ignore all that stuff.
Scott: I mean the comics don't know.
Rym: well the comics are amazing.
Scott: Maybe if you gave me the comics there go dig him out.
Scott: I lent to you.
Rym: I bought the trades cuz that's just better.
Scott: But I started with the issues Finish with them.
Rym: I can't change, but anyway.
Rym: This is this was a video that I found a while ago.
Rym: That is just princess Celestia lip-syncing to a song called marry France.
Rym: okay by Perry and Kingsley.
Rym: all right and She's got this vibrato hoof going on.
Rym: and then weird motion graphics happen weird recursive It's just weird recursive motion graphics and a vibrato hoof.
Rym: This is that same thing with insanely high production values and an actual good joke at the end Mmm, so I'd say just watch it and hopefully like us you will suddenly be reminded that ponies is coming back relatively soon.
Scott: alright, so Rims favorite thing in the world to do is to annoy people with sound.
Scott: He'll make an annoying sound or at least they'll just make sounds and once he finds out that they're annoying someone He's like he's like a dowsing rod.
Scott: He's searching for a sound that annoys people and once he homes in on it, and he finds it He says aha.
Scott: I found one that annoys you.
Scott: let me repeat it and never stop repeating it.
Scott: Yeah As long as I may lose this is no dude you may not.
Scott: so the problem the thing is he doesn't actually have a dowsing Rod.
Rym: he relies on your body Signaling that you're annoyed and it is you must not signal it is rims gambit because if you express displeasure I know that I'm succeeding and I continue.
Rym: if you tell me you're fine, and it doesn't bother you I trust you, and I trust that you wouldn't lie to me about that.
Rym: So I keep doing it because you obviously don't care.
Scott: so if you find us something that can annoy Rym That is like worth more than flat.
Rym: I think Scott actually might have fucking found my kryptonite all right.
Scott: So there's this girl named Lizzie.
Scott: at least that's her stage name.
Scott: Oh my god Her real name is some Korean name and Lizzie is ridiculously.
Scott: She's like the awesomest person so like she was on running man way back for like the earliest days of running man for like some Small number of episodes, but and she's in some kpop group called after school.
Scott: That's actually kind of lame, but she's also in the Incredibly awesome kpop group orange caramel, which are the people who do them.
Rym: I just noticed what the title of this video is right.
Scott: She's in that you know the girls who do the fish dance with the sushi.
Scott: Oh, yeah, yeah, she's one of them.
Scott: Yeah, she's also like starting solo stuff.
Scott: She's like all over the place.
Scott: She's crazy awesome, but back in the day She was in some sitcom.
Scott: Then it was basically like think of it like it looks like Saved by the Bell.
Scott: Yeah, it's Superficial it's winning from a distance more like boy meets world like something that would be on like TGIF Way back in the day that kind of sitcom.
Scott: yeah, right for like teens to watch.
Scott: She was on that kind of show way back in the day, and she had a catchphrase, which is I It's a ing I.
Rym: She actually or and she makes like a moe be motion when she does it to write like sideways V.
Scott: So orange caramel actually has a song eyeing right that guess.
Scott: that goes with this catchphrase.
Scott: So you can watch the music video for that if you want.
Scott: Someone went through the sitcom and cut out every part.
Scott: where Lizzie goes I that ET.
Scott: Yes, you should watch.
Scott: you should watch that You should watch.
Rym: I'm just gonna click on me mute.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: You should watch that part, so Yeah, this video is a epic because you see every possible eyeing and also be it's nightmare mode.
Scott: It's nightmare.
Scott: you can the title of the videos.
Scott: eyeing nightmare mode.
Scott: you can annoy the fuck out of pretty much anyone you want Just by playing this so that someone's bothering you just turn this shit on.
Scott: Also, it's good for a few situations and internet threads.
Scott: you need to reply to a thread with a good video You know.
Rym: oh, that's getting posted.
Rym: Yeah, that that's.
Rym: I'm gonna add that to my list of videos that I'm just waiting for the excuse to post in the for you Know like something's happening.
Scott: It's like one person pulls out like the one with all the Rockets coming out Yeah, and another person has like the.
Scott: you know the guy walking and plopping down the chair to sit in the popcorn.
Rym: That guy's that's one of my favorite animated gifs.
Scott: right and then you go with the eyeing bomb and it's all good Success.
Rym: so in the meta moment the book club book is watership down.
Rym: It's about rabbits who go on a dangerous and dark journey, and it's an awesome and amazing book.
Rym: There's cultist rabbits.
Scott: There's been.
Scott: for some reason after you selected it as the book club book.
Rym: It's like been coming up in places like showing once again that rimmins got are in fact trendsetters.
Scott: Yeah, the the author is like been interviewing.
Scott: I didn't even know the author was alive or how old the book was, but I guess it's only from the 70s.
Rym: Yeah, it's a recent book.
Rym: Yeah fun fact.
Rym: It was basically couldn't easily be published like some donkey dinky donkey little publisher picked it up and at a limited release in Europe like in London in the UK and Albion and It was insanely popular, but it sold out because it was a tiny little print run
Scott: And then it had a real
Rym: print.
Rym: it had a real print run in the US.
Rym: So most people in Europe and the UK read it as an imported book from America.
Scott: Interesting look how myself we're learning.
Scott: so the book club book episode be great.
Scott: I'm actually going to read it very soon and the reason for that?
Rym: I love how you're you you free.
Rym: you framed the idea that you haven't read it yet.
Rym: No, are you anywhere near getting even like a percent?
Scott: I read a few chapters, but I'm less than halfway, but you framed what you just said as Check out this good thing.
Rym: check out how great it is that I'm finally going to start reading this book.
Scott: So I was in the bookstore.
Scott: Well, I was waiting just because I was waiting for something else.
Scott: I wasn't there to buy a book Jesus Christ yeah, and I was looking in the nerdy book section and I saw some books that on the shelf that I recognized to my eye.
Scott: Oh, and I said is that danger mode?
Scott: I said that is the most dangerous that is most dangerous possible mode.
Scott: Do I dare?
Scott: I think I may dare.
Scott: no don't dare.
Scott: So I'm going to hurry up and get this book club book done so that I can take you to the land of danger.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: What is it gonna be?
Rym: the MD guys novelization?
Rym: No There is one much More dangerous.
Rym: Okay, just be warned cuz I've got a book that was recommended by someone I trust cute up an actual good book But it watership down is actually a really good book.
Scott: No, I think I mean the book that I'm saying is dangerous is not bad.
Rym: Okay, I was just about to say it's been again.
Rym: I have no idea It might be bad if it's if you ever cross me kind of Monte Cristo's just waiting Just just peeking just peeking into the window.
Scott: Just like hey this may actually More.
Scott: I don't how many how many pages is kind of Monte Cristo?
Scott: Uh 520 I want to say this may be more pages I don't know.
Rym: All right, all I'm saying scout is in the book club book.
Scott: It's a toka coca And so all I'm saying it's um, I hope I don't know if you've read this book already.
Rym: I don't know I might have it's possible.
Rym: Are you doing any?
Rym: is it dostoevsky?
Rym: No, okay, cuz I kind of want to do crime and punishment.
Rym: to talk about some Roscoe.
Scott: I like crime punishment.
Scott: I started reading if I didn't finish it.
Rym: Oh, so so you don't know what happens to Roscoe on the cough.
Scott: He like tries to rob the old lady or something, right?
Rym: And then Wow, welcome to.
Rym: like the first chapter.
Rym: It's like Star Wars.
Rym: Oh, yeah, like they're like that ship gets captured and then like something else happens Droids go to desert.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, no, like I heard there's a desert but I didn't get to that part.
Scott: yet They're not the droids.
Scott: You're looking for the end.
Rym: So in other news while we won't miss about guys steal some silver, yeah Sadly we will not be at magfest because we're going to be at Pac South presenting on Sunday January 25th at 4 30 p.m.
Rym: In the armadillo theater.
Scott: armadillo bad Game armadillo.
Rym: Yeah, and I suppose you say coyote instead of coyote.
Scott: Yeah, the armored armadillo that Megaman X tours a new asshole.
Rym: That Basically an updated version of bad games that we did at other conventions and it should be a fun time I go man X not being one of them.
Scott: Yeah quite the opposite.
Rym: It's bad for people who suck at Megaman games.
Rym: I guess I don't want to be easy.
Scott: as far as Megaman games go.
Rym: Well, yeah, cuz it's Megaman X games totally different kind of game.
Scott: Well, don't try to play Megaman X like harder You know what?
Rym: The real answer is don't try to play Megaman one on the NES just skip to two.
Scott: That's what most people watch.
Rym: a let's play a Megaman one if you really want to know what guts man's power gives you.
Rym: It's not that great.
Rym: So The predator the predator.
Scott: so I got to tell the story about the predator.
Scott: So way back in high school days, you know You could choose classes and I chose sci-fi class because I was a nerd and it wasn't.
Scott: you know Sci-fi class was pretty much read some sci-fi books.
Scott: I got here.
Rym: you're led the predator.
Rym: This article is about the album by rapper ice cube.
Rym: For other uses see predator disambiguation.
Rym: Yeah, I go on.
Scott: so in that class, you know, it wasn't like an honors literature class It was just a regular literature class.
Scott: So there were people in there of various intellectual, you know levels and You know, there was some kids in the corner.
Scott: they like to make trouble because they're trouble making kids and they were always just like the Predator.
Scott: they had the catchphrase like the predator and they said it a lot.
Rym: I would just say that all the time.
Scott: Yeah, it caught on with the rest of the class.
Scott: It was pretty fun and they try to wedge the predator in like to other conversations.
Scott: They'd be like like we were talking about HG Wells the invisible man, and yeah, it turned invisible like the predator.
Scott: You know shit like that.
Scott: what happened in class?
Scott: pretty much the whole semester or ever long the semester of high school was.
Scott: and Then that you know, they'd also, you know pester the teacher like can we watch the predator?
Scott: Right and at the end of class like it was like the last day of class Teacher let us watch the predator.
Scott: We watched the predator the end.
Scott: All right, and it was awesome.
Rym: Hey, you realize got the movie is just called predator boo.
Rym: The predator is just the alien in the predator not to be confused with the alien in Alien, not the alien.
Rym: Yeah, it's funny how they pulled them.
Rym: there is aliens the sequel.
Rym: There is also a movie called predators.
Scott: Don't watch that movie.
Rym: Don't watch any predator movie other than Predator.
Scott: so it's weird how predator and alien got like combined to the same universe.
Scott: Part of it is because in predator 2 on the predators ship.
Scott: There is an alien skull which wasn't just an I'm sorry I'm sorry a xenomorph skull.
Rym: Yeah, so Scott.
Rym: Here's the question for you Where if ever in any alien movie when was the first time the word xenomorph was ever said?
Rym: By a character?
Rym: I cannot recall even one I don't think anyway But that's the yeah like you see an alien skull hanging out on the predator ship which writes like awesome.
Rym: as a kid I was like oh, it's like.
Scott: that is the only other than until the movies like alien verse predator, right?
Scott: I there was no connection between these two But it's like there was friggin alien verse predator video games for the arcade and Super Nintendo way back in the 90s and it's like That.
Scott: was that just because the predator - like?
Scott: I don't know how the whole connection got started between these.
Rym: I think it shows you.
Scott: is it just because they came out around similar timeframes and we're about dangerous alien life forms That they sort of merged the same way?
Scott: that like Freddy and Jason have nothing to fuck to do with each other, right?
Scott: But then they just think horror movies that came out in the 80s.
Scott: Let's stick them together guys.
Rym: Well, I mean look today at the fan mashup culture of things That's just in the days before internet.
Rym: if a movie studio or a creative team was like hey Why don't we mash up these two current and popular properties?
Scott: How did they not?
Scott: these same people who were doing this alien predator mashup and Freddy Jason mashup?
Scott: How do hum they never managed to do Star Wars Star Trek mashup?
Scott: That is the most obvious of all mashups because they don't line up.
Scott: very well I know but even nerds have not dare.
Scott: It's like there's some sort of wall down the middle.
Rym: there is You know what?
Rym: It's because the ships are slow versus moving.
Scott: Yeah Star Wars ships fuck.
Scott: Enterprise is sitting still next to like the Death Star and then like a million x-wings come at it It's like oh my god.
Rym: Yeah, you know, you know who wins that fight the culture ships.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So predator I saw as a little kid But I actually saw a Robocop first.
Rym: in terms of like this like movies that were violent in that era of my childhood I don't remember the first time I saw my elementary school saw predator.
Rym: like before I saw predator.
Scott: I don't remember when I saw it or the first time I saw it, but it was on TV I saw and I mistook it for command like.
Rym: I'm confused.
Scott: So someone figure out like what year predator was on like weekend afternoon TV.
Rym: that's the thing until I became a teenager.
Rym: I can't base when I saw a movie by the year it came out.
Rym: I can base when I saw a movie by when it Was on HBO.
Scott: Oh, maybe I got on VHS from blockbuster.
Scott: That's also possible.
Rym: might have Yeah, but like as a little kid, I mixed up predator and commando because I didn't really know like what they were.
Scott: I didn't like the first time I saw predator.
Scott: I was not conscious enough to fully comprehend this movie.
Scott: Yeah, even though it's not a very complicated movie whatsoever.
Scott: I was very young.
Rym: It's interesting cuz Robocop.
Rym: I Like the straightforward parts.
Rym: I got a hundred percent.
Rym: as a little kid I was like, alright, he is a guy who got hurt and they turn him into a robot cop and now he's awesome And he saves the day.
Rym: I didn't get the subtext about gender equality in the future or Union or buying things for a dollar.
Rym: I got that because I Understood that cuz I had seen running man Played some Smash TV.
Rym: Yeah big money.
Rym: But I remember specifically that I saw the cover of predator somewhere That image of like the target or the reticle on Arnold and I was like, whoa, that's the guy who was in Terminator.
Rym: Oh shit, you know Terminator 1 I was talking about.
Rym: I saw Terminator 1 before.
Rym: I saw Terminator 2 like intelligent versus.
Rym: yeah Terminator 1 is just a horror movie basically and You know what watching predator again as an adult.
Rym: I'm gonna be very honest.
Rym: It is not a great movie.
Scott: However, I would never said it was great.
Scott: However, it's not alien.
Rym: It is definitely an enjoyable movie.
Scott: It is a good movie.
Scott: It is on the good level.
Scott: It is not like Die Hard where it's like.
Scott: whoa is a must-see movie.
Scott: But it you know, it's good.
Scott: You should watch it.
Scott: It's not like there's any bad parts, but everyone fixate Doesn't have to the chopper right to the chopper.
Rym: That's all.
Rym: anyone knows this movie.
Scott: It says it once.
Scott: they just said twice Yeah, but once it once is not the one time he says it is not quite as in a that's yet.
Rym: So it's funny cuz.
Rym: Scott and I had both seen the movie Like I had seen it when I was a little kid and I hadn't seen it since then.
Rym: So we're watching the movie again and every time a scene started I was like, oh right.
Rym: I remember this movie Like I forgot all these things that happen along the way.
Rym: As a kid like that scene where there's the knife and the scorpion Mm-hmm.
Rym: I was as a kid.
Rym: that was one of the most badass things I'd ever seen.
Rym: I was like That guy is so badass, but watching it again That guy is so scary.
Rym: I'm so crazy.
Rym: as a kid I looked up to that character like wow, that is one of the coolest people ever.
Rym: and now I look at him.
Scott: I was like true.
Rym: I was like if I see a guy like that on the subway I'm not turning my back on him.
Rym: Nor am I going anywhere near him.
Scott: Both of those things are true.
Scott: He is so cool and so scary.
Rym: But the other thing is that the acting was not subtle in a lot of parts.
Scott: No, the opening of the goddamn movie is like.
Scott: you might as well be a daytime cop drama.
Rym: Yeah, it's like Carl Arnold and Carl Weathers have their bonding moment and then they show off their muscles to be like Yeah, these guys don't have muscles.
Scott: He's like, you know some Star Wars Han Solo acting level like you son of a gun.
Rym: But again that kind of dialogue when I was my age was single digits was amazing.
Scott: It's still amazing But there's.
Scott: it's not high brow, but it's like well done low brow.
Rym: there's Surprisingly some subtle.
Rym: I don't want to say acting but Storycraft and character development in predator that I did not pick up on as a kid.
Rym: So look at how this movie goes.
Rym: It is well.
Rym: first Well, forget the alien part.
Rym: if you just if they cut out that beginning and you didn't know there was an alien yeah, the first half of the movie is super competent.
Rym: people Doing their super competent like we are ultra commandos doing our thing.
Rym: Yep, and you see like and he's not they're not a hit squad They're rescuing people and like they all get each other like you see these characters and you see that like they all work together They get each other.
Rym: The only tension at all is between them and Carl Weathers because he is the guy who's out of the game.
Rym: And they show that to you in the beginning because when they do the little arm wrestle Arnold wins because Arnold's still in the game.
Rym: He got out of the game.
Rym: He's wearing a tie He's a bureaucrat.
Rym: now guys in ties who are bureaucrats can't be trusted.
Rym: Oh sure enough.
Rym: He can't be trusted, right?
Scott: It's in a tennis style thing right.
Scott: you win this battle.
Scott: It means something right.
Scott: Arnold also wins because he's in the rescuing people game, right?
Scott: He's a good guy.
Scott: He doesn't do like.
Scott: he's not a murderer goes in and like hoses people down.
Scott: Yeah, but Carl is yep.
Rym: But then and and they're super competent and they don't lose their cool for anything.
Rym: Yeah until the alien comes so a character experiences some weird shit and That character is fucked up for the rest of the movie because these characters are master Keaton professionals.
Rym: So when they encounter the alien one by one they go crazy.
Scott: Yeah, so it's if you think about the most the most similar story to this is most dangerous game right and most dangerous game is About you know this guy who gets trapped on an island where the guy who's hunting him for sport And the thing is the guy who gets trapped on the island isn't a total badass.
Scott: But then again, he's just being hunted by a human hunter.
Scott: so like the disparity of Skill level it's like the hunter has to be stronger than the hunted.
Scott: But it's like how much stronger right?
Scott: if it's too much stronger Then it's really boring because it's like it would be unbelievable for the hunter to do anything But immediately kill their prey in a boring and you know not exciting way.
Scott: But if the hunter is too weak, then it's not scary enough.
Scott: So most dangerous game It's normal dude versus professional hunting dude, so what predator does is ramps it the fuck up.
Scott: It's like well if we want to have the hunted be the most badass humans ever Then we need to make the hunter the most badass alien we can imagine and that way it'll actually be scary and the.
Scott: you know The disparity in strength will be such that there is an entertainment tension horror etc.
Rym: Yep, but you see like as they go crazy like the famous scenes the I am firing my minigun until it runs out of bullets And it runs out of bullets, and then the gun just they're going.
Rym: Yeah, like those scenes, and it's the the movie set up to where that would not have happened.
Rym: But for the fact that that guy was fucked up by what's going on around him like he went crazy Even the moat.
Scott: that's how dangerous the predator is right.
Scott: It's but they show you except You can't see.
Scott: so right, but it's like they don't show you Necessarily like like an alien like you get scared of the alien because you saw it burst out of a chest And you know do all kind you know.
Scott: but and because it's dark and spooky like you can't tell where it is and they get you with like the cat and stuff like that in Predator it's like the predator.
Scott: isn't really that scary.
Scott: It's actually like an intelligent.
Rym: It's just dangerous.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: He's just like hi How you doing?
Scott: You know he can talk in a language?
Scott: That's not English, and you know he has technology flew in a spaceship, right?
Scott: It's not like this sort of dangerous wild animal thing.
Scott: It's sort of like hi there.
Scott: I'm the predator.
Scott: I'm hunting you.
Scott: I just happen to be a really awesome alien with crazy awesome homing guns and shit like that.
Scott: Yeah, so To make it scary first they give it this you know cloaking technology which in the one hand Demonstrates that the vastly superior technological capabilities of the predator it also allows them to conceal the predators.
Scott: You know image for you know see the viewer of the movie doesn't know what it looks like.
Scott: at the same time the bad Asses have a hard time shooting at it because they can't see it because it's all camo and whatnot.
Scott: all right.
Scott: So it's like it's an awesome Thing that they can use like for plot reasons and also cinematic reasons at the same time.
Scott: And it sort of like defines the predator the fact that he's got ghost in the shell You know Inviso camo technology, and yeah the effects other than the practical ones like the other effects.
Rym: Don't really hold up.
Rym: Spaceship looks way shit.
Scott: spaceship looks shit, but the camo actually looks pretty good considering the time that they made it true.
Rym: I mean it looks better than attempted efforts at similar things in that era.
Scott: and the predators costume You know pretty good.
Scott: No real not really worse than the alien one.
Rym: Yeah, definitely.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with it.
Scott: You know the explosions typical.
Rym: you know Everyone's got a billion bullets and you know typical action movie stuff.
Rym: But everyone always quotes get to the choppa.
Rym: It's like everyone forgot about gonna.
Rym: Have me some fun.
Rym: Go ahead me which might be my favorite line actually from the predator.
Rym: Go ahead me some.
Scott: it's much more useful than get to the chopper.
Scott: It's like I guess if you're at a store and need to get to the car, but I get to the chopper.
Scott: Yeah, like there's a lot of times Or you're gonna have you some fun like you're walking in like let's play a board game You sit down to play a board game like I'm gonna.
Scott: Have me some fun.
Scott: I'll go have me some.
Scott: You know.
Scott: sit down to record a podcast.
Scott: I'll go have me some fun.
Scott: Yeah, you can use that all.
Scott: goddamn day.
Rym: I mean the characters in general - like I I love the characters in this movie because they're all like big muscle dudes and two of them ended up being governors of states.
Rym: Like think about that for a second.
Rym: I forgot Jesse Ventura was in this movie.
Scott: Yep He was.
Rym: so all we need is for Carl Weathers to run for governor.
Scott: is he alive.
Rym: He was in Arrested Development That long ago.
Rym: all right.
Rym: He played.
Rym: He's he's joined the cadre of actors who played themselves as washed-up actors.
Rym: Did you get to that partner as the development?
Scott: I only saw it we saw at the beach.
Rym: so basically He's just like the sort of con man washed-up actor playing himself And he like uses his fame to get people to like buy him food and things and it's just actually funny.
Rym: no That's so.
Rym: you're such a superficial fan.
Rym: all you know is the banana stand joke.
Rym: you don't know any other jokes.
Rym: get to the job.
Rym: Also movie Definitely proud of his time kind of got away with having the.
Rym: this is the Native American character And this is the nerd character And this is the cowboy character, and this is Arnold the hero who wins with mud.
Scott: Here's the girl.
Scott: yep, we introduced because otherwise there wouldn't be any girl in this movie.
Scott: But yeah the predator is like.
Scott: you know it's weird that like from this pretty simple straightforward movie like this whole like like Franchise a predator like spawned out of this it like it's like whoa.
Scott: It's like I guess it's because like you have this one alien that clearly came from a race of aliens because it has technology Yeah, you know and it came to earth.
Scott: It's like so that sort of leaves this huge unexplained.
Scott: You know Universe out there to build upon and that's what allows them to create.
Scott: You know the entire Universe of predator and also the anything had just been like a wild animal that was living in the jungle the whole time That they wouldn't have been able to do anything else with it And we probably wouldn't have.
Rym: you know the same kind of it also set up a bunch of things about how like the predator had Been to earth before And had been hunting before.
Rym: yeah cuz similar things that happened in the past.
Rym: So there's a lot to do there, and you know like his ship is somewhere.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: like they could have made a movie that was like hey We found the predator ship and then it could have been good instead of bad But a few or maybe his ship is self-destructed.
Rym: when he's self-destructed yeah, it's hard to say yeah.
Rym: But one thing I've noticed is that a lot of people who talk about this movie Complain because Terminator 2 you weren't like.
Scott: Terminator 2 is 10,000.
Rym: No I'm saying you weren't.
Rym: you weren't Originally intended to know that Arnold plays the good guy and all the trailers like everything about the movie ruined that for everybody.
Rym: The matrix actually somehow got away with like that not being ruined in the very beginning.
Rym: predator Just from the very beginning of the movie shows you the alien ship.
Rym: That's the first scene.
Scott: is this alien dropship going like going earth?
Rym: I've seen people complain saying that the movie would have been better if it didn't show you that and you didn't know what the deal Was.
Scott: the same people get upset at spoilers.
Rym: nah because in this case Seeing the ship ahead of time in my opinion means it puts you in that tense situation.
Rym: where?
Rym: You know shit's about to go down.
Rym: You know there's this sort of Damocles just like hanging above the characters.
Rym: But the characters don't know it.
Scott: people put too much value on Surprise.
Rym: no I still agree with my bullshit, and I disagree with it.
Rym: I'm glad you agree that it's bullshit.
Scott: I'm gonna keep saying it cuz 100% true nope.
Scott: But here's people just want cheap thrills and surprise and can't appreciate something.
Rym: in Terminator 2 Not knowing would have made the early scenes filled with more attention not less Because that early scene would be.
Rym: there are all these people and they're all coming after John Connor And they're all evil and you don't know what's going on.
Rym: And then the reveal is an interesting twist and then the movie just shoots like a rocket out of that point.
Rym: knowing Arnold's the good guy takes some tension away, but in predator if the if the predator had attacked them right away Then it would have been like Terminator less tense, but because the predator doesn't attack them for a long time The longer he doesn't attack them the more tension you feel.
Scott: that is true You know like.
Scott: there's nothing in the movie besides that alien dropship scene at the very very beginning.
Scott: if you cut that out They don't.
Scott: there's no predator action for quite a while.
Scott: So it's like you would just be thinking - you would go that whole beginning part of the movie.
Scott: You would actually be thinking about like the commando guys that they're going to go and do it.
Rym: You might be thinking that maybe this thing that's attacking them is the government secret, right?
Scott: You'd think that like that's what the movie's about.
Scott: is You know going to take out these bad guys in the jungle like it's commando or something like that and like you know You wouldn't you know?
Scott: and then when the alien came like where the fuck did that come from?
Scott: and you know?
Scott: It'd be it would be a total mess.
Scott: I mean, I guess you could change around the whole movie But you need some kind of force to do it.
Rym: Here's what you have to do.
Rym: It was foreshadowed.
Rym: They could have done it both ways cuz they did it that needed.
Scott: you need to replace that foreshadowing with a different No, no, cuz look at the movie.
Rym: There's there's obviously Carl Weathers.
Rym: Dylan has a plus Dylan right?
Rym: I already forget all that.
Scott: I don't know anyone's name.
Rym: So you remember who Dutch is?
Scott: that's Arnold?
Rym: Yeah, okay, so Carl Weathers He is obviously hiding something and there's obviously like some you know, like there's that whole plot around.
Scott: He's tricking them into going in right but he's tricking them because he he knows Arnold will only go on a rescue mission Wants to get him to go on a murder mission, but he's tricking them to go in on a murder mission.
Rym: That's orthogonal to the alien plot.
Rym: Mm-hmm If you didn't know it was an alien you would think that his trick was This thing that's stalking them like some sort of government project like something and then the twist would have been oh It wasn't the government plot.
Rym: It was this other thing.
Rym: It would have been a very different movie instead.
Rym: So when you evaluate spoil
Scott: you need some scene where like they peek over a hill and see like the ship or something
Rym: Or even just like you see the alien night vision the IR vision and you think that's like the government people Tracking them or whatever like you don't really know what that is.
Scott: Yeah, that's a lot of the movie is you know through the Predators eyes like looking at them.
Rym: And so this is why I don't disagree with you 100% of the spoilers thing.
Rym: I don't agree with you 100% either.
Rym: I think in there are situations where spoilers increase tension or increase enjoyment and there are situations Where they decrease tension or decrease enjoyment and it's a matter of story craft and nuance and skill.
Rym: But in the case of predator the fact that you know, there's an alien from the opening credits I think is what makes the movie as good as that movie could have been.
Scott: I agree that there are cases where Spoilers can decrease enjoyment.
Scott: What I'm saying is that those cases is because the enjoyment to be had is fully or mostly in the form of surprise.
Scott: No enjoyment to be had elsewhere and thus works of art that are relying so heavily on surprise Thus that spoilers truly spoil them are not good works of art and you who cares about spoiling them They're not even worth watching or experiencing.
Scott: something like Empire Strikes Back is not ruined at all By knowing that Darth Vader is Luke's father.
Scott: In fact, it is enhanced.
Rym: But as we watch that movie a thousand goddamn times seeing Quality seeing Terminator 2 it was intended and not knowing Arnold is the good guy.
Rym: The surprise is not the big point.
Rym: The point is the tension before the surprise where Like John Connor's fuck the bad guy.
Scott: Have you watched Terminator 2 now?
Scott: It's not as good as the first time.
Rym: I'm saying.
Rym: if you saw it and didn't know that Arnold was the good guy the opening scene up until the Moment before the surprise.
Rym: reveal that time forget the surprise take the surprise out of the equation.
Rym: The first chunk of the movie would have been a better experience.
Scott: You don't have that good experience watching it.
Rym: No, I do have a good experience.
Rym: I think it would have been a better experience because the tension would have been ratcheted the fuck up.
Scott: I because I because I know that that I'm supposed to think Arnold's the bad guy.
Scott: last time I watched Terminator 2 I can still see all that tension right.
Scott: there is no problem.
Rym: Yeah, you say that but under you're not Ubermensch you're not rust.
Rym: call Nick off.
Scott: I'd had no problem.
Rym: every read the rest of a crime and punishment.
Scott: Listen captain ubermensch Arnold didn't try to rob.
Rym: No, they Didn't have him some fun.
Rym: No predator honestly Of a bunch of people like hanging out like hey, let's watch an old Arnold movie.
Rym: I think commando or running men are a better choice for that environment.
Rym: Yes predator However is a better movie than both of them.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: Also and while it has a lot of flaws It's not an unenjoyable movie, but I wouldn't.
Rym: I don't think people should go out of their way to see it Unless they're not old fan.
Scott: I think it's a must-see just in terms.
Rym: It's a must-see.
Rym: if you're a sci-fi movie It's a must-see.
Scott: just that be a nerd right.
Scott: have nerd knowledge.
Rym: If you're a nerd if you're a sci-fi movie fan If you're an action sci-fi movie fan, if you're an Arnold movie fan, you mean for a lot of people?
Scott: It's just sort of something like you have to know what the deal with the predator is.
Rym: You can't not know that but you could learn that from Wikipedia and which I think most people do.
Rym: I think most people know.
Rym: get to the choppa and yeah, that's the Arnold movie with the predator, right?
Scott: But you also got to see like the dudes arm falling off still firing a machine.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: They see they see animated gifs of that.
Scott: Yeah, it's good You know if you piece it together, whatever.
Scott: But 90 minutes isn't really gonna take you to watch the movie isn't really gonna be much faster Yeah, or slower than reading all that internet.
Rym: You know what the real moral is.
Rym: Arnold movies are a specific genre of movie And I really like Arnold movies and I did not stop liking them when I became wise.
Scott: they're not bad.
Rym: I'd buy them for at least a dollar.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.