Rym: It's Wednesday November 4th 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Anime is just animations a simmer down rims idea.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: I Forget if I promised I was gonna do this until the end of the year Or if I was just gonna do it till the end of summer.
Rym: but I'm just gonna start talking about biking again because now it's dark and And Not super fun to bike home in the dark promise breaker.
Rym: I'm pretty sure I've said until the end of the season or until the end of summer even with lights.
Scott: Yeah, bike and home in the dark kind of sucks.
Scott: Oh actually not you daylight savings time.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: Fuck you Except no, the problem is actually you like Dave like daylight saving time.
Rym: There's no s. it's just daylight saving time Sure, not daylight savings time.
Rym: Don't fuck with me when it comes to time, but The problem is we want to go to daylight saving time and never come back Correct.
Rym: You want to get to edt and stay on edt forever.
Rym: est is the bad news bear?
Rym: Yes, in fact, I want to go doubly like edt like double daylight.
Rym: I would like it to be dark until like 930 or 10.
Rym: I might fuck up with people got to go sleep When you're not going to sleep to like midnight unless you don't have a life You'd be surprised.
Scott: what a little kiddies going to bed like, you know.
Rym: Well when I was a kid like my parents made me go to bed when the Sun was still out Sometimes just because you know timezone and latitude in Michigan and everything.
Rym: Yeah, but all that aside I've been watching anime.
Rym: The problem is I'm watching old anime that we've won already talked about in GeekNights and to Scott's not watching with me.
Scott: so I The man who punches once I'm watching the guy who's way too big.
Rym: Oh, I got a way behind on guy who's too big.
Scott: Yeah Done shows on all these All of these before.
Rym: can't review Monogatari or one punch man until they're done or at least a season is done enough to where we both watch them and can do it.
Scott: Like hey, it was yeah, I mean I gave him the first two volumes of one punch man manga.
Scott: But it's like we don't you know, we don't need to do another show.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's almost the same as the anime.
Rym: Yeah, unless the only thing is the review of like the holistic beginning and like if I reviewed project blue cheek you based on the first Episode triple-a best show ever but based on the whole show.
Rym: It's like a B - B. ish, I guess roaches not bees.
Scott: Yeah, we can't do another episode on it and the other GeekNights episode about a show when we've only seen two more episodes of That show.
Rym: and what I've been watching lately other than things we just talked about is a lot of not Anime that Scott's not watching.
Rym: and I'm also watching Fujikomi ne because we never actually finished it and it's soon on Hulu.
Scott: I'm gonna watch.
Scott: there's a bunch of Lupin on Hulu.
Scott: I'm gonna watch all of it eventually because I really want to watch.
Scott: watching South Park Which I think there's a new episode tonight at least probably last night for most of you.
Rym: I'm a few episodes behind but you've been watching ponies.
Scott: That's a shame.
Scott: No, I gotta watch that.
Rym: yeah ponies started a little man like.
Scott: the last episode I watched was the whole town is like Harrison Bergeron.
Rym: that was literally the season opener.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: No, there was a couple episodes after the season opener So you watch a little bit after that?
Scott: No, that was the last episode I saw.
Rym: yeah So you saw the season opener and literally nothing opener was one or two episodes before that one.
Rym: No, I thought there was season opener.
Rym: there was a merger on ponies.
Scott: Oh, there's one or two before then.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: anyway, I've but get once you get to the Halloween one.
Rym: It's getting a little again But time is starting again - yeah and I think venture time starting again with something big.
Rym: I'm kind of into this Business.
Scott: here is something interesting for you.
Scott: By the way, there will be an episode this season of Adventure Time that was partially starboarded by Casey Green and someone else.
Rym: Oh, I'm surprised.
Rym: I didn't know that was happening I just tweeted it today.
Scott: Like when I left work, I saw that tweet.
Rym: Oh, I follow him on Twitter, but I have not looked at Twitter a little bit cuz I was actually doing work at work.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Maybe the dick butt will appear.
Rym: Oh, it has to.
Rym: So in the news We don't pay like a lot of like little anime cons or even like mid-sized anime cons and fan conventions in general come and go and some of them ask us to attend and we really usually don't because we're busy.
Rym: a lot of reasons why we don't always go.
Rym: but There was one anime convention that I had not ever heard of Until this story the Akiba Expo.
Scott: All right, it sounds like a normal anime con.
Scott: So where is it?
Rym: I guess it's in Anaheim, California.
Scott: They already have anime Expo like out there in California.
Scott: Why do they need?
Rym: Well, I was gonna.
Rym: I could go to the Akiba Expo website to tell you exactly when it was.
Rym: I think it was in December, but it might have been in February.
Rym: Like I don't know because coming up soon.
Scott: It's gone All right, so it's an anime con that failed.
Scott: exciting not news.
Scott: This happens all the time.
Rym: What's interesting is that this is By no means the first time that this has happened in very recent memory, but happens all the time.
Rym: Yeah, but most people don't seem to realize this because from what I can gather Thousands of people bought badges.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah Why would you buy some badges some shady con that you've never ever heard of?
Rym: see that's.
Rym: I followed up on all these stores.
Scott: It was like there was a convention in New York.
Scott: Actually, I think was when we were at PAX.
Scott: Yeah called waka con.
Scott: They supposed to be the Brooklyn Expo Center, yeah a place I wanted to check out but I Did not have anything to do with that because I was like, wow, this is totally shady.
Scott: But apparently it happened and it was somewhat legit.
Scott: So maybe I'll go to it.
Scott: No,
Rym: so not only did apparently thousands of people registered But
Scott: I was so scab of a con I never heard of before get
Rym: hotel rooms for it post about how excited they are That they're gonna be at it, but they bought a hundred and sixty dollar artist alley tables.
Rym: Wow, no one's getting their money back, I don't think anyone's get their money back.
Scott: that's a shame.
Rym: So this you know, like there was that minecraft con that was the same thing Like the people who ran it gonna get busted for fraud.
Rym: They're gone as far as I can tell.
Scott: Why don't we fraud and run away?
Rym: That's what I was talking about.
Rym: Are you so Scott?
Scott: I got my new convention.
Scott: if we're gonna fraud and run away why anime con?
Scott: fraud?
Scott: we can do so.
Scott: We can professional conference fraud where the tickets are a thousand dollars.
Rym: So the I've got Harry Potter Avengers con.
Rym: that's my con.
Scott: That's the convention.
Scott: I'm gonna make as much money as Wait till you see our guests.
Rym: So one we have a whole anime track.
Rym: We've got Miyazaki is gonna be there really given our keynote.
Rym: We've got a Satoshi con.
Rym: He's gonna give a really good vision.
Scott: Avengers Harry Potter con.
Rym: We'll get to that too.
Rym: Actually, I've got John Oliver to host the cosplay.
Rym: All right, so he's gonna be the speaker of the cosplay.
Rym: We're gonna have a rave.
Rym: at least 10,000 people can go to this rave.
Rym: We've got to mix Megumi Hashibara and every single kpop band.
Rym: Every single one every one every all of them, you know how many there are.
Scott: Take like a week just to hear one song from each of them.
Rym: I assume there's actually an infinite number.
Rym: It's like one of those functions where RNG just keeps popping up new band names.
Scott: the deeper you go I think somebody some at some point.
Scott: someone said there's like hundreds of idols in Kpop.
Rym: so That minecraft convention.
Rym: like people a lot of people were pretty sure it was BS from the beginning Even though at the same time tons of people like paid and try to go to it or whatever - con.
Rym: the entire internet knew it was gonna be a disaster, but yet somehow people showed up to it.
Scott: But this one isn't even gonna happen.
Rym: the time between the internet saying hey Is this convention a scam?
Rym:  it imploding was like two days.
Scott: Wait, why not?
Scott: Just if you're scamming and someone finds you out.
Scott: Why are you running away?
Scott: Why don't you just keep taking money?
Scott: So and say you're not a scam until the last possible.
Rym: I put even odds on one of two possibilities.
Rym: This is my guess Possibility one.
Rym: it was a scam from the beginning But the person running it got funding from someone else and I've heard some rumors about that.
Rym: might be how they Actually got this thing going.
Rym: Whoa squandered all that money and put together a best effort that was designed to fail.
Rym: So we can't easily be sued because it's not really illegal to fail.
Rym: It's illegal to fraud.
Scott: So if you try how did this person get funding for an anime con?
Scott: who's funding anime cons?
Scott: I will put it on a real fucking anime con.
Scott: that will totally legit happen not fraud.
Scott: if you fund me Someone funds me to run an anime con I will run a kick-ass anime con somewhere.
Scott: if you fund me say I don't have to go to my regular job The packs of anime cons The best fucking con will start small the first year, but we're gonna.
Scott: you know We won't spend all your money and then we're gonna use.
Scott: we're gonna profit.
Rym: for sure wouldn't even need that much.
Scott: You know we need and we're gonna kick ass year after year and we're gonna build that up and within like the third year It'll be like we'll be getting ready to like almost compete with anime Boston.
Scott: I would need like 300 K tops sure Oh plus enough to live.
Rym: Well, yeah plus anyway.
Rym: But so basically this threat appeared on 4chan.
Rym: and Is anyone planning on attending Akiba Expo?
Rym: It's a first-year con in Anaheim.
Rym: I wanted to go since 20 even drive in my house.
Rym: But I'm double thinking it because there's been some shady business practices and drama surrounding the event.
Scott: don't double think it.
Scott: You only need to think once shady.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: That's the one half a thing.
Scott: It's like what.
Scott: there's something shady about this?
Rym: nope Yep Capitals no Anna Twitter Started looking at this con because they noticed it because people started talking about it a little bit.
Rym: So I went and looked at the hashtags and it was all people talking about how excited they were to go.
Rym: And in fact, they're still talking about it.
Rym: I think a lot of people attending this con don't know that it's gone.
Rym: I'll bet people are going to show up in Anaheim because apparently they mailed their badges.
Rym: people tweeted pictures their fucking badges Oh snap, so someone did something that wasn't complete A lot but from what I can gather they posted a lineup of guests and then one by one to get.
Rym: the people who were Listed were like, uh, I'm not I didn't say I was attending that con.
Rym: Supposedly someone who was trying to staff the con with guest relations Leaked a bunch of emails and was like yo dog.
Rym: This shit is not happening.
Scott: All this all why don't you just contact the space that it's supposed to be in?
Scott: so that was the other thing.
Rym: No one was sure where it was because it was implied it doesn't have a location.
Rym: It was implied that was at some convention center and all the convention center.
Rym: Oh, yeah people.
Rym: so once Anna Twitter pointed at this someone pointed out immediately like yeah That event is not listed on the Anaheim Convention Center.
Rym: And then someone else said that oh, it looks like they're actually at just this hotel called the hotel in Anaheim.
Rym: So yeah, so those investigations began like real.
Rym: recently.
Scott: like this went this How long is this convention been taking people's money?
Rym: Apparently a long time For a while.
Rym: so the the Facebook page went from.
Rym: we're not a scam to.
Rym: the event is canceled.
Rym: their official website went from.
Rym: it looks like some general generic Squarespace site with The convention rules and policies which I should you not were a copy/paste of a rave Rules because it had all this shit about rave nonsense and how big your totems can be and totems.
Rym: Yeah, that's a reaver thing.
Rym: they bring these big totem poles and wave them around.
Rym: it's the stupidest They don't.
Scott: I never heard of this.
Rym: ray.
Rym: go go go to a rave and read their rules.
Rym: You were not allowed to bring Professional video or camera equipment which included anything with the detachable lens, okay?
Rym: You could not bring over-the-counter medicine of any kind or prescription medicine of any kind.
Scott: But the raves are full of drugs.
Scott: you are everyone brings them in.
Scott: so I don't think these rules are being enforced very well I don't know.
Rym: I don't go to a lot of raves.
Scott: Yeah, but Yeah, so it was really if you told me there was actually a rave that didn't have any drugs going on at it.
Scott: like.
Scott: I'm Not gonna be in a cloud of smoke.
Scott: I mean I like electronic music.
Scott: I would totally go and have a dance.
Rym: You want to go to a straight-edge rave?
Rym: I know of a few in New York City.
Scott: is it gonna be huge?
Scott: and is the good DJ gonna be there?
Scott: I'm gonna be there just DJ.
Rym: They're just straight edge.
Rym: They're all like Henry Rollins fans going to these things okay?
Scott: Yeah, that's a good time.
Rym: There's also quiet events.
Rym: They do raves that are big and giant, but they everyone gets headphones and the music's all just in the headphones.
Scott: I don't like that now.
Rym: You don't like that?
Rym: no That's not good, but do you want to like roll around in bubbles and get high on ecstasy?
Rym: like?
Scott: no I want there to be just a dance party where it's music only and it's legit dancing But the soap you know electronic music It's not a rave with drugs and all sorts of weird light stick people, but normal people.
Rym: Here's the there's.
Rym: what happened here with Akiva Expo Brings up a lot of interesting points that may or may not be worth further discussion not now, but in the future.
Rym: one Who are these people who see a website for a convention and without?
Rym: Looking at any other part of the internet type their parents credit card number in and rent a hotel room.
Rym: Who are these people who are still dateline now?
Rym: Tweeting about the con not knowing that it's gone.
Rym: I found a tweet where someone's like oh looks like the websites down.
Rym: Hopefully, it'll be back soon.
Rym: I wanted something something artist alley.
Rym: It's like yeah, dude I Think what if someone on an administrator was gonna has a gofundme?
Rym: He was like I will fucking legit.
Rym: go to this thing and live tweet the entire convention if you send me there.
Scott: Oh Okay, yeah, so I wonder if you go tweeting from outside the convey the hotel.
Scott: I wonder if he's gonna go anyway And just see like an interview these people who show up thinking there's gonna be a convention when they're all their badges And there isn't anything there.
Rym: uh there is such demand for anime cons that Pretty much any first-year con seems to sell out almost anywhere Which is actually kind of I can't imagine this comm is gonna be that big in the hotel.
Rym: well according to the website It's gonna be the fucking biggest thing you've ever seen.
Rym: you should have seen what was on this website.
Rym: People are posting Google caches of what the website looked like but the most beautiful thing in the world my favorite Thing mm-hmm.
Rym: I gotta pull it off here.
Rym: doo doo doo doo good night, so Sans Duvall tweeted good night sweet prince ten hours ago, and it is a screenshot of Where they announced.
Rym: the convention is no longer happening.
Rym: They didn't announce another website because that shit's gone.
Rym: They announced it on their website.
Scott: probably cost money if it's Squarespace.
Rym: Squarespace cost like ten bucks a month like it's not I mean if you're running away with all the money.
Scott: You don't have ten bucks a month anymore.
Rym: Do you to our guests and fans?
Rym: due to the recent rumors and allegations?
Rym: We are forced to bring Akihabara Expo to a halt.
Rym: most of our staff have left the organization due to threats as well as distrust Of the exposition due to recent events.
Rym: without people to run the show and without the people who helped us build this we cannot execute A show that we would be proud of.
Rym: in addition most of our guests have left due to the constant drama and harassment Our exposition has faced.
Rym: we wish the show could go on but without proper staffing and a solid lineup We cannot bring the same quality experience that we had promised you.
Rym: if you wish to receive a recent refund Please fill the form below.
Scott: Please fill the form and we'll know who all the suckers are.
Scott: Yeah, anyone gets a read.
Scott: I want to hear from someone who gets a refund.
Rym: Oh so option two Here's my other the other 50/50 hours than what happened here.
Rym: It is possible from some of the leaks I read of.
Rym: like guests were contacted, but like weren't sent contracts, and it was all.
Rym: it is possible that someone Got in over their head and thought they could run a con and somehow got a hold of enough money to like Start making a con But just didn't know what the fuck they were doing and tried to just kind of string it all along Until eventually it fell apart like a house of cards.
Rym: hmm I give even odds.
Rym: neither one of those things whatever but this You can just search for Akiva Expo on Twitter and over the course of two days You can see this go from a hundred to zero and it's beautiful.
Scott: And so in other news that actually affects people who affect a lot of people aren't stupid?
Scott: There was some mumblings this week.
Scott: nothing like totally confirmed or locked in or anything like that.
Scott: no details, but Netflix who has been producing shows on their own as shown great interest in making anime and Bollywood.
Scott: Yes, this may mean that they'll actually have a studio at Netflix that produces like Netflix original anime.
Scott: Or maybe it means that like they'll hire a Japanese studio like madhouse or somebody and be like hey Here's a bunch of money.
Scott: make this anime for us or who knows what.
Scott: but there's gonna be Possibly some animes in the future with any you know how many months or years?
Scott: That are only on Netflix until someone pirates them off of Netflix.
Rym: That's a big deal for one reason.
Rym: that reason is the number that I mean they're trying.
Scott: are they gonna put this on Netflix in Japan?
Scott: I presume to try to get Netflix to be a thing in Japan and maybe it is a thing there.
Rym: all right I also make it global.
Rym: But that number the reason this is a big deal is five billion.
Rym: Netflix said next year alone and just in 2016 They're gonna spend five billion dollars on original content B. so Think about how.
Rym: because there was that leak way back of all the like Licensing stuff and you all know all the nonsense about how little people who make anime actually get paid.
Rym: if Netflix Gives even what they would consider a tiny budget to an existing anime studio like force Everyone's gonna go work at that studio all 4c.
Scott: Definitely you got to pay them the big bucks.
Scott: Well, actually that's the studio.
Scott: if I was Netflix That's what I definitely would do is be like both see ghost in the shell up in the house.
Scott: here We go, but think about this.
Rym: if Netflix gave what they would consider a small budget to an anime studio That would probably end up being the biggest budget any anime has ever had ever.
Scott: in fact You know well Akira had a huge, but I'd be like.
Rym: well.
Rym: Here's a movie.
Rym: You're talking about shows.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, you can make movies fucking - who cares?
Scott: yeah, I get like IG for C team up.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you could just be like all star anime here.
Scott: We go.
Scott: I can just buy all your studios.
Scott: I'm Netflix.
Scott: you're tiny.
Rym: yeah It's kind of a big deal.
Rym: actually if this goes forward.
Scott: I know right who knows whatever animes they make could be like anime of the century and couple this with the Hulu thing.
Scott: and pretty much have Hulu and Netflix and Spent a lot more time talking about his news, but this news is a way bigger deal.
Scott: There's a lot less to say about it other than holy shit.
Scott: Let's do it.
Rym: come on.
Rym: Well, it does kind of relate into the actual topic of the show.
Scott: Which is all you?
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: so speaking of those Netflix shows one of the best ones in recent memory Bojack Horseman.
Rym: Bojack is actually a super good show and if you don't know what Bojack is like you haven't seen it and You assume that it's something just based on like screenshots.
Rym: You might have seen of the horseheaded guy or Maybe seeing the first episode and thinking it's like Archer or something.
Rym: it is not.
Rym: it is a human drama.
Rym: It's super good.
Rym: I highly recommend it.
Rym: Emily And I like just went crazy and binged on the entire thing and now we're just waiting for the next season which is already confirmed.
Rym: but Cartoon hangover at Frederator.
Rym: they've been doing a thing recently.
Rym: you might have seen these around a hundred and seven facts about something.
Rym: These are actually super good videos.
Rym: so my thing of the day is 107 Bojack Horseman facts And it's just a hundred and seven interesting things about Bojack Horseman.
Rym: the show and it ranges from like.
Rym: did you notice this thing in?
Rym: Background of this one episode - did you know this guy worked out it like Michael Eisner or something something like that kind of stuff.
Rym: it's a Fascinating and it's only like 20 minutes long.
Scott: Okay, so I didn't know about this until very recently But in 2014 there was this short Toy Story movie.
Scott: There was like 20 minutes long called Toy Story.
Scott: that time forgot.
Scott: All right It's a TV.
Scott: I think it was on TV, but I guess there's a booray now or something.
Scott: So you can watch this thing if you haven't seen it already.
Scott: Apparently despite only being like 20 minutes long it took them like forever to make it because it's Toy Story level quality.
Scott: It's like 20 minutes long.
Scott: right it was a big effort And it's sort of about this story Involving like these other toys that are called like the battle sores or something and you know they don't know that their toys and the Toy Story toys at the fight with them, or you know typical typical kind of story anyway.
Scott: so You know this is fictional toy within the Toy Story world known as a battle sore.
Scott: right that is this in this short 20-minute thing.
Scott: now Presumably if you're a toy in the Toy Story world you also have a cartoon right?
Scott: I'm sure there's a Buzz Lightyear cartoon that you can watch if you're in the Toy Story world.
Scott: so there's a. Theoretically there would also be a battle source cartoon.
Scott: And what would the opener of that battle source cartoon look like if it existed well here?
Scott: It is.
Scott: I'm not sure if this is actually part of that Movie the 20-minute movie or I heard.
Scott: maybe this was just because I've only seen this video on YouTube.
Scott: I think it was also.
Scott: may have just been a special feature on the bure if you got it Right, but what this is is theoretically the opener to battle sores right the Fictional toy in the fictional Toy Story universe.
Rym: I'm kind of into that.
Scott: Why is this notable?
Scott: Why do we care about this thing?
Scott: it's just a cute little.
Scott: animation is not very long right.
Scott: it's like 44 seconds of animation because This 44 seconds of animation was animated by Studio trigger and therefore it is a thing of the day worthy.
Rym: Yeah, that might save anime.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: So there you go in the meta moment.
Rym: We have a patreon and you should back it listen to the show after the end of the credits because I Say the names of people back there and possibly do some dumb stuff, too.
Scott: If you're really so foolish is to give us money.
Scott: I'm not gonna tell you no, but I'm gonna be like why?
Scott: Why we're using that?
Scott: we have money.
Scott: Why are you giving us money?
Scott: well, you probably have less money than we have but you have more money than we have.
Rym: call me if Everyone who listens to geek not just based on the stats.
Rym: I have gave us just one dollar one penny One penny one dollar a month.
Rym: That's actually enough money to start funding like some cool stuff.
Rym: and Also, we're gonna use this as an excuse to for real start up the you tennis show again.
Rym: I've already been doing some pre-production and we're making a bunch of other videos and content Like we're gonna start.
Rym: the bigger that patreon gets the more things other than GeekNights.
Scott: We're gonna do Also, you can buy GeekNights t-shirts made at Amazon store.
Scott: That's not a total waste of money, but it's still.
Rym: it's Classic GeekNights shirt that actually we sold like a couple hundred of those things back in the day And I've hardly ever seen anyone wearing one ever Partly because we sold them a long time ago and we only go to a few cars.
Scott: How many of you sold an Amazon?
Scott: so far of five?
Scott: There you go.
Scott: That's a good number.
Scott: Yeah, well cuz we relaunch.
Rym: what I expect now We don't have.
Rym: we have class.
Scott: wasn't one of those sold by you to you?
Rym: Yeah, one of those I bought.
Rym: so for I bought to make sure that they were good quality.
Scott: Do you have it?
Rym: Uh No, it actually didn't arrive yet Isn't it from Amazon?
Scott: shouldn't be here in two days?
Rym: No, because apparently so many people are doing the Amazon merch thing that they're way backed up.
Scott: Okay, but anyway, so yeah, uh, four people bought them good.
Scott: Yeah, it shouldn't be a large number.
Rym: It's no case shirt.
Rym: I like the shirt a lot.
Rym: It's actually.
Rym: it's a better poster, but it's pretty good shirt.
Rym: Yeah, if you wanted to share your geek that has posters left.
Scott: Uh, yeah somewhere forgot that we made them until just now.
Rym: I was thinking about reprinting them because those are actually easy.
Rym: I could have a box of posters in the apartment.
Rym: I'm not gonna have a box of t-shirts across like 15 different sizes and two different colors.
Scott: We should maybe we should make our website look like those posters instead of rebrand.
Rym: Ah I would actually be kind of into that.
Rym: Yeah, I like that style a lot.
Rym: Emily did that design right.
Rym: the book club book was the Wheel of Time.
Rym: we read the first book.
Rym: You should listen to that and read the first book.
Rym: We since read the first four books.
Rym: We're gonna do a patreon backers only show of the first four books of the Wheel of Time.
Rym: So you got to be giving us at least a dollar.
Rym: you're not gonna hear that one unless someone pirates it which I guess I'm not gonna sue you.
Scott: It'll still be Creative Commons licensed if you want to share it.
Rym: Go ahead Yeah, but it'll only be in patreon.
Scott: I guess we'll only link to it from there.
Scott: So it's basically honor system.
Scott: Yeah, I mean because really you're dumbass if you give us money, I don't really care.
Rym: I've also I've pirated things in my life.
Rym: So if someone pirates my stuff, I have basically no ground to stand on At all.
Scott: You can't pirate something that's Creative Commons licensed.
Rym: I am nothing.
Rym: if not It's not.
Rym: even if you don't if you don't give attribution, that's true motherfuckers.
Scott: Yeah, I would be pissed if someone like You know Unattributed that would be like.
Rym: really it's like I'm like I've found like websites that have our Content occasionally like a YouTube channel that has the audio from one of our episodes with a different title Not attributing us with one view, but the audio is there which has us attributing ourselves in it.
Scott: I guess if they ripped out us saying who we were and put it in something else.
Scott: That would be weird.
Rym: Yeah extra weird.
Rym: Yeah Luckily, we're pretty We've done a lot.
Rym: So it'd be really hard to pretend you were us at this point.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: And last but not least we are going to be at magfest Without me going to magfest.
Rym: I'm gonna continue to sort that out But we're gonna be at a bunch of panels and probably do one or two lectures.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Scott: I'm mostly just gonna play games at magfest.
Rym: Oh, yeah my modus operandi.
Scott: We should organize some of like our own tournament.
Scott: We should I?
Scott: we should either do magical drop or You know Star Wars.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you want to do some for real tournaments?
Rym: Yes among us and ours because other than that and doing panels my modus operandi is getting space war Way way.
Rym: Oh, we're gonna play a shit ton of space war.
Rym: I tend to get way drunk at magfest wander around playing arcade games That's and at least one Eclipse game we should come up with like a point system.
Scott: It's like, you know like this game of settlers is worth ten points for the winner and so and no points for anyone else and so on and then Keep score for all of magfest.
Rym: We will.
Scott: if we're gonna do that We should make like a good and then we can declare a winner of magfest.
Rym: in the very least We should make a Google form because people who for people
Scott: entering the game that they played who played who won
Rym: exactly Cuz then
Scott: I really need to know is game played who was in it and who won
Rym: and that way we can after the fact Sit down and figure stuff out like alright Scott won like 50 games a wizard, but Rym won the Eclipse game.
Scott: And we can also do stuff like play dig-dug whenever you feel like.
Scott: Post your high score for the weekend and then we can see who is the best at dig-dug over there.
Rym: I almost kind of want to start a subterfuge game like three days before magfest.
Scott: No, I don't think I'm gonna play subterfuge again.
Scott: It's just too time-consuming and distracting.
Scott: It's a good game But it's just like it eats your whole life and all your attention and it sort of messes up everything else in your life while You're playing one.
Rym: There was a one moment where I remember I was laying in bed.
Rym: I was looking at subterfuge and I could see that Andrew was online.
Scott: I turned off the notifications for the last two days and that was great cuz.
Scott: I only checked it like twice a day And he didn't mess my life up anymore.
Scott: But I really couldn't do anything much and I'd open it up and be like, oh look at all the shit that happened.
Scott: Fuck me.
Scott: You couldn't win doing it like that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well you you mr Literally everyone told me that you tried to make an alliance of everyone against Rym immediately But that's neither here nor there.
Rym: That's GeekNights Tuesdays.
Rym: This is GeekNights Wednesdays, so I don't know how long this will actually be.
Scott: but this topic is something that He thought it was a good idea for a show and I have nothing to say.
Rym: I didn't have a better idea for a show.
Scott: You know, I have better ideas for shows.
Scott: You just haven't read or watched any of the things that are better ideas for shit.
Rym: You haven't read or watched any of the things that I also have better ideas for show.
Rym: So that's the problem.
Rym: We I guess we'd go to the Dave and Joel format of we watch completely separate things and review them separately next to each other.
Scott: But I just gave the things that I just read.
Scott: I just gave to you to read.
Rym: you're gonna read them I'm gonna read them then we'll do the thing on them.
Rym: So but so Recently, I've decided that I'm gonna change the way.
Rym: I talk about something very specific and that is anime and manga.
Rym: I'm not gonna use the word manga anymore and I'm at all Pretty much, I'm not gonna use the words anime and manga when I talk about this stuff
Scott: because you just did yeah
Rym: and I'm trying I'm gonna try to break away from that because I don't think calling something anime
Scott: and
Rym: Meaning that it is Japanese animation made in Japan is a worthwhile distinction anymore.
Scott: I don't care.
Rym: Yeah, but that that's it.
Rym: I don't care.
Scott: I mean, it's useful to me because you know that it makes the.
Scott: It makes like when I'm searching for a show to watch.
Scott: It makes a lot more organized if that's separated out the animes from the not animes.
Scott: But
Rym: the majority of the animation I watch is not anime and in a lot of the rest of the world
Scott: for me It is and
Rym: in a lot of the rest of the world as we've often done It talked about in our panels like in Italy Anime, they call Adventure Time.
Rym: anime just means animation usually foreign animation.
Scott: So Sailor Moon fan subs I don't think there's too much Italian animation.
Scott: I mean, there's got to be some.
Scott: but yeah I've never heard.
Rym: but Sailor Moon fan subs are next to like that you want.
Scott: if you have you know The awesome Italian animation hook me up because I want to see it.
Scott: In fact the same goes if you know the best animations from any country.
Scott: that isn't Japan the United States France or Ireland or Russia.
Scott: Those are all the countries.
Scott: I've seen good animations from.
Scott: if you have good animations from other countries I know they exist.
Scott: Please tell me I want to watch them.
Rym: but so answer man.
Scott: actually today Canada Canadian I was also.
Scott: I've seen their enemy.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot of animation.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Rym: so answer man today actually because I read this earlier has an article that was sort of got me thinking about this concept and the Question was you should read answer man, by the way, if you're an anime fan, I'm gonna keep saying anime.
Rym: I'm just gonna mean something.
Rym: I can't stop saying anime.
Rym: The Christopher asked the answer.
Rym: man with the anime otaku industry being a fairly robust fandom in the West I was wondering is that mirrored for Western animation cartoons over in Japan?
Scott: Well, we Emily's told us that they have Cartoon Network in Japan and the dubs are really good.
Scott: Yeah, but I've seen some Dexter's lab Japanese and man the dub is really good?
Rym: Yeah it is.
Rym: but are there groups that work on fan subbing episodes of things like you see the universe or No, because they just have dubs of everything on their real TV like Simpson like they know.
Scott: Simpsons are everywhere in the world.
Scott: It's not like you know.
Rym: But he but the question card you never chose.
Scott: everywhere in the world Disney shows.
Rym: everywhere in the world Is there a fan culture like we have in the u.s.
Rym: And his answer is something that I've seen mirrored in other places and echoed around the world is that?
Rym: no It's pretty much only Americans that go like apeshit and weird about anime fandom Like anime fandom being its own things separate in the u.s.
Rym: Fandom of animation specifically and only from Japan.
Rym: That doesn't really happen everywhere else.
Rym: It's just America that does this to the degree that it does because a community arose, right?
Scott: It's it's because the history right is.
Rym: there was You know World War two, right?
Rym: Well band military brats and military servicemen coming back to the States having watched a bunch of anime while they were stationed there Right and they formed a communities in the United States to watch this stuff.
Scott: Whereas other countries say, I don't know like France It's like they didn't get the anime as early as we did.
Scott: there wasn't a community there formed around it.
Scott: They got it when it started being exported.
Scott: the same way It's being exported now and it was just to everyone at once.
Scott: suddenly, you know, they went from zero to hero.
Scott: we had this in-between part where there was a this, you know society built around it and the.
Scott: the current anime culture in the United States is simply the enlargement and you know Evolution of that original community that did not exist elsewhere
Rym: notice the primary complaint from anime fans who actually care about anime specifically from Japan when it comes to fan culture that the fan culture of anime in the US is if you Look at the convention scene the forum scene anything like that has expanded to include pretty much all.
Rym: Animation like Steven Universe stuff was is one of the biggest cosplays at anime cons in the u.s.
Scott: That's the kind of thing is talked about because a lot of the people now who happen to like anime they are not Originally coming from that, you know community.
Scott: They're coming it You know, they're just fans of animation who are coming into the community from the outside to go to the convention.
Scott: So imagine they didn't grow from you know, a fan sub place, you know.
Rym: imagine anime fan conventions in a world where that generic outside influence never came in and Anime cons would basically be identical to like Star Trek cons and sci-fi cons the deep
Scott: some of them
Rym: are yeah Deeply insular kind of like really outside of mainstream culture kind of weird and kind of inaccessible to outsiders, but instead anime cons became animation comic
Scott: cons
Rym: in a super general sense and I actually realized something and I hadn't thought about before because for a while like I've vacillated between Anime cons should probably focus on anime and let generic conventions like ConnectiCon be the fans of whatever conventions.
Rym: But in that world there is almost no reason to have an anime con anymore at all Like even less of a reason than have sci-fi cons because there's so few Actual anime that would come out where someone would have interesting content to present.
Rym: like there's no reason to have a panel.
Rym: How many times can you talk about Evangelion?
Scott: Hmm I mean the reason the conventions existed in the u.s In the first place was in order to like copy all your fan sub tapes with other people.
Scott: Yep, right, so we don't need to do that anymore.
Scott: And then it was.
Scott: well, even though we have you know, anime available It's not widely available.
Scott: We'll screen it here.
Scott: Well now you can just watch it on Hulu all of it and and then it was.
Rym: this is a niche fandom.
Rym: so if you want like lit crit or Analysis or like lectures or like academic interesting content anime consoles where was that?
Rym: like you'd go see Fred Schott.
Rym: reason
Scott: for an anime condom exist is for anime fans to get together and be with each other and have a good time and Cosplay because you can't really do that anywhere or take pictures of cosplay and do other fun events that you can't do Unless you're physically with other people like maybe play some games and those sorts of things and all the other things that do happen Don't really need to happen.
Scott: that there can just be on YouTube or you know They don't.
Scott: it's like there's.
Scott: no you don't need to have the con for those things to happen.
Scott: So it's like yeah, you can have your con but it you know, and I guess that you know that you to meet guests.
Scott: Right, there are people that you can see an anime con even though people mostly seem to care about the American voice actors.
Scott: But that's but I mean that's still a reason to go right?
Scott: is this?
Scott: their people will come Who oh, you know and make a public appearance and you want to enjoy their public appearance and have them entertain you and they need To be paid to do that and a con will bring up the money from all your entry fees in order to make that happen.
Rym: So in the modern era why not have the Steven Universe fandom also there.
Rym: Is there any good reason why not?
Scott: No, I mean there was a matter.
Scott: it's Pete, you know people getting together in a place to enjoy what they enjoy.
Scott: So if you know there if people if all the people who enjoy say a also enjoy be like I imagine Most of the people who like Adventure Time probably like Steven Universe.
Scott: How many people are there that are like Adventure Time only or Steven Universe only actually?
Rym: What's weird is a lot of people who are deep into Adventure Time that I see and even some people we know Once they saw Steven Universe.
Rym: It's like they forgot what Adventure Time was and decided Steven Universe is great and Adventure Time sucks Because it vented.
Rym: I'm suck there because Steven Universe has a straight forward direct narrative and Adventure Time is cool and experimental.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, but I've had some arguments.
Scott: You liked it for all those years and now suddenly you just change your mind.
Rym: Yeah, I've had some arguments.
Scott: That's like the people who are like can we be up was good until it got popular.
Scott: It's like that guy.
Scott: the show is the same show.
Scott: It doesn't change.
Scott: It's the same animation.
Scott: It can't change quality doesn't change over time.
Scott: Yeah anyway.
Rym: So here's here's what I'm getting at.
Rym: the only distinction between Anime anime at an anime con and Steven Universe and anime con is that the people and studio that made that anime were owned by a Japanese interest in Japan and I had to be kind of circumspect there because a lot of animation gets outsourced to Korea.
Scott: Is that anime now or other places?
Rym: Yeah, so if the only distinction is this specific?
Rym: View of made by Japanese people in Japan Which is being blurred by the fact that the world is modern and global Then the only reason to have an anime con that exactly
Scott: you have to admit that what you know It's not necessarily the fact that it was made in Japan in Japan by Japanese people.
Scott: It's that the kind of an animation that is made By, you know for a Japanese audience not even necessarily by Japanese people or by Japanese studio, right?
Scott: That is you know called anime Duh has certain genres tropes styles, even though I know that there's no uniform anime style true But I but there are certain tropes and certain characteristics of those animations versus other animations.
Scott: Not that other animations of other countries don't you know completely exclude those tropes.
Rym: But so what about shows like walk through?
Rym: From France that have all those tropes and might as well be an anime except they're not made in Japan Like they're in that same, you know quote-unquote bad show.
Scott: I don't like it.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm saying it has all those tropes.
Rym: Why is that not welcome that an anime con?
Rym: because again you're getting back to this.
Scott: Why would you not welcome it?
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it's not anime The people who want to make the definition.
Rym: I feel like there's no purpose for anime cons being restricted based on Japan.
Scott: Hmm it's a conventions.
Scott: people are getting together to have a good time and enjoy the culture that they share.
Scott: if this culture that They share they will enjoy it in that space that they come together.
Scott: It's not about.
Scott: but you know, it's not the culture that part doesn't come first.
Scott: It's the people come first, right?
Scott: It's you get the like-minded people whatever they have.
Scott: like-minded is what they're gonna do.
Scott: Right if you went to a sci-fi con a while a long time ago It would have been like mostly Star Trek shit and Ray Bradbury shit.
Scott: And if you go to one now, it's probably gonna be like the exact same people and nothing's changed.
Rym: maybe.
Rym: but yeah I've been to sci-fi cons.
Scott: It's like, you know this newer like if you go to fantasy con It's like they're.
Scott: you know, maybe before they were all Lord of the Rings and now they're all Game of Thrones And it's just you know, the things change.
Scott: But it's those people whatever the people that are coming to the convention that community whatever that community that's getting together enjoys.
Scott: That's what they're gonna celebrate while they're there Even if even if you kept it to just anime it used to be for my Locomist and then it was Naruto and now it's something else.
Rym: It's like okay last night Emily and I were watching a whole bunch of AMVs and It that was interesting because at this point I feel like people still call and like they say AMV.
Rym: But most of the new things like that they're being made are all to like Steven Universe and Adventure Time and Bojack and stuff Like that, okay, and but I found remember that older right now one.
Rym: Yeah That was like the biggest deal AMV back in the day because none of the shows in that anyone.
Rym: Oh, no, we were watching it and Emily and I were like, wow Literally no one in anime con would know who the fuck Ryoga is like.
Rym: this doesn't make any sense to anyone in the modern era except us old people.
Rym: So it's I guess you're.
Rym: it's hard to stop saying anime Because it's so widely used.
Rym: but I'm no longer gonna call manga mock comics or comics.
Rym: I'm just gonna call any sort of like sequential art like that a comic not gonna try to make a distinction For manga just because it was made on the eye in the islands of Japan.
Scott: I don't just think it because it's made in Japan.
Scott: I just think manga because When manga is produced in a different way, right then paying people even less.
Scott: Well, yes paying people even less.
Scott: but the fact that it's weekly and in black and white and produced rapidly right results in You know a different, you know There are certain qualities that you will get in that kind of production that you do not get in.
Scott: You know a comic made in the US and Marvel where it's a monthly pamphlet.
Scott: Yeah, but it's a different result doing things that way and therefore even though it's still sequential art That makes it a different genre.
Scott: not the fact that it's from Japan But the fact the way it's produced was you know causes certain characteristics that make it a different genre.
Scott: or at least, you know Section even if you like I both have superheroes like a superhero is a genre.
Scott: you could have a superhero manga and an American superhero comic, but the superhero manga will be Significantly different but you could say the same the American version because of that distinction.
Rym: Like there are words to talk about French comics.
Rym: French comics have the same thing like on day dizzy name.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, that's why they call them bond a dizzy name because I'm probably pronouncing that wrong.
Rym: That's close enough.
Scott: But here's a big fancy ass book and it's like.
Scott: the way they produce it is so different.
Scott: you get a different result that you would never see.
Scott: but someone making a comic in the US although people in America I mean in the US could make an album just like the way the French do they just don't.
Rym: But most people in America even comics fans even people who know a lot about it.
Rym: Don't call them bond as they call them comics.
Scott: Calm bond, isn't it?
Rym: You do you're weird.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: but the thing is when I get a French comic It's not in that format anymore.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: It's in like a trade paperback if it was still in that big-ass book.
Scott: I thought use that word to refer to those big-ass books.
Rym: Yeah I've seen a lot of those that are.
Rym: When I was in high school taking French class there was a kid name was Sean and We had to pick French names for the class, you know, like language classes name from us.
Rym: So he was like croissant and the teachers like you can't call yourself croissant and he Made a big fucking deal about that and eventually like the school said alright fine.
Rym: He can call himself croissant.
Rym: you can't stop it croissant.
Rym: and That like I. just I called that guy croissant for like four years even outside class.
Rym: Yeah a-plus My hero it became his name.
Scott: What's up croissant?
Rym: And on that note we killed enough time with the topic of little piston people off and will have Consumed.
Scott: him seems to care a lot about this.
Scott: I don't give a shit Wilkins Wilkins I just it's.
Rym: I feel like anime cons that try to focus on just Japan in the u.s.
Rym: In the modern era.
Rym: edge into this like fetishizing Japan area.
Scott: people have been fetishizing Japan for a long ass time.
Rym: Yeah Since I discovered that it existed and I feel like there's almost zero value to conventions around that in the modern Era, I mean Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But now we'll have consumed some shared media and we'll have a topic of a review of some kind on the next Wednesday.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: This episode's patreon patrons are in order of the amount of money they give us Rebecca Dunn Nicholas brand out James David White Christian Coombs, Jessica L Barlow mechanical mine Finn Eric Solver odd Rym eats poop Edgar Mendez William Eisen rose Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire Samuel Cordery Daniel Redmond Chris hadad Doug Snyder Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: and Now I present to you as promised in the Kickstarter page something Super dumb.
Media: It was the baby.
Media: I stole from Rando princess adora princess adora.
Media: You remember the baby the baby.
Media: we broke into the palace that time.
Media: It was the only time me and you work together.
Rym: Yes, I remember.
Scott: Yes the baby.
Rym: Oh, yes the baby.
Rym: Yes What the baby skeleton you remember.
Media: you must remember.
Media: it was that one time.
Media: Remember I was having a hard time with the vehicle couldn't get the jetpack flying on them on them You remember?
Scott: Oh Yes, the baby of course The baby.
Media: What the baby Skeletor think the baby you remember?
Media: we spent we spent hours looking for a crib And we made it.
Media: we fashioned a crib from from ostrich feathers.
Media: You remember we took a little bit of the hay and ostrich.
Rym: It was the only time Skeletor Remember?
Media: remember the milk.
Media: you remember having to nurse the baby, right?
Media: What?
Media: Skeletor it was your plan.
Media: you you drew up.
Media: you drew up the plans in front of me.
Media: It took like three hours Skeletor.
Media: mostly you were just standing there saying take the baby take the baby You.