Rym: It's Thursday, November 12th, 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: The Patrons got to pick the topic, and the topic is food related.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So way back at PAX, we met a friend, cool game guy, and the game guy knew that I played Civ 5 and invited me to play a GMR game of Civ 5.
Rym: Giant multiplayer robot.
Rym: That's that thing that'll basically, instead of using Pit Boss or all the janky ways that Civ 5 actually does that that seem to have problems, it basically just, you play your turn, hot seat, and then it automatically takes the save file, does everything to arrange everything.
Rym: It's like I get a notification on the desktop, I launch Civ 5, I take my turn, and everything's just handled and it just works.
Rym: And this was way back after PAX Prime, and I was too busy, so I was like, "Sorry, I can't join this
Rym: game.".
Rym: A few days ago, and it's been a long time since PAX Prime, a second game is starting up, because that first one I think is winding down, or has ended, so that's about how long these games take, I think, and I've joined it, and so far I've taken two turns in this.
Scott: You built your settlement with your settler.
Rym: Which is fucking bullshit, because I'm the Ottomans, and I didn't start on a coast.
Scott: And then you moved your worker, maybe got him started working.
Rym: I'm not a worker.
Rym: You don't start with a worker.
Scott: No, you got a warrior.
Rym: Yeah, I got a warrior.
Rym: I moved my warrior north, and then north again, and I did find a ruin.
Rym: They're not called huts.
Rym: So I'm headed toward that ruin.
Scott: I call them huts.
Rym: Yeah, because you played old Civs.
Scott: And what did you start producing in your settlement?
Rym: I started building a monument.
Scott: Another warrior?
Rym: Nope, a monument.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: I'm going to some early culture, and I got to find a coast, or I'm done.
Rym: I can't wait.
Scott: If you need to find a coast, shouldn't you build a warrior to explore more?
Rym: No, I would build a scout, which is what I'm building after I finish my monument.
Rym: I want the monument, so I'll start getting culture.
Scott: What do you got near you?
Scott: Some horses, maybe?
Rym: I got a whole bunch of things that require calendars.
Rym: I got incense, and I think indigo or dyes, so I need a calendar.
Scott: That early game settlers.
Scott: Not even thinking about tanks.
Scott: Or radio.
Rym: But yeah, the Ottomans' power is basically, naval units don't cost you shit to maintain, so I really need to be on the coast.
Rym: That's like, that's it for me.
Rym: That's it for Turkey.
Rym: So before we get into what we're actually doing the show on, Scott, you got any news?
Scott: So there's this dude, Robert Fidler.
Scott: Fidler?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: He's an old dude.
Rym: Robert Fidler is a pretty good name.
Scott: He's 66 old dude, right?
Scott: And he, you know, he's the kind of person who knows how to build a house.
Scott: And he lives in England, right?
Scott: In Surrey, Redhill, whatever.
Scott: And, you know, he knows construction.
Scott: Obviously he's a retired old dude.
Rym: Obviously he built something crazy or a park-like story happened to him, is my guess.
Scott: So he knows that if you just build some random house, you can't just do that.
Scott: He needs to be approved and whatnot.
Rym: I can't just like start throwing up a tree for it, like this is my house.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So he built a giant pile of hay bales, you know, which is totally OK to have on your property.
Scott: I guess.
Scott: If you have a big old property.
Scott: To hide the fact that behind the hay bales, he was building what can only be referred to as a castle.
Rym: That is amazing.
Scott: So he built a castle, a mock Tudor castle behind this giant hay bale.
Rym: Mock Tudor is like mock duck.
Scott: Yeah, to live in and be awesome.
Scott: And he knew he wasn't supposed to do it.
Scott: That's why he put up a giant pile of hay bales.
Scott: But he thought, you know, one of those people who sort of like thinks about these laws that don't exist.
Scott: He thought that, like, if it existed for so many years that then they couldn't make him take it down.
Rym: Are they making him take it down?
Scott: So, yeah, eventually he took down his hay bales, like, oh, my castle's been here long enough, shove it.
Scott: And so a high court judge agreed, saying he would be jailed for his defiance if the property is not demolished by June.
Rym: That's so sad.
Rym: Like, on one hand, I want building codes.
Rym: I don't want like the libertarian nightmare of people's houses just like burning down because they made him out of hay or whatever.
Scott: But he used hay to hide an actual castle almost.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time, I want people who want to do something cool like that to be able to do it.
Scott: Well, I guess he didn't do it properly.
Scott: He should have gotten permits and, you know, code inspections and all those sorts of things.
Scott: He could have done it.
Scott: But he didn't.
Rym: Yeah, I wonder if this is going to end with him going to jail rather than tear down his castle.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure they're going to, if he goes to jail, they'll tear down the castle while he's in jail.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: I wonder if the locals will try to protect his castle.
Scott: I don't think they like the castle.
Rym: Or if he is the local crackpot.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's that one.
Scott: That's the one.
Rym: So we have ideas for Thursdays and we forget them.
Rym: So whatever we were going to do this show on last week that we knew was like the best fucking idea for a Thursday show ever.
Rym: Can't remember it.
Rym: So it's gone forever.
Rym: We'll never do it now.
Rym: But Scott had the good idea of let's ask the listener who's paying us on Patreon.
Rym: Let him or her just pick what the show is.
Scott: This is a genius idea for many reasons.
Scott: Reason number one saves me a lot of work.
Scott: I don't have to think up a stupid show idea.
Rym: Yeah, instead you sit here and bitch and argue about how all the ideas they submitted are impossible and we can't do them.
Scott: They're garbage ideas.
Scott: You guys suck.
Rym: I think they're great ideas and you guys are awesome.
Scott: Rims is trying to curry favor.
Rym: Not one, I like curry.
Rym: And two, I think we could do a full 40 minute show on any of these topics.
Scott: I do not believe that.
Scott: Also, it's the greatest scam in the earth.
Scott: Just like running an orchard, apple orchard, and people pay you to go apple picking.
Scott: It's like they're paying you to do your job.
Scott: You're paying me to tell me a show idea.
Scott: Hey, Scott.
Scott: So I don't have to come up with one.
Scott: That is the greatest scam.
Scott: Thank you.
Rym: You want to buy this monkey's paw right here?
Rym: You're going to get exactly what you want from this monkey's paw.
Scott: It's like someone found a monkey's paw.
Scott: How many times can I use the monkey's paw?
Rym: They're like, I wish Rym and Scott would do an episode on zombies again.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: Fine, we'll do an episode on zombies again.
Scott: It'll be some shitty garbage episode.
Rym: And the whole time?
Rym: You asked for it.
Rym: The whole time, you have to remember in your head, you wanted this.
Scott: Right, like if I just do a show and it's bad, then it's like you guys are like, guys, why'd you do that stupid show?
Scott: But if you tell me to do the stupid show and you pay me to do it and I do it and it's stupid, it's like, that's what you asked for.
Scott: Now, what I'm actually really happy about- I'll be the monkey's paw rather than buying the monkey's paw.
Rym: We got actually a lot of submissions.
Scott: Quite a few.
Rym: Considering that I tweeted this like from work this morning and it's not that much later than when I tweeted it, we got a decent number of responses here.
Rym: The hitman very pointedly emailed me to say that he didn't submit pro wrestling to this because he doesn't want us to fuck it up basically by doing it unprepared.
Scott: I'm just going to talk about how it's fake and how it's hard to watch now that I'm old, but I understand it.
Rym: I actually have a lot to say about what I liked about it when I was a kid.
Rym: I was weirdly a big fan of Jake the Snake and The Undertaker and The Ultimate Warrior.
Rym: I was a fan of for some reason, but I never actually saw him wrestle.
Rym: So I don't know why I like knew a lot about him because he was not on the TV in my wrestling era.
Rym: Like he was before my wrestling time.
Scott: I was the biggest fan of Legion of Doom because they had like these red things, all these spikes all over it and it was badass.
Rym: See for some reason I like The Undertaker and I like the heels more than anything like I wanted bad guys to win all the time.
Rym: But anyway, so I didn't really come up with a rubric of how we were going to pick which of these shows to do and in the future.
Rym: what I'm going to do is take...
Scott: I figured that like most of them would be garbage shows that we've either already done or won't be long enough topics or aren't good Thursday topics and then only have like one left.
Rym: But what I want to do in the future probably is I'll do a two-step of first submit and then let's take them all and let everyone vote.
Rym: That way it'll force us like it'll be like we'll do a show on like the Baroque period of music because that's what you fuckers voted for.
Scott: I don't know anything about it.
Scott: Tell me a Baroque composer.
Rym: If it ain't Baroque.
Scott: You don't know a single one Mr.
Scott: Music Study whatnot.
Rym: I guess so...
Scott: I know a lot of composers.
Scott: I just don't know which ones are Baroque and which ones aren't.
Rym: You could do some Bach stuff like early Bach.
Scott: I like Bach.
Rym: Yeah, name anything Bach ever did.
Rym: Also which Bach?
Rym: Which Bach?
Rym: There's multiple Bachs.
Scott: JSJ.
Rym: Johann Sebastian J. Bach?
Scott: Joust Bach.
Rym: So next time I'll let you guys vote and just force us into one but what I decided to go with was.
Rym: I looked at the list and if anything was mentioned more than once like vaguely like if a category got more suggestions than anything else I figured we'd do that.
Rym: And sure enough there's a category that got more suggestions within its broad stroke than anything else and that category was food.
Rym: Eisenrode suggested just cooking like in general.
Scott: It's so general.
Scott: What is there to say?
Rym: Favorite dishes, cooking related mayhem, etc.
Scott: I don't have too many.
Rym: I have a lot.
Rym: Remember when Greg set that fire trying to fry an egg and the fire alarm went off and got kicked out of her apartment?
Scott: My favorite dishes.
Scott: Go to fancy restaurant.
Scott: Pay a lot of money.
Scott: Everything's delicious.
Rym: Remember our an unnamed friend who didn't know what that hood over the stove was and when you're supposed to turn it on?
Scott: Always.
Scott: With the stove just turn it on.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I got a lot of mayhem stories there.
Rym: Blank suggested Thanksgiving.
Scott: That's the show we're gonna do.
Rym: And George Patches.
Scott: I'm so sure that we had already done that show but we haven't and there's so much to talk about with that particular holiday.
Rym: George Patches said french fries.
Scott: There's not that much to say about that.
Rym: I got a lot to say about french fries.
Scott: I know George Patches and I know he loves him a french fry and is actually, if you want to eat a french fry, him making you a french fry in your kitchen is second only to the best french fries you can buy.
Rym: He's a man who respects the french fry.
Scott: He has practiced the making your french fry.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: So, full disclosure, I've never myself deep fried anything in my life and I don't plan to ever.
Scott: I've done it very few times and very carefully.
Rym: I've been around other people doing it like my parents making donuts or I mean I've done shallow frying.
Scott: It's usually a bad idea.
Scott: It's dangerous, messy and time consuming and difficult.
Rym: Well, wait till the day after Thanksgiving when there is the annual montage of people who burn their houses down trying to deep fry a turkey in the garage.
Scott: There are many mistakes that they make.
Rym: So, I do have some news and it's about french fries.
Rym: I'm going to make the french fries thing my news.
Scott: Instead of the topic, the news?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So, first off, Five Guys fries are not that good.
Scott: No, they're not.
Scott: They're just greasy and kind of nasty.
Scott: They make a big deal about how they use peanut oil and they have all these peanuts all over the place.
Rym: And yeah, peanut oil is superior for making french fries but that doesn't make the Five Guys fries good.
Scott: It is a very good choice for making french fries but Five Guys french fries is still not that good.
Scott: Oh, they also make a big deal about like all these Idaho potatoes they got in there.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: But they're not that good.
Rym: No, like the fries they're just like they're greasy.
Rym: You know what they're like?
Rym: They're like the fries you get if you go to like a food fair and there's some good food and then they also have fries.
Rym: So, they're kind of like half acidly made at a stand.
Scott: You know, there are certain deep fried foods where you get them when they're immediately fried and they're amazing because it's hot oil of deliciousness.
Scott: But if you let them sit for even a second it's like, "Oh, these are just really
Scott: garbagey.".
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Like a deep fried Oreo?
Rym: Do not let that get cold.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Like if that is, just throw it away.
Scott: But there are other deep fried foods like say a really good fried chicken where that shit's good cold out of the fridge next day.
Rym: Oh my, so Dirty Bird which is a deep like a fried chicken place near our office.
Rym: Like I guess it's a chain or whatever but we go there kind of often.
Rym: I always would just get fried chicken which was kind of bad because I ate a ton of fried chicken.
Scott: You don't want to do that.
Rym: And then I fall asleep at my desk.
Scott: I get fried chicken right on the corner of my street.
Scott: I don't even have to cross the street to get to it.
Scott: I only go there like once a month at the most.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: When I get fried chicken there I just fall asleep at my desk and like the whole day is ruined.
Rym: But I noticed one day recently that on their menu they have sandwiches which like normally when you go to a place that is like a fried chicken.
Scott: I was just at Schnippers.
Scott: I got the crispy chicken sandwich.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But when you're at a place whose thing is something like Fuddruckers makes mediocre burgers to only get burgers there.
Rym: Or you know like a fried chicken place makes fried chicken.
Rym: They had sandwiches heading in the menus.
Rym: I always ignore it.
Rym: But I looked under the sandwiches.
Rym: They actually only have one sandwich.
Scott: Fried chicken sandwich.
Rym: It's a fried chicken sandwich.
Rym: So I got it.
Rym: It's real good.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Dangerously good.
Rym: So I've been getting that now and I've been eating a lot of fried chicken.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: But McDonald's fries?
Rym: I used to like them as a kid.
Scott: You're doing the french fry show instead of your french fry news.
Rym: It is my news.
Rym: My news is that I'm doing the french fry show.
Scott: Well I thought you had some like actual french fry news.
Rym: I do but I'm going to get to that.
Rym: But McDonald's fries, this is my segue.
Rym: They were good when I was a kid and could still eat fast food.
Rym: But now that I don't go, like I have not had a McDonald's burger in many years.
Scott: I can't even remember.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like I do not eat that fast food.
Scott: It might even be like elementary school.
Rym: And the occasional time that I will eat that kind of fast food.
Scott: Oh I had one Burger King in the year like 2000.
Rym: Burger King is even worse.
Scott: It was at an airport.
Scott: It was Newark airport.
Scott: There was literally no other food.
Rym: I would just not eat.
Scott: I was getting on a very long flight.
Rym: I would still just not eat.
Rym: I'd eat the airplane food.
Scott: But it wasn't really a good area.
Rym: I would eat the airplane food on a domestic American flight before I would eat anything from a Burger King.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So as an adult, I ate like a McDonald's fry in the last couple of years.
Rym: And if you're, I guess they're good.
Rym: if you're able to eat shitty fast food and you crave that like.
Scott: You just want some salt and oil.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like the thing in your brain that says potato chips are great.
Rym: Just keep eating them.
Rym: Like that, you'll eat McDonald's fry and it'll taste real good.
Rym: If you haven't eaten that shit in a while, they are so disgusting.
Rym: They taste like the kind of food that a dystopian future would feed to its like underclass slaves in the 1984 universe.
Rym: So I basically only eat good french fries now, like Curly's fries on the shore.
Rym: Like, you know, a real good french fry.
Scott: A french fry made by George Patches here.
Rym: So there's a story here and there's a bunch of like other articles related to it.
Rym: And basically the gist of it.
Rym: Take this with a grain of salt because obviously it's a nutrition study.
Scott: I think you want to take more than a grain of salt on your french fries.
Scott: Quite a few grains.
Rym: You got to have it on one of those plates that's made out of salt.
Rym: That's not really necessary.
Rym: So it talks about how junk food, like garbage fast food, doesn't really correlate with obesity.
Rym: And there's a bunch of stuff about this.
Rym: How its number of calories eaten matters a lot.
Rym: But thin people actually eat garbage food at about the same percentage of their total diet as obese people do.
Rym: And it has this whole thing.
Rym: But then at the bottom there's something very interesting.
Rym: There's only one food where there is a difference in like the percentage of diet or like the frequency of eating between obese people, like morbidly obese people and normal people.
Rym: And that is french fries.
Rym: Only french fries are statistically significant there.
Rym: People, quote, the study showed morbidly obese people eat 50% more french fries than all other people.
Rym: Think about that.
Rym: All in this junk food study, only french fries were correlated with morbid obesity.
Scott: Let's just eliminate french fries.
Rym: I think part of the problem is that if you get a burger and fries at a fancy place, like a Shnippers, you get a reasonable amount of fries.
Rym: Like I'll eat the whole burger and all the fries they give me.
Rym: But if you go to like McDonald's, they basically give you like enough fries to be an entire meal on their own.
Rym: That's like 1,000 calories in there.
Rym: Maybe 2,000.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I just don't eat crab.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, you know, we do that anime openers panel at cons and we show like Italian Sailor Moon.
Rym: Well, this is a video from Italy.
Rym: It looks like it's an Italian boy band.
Rym: And they, their shtick, at least for this song, is Sailor Moon.
Rym: They dress up like Sailor Moon, but kind of like crossed with the Sailor Starlights from Sailor Stars.
Rym: Only you would know specifically.
Rym: They perform the Sailor Moon opener in Italian.
Rym: As far as I'm concerned, this is canon.
Rym: This is amazing.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Why don't they do a whole episode?
Rym: I think they should just, I think all 200 episodes of Sailor Moon should just be performed as live musical theater by these guys.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: That's your thing of the day?
Rym: That's my thing of the day.
Scott: Side note to that, there's a K-pop boy band, EXO.
Scott: They're like one of the most popular ones there is right now.
Scott: Maybe the most popular one there is right now amongst the Asian teenage girlies.
Scott: Some of their songs are good.
Scott: They are doing a promotion right now with, I guess, Kuri and Disney.
Scott: It is a Star Wars promotion.
Scott: So it's like K-pop plus, the song is called Lightsaber.
Scott: There's a video.
Scott: It doesn't have a lot of lightsabers in it, but it has a few.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Scott: It's a thing that exists.
Scott: that's just like, "Well, this
Scott: exists.".
Scott: All right.
Scott: So anyway, thing of the day.
Scott: You know Rod Serling, most people know him as the guy with the cool voice who talks at the beginning and end of your Twilight Zone episode.
Scott: And don't really know anything else about him.
Rym: I knew he was a chain smoker.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Most people were in those days.
Scott: That's how you get a voice like that.
Scott: Anyway, here's an awesome video of him being interviewed on a news program talking about censorship, which is relevant because a lot of people these days are having trouble understanding what censorship is and what it isn't.
Scott: And here's a person who knows exactly what it is telling you.
Scott: You know, why censorship is a problem, whose fault is it, etc.
Rym: All right.
Scott: It is relevant and also nerdy.
Rym: In the moment, the booklet book was The Wheel of Time.
Rym: We're still reading it.
Rym: I started up again past book four.
Rym: I'm almost done with book five.
Scott: Oh, I'm still way beginning with book five.
Rym: I am able to compartmentalize, so if we do a special show and talk about the first four, I can easily shut off the things I know from book five.
Scott: Yeah, I just stopped reading.
Rym: I'm reading comics now.
Scott: It's comic time.
Rym: Pretty much comes down to, "Whoa, you all just fucking know about Baelfire somehow.
Rym: Yeah, don't stop it.
Rym: Leave that
Rym: be.".
Scott: I'm in comic land now.
Scott: I'm not reading books now.
Rym: The problem was I was going to go back into comic land, and I will because we're going to do a comic episode next week, but I kind of read just enough of book five of The Wheel of Time to get past the "remember what's going on" and into new things happening.
Scott: I just finished.
Scott: I got into the new things happening with a little low gain action.
Rym: I'm more into like Garth Byrne or Brine or that guy.
Scott: Oh, he's hanging out?
Rym: Oh, he's...
Scott: I think I actually got to him too.
Scott: He's got like a manor, right, out in the middle of nowhere?
Rym: And now he's going off following some people.
Scott: I think that's actually where I stopped reading was just about that part.
Rym: Oh, so he keeps going off doing things, and it's leading towards some things, I think.
Scott: I think it's Brine or Brine.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: The only problem is... Ninuivinivinivine.
Rym: I just do not want her to be in these books anymore.
Rym: If I knew her in real life, I might stab her.
Rym: Even Matt I can deal with compared to her, but I digress.
Rym: We have a Patreon.
Rym: If you wanted to vote on the episode we did tonight, you should have been giving us money.
Scott: Or don't because that's a really bad use of your money.
Rym: All the suggestions we didn't do tonight, I'm going to keep in an ever-growing list for future votes.
Rym: So you paid for the privilege of suggesting that we do a show on, for example, Pitch me your vision of utopia assuming I have unlimited funds to invest and want Rym to be our leader from Lara.
Scott: Wait, why is Rym the leader?
Rym: If you want to have input into this, Scott, pay some money.
Rym: Fun fact, Scott can't see what I do on the Patreon unless he pays.
Scott: Can't you add my account to be an owner of that?
Rym: I don't actually know.
Rym: I learned Patreon just enough to get it going.
Scott: I made a free account.
Scott: Just go into the settings and add me as an administrator.
Rym: I'll go look it all.
Rym: I'll figure out how to do that stuff.
Scott: So then I can go and make fun of people.
Rym: Who paid us money because they're dumb.
Rym: So, somehow we didn't do an episode on Thanksgiving, which is...
Scott: I can't believe we didn't.
Scott: That makes no sense.
Rym: It's my favorite holiday.
Scott: Episode idea sent in by blank.
Rym: Yeah, it's the only blank one too.
Scott: Everyone else put who they were.
Scott: This person didn't.
Scott: But yeah, that's a terrific episode idea.
Scott: We can do plenty of talking about that and we haven't done it yet somehow.
Scott: And it's Thursday.
Rym: I have zero interest in the...
Scott: And Thanksgiving is also on a Thursday.
Rym: ...in the history of the holiday from a holiday perspective.
Rym: As far as I'm concerned, it is the holiday of when you're a kid, your family cooks a giant dinner and you hang out at grandma's house.
Rym: When you're an adult.
Scott: I always wondered, I'm sure I could just research this, but it always felt like, did this thing they claim happened on Thanksgiving?
Scott: Where the white people and the Native Americans made some peace and had a meal together and it was a good time.
Scott: Like, first of all, did that happen?
Scott: How frequently did it happen?
Scott: And why was this particular happening of it so significant and remembered to be a holiday for all time?
Scott: I get the feeling that Thanksgiving is really just kind of a racist holiday nowadays.
Rym: Except that stuff doesn't come up at all.
Rym: No one talks about pilgrims anymore.
Scott: Thanksgiving decorations really bother me a lot.
Scott: Especially the racist ones.
Scott: Why, you know, you should definitely complain about the Washington football team and especially the Cleveland baseball team.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: The Atlanta baseball team.
Scott: But go after this holiday, too.
Scott: I know some people are.
Scott: But, you know, the Washington football team seems to be getting hit the hardest and I feel like they should all be hit equally hard.
Rym: The problem with the Redskins, because that's their name.
Scott: They all suck.
Rym: The problem with them is that they, it's not like, the Chicago Blackhawks are in the edge of that, too.
Rym: Like, that's not the best name.
Scott: No, yeah, put them on the list.
Rym: But at least, so here's the difference.
Rym: Not that I'm excusing the Blackhawks, but there's a degree of one, the Blackhawks aren't saying, "Our name is not offensive.
Rym: Fuck
Rym: you.".
Rym: Like the Redskins are.
Rym: Two, Redskins, that's like blackface.
Rym: Like, that is way different than Blackhawks, which was nominally named not after the tribe, but after a World War II regiment, I believe.
Rym: Like, it's named after this military thing that themselves were in it.
Rym: Like, there is a history that you could talk about there and they're staying out of this argument.
Rym: Not like the Redskins that are trying to convince people that as far as they're concerned.
Scott: Weren't the Blackhawks formed before World War II?
Rym: I don't actually know.
Scott: The full story.
Scott: Their original six team, I believe.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And that's before World War II.
Rym: Maybe it was World War I. I don't remember.
Rym: I just remember trying to research that.
Rym: I was looking up the information to argue something about how the Redskins deserve the extra criticism they're getting.
Scott: The original six, right?
Rym: Canadian, Leaf, Ranger, Bruin, Blackhawk.
Rym: Hawks, Haki, T. I'm going to look up right now the origin of the Blackhawks name again.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Because 1926, World War I.
Scott: One, okay.
Scott: You said World War II.
Scott: I did.
Rym: I was right.
Rym: It was World War I. You were right and I was right, but I said the wrong World War.
Scott: That's okay.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: There's a difference between being called the Blackhawks because of this history versus being called-.
Scott: I knew that World War II happened after hockey was invented.
Rym: But yeah, all that aside, as far as I'm concerned, it is either the hang out with your family and have food holiday or the hang out with your family and friends and have food holiday.
Scott: Also football.
Rym: Also football.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: Also, the Lions play the only game I watch every year with them in it and I root for them and then they lose.
Scott: How many times have the Lions won on Thanksgiving?
Rym: I don't actually know what the stats are, to be honest.
Rym: It's more than one.
Rym: I remember the times they were up before halftime and lost by the end of the game.
Scott: You know, they suck this year, so they're probably going to lose again.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: I don't know who they're playing this year, though.
Rym: But I'm very happy that somehow the Lions have kept the tradition of that's their game.
Rym: That is a Thanksgiving tradition and they do the stupid thing where the turkey comes out and it has N turkey legs.
Scott: I haven't seen that on TV, actually.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm assuming it's still a thing because usually when halftime happens, I wander and eat a whole bunch of food from the table that has the potato chips and the sour cream dip.
Scott: M&M's.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Should we talk about Thanksgiving food?
Rym: Because I feel like we're in the food direction.
Scott: Well, people wanted food shows, right?
Scott: So Thanksgiving, you gotta make the turkey.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: You eat dark meat if you're a human being.
Scott: You eat white meat if you're not a human being.
Rym: I actually do like both on Thanksgiving.
Scott: I don't like white meat pretty much ever.
Rym: So you eat a bunch of dark meat.
Scott: Dark meat has deliciousness in it.
Rym: But you take white meat and you put gravy on it.
Rym: You don't put gravy on the dark meat.
Scott: How about you just don't eat white meat or the gravy because gravy is gross.
Rym: Gravy is delicious.
Rym: The fuck is wrong with you?
Scott: Not really.
Rym: Gravy?
Rym: The only thing better than gravy on turkey...
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: Gravy does taste, you know, it's not as bad as white meat.
Scott: Well, I put the gravy on the dark meat.
Rym: You wouldn't play God.
Scott: What's wrong with that?
Rym: But I'm gonna...
Scott: Also, I usually just eat the drumstick.
Rym: So we have a lot of traditions, like in the FRC, we'll actually do several around Thanksgiving, Thanksgivings that are just... We cook a full family Thanksgiving dinner.
Scott: Thanksgiving is pretty much the number one holiday, at least in the U.S.
Scott: I'm sure.
Scott: in other countries they don't have Thanksgiving, obviously, but they have other equivalent holidays that are basically the same goddamn thing with a different culture.
Rym: Well, actually the tradition goes back to England.
Scott: Some sort of harvest festival of autumn time, somewhere between September and December.
Scott: And you have lots of delicious food and your family gets together.
Rym: College millennial types.
Rym: We started doing this pretty early, but then it's obvious that a lot of people our age do the same thing.
Rym: People may or may not go home or do a family thing when you're in your 20s or 30s.
Rym: It's rare that the 20 or 30 year old is the host for their own family.
Rym: Usually you go home to mom or grandma or something like that.
Rym: But us and a lot of our friends will have alternate Thanksgivings around Thanksgiving just for their friends, but they cook the same family spread.
Scott: That would bring the leftovers from the previous, you know, you go on Black Friday, you hook up with everybody, maybe it's Black Saturday.
Scott: Everybody shows up, brings the leftovers from real Thanksgiving Thursday.
Scott: But remember last year we did- You're gonna feast, why not feast four or five times?
Scott: You got these four days off work.
Rym: Yeah, but I can't cook a whole turkey because even if I get like all our friends in New York together, a real turkey is still too much turkey.
Scott: You can get a little turkey, but it's still, it's just too much- You got to pre-order turkeys.
Scott: Usually those old ladies at the grocery store, you know how they do, they get the free turkey.
Scott: They buy all this stuff and they get points or whatever and they somehow get the free turkey, what the grocery store does.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I got the Wegmans free turkey one year at RIT.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, I took it home with me in an icebox and took it to Michigan.
Rym: But anyway, when we do the feast, we don't do a turkey.
Rym: What we usually do is either I'll make like four or five Cornish hens.
Scott: Some other bird, a ducks.
Rym: Yup, ducks.
Rym: Last year I did that crispy duck.
Rym: That was actually, I was real, a little spicy maybe, but I was a fan of that duck.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of people that take it too far.
Scott: Like the whole turducken thing, I think that's just like, it's just too much.
Rym: It's excessive.
Scott: It's just, it's like, that's like eating all the french fries at Conifado.
Rym: It's like the bacon worship thing.
Scott: It's like, yeah, everyone loves a feast, but you know, extreme food like that is supposed to be a joke.
Scott: It's not supposed to be for real.
Rym: Yeah, instead of doing the turducken, have like an ice Cornish hen, but you know, the turkey, you could cook that turkey any day.
Rym: The turkey's not the point.
Rym: The point is the sides.
Rym: You don't make real stuffing just all the time for dinner.
Scott: Yeah, it's a pain in the ass.
Rym: Yeah, and don't eat stove top.
Rym: That shit's poison.
Scott: But it tastes so good.
Rym: No, it's poison.
Rym: Don't eat it.
Rym: We ate it so much though, and it was good.
Rym: We did, and you know what?
Scott: If I made some right now, you'd eat it.
Rym: Yeah, it's like when you walk by McDonald's.
Rym: As much as I know that McDonald's is garbage poison, there's an animal part of my brain that says, "Yo, dog.
Rym: That is so much oil and
Rym: protein.".
Scott: I'm going to make some stove top, and you're going to get home, and it's going to be ready.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: I'll salivate in a Pavlonian fashion, and then I'll knock it on the ground and refuse to eat it because it's dangerous.
Scott: I think you'll eat it.
Rym: No, I can't.
Scott: I'll eat it.
Scott: Plus...
Rym: Maybe I'll buy some on the way home right now.
Scott: I haven't eaten it in years.
Rym: Well, you're going to melt your stick of margarine into it.
Rym: You can't use butter.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: Also, don't burn it.
Scott: It's all right.
Scott: I'm going to make stove top.
Scott: I'm going to buy some tonight, and that'll be the first time I had stove top in many years, and it'll be delicious.
Rym: Yeah, I can live stream eating the stove top.
Rym: Oh, I can taste it in my mouth now.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Scott: It's wet buttered bread.
Rym: The thing is, as much as stove top will trick me, Scott, it's the season for real stuffing.
Rym: When we do our feast...
Scott: Real stuffing is way better than stove top.
Rym: I almost want someone else to cook the bird this year so I can cook the stuffing because, honestly, fun...
Scott: You don't actually make the stuffing in the bird because that's stupid.
Rym: Yeah, there's a time and place for the stuffing in the bird.
Rym: The time and the place for that is grandma is making a gigantic turkey for your entire extended family, and grandma is going to put up with the old style of cooking a turkey for an entire day.
Rym: I'm not going to cook a turkey for 12 hours.
Rym: I'm going to cook a turkey for three hours.
Rym: So don't even try to make stuffing in a bird.
Rym: In fact, even when I made the stuffing in the Cornish hen, it was good, but it wasn't enough.
Rym: So, do you want to make the bird this year?
Rym: No.
Rym: Friends, who wants to make the bird for the New York feast, missus?
Rym: Because I kind of don't want to make the bird.
Rym: Maybe we should do one in Albany and get them to make the bird.
Rym: Get Pete to make the bird.
Scott: You can just pay someone to deliver one.
Rym: Yeah, that feels...
Scott: Boston chicken?
Rym: No, no, no, no.
Rym: I'm done with that nonsense.
Scott: Oh, sorry, they changed the name to Boston Market.
Rym: So what is the best side in Thanksgiving food?
Scott: Depends on whose house you go to.
Rym: In general, assuming they're all of equal grandma quality, what's the tops, other than stuffing?
Scott: I mean, everything is so equally good, right?
Scott: So I guess you got to start somewhere.
Scott: You got to start with the sweet potato, but not just any sweet potato.
Scott: The special extra candied sweet potato with perhaps honey, brown sugar, just sugar.
Scott: The candied yam or whatever you want to call it, you know, delicious sweet potato.
Rym: Yum, sweet potato, even just like squashes all cooked in that way where they're basically just a vehicle for honey and molasses and sugar.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: What else is delicious?
Scott: Maybe you got someone who makes a meatball?
Rym: I feel like the meatball, like the sweet meatball and the lo mein are a very...
Scott: Lo mein?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I've never seen lo mein on Thanksgiving.
Rym: I've seen many lo mein on Thanksgiving.
Scott: Whoa, I've never seen that.
Rym: It's basically just like Thanksgiving themed lo mein.
Scott: I've never seen that in my life.
Rym: It's a pretty common thing.
Scott: You know what, I will say the cranberry sauce, overrated.
Scott: It's a tradition, but usually someone buys a can of it, dumps it out, and no one eats it.
Rym: Look at that shit, it's disgusting.
Rym: It's still in the shape of the can.
Scott: Even if someone makes the fresh cranberry sauce, it's like, all right.
Rym: Well, here's what I've noticed.
Rym: In the Midwest and among heathens and Philsteins, what I see people do is they'll have the gelatinized cranberry sauce or the cranberry goop, and they slice it up and they eat it like it's its own thing.
Rym: That's not how you do it.
Rym: You know what you do?
Rym: You're supposed to put that on the white meat next to the gravy and have sort of like a moulange.
Scott: That's why I don't eat, first of all, don't eat the white meat.
Scott: Second of all, don't eat the cranberry sauce.
Rym: The cranberry sauce is an accent to the other sides or perhaps the main dish.
Scott: Just don't do any of that.
Scott: That's all bad.
Rym: Stuffing we've talked about, but...
Scott: Stuffing is way up there as well.
Rym: I like stuffings that have sweet, like golden raisins or cranberries or things like that.
Scott: I like any kind of stuffing as long as it is hot, wet breads of deliciousness.
Rym: The best stuffing in my opinion...
Scott: You can put in celeries, you can put in all kinds of stuff.
Rym: It is mostly celery and onion and really, really savory with a bunch of fucking cayenne pepper just like mashed in.
Scott: Whatever you put in that stuffing, you really can't ruin it as long as you forgot the wet bread.
Rym: I'm a big fan of the mashed potato filled with gravy.
Scott: You know, I do like a mashed potato, but I don't like it on Thanksgiving because it interferes with my yam of candy.
Rym: You know what though?
Rym: It can serve to protect the yam from other relatives or friends.
Rym: When I was a kid, my little brother would eat basically a milk jug's worth of mashed potatoes.
Rym: And I feel like that was the sacrificial dish that prevented him from eating all the stuffings so I could eat the stuffing.
Scott: You eat sacrificial dishes on the table like a veggie mix?
Rym: I feel like so...
Scott: A little asparagus to get someone distracted.
Rym: Every Thanksgiving, there's the big salad bowl with the salad.
Rym: I feel like most people take just enough salad to be polite and really the salad's just like everyone lying to themselves.
Rym: Just don't bother with the salad on Thanksgiving again.
Scott: But I do the salad.
Scott: I want salad.
Rym: You're the only one.
Scott: Like I scoop a nice big bowl of salad to eat before eating all the other good stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like I should just eat all the other nonsense foods on that day.
Scott: But I mean, you're making the same amount of food no matter what, so anything you don't eat today is just going to be a leftover tomorrow.
Rym: True, but the salad is the most leftover thing and it doesn't keep that line.
Scott: Great, so I can eat some salad tomorrow too.
Rym: Yeah, but salad by the third day is not great.
Scott: I'm not eating salad on the third day, but I'm still going to have a candied yam on the third day because I ate salad and I didn't eat ten times as many yams on day one and two.
Rym: A oft overlooked is you've got to have the biscuits or the rolls, the dinner rolls.
Scott: You need some kind of bread.
Rym: No, it can't just be bread.
Rym: I'm going to take a hard line.
Rym: People who have the toast or just bread or like garlic bread.
Rym: No, it's got to be.
Scott: No, garlic bread, what?
Rym: It's got to be dinner rolls, like the kinds that have the little crack in the top and you crack it open.
Scott: Any kind of nice breads will do.
Rym: I think roll is required.
Scott: I mean, you could make like the kind of bread I just made.
Scott: That'd be fine.
Rym: I feel like that serves a different purpose because that's not going to come out hot and you're not going to get an individual.
Scott: You can heat up bread without toasting it.
Rym: No, it's not the same thing.
Rym: It's not steamy inside.
Scott: You can also get bread that was just baked.
Rym: I feel like most people, the problem is dinner rolls get a short shrift because in the old days, like my grandma and every grandma I knew, they didn't have a microwave or if they did, it was a separate appliance.
Rym: And in the kitchen, they had a stove on the bottom that they cooked the turkey and the stuffing and everything in.
Rym: And they had the stove on the top that they cooked all the rolls in.
Rym: Most people do not have two ovens anymore.
Scott: I see a lot of people, they've got two ovens.
Scott: They got, you know, the regular oven and they got one like built into the wall somewhere.
Rym: Yeah, most people, that's a microwave.
Rym: The second oven is kind of rare.
Scott: Microwave is usually above the stove.
Scott: I'm talking about an oven like in a wall separate.
Scott: Who?
Rym: Name someone who has that as a second oven.
Scott: My friends, the Cohens.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I know at least one grandma who has it.
Rym: Yeah, you're naming grandmas and like older relatives.
Scott: There's plenty of people who got two ovens.
Scott: All kinds of kosher Jews, they got two everything.
Rym: Okay, yeah, kosher Jews.
Rym: So you've got the exception then.
Rym: Normal people do not have two ovens even though they should instead of a microwave.
Scott: Even though one's dairy and one's meat.
Scott: You could put a bread in the dairy one, no problem.
Scott: As Jen and I'm Passover, you just set it on fire.
Rym: Like if I had my druthers, I would get rid of our microwave and put a second convection oven up there just for making bread and rolls.
Scott: A convection oven is not a regular oven.
Rym: Yeah, but you can make a fucking roll in there just fine.
Scott: And a microwave is needed for things even though it is rarely used.
Rym: Most people reheat leftovers in the microwave and that is the worst way to do most leftovers.
Scott: Most leftovers, that is true, they come out worse in the microwave but sometimes, just ain't got time for that shit.
Rym: You know what, just wait, it's worth it.
Rym: It only takes like 10 minutes to preheat the oven.
Scott: I'm hungry right this second.
Scott: Microwave, and there's certain things that you can't eat at all without the microwave.
Rym: Just don't eat those things.
Scott: But they're delicious.
Rym: Like most Thanksgiving leftovers, you can have some turkey.
Scott: I actually only use my microwave for like one thing which is those plastic bags with Indian food in them.
Scott: And you make a rice in the rice cooker and you put the plastic bag in the microwave after cutting a little slit in it and then you dump the hot...
Rym: Or you just dump the plastic bag in boiling water.
Scott: I don't like that method.
Rym: Why?
Rym: That works just as well.
Scott: It's a pain in the ass.
Rym: No it's not.
Rym: But, I mean, like reheating leftovers, Thanksgiving leftovers, the best way to do it, set your oven to like 390/400.
Rym: Put all the leftovers like mashed into some thin tin foil and just throw it in the oven for like 5 minutes, maybe 10.
Rym: I can't think of a better way to reheat almost any Thanksgiving leftover.
Scott: The oven does preheat better than the microwave which makes everything mushy and bleh.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Oh, what other sides?
Rym: We're not even talking about desserts yet.
Scott: What about Thanksgiving?
Scott: things that aren't food related?
Rym: Like what?
Rym: You can hang out with your family.
Scott: Did anything ever happen onto Thanksgiving?
Scott: that was weird?
Scott: That was different from any other Thanksgiving?
Scott: For me, no.
Rym: I've never had the like racist uncle starts talking about how the Jews are stealing his money.
Rym: Like that never happens in my family.
Scott: That doesn't happen in my family either because anyone who's like that is just not invited.
Rym: Yeah, they're the other side of the family.
Scott: I don't understand this.
Scott: It's like people have someone in their family.
Scott: that's shitty and they feel some sort of obligation just because you share genetics with this person that you have to be with them on this holiday.
Rym: Yeah, your racist uncle, unfriend him on Facebook.
Rym: It's okay.
Scott: Yeah, it's like just because someone shares genetics relations with you, like they're a bad person, you know, maybe you have a really big family, just don't associate with them.
Scott: You're under no obligation whatsoever to do that.
Scott: Don't invite them to your house.
Scott: If they invite you, don't go to their house.
Scott: Don't talk to them.
Scott: Don't be friends with them.
Scott: And don't do anything with them.
Scott: They say, "Hey, how come you stopped talking to
Scott: me?".
Scott: And you say, "Because you're a crazy racist old uncle.
Scott: Go fuck yourself.
Scott: I don't want to talk to you because you're a horrible racist human being.
Scott: You're not my friend.
Scott: You're not anyone I want to be related to in any
Scott: way.".
Rym: See, it's interesting that that is like the meat.
Rym: Like that is a big meat.
Scott: It's that simple.
Scott: Problem solved.
Scott: And then when you hang out at your family gathering, sure, there's less people there.
Scott: But you're all having a good time because it's only good people that you actually care about.
Scott: And you don't have to give any of your delicious candied yams to some racist assholes.
Rym: I'm just amazed at the meme I see on a regular basis everywhere.
Rym: People talking about how going home for Thanksgiving is the worst because of racist Uncle Joe.
Rym: And you know how he's wearing his Trump hat at the table just waiting for anyone to say anything.
Rym: And like the Johnsons didn't want to invite him, but the Johnson Johnson's invited him anyway and they didn't tell him so he shows up.
Scott: If he shows up, don't let him in.
Rym: But half the people want him there.
Rym: No one wants to create a scene.
Scott: Anyone who doesn't, if he tries to create a scene, call the cops.
Scott: You just sit inside watching football while the cops arrest his ass.
Scott: And if anyone says no, they want him to be here, they're racist too.
Scott: Why are you letting them in?
Rym: I just get the impression most people's families are way more drama filled than all our families.
Scott: Yeah, you know why they're drama filled?
Rym: Because they let the uncle in.
Scott: If you don't let him in in the first place, you don't have this problem.
Scott: You had to start, they already made the mistake of this person's been to Thanksgiving so many times.
Scott: In my family, that person was never allowed at Thanksgiving.
Scott: We never see them.
Scott: They're gone, baby.
Scott: I don't even think they're out there.
Scott: They probably died.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: And because we cut that shit off early, like before I was even born, before I even understood this policy was intact, we've been protected from it ever since.
Scott: I didn't have to start this up suddenly.
Scott: I had it right from the beginning.
Rym: It's interesting how it's such a common theme around the holidays.
Rym: The arguments at Thanksgiving and then the drama and depression around Christmas go hand in hand, it seems.
Scott: Just because someone is related to you doesn't mean they have to be a part of your life.
Scott: Sure, you can make them if you want to, and it's perfectly fine, but there's no obligation to do that.
Scott: Just because there's some DNA in common, that means nothing in society.
Rym: What does amaze me is a lot of people also talk about how Thanksgiving... It's interesting, you see this split between people who show up to Gennaro family Thanksgiving dinner and don't know the reality of the real world or what's up, and then there's this whole other set, because I was reading a FARC thread about Thanksgiving today, and there's a bunch of people talking about how when they were kids, Aunt Mildred would always offer to go to the store, and they thought that was weird because she's missing out on football and family, and now they're older, they're coming back from college, and they realize Aunt Mildred way into marijuana, and suddenly they're good friends with Aunt Mildred because they come back home, and they're like,
Rym: "Whoa!".
Rym: Thanksgiving seems like the holiday where people who were kids and went off to college come back home and have their first adult interactions as adults and seeing adult members of their not immediate family as adults.
Rym: You have the conversations with your uncle who's not racist.
Rym: that just couldn't happen when it was still a child versus uncle relationship.
Scott: Yeah, well, kid Thanksgiving is totally different from adult Thanksgiving.
Rym: Yeah, kid Thanksgiving is the kids' table.
Scott: Right, and even if you're a football fan as a kid, are you really watching and understanding?
Rym: Some kids are.
Scott: You're probably playing Nintendo while someone else is watching football, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You're playing Nintendo, you eat a delicious food, you play Nintendo, you go home.
Scott: Say hi to grandma.
Rym: I remember one thing that I remember very specifically is I was always really excited to go to any grandma's house.
Rym: That was just always great times.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But I remember mom is always bored.
Rym: Mom's kind of going like, "Uh-huh,
Rym: uh-huh.".
Rym: Well, mom's mom is talking about what moms talk about.
Rym: And dad's watching TV, like football, talking to uncle and grandpa and all those people.
Rym: And they're all also kind of bored and just sort of chit-chatting.
Rym: And kid wants to stay forever because, yay, grandma's house.
Rym: Everyone else wants to go home.
Scott: Well, there's always that division, right?
Scott: Historically, it's like a gendered division, but in my family, not really.
Rym: Yeah, when I hang out with your family at Thanksgiving, I actually spend a lot of my time in the kitchen.
Scott: There's a kitchen crew and there's a living room crew, right?
Scott: You're either watching football or you're involved with food and kitchen action.
Scott: And there's a lot of going back and forth.
Rym: The third crew is Nintendo.
Rym: Kids, if there are kids.
Scott: Yeah, but there's no kids anymore.
Scott: But maybe your family has some.
Scott: But yeah, there's like these two or three crews that occur.
Scott: And people might transfer between them at various times, right?
Scott: But, you know, that's sort of like how it always goes down.
Scott: I wonder if like other countries that the other, not Thanksgiving, but similar to Thanksgiving harvest type holidays, it sort of plays out the same way.
Rym: It seems like in the kitchen, everyone's talking about family.
Rym: And in the room where the TV is, everyone's talking about either nothing or if it's a cool family, everything but family.
Scott: Or yelling at the TV.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, you piece of shit dropped the ball.
Scott: What's wrong with TV?
Rym: But yeah, like even in our group, like I noticed when we have our Thanksgiving-ish feast with our friends, even though like our apartment is like one big room in the front, basically, like the kitchen's kind of like just in the living room, effectively.
Rym: People like crowd into the kitchen and like stand shoulder to shoulder, like right next to the fucking oven, like getting in everyone's way trying to cook, all talking about like so-and-so friend and basically talking about the family.
Rym: And there's like two people sitting in the entire rest of the apartment playing video games with tons of fame.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But why?
Rym: Like there's something about like the bustle of the kitchen if everyone wants to be in on that action for some reason.
Scott: Yeah, the smartphone also.
Scott: A lot of people are like, you know, there's the general nonsensical lament of like, you know, smartphone ruining socialization.
Rym: Yeah, but when I was a kid, it was my mom reading a magazine going, "Uh-huh,
Rym: uh-huh.".
Rym: Right.
Scott: I mean, everyone's sort of pushing that now, right?
Scott: The truth, which just wasn't pushed, which is like, yeah, you know, person had their head in a newspaper, head in a magazine, head in a book, head in a, you know, whatever.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Just cutting themselves with it because there isn't anything.
Scott: But the smartphone actually, you know, at Thanksgiving in particular or any family gathering, you know, there's some people who, you know, play that old blame thing of, you know, but really I think it's enhanced in a lot of ways.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, you know, a lot of times I see like the argument starts up like, "Blackhearts are named after blah.
Rym: I thought they were named after
Rym: blah.".
Rym: And instead of that turning into either like a dumb argument or just petering out, people pull out smartphones and suddenly everyone's like, "Oh, the Blackhearts were founded in 1926.
Rym: What?".
Scott: There's also a lot of game playing going on like, "Hey, help me beat this candy
Scott: crush.".
Scott: Or, "What's that game you're playing?
Scott: A little Hearthstone over
Scott: there?".
Rym: Oh, hey, you want to see pictures of the trip that the kids are on right now?
Scott: Oh, hey, let me take some pictures of us right now on Thanksgiving and then tweet them to other people.
Scott: Oh, let me take a picture of our yams that are better than everyone else's yam.
Rym: All the bored millennials who are home with their families are talking to each other being like, "Man, my Thanksgiving.
Rym: Man, my
Rym: Thanksgiving.".
Scott: "My turkey's better than your
Scott: turkey.".
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: And if anyone has anything that happened to them on the Thanksgiving, like the turkey set on fire, everyone can now sit around and watch Vines if turkey's on fire.
Scott: Her house is burning down from trying to deep fry the turkey in the garage.
Rym: There was a time when I'd have the family hang out where the TV would be on in the background like when football wasn't happening and everyone's ignoring it.
Rym: It's just kind of there.
Rym: But now when there's the gathering, because you got the ability to have the YouTube channel up, there will be the YouTube going and running commentary of people putting stuff into the queue and yelling and watching it.
Rym: I kind of like that dynamic among friends and family.
Rym: I don't like it when it happens every night and it ends up being a time waster of like, "Let me show you this YouTube video that no one wants to
Rym: see.".
Rym: But like the Thanksgiving vibe.
Scott: But I just want to show you this YouTube video that you don't want to see because I want you to watch it.
Rym: There's a good Steven Universe meme about that lately that once you watch the show, it's pretty good.
Rym: But now like in the family gathering Thanksgiving situation, it's interesting because it's like all these people have different sets of memes and things they know about on the internet.
Rym: The ability now with smart TVs for everyone to like start throwing stuff into a queue in the family gathering means that there's a guaranteed stream of entertainment in that room and anyone who doesn't want to be involved can go join the kitchen crew so everybody's happy.
Scott: It also helps out with recipes for the kitchen crew.
Scott: It also helps out with fantasy football for the living room crew.
Rym: Oh shit, I gotta update my team.
Rym: Actually, I do.
Rym: There's money on it at work.
Scott: I don't play fantasy football.
Rym: I don't play much, but my office is really into it for some reason.
Scott: What office isn't?
Scott: Mine is the one that's not into it.
Rym: If they did fantasy hockey, I'd be a lot more into it.
Scott: You can do that.
Scott: You want to do it?
Scott: We can set it up.
Rym: Yeah, no one in my office gives a shit.
Rym: That's the problem.
Scott: You can just set it up next year, which is not your office.
Rym: We'll do it with FRC.
Rym: Yeah, I'll do it next year.
Scott: Set up a real fantasy hockey.
Scott: Not a now finally illegal in New York maybe daily fantasy gambling, but actual more skill and luck.
Scott: fantasy team girls.
Rym: Yeah, next Tuesday's show we'll be talking about that biz.
Scott: For sure.
Scott: Not that we haven't already said everything about it already.
Rym: Yeah, most of it will be, "Yeah, we were right.
Rym: Told you
Rym: so.".
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: So, the Thanksgiving dessert.
Scott: Pie?
Rym: Pumpkin pie is the only acceptable dessert.
Scott: I don't like pumpkin pie, so I make apple pie.
Scott: And you can just deal with that.
Rym: Apple pie is okay as long as there's also a pumpkin pie.
Scott: Or whatever grandma baked.
Rym: Pumpkin pie.
Rym: It's got to be a pumpkin pie.
Scott: We don't do pumpkin pie.
Rym: I don't understand.
Scott: Pumpkin pie is- Pumpkin is not for eating.
Rym: I don't know how you come to that conclusion.
Rym: How do you like yams and squashes and things?
Scott: Squash isn't that good.
Scott: A yam is good.
Rym: Yeah, they're not that far apart in terms of the dishes that come out.
Scott: Pumpkin is for decoration.
Rym: What about a sweet potato pie?
Rym: Very similar structurally to a pumpkin pie.
Scott: I don't really eat a sweet potato pie.
Scott: I mostly eat a sweet potato.
Scott: And I eat a pie.
Scott: I like a fruit pie.
Rym: I do like fruit pies, but I feel like Christmas, you got the apple pie comes out.
Rym: And in the spring, apple season.
Scott: I don't do Christmas because I'm not a yam.
Scott: I got my chance for apple pies.
Scott: Thanksgiving in the apple season.
Scott: December is already- apples are done.
Scott: Even by Thanksgiving, apples are mostly done.
Scott: But you still got some leftovers.
Scott: But you gotta go for the apple pie while it's still fall and not winter.
Rym: I'm a big fan of the pumpkin pie that actually uses pumpkin.
Rym: Most pumpkin pies, I've talked to those on Geek Dice a lot, are made with kind of like bullshitty squashes instead.
Rym: Because most people don't actually like for real pumpkin pie.
Scott: I don't.
Rym: Have you ever had a real pumpkin pie?
Scott: Yeah, that's why I learned I don't like it.
Rym: When?
Scott: Long ass time ago.
Rym: Maybe you'll like it now as an adult.
Rym: Because I have noticed my palate has changed a lot.
Scott: I'm sure if I eat anything enough, I doubt it'll become a favorite food that I desire.
Rym: Oh no, but I've noticed, especially with big Thanksgiving kind of foods, the things that I like the most have changed as I've gotten older and taste buds have started to die.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: That is something that will continue probably for the rest of my life.
Rym: Probably.
Scott: I was always a big fan of stuffing.
Scott: I ordered some Indian food the other night and I got a little chana masala because you get the little chickpeas.
Scott: It's a lot better deal than getting like chicken tikka masala where you get like four pieces of chicken and you're done.
Scott: You get all this curry you can't use.
Scott: That thing's full of chickpeas because it caused nothing.
Scott: I chose the hottest possible option and it really wasn't hot.
Scott: It's like, oh yeah, this is definitely hot.
Scott: They put these two peppers in there and it feels hot.
Rym: I find myself doubling the amount or the strength of onions and things.
Rym: I find myself putting cayenne pepper in just everything.
Rym: So Thanksgiving's coming real soon actually.
Scott: The best part of Thanksgiving, you don't got to go to work.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: And on the day after, you don't got to go to work.
Scott: And if anyone tries to make you go to work on Black Friday, you say no.
Rym: It depends.
Rym: Retail people should not have to work.
Rym: It should be a national holiday.
Scott: Just refuse to work on Black Friday.
Rym: But at the same time, depending on your job, I have had a lot of luck in my life working like the day after Christmas.
Scott: What job does someone have where they can't refuse?
Scott: Fireman.
Scott: Fireman go to work.
Rym: Are you talking about in an ideal world or the real world?
Scott: If you work at the power plant or the sewage treatment, go to work.
Rym: Yeah, in an ideal world.
Scott: If you work at the hospital, go to work.
Rym: Yeah, like military, like you're standing on the border of North Korea.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Alright, but they don't have Thanksgiving.
Scott: They have a different holiday this earlier.
Rym: Well, there's American soldiers hanging out there.
Scott: Oh yeah, sure.
Scott: I mean, they're celebrating Thanksgiving at the base or whatever.
Scott: They're good.
Scott: But I mean, if you don't have a job like that where you must go to work, you know, police, yeah, go to work.
Scott: There's probably going to be some drunk driving on this holiday.
Rym: You know, forget all that.
Rym: There's a much more important thing to say.
Rym: Don't buy anything on Black Friday.
Rym: Do not encourage them.
Scott: Professional ice hockey player, go to work on Black Friday.
Scott: Professional basketball player, you can go to work on Black Friday too.
Scott: I don't really care if you don't, but you probably should.
Scott: But yeah, most jobs, don't go to work on Black Friday even if they say to.
Scott: And if they fire you, give them the finger.
Rym: So my biggest advice to you, all of you out there, if you're in college right now and like you're getting to that point where like you can go home for Thanksgiving, like you should probably still go home for Thanksgiving.
Rym: But seriously, start now, get all your real friends, like not the Facebook friends, but their actual friends and pick a weekend either before or after Thanksgiving and just do your own Thanksgiving.
Rym: And let me tell you, you're going to fuck up the turkey because you guys have never done this stuff before.
Rym: Like you're going to mess some stuff up, but start cooking Thanksgiving dinner for your nerd friends in college on a non-Thanksgiving day now and make it a tradition that's going to pay out in like 10 years.
Scott: But here's the real truth.
Scott: If you're so sad a person that you listen to GeekNights or even give us money, you probably don't have any friends even if you're in college.
Rym: Scott hates all of you and us and this.
Scott: So what you should do is to avoid Crazy Uncle Whatever.
Scott: Don't go to Thanksgiving with your family if they refuse to make Crazy Uncle not invited and just make your own personal fucking Thanksgiving just for you and just make all these delicious foods and you can eat all of them with nobody to fight over that giant bowl of fucking stuffing.
Scott: You just eat all of it, just you, nobody else.
Scott: And be like, "Oh my God, I am the king of the
Scott: world.".
Scott: Just watch the football on your own and you won't have anyone fighting with you to change the channel to some other bullshit.
Rym: Well, I guess think of it this way.
Rym: If you are someone who has... If you have family drama to where Thanksgiving...
Scott: During halftime just play Rocket League and be like, "Fuck
Scott: you.".
Rym: If Thanksgiving is more stressful for you than fun because you're in that kind of life, at least once do something like Scott said and invite only your friends over.
Scott: I thought we said they didn't have any.
Rym: No, but you got to have something or make some friends.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Your friend, the turkey, kill him and set him on fire until he is delicious.
Rym: Because a couple of years ago, Emily and I had started, we try to not go home over major holidays and try to convince our family, "We'll do our Christmasy celebration some other weekend around
Rym: Christmas.".
Rym: But we just stayed home on Christmas last year.
Rym: Oh my God, was that the best...
Scott: You should try the better Christmas option.
Rym: Go to Costa Rica, like Tropical Island?
Scott: Well, that's a really good option.
Scott: I'm talking about the normal better Christmas option, which is movie plus Chinese food.
Rym: Oh, we did that.
Rym: We did that.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I want to say this year, this year there is a rare event.
Scott: Usually it takes a whole fucking lot to get me to go see a movie.
Rym: Oh, I see where you're going with this.
Scott: And usually on Christmas, there's maybe one movie, maybe, to go see in the theater on the Christmastime, maybe.
Scott: And you pick the best option of what's available.
Scott: This year, there is a double must-see.
Scott: It's got a Christmas double feature.
Scott: You got to eat your Chinese food between or after both of them.
Scott: You have Star Wars, which remains to be seen if it's must-see, but yeah, you're going to see it.
Rym: You're a nerd.
Rym: Never forget, you guys.
Rym: You know how hype you are now?
Scott: Even if George Lucas made this one, which he isn't, you would go see it.
Scott: So shut up.
Rym: You were just as hype before Jar Jar Binks.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And also, the double feature, you got Hateful Eight.
Scott: So two movie Christmastime.
Scott: Watch out.
Rym: Daddy two.
Scott: Daddy two.
Scott: Rare year.
Scott: Rare.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: Thank you, Patrons.
Rym: For once, you guys actually got to kind of pick the episode.
Rym: So in the future when we do this, as I said, you will actually be able to vote on the specific topic from the submissions.
Rym: We'll take up a nominations process and then a voting process.
Rym: So it should be fun.
Rym: And stay tuned.
Rym: This weekend, we're actually starting up GeekNights Presents again.
Rym: We're at least doing some pre-production and we're going to start that show again real soon.
Rym: So now, in order of the amount of money they're giving us, the Patrons of this episode are... And now I present to you... Yes, I do.
Rym: You and your pussycat nose.
Rym: What's new, pussycat?
Scott: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Scott: What's new, pussycat?
Rym: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Rym: What's new, pussycat?
Scott: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Scott: What's new, pussycat?
Rym: Whoa, whoa, whoa.