Rym: It's Tuesday July 7th, 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Ray and Eric and Izzie's Lost Cities.
Scott: Also known as Rym Cheats.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: We had a... I'm not cheating, I'm winning.
Rym: So we had a 4th of July party that was notable in one way.
Rym: When we first moved, well when I first moved to New York City which wasn't too long after Scott moved down here the 4th of July fireworks were on the East River.
Rym: Like right next to my apartment and all up and down.
Rym: Like right there.
Rym: And then every other year after that I don't remember that.
Scott: I remember them being in 2009.
Scott: I'm pretty sure they were in the Hudson River.
Rym: But they had them for many many years in a row over next to New Jersey for no good reason.
Rym: And New York City has finally taken them back.
Rym: and let me tell you there were barges all the way up and down the East River and they were all synchronized and that was one hell of a firework show from the roof.
Rym: So yeah.
Rym: We had our awesome party.
Rym: We played some games that we're going to do a separate GeekNights show about after we do a little more research.
Rym: And Scott is distracted because his iPad broke I guess so he doesn't have his...
Scott: It's hard for me to do the show without my iPad so I'm using my iPhone.
Rym: If only you had a reliable Android device.
Rym: It would just mysteriously stop working.
Scott: Yeah, so mysterious.
Rym: Yeah, well what happened to it?
Rym: Why did it stop working?
Scott: It was a hardware failure.
Rym: So you can get a new one for free or you're just fucked?
Scott: I didn't pay for AppleCare because that shit's a ripoff.
Scott: You shouldn't pay for it.
Rym: And now you got to buy a brand new iPad.
Scott: I was going to buy a brand new iPad anyway.
Rym: In September, now you're going to not have an iPad until September?
Scott: Yeah, I can live without it.
Rym: So we kind of needed it this weekend.
Scott: That's the only time I needed it.
Scott: If it broke next week I wouldn't have even thought about dealing with it.
Rym: In other news, because this is the opening vid, you know many of you new listeners to GeekNights we kind of talk about stuff in the beginning and I promise not to talk about a certain topic for the rest of the year in the opening vid.
Rym: But my left eye has been twitching for like three days.
Rym: The eyelid?
Rym: Or the eye?
Rym: The eyelid.
Rym: I've had that.
Scott: But I haven't had it for three days.
Scott: I've had it for like an hour here maybe.
Rym: Yep, it's coming and going but pretty much three days.
Rym: And usually that only happens if I drink like way too much garana or something.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: There's a thing.
Scott: It's supposed to happen when you're old but I guess...
Rym: Maybe we're old.
Rym: There was just that article on Slashdot.
Scott: Real old.
Scott: Like grandpa old.
Rym: Talking about how some people when they're 40 they look like they're 60 and some people when they're 80 look like they're 40.
Rym: Apparently there's a pretty well... People do just straight up age at different rates.
Rym: Well they don't know what the cause is.
Scott: Pretty sure it's just genetic.
Rym: But the people who look older when they're young, in terms of health, they basically are older.
Rym: They might as well be 70 or 80.
Rym: It's not just that some people age differently in looks.
Rym: If you look way old when you're young you're probably also actually effectively old.
Rym: So yeah.
Rym: Game nine.
Rym: Tuesday.
Rym: Low energy here on Scott's side it sounds like.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: They announced the Spiel des Jahres winners for 2015.
Scott: In between the last time we did a Tuesday episode and now.
Scott: And they're games I never played.
Scott: The winner was Cult Express.
Scott: Never played it.
Scott: The Kenner Spiel winner was Broom Service which is a cool name but I never played it.
Scott: I don't know anything about it.
Scott: The kids game was Spinderella.
Scott: Another fun name.
Scott: Never played it.
Scott: Don't know anything about it.
Rym: The thing is I guess it's fine because a lot of times there are so many tabletop games.
Rym: That pretty much I wait until the Spiel des Jahres are announced and then I check out those specific games and I pretty much ignore the rest.
Scott: Yeah but I think this is one of those awards where they hand it out every year no matter what.
Scott: And most awards are like that.
Scott: They give out the awards every single year no matter what.
Rym: The Oscars should have a none of the above for best picture.
Scott: Well right.
Scott: I think that you need some awards like that.
Scott: Not for giving out awards that you deserve to be awarded but just for the sake of history.
Scott: people can look back and say.
Scott: Ah look.
Scott: This was the best in that year and this was the best in that year.
Scott: If you just don't have a winner then when someone looks it up they'll be like wow.
Scott: All they know is that everything sucked that year.
Scott: You learn a lot more if you say wow that was the best that year.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: We learned a lot a while ago like months ago.
Rym: We were arguing about movies and things and then we went back and we looked at best picture year by year.
Rym: And there was in fact like this ten year run of amazing movies.
Scott: Yes there was.
Scott: No there isn't.
Rym: There's still some good movies.
Scott: As long as it's in the sea.
Scott: But it's not like you.
Scott: look at every movie that came out in that year and it's like wow every single movie that came out that year was incredible.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: so I think that we need you know because the other thing that happens when you have annual awards is you have like two masterpieces come out at the same time.
Scott: And you can only give the award to one of them right.
Scott: So I feel like for every category of awards that's out there for everything that's being awarded you need to have awards of both types.
Scott: You need to have the award where we give this out every year to the best no matter what it is even if it's garbage.
Scott: It's just the best that year.
Scott: That was an awful year.
Scott: And you need to have another award which is you award it when there's a masterpiece.
Scott: If there's five masterpieces at once you just give out five of them.
Scott: And if everything sucks you just give out none.
Rym: You could go one step further.
Scott: There's no time when you give them out.
Scott: It's when something worthy appears you bestow the award upon it.
Scott: Sort of like how the queen knights people.
Scott: It's sort of like there's someone worthy of being knighted.
Scott: You're knighted.
Scott: Why don't we just do it?
Rym: Why don't we just do it?
Rym: Why don't we just make that our thing?
Rym: Penny Arcade used to do the wear/write awards.
Scott: Yeah but that was an annual thing.
Scott: And they were only mostly right.
Rym: So why don't we just do it and award our...
Scott: Geek Knights Awards?
Rym: Yeah the Geek Knights Awards.
Scott: Whenever something is worthy of an award we give it one.
Scott: Instead of having a show that's like the award show we go.
Scott: Oh!
Scott: Something appeared that is worthy of a Geek Knights Award.
Scott: Here it is.
Rym: I would do three.
Rym: So here's what I'd do.
Rym: You have one award which is every year this was the best game or the best game in that category of this year.
Rym: And then there's a separate discussion of is that game better than the best game that's ever won that award in history.
Rym: So every year it's like the best game this year in worker placement was this game.
Rym: And the best worker placement game of all time...
Scott: The problem is you can't be award giver outer unless you've played or for board games for example every single fucking board game right?
Rym: Yeah because the Oscars people watch all those movies.
Scott: You know they should right?
Scott: But they don't.
Scott: But that's the thing is I don't want to be... I can't simultaneously say hey their Oscars are bullshit which they are.
Scott: And that be one of the reasons if I'm giving out an award where I'm also bullshit.
Scott: I have to not be bullshit.
Rym: Why don't we just claim the awards like the Geek Knights?
Rym: we're full of bullshit awards.
Scott: Because then that won't be what I'm talking about.
Scott: We could do that but that won't be what I'm discussing right now.
Scott: That would be something entirely different which might be okay.
Rym: Well it's also trouble if you do the cumulative thing.
Rym: It's like alright.
Rym: so Puerto Rico and Tigris and Euphrates.
Rym: is one of them objectively better than the other one?
Scott: It doesn't matter they're both masterpieces.
Scott: they both get the award.
Rym: Yes but if you do the cumulative thing it's hard to say which one is the master.
Scott: You don't need to say that that's pointless.
Rym: Yeah but that's the kind of thing the nerds actually care about more.
Rym: Making up artificial hierarchies.
Rym: Nerds love the top 10 list of top 10 X's in Y just so they can argue about it.
Scott: The number one reason to be an awards giver outer right is so that when people who receive awards.
Scott: If your award is is respected then people who receive the award will then put your logo on their box.
Scott: Like if you you know Oscars are under suspected awards of a movie wins an Oscar.
Scott: They put Oscars on their posters on their what on their ads on TV and everything.
Scott: And then because of that that makes your award more legit.
Scott: And now you get money just for doing this stupid awards nonsense right?
Scott: Suddenly you become a thing.
Scott: The spiel des Jahres is given out by like.
Scott: isn't it like a journalistic publication?
Scott: So the fact that I think it is given out by a jury of German-speaking board game critics who review games released in Germany.
Scott: Okay but it's like you know that helps them right to be like.
Scott: I'm a spiel des Jahres judge.
Scott: And if the more people that put spiel des Jahres on boxes because it's a respected award helps them you know be respected.
Scott: This is why I remember the early days of the web.
Scott: people would always just like make up awards for websites.
Scott: Yeah and you'd get.
Rym: remember the parsec awards and I still have this trophy.
Rym: it's sitting right here.
Scott: Yeah I think that's still around but that's no.
Rym: they stopped giving out like anime podcast and whatever.
Rym: So I have two trophies on my desk covered in dust.
Rym: One of them is third place in the 30 to 39 year old category at the multiple sclerosis run.
Rym: the US New York finish 5k in 2014.
Rym: And the other one is the 2007 parsec award best anime podcast GeekNights anime.
Scott: That's another thing you can do with awards.
Scott: is you can get people to come to a place right?
Scott: It's like hey.
Rym: I know they didn't.
Rym: I point out when we won this parsec award everyone who was nominated in that category was there and then they announced that we won and no one went up to get the award.
Scott: I don't know if everyone in the category was there but I'm sure someone was.
Rym: Everyone who was nominated and met like in the end was there because they all gave me shit about it and I was like what?
Scott: The point is if you have an awards thing you can make it an event you can get a TV deal you can get people to stay in a hotel you can make some money right?
Rym: Yeah so maybe we should do the masterpiece thing and forget all the other kinds of awards.
Rym: The certified list.
Rym: it's like the steam list.
Scott: What's your news?
Rym: So I got two news that are the same news because they prove a point.
Rym: So way back there was Twitch plays Pokemon which was an important like I'm not even joking an important cultural phenomenon and kind of an amazing thing.
Rym: Like that was a very cool thing.
Rym: that happened and separately not that long ago in fact on April 1st.
Rym: so a few months ago a subreddit appeared.
Rym: I got I paid attention to the subreddit.
Rym: some people did some people didn't and in fact you can see the record forever of who did pay attention who didn't.
Rym: but a button appeared on this subreddit and the button was counting down from 60 seconds to zero.
Rym: If you click the button it reset the timer to 60 and you could never ever click that button again ever.
Scott: Did we discuss this already?
Rym: So barely we didn't talk about it that much because Scott just clicked it right away and whatever.
Rym: so people kept it going for a long time.
Rym: In fact it ended the 5th of June.
Rym: so a human being or a script that a human being wrote that only had one chance maybe two or three chances if you had multiple accounts to like spam Reddit.
Rym: A human being clicked this button by one means or another every at least every 60 seconds from April 1st to June 5th at 2150.55 UTC.
Rym: And now it's over and you just can't click the button.
Rym: and that's it like literally.
Rym: that's it and it was a super cool thing.
Rym: Both of these things were super cool and in gaming whenever someone does something clever like remember Salty Bet?
Rym: Salty Bet was the most amazing thing ever until everyone got tired of it.
Scott: For like 10 minutes.
Rym: Yeah like who even pays attention to it anymore?
Scott: It was good for a few months actually.
Rym: Yeah like we'd be doing the show and we'd just have it out in the corner kind of half watching it.
Rym: But these things these flashes in the pan are super important.
Rym: but my moral my lesson to you is if you see a thing like that a cultural gaming phenomenon event and you think hey what if I do that?
Rym: but?
Rym: Just stop right there because everyone who tries to do the same thing again just fails.
Rym: And I don't know why this is making the news everywhere but Twitch plays Metal Gear Solid whatever on the Game Boy Color is like in all the gaming news sites today.
Scott: It must be a slow news day.
Rym: So I went and checked it out and one there's 180 people watching it.
Scott: It's a slow news day.
Scott: one gaming site posted.
Scott: the other gaming sites copied it because the first one posted it.
Rym: And pretty much no one watched any of them but the original one.
Scott: I watched the fish play Street Fighter a little bit.
Rym: A little bit.
Rym: In five minutes.
Rym: Yeah five minutes moderately amusing.
Rym: Twitch plays Pokemon and the button were different because all the hundreds of thousands of people who paid attention to that were all paying attention at the exact same time.
Rym: So a community formed around that thing.
Rym: Salty Bet formed a community that lasted as long as Salty Bet lasted.
Rym: That Reddit button.
Rym: There are people who live on that subreddit now basically.
Rym: This Metal Gear Solid thing and all the copycats will never have a community.
Rym: The other interesting thing is the people who are promoting this and trying to make it happen.
Rym: Metal Gear Solid on the Game Boy Color is possibly the worst possible game to do this for.
Rym: There is literally no way they can actually beat the game unless one person is in the chat alone.
Rym: I mean the game requires timing and stuff.
Rym: And watching this chat, it's just kind of really sad.
Rym: And everyone is really unhappy here.
Rym: Anyway, things of the day!
Rym: This is a, well it's a Google Doc with a bunch of animated gifs in it.
Rym: But it's basically an essay by Ite Karen, the owner of that studio that made that cool mushroom game.
Rym: we played at the sheep's meow thing way back.
Rym: You remember that?
Rym: You paying attention?
Rym: You doing the show?
Rym: What's going on over there?
Scott: I'm remembering my thing of the day.
Rym: So this is a cool game where you erase part of your fungus and then the fungus sort of grows from its other parts.
Scott: Oh yeah, I played that.
Scott: I remember.
Rym: It was this really cool puzzle game.
Rym: So this is an essay that was basically presented as a talk at GDC 2015.
Rym: And it is a very, very, very in-depth mathematical detailed examination of basically every possible way to scroll your 2D game that may or may not involve scrolling.
Rym: This is super detailed and anytime someone makes a crapo game on a phone or something or a platformer or cheetahmen and it's bad, it's because of this stuff.
Rym: This stuff is one of the most important things when it comes to any 2D game that involves motion.
Scott: Just do it the way Super Metroid does it.
Rym: No, because Super Metroid does what it does.
Rym: Super Metroid is an example here for very specific reasons.
Scott: Yeah, because you go in the door and it loads the next room and unloads the previous room, right?
Rym: No, they're not talking about that kind of scrolling.
Rym: They're talking about within each zone.
Rym: It's the walking scrolling.
Rym: Do you use a lerp smoother or a straight up position lock?
Rym: Do you just lock the guy to the center of the screen?
Scott: Yeah, Super Metroid, you only push the screen when you get closer to one of the edges.
Scott: You can move around the middle without scrolling anything.
Rym: So like Mario 1, the good example is, it keeps you at the center of the screen, but depending on when you backtrack, it doesn't move it quite the same way.
Rym: They call it the speed up push zone.
Rym: So this does say it gives you a name for every kind of scrolling.
Rym: And it gives you an animated gif that makes it extremely obvious what they're talking about.
Rym: And you're going to feel kind of dumb that you didn't notice some of this stuff.
Rym: A lot of games that seem really similar have way different scrolling and because it's implemented well, you don't even realize what the game's doing.
Rym: And it's brilliant.
Rym: Like here, Donkey Kong Country, lerp smoothing, position locking, region based, anchor, dual forward focus.
Scott: Yeah, Nintendo gets everything right.
Rym: Most of these games are Nintendo games or modern indie games by really smart people.
Scott: See, this is the kind of thing that Nintendo always gets right, which is why their games take so goddamn long to make.
Scott: And why when you play a Nintendo game, even if it's not a good game for other reasons, it just works.
Scott: As opposed to you get some indie game, you're like, man, this feels kind of janky.
Scott: It's like that's because they got this sort of thing wrong.
Scott: And not just scrolling, but also the jumping, shooting, etc.
Rym: So, like, really, if you think you're designing games, you want video ball is taking a long time.
Scott: Why is this triangle shooting each other?
Scott: Because they're getting this thing right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, well, I think I'll talk about later.
Rym: But seriously, you should if you're a game designer, you should.
Rym: you should read this entire essay top to bottom.
Rym: And you should reference these animated gifs on a regular basis of your video game developer, not necessarily game design.
Rym: Anyway, video game designer to maybe designing the game.
Rym: How is it supposed to scroll?
Rym: What do you do?
Rym: What's the game's focus?
Rym: How's it working?
Rym: Stuff matters.
Scott: So little are traveled 60 meters while limbo dancing on roller skates.
Scott: A record setter dot com world record.
Scott: She remained under six inch bars for the duration of the attempt.
Scott: This attempt may have been broken to check the current status.
Scott: Visit this URL.
Scott: The here's a YouTube video showing the successful attempt.
Rym: The video kind of amazing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You can't do this now.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: No, I don't think any of you could even limbo under a 12 inch bar.
Rym: Me attempting to do this would resolve my death.
Rym: What can I limbo?
Scott: I think you would just sort of roller skate and then fall forward on the ground and be done.
Rym: How?
Rym: I think you'd fall backward.
Scott: I mean, she goes forward.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So what are the official rules of limbo?
Rym: What style of limbo is this?
Scott: I think it's just.
Scott: you had to be on roller skates.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And you got to skate forward as far as you can.
Scott: But you have to remain.
Scott: Your body has to remain not touching the ground except for the bottom of the skates and also not touching the bars above you that are, you know, maintaining your low height.
Scott: You can get your body loaded the ground by any means necessary.
Scott: But considering human anatomy, you know, ignoring freaks of nature.
Rym: I feel like the people.
Scott: This seems to be the best way to do it.
Rym: I feel like maybe the people who are good at this are.
Scott: it's the genetic advantage advantage partially contortionism and also being a small child.
Rym: So in the moment, the book club book is still the wheel of time.
Scott: And oh, the world.
Rym: It's a fantasy book.
Rym: And they got to a fantasy town.
Rym: And now they're in a fantasy in.
Rym: Have you gotten that far?
Rym: Have you read any?
Scott: I think I'm almost at the fantasy town.
Scott: I'm like, I'm like, I'm like on the road right behind that town.
Rym: Did they get to go through the gates of a town yet?
Scott: No, they're getting to it.
Rym: Oh, all right.
Rym: There's not that there's not that much travel between the boat thing.
Scott: They are.
Scott: They finished the boat thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You're almost at the town.
Rym: All I got to say is the main character is OK.
Rym: His two dumb ass friends.
Rym: Like, I really just.
Scott: Why are they even?
Scott: Why are they even there?
Rym: I would like them to die.
Rym: I imagine they will.
Scott: They don't do anything.
Scott: I don't even know which one's which one with the ax and the one with the bow.
Rym: Matt, I think is the dumb one.
Scott: Is he the ax or the bow?
Rym: I don't know, but he's the dumb one.
Scott: The ax one's the better, smarter one, I think.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The guy named Matt is the dumb one.
Rym: I'm pretty sure because he just.
Rym: I just want him to shut up.
Rym: I really you know, it's funny maybe because I'm reading this because the book is like I could see if you're a kid who doesn't live in a big city and you're reading this book.
Rym: It's definitely like, oh, I wish I could go on a journey like this.
Rym: Oh, man, that warden guy is so scary or the water or whatever.
Rym: But me as an adult reading this book, I really sympathize with the eyes today and the warden.
Rym: And I really don't like the kids.
Rym: Yeah, I I would basically be the guy with the sword yelling at them to shut up the whole book.
Scott: Pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, we are going to be live at Connecticut 2015 this weekend in like two days.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Rym: On Thursday night, there are a few panels in the Marriott and you don't want to do that shit.
Rym: No, if you're going there, because as much as I want them to mail the badges, they don't mail the badges yet.
Rym: You can pick up your badges on Thursday, like most of the day.
Scott: Great.
Rym: And there are like four panels on Thursday.
Rym: And you don't even need a badge to see.
Rym: I'm totally open to the public.
Rym: Oh, so that's cool.
Rym: I am at least and we'll see if Scott wants to join me or not at six thirty p.m.. And people being really mad about the fact that we told some cold, hard truths about why no one will game.
Scott: Maybe I'll show up and sit on stage while you do that panel to an audience of zero and eat a DiBella sandwich.
Rym: I suspect I'll have you.
Rym: should the panel just be the two of us just eat a DiBella sandwich and be in love and just be like, you're assuming you're getting a sandwich.
Rym: I really hope you get me a sandwich.
Rym: I'll be really sad if you don't.
Scott: Should I take after my uncle who doesn't show up with a sandwich when you give him tickets to the All-Star?
Rym: Do you want to be that guy?
Scott: My uncle?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: He's not bad guy.
Scott: No, he just doesn't get you a sandwich.
Rym: He's a bad guy.
Rym: On Saturday, we're skipping Friday because we do kind of run the whole panels department.
Rym: So we have work to do Saturday.
Rym: We're doing analyzing anime Utena, the history of losing Five Nights at Freddy's live with our boss at Connecticut, the director of all programming who's never played those games before.
Scott: Matt is actually going to do that.
Scott: Oh, Kristen.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, why Five Nights at Freddy's is scary and foreign anime.
Scott: You're going to get mad to them.
Scott: Like, really?
Rym: Now, I would like to see Matt play that game.
Scott: He's probably has.
Rym: Yeah, I don't.
Rym: We'll see if he has.
Rym: Maybe we'll trick him into coming into the room.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: You can even find him.
Rym: Yeah, I know.
Rym: Finding him is a lot harder than finding like a kahil at a PAX.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: When the convention like you see him before the convention starts, then the convention starts and he disappears.
Scott: And then when the convention ends, there is occasionally on the radio, you're here.
Rym: This is operations looking for Matt and then just silence.
Rym: That happens a lot.
Rym: It's his convention.
Scott: He owns it.
Rym: If I have the ring convention, you're not going to see me at the convention.
Rym: I'll be there, but you won't see me.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Oh, the main bit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The main bit is this game called Lost City.
Rym: So, Lost City is an old, old, old Reiner Knizia game that we just like knew about.
Scott: Well, I played it.
Scott: I knew I had played it in the past with people.
Scott: I knew this game.
Scott: I knew it was a great two player game, but Rym had never played it.
Rym: And the other people play it.
Rym: I just kind of ignored it.
Rym: In fact, I owned it and didn't realize I owned it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The other day, the other day, it's like, hey, let's just play a two people game.
Scott: So I go over to the closet.
Scott: We're looking and I see lost cities in there.
Scott: I'm like, hey, I haven't played lost cities in a couple of years.
Scott: That game is an amazing two player game.
Scott: Let's play that.
Scott: And Rym hadn't played it and he owned it.
Scott: So we took it out.
Scott: I reread the rules and we played and we've been playing it a whole bunch.
Scott: Because you remembered how amazing it was.
Scott: My memory was absolutely correct.
Scott: It's amazing.
Rym: I want to point out, Scott taught me the game.
Rym: And remember, we just did that show.
Rym: We're talking about Wil Wheaton and tabletop, how even professionals like us will like mess up the rules.
Scott: I got the tiniest thing wrong.
Rym: It's a big deal.
Rym: Scott is kind of a big deal when teaching me this game.
Scott: But otherwise I was absolutely correct about all the other rules and I didn't miss any other rules.
Rym: However, you suck at this game.
Scott: I don't suck.
Scott: You cheat.
Scott: I just beat you just now in that one round.
Rym: You beat me in a one round by a few points.
Rym: Meanwhile, in every other round and game of this, I've crushed you.
Rym: The three we played in a row, what was my score?
Rym: Like 280?
Scott: I mean, there is a certain amount of luck in this game.
Rym: Yeah, but I can't always be lucky.
Scott: You can be lucky three out of four times.
Rym: Especially when you're the one shuffling.
Rym: And so, Lost Cities is actually a really, really simple game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, there is a deck of cards.
Scott: In this deck of cards, there are five.
Scott: It's really a card game.
Scott: It's like it comes in a box with a board just to sort of increase the production value.
Scott: It's just a deck of cards.
Scott: But the deck of cards has the numbers two through ten in five colors.
Scott: Yellow, red, white, green, and blue.
Scott: And it has, in each color, there are also three handshake cards.
Scott: I don't know what they're actually called.
Scott: No one cares.
Rym: Investments.
Scott: Yeah, the theme of the game is you're going on expeditions.
Rym: Adventure into the unknown for the daring and adventurous.
Rym: There are many lost cities to find and explore.
Scott: Yeah, there are five different lost cities to search for.
Scott: The red one, the yellow one, the green one, the blue one, the white one.
Rym: Scott, you're missing the great flavor of this game.
Scott: No one gives a shit.
Rym: The search can take you to the Himalaya.
Rym: The white.
Rym: The Brazilian rainforest.
Scott: The green.
Rym: The ever-shifting sands of the desert.
Rym: The yellow.
Rym: Ancient volcanoes.
Rym: The red.
Rym: And to Neptune's realm.
Scott: The blue.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, basically, you play cards in the different expeditions.
Scott: And for an expedition to pay out and give you points, you have to play enough cards for that expedition to get to the successful point, right?
Scott: If you start playing cards in an expedition, but you don't play enough to make it successful, you lose a bunch of points.
Scott: because you went out and geared up and went to Neptune's realm, and you didn't really find anything there, and you just went your ass back home, and you just wasted a bunch of money, so you lose points.
Scott: If you don't even try, you don't play any cards of a certain color, then it's just a zero.
Rym: So, basically, think of it this way.
Rym: The game is all about risk management, risk aversion, and reading the other player and their discards, and managing the deck timer.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Because, basically, what you do is you draw a card, play a card.
Rym: Well, you play a card, draw a card, actually.
Scott: That's the worst part.
Rym: It's like a battle line.
Rym: You gotta play something.
Rym: Gotta play something.
Rym: And your only option is either to discard on the top of a color in the middle, and then the other person on their turn could choose to draw that as their draw, or play it in one of the piles, and now you're locked in.
Rym: That pile's gonna score.
Rym: If you ignore a color completely, it never scores, but if you put even one card down there, you could get up to negative 60 points.
Scott: That's a lot of negative points.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Scott: If you play the wrong things.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, and the other thing is, so let's say you play down, you know, handshakes have to come first.
Scott: If you play one handshake in a column, that doubles the score.
Scott: Even if it's a negative score, it'll be negative doubled.
Scott: So, if you just play one handshake, that score is negative 20, negative 40, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But you have to play the handshake first before you play anything else.
Scott: So, like, if you play the number three, and then you draw a handshake, the handshake's useless if it's the same color.
Rym: So, here are the actual rules.
Rym: The game is really simple.
Rym: You have, like, a hand of eight.
Rym: Both of you have a hand of eight.
Rym: The oldest player goes first, so I always go first, I guess.
Scott: Older by, like, two months and change.
Rym: But older nonetheless.
Rym: The rules are very explicit.
Rym: We're not going to mess up the rules.
Rym: And on your turn, you either play a card onto one of the colors, or you discard a card into the middle on one of the colors, covering up any cards that are already discarded.
Rym: Then, you draw a card, either from those discards or from the top of the deck.
Rym: And play continues until someone draws the last card in the deck, meaning every card has been drawn.
Rym: You then immediately score.
Rym: And before you do all of this, you agree how many rounds you're going to play.
Rym: The game says three is a good number.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, the reason you play rounds is because while the game isn't, you know, super luck-based, I mean, it's still got some luck involved, right?
Scott: You could theoretically get some awful draw.
Scott: that's, like, unplayable, and you end up with no score, even though you played as well as you possibly could.
Scott: So, you mitigate that by playing a few rounds, and then all the luck is washed out in, you know, the multi-round play, and you see who's really better at the game.
Rym: Now, that's pretty straightforward, but as Scott said when he was teaching it to me, then there's a Kinesia twist.
Rym: Because remember, this is Rainer of Kinesia.
Rym: You know, Amun-Re, Battle Line, Ra, through the desert, modern art, there's always a Kinesia twist.
Rym: The twist is, for each color, the score you get is one, like Scott said, multiplied by two.
Rym: Well, it's multiplied by one plus the number of handshakes you've played.
Rym: And, before you multiply, or add your score together, you subtract twenty from the total face value of all the cards' sum.
Rym: So, if I play a four, five, and a ten, that's nineteen, so that's a negative one on that row.
Scott: And if you get three handshakes, that's four times negative one, so negative four.
Scott: That's bad.
Scott: And think about it, it's really hard to get to twenty when you've got, in the deck, cards numbered two through ten, and that's it.
Scott: One of each.
Rym: Oh, and did I mention, you have to play the cards on their correct color, of course, and you must always raise the value of your pile.
Rym: You must always play a higher card than any previous card you've played.
Scott: Right, so you play the two, and then you play the five.
Scott: You can never play the three or the four ever.
Scott: There's no way to pick up that five.
Rym: And that's when Rym immediately discards the three and four he's been holding on to, and now you can't draw them.
Scott: Right, so it's like, on the one hand, you know, I could try to hold out to get the three and four.
Scott: Maybe they're in the deck, I don't know.
Scott: Rym has them.
Scott: But if I assume he has them, even if I say, well, he has them, there's no point in holding out for them, because I won't get them, I'll just play my five, that now frees his hand up, and he can now finally discard them.
Scott: If I had maybe held out longer, he might have been forced to discard them, just to do something, and given me a play.
Rym: There is one other rule, and this is the rule that Scott forgot.
Rym: If you play eight or more cards in a pile, then after you do all the scoring, you get twenty additional points.
Scott: Right, so you can play, you know, it might be hard to get over twenty if you don't get the big cards, like someone might be holding them out on you.
Rym: I think if you play eight cards, you're guaranteed to be above twenty, making it moot.
Scott: Yeah, well, you could...
Rym: Two, three, four, what Scott, what's two plus three plus four plus five plus six plus seven plus eight plus... Alright, handshake.
Scott: Three handshakes, two, three, four, five, six.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: That's eleven... Yup.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna get positive points.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: It won't be that, it won't be a lot though, but it'll be still a great play.
Rym: Okay, so with all this combined, like the rules make it very clear, and again, this is actually an example of really well-written rules, like you just read these things, they're beautiful.
Rym: Your expedition, each one could be worth anywhere between negative eighty and a hundred and fifty-six.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: That's a big swing, that's a wizard swing.
Scott: Yeah, negative eighty is three handshakes and nothing else, and one fifty-six is.
Scott: you play all the cards in order perfectly in the whole set.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So, we've played this game a bunch, I'm pretty much the god wizard of this game, at least for now, but it's interesting.
Rym: the interplay, like one thing I've noticed that I started trying right away, it seems like a pretty powerful strategy, is if I think Scott's not going after a color, I'll start banking cards by discarding them, because, you know, the round ends when the last card is drawn.
Rym: So I can bank cards into the middle and draw new cards by discarding.
Rym: if I'm confident Scott will not draw those cards from the discard and use them.
Rym: Then later, if I get cards of that color, and that's actually more likely because Scott's not investing in that color, then I can just redraw those as my draws and have guaranteed points.
Scott: Well, a good way to stop this strategy if your opponent is using it is, "Oh, I see that he has begun redrawing the cards he previously discarded to sort of make a huge play in that color, let me-".
Rym: Yoink, there goes the six!
Scott: "Let me take one of the cards from that perfectly open discard pile.
Scott: so now that they cannot use it.
Scott: Oh, there's still- I'll take another one from there, just hold it in my hand where they can't get it, yes?
Scott: Thank
Scott: you.".
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But, you could twist that one step further and use that as a stalling tactic to get the other person to not finish a bigger pile of something.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: There's a- because it's a two-player symmetric game, there is a huge amount of card counting, reading the other players' plays, bluffing, all that stuff combined.
Rym: You can take really big risks, sometimes you get fucked by those risks.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you could just, like, a lot of times you'll start a hand and in your hand you'll see something like, "White handshake, white two, white
Scott: ten.".
Scott: And you're like, "Alright, this is gonna happen,
Scott: right?".
Rym: I'm going for that long inside straight.
Scott: I mean, I'm gonna get- I just need like one more- one or two white cards in the whole- this is turn one, right?
Scott: There are, I know for a fact, a lot of white cards left in the deck.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: All I need to do is see pretty much any two of them, and this will be a positive play, and I can just make easy plays at the start of the game, I can just go white handshake, white two.
Scott: So, of course, what happens is you play white handshake- And then Rym goes, "Three, four, six, seven,
Scott: eight.".
Scott: And it's like, "You just turned one!
Rym: How could you possibly
Rym: know?".
Scott: But, it's like, that was a somewhat reasonable risk to take, and you know what, if you didn't just get that horrible luck of, "Yeah, Rym had every white card in his hand, you just didn't know
Scott: it.".
Rym: Yeah, heading into the Himalayas is a horrible risk to take.
Scott: Then, you would've had, you know, you could've drawn, like, it was possible that the deck was shuffled in such a way that every other card was white, and you would've just kept drawing white cards and playing them, and played them all in order, some majestic, perfect luck, right?
Scott: It can happen, there is luck.
Scott: But, you shuffle in the cards, I mean, you can't- you can only blame it on luck three out of four times like I can.
Rym: So, this is basically, like, one of the best two-player tabletop games I've ever seen.
Rym: So, if you need two-player tabletop games- Which everyone does.
Rym: Get this and Battle Line, 'cause they're both great and they're both Genizia, and I guess Oshii?
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Can you name another good two-player game?
Rym: We've played a lot of bad two-player games.
Scott: Hellas.
Scott: All the other ones ever.
Scott: Netrunner's a good two-player game.
Rym: Netrunner is a good two-player game.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: Not that many.
Scott: Yeah, Lost Cities, go find out what treasure is lying in them.
Rym: Alright, and on that note, we will see you at ConnectiCon, 'cause we got shit to do before the con.
Scott: Yeah, I got a lot to do, I can't sit around.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.