Rym: It's Tuesday March 3rd 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight the games we played at Pac South so long ago.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know we had a long hiatus after Pac South for a lot of reasons and It's weird that we're finally talking about Pac South Literally like before.
Rym: I pack for Pacs East.
Scott: yeah, I got a pack tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, too many packs is?
Scott: I had a dream And it was real really.
Scott: yeah, I remembered that Captain Jack's entire discography is on Spotify.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: Oh Shit, you're Captain Jack.
Scott: You get what I get your autograph.
Rym: Oh my god Captain Jack.
Rym: man You know what I I you know what.
Rym: I just realized the same thing you realize a little while ago.
Rym: I'm gonna do well.
Rym: I'm well.
Rym: I'm working on shit tonight Jack.
Rym: so you know what I got in my hand something you haven't gotten to use yet our special enforcer badges.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: I remember.
Scott: I forgot.
Scott: I thought I lost it, but I guess I know.
Rym: Because this was the first packs we could use them legitimately because we weren't enforcers at South.
Rym: okay, so uh yeah It's packs time and we'll talk about that later, so I got any news.
Rym: It's a gaming day.
Rym: We haven't talked about games in a while.
Scott: You know GDC is happening.
Scott: You think there'd be a ton of gaming news, but actually I didn't see anything worth talking.
Rym: GDC is not for the.
Scott: Usually things still happen there that were every year past of GeekNights.
Scott: you can find probably an episode.
Scott: We talked about some news from GDC, but I haven't seen any at all date night.
Rym: I chose.
Scott: They're like doing stuff We have nothing to talk about with it.
Rym: No we don't.
Rym: uh News from GDC?
Rym: wow there is literally Nothing.
Rym: the biggest gaming news.
Rym: I could find is that you know valve is not holding a press conference today.
Scott: Bigot new flat news flash.
Scott: there is no news.
Scott: Yeah, geo g.com is having a sale right now.
Scott: They've done this a few times before I think where they sell games like ridiculously low prices like even lower than the usual Ridiculousness, but in limited quantities, so it'll be like this $50 game is five bucks But only like 20 people can get it for five bucks.
Scott: and as soon as 20 people buy five bucks Then they switch it to a different game.
Rym: I think I know why there's no news out of GDC this year because PAX East is like in a few days.
Rym: Yeah, I think they're gonna coincide the announcements with PAX East sounds good to me?
Scott: Yeah, whatever, so I want to talk about.
Scott: I do some geek bite who a geek by game.
Scott: I've been playing recently Skeleton clicker also known as el Diablo.
Rym: is this?
Rym: oh wait a minute.
Rym: You're talking about Diablo aren't you?
Rym: Okay, I was like who is it like how?
Scott: the last time we talked about this game We were talking about you know the real money auction house garbage, and now you should never play this horrible game.
Scott: That shit was removed actually quite a long time ago by now.
Rym: It is kind of sad and interesting that I cared so little.
Rym: I didn't pay attention to that.
Scott: I only got the game because there was some ridiculous sale that like Blizzard ever has a sale.
Rym: I think I have the game too But I don't think I paid for it.
Scott: They had a big old sale and you got the game and the expansion and a whole bunch of garbage whatever for like way less Than the usual price.
Scott: so then I found a friend to play it with.
Scott: so We're just in clicking on skeletons.
Scott: and Yeah, everything I've said about el Diablo in the past is still true.
Scott: You literally do nothing in this game But click on skeletons, and if you're about to die run away and push the health potion button And then click on skeletons again.
Scott: perhaps click on some demons perhaps click on some ghosts or something?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: you just click on bad guys And then it makes it really easy to optimize your equipment even more than the old days.
Scott: cuz like.
Rym: What did Dave say?
Rym: cuz David it's weird you know.
Rym: so lately Dave and Joel have been on fast karate.
Rym: I've been talking about a lot of the things we talked about like.
Rym: we've just both been covering like the same anime and the same games and things like weirdly and We basically been saying the same thing.
Rym: so they were just talking about this and saying a lot of the things that we're saying right Now yeah like it'll tell you you know on an item.
Scott: Let's say you find a hammer.
Scott: It'll be like strength plus 30 with this hammer and okay What does that really mean though?
Scott: well down on the bottom?
Scott: It'll show you like.
Scott: well that will increase your damage.
Scott: this if you equip this item instead of the item you have now Your damage will go up by 30% Your toughness will go down by this percent your healing will go up or down by this percent etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: so You only need to look at that you can completely ignore all the other numbers.
Scott: So I'm playing a wizard II who's pretty much a glass cannon wizard II.
Scott: yeah Far away from anything that can kill you.
Rym: get someone else to tank I believe.
Scott: do as much range damage as possible then run away and continue to do so perhaps.
Scott: So I only care about increasing damage, so there's really not any thinking that goes into this game.
Scott: It's pretty much just the story.
Scott: wait.
Rym: That's the same strategy.
Rym: I used in.
Rym: one must fall 2097. just increase damage.
Rym: Don't care about anything else right?
Scott: so It's just the story pretty much in this game other than clicking on the skeleton.
Rym: So I'm gonna go get to y'all.
Rym: I got him.
Scott: Yeah, the story is pretty much that.
Scott: But for some reason like you sort of care, but I do.
Scott: there's one giant plot hole that I don't understand.
Scott: Is that?
Scott: you know?
Scott: it's about like heaven's.
Scott: real hell is real.
Scott: There's demons in hell.
Scott: There's angels in heaven.
Scott: They're all really wicked powerful, but somehow thanks to grinding you're even more powerful Dude.
Rym: see also D&D.
Scott: I mean once you get level 20 like you're already much The angels and demons are fighting angels with good guys.
Scott: you're on their side even though they have some infighting issues whatever and Then you know you got to go kill all the bad guys because they all came back since Diablo 2. right Big deal.
Scott: the one thing I don't understand is spoilers In the last act of el diablo.
Scott: trace.
Scott: el diablo Goes to heaven to take on heaven itself as opposed to like the end of Diablo 2 where you go into hell to get Diablo.
Rym: that's a smart move right?
Scott: The thing I don't understand is like isn't like God up there.
Scott: It's like he's taking all these angels.
Scott: It's like wouldn't?
Scott: God doesn't appear at all to do anything about this.
Rym: well Maybe this world exists in a mythology where there's a demiurge Which is like with the angels, but there is an unknowable further God that doesn't interact.
Scott: well That gnostic bullshit that is certainly likely because God ain't showing the fuck up, and it's like why do I do this?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: shouldn't you Diablo show up in heaven and God just like Scott?
Rym: Oh, yeah, Scott so think of this in medieval like images often like everything's two-dimensional partly because you know that's God's perspective on the world.
Rym: So you are God in Diablo.
Rym: you are sitting outside of the plane of this world existence.
Rym: so why with a screen Controlling an avatar just like God's doing Dungeons & Dragons.
Scott: That's how you want to do.
Rym: That's how I want to do.
Scott: alright That's one more thing.
Scott: I had to say about Diablo trace right.
Scott: It's just uh you know It's really a nothing game like you just have nothing to do and you want to click on something.
Scott: But yeah your brain has already used it up its willpower for the day.
Rym: Yeah, like you know you don't want it.
Rym: You want one step above just drawing squares on the desktop, right?
Scott: For some reason even though torchlight and torchlight 2 are the exact same fucking game as Diablo 1 2 3 Especially 2 & 3 same exact goddamn game.
Scott: the art is different.
Scott: Maybe yeah for some reason.
Scott: I don't know why.
Scott: Usually I know why or I can figure out why but I'm trying to figure out why and I don't understand because I went back And loaded up torchlight, and I clicked on some skeletons there.
Scott: Then I clicked on some Diablo skeletons and as far as I can tell there's no real difference.
Scott: But for some reason me, but also other people that I know all seem to agree that it's like yeah Diablo you kind of like clicking on the skeletons and in torchlight you get bored of clicking on the skeletons really fucking fast.
Rym: I think it's partly that kind of like how different FPS is and it's not just like.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: I was getting plenty of loots in Both of them.
Scott: it's not the loot reward No It's the like.
Rym: when you click and you cast a spell and you hit something I think the animation and the sound and the motion Reaction just feel Like I was using guns.
Scott: It was pretty satisfying.
Scott: boom.
Rym: Yeah, I think it's just a little.
Rym: for whatever reason It's a little more satisfying can't figure it out.
Rym: Might also be just like a slight like frame timing.
Rym: Scott you're playing on different frames.
Scott: I have no idea what you know why the exact like pretty much this and it's not like torchlight is like some obviously Crappy jank version.
Scott: right it's a highly polished well-developed game.
Scott: You know good.
Scott: You know well programmed everything.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with it.
Scott: It's it's professionally made.
Scott: I I don't know what magic blizzard put in the Diablo.
Rym: you can't always understand the whims of the human heart.
Scott: also I wonder sorry if I offended anyone like you know anyone who speaks Spanish by always saying El Diablo But Scott's done this as long as I've known him.
Scott: I wonder if in Spanish-speaking countries is it called Satan three Or or devil three?
Scott: I am sure the Al's above three.
Rym: I am confident It's just called Diablo, but I haven't looked this up.
Rym: So I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Scott: and would we get in trouble if we made a game called like Satan three?
Rym: I'll bet we could get away with making a game just called Satan.
Rym: all right I wonder if there is a game already called Satan.
Rym: I mean, there's Satan's hollow sure, but that's not Satan.
Scott: You should make Satan's hollow - where you electric boogaloo.
Scott: Yeah, you click on the bridge.
Rym: So I did a livestream last night kind of on a sudden whim Because I got home from doing a bunch of stuff and I was supposed to be working on of all things I've been making for like a couple weeks now a really long sort of Mechanical explanation of five nights at Freddy's like the first one.
Rym: It's got this freaking game.
Rym: They're really good at being a horror game.
Scott: This is a game I needed to play for like five minutes and never needs to look at again.
Scott: Yeah, when you're like obsessed with it so much you're making a crazy long video.
Rym: I am and it's a really good video but so I've been kind of like playing one to analyze and be able to talk about it and all this stuff and making this Long video and I sit down to finish that video because it's almost done.
Rym: And then I see a bunch of people tween about five nights at Freddy's 3 because it came out suddenly like it Scott I think people I think people knew it was coming.
Scott: Well.
Rym: No we knew it was coming.
Scott: We didn't know when that guy seems to be cranking him out.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Scott Cawthorne is Already in my mind a genius.
Rym: Here's why.
Rym: why prolific so prolific?
Rym: well?
Rym: No he made other guy I'm gonna read.
Rym: I'm gonna quote Wikipedia because it tells the story.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I haven't verified this story 100% but Wikipedia has to take it at that quote.
Rym: the idea for five nights at Freddy's stems from the negative reception towards Scott Cawthorne's previous game the family-friendly chipper and sons lumber company where players ridiculed the main character a young beaver as Looking like a quote scary animatronic animal.
Rym: Jim Sterling called the game unintentionally terrifying.
Rym: Although initially depressed by the poor reception to chipper and sons Cawthorne who had previously developed a chipper and sons Christianity oriented games Eventually used it to inspire himself to make something intentionally scarier, and that's when he made five nights at Freddy's.
Scott: So this guy's like a big holy roller here.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know much about him.
Rym: I haven't done a lot of research on him I've only been focusing on the game, but so five nights at Freddy's just became virally Ridiculously successful, but in this weird like sharded off world It's like there's one corner of the internet where everybody's obsessed with this game and knows everything about it.
Scott: And I mean there's some corner of the internet where people are still crazy about Ultima big corner Like you run into.
Rym: you know like like go to a patch like everyone's like oh my god five nights at Freddy's.
Rym: like you see Some cosplay, but then you like talk about it at another packs and literally no one in the room had even heard of it.
Rym: so Anyway, the three came out and I tweeted kind of like ha Would anyone care if I just bought it and live-streamed it right now and a ton of listeners were like fucking do it.
Rym: So I did it.
Scott: Yeah, we won't have to pay for that shit.
Scott: You do it.
Rym: So it was interesting.
Rym: I played five nights at Freddy's 3 Literally knowing nothing about it and just kind of completely blind.
Rym: So basically I did for three what I said You should have done for one watching other people play these games is the wrong way to experience them Unless you're watching your excitable friend play them like at a party.
Rym: And then Kate couldn't even take it and gave the controller back to me and forced me to play it, but I digress.
Rym: So I played five nights at Freddy's 3 and I kind of reviewed it as I was playing it.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It's the second best of the games.
Rym: It's really good at what it does.
Rym: It's worth playing.
Rym: if you like these kinds of games just buy it and play it.
Rym: don't watch like markiplier.
Rym: Those people play it on YouTube.
Rym: play it yourself You know like those PewDiePie types.
Rym: So just play it and it's kind of fun.
Rym: and it.
Rym: it actually got me a couple times too, you know I knew it was a jump scare.
Rym: I'm like, alright, this game is a jump scare game.
Rym: Oh, I bet a jump scare is coming now and I lean back like I'm not gonna get jump scared.
Rym: That's stupid.
Rym: and then it doesn't jump scare me.
Rym: Okay, and I lean in and then it jump scares like the moment I lean in.
Scott: You just jump scare of like when?
Scott: There's not pot like you couldn't possibly expect it like like you.
Scott: check all the cameras.
Scott: You see all the guys are like totally where they belong.
Scott: Yeah, put the camera away jump scare.
Rym: Yeah, so I actually Not so.
Rym: in my video for teleported fuck you.
Scott: for
Rym: five nights at Freddy's one I talked about that because the part of the reason why it works that the game uses a series of tricks to where you figure Like you learn Oh a jump scare happens when this occurs, but then they'll be us like in the next night.
Rym: They'll subtly break that rule and introduce a jump scare you didn't expect.
Rym: So when the power goes out sometimes Freddy just doesn't attack you right away.
Rym: Sometimes he doesn't attack you at all.
Rym: It becomes 6 a.m And you win the game.
Rym: does these things to trick you into getting jump scared even after you think I'm going to lean back and not Get jump scared.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: So yeah, three is pretty good.
Rym: And if you're curious if you should play it just watch my live stream.
Rym: You'll see exactly what it's like and then you'll see enough to know if you should play the rest of it or not.
Scott: You didn't beat it.
Rym: now I got to the fourth night in a blind play and then it was like midnight and I really had to go to bed Hmm, and I really needed my heart to stop beating so fast.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: Someone tweeted this.
Rym: I think it was Nahasha Allegri.
Rym: I'm not I don't remember but it's quite internet thing and I Was suddenly reminded that this existed.
Rym: so the Super Mario Brothers Super Show was pretty pretty good at being what it was I guess.
Rym: of all the episodes in that show There was one that I saw once when I was many on sin And I did not like.
Rym: I had vague memories of it But I couldn't remember anything that happened in it and I wasn't really sure if it existed or if I'd made it up.
Rym: There was no internet back then so I couldn't like find a list of episodes or anything.
Rym: So I forgot about it now years later.
Rym: I realized what it was and I was reminded of it the other day.
Rym: I submit to you the Super Mario Brothers Super Show episode entitled bad rap where Every character raps the entire time Badly and there's a like rap beat.
Scott: Well, this is the early 90s when like MC Hammer was the shit.
Scott: Yeah, big deal this hit the mainstream.
Rym: This is amazing and Terrifying.
Rym: I dare you to watch the whole thing.
Scott: Yeah, oh My friend cookie must.
Scott: he came to my city.
Scott: actually he lives in New York City Yeah, but anyway, he went over to Manhattan where he doesn't live.
Scott: He lives in Queens And he visited el museums.
Scott: They're all pretty close to each other.
Scott: The big ones the MoMA the met the Guggenheim.
Scott: he visited them and while he was there.
Scott: He learned many things.
Scott: he enlightened himself Thanks to all the magnificent artworks And he shared those enlightening discoveries with us people.
Scott: So if you need to be enlightened By the Cookie Monster and you don't live in New York and you can't go to these museums like just on a whim like people live in New York can You might need Cookie Monster to enlighten you about why you should move to New York.
Rym: My favorite part about that is in the Guggenheim.
Rym: He doesn't say anything.
Rym: his facial expression says it all.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: That was a good a good little bit there.
Scott: I mean also Why you should have googly eyes.
Rym: Googly eyes are pretty good.
Scott: It's a pretty much make everything better in the meta moment.
Rym: The book club book is still water ship down.
Rym: It's about rabbits on an adventure.
Rym: It's kind of important.
Rym: a lot of nerds have read it a lot of nerdy things.
Rym: We're inspired by it.
Scott: I guess I'll read more on the PAX bus.
Rym: We are going to be at that PAX which is on Friday this weekend.
Rym: It's gone.
Scott: So this PAX is in three days.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, there's gonna be no GeekNights on Thursday.
Scott: We have a panel at that PAX.
Scott: Yes on a really good time Friday at 4 30 p.m.
Rym: On Friday in the bumblebee theater.
Scott: That's the front right theater.
Scott: Yeah, go straight into PAX turn right and up and it's like the first thing.
Rym: Yeah, go straight into PAX on the main floor turn right and then go to the end of the hall.
Rym: turn left.
Rym: It's the first one right there.
Rym: Yeah bumblebee and the upstairs the up of escalators But not the up up the up up.
Scott: the up up is main events and some other.
Rym: Well, there's all.
Rym: there's an up up that goes to some other theaters.
Scott: It's the one up.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, it's the.
Rym: well now it is the up up actually because there's air animals land animals sea animals.
Rym: We're not all the way down in the cuttlefish.
Scott: No, we're not into cuttlefish.
Rym: We're presenting.
Rym: What is losing?
Rym: It's gonna be fucking awesome.
Rym: If you want to find us at PAX to figure out like how to game with us or ask us a question or whatever right after going to that panel and Grabbing us as we come out of the room is pretty much your best possible chance.
Rym: Otherwise, you're gonna have to hope you run into us in tabletop.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna be sad.
Scott: I'm gonna get one of those little signs where it's like that lets you put an eight and a half by eleven piece of paper And stand it up in a piece of plastic.
Scott: Are you sort of like an L shape?
Scott: Yeah, I'm going to staples Oh nice.
Scott: Yeah, and I'm gonna write on it pretty much like hey, you know, let's play netrunner.
Scott: I'm gonna put at the end of the table and tabletop when I'm sitting there.
Scott: So now it'll be easy to find us either if you want to play netrunner or not.
Scott: You can still find us by looking for a netrunner sign And we're enforcing at night at least I am.
Scott: so don't look for me after seven o'clock.
Rym: Yep I don't know when I'm forcing.
Scott: come to tabletop at seven o'clock or later on Friday or Saturday But I can't play games with you, but I can probably help you out with shit.
Rym: He can kick you out.
Scott: I can't kick you out myself, but I can definitely.
Scott: you can put in.
Scott: I can have you kicked out.
Rym: You can put into motion a process by which you will be removed only if the person does something worthy of engaging that process.
Rym: Yep, so don't show up to tabletop at night like naked and vomiting.
Scott: Don't show up with alcohol or drugs or anything that it says in the back of your packs badge not to do like.
Scott: don't punch People there, yep, I don't deal with you But you can just come and ask me questions while I'm in for salating because that's.
Rym: and then so, you know, of course Next week once just like the last bags There won't be any shows at least not in the beginning of the week because I'm going straight from packs to London.
Rym: You're first for two other events that are not related to gaming and not fun.
Scott: if you live in London If you live in the crown jewels and bring them to me.
Rym: if you want to hang out in London Do that.
Scott: Well, how come you're not as good as Lupin?
Scott: Why do you suck next Wednesday morning?
Rym: I might have a bunch of free time.
Rym: We could grab like breakfast or brunch or something.
Scott: There must be like a nerdy place to go in London like a comic shop or a gaming.
Rym: Oh, yeah I've been alone enough.
Scott: I know a bunch of stuff to do or a tabletop cafe kind of place You know bicycle bike shop.
Rym: Yeah, so at Pac South we played South by the packs.
Scott: East is this weekend.
Scott: Pac South was weekends ago.
Rym: now We're not.
Rym: I mean, we're gonna do a show later to review San Antonio But a Thursday show.
Rym: we don't need to do a whole show on reviewing Pac South because Pac South was a pax.
Rym: It was equivalent to PAX Australia.
Scott: It was a real time Bigger than the first packs, Australia.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: It was well.
Rym: Yeah, you didn't go to the second PAX Australia.
Rym: It is the same as the normal PAX Australia the second packs.
Rym: Yes, though the one that you didn't go to.
Rym: Okay, and It was a packs.
Rym: It was great And honestly if you had to choose like if you had to drop up if you had to choose two paxes to go to I would say go to Australia and prime.
Rym: if you had to choose three, I'd say Australia Prime and South.
Rym: I'd put East last only because not because East is not good.
Rym: No, but because you can't get a fucking hotel room.
Scott: Yeah, and I was already Western there's nowhere to eat.
Scott: It's nothing about the packs itself at East It's just that like it's East is like the even though we live really close to East.
Rym: It's the closest one Yeah, it's the most inconvenient one because it is easier to get to and get hotels for pax prime and Australia Than pax East.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, so, you know Pac South was a pax, you know We spent most of it playing games like you do.
Scott: one interesting thing Was that like the tabletop was really big maybe huge maybe the biggest tabletop of any pegs and it wasn't super crowded.
Scott: The attendance wasn't like prime or East level attendance.
Scott: Yeah, it was still sold out.
Scott: Yeah yet is right It was the first year of a new packs in a dent not so densely populated area of the world You know, Texas a big flat.
Rym: Yeah The only thing that was very interesting that I kind of want to mention is that you know It didn't.
Rym: really it's sold out I think like right at the end like it didn't sell out up until the con.
Scott: Yeah You could get badges for two of the days or almost right up until the number of people within Geographic distance of San Antonio who are nerds and want to go to a pax and what is not.
Rym: based on my completely anecdotal entirely biased personal experience the demographic of pax prime is everyone who's a gamer who can get there like people I from Everywhere like in fact the average person I meet at pax prime is not from anywhere near Seattle.
Rym: It's always people from New York and Europe and just like Canada It's a bit like the same percentage of Greek people in Astoria.
Scott: Astoria is still a Greek neighborhood.
Scott: There's still plenty of Greek people.
Scott: They own most of the real estate like the buildings and shit, but the majority of people there are not Greeks It's just enough.
Scott: They're just.
Scott: they just sort of outnumber any other individual group.
Scott: So there's the same thing.
Scott: like you go to pax prime.
Scott: Washingtonians aren't the majority at the pax at least only having badges But they outnumber any other individual group.
Scott: There's still the most of them.
Rym: pax East seems to be in my experience Mostly people from New York Boston and Washington.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much you're gonna get even amounts from all over the Northeast.
Scott: You're also gonna get some more Europeans and some less Australians and other types because But you're gonna get an increase relative percentage wise of people from Seattle Washington area because that's the pax area.
Rym: Yup, so pax Australia was mostly Australians and foreign people who work in the games industry Of course and top-tier Lot of Kiwis and a lot of people from Europe actually.
Scott: But well, you also get at pax south even when I was there I was saying I said Australia.
Rym: No,
Scott: but I'm saying I had quite a few like Chinese Japanese true Southeast Asia street passes because you know If you speak English and you're up there pax out pretty close,
Rym: but seriously I feel like the majority of people I interacted with at pax south where they lived in San Antonio Or drove there from somewhere nearby.
Rym: Yes, and had only one day bad.
Scott: Yep, Dallas, Houston Phoenix those types.
Rym: so I feel like pax south is pretty much people who can't afford to get into other pax I think it was some Oklahoma or can't get badges or hotels for other paxes.
Scott: Yeah, I think I picked up the Oklahoma Street pass, which is the one I did not have.
Rym: Yeah So but as a result It's way easier to get into pax south than say pax east.
Rym: Like it's easier for me to go to pax south than to go to pax east despite living in New York.
Rym: Yeah, and if I had to choose between them, I'd go to south because there's way more room in tabletop and there's way more restaurant.
Scott: Yes, it was way easy to eat there.
Rym: Yeah way good food.
Rym: Well, you have relatively good food nearby.
Scott: Yeah, it's not New York food.
Rym: So we played a bunch of games.
Rym: We talked about the games we played.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know since there wasn't so much at the pax we've spent of course a lot of time gaming Yeah, and there wasn't anything in San Antonio.
Scott: So there wasn't much San Antonio is.
Scott: there wasn't more than a day's worth.
Rym: There is one point three days worth of shit to do in San Antonio if you stretch it and you don't have a car.
Rym: Yeah two full days.
Scott: if you have a car and you spend a lot of that time like watching a whole movie or a whole night of viewing at the Alamo Drafthouse.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'm glad we didn't go to that anime thing though, cuz that looked pretty like booby scary.
Scott: Yeah, well Funimation was doing it.
Scott: I think whatever.
Rym: Yeah, but it wasn't.
Rym: it wasn't good.
Scott: No anyway Anyway, so what games did we play?
Rym: We played though?
Rym: I didn't play but I watched them play.
Rym: Sheriff of Nottingham.
Scott: Ah Who is the sheriff?
Rym: I will be.
Rym: It's like a lying bluffing game, you know, like.
Scott: maybe the person played it should explain it.
Scott: Okay, so basically On your turn right you're gonna sort of you have a hand of cards and You're sort of putting cards into this bag actually comes a little bag.
Scott: Yeah We feel like really Snappy buttons and you're basically trying to get your goods into Nottingham and the sheriff is that someone's the sheriff and they're at the gate.
Scott: so you take turns being the sheriff.
Scott: when you're the sheriff You don't do the bag thing, right?
Scott: Everyone puts out a bag and they tell you what's in the bag.
Scott: So they'll say like there are three Chickens in this bag.
Scott: There are four wheats in this bag.
Scott: I forget the specific goods, but it's you know goods like that, right?
Scott: now that may or may not be what's in the bag?
Scott: if It?
Scott: so if it is what's in the bag, then that's good for the person putting it in.
Scott: But if it's not what's in the bag, it's bad for them.
Rym: But I come up to Scott with my bag and I'm like, there's three apples in here Scott.
Scott: now He's gonna give me three apples now.
Scott: I have to decide Do I look in the bag or not?
Scott: look in the bag is on the sheriff.
Scott: I choose each.
Scott: I can open all the bags.
Scott: I can open none of the bags.
Scott: It's completely up to me if I'm gonna open the bag or not.
Scott: Each bag has a snap on it.
Rym: Yeah The game is really good.
Scott: rules about like once the snap is on is latched by the player They cannot unlatch it and as soon as the sheriff unlatches it they've made their decision to open it.
Rym: Yep, or like a sheriff it close again.
Rym: if the sheriff hands the bag back to you It's gone.
Rym: you can't ask for it again, right?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: So You know the sheriff opens the bag.
Scott: if in the bag are The goods that you said were in there then the sheriff opened it.
Scott: The sheriff has to give you money like oops.
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: I opened your bag.
Scott: if the goods that are not correct Right, then the sheriff opens it.
Scott: you get in trouble, right?
Scott: So, you know, that's how it works.
Scott: And of course if the sheriff doesn't open the bag you just sneak all the goods through whether they're good or not.
Rym: Yeah, it was actually three crossbows.
Scott: Yeah, so there's legit goods like apples and stuff But there's also not legit goods like crossbows and gems and all sorts of illicit.
Scott: You know contraband the contraband are worth way more fucking points.
Scott: now It's really all about sneaking through contraband.
Scott: is the whole game is how much contraband?
Scott: Can you sneak through?
Scott: because wow, you're gonna get a lot more points if you sneak through contraband.
Rym: It's just a really like awesome fun bluffing game.
Scott: Yeah, it's very just.
Scott: straight up You know put stuff in the bag bluff mess with the person who's the sheriff.
Scott: also be really good at being the sheriff and tell Who's lying and who's not?
Scott: People can also bribe you like yo I will give you some money if you don't open my bag or I will give you money to open rims back.
Rym: You can make pretty much almost any deal you want.
Scott: you can think about this mathematically right and to where it's like.
Scott: Okay, if the sheriff opens my bag, I'll lose this much money.
Scott: So I'll give the sheriff half of what.
Scott: this person who is the sheriff right now is a losing is player who's not doing well.
Scott: So giving them half of my profit margin on my illicit good Is not going to hurt me very much.
Scott: I can make a binding agreement with them for something immediate.
Scott: So I'll give that.
Scott: I'll be like half my profit is three.
Scott: I will give you three to not open my bag.
Scott: if they don't agree Well, they'll open my bag and I'll be screwed.
Scott: Anyway, if they do accept it, okay I'll cut my profit margin in half.
Scott: but at least I will you know get something out of it.
Scott: and Giving them three is no big deal because they're losing so whatever.
Rym: I mean, it's just a really solid game.
Rym: Why don't you play it a bunch more probably do a very like deep down?
Scott: You might do a whole episode on it.
Scott: So that will leave it at that.
Rym: So the other big god German style board game we played was navigator navigator, I really like navigator.
Rym: I tried to buy it, but you can't get it on Amazon.
Rym: So I'm gonna have to go to the strat and probably pay full price for it.
Scott: I plow.
Scott: well next time I'm there I'll let you know if I see it there.
Rym: if you see it there I'll put it in.
Rym: I'll just buy it from you unless the guy wants like more than a hundred bucks.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: they charge a lot there.
Scott: So this is a game that's you know, it's really hard.
Rym: It has the same brain feel as games like imagine Endecker crossed with Puerto Rico sort of like that kind of guy.
Scott: you.
Scott: it's got cool parts where you're moving boats around.
Scott: That's the fun.
Rym: It's got really good mechanics around.
Rym: like you can build factories or you can like.
Rym: there's sort of like this Commodities market in the game.
Rym: some people profit if people are selling a lot and then other people profit.
Rym: if people are Refining a lot and selling or refining kind of push the meter in the opposite direction.
Scott: If someone buys a bunch of goods because they want them, you know, because they need them for stuff Then the price will go up.
Scott: So if you're producing those goods that the price just went up for and you sell them then you'll get more money.
Scott: But then of course if you start selling a bunch of them and putting more in the market The price will go down.
Scott: and it's sort of like power the bottom of power grid.
Scott: only if the bottom of power grid were controlled by player actions and not just sort of this automatic thing that happens every turn on a Schedule.
Rym: but more importantly it's a rondell game rondo.
Rym: I'm a big fan of rondell games ever since NTK and The rondell kind of makes it Yeah.
Scott: If you didn't have the rondell This game would be way too Like super easy because you can just take the perfect action every turn like in Puerto Rico.
Scott: You can just take the action you want unless someone took it already in this game that rondell.
Scott: pretty much there were so many turns Where it's like.
Scott: I know I'll do this action and this action of this action and I'll get to do all this.
Scott: It'll be super efficient perfect choice.
Scott: And then I look at the rondell and I'm like I'm gonna have to go around the rondell like three times to do all that and I could do it too.
Scott: I could do all those actions with only one trip around the rondell But I need to do them in this specific order and the rondell is made in the most evil possible fashion.
Rym: The rondell is very well designed Evilly designed and but because of the rondell the thing the thing that I think gives us I gotta play it a much more Before we really really played it once just like Sheriff Nottingham.
Rym: But the reason I want to buy it is that it shows Promise.
Rym: I have not seen in many recent games that try to have this depth of mechanics because with the rondell I think the game has a similar interplay to Hans the Teutonica where it's not so much about having a Coherent strategy.
Rym: It's about having a tactical stretch like following a tactic and reacting to how the other players are playing The game.
Rym: it's a highly reactive game.
Rym: Yeah, but it's not an attacking game.
Scott: yeah, like if some you know you might have a really efficient move and you got planned out for three turns and then someone else Moves forward and takes your biz with their fast boats, and it's like well Okay, I guess that plan isn't gonna work, but I already moved on this rondell.
Scott: So now I need to figure out something else to do on this rondell.
Scott: But you know you can only really go one move on the rondell before other people do stuff.
Scott: So there's some things you can do I think.
Scott: to take two turns in a row though.
Rym: Well, you can take on navigator action if you are the navigador right.
Rym: yeah, but I really like it.
Rym: I can't say if it's great yet.
Rym: I gotta play it some more, but it's in the queue.
Rym: We played a shit ton of doom like original doom.
Rym: Scott is terrible.
Rym: at doom deathmatch.
Scott: I'm not terrible.
Rym: you I had like four times the number of frags you in a one-on-one.
Scott: It's not correct.
Rym: That is a hundred percent.
Rym: You had more.
Scott: you didn't have four times.
Rym: I had so many more.
Rym: It was ridiculous.
Rym: I would kill you like seven, eight times in a row.
Scott: I should have taken a screenshot.
Scott: You know what.
Scott: there is no screenshot.
Scott: I had more.
Rym: Yeah, all right all right.
Scott: I didn't have more, but it wasn't four times.
Rym: All right, Scott if you believe that to be true.
Scott: also despite me having less.
Scott: I still had many.
Rym: Not that many.
Scott: I had many also.
Rym: You just had more.
Rym: many of your kills were while I was semi-idle and setting up my control.
Scott: there were many kills when I was Idle and setting up my control.
Rym: no there were not all right.
Scott: We're opening a menu.
Rym: If you honestly think you can stand by your doom skills, and I propose this to you Let's play some live stream doom deathmatch you and me also.
Scott: It was very disappointing to go into the PC room and not be able to get a full counter-strike game.
Rym: Oh my god That was the saddest thing ever.
Rym: we go to PC freeplay early on like Sunday morning And we're like perfect counter-strike time.
Rym: you sit down.
Rym: There's a ton of people in there.
Rym: we see sat near some people playing counter-strike And then I tried to like a tap them on the shoulder and every one of them is just playing in rando games online And it's like dudes.
Scott: There's like a LAN here.
Scott: this server is running in this room There.
Scott: wait if you open the LAN tab there they are and why aren't you on them?
Rym: no one was on those servers.
Rym: There was one dude who was willing to play counter-strike.
Scott: We had to tell him we had to talk to him because he's sitting next to us and get him to join the server with.
Rym: And he was super cool, but everyone else was literally playing rando fucking games online silently Just like they would at home.
Scott: also why also MOBAs?
Rym: yeah So as we got up because when we got in there a lot of counter-strike we played for like our hour And then they kicked us out.
Rym: so I remember I got up to leave and I turned around And it was a sea of people playing nothing but MOBAs.
Scott: We should go and play Skeleton clicker.
Scott: yeah, that would be a good PAX game.
Rym: Yeah, only if you're a rowdy and possibly drunk.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: everyone be like Get the El Diablo!
Scott: Making a fun joke.
Rym: So we found an amazing game.
Scott: Oh no you didn't click on the skeleton.
Scott: What is wrong with you?
Rym: We're gonna talk about this game in more detail too But it's on the House of Iron Mouse website.
Rym: the game is called bring your own book.
Scott: bring your own book.
Scott: Do you literally bring your own book?
Rym: so everyone brings a book of their choice?
Rym: Okay, like a physical book printed pages.
Scott: Does it had to be nonfiction fiction C-spot run Dr.
Scott: Seuss.
Rym: I suggest you bring fiction I guess.
Rym: But basically what you do is it's kind of one of those like It's a game or you'll have a prompt.
Rym: so everyone gets a prompt like I'm gonna read some.
Rym: because they gave us a cards against humanity.
Scott: Prompt or apples to apples.
Rym: prom the name of an inn in a D&D campaign overheard at a LARP Something you could hear Mario.
Scott: So with those kind of prompts this those prompts are made specifically for nerds.
Rym: This isn't a dialogue from an episode of a soap opera like General Hospital.
Rym: Okay, you could play words tattooed on someone's body a good warning to children an item in a police report.
Scott: All right, so there are cards in there.
Scott: you could play without nerdy all over the place.
Rym: But then the timer starts and everyone flips through their own book until they find a passage an uninterrupted passage That matches the prompt.
Rym: and then there's rules about like the order like once you're done Everyone else has a certain amount of time.
Rym: and then much like apples to apples or cards against humanity.
Rym: Everyone reads their prompts All right.
Scott: Now, how do you vote?
Scott: who who's the?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's we're gonna talk about.
Scott: this game is one person like the person with the prompt you.
Rym: then you're going to talk about this game Excruciating detail because it looked amazing and the people we saw getting a demo and playing it.
Rym: We're having a lot of fun.
Rym: They brought a ton of books with them.
Rym: I saw one guy was pointedly using the Lord of the Rings giant edition.
Scott: what would be the best book to use?
Scott: with that I Mean like like seriously like.
Scott: it has to be a book that would produce Hilarious results that would score points that are also relevant.
Scott: has to be a book that like, you know Well enough that you can find stuff.
Rym: Yeah, you know what I would use.
Rym: Honestly the darkness that came before Know that book well enough and it is eminently quotable.
Rym: I mean, here's one a phrase you wouldn't want aliens to judge humanity by.
Rym: I could find that what pretty nothing you see.
Rym: I could find that words of nothing in like seconds.
Scott: What do you see?
Rym: a line written by dr.
Rym: Seuss might be harder.
Scott: What if you have that in the Hat in front of you?
Scott: you could just be like, yeah thing one and thing two.
Rym: This game was just like really good concept and the people seem to really have their stuff together.
Rym: So promising.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: We played video video ball The sport that has replaced all other sport in a grim and dark future.
Scott: Hopefully it ice hockey finds an underground exist.
Rym: I'm telling you guys now you heard it here first Video ball is going to be a breakout game in the coming months.
Scott: video ball is gonna be the shit.
Scott: It's coming.
Rym: video ball is going to be an e-sport and I think it's going to begin in like the next few weeks Because it's gonna be the next knit hog.
Rym: If it's the next nig hut knit hog, that's fine because I'll play it with like the few people who remember it.
Scott: at worst It's the best knit hog is what I'm saying.
Rym: I just think Pax should get the guy on the video ball staff who does the commentary like when they're at cons to be the commentator of every omegathon finale.
Rym: henceforth, I Mean this guy like.
Rym: I can't even do him justice, but I'm not even gonna try.
Rym: he's great.
Scott: So there's this game that we saw also in the expo hall there that made a big splash on the internet afterwards Even though some people were slow to discover it I guess because they weren't at PAX South.
Scott: Yeah, there's a game.
Scott: it had a nice booth right in the middle called star Mazer.
Scott: It's star.
Scott: Oh, I forgot all about that game.
Scott: It's a point-and-click adventure.
Scott: It's also a shmup and it's got sort of like stylings of space quest but also anime But also sort of like I don't know really good stylings.
Scott: You'll know the stylings when you see them.
Rym: It's the kind of styling where you implicitly trust whatever creative team is making the game.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you just see the logo and you know what this game is all about style wise.
Scott: So it's like point-and-click adventure then some shmup action like combined.
Scott: It's like, oh, that's a really good combo That never existed with some really good style and since being kick-started I sort of see this game ending up being on the same level as like a shovel knight kind of deal.
Rym: Yeah, for sure.
Scott: Oh and in fact, it looks like there's some sort of crossover with shovel knight.
Scott: That was a stretch goal that was reached.
Scott: So there you go.
Scott: If you're into that keep an eye out for this because I think the Kickstarter is over.
Scott: It's over.
Rym: Sorry so much for that.
Rym: Oh, well the other we played us some real money gambling real Money gambling.
Rym: cordial minuet Jason roar.
Rym: I'm holding the card.
Rym: He gave me when we were talking to him.
Rym: It's just a dollar bill with his website on it.
Scott: business cards often cost more than a dollar.
Rym: My blue cards are like 88 cents each.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: So Basically real money gambling.
Scott: he made this game called cordial minuet.
Scott: It's themed as like an underground illuminati kind of deal.
Rym: his booth at PAX was like this gypsy Caravan like fly.
Scott: He bought like displays from tablets that had HDMI inputs from Southeast Asia.
Rym: So the outside like imagine in Shadowrun.
Scott: You know, it looks like the gypsy tent from Zelda link to the past only spookier without the eyeball.
Rym: But some like magic runes on the front, but the inside is like a cyberpunk dystopian gambling den.
Rym: Yes, exactly I was about to say imagine in Shadowrun if you went to do an alley You saw the Zelda 3 hot and in there a bunch of deckers or gambling for real money.
Scott: So you can play this if you can get into it.
Scott: I'm into it.
Scott: I was into it before PAX out.
Scott: I'm gonna play it a lot later after because when I launched it, it was like give real money and I was like I don't want to give real money gambling.
Scott: and then when I talked to Jason roar He was very convincing and he said you can play for a penny and I'm like, oh just one penny.
Scott: This one penny.
Scott: and also I'm good at games.
Scott: I have like I'm in like the top ten elo rankings.
Rym: Yeah I don't play high stakes.
Scott: So like my profit like I don't even chart on like the profit rankings or the total money rankings I just win a lot way more than 50% of the time.
Rym: We'll talk about this game in much more detail later as well But it's kind of like.
Scott: basically I think there is a huge the near future Prediction right not betting on the prediction though, even though it's a prediction about betting.
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: I might bet on it.
Rym: I'm thinking I got.
Scott: people have discovered that gambling and Skill based games is legal in the United States of America.
Scott: There is a specific legal exception for fantasy sports and that is huge and somewhat.
Scott: skill based Poker has already been on the rise though.
Scott: That is specifically illegal in many places.
Scott: But but specifically as poker right look at things such as you know Netrunner tournament pay to get in win prizes and also Jason roars real money gambling cordial minuets skill based game.
Scott: You know put real money out there.
Scott: This is gonna be a big thing.
Scott: It's getting bigger all the time.
Scott: Get ready for it.
Scott: it's like that's gonna be the next wave to replace the lost revenues.
Scott: now that people have figured out like the You know sort of Candy Crush money-making Candy box type games Real money gambling is gonna be the next thing on the mobile devices with the games to make money.
Scott: So if you want to make a lot of money I suggest making a skill based real money gambling now.
Rym: if you want to do this You need to be kind of like Jason roar like you need some like game theory like real game theory.
Scott: No Cuz the way you make money in a real money gambling situation if it's a game of skill Right is.
Scott: you cannot be opposing the player because someone with a lot of skill We'll win and clean you the fuck out.
Scott: You need other people to oppose each other.
Scott: put money down Battle each other.
Scott: winner takes the money loser loses the money, but you're the fucking house and you take a cut.
Scott: This is more than just how this works.
Rym: That is how Success look at.
Rym: look at.
Rym: look at some big successful businesses in recent memory.
Scott: steam valve Uh, yes you publisher sell game to this gamer.
Scott: I don't care if your game is any fucking good on a plant, but I'm raking it in.
Rym: Oh Hasbro, you make this movie you make told you make toys.
Rym: with the license for this movie We're just the middleman.
Scott: Yeah, you have to.
Scott: yeah, you want to make Transformers movie?
Scott: You must give us money whether it succeeds or fails.
Scott: Thank you.
Rym: Yep, a grub hub.
Rym: Oh you want to buy some pizza?
Scott: Well you buy pizza from that restaurant you deliver it and since you used our website we get money.
Rym: I'm not even gonna I'm a casino.
Rym: just be the casino.
Rym: Yeah, don't be the gambler.
Scott: Is that a middleman?
Scott: I see like a middleman like grub hub can be beaten out But a you can't really replace like someone's.
Scott: you know Brokering real money gambling between two people you need that third party cannot be eliminated.
Scott: You need someone there to sort of enforce their gamble.
Scott: Otherwise, like I'll just go into a. no you theoretically don't theoretically but so it's a random cryptocurrency.
Rym: Transactions.
Scott: No, but there's no way to guarantee that.
Scott: I forced me to give you the money.
Rym: Well, no, you need some sort of currency.
Rym: you you have technological escrow.
Scott: There is.
Scott: is there a completely technological escrow that does not require like someone to own a computer that enforces it or anything?
Rym: Yeah, Bitcoin already.
Scott: Does that work?
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: How does it escrow?
Scott: So I give you a Bitcoin?
Scott: It's not.
Rym: I'm saying that it is that there are ways to do it.
Rym: I can't name a specific.
Scott: I don't think.
Scott: I don't think it works.
Scott: like you have to give the Bitcoin to someone.
Rym: Yes It would be.
Scott: who do you give it to and we grow?
Rym: which is I'm saying it would be trivial To do the same kind of cryptographic technology.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Some computer has to be the escrow that it's holding on to the bitcoins while you are playing the game and then it has to Look at the state of the game Ensure the game was legit and give the winning monies to the correct winner.
Rym: the game It's never do that the game itself.
Scott: who is running on which computer and who is ensuring your separate computers and the clients?
Rym: the two-game clients interrogate each other cryptographically to ensure that they're both.
Rym: It is a hundred percent theoretically you make it that mr.
Scott: Genius, I think there has to be a third That is trusted.
Rym: Who's gonna make that?
Rym: some people we know.
Rym: I can name two and I won't talk about on the show.
Rym: Yeah, they're gonna get together.
Rym: They're gonna make it.
Rym: Okay the last big game we played was USCMC.
Scott: so USCMC is really just torchbearer with alien Luke crane and Jared Sorenson basically made a mind of.
Rym: you know an official mod of Torchbearer that is the USCMC field operations manual, you know the movie aliens aliens.
Scott: Yes Specifically alien not alien aliens.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I just go home and watch alien or Check it out independently targeting particle beam phallax.
Rym: Whap.
Rym: Yeah that kid that game that movie.
Rym: It is that movie the role-playing bug hunt.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes it is.
Rym: So Torchbearer is a really like actually relatively simple system with a lot of skin and theme on top of it.
Rym: But the system is a very good way to broker like the role-playing situation of a team of people Attempting to achieve a goal by going into a place and then coming back out of that.
Scott: If you think about it aliens is very, you know dungeon II right?
Scott: It's like alright, we landed on this planet.
Scott: You're a team we go into this building.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's basically just a dungeon crawl.
Scott: that movie, right?
Scott: The mother alien is way down at the bottom.
Scott: It's a hundred percent a dungeon crawl.
Scott: So you don't need a different game to tell that story.
Rym: you have a team that's got a stated goal.
Rym: You've got members of that team who have personal goals Yep, and then you've got a mystery and a twist.
Scott: you have rooms to navigate treasures to acquire It's the only part you really take out is like the labor to bring the treasures out because it's not really physical treasures It's knowledge treasures you're looking for.
Rym: So our good friend Andrew put together an adventure for us and me and Scott crazy drunk Yeah, he did get he.
Rym: he drank a little too much of his milk in the course of running all the milk.
Rym: I point out that we Partially succeeded in our mission and only Scott and a bunch of civvies who deserved it died.
Rym: Scott you fucking ah You fucked us the civilian we we Really?
Scott: I wasn't even supposed to be there in the first.
Scott: that's the reason that I was so willing to just like shoot them.
Scott: It's like we.
Scott: basically he starts out and there's like, you know Some company Whelan company guy giving us like the briefing and our commanding officer Awesomely is like you're fucking coming with us into this, right?
Scott: So that was not part of the adventure to begin with.
Scott: Guy was not supposed to come with us to the space.
Rym: We made a test to make him come right.
Scott: so you shot him.
Scott: Okay, so it I figured a. We are we are able to beat this mission beat, right?
Scott: We're able to complete this mission without this guy because the it was designed such that this he wasn't even supposed to come with us.
Scott: That was like us thinking outside the box.
Scott: So killing him is not really end of the world and was actually went along well with my beliefs to try anti corporation, right?
Scott: To my odds of being successful there.
Scott: We're really really high.
Scott: I rolled really really badly.
Rym: you failed to shoot that but there were two roles in a row.
Scott: I just exceed on one of them either the one to get him to do what I wanted and intimidate him Which is had a really high chance of success that I failed or the one to murder him Which had a really high chance of success but failed.
Rym: So, of course, he runs off and hides in the facility and eventually like rallies all the other scientists who are alive against us.
Rym: Yeah, because we're kind of the bad guys now sure and I think the the greatest moment in this game toward the end was Scott.
Rym: we were all in like the a the EVA room like the extra-vehicular activity, you know space station, right?
Rym: And we're all like we put on EVA suits just in case and Scott's like I'm not putting one on like.
Scott: yeah We're not going outside.
Scott: Someone else is going outside.
Scott: So why would I need to put one on?
Rym: all of us put these suits on except Scott you were going outside.
Rym: I wasn't who pointedly and repeatedly reminds everyone throughout this entire scene.
Rym: Well, I just I don't have one on.
Scott: yeah I'm just like.
Scott: yeah, I don't put one on because I'm not going outside.
Scott: I'm not opening the door.
Scott: There's no reason for me to put one on.
Scott: these other people aren't putting them on and I've gotta want to be flexible and mobile Not wearing a big heavy space.
Scott: so we all.
Scott: I'm inside in a safe place Where I can shoot my gun or do whatever else I need to do.
Rym: So we all jump into space as you were going into space and I wasn't to get our ship back, right?
Rym: The xenomorph?
Scott: I was waiting there for you to come back.
Rym: Xenomorph comes up on Scott's ass, right?
Scott: So I try to shoot it.
Scott: that didn't work.
Scott: So then, you know, of course now You know my best-laid plans.
Scott: I'm not going outside.
Scott: Actually, the only way to get rid of this alien is to pull an alien one and open the door.
Scott: Well, we all applauded Scott for this action But I did not have my suit on cuz I the last thing I thought I would be doing would be opening the door.
Scott: so I Sacrificed myself and open the door anyway to kill the alien.
Rym: So the both.
Rym: the funniest thing was that Scott opens the door the alien I tried to hold on.
Rym: the alien makes its check and Holds on.
Rym: Scott fails his hold on check.
Scott: So that's not supposed to be how it works.
Scott: Didn't you see alien one?
Scott: So yeah, it's supposed to be the other way around.
Scott: It's really just.
Scott: you can't blame me for doing.
Scott: It's like if I failed those roles Which I did so from.
Scott: I can make fun of me cuz I'm stupid and it looks like I failed was bumbling.
Scott: But if I succeed in all those roles, I would be a genius and a hero.
Rym: So from our perspective we hear Scott scream motherfucker But just space the room and then just he comes flying out of the door alone.
Rym: So I look like I committed suicide Andrew.
Rym: Yeah Andrew turns to us.
Rym: He's like you're gonna save him.
Rym: and I was like, oh shit Scott's got the data.
Rym: He's got the USB stick with that data we need.
Rym: so I'm like, yeah I try to go save him and then as soon as I learn that Bringing his body back to the ship in time to save his life is a factor in the test.
Rym: I Asked Andrew with a straight face, so it'll be easier if I wait for him to be dead.
Rym: and Yeah, and Andrew says yes And that's what I do because my belief was only one of us needs to make it back alive.
Scott: Sure Yeah, if I'd succeeded on those tests, I would be like hero genius and those.
Scott: I had good odds except grabbing one.
Scott: That was bad.
Scott: I guess the other two I had good.
Rym: I applaud you for opening that door.
Rym: You may have saved humanity Maybe of course our chicken shit outfit just fucking ran and brought the heavy artillery Basically nuke the station from far space.
Scott: all hero, bro.
Scott: You guys are the chicken shit.
Rym: We just came back with nukes Chicken shit.
Rym: Yeah, so even if you don't play torchbearer or tabled up RPGs go to this link and read this Document.
Scott: this document is an RPG document reader.
Rym: Even if you're not this document is full like you'll understand a lot about.
Rym: like you'll read this You'll be like, oh damn aliens and then you're just gonna want to play aliens.
Scott: Uh, the RPG.
Scott: This is pretty much it right now.
Rym: What's funny though is uh, Scott and I had just kind of randomly Just watched predator.
Scott: the predator, which also kept saying this theme.
Scott: We kept saying go ahead me some go have me some fun.
Scott: Have me some fun.
Rym: So the rest of the group watched aliens.
Rym: before this we watched predator.
Rym: So our group was a mix of the Marines from predator and the Marines from aliens.
Rym: It was beautiful.
Scott: Get to the chopper.
Scott: They've these shots all.
Rym: get to the shot.
Rym: And that was basically our PAX South.
Scott: no the gaming part yeah, and that way you can remember from all those weeks ago.
Rym: Yeah, I got notes.
Rym: We'll talk about San Antonio later.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night Oh.