Rym: It's Wednesday November 18th 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: descender Let's do this.
Rym: So if you're listening to this it is already too late to get badges for paxies.
Rym: that shit went live this morning.
Rym: That's a shame and as of dateline 624 p.m.. Eastern Standard Time doing the show kind of early tonight.
Rym: Of course three-day badges are sold out.
Rym: there aren't that many of those.
Rym: Saturday is sold out.
Rym: Saturday sold out within like five minutes.
Rym: Friday and Sunday are almost sold out.
Rym: This isn't news that paxi sells out immediately But the thing that you all need to pay attention to in the future is that many of you probably got badges.
Rym: People who wanted badges mostly got them.
Rym: But what people did not get her hotel rooms because there are not enough hotels in the city of Boston
Scott: You can stay on the other side of the city barely
Rym: I clicked so I already had a hotel But I clicked when I as fast as I humanly could when the site went live to see in the queue like what hotel I could have gotten had.
Rym: I not had my other way to get a hotel and Despite clicking within 30 or 40 seconds of it going live Literally the closest hotel I could get was like two miles away.
Rym: on the other side of boss.
Scott: I'm saying on the other side you take a taxi every day.
Scott: You gotta take that shuttle or the shuttle I.
Rym: I couldn't deal with that at a PAX.
Rym: I don't do that for I don't.
Rym: there's no convention.
Rym: I commute to.
Scott: no It's not good times.
Rym: Yeah, so uh those of you complaining There is nothing to be done about that except don't try to get badges first.
Rym: get your hotel first.
Rym: That's the secret with paxis.
Rym: the hotel is the limiting quantity.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's like the ticket.
Scott: It's like someone will be selling the ticket.
Scott: you might have to pay a bunch of money But you can get one if you really want one.
Scott: you can get one by spending money.
Scott: They'll be for sale usually at cost.
Scott: the last Badges yeah, you can get them at cost usually from someone who can't go or something like that.
Scott: right, but the hotel How you gonna get a hotel room?
Scott: You just can't.
Scott: it's not like you.
Scott: someone's reselling their hotel room that they already got right?
Rym: Yeah, I mean magfest is having that problem already.
Rym: like air B&Bs are taken like there is no way to get a hotel room anymore Mm-hmm.
Rym: so uh my other advice to you is Go to PAX South instead.
Rym: unless you live in Boston It's cheaper to go to PAX South in Texas then to PAX East from.
Scott: we live in New York.
Scott: It's way closer to Boston than San Antonio.
Scott: It was cheaper to go to San Antonio than it was to go to Boston.
Rym: Yeah, because a cella or like Amtrak or even the buses not that much cheaper.
Scott: bull buses 20 bucks.
Rym: Yeah, the bull bus not ideal.
Rym: What's wrong?
Rym: Takes forever.
Scott: doesn't take that long.
Rym: It takes a while.
Rym: I'll do the Amtrak.
Rym: I'm never doing the buses again.
Scott: The bus goes to the exact same place again.
Rym: It takes like two plus more hours.
Scott: Oh, no, I'll just leave earlier.
Rym: Yeah, plus I got.
Rym: it's really more pleasant, but the hotels are like half the price.
Rym: yeah, there's food Everywhere and you can still buy Friday Saturday or Sunday badges to PAX South Like you can totally like this.
Rym: hotels within a block of the convention center totally open for now.
Scott: Yeah Pax prime renamed to backs west.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I'm really somewhat related.
Rym: news ominous Portentous.
Rym: So, yeah Otherwise got any news.
Rym: It's a Wednesday.
Scott: This isn't really the biggest news, but Now available for purchase with real money.
Scott: They released a box set of like every Miyazaki movie in on berets or whatever.
Scott: So obviously you shouldn't be buying any berets.
Scott: But in case there is something I know I mean like I've seen them all but I know people who haven't seen them all.
Scott: I'm sure a lot of people haven't seen them all.
Scott: so this is the chance.
Scott: like this is the time now you can go and Get all these movies.
Scott: I don't don't buy the berets But I'm sure you can get digital downloads or you somebody ripped all the berets You know, whatever.
Scott: but now is the time to watch all the Miyazaki movies.
Scott: in case you've missed some You know with English subtitles on them the dub.
Scott: good movies are bad all of them You know.
Scott: not, you know, just all of them.
Scott: the whole set will sit.
Rym: and while we don't talk about it constantly We're still watching Adventure Time.
Rym: like Adventure Time is still great right up There was Steven Universe and all those I feel like people stop talking about it, but it's like it hasn't gone anywhere.
Scott: It's still.
Rym: Yeah, well partly it just started up again recently.
Rym: So there's a bunch of episodes and I guess it's only South Park schedule.
Rym: Yeah, which is fine because they're always great and I'm happy to see them.
Scott: and it seems I guess there's a new South Park.
Scott: It's tonight.
Rym: Oh, yeah One of those skip weeks I'm fully caught up on South Park now, so it is a good time.
Rym: interesting continuity of that.
Rym: But Adventure Time if you didn't know is Having a miniseries called stakes about delicious delicious steaks.
Rym: nope, like wooden steaks like what you'd use to kill a vampire and Marceline's backstory as a vampire hunter.
Scott: So her dad being all evil we're gonna find out.
Scott: probably haven't seen Marceline's dad in so long Abadir.
Rym: yeah, just the other night Emily and I watched the episode where they go down and stand in line and episode so good Oh my god with the bananas.
Scott: I know you.
Rym: when he lets everyone out of prison He's like so yeah, you can all leave but I mean you're in the night our sphere.
Rym: So I There's a lot of people don't.
Rym: but that show is still like grade-a Animation and it is still coming out.
Scott: Why would they stop?
Rym: I wonder how long it'll keep going.
Scott: because well, what will end first?
Rym: Adventure time or Lo Simpson ace adventure time or Western democracy?
Rym: But think about this Simpsons or the world.
Rym: Adventure time has been going You know year by year and Finn is aging in real time as the show went.
Rym: Yeah They could just keep going.
Rym: Imagine if 20 years from now.
Rym: Finn is just an adult and the show is just continued on without an arm.
Rym: Yeah, or maybe he's got a cyborg arm.
Rym: Maybe a sword arm.
Rym: Maybe is a sword.
Rym: There's an episode coming out.
Rym: The title is just I am a sword.
Rym: So, you know that shits coming back.
Scott: That's gonna be good one.
Rym: It is.
Rym: But adventure time continues to be great and quote Told in eight parts stakes details Marceline the vampire Queen's desire to no longer be a vampire.
Scott: Well, she wasn't a vampire to begin with so I'm sure she became a vampire.
Rym: But as we know from the plot of a few seasons back it when Finn and Jake and the wish that the Lich never Existed and all that nonsense.
Rym: Mm-hmm that if she was not a vampire she can get she'll live a long time But she's not immortal.
Rym: Nope so The fact that she's a vampire is the only reason she is still young and hot and generally awesome as opposed to an old angry Chrome, but she won't have to drink red stuff anymore.
Rym: She just ate real food like everyone else true and then she won't just see everything through the blood red vampire eyes as she's talked About in the past.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So but then she won't be immortal So theoretically she might die of old age and Bubs will still be around.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yeah Maybe we'll know at the end of all this.
Rym: I'm not gonna look up any spoilers.
Rym: You shouldn't either.
Rym: just watch it.
Rym: I guess it's out.
Scott: if you're not watching adventure time at all period maybe our description of this miniseries Sort of thing sub series part will make you realize that it's not just like oh my god math.
Rym: If you're not why?
Rym: yeah adventure time season one is oh my god math and it's great.
Rym: Season two is math and plot and then it just keeps changing like every season is way different.
Rym: The show evolves in a way that very few television shows ever have like.
Rym: it's very rare to see a show that is where it is now and Going back like in 20 episode chunks.
Rym: It's like a totally different show every time.
Rym: South Park South Park.
Rym: Yeah, South Park has done that to a degree But at the same time South Park has also had some constants that only now are being discarded like the relics that they are.
Rym: officer bar Brady It's not killing Kenny a long time ago, yeah, well because there's a plot around that I know in fact, they made the plot of why he's that way cannon.
Rym: Yeah in that miniseries with the key Things of the day.
Rym: so in panels as we have said and as anyone who does panels like us has said Lotus war pretty much like one of the first big anime in the US where a lot of people are like, holy shit anime.
Scott: It was a generic fantasy with general mass appeal, you know fighting dragons Yeah, very D&D style.
Scott: very it was serious.
Scott: It wasn't silly like slayers Yeah, so it didn't have a lot of like, you know Anything culturally specific to Japan or anything?
Rym: it was one of the first if not the first Anime series to be released as a box set and DVD in the United States.
Scott: Yeah, and you know There was a TV series and OVA and you know And you had also the Lotus Island thing going on.
Rym: Lotus Island is the best aspect of Lotus War.
Rym: The second best aspect is the first episode of the original OAV and then none of the rest of it's that great Soundtracks good, but if you didn't know it's based on a bunch of nerds playing D&D.
Scott: I mean one-to-one like these nerds played D&D and then they took their campaign and made this anime out of it.
Scott: Literally, I mean look it's dwarf elf Fighter, I mean, come on Yeah, like you thought like.
Rym: oh, it's just like my D&D game.
Rym: No, it is a D&D game is literally It's exactly what your friends all said.
Rym: They do where you're gonna write the novel of your campaign because it's so original and great.
Scott: Of course, you know someone else did it and you didn't because they're better than you.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: What's real interesting is The stats for some of these people not great But they have sketches like there's deed lit like that's the characters straight up.
Rym: Okay So, uh, yeah These are the actual character sheets of the D&D game that got turned into an anime That was super super huge in the US for a while and now is basically completely forgotten Everywhere except for us.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: Alex just launched Civ 5.
Rym: Shit's going down in our long-form game, but I digress.
Scott: Whose turn is next?
Rym: Chris.
Rym: Okay I set up to where it goes James Lisa and the AI and then me.
Rym: So once it hits that little like bam bam bam bam and come right back to me anyway.
Scott: Anyway, so yeah Oh thing of the day.
Scott: So there's these dudes in Australia, right and they did perhaps the most Australian thing there is, you know wearing shorts sandals t-shirts Sitting at a picnic table drinking, you know about as Australian as it gets.
Rym: that's pretty Australian.
Scott: But the one difference is their picnic table Was motorized with wheels and they're driving it down the road.
Rym: that you know.
Rym: That's a step up because when I was at PAX Australia there was a bus stop at the con.
Rym: that was a bar that you could basically sit in a little car and Pedal and drink and it drove you around.
Rym: This is a step up from that.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So Yeah, the cops want to go after them, but almost everyone is like nothing more Aussie than that.
Scott: What the fuck cops lay off.
Scott: Also, where can I get one?
Scott: I See a future where all cars are replaced by motorized picnic tables.
Scott: Imagine self-driving.
Rym: just New York's just had self-driving automated tables like that Just kind of put her hard.
Scott: to play.
Scott: a board game though might get blown off the table.
Rym: You got to play magnetic board games only even then.
Scott: if it goes a little, you know, if you're going fast I mean you didn't getting quite a wind there.
Rym: Yeah, you know Ukraine is weak situation possibly to New York, right?
Scott: But yeah motorized picnic table, that's awesomest.
Scott: I want to see races in the meta moment.
Rym: The booklet book was a wheel of time a long time ago.
Scott: now It's the square of space.
Rym: No, it's still the wheel of time.
Rym: So We just keep reading those books.
Rym: I blew past you you do I stopped.
Scott: I'm reading comics.
Scott: now I haven't read.
Rym: finish the fourth book, right?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: I'm all the fifth books actually real short.
Scott: I read only the most beginning of the fifth one and then I stopped in him reading comics.
Rym: Yeah, I got into some shit.
Rym: a bunch of ale.
Rym: Let's say came back over the wall a Bunch of what came over the whale?
Rym: Those people ale.
Rym: I think it's just ale a lemon.
Rym: Yeah, Nina winna Vinay is real annoying now Like more than before she is so bad that pretty much every character like every character who knows her has had long Conversations on how much they are sick of her shit.
Rym: It's kind of great actually But I digress.
Rym: Otherwise, we're gonna be at magfest doing panels.
Rym: We're gonna be probably at pecs out doing panels and probably be a paxies doing panels probably an anime boss and doing panels.
Rym: Stay tuned for panels.
Rym: And otherwise, we have our t-shirts on sale again, so you can just buy those.
Rym: I got one.
Scott: Does anyone bought one?
Rym: Uh, yeah, like six or seven people now, okay, but I got why they're way higher quality than the first print.
Rym: run like way better.
Scott: So you should buy one without our faces on it and then it'll be really good t-shirt.
Rym: No, cuz there's standard t-shirt, but it's a good face.
Rym: It's a good face shot of us.
Rym: It's a quality shirt.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: Okay, I'm gonna wear it to work.
Rym: Okay?
Rym: Yeah, there's something about wearing a shirt that has your own face on it Not ironically and just waiting to see if anyone notices.
Scott: That's something you would do.
Rym: Yeah, that is definitely something I would tell.
Rym: your ego is that big and our patreon is going strong.
Rym: We're getting close to some of those stretch goals that require us to do things.
Rym: So if we get a little more money in the patreon We're gonna release with commentary all of the beta episodes of GeekNights to the patrons.
Scott: Yeah, don't spend your money in that garbage.
Rym: Yeah, we sang our own theme song guys.
Rym: So you don't want this.
Scott: You're gonna hear it's like if you go to the grocery store and they're like mystery dessert and you're like, ooh I'll pay five dollars to mystery dessert and it's poop in a bag.
Rym: That's like at the anime con and the dealers got the mystery grab bag $20 and you open it up and it's just like some air gear trading car.
Scott: That's like loot crate The stuff the comic book store couldn't sell and it filled up the warehouse.
Scott: So they gave it to loot crate and then loot crate send it to you and you paid for it.
Rym: It's a company that just redirected a conveyor belt that was going to the dump and it redirected it into basically Entirely true.
Scott: so loot crate does it seems at least from I can't I don't know this for sure but it seems for the most part what they do is they take in the nerdy inventory that doesn't sell well the stuff that Would go to the discount rag otherwise and then manages to sell it by, you know.
Scott: So, you know with their method of get a mystery bunch of nerd stuff every month.
Scott: But it seems like they also do promotional things.
Scott: Like let's say you really wanted to promote Batman's right?
Rym: so you know in the old you would you would buy it Batman in the like swag bag, right?
Scott: So DC would pay loot crate to say hey put a bunch of this Batman shit We just made that's good in the loot crate to promote Batman this month.
Scott: So I think they also make money that way.
Rym: But anyway, there's another stretch goal if we get past that one where we'll actually live stream GeekNights every night Like every time we do a show, we'll just live stream us doing.
Scott: who wants that?
Scott: I don't know, but you have to put things people want that are actually good.
Scott: But what you should put give us a thousand dollars a month We'll stop making this goddamn show that there is.
Rym: there is the stretch goal of we will literally quit our jobs and dance for you full-time forever.
Rym: So I get us to that one.
Rym: I would really like that.
Rym: But yeah, listen to the part of the episode after the credits because I do a patreon thing Every night now.
Scott: All right, you want to definitely want to stop before the credits.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is it's real hard.
Rym: I don't know if you've ever Scott looked at a list of like 50 or 60 names and tried to say all of the names Very quickly in a row just by reading them and pronouncing them all correctly.
Scott: Why are you doing this?
Rym: Cuz I said I'd do it.
Scott: Why don't you?
Scott: I mean some patrons.
Scott: you should say the name once not every single show.
Rym: No Cuz they that's all.
Rym: they got a key paying for me to keep saying their name And I say the names in the order of the amount of money they give us.
Rym: Someone is always giving $1 more than whoever gave the most to be at the top.
Scott: Is that true?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Why are people doing this?
Scott: What the hell's wrong with you?
Rym: It's great.
Rym: It's real great.
Rym: Okay We're an institution.
Rym: what can I say?
Rym: we provide a lot of joy to people's lives.
Rym: I think he's right.
Rym: I mean the listener really is into this and I guess I joke from is gone.
Scott: if you want to give us money Here's a better idea.
Scott: get an Amazon gift card and don't send it on this patreon.
Scott: Just send it to me.
Rym: No, no No.
Rym: If you're gonna send us money Use the YouTube fan funding and just click and say give us money.
Scott: you could do that, too.
Rym: Cuz that'll go to me.
Rym: cuz most of the stuff's on my channel Do it through.
Scott: anyone that's taken a cut.
Rym: just send me an Amazon Bunch of people said they don't want to do the patreon because they only want more gig knives presents antenna.
Rym: So to those people I said, okay don't patron us.
Rym: It's fine.
Rym: When we do episodes just put money into the YouTube thing once the episode is live.
Rym: So I'm doing pre-production.
Rym: gig knives presents you.
Rym: tenna is also coming soon.
Rym: Thanks to the patreon.
Scott: So one of our favorite.
Scott: I finally got room to read some comics.
Rym: Yeah, I read a bunch of comics.
Rym: The problem is in the pile of comics Scott gave me there was also all the one punch man.
Scott: so that got read first because But you didn't read the other thing that was in there.
Rym: But now I did.
Rym: there's one thing I gotta read.
Rym: That'll be the next show.
Scott: So Jeff Lemire, perhaps one of the favorite comic creators of GeekNights also known for making things like Trillium Sweet Tooth You know Essex County trilogy.
Scott: Yeah, right and he's been doing a lot of stuff for like, you know DC and whatnot.
Scott: You did some superhero stuff, but we should just get him on the show.
Rym: He's like one of our favorite comics people.
Scott: Yeah, he's just Canadian duty likes hockey.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: So he's doing this new series and I saw the cover of it and On the cover yellow robot boy in space and it's like well, that's all I need to know.
Rym: Not just robot boy in space It's robot boy in space silhouetted by the moon looking up pensively and it's called descenders Like what the hell is this thing?
Scott: So All you need to know is Jeff Lemire made it and that's what's on the cover and that's a cell Immediately some kind of sci-fi thing with a robot boy.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's like.
Scott: is this Astro Boy?
Scott: It's like what?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: So I'm getting an Astro.
Rym: There's definitely an Astro Boy vibe.
Scott: It doesn't punched anyone at all.
Rym: Yeah, no punching Astro Boy didn't punch people right away.
Rym: He was just a sad sort of orphan almost thing.
Scott: Anyway, anyway So, uh, I bought issue one and I was like I read that and I'm like, well, that's exactly what I thought it was gonna be winner.
Scott: Yeah, and Very recently trade paperback number one came out and if you get that You can even get it digitally if you really want to be.
Scott: there's only like one issue out beyond what's in the trade.
Scott: So the trade is pretty much it.
Rym: Yeah, so you'll know as much as we know just about.
Scott: I think there's one more issue you can read anyway.
Rym: So there's a big info drop at the like.
Rym: a mic gets dropped at the end of the first trade.
Scott: Sure So what is descender actually about?
Scott: Well, it's quick summary.
Scott: It's not really spoilers or anything.
Scott: there is a sort of solar system and There are aliens living on all the planets in the solar system.
Scott: Yep, different kinds of aliens in each planet like this one There's like even a weird water planet like they're way different and there's sort of one central planet and that central planet is like the galette The you know the council or whatever, right?
Scott: It's like the capital place and all the different aliens come and visit.
Scott: Yeah, every sci-fi setting right and there's some super high-tech shit, especially Super high-tech robots, you know because super high-tech sci-fi future Meanwhile on some faraway rock.
Scott: That's a lot like the rock from say aliens.
Scott: Yeah Very similar to the rock from aliens.
Scott: there is a family mining or something and They got a boy robot who's like a member of the family, you know, that's very Astro boy right there.
Rym: Like.
Scott: it's also like say a bicentennial man where a robot is a member of the family Yeah, or like aliens where a family is mining on a rock far away Yeah in space and then maybe a disaster befalls, right?
Scott: So this robot boy You know outlives all the people on the mining rock.
Rym: Yeah, he basically wakes up like something activates the system and they're totally dead.
Rym: Everyone's been dead.
Scott: Meanwhile back on you know the center of the you know civilization some strange gigantic robot heads Unicrons or some shit actually reading.
Rym: it was pretty great because basically the whole beginning of the comic other than the boy on the moon Is all these shots of people being like.
Rym: And then someone else looks out of frame and says what the fuck is that?
Rym: But it doesn't show you what the fuck is that until for a while you keep flipping it.
Rym: Finally, you see what the fuck is that?
Rym: It is just a giant Fucking robot standing there looking at everyone like bad news.
Scott: bad in space bigger than your planet Like Independence Day has got nothing on this thing.
Rym: This is like Unicron level Yeah, and it's like humanoid just like Jay.
Scott: it's just standing there and you know, so you're thinking ooh It's that that's that same old thing.
Scott: We see in every kind of alien story, right?
Scott: You encounter the alien.
Scott: Are they gonna be good?
Scott: Are they gonna be bad and never good?
Scott: No, just like Independence Day.
Scott: They're immediately just bad.
Rym: Yeah, it's great.
Rym: They go up and they're like, I think it's gonna communicate and then kill all humans.
Rym: Yeah, they all just fuck everything up for a while and then leave mysterious.
Scott: They didn't kill everyone but they just fucked everything.
Scott: the fuck up like your bad Right, the greatest and the artwork is so amazing.
Scott: But the best one is that one whole page of like the girls mom getting eye-lasered by the giant robot.
Scott: Oh, it's like I want to put that shit on my wall.
Scott: Yeah, I don't need the original It's too much money.
Scott: Give me a print that's like twice the size or something.
Scott: Yeah, so I can put that up.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so think about that normal sci-fi universe these giant Humanoid robots appear.
Rym: they're super advanced.
Rym: No one understands them and Everyone's kind of waiting for what they're gonna do.
Rym: They fuck up a bunch of shit and then they disappear.
Scott: It's like why didn't if they were evil, why didn't they just kill everybody?
Scott: It's like there's so many questions and secrets of space you want to know and then of course the ultimate secret of space.
Scott: obviously Robot boy is connected to the giant evil robot somehow and that's the terrible secret of space that you're trying to find out.
Rym: Now it's Jeff Lemire's the author and looks like Dustin Nguyen is the artist for this.
Scott: Yep, and There is already.
Rym: I was looking up like the Wikipedia just to talk about like dates or whatever, but there's already a movie.
Scott: Well option, you know, yeah, it's actually gonna get made.
Rym: Well, I think so Sony picked up the rights for the series to make a movie So the odds are better than if anyone else had picked it up.
Scott: I mean it did make that surrogates movie.
Rym: Yeah, and this has.
Rym: this is a screenplay for a movie written all over it.
Scott: Jeff Lemire gonna get the payday.
Rym: Yeah, he deserves it.
Rym: Now ideally imagine if this were done as like an animation in the kind of the style of the comic.
Rym: But you know, that's not gonna happen.
Rym: Oh my god, that would be.
Scott: you're gonna really make all those watercolors to end.
Scott: Yeah That'd be so much work.
Rym: Can't express how deeply I'd be into that sure, but I'm so much works But no Sony's actually.
Rym: so what Lemire and Nguyen said was quote.
Rym: It was a competitive situation for descender.
Rym: So multiple people were probably bidding already to make the movie chair and Sony had the highest bid.
Rym: Boom.
Rym: Yeah You're so good cash money.
Scott: Don't wait all the bills.
Rym: You should just read it like.
Rym: if you're a comics fan Like this is one of those things of just read it because it's like you're.
Scott: you know, you're probably out there some sci-fi.
Scott: You know your nerd you like sci-fi stuff.
Scott: You're looking for this, you know stories like this and there aren't really a lot of them.
Scott: Yeah, it's like what else are you gonna go get?
Rym: In fact, you know what?
Rym: I'll say and I'm not again.
Rym: I don't want to spoil stuff because so much happens in the first trade.
Rym: It's like saga like you think.
Rym: start thinking like alright I see where this is going and this is definitely on the sock.
Scott: like this and saga.
Scott: I like the top two comics right now.
Rym: Yeah, cuz every page you're like, oh, whoa.
Rym: Whoa that escalated quickly Oh shit, and then it ends on a cliffhanger of what?
Rym: so Remember Prometheus?
Rym: Yeah, remember how Prometheus was the story of hey Here's a terrible secret room space and we're gonna fuck everything up and it sucks the end.
Rym: there are.
Rym: see already there are scenes in this where the same from a theist kind of thing happens and The care it's.
Rym: it's sort of like what happens in that scene is should have been what Prometheus did Like.
Rym: I don't want to say anymore.
Scott: I mean like.
Scott: look we've referenced so many.
Scott: I mean you got the Astro boy and the aliens too and the.
Scott: for me It's like you get so many things coming in on this the Independence Day.
Scott: It is like the best of all sci-fi things together, but it's not any one of them.
Scott: You know, it's not like a redo of any one thing.
Scott: It's like, you know the aspects of all the best aspects of all the best things combined.
Rym: I mean, we're already on pig planet with gladiatorial arenas robot genocides going on space pirates.
Rym: Of course one of those people is not a human.
Scott: Hahaha Glad you brought up those nasty who's.
Rym: who's kill kill who's.
Scott: Yeah, so there's a lot of characters in this probably and it's like.
Scott: the main character is like, you know, the robot boy.
Scott: It's like he's okay.
Rym: He's earnest and he's you know, what personality wise he's Astro boy.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much The girl, you know who's you know?
Scott: From the galactic I guess security whatever I don't know here.
Rym: you CG.
Scott: Yeah, she's like, you know, she's I don't know what she's technically is from but like she's way.
Scott: awesome Yeah, but obviously the best is driller.
Rym: driller is great.
Rym: driller Driller is a.
Scott: they should just make driller the comic.
Rym: I want a t-shirt.
Rym: That's just.
Scott: driller is a killer driller It's a real killer.
Rym: Well, there's there's a moment where drillers like driller not kill for now and everyone's like, okay good Read this and then there's another part.
Scott: it's like driller killer now.
Scott: Yes, driller killer Kill.
Scott: He's basically just you know, he was on the little boys on the mining planet and There's no all the humes on the mining planet are dead, but he finds driller Drillers driller.
Scott: He's a mining robot, but he has some sort of brain and he knows he's stupid.
Scott: He's like.
Scott: he's like driller stupid.
Scott: Yeah, but driller hate humes and driller a killer Yep, a real killer.
Scott: And he drills and he kills and I think his dad was crash man.
Rym: The other the big guy.
Rym: the other big guy reminds me a little bit of Bato from what little we've seen of him.
Scott: Yeah, he doesn't talk.
Rym: big Hume Yeah has some cyborg and he's hanging out with the girl who's a badass a little bit of a major vibe Like that kind of character bringing the ghost in the shells into it.
Scott: How many more sci-fi properties you want to bring into the descender?
Rym: Considered with it with the codexes and the technology culture series is here.
Scott: Like this is a culture series kind of I could bring in the Marvel Comics giant things There's a lot like celestials that thing that came to the planet little Galactus action, maybe.
Rym: Yep Galactus.
Rym: It's Galactus attack the culture.
Rym: Sure, that's what's going on here except or maybe like it's not.
Scott: it's not at the culture level It's something it's the civilization that we're dealing with.
Scott: here is some weight.
Rym: So it's not the culture but it might be the culture.
Scott: would culture Sure the culture would come and subsume or erase this shitty not culture.
Rym: This could be early collect before the culture form.
Rym: You don't know the backstory of the culture could be in that universe.
Rym: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, the only thing it doesn't have is Star Wars like straight up there.
Scott: Yeah, there are there are doesn't seem to be like spaceship space battles.
Scott: It seems like they get in spaceships go to sleep and wake up on a planet somewhere.
Scott: They don't really go pew pew with the x-wings or star destroyers, right?
Rym: Yeah, they've hit a lot of planets in a hurry in these six issues that we've read.
Rym: But yeah, you should read this just for driller And you know, we haven't done a lot of comic shows in a while.
Rym: You should also read fucking everything Jeff Lemire's touch.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: We've reviewed most of you don't need to read.
Scott: I mean like, you know, I mean everything he's done is good But it's like.
Scott: you don't need to read like that DC Animal Man run.
Rym: It's now.
Rym: it's good.
Scott: I mean we talked about that in the new 52 episode a long time ago.
Rym: But you don't have to like Essex County like you want.
Scott: that's a must read.
Rym: you want some melancholy Canadian hockey sadness.
Scott: Yes, sweet tooth must read right, you know descender must read Trillium, which we did an episode on.
Rym: Oh, right I only read the first issue with that.
Rym: I don't know what the fuck happens.
Scott: I got me a trade pair back.
Scott: of that only one It's the whole thing.
Scott: It's oh, I should read that it doesn't go on.
Scott: It's it's it's one.
Scott: It's.
Scott: you know, I only read the first issue One trade and I only know that first issue has the flippy floppy.
Rym: Yeah, it does so.
Scott: I know the trade does not have the flippy flappy.
Rym: Oh Okay.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta I gotta find out what's going on with that flippy floppy word.
Rym: Where are the two?
Rym: me?
Scott: Maybe drill us there.
Rym: Why don't?
Rym: there's nothing else to say?
Rym: I'm not gonna spoil this for you.
Rym: just read it.
Scott: there's plenty to say like drill.
Rym: ah Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: Scott does not listen to the show.
Rym: So he has no idea really what's going on here.
Rym: This is like the private club just for you guys and me.
Rym: so of course first the patrons for this episode Sorted by first the amount of money you give us and then second by I have no idea how it's sorted Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando James David White Christian Koontz Jess mechanical mind Ryan Perrin drew up in Lander rare Laval Brian Cedroni Rochelle, Mantanona Finn Eric Silveraude Rym eats poop Edgar Mendez William Eisen rose Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fires Samuel Cordery Daniel Redman Chris hadad Doug Snyder Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Rym: And now uh, I don't know this is kind of our time just you and me.
Scott: the next time you see sky It'll be over another town.
Scott: The next time you take a test It'll be in some other school.
Scott: Our parents they want the best of stuff for us But right now they got to do what's right for them because it's their time their time up there Down here, it's our time.
Scott: It's our time down here.
Scott: That's all over the second we ride up Troy's bucket.
Rym: This is our time.
Rym: So if you want us to do like a particular show or you want to have feedback or push us in the direction Like I said just posting the patreon Scott will never see it and he'll never listen to this.
Rym: So if you send me things I can respond here Ovaltine style Scott.
Rym: I don't think he'll ever figure it out unless one of you tells him.
Rym: and even if one of you tells him to listen to this He'll probably not believe you and think that I'm told him.
Rym: I told you to try and trick him into listening to it.
Rym: And Yeah, I'll know if he listens to this or not.
Rym: And so I present to you Scott Reuben's theme song.
Rym: argument Scott Reuben Yeah, this just keeps going.
Rym: I can just sit here and mess around all night.
Rym: This is all just extra stuff happening for you.
Rym: Just rimming you forever a hundred years rimming you guys.