Rym: It's Wednesday, October 12th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We're talking about two shows that only one of us watched.
Rym: I guess movies.
Rym: The Newish Gundam, Kookaroo's Doan's Island, and Star Trek Prodigy.
Scott: I didn't realize the Star Trek one was a movie.
Rym: It's not a Stevie show.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So if you listened to our last GeekNights episode, I talked about the car that appeared under mysterious circumstances.
Rym: I'm really invested in this.
Scott: That was on Friday night.
Scott: It is currently Wednesday evening dusk-ish, and the car is still there.
Scott: So it's Friday night, Saturday, Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday.
Scott: Car's still there.
Rym: It's kind of amazing.
Rym: Now it was a holiday weekend, but it is no longer a holiday.
Rym: It's like regular work time now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So it's like on the one hand, I just want to wait it out and see what happens and not interfere, right?
Scott: But on the other hand, I just really want to tell somebody.
Scott: Not it's like I don't want to tell, you know, the authorities.
Scott: It's like that's right.
Scott: It's not my business, but I just like I want to find someone who gives it.
Rym: I feel like what this warrants is you make a Reddit post in the Astoria Reddit be like, so what's up with this car?
Rym: Yeah, what's with this car?
Rym: would be a pretty good headline for that post.
Rym: Like, what's the deal with this car?
Scott: I don't know if anyone else will care, but I don't know.
Rym: I feel like that's the kind of thing that would get a very niche audience.
Rym: that could slowly grow a little bit.
Rym: Depends on how long this lasts.
Rym: If that car is still there a month from now, suddenly this becomes legendary.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I could do the mystery of the car.
Rym: Yeah, you got to go down and put some chalk on the wheel and the road.
Rym: So you'll know if it moved, because what if someone moved it and parked it again in the weird angle?
Scott: Does that's not going to happen?
Scott: I don't think they could.
Rym: You don't know.
Scott: Could be it could be a tow truck is going to move that car.
Rym: So speaking of which, my car, you know, the one that we use basically just to go to places that you can't get without a car.
Rym: If you live in New York City, like ski mountains and hiking places, I was able to get it out.
Rym: I haven't used this car in months because I don't drive this car often.
Rym: Like I pay a lot to keep this car just to use during the winter and like hiking season.
Rym: And I had something happen to me I've never had happen in my entire life.
Rym: I had gas go stale.
Scott: What even happens if that happens?
Rym: So if you wait long enough, it just won't work.
Rym: Like gasoline actually just stops working.
Rym: It goes stale and as a shelf life, just like anything else.
Rym: Most people will never encounter this because they use their cars.
Scott: Do you just like siphon all the gas out and pump new gas in?
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty much what you have to do if it gets bad.
Rym: But it's not that stale.
Scott: What do you do to dispose of the bad gas?
Rym: Uh, dispose of it the same way you dispose of other harmful volatiles.
Scott: I'm going to have to Google this to learn the chemistry.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So basically, in this case, I didn't have to do anything because I went to get the car to check it out, you know, drive it around a little bit, which you got to do periodically, which the Russian military seems to have not done with all its cars.
Rym: And check engine light came on and I was like, oh.
Rym: So I drove to like the auto zone to get the codes pulled because I don't own a thing that'll get the codes out of my car.
Rym: And it says the engine's running lean.
Rym: And that actually made sense because there is like an eighth of a tank of gas and that car hasn't moved in a couple of months.
Rym: So that's about the point where the gas would start to go stale.
Rym: So all I had to do was fill the tank and it's fine because I can dilute that little bit of stale gas with a whole bunch of good gas.
Rym: And I'll be driving the car enough with the hiking coming up and apple pick in and all that nonsense to picking.
Scott: time is over.
Rym: There's a little bit of apple picking left.
Rym: There's like two more weeks of some apples, just not the varieties that people tend to be excited about.
Scott: Hardly any varieties.
Rym: Plus, I don't eat that many apples.
Rym: Like I can't eat the number of apples that I would actually pick apple picking.
Rym: I go to apple picking to hang out in an orchard to eat cider donuts, to drink cider and to go home.
Scott: Well, anyway, anyway.
Rym: So in the news, there is actually a ton of news going on in the animation space.
Rym: But the most important thing that came up very recently is one.
Rym: not that long ago, like 10 days ago, Cartoon Network celebrated its 30th anniversary.
Rym: Yep, which is pretty notable.
Rym: Cartoon Network launched on October 1st in 1992.
Rym: Took a little while for it to get going.
Scott: And I'll link to an article that kind of talks a big deal for, you know, even when we didn't have cable, right, us 10 year old cartoon watchers who only had Nickelodeon and Saturday morning cartoons.
Scott: Cartoon Network coming into existence is a big deal.
Scott: And I was you know, we did an episode on it.
Scott: I was very excited when I was finally able to watch it or when I could see it at other people's houses or whatever.
Rym: Right.
Rym: So the news today and there's a big Internet discourse about this where like a third of people talking about it are acting like it's the end of the world.
Rym: Another third of them are trying to downplay it and saying it's not as bad as people are saying.
Rym: You're all just fear mongering.
Rym: And another third of them have no idea what the fuck's going on.
Rym: So the best way I can summarize this is this is not just Cartoon Network.
Rym: Cartoon Network and what's happening with them and Warner Brothers is like one tiny piece of the broader puzzle, and it's the same puzzle we've been talking about on GeekNights for as long as there's been GeekNights.
Rym: All media is consolidating into one giant company.
Rym: It's just happening very slowly, but it's happening and it's accelerating.
Rym: And this is the kind of thing that happens when media consolidates.
Rym: So all the Cartoon Network regulation, all the Cartoon Network stuff seems to be being good.
Rym: It's getting merged into like the generic Warner Brothers pipeline.
Rym: And Warner Brothers is shutting down tons of stuff and consolidating.
Rym: And there's all sorts of nonsense.
Scott: Well, Warner Brothers is like an interesting situation, right?
Scott: Because Warner Brothers discovery was up until recently part of AT&T.
Rym: Yeah, which is already weird and probably should be illegal.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But, you know, because of situation, I happen to have a small amount of AT&T stock despite them being evil or whatever.
Scott: Had some.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I noticed one day I randomly logged into the E-Trade and I saw that it's like there was a new symbol.
Scott: I think I told the story on the show before.
Scott: A new symbol had appeared in my portfolio and I had not made any trades.
Scott: And I was like, what the fuck is that?
Scott: Did someone break into my account, even though it's got all the security on it?
Scott: What's the deal?
Scott: And it turns out that I just, you know, wasn't paying enough attention.
Scott: And they split off Warner Brothers discovery from AT&T.
Scott: So everyone who had AT&T stock just got free shares effectively of WBD, right, as it split off.
Scott: And, you know, there's reasons.
Scott: they say they did this.
Scott: And I'm sure there's real reasons that are not said.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's a thing that happened.
Scott: But then, of course, since then, Warner Brothers Discovery operating as its own deal has, you know, kept coming back in the news, doing various things.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Warner Brothers Discovery has canceled tons of projects.
Rym: There's been all sorts of shenanigans.
Rym: There's a lot you can go read online.
Rym: I'm not even going to try to summarize it all.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But if you if you look at the stock price, basically what happened is WBD split off from AT&T, right.
Scott: And then it basically WBD from that point, it just went down.
Scott: Everyone who had it and was paying attention just like sold it as soon as they got it, which is what I should have done.
Scott: But I didn't know.
Rym: Nothing we're saying is financial advice.
Rym: We're not giving you any investment advice.
Scott: No, I'm just saying.
Scott: I'm just saying this is what had no advice.
Scott: This is just a tale of what happened.
Scott: This is what has what has occurred.
Rym: You know, that's actually a line that I use a lot ever since we watched that video that I made a thing of the day about the monkey.
Rym: It's like I'm not saying this is a good thing that happened.
Rym: I am simply saying that it happened.
Scott: This is what has happened.
Scott: There was a split of some kind.
Scott: The stock price went down and then all these news is keep happening about them doing things.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So Warner Brothers TV group chairman Channing Dungy sent an email or a memo to employees announcing eighty two layoffs and forty three.
Scott: eighty two.
Scott: That's no big deal.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, and forty three additional vacant positions that will no longer be filled, which actually represents a twenty six percent reduction in their scripted, unscripted and animated divisions combined.
Rym: Twenty six percent is a pretty big number.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's not a big place, so it's like percentage wise, it's a big number.
Scott: But like the news came out today, the Intel is laying off thousands of people.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So it's like, but what is that percentage?
Rym: The whole the whole I mean, capitalism is a failure.
Rym: That's really the underlying story here.
Rym: I'd say a third of all night's news is are actually just us saying capitalism is an egregious failure to humanity in various different ways.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: But they also announced that they're canceling a bunch of their incubator programs for new talent.
Rym: So Stage 13 is going away.
Rym: The Warner Brothers Writers Workshop is going away.
Rym: The Warner Brothers Directors Workshop is going away.
Rym: I've seen a lot of non white creators pointing out that some of these places are where a lot of non white, non wealthy people get their start in this industry.
Rym: So this is one of a series of cataclysms.
Rym: I feel like the entire entertainment industry, like like broadly globally, is barreling toward bad outcomes.
Rym: But animation seems to be bearing a particular brunt on it right now.
Scott: Well, I mean, this is what we taught.
Scott: We've been talking about this since, like, you know, the Napster days.
Scott: I was like, hey, you know, and you know, it's like in the days like Creative Commons is a new thing.
Scott: It's like, hey, we have the Internet now, which means that artists no longer are gated from distributing their works to the world.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You don't need to, you know, make.
Scott: you can make a movie like we used to.
Scott: if you made a movie by yourself in the 80s or 90s, it was on a VHS tape that only you and your friends would ever see.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And now there's YouTube.
Scott: So it's like, you know, when we were kids, we were watching the Saturday morning cartoons.
Scott: So those cartoons made money because they were covered in advertisements on Saturday morning with lots of viewers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then we watched cable cartoons, which is the same thing, basically.
Scott: But it's like now the kids watch the TikToks and the YouTube, which make some monies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But they don't make the mega Hollywood monies that a Saturday morning cartoon could make.
Scott: And it's like the mega cartoons, you know, like a big, big, real professionally made show, like a fucking adventure.
Scott: time costs a lot of money to make.
Scott: But is it going to?
Scott: how much money is it going to make when you air it or sell it or whatever?
Rym: What's the opportunity back?
Rym: What's the opportunity cost compared to taking that money and putting it in the stock market?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like so and that same story can be told for all sorts of different forms of video and audio entertainment.
Rym: I think there's something even more in music.
Scott: It's got hit first because the production costs of music are lower, though not always low.
Scott: And the distribution costs, especially bandwidth, were much lower.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, the music thing happened first.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But look what also happened there.
Rym: The same thing that drove reality TV and the same thing that's driving a lot of TV changes.
Rym: Now, a lot of people don't care that much about what they listen to or what they watch to.
Rym: They just want.
Rym: they want something like imagine the kind of person who would just turn on the TV and flip through the nerds who were like really caring about the something.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I think there's something sort of subtle and slightly insidious going on underpinning all of this, because one thing we predicted that we were I still think we're right about.
Rym: But technology trends have actually sort of staved off one of the outcomes advertising still remains, I believe, very strongly, largely a scam perpetrated on almost everyone involved in the ecosystem.
Rym: But advertising has been the way that most media gets funded, like in America, for most of the history of media in the modern world, like since the advent of radio and television and even newspapers to a big degree.
Rym: So all that said, as that ecosystem gets exposed and collapses, you'd think, well, that revenue dries up and media collapses.
Rym: and that is happening.
Rym: But because also the technology trend is most people do not have a general purpose computer anymore.
Rym: They're using things like tick tock.
Rym: They're being pushed into appliances and gated applications where they can't avoid advertising.
Rym: So the media that makes the most money will increasingly be the media that is in those gated ecosystems where advertising is unavoidable, thus propping up the perceived value of advertising and delaying the inevitable destruction of the entire ecosystem.
Scott: I think something else that has happened, at least especially in sports entertainment, but also in others, is that there are new ad buyers that have appeared and other ad buyers
Rym: like crypto bullshit was a flash in the pan of ad buying, but they bought a lot of ads before NFTs collapsed.
Scott: You know, while gambling is a huge sports, gambling is a huge ad buyer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like there are new people who are buying ads.
Scott: It's like, you know, other people, you know, a lot of people other than like cars and pharmaceutical drugs and certain things like that, you know, sort of large and, you know, I guess, you know, soft drinks or whatever.
Scott: It's like a lot of ad buyers washed up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or they left.
Scott: They stopped buying ads on television and started buying, you know, targeted Internet ads.
Rym: And there was this brief era where most people use the Internet also knew how to block ads.
Rym: But now most people use the Internet, only have a phone and have no understand.
Rym: They don't even know that blocking ads is a possibility.
Scott: Man.
Rym: Yeah, it's it's all going to be rough.
Scott: And in terms of in terms of cartoons, it's like we're only going to get to watch cartoons if someone can make money making cartoons.
Scott: And it's very hard to make money making cartoons right now.
Rym: Never mind the fact that companies can mind their back catalogs forever with almost no incremental cost.
Rym: And it's just free money for them.
Rym: And even as consumers, if no anime were ever made again from this point forward, I sadly would still in my entire life not run out of anime.
Rym: I kind of want to watch.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I don't watch most of the anime that comes out.
Rym: I think there's some we're going to talk about some anime in a moment that I really want to watch.
Rym: And I just haven't had time to watch yet.
Scott: I mean, even a very long time ago, centuries ago, right.
Scott: Renaissance times, there was still already more music books.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I didn't have movies.
Scott: They didn't have cartoons.
Scott: There was.
Scott: there were enough books and songs and whatever else they had that you in a human lifetime, especially since the human lives then were shorter.
Scott: You weren't going to get through it all.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But now we're at a point where basically even a very unfortunate life that's also a long life.
Scott: So you don't have a lot of resources, but you're going to be a live a long time.
Scott: And even if you're going to work, it's like there is you will never like.
Rym: I think I have enough entertainment to last the rest of my life just just in the videos folder of my NAS.
Scott: Right now, there's enough stuff to last several lifetimes for basically anybody.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like so at the so.
Scott: how much money in a capitalist society, right, where we're not just we're not putting, you know, just valuing the creation of new art on its own, right?
Rym: Only valuing how popular is your art, especially when the majority of people consuming art don't actually care that much about what particular thing they consume, which you may think that sounds crazy.
Rym: You're listening to a weird podcast by two guys like us.
Rym: You are already such an extreme edge case that you are irrelevant to capitalism.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So speaking of cartoons making any money, for some reason, this anime season, there must be some way that anime are making money because they're sure are making a lot of them.
Rym: Well, they don't pay anyone who makes anime anything.
Rym: So that'll eventually dry up on its own.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, a lot of them are propped up by sponsors or whatnot.
Scott: But anyway, this anime season that just started like right now is quite unusual in that I'm counting at least six to eight shows that are worth like me paying it personally, keeping notice of if not just watching.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which is a very large number.
Scott: The typical anime season, usually there's like two to three shows that maybe I'm thinking about a little bit.
Rym: Remember when we used to do, we'd judge anime by its cover.
Rym: We were really rarely wrong and there'd always be two or three like every season.
Scott: This season has a lot.
Scott: So what is out this season?
Scott: So there's several series that are getting sort of additional seasons.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I think there's a new Golden Kamuy season, which is something I thought about watching.
Scott: It's a borderline one.
Rym: Right.
Rym: That's for when I'm retired.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Mob Psycho, which I watched the first season of, has, I think, a third season coming out now.
Rym: That show's great.
Rym: I didn't even finish the first season.
Rym: I just haven't had time.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it was OK.
Scott: I didn't really feel compelled to watch the second season, but I know it's a big deal show for a lot of people.
Scott: So it's worth paying attention to.
Scott: The Spy X Family, which I've now watched three episodes of in the first season, which I know is a big deal for a lot of people, is definitely the kind of show we would instantly show at the anime club if we were still running it.
Scott: Oh, absolutely.
Scott: It's a big time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: OK, but now what?
Scott: what other shows are right?
Scott: Oh, there's that pop team epic, you know, that really one that's like the wacky comedy one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That one has a new season going on right now.
Scott: Yo, a pedal, which I care about finally has a new season.
Scott: They ended the previous season, I guess, a few years back.
Scott: All right.
Scott: They ended that previous season in the middle of a race.
Rym: I assume that they will never finish this race.
Scott: No, the new season starting like in like less than a day or like it already started, I think maybe.
Scott: And I'm pretty sure it just picks right up where they left off in the middle of that race.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I doubt that season will finish the race.
Rym: I think I think that whole season is going to get to the final of the race.
Scott: There's been enough seasons.
Scott: They've already finished a handful of races.
Rym: I mean, Initial D got more car races done than they just took a few years.
Scott: They just took a few years off.
Scott: They're way behind the manga, as far as I'm aware.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That remake that anniversary remake of Urusei Yatsura.
Rym: I want to watch that.
Rym: That looks so good.
Rym: The animation looks so good.
Rym: The voice acting's not sublime.
Scott: You know, if it's not any good, you can just watch.
Rym: But it looks like just judging it by its cover, it is the exact inverse of what happened with Sailor Moon Crystal.
Scott: Somehow, I don't know how the fuck this happened, right?
Scott: Anyone remembered this at all.
Scott: But I encountered at least one or two people outside my usual circle who remembered this.
Scott: And I was like, wow, I'm not the only one.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So there's a show from way back, way back called Digi Carrot.
Scott: So this show.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So this show was just some sort of comedy short series.
Rym: If you even know what we're talking about, your back definitely hurt when you woke up this morning.
Scott: Absolutely.
Scott: And basically there was a. there was a I don't know if there still is, but there was.
Scott: it might still exist, a chain of nerdy stores in Japan called Gamers.
Scott: Like Gamers is the name of the store, a physical retail store.
Scott: And the store had like a mascot that was, you know, this Digi Carrot cat girl kind of character with bells on her head or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Rym: The other Robbie and Rose, the rabbit that I guess her nemesis.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But there was like a, you know, they made an anime series like based on this character.
Scott: And now there's like a new remake of it for the anniversary or something like that.
Scott: And it's it's basically the same thing as like I don't know if people realize the tick, you know, the blue guy that there was a comic book store in the United States called New England Comics and the tick was like their mascot.
Scott: And they would use the tick as like a parody superhero in their in like their advertising flyers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then somebody made a comic, a real comic book series with the tick.
Scott: And then it became a cartoon and became a TV show.
Scott: And then it be right.
Scott: And Digi Carrot is basically the same deal where some store mascot became a thing.
Scott: There were a lot better mascots that never became.
Scott: that had a narrative series.
Scott: It's like there's no fucking Tony the Tiger comic or cartoon.
Scott: It's just commercial.
Rym: Well, the reason they haven't done that, I assume, is solely because so many people are so openly horny for Tony.
Scott: Just make a horny one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Lean into it.
Rym: To make me the product manager, I will make you so much goddamn money.
Rym: That demographic has unlimited resources.
Scott: The New York Rangers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it's hockey season now.
Scott: We just won big first game undefeated New York Rangers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They are leaning hard into the Cried Vantage ad bromance.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In the social media.
Scott: They are not shying away.
Scott: It was amazing to see that they find no reason that Frosted Flakes could not do the exact same thing.
Rym: Anyway, give me the grainy anime.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So did you care remake of some kind or new season or something?
Scott: What the hell?
Scott: Like what?
Scott: And then, of course, the number one, you know, cannot be ignored.
Scott: The Chainsaw Man anime has begun.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Chainsaw Man is the biggest deal in the anime manga world.
Rym: I got to finish reading the manga because I feel like we should do a final thoughts, like full review of it.
Scott: And I read the whole first manga series.
Scott: Another manga series is coming.
Scott: And, you know, who knows how much of the anime, the manga, the anime season will cover.
Scott: But yeah, the first episode is out.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And also, don't forget, Cyberpunk Edgerunners, which I think both my mom and dad will also be into.
Scott: I don't think that counts as like current anime season, but I do want to watch it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, it is of all the animated things that I could watch right now, regardless of where and how I watch them.
Rym: That's actually at the top of the list for me, because that is the ultra-violent sci-fi type of anime that got me into anime when I was in fourth grade.
Rym: Like that is the shit.
Scott: I don't think it's going to be more ultra-violent than Chainsaw Man.
Rym: It is very much monofilament whip, the anime.
Scott: Chainsaw.
Scott: Monofilament whip.
Scott: The bad guy in Chainsaw Man is the gun devil.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I just want to remind you, anyone out there, if you if you imagine what cyberpunk is to people of our generation, we think of a little chain gun called Reason and we think about monofilament whips.
Rym: Now, fucking badass, they sound like they are.
Rym: But yeah, there is.
Rym: there is a lot of good anime to watch, irrespective of the doom and gloom.
Rym: we just talked about of capitalism destroying anything.
Scott: Yeah, I wonder when is capitalism going to be able to destroy anime?
Rym: or will the passion keep it going?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day, so I can't use that PBS space time that I use that I watch and I used once because, you know, we have a rule.
Rym: Am I going to keep using the same channel over and over again?
Rym: PBS has a parallel channel with a different guy so I can talk about it.
Rym: There is PBS Eons, different guy.
Rym: And this video is fascinating.
Rym: So it's kind of topical because we're, you know, years into basically the most the biggest pandemic in like modern history in the world.
Rym: And this video is about the biggest pandemic ever.
Rym: There was a pandemic with a virus that lasted at least 15 million years and was so absolutely devastating that almost all mammals alive today are the ancestors of the few that survived this 15 million year pandemic.
Scott: So but mammals somehow made it.
Rym: Yes, because a lot of them didn't.
Rym: And this video talks about how we figured out that this disease even existed.
Rym: And it is records.
Rym: It is.
Rym: This is remnants of the adaptations that allowed certain orders of mammals to survive.
Rym: This are in our DNA today.
Rym: And we found these fragments in like every mammal.
Rym: And then we found that the very small number of mammals that do not have it.
Rym: And there's a lot of stuff I do not understand enough to even briefly summarize.
Rym: The video is only 10 minutes long.
Rym: It does a way better job than I possibly could.
Rym: This is so fascinating.
Rym: Just watch it.
Rym: But, yeah, 15 million years, hopefully coronavirus, maybe in like 100 years, will deal with it.
Rym: Maybe 50, maybe 20.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: At least a ton of people I know got COVID relatively recently at work, and I did not, despite being directly, deeply exposed to all of those people.
Rym: And the only difference between me and them, I got the new booster.
Rym: None of them did.
Rym: So if you did not get the new coronavirus booster, go get it.
Rym: Like, do not wait.
Scott: All right, so I don't think I've used this guy as a thing of the day before.
Rym: You've talked about it with me, but I don't.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think you've actually talked about it.
Scott: There is an Internet creator primarily on TikTok, but also a YouTube channel where he sometimes cross posts his content.
Scott: And I become a huge fan.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This guy, I think his real name is Masoud Boumgard.
Scott: He's a stand up comedian.
Scott: I think he's from South Africa, I think, because I watch some of his stand up on YouTube and that's what he mentions it once or twice.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I think that's where he is.
Scott: Not 100 percent sure.
Scott: And he has created a character.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's sort of like Uncle Roger, right, where he's like, it's actually a stand up comedian who's created a character that they pretend to be.
Scott: And that's the joke.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the character he has created is self help sing, right?
Scott: S-I-N-G-H.
Scott: And he's an alternative life coach.
Scott: So if you think if you're going to parody those self help guru type people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, those people are all full of shit.
Scott: So if you tried to parody them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like it's going to be one of those situations where you can't tell the parody apart from the reality.
Scott: You're just going to end up being one of them.
Scott: So what he's done is sort of genius in that by being it's like if you are alternative, alternative medicine would just be medicine.
Scott: So an alternative self help guru is just a legitimate.
Scott: So like someone who will actually help you and give you good advice.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so all his videos are pretty much the philosophy that I already had in life just being told to me.
Scott: He's like.
Scott: he's like, fuck the work deadlines.
Scott: Nobody will actually die.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if you have a shitty day, go home and go to bed.
Scott: It's like, yeah, it's like all this really common sense advice you should actually follow presented as if it's not good advice you shouldn't follow from some weird self help guy.
Rym: And that is that is a magic combination of being parody, but also being actually legit like that is hard to do.
Scott: Yeah, so I really have become a big fan of this guy.
Rym: I mean, his philosophy is very much like how I live my life.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty.
Scott: it's like if you need a real self help guru, you need the alternative self help guru because the real ones are bullshit.
Rym: Right.
Rym: So what did I tell you?
Rym: Because I like someone I was doing some mentoring for in their career a few weeks ago.
Rym: And I basically said the company won't burn down if this project doesn't go exactly right.
Rym: Like that's right.
Rym: And if the company would burn down because this project doesn't go exactly right, you need to be paid way more money because this is a really important project.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What are the other?
Scott: if everyone is depending on this thing happening on a certain day, otherwise a disaster will happen.
Scott: Then that means you are so critical and so important that you should be paid a zillion dollars.
Scott: It's like, you know, like the star franchise athlete on a team or something.
Rym: I would say that there is.
Rym: there are a few cases where society gets that wrong.
Rym: That's a whole different conversation.
Rym: Like teachers should be paid a lot.
Rym: They're very important.
Scott: All I'm saying is that if everyone followed the advice of self-help, saying the world, our society would be incredible.
Rym: Well, because remember the thing about self-help, like actual self-help, not fake self-help is similar to psychotherapy and everything else.
Rym: You can't therapy your way out of the crushing despair caused directly by capitalism and a cruel and indifferent society.
Rym: But you can react to those evil and dangerous pressures in a more healthy manner.
Rym: You can't solve the problem, but you can change.
Rym: You can try to change your attitude about how you react to the problem you can't solve.
Scott: I'll always remember the mural that was painted, you know, nearby some years back that said anxiety was.
Scott: it said anxiety is normal in an unjust society.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: It's like this injustice.
Scott: If you don't stop the injustice, of course, it's going to be.
Scott: It's like, you know, if you just try to stop the anxiety and let the injustice continue, they ain't going to work.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So in the news, let's see the.
Rym: the panel Emily and I did at PAX West is, of course, on our website.
Rym: The Book Club book is Binti, which read all three.
Rym: It'll take you like three hours, maybe six hours total if you're a slow reader.
Rym: It's real good.
Rym: We'll probably do the show on it next week on Thursday.
Rym: I see no reason not to.
Scott: Unless something else comes up.
Rym: Yeah, something else comes up.
Rym: I didn't do the thing that might have gotten in the way of this episode because nobody else wanted to go.
Rym: And also it is crazy windy outside, which might have made that event a little bit difficult to attend comfortably.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Why not have it on a Wednesday?
Rym: But otherwise, I guess you'll have to pick the next book club book.
Rym: Are you going to do the choice?
Scott: I already have to two books selected.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I also have two books selected for the following one.
Rym: It's going to be a fun time.
Rym: So if you don't remember, the way we're going to do the book club now is whoever's turned it is to pick has to choose two books.
Rym: And the other of us chooses which of the two.
Rym: It's an I slice you pick situation.
Scott: I cut you choose.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, we'll see how it goes.
Rym: And otherwise, websites coming along, we got a bunch of stuff going on.
Rym: Stay tuned for there will be gig nights panels at PAX Unplugged.
Rym: Maybe there'll be Rym and Scott together.
Rym: Maybe it'll just be Rym as the last several PAXs have been.
Rym: The world wonders and we will see how that goes.
Rym: But that's not now.
Rym: And we don't have any major hiatus coming up except for the regularly scheduled ones around the end of the year holidays.
Rym: So with that, let's talk about some shows.
Rym: So you want to talk about Gundam first?
Rym: Then I can talk about Star Trek.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So this so so people are aware, right?
Scott: The original Mobile Suit Gundam, right?
Scott: The original TV series from nineteen seventy nine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When that show came out, the art director of that show.
Scott: What was his name?
Scott: I always forget his name, even though it's right there.
Scott: Oh, Yoshikazu Yasuhiko.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He is also the person who made the Gundam the origin manga.
Scott: And just so we get this out of the way, if you want to experience the story of the original Gundam, right.
Scott: Char, Amuro, all that shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The manga is the best rendition, period.
Scott: The three compilation movies being the second best rendition anyway.
Scott: But when they were making that original TV series, right.
Scott: The art director, Yasuhiko, he got sick around episode fifteen or so.
Scott: Right.
Scott: At least when they were working on those episodes and he was out and they, you know, they were outsourcing some animation and stuff and he just wasn't there.
Scott: For a set for a few episodes or whatever.
Scott: In episode fifteen, which was titled Kukunu's Dawn's Island.
Scott: It was this little story about an island that they went to and whatnot.
Scott: That episode was animated poorly.
Scott: Very poorly.
Scott: If you've seen, you've probably seen these meme images of like, you know, the original Gundam with like its head drawn very stupidly.
Scott: If you see the image, you might recognize this is not that uncommon in anime.
Rym: There are almost any long running or major show will have like the episodes that are drawn.
Rym: weird for some reason.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, anyway, that image is from this episode.
Scott: It's just really bad animation in this episode.
Scott: And because of the infamy of this episode, when the show was released in other countries, such as the US, that episode fifteen was not included.
Scott: And it didn't really matter that it wasn't included because it was sort of like the standalone side story deal.
Scott: that didn't have a huge impact on the overall plot.
Scott: You weren't really missing much.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like the compilation movies don't really include anything that happened in that episode.
Scott: It's like they were.
Scott: it was compiled out.
Scott: So because of that, it became infamous.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like we want to see the lost episode.
Rym: You know, spoilers, most things that are infamous and they're not actually worth seeing anyway.
Scott: So for some reason, due to the infamy of this episode, right, they did what was sort of like the opposite of a compilation movie is like an expansion movie.
Scott: It came out this past summer, right, in Japan is.
Scott: they made a whole movie, right, a script of that episode and stretching it out to like, you know, movie length and producing it with modern animation, some CG robots a little bit, you know.
Rym: Now, I got to say, that is a pretty cool thing to do.
Rym: And I would like to see that happen to other things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So they just took this episode and they stretched it out.
Scott: And I'm like, man, it's like instead of compilation movies, you try to take a whole like forty nine, thirty nine episode series, twenty six episodes and squish it so someone can watch it in less time.
Scott: What if you did an expansion?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Why not take every episode of Evangelion and make each one a movie?
Scott: Ninety minutes each.
Scott: Right.
Rym: That was a trend for a brief time in anime.
Rym: Remember, there was Tenji Muyo, the
Rym: O.A.V.,
Rym: and then there was Tenji Muyo, the TV series that was just spread out.
Scott: and was it twenty six movies?
Rym: It was basically.
Rym: they took a short O.A.V.
Rym: and expanded it into a long, boring TV show.
Rym: And the same thing happened with El Hazzar.
Scott: We've got, you know, you got your Futurama and your Adventure Time, you know, movies that happened after the TV series is right.
Scott: But those are only a handful.
Rym: It was like, no, take like the Puhoi episode of Adventure Time, which is one of the more important and famous episodes.
Rym: That's the Pillow People episode.
Rym: I have to keep saying that because apparently no one remembers that it's called Puhoi, except me.
Rym: I don't know why I remember that, but imagine if that was an hour and a half long movie.
Rym: That would be fantastic.
Scott: So anyway, they took this episode that was infamous.
Scott: They expanded it and fleshed it out to be a whole movie.
Scott: And when the movie starts, right, it says this is a retelling of episode fifteen of Mobile Suit Gundam.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And now we're starting.
Scott: It's like it doesn't pretend that like, you know, any.
Scott: it's like it expects you to have just watched episodes one through fourteen.
Scott: It's not to know who these characters are.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like you can still enjoy the movie not knowing who the characters are because you'll know that like, oh, that's a Gundam pilot, I guess.
Scott: I guess that's the captain.
Scott: I guess that's their friend.
Scott: Like there won't be any meaning to those characters because those characters that are the Gundam characters don't have any character development or exposition in the episode.
Scott: Like you're supposed to know who they are.
Scott: But other than not knowing who they are, everything else about the plot, you know, the new characters that are introduced just for the movie, et cetera, et cetera, like you can completely understand the story.
Scott: It's totally self-contained.
Scott: It begins, middles, ends.
Scott: You know, you can watch this, but it obviously will have much more meaning if you know anything about the original Gundam.
Scott: And, you know, is this some great anime movie?
Scott: Like, you know, the ones we say, oh, you got to go to the theater and see them.
Scott: No, it's, it's a TV episode that's just way better produced and bigger and better and nicer and, you know, well done.
Scott: And, you know, it's worth seeing, I guess.
Scott: But, you know, it's not run out and see, like we say for, you know, the Hosoda movies and the, you know, the Yuasa movies and the Miyazaki movies and all those.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, yeah, I mean, there are.
Scott: I haven't seen the original old bad episode, so I don't know, like, what things were added, what things are removed, if any, what things were changed.
Rym: But, you know, I mean, that old episode is probably only twenty three minutes long.
Rym: You could just go.
Scott: Yes, indeed it is.
Scott: But, you know, I still enjoyed it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it's pretty obvious, like what was going to happen in the in the movie.
Scott: It wasn't like, you know, a complicated plot.
Scott: But, you know, it panned out well.
Scott: Everything really came together.
Scott: You know, there were, you know, a good, you know, progressive arc, but basically, I guess, short summary of it just to, you know, to wrap things up is, you know, the the main Gundam characters are on their on their ship, chilling, awaiting new orders.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they get ordered to go on this mission to clean up some remnant hostels from a previous battle that are on this island.
Scott: And they go to the island and there's this dude there who's got a, you know, who's obviously a Xeon guy and he's got a fucking, you know, Zaku.
Scott: Yeah, he's got a Zaku and he's hella dangerous.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they can't really beat him.
Scott: And then there's bad weather.
Scott: And so after they send they send people in to go find out what's going on with the island and then they you know, they think, you know, they're dead because they're lost and they had they can't they can't search the island right now with the bad weather.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Well, that's like the plot of, I don't know, a third of all Star Trek episodes.
Scott: Anyway, it's an excuse to have them trapped there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it turns out, you know, the the the the doin guy, that super bad ass Zaku pilot, he's got all these kids on the island he's taking care of.
Scott: He's he's a good guy and he's probably he's up to something good.
Scott: You know, he's abandoned the the Xeon people.
Scott: He's just defending the island from war in general.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then, you know, shit happens and it turns out the secret shit on the island, of course.
Scott: And, you know, eventually Xeon comes back to the island and the good guys come back to the island and they fight and then everything is resolved somehow.
Rym: I mean, I guess it had to be because it was originally a self-contained episode that wasn't even important enough to compile.
Scott: It had to be.
Scott: Otherwise, there wouldn't be episode 16.
Scott: You know, episode 16 is coming next.
Scott: Did you at least know that much?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's really, you know, a story of the characters that are introduced for this episode.
Scott: Doan and the children and, you know, the Gundam characters are just sort of, you know, passing through to sort of reveal which is interesting because that is how like the Slayers movie slash OAVs were.
Rym: That is how a lot of the One Piece movies are.
Scott: It is a lot like a Slayers movie.
Rym: Like the main characters don't have an arc, they're just there and interact with the new characters who have an arc and that are never seen again.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's one of those.
Scott: It's a. it's a pretty good one of those, actually.
Scott: Like if you took and made the original Gundam series and made a movie like this for every episode, that would be a very positive, incredible thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like it might take forty nine years if they do one a year.
Scott: It might take it might take ninety eight years if they do one every other year, but I'm glad they made this.
Scott: It sort of puts the infamy thing to rest, you know, if you and if you're a Gundam fan, see it.
Scott: And if not, you know, but yeah, they aired it.
Scott: Oh, I forgot to mention this.
Scott: They aired it in the air.
Scott: It.
Scott: it was in US theaters two nights only one night sub the next night dub one showing of each.
Scott: And that was it.
Scott: So to see it now, you're going to have to either wait for it to be streamed or Blu-rayed or pirated or imported or something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I saw.
Scott: I went to the movie theater and I saw it during the one night sub screening.
Scott: And that was, you know.
Rym: All right, not bad.
Rym: So the thing I watch that I know Scott will never watch will never watch.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I'm on a big Star Trek kick again.
Rym: I rewatch DS nine.
Rym: And if you're a Star Trek fan, the Star Trek cup overflow recently.
Rym: And other than the movies, because there's drama, all of the Star Trek TV shows are just on Paramount Plus.
Rym: So I'm actually paying for that service because we were watching like all the Star Treks.
Rym: But there are actually two different independent Star Trek animated series that are currently airing simultaneously.
Rym: That are set in different times in different places.
Rym: So this now brings the total of animated Star Treks to three, if any of you remember the original animated series, which even I knew that existed, even though I never watched it, didn't have that many episodes.
Rym: In fact, it had two seasons.
Rym: So there is like twenty two episodes total of that animated series, the original one.
Rym: So lower decks I've talked about.
Rym: It's fantastic.
Rym: I love the shit out of it.
Rym: Star Trek Prodigy is interesting because if I had to describe it one, if you did not know Star Trek existed, like say you've never heard of Star Trek, but you had heard of Star Wars and I showed you a random episode of, I don't know, Star Trek, the next generation, you would not think that this was Star Wars.
Rym: You would know that it was something different.
Rym: Just obviously it's so different in like how action is portrayed and how characters talk and what kinds of stories there are.
Rym: But if I and I would say that is true of almost all Star Treks.
Rym: But if I showed you a random episode of Star Trek Prodigy and you would never heard of Star Trek, I think you would assume this is set in the Star Wars universe.
Scott: Well, but there would.
Scott: there were, first of all, even no matter how it's structured or the plot or the characters.
Scott: Right.
Scott: A, there would be some people wearing like, you know, Starfleet uniform.
Rym: Ah, there really aren't in Star Trek Prodigy.
Rym: All right.
Rym: There is one character wearing a Star Trek uniform.
Scott: Well, that would give it away.
Scott: Just one is enough.
Rym: But if you had never heard of Star Trek, that's just that's just there's that one human wearing the weird uniform.
Scott: The other thing is that Star Wars, no matter which Star Wars it is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There are certain like, you know, Star Wars things that are always going to like appear like, you know, a ship that looks something like an X-wing.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: There's there's stuff like that in this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or, you know, a guy wearing some armor that's reminiscent of a stormtrooper.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There is basically that.
Rym: there is basically a Darth Sidious.
Rym: There is basically a Darth Maul, like the bad guys.
Scott: Aesthetically, like aesthetically, you would think that like, oh, is that is that?
Scott: is that an evil?
Rym: If you watch this, you look at one guy and think, whoa, is that like the Emperor's son?
Rym: You see the other guy like, whoa, is that?
Scott: so you're saying that they have pirated Star Wars aesthetics and into their show.
Rym: So it's more that it's telling the kind of story that Star Wars, like the expanded Star Wars universe would tell more so than what Star Trek typically does.
Scott: But why is it called?
Scott: Prodigy is the name of a ship like usual.
Rym: So that's actually TBD.
Rym: So only one is out.
Rym: There's more coming.
Rym: But basically it the ship in this one is not called the prodigy.
Rym: It's it's a whole other thing going on.
Rym: So to avoid getting into the details of Star Trek for the Scott audience, this is set after one of the other Star Trek's called Voyager, and it's way out in like so far away from the Federation that the Federation basically doesn't exist out there.
Rym: And a Star Trek Federation ship is basically crashed or something happened to it.
Rym: So it's out alone, way out in the edge of the universe.
Rym: A bunch of kids who are basically slaves on a planet that is run by an evil Star Wars looking emperor type dude.
Scott: Well, that sounds like the first Star Trek series slaves on a planet.
Rym: They basically find this ship and use it to escape from this planet.
Rym: The ship happens to be a Federation ship.
Scott: They basically seal a Star Trek, a full size one like that has a city inside.
Rym: It is a full size Star Trek ship that is just a couple of kids.
Rym: Yeah, a couple of kids works.
Scott: It crashed and it still works.
Rym: Well, we don't know what deal like.
Scott: I'm trying to avoid the full of thousands upon thousands of corpses.
Rym: And no, it's empty.
Rym: In fact, the only thing on it when the kids get onto it is a hologram and holograms in the Star Trek universe or semi ascension like it's complicated.
Scott: So it was guarding this.
Rym: No, no, it was guarding it.
Rym: They find it, salvaging it.
Rym: No, in fact, the evil guys vaguely knew it was there and we're looking for it, but the kids found it.
Rym: It's enormous.
Scott: Yeah, could you not find it?
Rym: That is all revealed.
Rym: That's part of the story of the show.
Scott: This doesn't make any fucking sense.
Scott: OK, so the kids, even with my little Star Trek knowledge, it makes no sense.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So it's kind of crazy.
Rym: Actually, the kids find the ship and the deal is the ship.
Rym: The only thing on the ship is the hologram, which is a copy of a real starship captain from a previous Star Trek set way before this show happens, like Captain Jane.
Scott: OK, well, that's good.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: So the hologram sees these kids and is like, I guess you're the new cadets and the kids are like, boy, howdy.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: And the kids be like, we don't have to do it.
Scott: I mean, they want to.
Rym: But if they basically want to steal the ship, so obviously they want to.
Scott: But they could just be like, you're just a hologram.
Scott: You can't tell us what to do.
Rym: Well, the hologram is currently able to run the whole ship and oh, that's how the corpses got disposed of.
Rym: OK, well, there are no corpses.
Rym: We don't know the deal with the ship yet.
Rym: So the kids basically just are on the ship.
Rym: They act like, yes, there's a hologram alone.
Rym: Of course, we're cadets and the holograms like good because this ship is designed to train cadets on this whole sort of special mission and they don't understand and adventure.
Scott: What a coincidence.
Scott: That's probably a lie.
Rym: Yeah, there's a whole real Star Trek plot, but that does not really get revealed until the end of season one.
Rym: But if I had to describe what the show is actually about, not in a Star Trek context, these kids basically find the ship and go off on an adventure and there's a sinister undercurrent and the evil guys are chasing them.
Rym: There's almost no human characters.
Scott: And it is just the evil guys who are who are enslaving them can chase them through space.
Scott: It means they can fly in space.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: How come they weren't able to locate a giant ship on their own planet?
Rym: That's kind of revealed and complicated.
Scott: Does it have a cloaking device?
Rym: I'm not going to explain to you the deal with cloaking devices in Star Trek because there's a lot.
Scott: Pretty sure only bad guys have them.
Rym: That's actually low key kind of true for complicated reasons.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I know.
Scott: I know there's bare minimums.
Scott: I'm a nerd.
Scott: Even though I don't like Star Trek and have watched almost none.
Rym: So the deal is I know that to end the war in the old Star Trek, only the bad guys that had cloaking devices, the Federation could easily develop this technology.
Rym: And to end those wars, the Federation basically signed a treaty where they agreed they would never research or use cloaking technology under any circumstances ever.
Rym: They're just like our ships.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I didn't know that there was a reason for it.
Rym: There is a canonical reason for it because it is a plot point in one of the Star Treks, Deep Space Nine, because the Romulans give give the Federation permission to use one ship with a cloaking device for complicated reasons.
Rym: Anyway, I digress.
Rym: So the show really is almost like a kid's introduction to Star Trek.
Rym: It's almost like imagine if there's a kid in the real world today who's like twelve, ten, maybe eight, and you want to introduce them to Star Trek.
Rym: This show kind of almost walks a kid through.
Rym: what's the deal with Star Trek, but is also a good kid's show.
Rym: I would say this is absolutely a show aimed at kids for kids.
Rym: Good for kids.
Rym: It's very Star Wars like.
Rym: it's super fun.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's interesting that I just talked about Gundam, because at least the part about kids finding a powerful technology is a very Gundam thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Just instead of one kid finding one robot and becoming the best pilot of it, it's a group of kids finding a whole ship and becoming the crew.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And they escape with this ship and shenanigans in space ensue.
Rym: And the bad guys are trying to chase them.
Rym: And I'm not going to spoil anything that happens.
Rym: But for Star Trek nerds, it's interesting because until the last episode, you don't really know when this is set because it feels like it's set way after most of the Star Trek most people have ever watched.
Rym: And it is set after a lot of Star Trek.
Rym: But if you don't know anything about Star Trek, it's just a sci fi story.
Rym: that's actually pretty compelling and pretty well done and good for kids.
Scott: I just want to say we can end the show, but, you know, the trope of kids find, acquire powerful thing, magic, technology, objects, whatever.
Rym: It's a good genre.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like that's a good genre.
Scott: It's been done a million times.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We've also occasionally seen the adjacent one of two different groups of kids or two kids.
Scott: Both acquire some kind of MacGuffin technology magic at the same time.
Scott: And one good one's good and one's evil.
Scott: We've seen that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Scott: What I haven't seen is anyone go over to write three or four, not kids in the same group.
Scott: I've seen that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I'm saying like three or four or more different groups of kids all find powerful things at the same time.
Rym: Isn't that just Pokemon?
Scott: No, because the Pokemon is about the one kid who's the champ.
Scott: Everyone else is just normal Pokemon.
Scott: It's not like you ever see.
Scott: in Pokemon, you never have a situation where like five different ashes are out there all catching different legendaries who all show up at the Pokemon, you know, league at the same time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You don't see that.
Scott: It's one person who's catching the legendaries.
Rym: You know what's funny?
Rym: Even the isekai shows tend to have this.
Rym: You often like for Shiggy Yugi did this even go all the way back.
Rym: Multiple people get transported to the magical world or the sci-fi world.
Rym: But that's together.
Scott: That's like, you know, El Hazzard.
Scott: They go together.
Rym: But they go together.
Rym: But you almost always some of them end up like on the evil side and some of them end up on the good side.
Scott: El Hazzard.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He's got the bug room.
Scott: One guy.
Scott: It's two groups.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The good ones and the bad ones.
Scott: But there wasn't a three a three way.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or a four way.
Rym: I feel like the more complex.
Scott: interesting is occasionally you see a little less black and white.
Rym: I think you occasionally see the three way.
Rym: But the three was usually like.
Scott: Give me an example of the three way.
Rym: So you see some of those less.
Scott: one example, one show, one book, one movie, one.
Rym: So the trope would be it.
Rym: I think it boils down to.
Rym: you might have an individual character, but I think it was a good specific example.
Rym: That isn't just like a random El Hazzard character where you've got the typical two factions.
Rym: But then there's one character who's like, fuck all this.
Rym: I don't care about any of this.
Rym: I'm just doing my own thing.
Rym: And they're a side character, but they never are involved in the real plot.
Scott: Yeah, I'm talking main main characters, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: But I would say if you want to introduce kids to Star Trek, Prodigy is like the gateway show to get a kid interested in Star Trek at all, because it kind of over the course of the show teaches you what's the deal with Star Trek and what's the deal with the Federation in a pretty interesting way.
Rym: But it is a kid's show.
Rym: It's not like the grim, dark nonsense of Picard or the typical Star Trek fare of what most Star Treks are like.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Linky G, Dread Lily Tenebrae, a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Casecare makes music.
Rym: Chris Haddad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Sherwin Von Horl.
Rym: Stop all the downloading.
Rym: The next station is Finch West, Finch West Station.
Rym: And many, many people whose names I will not say because they have correctly chosen to give us like a dollar.
Rym: So anyway, yeah, we're still back.
Rym: I got nothing new.
Rym: I'm really hungry.
Rym: So I'm just going to end this on a song that you may recognize.
Scott: You were first to the match called the Reindeer Girls.
Rym: Oh, something.