Scott:
Rym: It's Thursday, May 26th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym, and I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we talk about trains.
Rym: Choo-choo.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: We have only talked about trains once before.
Scott: We've talked about a lot of trains on this show.
Rym: I'm not talking train games, but I want to point out that on October 23rd, 2013, we talked about Take the X Train.
Scott: That was an anime, yeah.
Rym: That was the only show that had the word "train" in it.
Rym: Even the reviews of 18xx games don't actually say "train" anywhere in the title of the GeekNights episode.
Scott: Yeah, that's, you know, that's how it goes.
Scott: But yeah, I'm surprised, you know, there's some things that are just so obvious.
Scott: Like, we had to have done an episode on that, and then of course I go and I search, and I find out, yup, it was Rym deleted that episode because it was such an obvious one.
Scott: I'll put some protections in the new website to make sure this doesn't happen anymore.
Rym: You get to the point, I mean, I just sort of assume, any idea I have for a GeekNights episode, my brain just says, we've definitely already done that, probably in like 2007.
Rym: But some things we just never got to, or some things we zoomed way in and never talked about the topic.
Scott: Alright, well, the people who are for some reason watching a podcast, even though there's nothing to frickin' see, we have no visual content, really.
Rym: I do show my web browser and what I'm looking at while we're talking, so the listener knows when I'm just reading Wikipedia, usually.
Scott: Okay, good.
Scott: That's usually what we do on this show.
Scott: And the people listening, which is, I guess, you still shouldn't do that because the podcast isn't worth listening to, but if you're, you know, that's the correct way to, anyway.
Scott: May or may not notice, I bought a new microphone, right?
Scott: You know, it showed up immediately when I ordered it because that's how professional audio/video places do.
Scott: You know, you order from them and they're like, oh, they must have like a concert tomorrow.
Scott: We gotta get it to them stat, right?
Rym: And I can say that Scott sounds better through the Discord we use to record GeekNights.
Rym: It was noticeable, and I'm gonna do a little spectral analysis.
Rym: I'll post it for the Patreon patrons, a little, I'm gonna do an analysis of Scott's old microphone versus this one.
Rym: That'll be really easy to do.
Scott: The reason I bought this one wasn't necessarily for its sound quality, even though I hope the sound quality is better because it costs more money than the old microphone, but really I bought it for the ergonomics, right?
Scott: So you can see this feature where the XLR connector is separated from the microphone.
Scott: So you can adjust the microphone's position without tugging on the XLR cable.
Scott: So that's really great.
Scott: You know, it hangs downwards, you know, as opposed to pointing straight in.
Scott: So now that means I can sit differently.
Scott: I can move the arm differently.
Scott: It's better on my neck and such.
Scott: And because it has this built-in windscreen, which I might replace with even the big daddy windscreen.
Scott: We'll see about that.
Rym: That thing is so big.
Scott: It is laughably large.
Scott: But that means I don't need the windscreen blocking my face.
Scott: So if for some reason someone really wants to see my face in bald head, I'm not hiding behind a black disc anymore.
Scott: But actually, you know, all those things aside, this microphone came with a feature I did not expect and greatly enjoy.
Scott: And might cause me to buy the microphone again or maybe return it and keep buying new ones if I could get away with it.
Scott: Is that this microphone has the smell of a brand new NES cartridge.
Scott: Ooh!
Scott: Mmm, it smells good.
Rym: If someone can make a cologne that smells like that accurately, they'll be a billionaire.
Scott: I'll order it right now.
Scott: Let's see, does that exist?
Rym: If it exists, I'm buying it too.
Scott: Cologne.
Scott: The Legend of Zelda NES cartridge air freshener.
Rym: Nah, there's no way.
Scott: Den-e-nes very gentle cologne.
Scott: That's baby cologne.
Rym: I'm looking for perfume instead, just in case.
Scott: Game on.
Scott: What is this?
Rym: I don't think anyone has... Wait, there's NES soap, but it doesn't look like it smells like an NES.
Scott: NES cartridge coaster.
Scott: No, that's not it.
Scott: Cologne, not coasters.
Rym: You know, the problem is, to make that smell, it probably consists of carcinogens.
Scott: Of course, it's some kind of plastic box.
Rym: Lots of volatile organic compounds.
Scott: I mean, cinnamon is a volatile organic compound, right?
Scott: So don't come at me with that kind of nonsense.
Rym: It's a pretty good microphone.
Scott: Yeah, it's an ancient microphone.
Scott: This microphone's been in production since the 70s, right?
Rym: Not quite as long as the SM57.
Rym: Up until this point at home, you were using the same microphone that Lyndon Baines Johnson used as president of the United States.
Scott: Well, I think the reason they don't use this one is because it would look kind of silly when you're standing at a lectern.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I remember, I was trying to figure... Because we bought the SM57 because the president used it, of course it's good enough.
Rym: And it was cheap.
Rym: It was way cheaper than the SM57.
Scott: It is good enough.
Rym: But then we discovered, when I did some research, because I finally figured out why the president of the United States used that microphone from Lyndon Baines Johnson to Barack Obama.
Rym: Pure aesthetics.
Rym: The SM58 would have been better at being the president's microphone, but someone thought the 57 looked better on TV and film.
Rym: That was the sole determination.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: But for anyone who can't see, this is the one I got, is the Shure SM7B.
Scott: And I expect there's really no upgrading from this.
Scott: Like, this is the... I podcasted for 16 years, it doesn't look like we're going to stop.
Rym: So the microphones you've used for GeekNights, not counting the Logitech stick microphone and those shitty radio shacks in the early days, we used the SM57, then we upgraded, and Scott was using, I think, a beta 58A.
Rym: And then eventually I started using the beta 87A, and now Scott's on this, which is weirdly enough...
Scott: I was using the 57 again when I started podcasting from my apartment.
Rym: Also, I had to get the beta 58A that you were using repaired because the inside of it rusted from so many years of podcasting.
Scott: Well, I don't think that happened to this one.
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: Because the shape of it, it's not going to happen, right?
Rym: Yeah, but I don't think there's going to be a better microphone for you because we're not recording music.
Scott: I don't think there's a better microphone just for podcasting, period.
Scott: It's like, what can you possibly get?
Scott: that would, you know, why?
Rym: I mean, other than highly specialized things like things for on a stage or like a bad acoustic environment, but it's a pretty good looking microphone, pretty good sounding microphone.
Rym: But I will post some screenshots of the differences between the two in a spectral analysis because I do have to remake the GeekNights pipeline, at least the Scott part of the pipeline, to make sure the audio levels mix in nicely.
Rym: And I've got to change the noise profile because I have an old noise profile for you.
Rym: But yeah, that's just part of what it takes to make a podcast.
Rym: In the news, of course, there were so many mass shootings, like, we don't even need to talk about them.
Scott: But there is a- You know, the onion story, just, you know, roll it again, right?
Rym: No way to prevent this.
Scott: No way to prevent this says only country where this regularly happens.
Rym: So what I want to talk about is an orthogonal story that broke today.
Rym: And this is not even related to the three mass shootings that happened in the last few days.
Rym: This is a sea change in what kills children in the United States because as of now, guns kill more American kids than cars do.
Rym: That is a huge statistic.
Scott: Of course, they're only counting children who died because they were directly hit by a car or were in a car when the car crashed.
Rym: Oh yeah, that doesn't even count all the kids who die as the externalities of air pollution from cars, stress from cars, lack of access to a car because there aren't any other ways to get around in most of America.
Scott: I mean, you could think about it this way, right?
Scott: There's so many ways a car can indirectly kill a child, right?
Scott: Maybe their parents die in a car crash and now the child is unsupported and orphaned and then because of that, they die from something else, right?
Scott: It's like that would never show up in the statistics as the kid died because of a car crash even though if it was not a car dominant society, the child would be alive and so forth.
Scott: You can think of so many such scenarios.
Rym: But this speaks to a broader point about America and the Republican Party in America and it ties into not just this problem but also what happened with COVID and what happens with car deaths and everything.
Rym: There has been a conservative strategy in America for decades that is continuing to bear fruit where you normalize something that shouldn't be normalized and once you get it to the point to where people assume they can't do anything about it, they stop trying to do anything about it and then you win.
Rym: That happened with cars.
Rym: I've talked to them on the gig nights before.
Rym: Every other weekend or so, Emily and I go hiking or camping like way upstate.
Rym: so we drive out of the city in a car and I have seen what is clearly a fatal collision probably five times on those trips.
Rym: Five times in three years?
Rym: That's terrifying.
Rym: On average, one person dies per day just on those roads and yet that's not a major news story.
Rym: That's endemic.
Rym: Most people just accept that as part of the world.
Rym: They don't think that hard about it or they rationalize it as cars.
Rym: You need a car.
Rym: What are you going to do without a car?
Scott: COVID.
Scott: And these deaths, right?
Scott: I mean, everyone's going to die.
Scott: It's a premature death.
Scott: Someone dies before they had to.
Scott: They could have had a longer, better life and brought more joy.
Rym: How many human years.
Rym: do cars just erase from the world?
Scott: But it's different from, you know, it's like if you die because of lightning, it's like, well, it's like, yeah, there's nothing we can really do about that.
Scott: You know, it's like, you know, we can have lightning rods and stuff.
Rym: Which we do.
Rym: We require lightning rods on buildings.
Rym: Like we teach kids about lightning.
Scott: Lightning is going to kill people and we can't stop lightning from happening.
Scott: But cars are, you know, the transportation infrastructure is purely something that we have.
Scott: It is of our own making.
Scott: And it is entirely within human power to dictate all the terms of it.
Scott: It's not the laws of physics where it's like, well, nothing we can do about that third law.
Scott: It's like, right?
Scott: Every human law can be anything, right?
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: people, I think, lack imagination because they're always focused on the reality of what the government is, what the current laws are and how hard it is to change them based on, you know, what country you live in and what you're, you know, whether you're democracy, autocracy or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But laws can be anything.
Scott: You could if you made a new country, you know, it's like you could any idea that you could have could be the law.
Rym: Might not be a good idea.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: But it's like it could be anything.
Rym: That's why the language I like to use around this is to say that every person in America who dies by car, that was a choice made by society.
Rym: Society chose to kill that person.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Indirectly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or even if they didn't chose to kill them, you could say that they didn't care.
Scott: They allowed.
Scott: They just didn't care.
Scott: Or, you know, they chose to, you know, allow for the conditions in which that occurred.
Rym: So, you know, the same thing.
Scott: There's no however you want to however you want to put it.
Scott: None of them are good.
Rym: So the same thing is happening with covid as covid becomes like to the point where it's just going to be endemic.
Rym: That was kind of the strategy from the right all along.
Rym: Make it an unsolvable problem so that people stop trying to solve it and just I almost said live with it.
Rym: But of course, it kills people.
Rym: just accept it.
Rym: And the fascinating thing is that there is a scant argument for at least cars and covid in the current environment that it's very difficult to deal with them for a lot of practical reasons.
Rym: That's not to say we shouldn't have tried and shouldn't still try, but there's a lot of practical reasons to slow that down.
Rym: But guns are different in that nobody needs a gun to get to their like to drive to to get to school like guns.
Scott: Right.
Scott: These other systems that we have.
Scott: It's like we, you know, we need a transportation system, how you want to design it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: How, you know, how it functions, who pays for it, et cetera.
Scott: Those all those things can be discussed.
Scott: But I don't think anyone's going to say we don't need any transportation technology deployed in any means.
Scott: Everyone will just walk or run everywhere with their own ability.
Rym: There is one guy on a fixie with a whistle and lots of tattoos who says that.
Rym: right.
Scott: Society can't society cannot function without some sort of, you know, transportation technologies.
Scott: And as soon as you have transportation systems, they need some sort of governance or regulation to prevent chaos.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whatever, whatever technologies they are.
Scott: Even if we invented teleporters, we would need some sort of, you know, federal teleportation authority.
Rym: Even in Star Trek, the Federation has the concept of credits.
Rym: So some jackass doesn't just constantly teleport everywhere all the time at everyone else's expense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, oh, I'm never going to walk.
Scott: If I have to move two feet, I'll teleport.
Scott: I'll teleport to the counter to get my snack and then to pay the cashier and then teleport back to my seat.
Scott: It's like, no, you can walk that.
Rym: Electricity is very similar.
Rym: We need electricity.
Rym: That is like a fundamental aspect of humanity in the modern era.
Rym: But there is no good way to make electricity.
Rym: Every way has pros and cons.
Rym: So we agree we need electricity.
Rym: So we have to have a conversation as a society about where and how to make that electricity and what externalities are we willing to accept as a society.
Rym: But guns, we don't have to accept.
Scott: Yeah, guns have very, very limited necessity, right?
Scott: It's like the vast majority of people and societies and places do not need any guns for anything, anytime whatsoever.
Scott: They're a useless item for almost everybody.
Scott: The only people who need to have a gun, right, would be like a hunter.
Scott: You could even hunt, right?
Scott: If you need a military, we can discuss that, too.
Rym: I would argue it is very difficult to be to be pacifist in the current world.
Scott: As long as another country has a military, your country needs a military.
Scott: And then, right, certain kinds of hunting, I guess you can't hunt with a bow.
Scott: You're going to need some kind of weapon to do the hunting, right?
Scott: And a gun is often the best choice.
Rym: But even there, we could, as a society, say bolt-action, single-shot rifles are the only allowable guns, which are fine for hunting.
Scott: Right, it's like there are many, there are many, many guns.
Rym: Maybe shotguns for bird hunting as well, and that's it.
Scott: Yeah, like a duck, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like you're not going to bow hunt for ducks.
Rym: I mean, people do.
Rym: I have a relative who does.
Scott: That's fucking badass.
Rym: That same relative, Scott, you know, he hunts deer for subsistence.
Rym: You know how he hunts them?
Rym: He doesn't use a gun.
Rym: He thinks guns are for babies.
Rym: He doesn't even use a bow.
Rym: He stalks them with a knife.
Scott: That's fucking nasty.
Scott: But good luck.
Scott: stalking a duck with a knife, is all I'm going to say.
Scott: Yeah, a deer maybe if you're like, you know, a ninja or something, but yeah.
Scott: Anyway, the point is, is that even for hunting, the guns you need for hunting, right, are a certain set of guns, right?
Scott: A few shotguns for, you know, ducks, birds, whatever, right?
Scott: And then for, even if you wanted to hunt a moose, it's like there is a gun that would be appropriate for that.
Scott: And in our society, first of all, handguns are appropriate.
Scott: I don't know that much about guns and hunting, but I know that a handgun is the appropriate weapon for hunting almost nothing.
Rym: Nope, the only cases I am aware of on earth for handguns and hunting is usually people who want to be able to mercifully finish an animal off that they wounded once they get up close to it.
Scott: Okay, good one.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: But also a lot of people shoot themselves that way because most people have no fucking idea how to use a handgun.
Scott: Now, for that use case, though, you would never need a handgun that has a large magazine or any kind of rapid fire mechanism, right?
Scott: At all, right?
Scott: It could be a slow, you know, lousy handgun.
Scott: It doesn't even need to be accurate at range because you're getting close to some animal authority.
Rym: I mean, actually, you could replace the handgun with a captive bolt gun.
Rym: That's what they used to murder cattle.
Rym: It's basically a gun.
Scott: I thought that the cattle ones, though, were usually like, you know, pneumatic or hydraulic or something.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but there are gun-powered- You can't really carry a compressor around with you.
Rym: Well, did you ever see No Country for Old Men?
Scott: Uh, yeah, but I don't remember most of it.
Rym: Well, that's literally one of the main plot devices.
Rym: is the one crazy guy carries a cattle gun and a compressor around with him everywhere.
Scott: Okay, but anyway, the point is the vast majority of guns are devices that are needed by nobody unless they intend to murder other humans.
Scott: And therefore, we should disallow their manufacture, sale, whatever, to the extent possible.
Rym: It's even worse than that.
Rym: If one would argue that a police force needs guns, well, I want to point out that in the most recent school shooting, the cops who were there before- Well, we can talk about that.
Scott: It's a whole 'nother?
Rym: topic.
Rym: All we'll say is the cops who were there, go read what happened and what those cops did.
Rym: They refused to go in because they were afraid of getting shot.
Rym: So they waited until the guy basically offed himself and then they went in after he killed all the kids.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Could you imagine, right, you know, a house on fire and the fire department?
Scott: You know, sometimes the fire department won't go in because that's the right thing to do depending on the fire and the situation.
Scott: But can you imagine the fire department not going in when it's the right thing to do because they're afraid to go in?
Rym: My dad was a fireman.
Rym: My grandpa was a fireman.
Rym: And what I'll say is that both of them lost a lot of friends because firefighters charge into burning buildings to save kids.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And one thing my dad said to me when I was really young, and I was figuring out careers, and they don't tell you what careers there are, and a lot of kids are like, "I could be a fireman or a police
Rym: officer.".
Rym: And I remember what my dad said was, "Nobody says, 'Fuck the fire department,' and spray paints it on a
Rym: wall.".
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I mean, you know, we often complain about the police pointing to the horrible things that they do, right, beating up peaceful protesters, harassing churro ladies, right, you know, et cetera.
Scott: And I think more needs to be said about what police don't do, which is their job.
Scott: They don't do what they're supposed to do.
Rym: They didn't help me get my stolen bike back.
Scott: They don't do anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whether it's a job, large or small, the things that the police are supposed to be doing that we say are within the things we want them to do, they don't do those things.
Rym: I saw a great commentary.
Scott: And they're cowards.
Rym: Remember when the Republican coup on January 6th, and there was that one black cop who saved a bunch of senators.
Rym: There's a video about it.
Scott: I saw a really fascinating- A cop doing what he was supposed to do.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: Yeah, in the commentary, there was an op-ed in Waypoet.
Rym: It was basically like, that story made the rounds and resonated because that is a shocking behavior for a police officer that is rarely seen.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Because think about how many, right, it's like, yes, the police on January 6th, the Capitol Police, were outnumbered, right, by a great deal, right?
Scott: But, you know, there's stories about a handful of them who did what they were supposed to do.
Scott: All the rest did not, you know, it's like, they might have done something.
Scott: Some of them were like, you know, there were those videos like waving people in and shit, right?
Scott: It's like, all the vast majority of them did not do their job, right?
Scott: But of course, today a little while ago- And those people who don't do their job, you want to give guns to those people.
Scott: Oh, they have them already.
Rym: Republicans in the US Senate filibustered dead the Domestic Terrorism Prevention Act that would have restricted guns and investigated things like police for white supremacy.
Rym: They filibustered it dead.
Rym: This wasn't even a bill for the current shooting, this was the bill for the other shooting that happened a little while ago.
Scott: So, no matter how you want to interpret it, right, the point is, is that Republicans, you know- Are the leading cause of death for children in America now.
Scott: Right?
Scott: They are, you know, basically in favor, right, of domestic terrorism.
Scott: They want domestic terrorism to happen, they do not want government resources being used to prevent you from dying.
Scott: They want, they would rather, if given two choices, no matter what their logic is or reason for it, they have chosen that the government should not spend resources.
Scott: They think that is more important than you not dying from a person with a gun, if you're in the United States.
Scott: Given those two priorities, they chose the priority of government spends less money.
Scott: So, there you go, they care about government spending less money more than they care about you dying from a domestic terrorist before you would normally die by natural causes.
Rym: So, not to, but anyway, but in some other news, we're gonna talk about Twitter, but for once, it's not to talk about the technology directly.
Scott: Or any social media biz or anything like that.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, what happened here is that, you know, we've talked about on the show, especially on Monday episodes, about two-factor authentication, right, and how you should use it for everything, as much as possible, even if it's a hassle, right, because of security reasons, you don't want anyone stealing your accounts.
Scott: If you do it properly and you have your backup codes, right, you won't lose your account and you'll never have to worry about, you know, anybody busting, you know, "hacking" your Instagram, right?
Scott: But, if you're doing two-factor authentication, you want to do it using TOTP, which is Google Authenticator with the six-digit codes, right, or any other equivalent app, or you want to do it with a physical device or biometric thing, like a YubiKey or fingerprint thing.
Rym: Or the out-of-band verification, like what Blizzard does, where there's like an app and you hit a button that says, "Yes, that was
Rym: me.".
Scott: Well, that's just TOTP.
Scott: SteamGuard is also effectively, they're all just effectively the same as TOTP, but also the Apple ones, right, your face IDs, your touch IDs, those are okay as well, right?
Scott: But, you do not want to use the SMS one, where they text you a number and you then type that number in.
Rym: We've talked about it at length.
Rym: It doesn't work.
Rym: It's completely insecure.
Rym: If you're using SMS for two-factor, you might as well be using nothing.
Rym: It probably makes you less secure than nothing.
Scott: Now, what Twitter did here is evil, right, and bad.
Scott: What they did is they had people sign up for two-factor auth using, you got to give them your phone number so you can get text messages, obviously, right?
Scott: And then, when people did that, if you read like, you know, the privacy, you know, documents and, you know, terms of service and whatever, it says, "Yeah, user, give us your phone number for two-factor auth.
Scott: We're only going to use your phone number for two-factor auth, right?
Scott: We're not going to use it for any
Scott: shenanigans.".
Scott: But, in fact, they did use it for shenanigans.
Scott: If you gave them your phone number in order to do two-factor SMS authentication, there was a period of time in which they were using those phone numbers for tracking, for advertising, even though you had given them your phone number under another pretense, which was security, and the FTC said, "We caught you.
Scott: Pay a bunch of money.
Scott: You done
Scott: wrong.".
Rym: This is pathetic because Twitter is being fined a pittance.
Rym: It's a one-time fine of $150 million.
Rym: That rounds down to zero.
Scott: That might be a lot for Twitter.
Scott: They're not doing that well.
Rym: They're not doing well, but that still rounds down to zero, even by the kinds of budgets I work with at work.
Scott: I think that it'll get Twitter to stop, though, which is the intent, right?
Rym: But I want to point out, if this had happened in Europe with the GDPR, the fine would not have been $150 million.
Rym: The fine would have been, well, either 20 million pounds, which is a lot less than $150 million, or 4% of the annual worldwide revenue from the preceding financial year of that company, whichever is greater.
Rym: So, if you're a big company, they charge you 4% of your revenue.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: I like it a lot.
Rym: There's some parts of the GDPR that are little less.
Scott: We could argue about the percentage, but I like the concept.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: This should be a $15 million fine for Twitter, or a $50 billion fine.
Rym: Just shut Twitter down.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, the point here is that this is yet another reason not to use SMS for authentication, or not only that, but do not give any company more of your accurate, personally identifying information than is necessary.
Scott: So, if you're buying something from a store, you're going to have to give them your name and address to get the things shipped to you.
Scott: There's no way around that.
Scott: So, give them accurate info.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But if they ask for your social security number, do not fucking give it to them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If it's an optional field, do not fill it in.
Scott: Just don't fill it in if it's optional ever, because it can only help them.
Scott: It doesn't benefit you in any way to give more info.
Scott: that is not necessary.
Rym: Plus, they'll figure it out.
Scott: For example, if you go to a video game website and it says, "What's your
Scott: birthday?"
Scott: We can only share screens.
Rym: January 1, 1900.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can put in any old birthday.
Scott: Why would you tell someone your actual birthday?
Scott: There's no benefit to you putting in any old date that gets you in to see whatever you're trying to get to see.
Rym: In fact, I put fake birthdays into everything to the point that it has actually polluted the public records about me.
Rym: A few years ago, I got a spam that made it through the spam filters.
Rym: But what was notable is it was a company that was like, "Happy birthday
Rym: something."
Rym: And it listed a very specific birthday that I had put into one website and only one website.
Rym: So, I know who sold them my information.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But also, with the birthday thing, a lot of companies like to send you coupons or other bonus things on your birthday.
Scott: If you spread out those dates, remember, only putting in a date if they require you to tell them your birthday.
Scott: But if you spread out those dates and put them at appropriate times, you can get stuff all the time.
Rym: I remember more than once when I was poor, I would casually mention, as I was a group of friends at a restaurant, that it was someone's birthday and often the restaurant would give us a little bit of free food.
Scott: Mmm, free cakes.
Rym: That's real important when you're poor in college.
Scott: They might want to look at someone's driver's license, though.
Rym: I found that in practice, they don't really care enough to do so, but like Starbucks will check.
Scott: Don't do it at the same restaurant too frequently.
Rym: Nope, nope, nope.
Scott: But yeah, don't give out your personal information more than absolutely necessary.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, check this out.
Rym: You may see, remember, that I used one of the better Eurovision entries from one of the better Eurovisions.
Rym: Subwoofer's song, the Grandma Banana Yum Yum song with the wolf.
Rym: And Subwoofer has put out an official video.
Rym: This is the last I'm going to talk about this video on GeekNights, this music video.
Rym: They put out an official video.
Rym: that is the full instructions for how to do the dance in the video.
Rym: And it's a very instructive, easy to follow video.
Rym: Like, you could learn this dance.
Rym: I think I'm going to learn it.
Rym: It's not more complicated than the mamalayo.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: If you want to learn the yum yum dance.
Scott: That's it?
Rym: That's it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So, there's this Instagram account, OneBreathDiver.
Scott: It's an Instagram account belonging to someone named Jules Casey.
Scott: They are a free diver and scuba diver and an award-winning photographer in Australia, according to their Instagram profile.
Scott: And, you know, the whole Instagram account, I guess, could be considered a thing of the day.
Scott: Because all these amazing photos of, you know, under the sea creatures of various kinds.
Scott: And these are really good photos going on here.
Scott: But in particular, this one video of some scallop guys, right?
Scott: And, you know, I mean, you've probably seen a scallop, right?
Scott: Like, after it's been taken out of the ocean.
Scott: You've probably seen one after it's taken out of its shell.
Scott: Just like a little white disc of deliciousness, right?
Scott: But a living scallop that's still, you know, doing its thing is not something I've seen too often, right?
Scott: And in this video, you can see some little scallops alive under the sea.
Scott: And you can see how they move.
Scott: It's like they don't just sit in one spot their whole life, right?
Scott: They move around.
Scott: How do they move around?
Scott: In a very entertaining manner, that's how.
Scott: So, watch and be entertained.
Rym: In the meta moment, the Geek Guys Book Club book remains Stein Fox Gambit.
Rym: I think we can do this on the next Thursday's show.
Rym: I'm going to be done with this book, like, imminently.
Rym: Uh, got a lot to say about it.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: Definitely reading the sequels.
Scott: You know, that's how you always do it.
Scott: I feel like I could pick any series.
Scott: Like, if I did fucking Baby-Sitters Club book one, Rym would be like, after that Book Club episode, Rym would be like, "I'm on Baby-Sitters Book Club
Scott: 100.".
Rym: As a kid, I got pretty deep into the boxcar children.
Scott: Boxcar kids?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't remember boxcar children, but I do remember, you know, Hardy Boys.
Scott: I just read a few random ones here and there.
Rym: I read a few of the old ones, and as a kid, I didn't like them that much.
Rym: But there was a re-release, like a modernized Hardy Boys that was released when I was in, I want to say, late elementary school.
Rym: And it was hardcore and modern, and there was guns and spies, and I was real into that.
Rym: I read, like, 15 of those things.
Scott: There was, I keep forgetting the guy's name every time, uh, that it comes up, but there was this guy who wrote, like, a whole bunch of, um, sports, uh, fiction.
Scott: I'm sure I've mentioned it on the show before.
Rym: Yes, you have mentioned it on the show before.
Rym: When we were talking about reading classes in school.
Scott: Those weren't a series, they were all just these individual books, right?
Scott: And then there was also, of course, uh, you know, because I was there right before the sort of Goosebumps Animorphs type kids, they came after me.
Scott: Right?
Scott: But I was reading some, uh, not just the Hardy Boys, what were the other ones?
Scott: There was the, uh, Encyclopedia Brown.
Rym: Encyclopedia Brown!
Scott: And there was some, anyway, Meta Moment, read this other book, Nine Fox Gambit.
Scott: And also the GeekNights website is coming along nicely.
Scott: Oh, Matt Christopher, that's the guy who did the sports books.
Scott: Yep, Matt Christopher, that's the one.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Alright, so, trains!
Rym: We, uh, we actually think a lot about trains in our daily life.
Rym: Trains are really important to me.
Scott: Yeah, trains are, like, such a significant part of our lives, and we've done episodes about so many other train things, and I'm sure we've talked about it during news and whatnot, but we've never done a main bit on trains, so now is the time.
Rym: So, trains, I think, are one of the most important things to invest in as humans to help address the existential crisis of climate change.
Rym: Trains are more important now than they have been in a hundred years, I think.
Scott: You know, I mean, well, trains were super important when they were first invented, you know, the steam engine and whatnot.
Rym: They were really the first efficient way to travel long distances over land in the history of humanity.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, before trains, if you wanted to go over land, right, it's like you either, you know, it's like Oregon Trail, you know, it's like getting a wagon and it takes you fucking forever, right?
Scott: So not only could a train get people, but also goods, a long way, very quickly.
Scott: It's really funny,
Rym: when I was a kid, like a kid brain, before I went to school and learned stuff, I always thought that there was this evolution of transportation, and I thought that like walking led to scooters, led to bikes, led to motorcycles, led to cars, led to trains.
Rym: I thought trains were like the next step from cars.
Rym: It was not until I went to school that I learned that cars came later.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Because trains just seem more impressive and more useful, even to my kid brain.
Scott: Well, they can go faster, right?
Scott: You know, but I guess the one downside of the train that car people always talk about is the freedom of the open road.
Scott: The train can only go where the tracks go, right?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: But I would say that that is-.
Scott: But the train was such a revolution that once the train was invented, they built tracks like mad, right?
Scott: They're just like, "Oh my god,
Scott: trains!".
Scott: And we had to build tracks everywhere to the point at which they were, you know, enslaving people and all sorts of horrible things just to get more tracks going to more places.
Rym: Any old city in America, under almost every street, are buried.
Rym: Tons of old tram and train tracks from the pre-car era.
Rym: But also, this whole idea that, "Oh, well, people can go anywhere in a car, but if a train-" Society built itself around trains before there were cars.
Rym: The idea was, if you built a train somewhere, the fact that it's only on those rails is really important.
Rym: There's an idea of infrastructure inertia, where once the track is there, it's hard to move or to get rid of it.
Rym: So, if someone builds a track somewhere, it makes a lot of sense for towns to grow around where there's stations on those tracks.
Rym: So, the map of the train network caused the map of cities and humans existing in America, just like how before trains, rivers caused that.
Rym: That's why every old city is on a river.
Scott: Yep, it's like, hey, you might have a place where no one can live, maybe not because it's not a livable place, but because no one can get there.
Scott: A train track that's going from A to B happens to pass that place.
Scott: Someone can get out there, just one person gets out there, build a train station, the track is there, and suddenly you have settlement happening.
Scott: Is it a problem that the train doesn't go everywhere?
Scott: It's like, just live where there's a train station, or live where there's a track and build a train station.
Rym: Yep, or have an alternate means of transportation not to get everywhere you're going, but to get to the nearest train station.
Scott: Yeah, it's, you know.
Scott: But yeah, so, you know, a train is really just like, you know, it has a schedule, you can't necessarily always go when you want, but it's like, it'll get you there when you need, right?
Scott: And if more people were using train, and more was invested in train, there would be more trains that are bigger and faster and more on time, going to more places, right?
Scott: Whereas instead, in the United States at least, we have less trains going less places, to the point at which we have like rail trails all over the place of where there used to be a train, but there isn't anymore, because the track is unused because it was replaced by trucks or whatever.
Rym: But the worst part is, all those rail trails?
Scott: Now it's just a nice hiking trail in the woods.
Rym: Like, I like them, but people have this idea that the tracks weren't necessary anymore or wouldn't be useful, and that's why they turned them into rail trails.
Rym: No, if they ran trains on those tracks instead, those trains would be packed.
Rym: They just stopped running the trains.
Scott: Yep, pretty much.
Rym: I mean, there was a big fight, and we even talked about this on GeekNights back in like 2006 when we lived in Beacon, because there was a big plan to have Metro North, which is the commuter rail for like downstate New York to get into New York City.
Rym: The Metro North Railroad, along the Hudson River, only goes all the way up to Poughkeepsie, and that's where it stops.
Rym: If you want to go further north, there's no commuter rail.
Scott: You gotta use Amtrak, which is not a commuter train, it's a different train.
Rym: There are tons of people who commute to New York City from further north than Poughkeepsie.
Rym: Terrifying numbers of people.
Rym: So what they do is they drive all the way down to Poughkeepsie and park in Poughkeepsie at the end of the line.
Scott: Or take the Amtrak the whole way.
Rym: Yep, if they live far enough north.
Rym: So there was a plan to just extend Metro North three more stations north.
Rym: They proved that those trains would be completely full, it would get a huge number of cars off the road, and all the little dipshit towns north of Poughkeepsie, their local municipal governments blocked it because they didn't want to make the commute easier because they were worried that, and you can read between the lines what they were actually worried about, city people might live up here.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Never mind the fact that- It's like if you're worried about noise, you're not, you're clearly, that's a lie, because you have cars driving all over the place making way more noise than trains.
Rym: But never mind that those towns only exist because all the people who live there drive to Poughkeepsie to work in the city anyway.
Scott: Yeah, I mean these are all US train problems, right?
Scott: If you look elsewhere in the world, right, trains- There's trains everywhere.
Scott: Right, especially like Japan, China, right?
Scott: It's like they got trains everywhere, right?
Scott: China probably even goes too far with it, right?
Scott: They're just like, "Oh, we want to build a train here, knock it down all your houses,
Scott: bye.".
Scott: Yep.
Scott: "Move over there, we're making
Scott: trains.".
Scott: But the trains work, right?
Scott: They're efficient, they're powerful, they're economically, you know, make sense, a lot of sense, and they got newer, faster, better, safer trains in every conceivable way, right?
Scott: They got freaking bullet trains, and it's like, when I was a kid, you know, it's like, you know, not riding too many trains when I was a kid other than, you know, the occasional
Rym: like- I remember the first time I rode a bullet train in Japan with Emily, and it's even one of the older slow ones.
Rym: It's, this, what I rode has nothing on the newer trains in China in the year 2022.
Rym: This train, I remember it got faster, and faster, and faster, and hit a point where I thought, "Damn, this is crazy fast," and it had a lot more getting faster to do.
Rym: that I did not realize.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And it's like, you know, hey, train technology has advanced incredibly, you know, it's like, sure, a bicycle is always gonna be the most efficient in terms of energy per whatever, but you can't move that amount of stuff with a bicycle, right?
Scott: It's like, you need a freight train sometimes, you need a passenger train, you know, or a mixed train or something, you know, for certain loads, it's like, that's the best way, you know, you can fit more containers on some mega freight train than you can on an airplane.
Rym: It's, most of the, like, the things that make trains faster are not technological problems.
Rym: Americans think trains are slow, and the American trains actually could go a lot faster.
Rym: We just haven't invested in repairing and replacing old tracks.
Rym: Like, even our Acela, the fastest train in America, it could go, like, two or three times faster if we bulldozed a small number of nimby houses in, like, a few parts of the Northeast, so the tracks could be made better.
Rym: Those trains are already capable of going way faster than they do today.
Rym: They're basically America's bullet trains, but...
Scott: And even if those upgrades were made, those trains would still be slow and sad compared to the bullet trains of the rest of the world.
Rym: But even those slow bullet trains, if we used our slow bullet trains effectively in America, you could commute from Albany or Philadelphia to New York City on a train faster than you can drive there from, like, a little bit upstate.
Rym: It's kind of terrifying that we have not built trains in this country, and I hate it.
Scott: Anyway, so, but yeah, when I was a kid, it's like, I knew about bullet trains.
Scott: It's like, you saw imagery of bullet trains, but I never saw one, like, in person.
Scott: Like, it was weird that bullet trains were a thing that, like, we knew about from, like, books and photos and video or TV.
Scott: Oh, I don't know.
Rym: For the bullet trains, I never rode a train that was not a toy, like, a steam engine in an amusement park, until I moved to New York.
Scott: Oh, I did, because I would take the train to New York City.
Rym: I lived in Michigan.
Rym: There were no trains anywhere.
Rym: No train could take me.
Scott: And we also took Amtrak to Florida.
Rym: Yeah, we drove to Florida, or we flew to Florida.
Scott: We also drove to Florida.
Rym: Yeah, but there weren't trains where I grew up.
Rym: So, as a young kid, I also had this perception, like, I only ever saw old-timey trains, because they were always, like, historical trains.
Rym: I didn't see our freight trains.
Rym: I didn't see, like, modern passenger trains in person until I came to New York.
Scott: It's, like, even though I did ride trains on occasion when I was young, it's, like, I was always disappointed.
Scott: I was, like, you know, these, you know, they were still fun, because it's still kids and trains.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: It's still fun times, right?
Scott: But I was, like, I knew bullet trains existed, even pre-internet, somehow, and I'm, like, "Where are they?
Scott: Where do they go?
Scott: How come I can't ride them?
Scott: Why don't we use the bullet train?
Scott: Where is
Scott: it?".
Scott: You know, in New York City, there must be a bullet train there.
Scott: Not anywhere in the United States is there a modern train.
Rym: If there was a bullet train in New York, I could get to, we could get, like, upstate faster than flying.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I guess bullet train is an unfortunate name, but...
Rym: Nah.
Scott: Considering.
Scott: Yeah, just a modern train, right?
Scott: I still haven't ridden one, even after, you know, this much of my life is over.
Scott: I still have not ridden on a modern train, because I haven't gone to any of the countries that have them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But I think what's most important about trains is, aside from, you know, all the energy efficiency and the infrastructure inertia and everything, it's that I don't have that much time to live, and before I lived in a place where I didn't have to drive, I spent a lot of time piloting a car, and you can only do so much that is not driving.
Rym: when you're driving.
Rym: You can listen to a podcast, listen to some music, maybe have a not super intense conversation with someone, and that's about it.
Rym: You're basically wasting that time.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like, if you drive somewhere for an hour, right, you get an hour older, that's almost the same as just dying an hour sooner.
Rym: I would rather take a train somewhere that takes three hours than drive somewhere in an hour, because sure, that three hours, I am limited to what I can do, but you know what?
Rym: I'm sitting on a train with my laptop and my Switch and my phone and some snacks.
Rym: That's what the fuck I'm doing at home anyway.
Scott: Yeah, and it's, you know, unlike, you know, people can attempt on an airplane to join the Mile High Club, but on a train, right, you can get on a, you know, proper trains.
Rym: I'm in the train club.
Rym: I am absolutely in the train club.
Scott: Yeah, proper trains have cabins.
Scott: You can get it on on a train.
Scott: I have done that.
Rym: Full disclosure, that has happened on multiple occasions.
Scott: I'm just saying, you can do it, right?
Scott: You can do it on Amtrak.
Scott: It's okay to do it, unlike on an airplane where you can get caught and get in trouble.
Rym: So get this, you know how Emily and I usually, if we go visit her family out in LeRoy.
Scott: If not expected.
Rym: So we could fly to LeRoy, which is near Buffalo, like way upstate by RIT.
Rym: Flying, it's about an hour flight, actually it's like a 45 minute flight, plus an hour to get to the airport, plus an hour of security bullshit and waiting, plus getting from the airport in a car that I have to rent all the way over.
Rym: Or I can take, we can take like a six and a half hour Amtrak in a private car with two beds and internet and holes and a private toilet or a giant room with a shower and stuff in it.
Rym: And those rooms cost, the difference between a regular economy ticket on Amtrak and an economy ticket plus being in that room is less than the cost of a flight.
Scott: Yeah, depends where you're going, but yeah.
Rym: Well, when you're going, those trains, those sleeper cars are only on a few lines.
Rym: So you know what they're not on?
Rym: The lines that go from here to like DC, because if there were sleeper cars to DC, I would go to mag vest in a sleeper car.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But I mean, there's also trains out there that are like, there's a train out in California that has special cars with glass sides.
Rym: I rode in one of those when way back we went to PAX for, uh, you know, PAX and then Scott left.
Scott: And I sit in this train and you look out the window and it's like the train ride itself becomes, you know, a special, you know, like it's now, you know, a special thing in and of itself.
Scott: It's not just a means of getting from here to there.
Scott: It's almost more like a, it's almost approaching like a cruise where it's like, yeah, it's getting you here to there, but it's also itself a destination.
Rym: It's amazing.
Rym: The seats are sideways and you're facing giant panoramic windows and usually there's little lookout towers that you can climb up into.
Scott: And, but it's like their train tracks specifically go past beautiful scenic vistas that you're looking at.
Rym: I only rode those once, but way back and we were at that PAX West.
Rym: after you went home, I had a lecturing gig at, uh, I think Kai Fu in Portland.
Rym: So they paid for me to take a fancy Amtrak to Portland from Seattle and I enjoyed that Vista and it was fantastic and I'd like to do it again someday.
Scott: Even if you don't have the Vista, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you think about like old style, old school train, like, you know, murder on the Orient Express, right?
Scott: It's like, it's like a moving dinner party.
Rym: I was, I bought a ticket to take the Orient Express to Istanbul many, many years ago, uh, because I was doing some travel for work and I was going all around Europe and all this stuff and I looked and I was like, you know what?
Rym: It's actually not really much more expensive than flying.
Rym: I'll just use some vacation days and I was going to take the Orient Express to Istanbul.
Scott: But you didn't.
Rym: I didn't because the coup attempt happened in Turkey.
Rym: Uh, it failed and I canceled my trip and I haven't been to Turkey since.
Rym: and because I wasn't going to Turkey, I had to curtail that whole trip.
Rym: So I just went to Germany and I canceled everything else.
Rym: And then I never had an excuse to go back.
Rym: and then there's COVID and the Orient Express goes through some troubled lands these days.
Rym: So it's a different situation than it was back then.
Scott: So I guess the last thing train-wise, right, is that there's this huge, you know, nerdery around trains.
Rym: Oh, as a kid, I was obsessed with model railroads and I was also obsessed with actual trains.
Scott: It's true for cars too, right?
Scott: You got your hot wheels and you got your, you know, hot rods and car nerds, right?
Scott: You got your airplane nerds doing flight simulator and all that, right?
Scott: But train nerds, it's like these nerds are every kind of transportation, boat nerds too.
Scott: But the train nerds somehow seem different and apart from the other transportation nerds.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: Right?
Scott: In some kind of way.
Scott: The
Rym: train nerds, what I find
Scott: is- I can't, it's like, it's hard to put my finger on exactly what it is because it's like, it's like there's people who make model airplanes, people who do model trains, people who go to the airport and watch planes take off, people who go to the train station and watch trains come and go, right?
Scott: It's like everything, there's no particular thing that you can say train nerds are doing that other forms of transportation nerds are not doing.
Rym: But yeah, if you add them all up, the train nerds stand apart and we all know this.
Scott: There's some sort of aesthetic and attitude and, you know, behavior of the train nerds that is different from the other transportation nerds.
Rym: One thing I noticed just as a kid because I was really into trains and one friend of the family, like one of the dads, he was one of those come into my basement train dads.
Scott: And he had the whole- I knew quite a few of those, two or three of them.
Rym: The whole basement set up and I was obsessed with it.
Scott: If I had a basement, there's a non-zero chance I would be that.
Rym: Non-zero, there is a one chance that I would have that.
Scott: Oh, wow, okay.
Rym: Because I had model, as a kid, I had HO gauge and I had a bunch of different gauge model railroads.
Scott: The tiny ones- And an oval on a flat board and it was kind of sad.
Rym: Oh, I had switching mechanisms and everything.
Rym: I had all these hardcover books on like train nonsense.
Rym: But one thing I like, one of the aspects of the train nerds that seems hyper specific focus is there's this extreme attention to detail that I don't see in those other hobbies.
Rym: Like extreme attention to detail in terms of period accuracy and operational and logistical accuracy.
Rym: Case in point, every train nerd, the highlight of their set up, if they're a basement train nerd with the basement set up, in my experience, I don't know if someone might correct me and they have a different experience, is the complicated switching mechanisms and showing off all the ways they can route the trains and simulate the real routing that happens in the real world.
Rym: Like activating and deactivating the switching and the signaling is something like most of the flight nerds I know don't hyper, like the flight sim people, they don't necessarily simulate the full ground control, air traffic control experience.
Rym: They mostly simulate the operating the plane experience.
Scott: No, there's those people who are online who are like pretending to be flight control.
Rym: There's a subset.
Rym: I would say that subset of airplane people are nearly identical to train people.
Rym: I just think in train nerdery, that type of focus is the majority, where in these other communities it's the minority.
Rym: That is a speculative guess.
Scott: Or maybe it could be because trains in the United States have fallen so far that the train nerds have, by and large, are more overlapping with historical things.
Scott: And even though there are, there are people who do the classic cars, there are people who do the old planes at the air show, right?
Scott: But I think maybe it could be that there's a great overlap of the train nerds with history, you know, as a percentage of train, a percentage of overall train nerds being historic train nerds, where I think a lot of car nerds are like modern car nerds.
Rym: But also you can make physical working model railroads with accurate switching and simulate a lot, a terrifying percentage of real world train stuff.
Rym: Can't really do that with cars or planes in your basement.
Scott: I think the other thing is that the train nerds also have an element of real world preservation, at least in the United States, of geographic places.
Scott: There might be an airfield here or there that someone is, you know, preserving and turning into a museum.
Scott: There might, you know, cars, like there aren't really planes, maybe an old racetrack or something here or there.
Rym: But go to any town that has a defunct railroad, there is a society of like three guys with beards who are dedicated to restoring it.
Scott: There are old stations and train tracks all over the place that have little foundations that are turning them into museums and preserving them and checking them out.
Rym: In Beacon, where we lived, there was, there used to be a hotel and a ski resort at the top of the mountain in Beacon, like in town.
Rym: And we go hike up there a lot.
Rym: There was also a railroad, an inclined railroad that went from Beacon, like downtown, up the mountain to this hotel.
Rym: And it was dilapidated, it went out of service in like the 50s and then some vandals burned it down, like what was left in the 70s.
Rym: While we were living there, there was a very vocal society of I'm pretty sure exactly seven men, all of whom had white beards.
Rym: And they were desperately, constantly, aggressively trying to raise money to rebuild that inclined railroad and then run it.
Scott: Right, because even though this collapse happened, the collapse was within the lifetimes of not slightly before our lifetime, but well within the lifetimes of many, many people who are still alive, right?
Scott: And, you know, still of sound mind.
Scott: And they're like, hey, I remember a time where there was all this awesome shit and all that shit is gone, right?
Rym: The metro north train that used to go from Beacon across into Connecticut was still active, while many people who are alive today, like they're still alive.
Rym: Like that was active in living memory.
Scott: Right, I mean, when you think about like us, like I guess, you know, in terms of our memory of the heyday would be like the 90s, right?
Scott: And it's like, but none of us are out there like, you know, bring back malls with all this garbage in them, right?
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: we have, you know, memories of that, of like a time where there were like these things that existed that were built up and awesome that then went away.
Scott: But if the things that we remember for the 90s being built up and awesome that went away were actually like useful things.
Scott: Right, like I would be, you know, if it wasn't shopping malls, I would be like, hey, you know, earlier in my life, shit was cool and that shit is all gone.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Here's something.
Rym: There's one thing from our childhood, arcades.
Rym: We are some of the, we're literally some of the youngest people who experienced an era where there were multiple arcades in every town.
Scott: Yeah, but the problem is, is like we sort of recognize that like bringing back arcades isn't really, you know, great.
Scott: It's not really worth trying to bring back and you couldn't bring it back in the way it was and just plenty of people are preserving the machines and we can set them up anywhere.
Scott: And like, that's fine.
Rym: But similarly, we don't want to bring back the trains from the 70s.
Rym: We want to make trains in 2022s.
Rym: I don't want to bring back the exact details of a 1989 arcade, but there's aspects of what happened in arcades and what those structures were that I want to reinvent and bring back.
Rym: What stops?
Rym: that is primarily, actually, I think the fact that the people who want those new experiences mostly live in cities and because of capitalism, it is literally impossible to pay the rent on the space you would need to have an arcade.
Scott: Arcade doesn't really make economic sense in most places.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: But if somehow you could have an arcade in Japan, you can see the arcades are closing.
Rym: If you could somehow have arcades even before the pandemic, they would be packed.
Rym: Look at Barcade, which kind of sucks because it's so loud and so crowded.
Scott: They make all their money from booze.
Scott: It's like, I don't make the money from the arcade games.
Rym: Also, people are packed for deep waiting in line to play.
Rym: They're desperate to play the games.
Rym: It's so packed.
Rym: You're trying to like shove your way.
Scott: They're just they're just drunk.
Scott: So they don't realize how crappy it is to play a lot of those games.
Rym: That's me at Magfest.
Scott: Or, you know, the games are there for the social aspect, right?
Rym: I just I really miss the social aspect of just playing competitive games with strangers in person.
Scott: Yeah, me too.
Scott: But I also miss, you know, you know, I guess I don't miss riding a train.
Scott: I just rode one.
Rym: But here I miss the Internet.
Rym: before spam existed.
Rym: That used to exist.
Scott: So there were no such thing.
Scott: At the end of the day, it was spam way before we got on there.
Rym: Well, depends.
Rym: So early email, I never got spam.
Rym: I didn't have any spam filters.
Scott: I got spam on AOL right away.
Rym: I didn't use AOL because I wasn't stupid.
Scott: Not like I was choosing the Internet service.
Scott: I mean, I got off AOL pretty quickly.
Rym: So I used burner AOL accounts with free trials to do shady shit.
Rym: But I never used AOL on purpose, for real, for anything other than shady shit.
Scott: That's what my family was using until I got my own computer in like '98, '99.
Scott: Then I got my own service from the phone company.
Scott: But even that, I got spam.
Scott: I got to RIT, got spam.
Rym: I remember RIT, I got my first spam email.
Rym: It wasn't until RIT because I reported it to RIT's IT department.
Rym: I forwarded it to abuse@rit.edu and I was like, "What the fuck is this email that came to
Rym: me?".
Scott: I had spam pre-RIT from non-AOL.
Scott: Anyway, trains are awesome and even in places that do trains right, at least there are some such places in the world, it's really like train is the way to go for a lot of things.
Scott: There's not enough train.
Rym: And if you're interested in what it could look like, not to build a new bullet train, we know what that looks like.
Rym: Actually, the president, Biden, has a proposal specifically for that.
Scott: Call it high-speed rail.
Rym: Yeah, well it's high-speed rail because there's different levels of rail.
Rym: Anyway, there is a real plan to build a train network in America that would transform American society.
Rym: It's being aggressively pushed by our president and one of our political parties, and being filibustered by the other political party.
Rym: But in New York City, there's some old freight rail that goes out through the back right corner of the city, like the back of Queens and down into Brooklyn.
Scott: It's more like the middle of Queens.
Rym: Yeah, it's not the back.
Rym: It's the part of Queens that does not have a lot of mass transit.
Rym: Like, subway stops are few and far between.
Scott: Anyway, they want to put trains on tracks that are just sitting there already.
Rym: So despite the facts...
Scott: You just have to do a little bit of work on it to hook them up to existing other places.
Rym: Yeah, the proposal is basically, "Hey, this old rail line would be really useful.
Rym: Why don't we just run, like put platforms on it, and run trains on it for
Rym: people?".
Rym: And early studies showed that even though this just is random freight track that already exists, and you can't really pick where it goes, like it's gonna go where it already goes, so it just picks this semi-random path through some of the outer parts of some of the outer boroughs, they estimate that its ridership would be huge, just because people are so desperate to be able to get places not in a car.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: In the end, trains are the best.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Cat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are A bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Krista Don, Chris Rymer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, Kishaya85, Rebecca Dunn, Reemie Bedwell, 34Cowers, Sam Erickson, Shervin Hurrell, Stop All the Downloading, Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is Spadina.
Rym: Spadina Station.
Rym: Several people whose names I won't say and I'm going to stop right now because very important hockey is imminently incoming, so I simply leave you with something you really should have seen coming.
Rym: My basement.
Scott: Go show your barbecue to the basement.
Rym: With a concrete floor, it's cool to the touch.
Rym: Turn off the heat, the heat's too much.
Rym: I turn on the light bulb, on the wire.
Rym: Turn on the dehumanifier, I'm serious.
Rym: When I flick this next switch, look you in the eye and I say, "Check
Rym: this.".
Rym: My trains.
Rym: I got smaller ones.
Scott: Tiny little trains.
Scott: I come down here just to get away.
Scott: My trains.
Rym: My trains.
Rym: It's like magic.
Rym: Magic trains.
Scott: I wish these trains could take me away.