Rym: It's Monday November 7th 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about the posse model.
Rym: publish on your own site syndicate everywhere elsewhere.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Oh, I guess it is elsewhere Just elsewhere.
Rym: Yeah, I say I say I should go for everywhere.
Scott: Good.
Scott: Good luck trying to get everywhere.
Rym: It's aspirational it's a should not a must in the RFC.
Rym: Okay, I Guess DST and Powerball are too good opening bits.
Scott: No power boss.
Rym: So there is a an old and ancient and Really bad logical fallacy.
Rym: It's sort of like a very specific and famous argument.
Rym: That is objectively wrong and easily defeated.
Rym: But it made is particularly popular in Christian circles and that is Pascal's wager.
Rym: You're unfamiliar with Pascal's wager The.
Rym: the idea is that either you in your life You have to bet and your bet is does the Christian God exist or not?
Rym: if you bet yes, and you're right Infinite reward, you know you go to heaven or whatever.
Rym: Yeah bet.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: No.
Rym: Well, you only lose a little bit.
Rym: You just died nothing.
Rym: But if you bet no and Right.
Scott: so that so, you're right.
Rym: so Oh Scott You can't hold it in.
Rym: anyone with even a small amount of logic immediately sees why Pascal's wager is a terrible logic experiment.
Rym: It is wrong from like 20 different perspectives.
Rym: It is disproven by a gentle grunt of anyone who knows anything about anything like Choosing to believe it and being wrong.
Scott: It's like oh you didn't lose much.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: I just spent my whole life praying and obeying these nonsense.
Scott: Huge cost that's a huge cost.
Scott: not a small cause but even worse.
Rym: and I think Homer said it best and I think season four The Simpsons I'll paraphrase him.
Rym: He said something like and what if we worship the wrong God?
Rym: Are we just making the real God angrier and angrier every day?
Rym: But Powerball the lottery right now.
Rym: Is that a Terrifying amount of money.
Scott: It is the biggest it's ever been.
Scott: It is one point.
Scott: the jackpot is 1.9 billion Dollars.
Scott: that obviously most places.
Scott: the taxes will be half and if anyone else wins well half again.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like Okay a billion dollars For we're going to at the a billion dollars, right?
Scott: How many billionaires are on earth?
Scott: How many billion more than you think but not that many.
Scott: the number that should exist is zero.
Scott: The number that do exist is about a thousand, right.
Scott: so We're gonna take at random complete random right.
Scott: Somebody who a is okay gambling, right?
Scott: That's something that right.
Scott: Yeah, B is in the United States or at least located in the unit, you know somewhere that they can buy a Powerball ticket.
Scott: Not Utah, Nevada.
Scott: I don't think they don't sell them there.
Rym: Yeah, there's like four states that don't allow it.
Scott: Yeah, someone who was basically within the past few days In a place where a Powerball ticket was for sale had two dollars chose to buy it.
Scott: One of those people will be randomly selected to become one of the thousand Wealthiest most powerful people on the face of the planet based on no merit or anything.
Scott: Now that is everyone who paid two dollars will be chipping in to help that person out now To make a modern Pascal's wager.
Rym: that is basically for all intents and purposes in a capitalist Hellward world an infinite reward like that is enough money even after taxes for someone who?
Rym: Gives a shit to change the world like that is good.
Scott: We could all get lucky right if this.
Scott: but the person who wins it happens to be a person like me Right who would try to fuck the?
Scott: you know, fuck the world in a good way Make things better or at least a tech, you know or succeed or fail.
Rym: You're gonna crack the world shell and you're gonna hope that there's something good in there.
Scott: Right, not just someone who's gonna live on a beach or in a Ferrari.
Scott: I mean that probably do those things too, but like not just only do those.
Rym: If I won like I'm gonna try to change the world but I'm also going to make sure I'm very comfortable while I do so like I'm gonna but Comfort can.
Scott: hopefully it won't be a person who's right.
Scott: Hopefully it won't be a person who squanders it.
Scott: It's easy to even that a ludicrous amount of money.
Scott: It is easy to squander it all quickly.
Rym: Yep, way easier Might have implied.
Scott: to those of you who even know what that is Yep, I mean, you know, but buy something large and it fails right, you know by an Be too generous with other people and then your whole family loots you and then that's it.
Rym: No, I did learn something recently.
Rym: There's I forget where it was might have been like the Atlantic but far clink to it.
Rym: It was a long article talking about the myth that most lottery winners end up destitute and ruined and destroyed.
Scott: They don't have destitute but a lot of them You know don't manage the money as well as they could and don't live a life of luxury as high as they could have lived.
Rym: Yeah, but a long form analysis showed that most lottery winners big jackpots actually do just fine and do just retire and live.
Rym: But the few who go out in a blaze of glory are the ones that everybody knows about and the media will talk about When they go out in their blaze of glory.
Scott: See, I said this elsewhere, but I want to say the person who is the luckiest person right now Right is not the person who buys a Powerball ticket and has a one out of 200 million something chance of winning All right.
Scott: Yeah It is the person who is a lawyer who is an expert on taking care of people who won the lottery.
Scott: because the odds are if When someone wins this which will eventually happen if not today then soon is going to call One of those few lawyers who is an expert on handling people or in the lottery or they aren't in which case Bring the popcorn.
Scott: if it's the kind of person who is not going to call one of those lawyers the billion will be squandered.
Rym: So here's a modern Powerball.
Scott: If I won I would be calling one of those people before I called any friend or family.
Rym: Yep, I would not type the words into anything Nor would I say it out loud because at that point you're in extreme danger.
Scott: Yep, I would call one of those lawyers make sure it's them visit not tell them anything till I visited them in person.
Scott: Yep They get get their advice before I even started to fill out a claim form to give you not Americans of the extent of this.
Rym: Danger like to be clear.
Rym: Lottery tickets in the US and the Powerball specifically is one that falls under this category are bearer Instruments meaning the law says whoever fucking has it right now is the lawful owner of it unless you can prove it was specifically stolen.
Rym: Yep, so, you know diehard Bearer bonds.
Rym: Yeah, there's a reason there aren't a lot of bearer instruments left on earth because they can be stolen.
Scott: Yep,
Rym: so my new Pascal's wager if the reward is infinite and the risk to you is Two American dollars it is unlikely that those two dollars Will round up to any meaningful change in your life Compared to even a one in 200 million chance of becoming one of the richest people on earth.
Rym: So I bought some Powerball tickets, I doubt I would like with that.
Rym: Yeah But one last time I think I think we're good.
Rym: I got a couple this time just in case the odds are you know, what?
Rym: The odd the like risk calculus is better than putting that money on red at a blackjack table or the blackjack.
Scott: Yeah, I mean sort of really think about it this way.
Scott: if you think about this way, right it cost two dollars, right?
Scott: It's the lot.
Scott: The jackpot is 1.9 billion Right, and it's a one out of 200 million something chance of winning.
Scott: Yeah, so if I mean there might be split winners or something or you know I or whatever.
Rym: but the odds of a split winner are higher because more people are buying tickets a lot more people.
Rym: That is why nobody has ever bought those numbers.
Rym: That is why nobody will buy all the numbers because it won't work out if anyone else wins.
Scott: Yeah, but even if you bought all the numbers right the if you just divide the jackpot by 200 million It comes out to like nine point five like ten bucks.
Scott: Yeah, so I mean that doesn't mean that like, you know, you spend two bucks.
Scott: You're gonna.
Scott: you're probably gonna get zero not ten, but yeah It's like it's in the realm where you know the.
Scott: it's like yeah.
Scott: Even though the odds of winning are so low the when the reward becomes high enough it starts to actually make sense Mathematically sort of.
Scott: yeah now that don't do not gamble.
Rym: that said lotteries should be banned.
Rym: We could we could take that money and pool it in a much more effective way.
Rym: It is called tech inherent right.
Scott: this thing that is happening right randomly giving a billion dollars To well have likely half of it to the government, which is fine, right taxes Yeah.
Scott: But giving the other billion dollars to a person at random that is not something that should ever happen in a functioning society.
Scott: Randomly us giving that amount of wealth to a single individual at least randomly is better than giving it specifically to a conservative.
Scott: Sure, but it might be a conservative person.
Scott: and then what yep It is it it's you know, if this is not a thing that should be happening at all Yeah, imagine locking a bunch of people in a room and randomly one of them will be handed a knife.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: That's the whole game.
Rym: You're locked in the room with them.
Scott: One person gets a knife We're locked in a country and one of these people will be given a billion dollars.
Rym: And also daylight saving time just happened and The problem is half our government actually did pass a bill to do the correct thing.
Rym: Go to daylight saving time.
Scott: Well stay there, right?
Scott: Well, they did it by accident.
Scott: Yeah, someone was literally a like not paying attention and that's how it snuck through.
Rym: the other half of our government won't touch it with a 10-foot pole because For reasons that we don't have time to get into.
Rym: because if they're actually hard to understand and it's not like we understand them Like it's not it's a complicated space.
Rym: America is divided about 50/50 on what to do about daylight saving time.
Rym: weirdly like a bunch of Americans really like the current system and don't want to change.
Rym: and It's the old sicko sign story and it doesn't even line up with our political parties at all.
Rym: Like it is almost a random distribution.
Rym: So it'll never happen because that's the kind of issue that our current government is incapable of talking out.
Rym: but there is news.
Rym: There's only one news today because it's the biggest news.
Rym: Twitter is not technically dead yet But goddamn is it moving faster than even I thought it would move toward actually dying for real?
Scott: Yep, after all the bullshit back and forth with you know musk face we talked about all this time.
Scott: Yeah in the end.
Scott: Well, it's that we there might still not be the end the end But there might be more developments in the legal front.
Rym: Yeah Right now all the desk got said eloquently before we started the show.
Rym: Most of the developments since the this dipshit bought Twitter have been that dipshit did something even worse than the last thing he did And they're like three of those stories per day.
Rym: So we're not gonna catalog them all right.
Scott: So sometime last week He actually had to go through with it and bought Twitter for reals and there are so many individual Addendums on to that of like.
Scott: what happened since?
Scott: firing people laying off people in mass laying off people but not giving the required 60 90 days notice is required by some states.
Rym: breaking laws firing executives who have golden parachutes and not you know losing the Person Twitter had that any advertisers trusted during an unrelated downturn in ad buying globally?
Scott: Yeah advertisers leaving Twitter on purpose.
Scott: people leaving Twitter check the validation verified system changing randomly Just all.
Scott: it's just Non-stop of it's like as soon as he bought it.
Scott: It's like every day something else on Twitter fucks the fuck up.
Scott: Right if you didn't, you know already understand how much of just yeah Ellen musk is not you know, people make him out to be like some sort of fucking genius.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: He effectively won a lottery because a lot of YouTube stardom a lot of tech pros especially white male ones.
Rym: Three the reason they have so much money is because they happened to work at the company that hit it big by accident.
Rym: Yeah, how many companies tried to build PayPal?
Rym: Do you have any companies tried to build Amazon?
Scott: Okay, so hold on.
Scott: so first of all, right Ellen Musk did just happen to be at PayPal and right but That's not why he's wealthy.
Scott: Oh, yeah his family His family owns emerald mines here, right?
Scott: Even if he said right there other people whose parents own diamond mines that you don't know about and they're living a filthy rich Luxurious life and they just keep their mouth shut and don't try to fuck with the world They're just evil on their own quietly, right?
Scott: This is just one asshole who had to be loud evil and stupid.
Scott: Oh, he's not he just he's not like some fucking genius, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you compare them to like Lex Luthor from comic books, which is somewhat apt but Lex Luthor Canonically in the DC Universe has the highest IQ of basically anyone in the entire universe human or otherwise.
Scott: Yeah, right He's like a mega genius.
Scott: He's just got other flaws like sociopathy Narcissism obsession with killing Superman.
Scott: It's all right, you know inferiority complex to Superman all kinds of other Emotional is mostly related to Superman Right.
Rym: Yeah, mostly which funnily enough gets down to what's a genius.
Scott: He's he can invent things.
Scott: Ellen Musk can't invent anything.
Scott: All he can do is hire someone to build a rocket.
Scott: He couldn't he wouldn't know what the top from the bottom if it was up to him.
Scott: He's basically got some bro.
Rym: He's got some of the power of a Lex Luthor, but none of the capabilities of a Lex Luthor, right?
Scott: He's just some bro.
Scott: not if you went to a college and just grab some bro from a like a from a frat who knew how to like, You know, it was at okay computer knowledge.
Scott: Like that's and you swapped him for Ellen Musk.
Scott: Give me the same fucking thing.
Scott: It's just some guy right?
Scott: Yeah, you know who had you know, is he?
Scott: is he a moron?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well in some ways.
Scott: Yes, but it's like he has about the same education we do right?
Scott: We're not geniuses or we can't win a fucking Nobel Prize or Fields Medal or anything, right?
Scott: So it's like, you know, but he's in charge of Twitter and unlike say SpaceX, right?
Scott: Oh, he's got his hand on the wheel of Twitter and he's crashing it On the wheel.
Rym: He is like fucking with the engine himself While it's driving down the highway.
Rym: Yeah, I mean dude is arguing with Stephen King like on Twitter about the $8.
Rym: is that Stephen King is like I'm not gonna pay you.
Rym: I'm just gonna leave.
Rym: and he's trying to argue with Stephen King like no you won't Like what who is even.
Scott: but it's funny that one of the wealthiest people right now and Musk has you know Many billions much more than this lottery.
Scott: All right Why does he get?
Scott: why does he need $8?
Rym: Yes, look from if I was a multi-billionaire the one thing I would not be doing is Personally arguing with dipshits online like.
Rym: that is the one thing you do.
Scott: that's time for that.
Scott: Who has time for that?
Scott: if you got if I won the lottery you probably never hear from me again.
Scott: Why would I spend my time?
Rym: That's my time.
Rym: I have my time.
Rym: I'd be running the board of like whatever charity I built to try to save the world.
Rym: the other half of I would be Paris key sale jumping.
Scott: Well, I wouldn't be doing that because that would be the end of the enjoyment of my billion dollars.
Scott: Good, you know, I'd be fucking you know, buying the government and turning it to the left.
Scott: I would if I bought Twitter, you know what I do.
Scott: I'd say, you know, it's free Nazis are banned.
Scott: No ads for anyone Yeah, etc.
Rym: I'm gonna run it.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I converted to a public benefit company.
Scott: He already converted to a private.
Scott: come it's not public anymore.
Scott: So he can do that now Really be a shareholder.
Scott: Yeah, you could say no more ads.
Rym: We're not even gonna try to make money We're just gonna make Twitter the best thing ever Except what he seems to be doing with it right now as of the news I just saw scrolling from making it the worst thing ever.
Rym: He's actively trying to get Republicans elected in our midterms tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know, it's a bad person.
Rym: Oh, so I guess that the threads because this conversation that people are having is so widespread Outside of my office.
Rym: there there's a chill homeless dude Like I know him but like he hangs out around our office and there's a cop who hangs out there.
Rym: I overheard while I was waiting for a traffic light to change today the two of them talking about what they're gonna do now that Twitter is Dead like I could not make this up.
Rym: That is the conversation they were having and the guy was like, you know The all my friend find it hard to believe.
Scott: the cop and the homeless person were talking and this was not a white cop.
Scott: About about anything.
Rym: this was not a white cop.
Rym: this cop is.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: I'm not saying this is a good cop But this is not a white say.
Rym: But I overheard this conversation.
Rym: like my mom was meshing to me like yeah What should I use cuz Twitter's dead?
Rym: Like I can't use it anymore.
Rym: Yeah, should I go to Mastadon or co-host or whatever?
Rym: But co-host is just a bunch of people.
Rym: all made accounts, but no one's posted anything.
Scott: as far as I can see I was making accounts at places to ensure that I have the account with my name on it.
Scott: I'm not using any place until I know it's the play the threads I can see that are sort of relevant.
Rym: this conversation is one the what is going to happen to the company which basically He's doing the inverse of basic management like dude fired everybody to the point that I don't know how the company will continue to operate.
Scott: I think it's just gonna.
Scott: it's basically.
Scott: I don't think it'll disappear and die.
Scott: It's too big and I still has too many people using it.
Scott: Probably some people aren't even aware or care about what's going on but I think it'll just recede like all the other.
Scott: many other social networks have where it's still a Platforms have where it still exists, but it has less users.
Scott: Pete less like like Craigslist is still out there even though it's been gutted Live journals still out there.
Scott: Tumblr is still out there.
Scott: People are going to tell her.
Scott: in fact, there's There's
Rym: a second question around the financial health of the company in that it costs a lot But it costs a lot to run it and You can't really just take your personal money and pump it in to keep it afloat Even run out of money eventually considering here.
Scott: Here is a dark you want to hear a really dark Prediction here.
Rym: I've heard a few.
Rym: it is it is public information Right that he was heavily financed by the Saudi Arabian and also there's Relatively breaking news that the US government is looking into the national security implications of that.
Scott: indeed, but the Saudi Arabians, you know are known for Using, you know violence on people.
Scott: Yep, if he beat billionaire of the world or not You know if he fails his if they if they don't do well financially on the Twitter That is uh, who know who knows what could happen?
Rym: that is not the darkest thing I have heard among by capital markets people.
Scott: I know surprisingly Dark as my brain.
Rym: Yeah, I There's some darker things about.
Scott: I'm not saying I want that to happen I'm just saying his personal life is in shambles independent of all this.
Scott: Well, that was always been the case.
Rym: Yep, so but there's a thread there of it might run out of operating capital because It was never running in a profit like it was always running at a loss.
Rym: But it was making a lot of money from advertising and it appears you just had right.
Scott: It's like if you're a start-up you have your money from you know Investors the VC people and then you have to get more rounds when you run out.
Scott: and that's your flow.
Scott: is investment.
Scott: Spend it investment spend it until revenues, right?
Scott: and even if you're not profiting the revenues can come in and you can spend them and you have this cash flow and you can Operate by spending the cash that people give you to buy your product and you can pay your employees and you can buy stuff Even though you know, the overall Treasury is slowly shrinking.
Scott: You can just keep operating Because there is fuel coming into the tank that will get burned, right?
Scott: It just might be burning it faster than it comes in but you know, eventually that stops working, but it still gives you runway.
Scott: Yeah, but so Twitter doesn't have investors really.
Scott: it was public and is now private.
Scott: So there's no cash flow coming from there.
Scott: and if investors pull out, it's like yes, they heavily decreased operating costs by laying off so many people but They could you know run out of fuel.
Rym: Yep, especially considering we know huge numbers of advertisers have quit now They probably don't care that much about like all the things he's fucked up.
Scott: Yeah, well and advertisers who have stayed might see that there's.
Scott: let you know Once the numbers have to cut, you know It's like he has to.
Scott: he doesn't have to reveal any numbers publicly because they're not public anymore.
Scott: But advertisers are gonna want to see proof.
Scott: right that you know user Registrations are up, but there's that there's a factor right now.
Rym: So remember the news we talked about the other day.
Scott: Google had the first drop in advertising revenue in the history of Google and that was Google who doesn't have a you know Some random CEO suddenly at the wheel driving into a wall.
Rym: Advertising buys on digital inventory are down across the board and companies are less Trustful or less credulous of the data they get from those companies.
Scott: So yeah, they're basically looking for numbers go down right and especially they come from him.
Scott: They're not trusted numbers.
Scott: The advertisers that stay are gonna want to pay less and they're gonna buy less if they stay at all.
Rym: and the ones that leave They're looking for any excuse to cut their advertising budgets because of the current economic climate.
Rym: Musk handed them an excuse to just say what cut it to zero and then they can go to their boss and say yeah I just saved us 15 million dollars a year.
Rym: What'd you give up?
Rym: Nothing?
Scott: Nothing is right.
Rym: So Twitter is a company might just collapse entirely.
Scott: independently of that There's a whole but could be a situation where once it's small enough someone else buys it for buys it low like the pinboard guy Bought delicious.
Rym: Yeah, I would love to buy Twitter But maybe if I went it'll still be too high for you to buy if I win that Powerball.
Scott: If you win the Powerball, you could buy it right now.
Rym: Yeah I feel like I feel like that train company.
Scott: It's ready for some shorts And see you you would wait for the last train to rust and then jump.
Scott: Yeah, there's no reason to do it now.
Rym: Yeah, it's probably still too high but Twitter's got like four to trains, but we are fast approaching the rust.
Rym: so there's also the threat of people who use Twitter as a source of journalism.
Rym: a lot of people go there to find out about the news and Mmm, there's really nothing normal people will use.
Scott: that replaces that And I think normal people don't even use Twitter.
Scott: normal people use other new like newspapers and TV.
Scott: You'd be shocked.
Rym: pretty much Twitter based on the data I was looking up over the last week because I've been following the whole downfall of Twitter.
Rym: other if you discount really old people and extremely conservative people a scary percentage of Americans go to like Google News or Twitter Or places like that or Facebook Tik-tok.
Rym: Yeah, take talk less.
Rym: So but it's self-reported data mostly.
Rym: So why mmv on that?
Rym: but the journalists are actually starting to leave the platform, which doesn't bode well, there's people who use it as a social network and They're all going to Mastodon like the people who care enough to leave.
Rym: that seems to be the primary Destination because it's the closest to what they think Twitter is.
Rym: Well, it's because it's the largest thing that exists already like I looked in a lot of the people I follow on Twitter who made Mastodon accounts are actually posting but the Mastodon interface kind of Sucks and I am NOT.
Scott: I am NOT going anywhere making it.
Scott: You can make whatever interface you want for it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I could but how are normal people gonna do that?
Rym: You'll they'll buy your interface on the App Store, I don't think normal people quite understand how it works.
Rym: So I'm not committing to any platform.
Rym: Like I just backed away from that kind of social media.
Scott: Talk about that in the main bit.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So but then there's all the like the ecosystem of indie creators who basically use Twitter for all their marketing because it's free and They're all sticking around these.
Scott: typically if you're a creator trying to market on the platforms you're posting to all.
Rym: Yep, the problem is a lot of them seem to get most of their traction from Twitter But I think everyone has a primary platform where they have most of their followers.
Scott: It's gonna be specific to them.
Scott: If someone was someone who you know had up the biggest following on Twitter and now Twitter is failing It's like yeah, it hurts them.
Rym: Yep And they got it.
Rym: you got it.
Rym: If you have if your primary following is on Twitter You got to do everything you can to build backup places for people to follow you and get them there.
Scott: I know that's that's isn't?
Scott: that's not different That's just you know, that's how it's always been right.
Scott: people who like, you know made.
Scott: I talked about this story so many times.
Scott: the company where all the company did was make a Visual Studio plugin and it's like the end game for them was either have Microsoft buy them or Microsoft add that feature to Visual Studio and their company goes out of business, right?
Scott: So it's like if you're.
Scott: if your business depends on someone else's business You basically have to a hope they don't fail be always stay in their good graces, right?
Scott: Etc.
Scott: You can't other.
Scott: you should be building your business so that it can stand on its own feet.
Scott: And if it if you're leaning on someone else and they fall down through even through no fault of your own Well, I mean I don't want to blame the victim but it that's just.
Scott: that's just business.
Rym: But I think I've noticed a lot of younger people who have not you like not been around.
Rym: I mean social media came into existence while we were already online Like we have been online for the entirety of the existence of the concept of social media Platforms geocities like aim everything all
Scott: the way that he had or cut accounts right on day one almost day one ish.
Scott: So I remember when Facebook was a new thing.
Scott: I had a Facebook account when it was college.
Rym: by the time Facebook came out I wasn't at college with the university email address anymore, and I couldn't sign up for it.
Rym: I Was working at IBM and I didn't have access to my old RIT email anymore.
Scott: My Twitter account is 15 years old.
Rym: Yep So but I think a lot of younger people or people who haven't been around this block I'd think they radically underestimate how quickly a Seemingly too big to fail platform can suddenly fail.
Rym: Like I don't think they realize how fast old platforms went from.
Rym: it'll last forever - there are 10 people left.
Scott: Well, I think we've gone through an extensive period.
Scott: like I said, the Twitter account is 15 years old, right?
Rym: So we've got used it longer than any social media platform.
Rym: I have ever used.
Scott: Alright, we've gone through a period where the sub the platforms that are big now have had a staying power of some sort even though I guess tik-tok's new and Whereas the period before then they were coming up and going down like every year a few years, right?
Scott: They were coming and going right and it's like.
Scott: I was always been of the opinion that like yeah, Google can fail one day.
Scott: It's like, you know, myspace looked unassailable right.
Scott: all these things Unassailable Right.
Scott: It's like it still exists, but it's small.
Scott: It's it's like I don't so I didn't.
Scott: I don't believe that anything is Unfailable.
Scott: right.
Scott: Facebook is dying.
Scott: Twitter is dying.
Scott: No, right, you know tik-tok can die.
Scott: I even believe YouTube can die.
Scott: I don't know what's gonna happen when it does.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I there's a reason I have a Vulnerable of everything I've ever uploaded to YouTube.
Scott: YouTube seems more invulnerable than anything that's ever been.
Scott: I'm confident that YouTube will die within my lifetime.
Rym: I don't know what's gonna look like, you know, one thing that I don't think could die is the technology part of Amazon.
Rym: I feel like it's so important that if it died a Consortium would either buy it or the government would nationalize or something would happen.
Scott: It would be - I'm talking about You know the yeah, you know user-facing like social media platforms.
Rym: if YouTube disappeared tomorrow, like it died tomorrow Instantly, I would not be as surprised as you would expect.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know people got to be prepared for that anyway.
Rym: But anyway things Of the day.
Rym: so, uh This is an algorithm that is actually near and dear to my heart for most of my life Because I was into audio and audio engineering like back and like playing with the reel to reels as a kid.
Rym: So the fast Fourier transform is So important to audio that talked about on GeekNights many times.
Rym: Yeah, it is one of the most important algorithms of all time.
Rym: It is used for like everything and Verisatium and I haven't really I checked.
Rym: I have not linked to them more than a handful of times over the long run of GeekNights, so I'm linking to them now only because this video was so good.
Rym: It is a half hour long and it is titled the most important algorithm of all time.
Rym: And it talks about not just how fast Fourier transform works where it came from Why it was so important compared to an actual Fourier transform like doing the full transformation Against a full data set.
Rym: But it gets into things that you probably never even thought this algorithm was in any way related to.
Rym: This is just a fantastic deep exploration of how important FFT is.
Scott: So Talk about some ROMs, right?
Scott: I don't know if anyone out there The listener has ever tried to play an arcade ROM and maim Yeah, but unlike say, you know, you might dump, you know, like an NES ROM, right?
Scott: It comes out as one file an NES file and that's it Right, and even though the NES cartridge might have multiple ROM chips in it You basically, you know, you read out the whole cartridge, right?
Scott: Yeah, that's it You know.
Scott: but for maim Right an arcade machine an old arcade machine is like a motherboard with a whole bunch of ROM chips on it like integrated.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: there's some I guess for neogeo.
Scott: There's gonna be a cartridge right I guess but for other ones not so much.
Scott: So you basically had to pop out all those individual RAM chips and You know, they're EEPROMs or whatever and read them individually and make a binary file for each one.
Scott: Alright, and it's like.
Scott: I never really thought about like, you know what it looks like when you try to like rip You know a ROM from an arcade board.
Scott: Alright, so this person here They happen to get an arcade board for a game called the gladiator some beat-em-up game and just coincidentally The board they had had version 1.04 of the game.
Scott: and it turns out that maim and you know If you go to you know, they had version 1.07 and they had like version 1.
Scott: Yeah, they didn't have any of these in-between versions and they were like, oh I got a version of an arcade machine That is not on maim that they didn't know about.
Scott: Alright, let me rip it and upload it and They had the hardware to do it and I was like, oh, so that's what that looks like that and it worked.
Rym: It's really cool.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: so now if you if you come across an arcade machine, what you should do is Check the version and then look on maim and see if you know that version is in the database.
Scott: And if it's not find someone who's got an EEPROM reader.
Scott: Preserve that.
Scott: that's slightly different version of the game.
Scott: but I thought was really interesting is that like there were a few different EEPROM chips in the on the board that they had to And all of them were basically identical to the ones that were already up there except for one.
Scott: So it was really just one chip had something a different code on it.
Scott: They needed to be modified.
Rym: So In the meta moment the GeekNights book club book is currently a leaf the unseen.
Scott: I wonder if I can even see this book.
Scott: I bought it Also You know, it's it's.
Scott: I guess it's what's a cyberpunk middle-eastern deal.
Scott: Rimsky out it from - I'll leave the unseen is a middle-eastern Choices of books from the same author who only has two books that aren't common a middle-eastern cyberpunk adventure.
Rym: I think Scott you wrote the words out our website.
Rym: that description alone is enough to convince me to read it and that is correct.
Scott: Well, yep.
Scott: I think that's probably what made me add.
Scott: It's my wish list in the first place.
Scott: Yep Also previous book club book city we became well just like the other day like maybe less than a week ago the book the sequel book world we made.
Scott: Also band K. Jemisin was released.
Scott: so you can now read that book.
Scott: Although it is not the book club selection We might do an episode on it.
Scott: That's not a book club episode.
Rym: I think it might be worth it.
Rym: That series is a very speaks to us shall we say.
Scott: it's getting red though Absolutely, I got.
Rym: I got to know what happens with that horrible island.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah All right.
Rym: Otherwise, uh, of course I have just left Twitter entirely but it underscores how deeply Twitter got its tentacles into everything that the streaming template that the 14 people watching the stream are seeing still has both of our Twitter handles in it Despite the fact that I have literally deleted the Twitter app.
Rym: I gotta fix that at some point.
Scott: is the same handle on every platform?
Scott: true I'm not.
Rym: I don't actually use this handle on many places.
Rym: I use this on Twitter a long goddamn time ago But I actually go by GeekNights' Rym or just Rym.
Rym: on most other platforms Shazar is kind of a.
Scott: you should have gone by the same name everywhere then it's much easier.
Rym: Well, the problem is I tried to but thrill house was taken on most platforms.
Scott: That's a prize.
Scott: Not my fault.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So otherwise if you have fled Twitter like us The best place to talk to us is our own forum.
Rym: the GeekNights' forum is rocking and I'm spending more time in there.
Rym: It's cool place.
Rym: Also.
Rym: There is a GeekNights' discord.
Rym: There's cool people in there.
Rym: cool stuff happens in there.
Rym: Uh Otherwise, I don't know if email us like email still works.
Rym: Email is adjacent to social media and I still have a Google account.
Rym: So I guess there's that.
Scott: hmm, yeah, so You know in the wake of Twitter dying, right?
Scott: We have to discuss.
Scott: You know, what?
Scott: What do we do now?
Scott: Right and it's like You know for the longer for GeekNights' entire existence, right?
Scott: We've done a pretty good job of Somewhat strictly following what's known as what.
Scott: I didn't realize it had a name.
Scott: I was just following it without knowing it had a name.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I similarly I always just thought of it as why doesn't everyone do this?
Scott: It makes sense Right the way we used to do things which is the posse model Right, and it's called posse because it stands for publish on your own site POS, right?
Scott: syndicate elsewhere se right and the idea is You are going to put out some something you've made on to the internet so that other people can see it be it text video audio Video game, you know PDF file, whatever some data you want to put it out there in the world, right?
Scott: So you could And what people mostly do these days is go to a platform, right?
Scott: Maybe it's a photo and they put it on some photo site like smug mug or flicker or yeah Graham.
Scott: Maybe it's a video and they upload it to YouTube or Vimeo.
Scott: Maybe it's a short text and they put it on Twitter or Somewhere else like that if it still exists.
Scott: Maybe it's a long text and they put it on.
Scott: they have a blogger or the wordpress.com or you know Anywhere right.
Scott: this does, you know, you can cross it all, you know, they got a music and they put it on SoundCloud, right?
Scott: and What inevitably happens is those places die they shut down they do copyright takedowns.
Scott: They do right You know, they delete accounts.
Scott: people get banned.
Scott: people, you know They're they.
Scott: people get angry because they're their posts got blocked or people, you know, it's like yeah, you're posting on someone else's Platform, right?
Scott: They don't have no obligation to host you.
Scott: They're doing it because they want to make money and if they don't want you there they kick your ass out.
Scott: Yeah, you come over to might invite you into my house.
Scott: And if you behave poorly for any reason I kick your ass out.
Scott: Don't come back.
Rym: That's how it works.
Rym: All right, and Twitter is actually a place where I got very lazy about this because originally Twitter I treated as ephemeral media.
Rym: I treated Twitter the same way.
Rym: I would treat like an IRC channel or like a chat on a like a Google something like I'd like to have an archive of it but I didn't treat it as publishing content so much as like ephemerally having conversations online, but over time me and many people evolved to Creating primary content directly on Twitter and I realized thinking about it now with this model.
Rym: The only other time I've ever done that is when I briefly used tumblr and I made content on tumblr and I did not put It anywhere but tumblr and that tumblr lasted about 20 posts before I gave up on it.
Scott: So what we used to do back in the day the posse model is instead of publishing any of your shit on these other Platforms and where it's subject to who knows what problems right you publish your shit on your own Site.
Scott: you make a website a home page.
Scott: We called it home pages because that was your home on the internet.
Scott: if anyone wanted to find your shit They would had to come to you.
Scott: Yeah, I'd your shit that you published yourself.
Scott: No one can take your shit down.
Scott: It's your website as long as your entire website isn't taken down by your hosting provider.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, which is pretty rare, right?
Scott: It's like I'm sure even Nazis can you know, usually sometimes get away with hosting somewhere in some country.
Scott: Yeah It's like you're you're good.
Scott: It's like, you know You don't have to worry about some YouTube copyright bullshit.
Scott: if you publish the videos on your own website, someone could come and sue you directly, but It's probably not gonna happen because how are they gonna find your videos?
Rym: Yep So imagine I don't know a long-form content in a tweet like a tweet thread or something and then the where we got lazy I would just buy would just make a Twitter thread and that's it.
Rym: That's the only place that exists and then it gets taken down and I'm screwed.
Rym: So instead I post on my own site.
Rym: It doesn't matter how I could be a microblog.
Rym: Who cares?
Rym: I put that content here from recruit comm Slash blog like to forex time some URL.
Scott: that is your URL a URL that you control where the official Original version of that content is posted and always available as long as you can keep that website up.
Scott: Rym comm slash Rym's tweet.
Rym: Yep, so then how do people find it?
Rym: because the a lot of the times the reason people start using about discovery later.
Rym: yeah, well in terms of syndicate elsewhere means I post here on my website, but I cross-post from my website to all the other places.
Rym: I want this content to appear and more importantly I Link back to my own website if you keep its pot if it's feet.
Rym: There's a lot of edge cases in like two-way communication and like reply.
Rym: There's a lot of nuance we can get into but the idea is my kind of my tweet post.
Rym: Yeah, my blog post is on my website.
Rym: My blog post is also on Twitter with a link back to my website.
Rym: My blog post is also I don't know on Instagram as a photo with a link back to my website.
Rym: Let's say the tweet gets taken down.
Rym: Well people can still find the URL to my site and the Instagram.
Scott: It's on on your discord server.
Scott: There's a link to your blog post.
Scott: Maybe the entire text gets copied there in a.
Rym: in our worst case I make a torrent that within I make a distributed torrent.
Rym: That is just a URL linking to my post in a text file like.
Rym: there's ways to get it out there.
Scott: Still use right.
Scott: other people are not going to.
Scott: you know, noticeably, you know Necessarily know your website or come to it on purpose, right?
Scott: They want to use the systems that they use.
Scott: Maybe someone out there wants to use an RSS reader.
Scott: Well good.
Scott: You have an RSS feed, right?
Scott: You know, whatever someone wants to use you just make a link or a complete copy of your content with or without a link.
Scott: Right and you post it on every other platform automatically, but your own website is the original source for that content and you just keep it up and you don't let it go.
Scott: and That's that.
Scott: and that's the rest the way GeekNights has always done it.
Scott: We did all of our Content and podcasts on our website that no one goes to.
Rym: every URL Thanks to a lot of hard work by Scott is still valid to this day.
Scott: Yeah, it's a huge.
Scott: That's part of the new website trouble trying to keep all these URLs working.
Rym: I mean what 95% of all our thing of the day links are broken.
Scott: You know, we're working on that too.
Rym: Yeah, you know who else did this?
Rym: very well the same model.
Rym: They followed it up until they didn't and them not doing it destroyed them College Humor.
Rym: College Humor followed that model Religiously and I credit that as a big part of their success.
Rym: screw attack originally was like that too But then in the pivot to video they ended up putting their content primarily on platforms and then those platforms fuck them over.
Rym: But they'd already sent their audience to those platforms.
Rym: So no one even knew to go back to their website and they were done.
Scott: Yep So, you know, this is basically if you are a publisher of content This is the right way to do things.
Scott: if you're a reader of content Well now we have problems right because who's gonna actually go to all these different fucking websites, right?
Scott: It's like if you think about all the stuff that you're looking at on your your feeds that are automatically collated for you.
Scott: All right, it's like unless all these websites out there make RSS feeds the right way, you know And even then it's like you're not gonna be able to you know Go and collect all of these into one place to read them all easily Right.
Scott: So, you know, I guess you're just hoping that people all use.
Scott: I guess You know if you you pick your platform of say Instagram and you hope that everyone you care about following is cross posting there, right?
Scott: Automatically somehow, you know, it's it becomes a huge pain visiting websites.
Scott: is you know time-consuming to even remember webkit?
Scott: You know, I tried web comics back in the day.
Scott: web comics are the ultimate at following the posse model.
Scott: They almost right they were pretty much all of them posted on their own site and syndicated elsewhere.
Scott: until the past You know few years they started posting only on you know, the platforms directly.
Scott: Yeah But it's like I want.
Scott: you know There were people who try to make web comic aggregators because the web comics are really bad about making it easy to read all the web comics at once.
Scott: and now you've got shit like webtoon and it's like people just post a comic on webtoon and If something happens to webtoon all those comics are gone.
Rym: I think a lot of that Again.
Rym: Why did people like shut down RSS feeds?
Rym: like.
Rym: why did RSS feeds as we knew them back in the day mostly die?
Rym: Because if anyone looks at your content via an RSS feed They didn't see the ads that you were using to make money because no one has any other way to make money with anything online.
Scott: Yep How was that?
Scott: People blame like.
Scott: the death of Google Reader is like the death of RSS and it's like.
Scott: no there were still plenty of other.
Scott: reader Software is available at the time, right?
Scott: Yeah, the death of RSS was because there was other ways to get a feed of data that appeared.
Scott: You know, when did?
Scott: when did Google Reader shut down?
Rym: I would argue that the death of That kind of syndication as platforms move toward aggressive ad monetization is why Google Reader died and not the other way around.
Scott: Yeah, Google Reader ended in In 2013.
Rym: oh my god, I just turned into a skeleton hearing that year right.
Rym: Twitter started in 2006 right and remember for the first couple years It was like SMS only and there was an iOS app that kind of worked and that was it didn't even work Android yet The point is by 2013, right?
Scott: What was it that killed Google Reader?
Scott: It wasn't right.
Scott: It wasn't the fact that you know Google think like RSS didn't die because Google Reader shut down.
Scott: It's they shut down Google Reader because Twitter was here, right?
Rym: that's why there was nothing for any RSS feed aggregator to look at anymore.
Rym: like everyone shut down their RSS feeds or They reduced their RSS feeds to contentless links back to the platform.
Scott: They posted to Yep Which I guess web scraped but I suppose I mean there are still RSS readers out there.
Scott: I still use one.
Scott: it still works right, but you know, you can't Some of them like.
Scott: let you incorporate, you know, Twitter's and reddit's and all these sorts of things.
Rym: I feel like we did a GeekNights episode when Google Reader died Explaining that Google Reader did not kill RSS by dying.
Rym: Google did not kill RSS capitalism did but that episode was probably a long time.
Scott: Well, the other thing is that you know, if your people post on the platforms, right?
Scott: It's like well the platforms aren't gonna make RSS because then they lose all their value, right?
Scott: It's it's like why would anyone go to Twitter if Twitter had an RSS feed for every single Twitter account?
Rym: I would now?
Rym: I would never.
Rym: I would literally just have an ad free RSS feed Interlinking Twitter with all the other shit.
Rym: I read I wouldn't even know that content came from Twitter.
Scott: Then all the plat.
Scott: if this RSS or anything like it all the platforms just become dumb pipes They don't.
Scott: they don't have any way to make money or extract value or anything.
Scott: They're just dumb pipes sending feeds of data, you know between people's.
Scott: everyone would choose whatever client software for reading they liked the most and choose whatever software they like for publishing the most and Publish anywhere and read anywhere and all the different services would just be you know Funneling that data around and that would be it.
Scott: and they know they don't want that to happen, right?
Scott: That's why they won't let everyone like use the Twitter API unlimitedly even though it's like Why not?
Scott: I can the only even if the only functions I could do with the Twitter API are the same Functions that I could do with a Twitter client.
Scott: They can't allow that because being able to automate those functions Means I don't have to go to the Twitter website or see the ads or etc.
Rym: Etc, right?
Scott: hmm Anyway, so I think the thing is if the whole world were to do everything the way we say right with it with a posse Model, right?
Scott: First of all, all the services become dumb pipes like we just said.
Scott: right but the real problem is Discoverability, right?
Scott: So it's like, okay if you stick with one platform Right, the platforms have many ways to sort of over solve the problem of discovery, right?
Rym: I would say that it's not even over solving.
Rym: the platforms have a vested interest in Keeping you on the platform and tailoring the platform to you to make sure you never go to any other platforms, right?
Scott: So it's like if you go to Twitter, you know They start suggesting people to follow and you know YouTube is showing you videos from channels that you don't subscribe to and You know They're trying to get you to put your contacts in to help you find your friends and they're showing Tweets your friends liked or tweets your friends retweeted or you know They're always trying to show you some kind of content.
Scott: That isn't just the content you follow Explicitly and nothing else which is what RSS does.
Scott: Yeah, it goes.
Scott: so It's like it's hard not to discover new content because it's just being shoved in your face because that's how they keep you there.
Scott: That's how they make money right?
Scott: if everyone has just got their own websites, right?
Scott: Forget the problem of the technical difficulties of normal people not being able to host their own websites.
Scott: It's like how do you find shit?
Scott: Well, Google Google is how you find shit or I could see one.
Rym: we would have an industry arise around Curation.
Scott: people would seek out the people who were good at telling them what to look at And I don't think so because that would have happened back in the day and it didn't.
Rym: yeah, I saw it happen.
Rym: hmm, I Also think you would see companies could try to make meta algorithms that try to do try to find good content Across all the platforms for target to do that and probably charge subscription fees for that.
Scott: Hmm I think the real end result is is a good result, which is that like?
Scott: yeah Discovering new things would mean explicit effort on the part of the reader as opposed to advertising or other push-based things Intruding like.
Scott: I support order for your feed to get more full of data.
Scott: you would have to go out and explicitly find a thing that you liked and intentionally and Only and then you would see more of that and that only and giving us, you know the pull instead of the push.
Scott: No one's pushing content on you.
Scott: You are choosing what to see and not seeing anything else.
Scott: Yeah And therefore you're seeing less.
Scott: everyone to be seeing less.
Scott: a lot less spending a lot less time doom scrolling on their phone Spending a lot less time reading fake news or whatever other nonsense, right?
Scott: It would just be better, right?
Scott: We don't know we're reading too much shit.
Scott: It's like the you know, yeah have gone through even before all these, you know collapses that are happening.
Scott: I went through all of my you know, social, you know platform things.
Scott: I Deleted slash uninstalled several of them.
Rym: Yeah, I did.
Rym: I would like semi-annually do a big purge of all the things I followed all the things I use.
Scott: I would delete apps all the all the ones that I kept using.
Scott: I'm still got Twitter here.
Scott: I've unfollowed Unfollowed like 33% of the people I was following on Twitter and then I unfollowed again 33% more.
Rym: It's actually I straight-up deleted the Twitter app, but I mean this was you know while ago Yeah, but now like everyone like once a day.
Rym: I look at it But like I'm dropping other platforms to not just Twitter, even though there's nothing wrong with those platforms They're not really doing anything useful for me, right?
Scott: There were people that I was following and I looked and I said I see that person.
Scott: I did follow them with intent.
Scott: Yes, I enjoy what that person does.
Rym: I like that person.
Scott: I like that person and then I look at the content that they're putting into the feed and I'm like is This content that they're putting into the feed.
Scott: Is this really do I need this in my life?
Scott: Am I personally?
Scott: Getting value, you know, even if I love this person am I getting value from this information?
Scott: This is information that I need to know right?
Scott: that helps me in my life.
Scott: That's important, right?
Scott: Is it even entertained like, you know, yep, like it could be.
Rym: do I want or entertaining enough?
Rym: Does it make me smile?
Rym: Does it make me smile enough?
Rym: Like there's a lot there.
Scott: It's like a lot of it.
Scott: It's like yeah, it may have at one point, but it doesn't anymore.
Scott: It's like only get.
Scott: why am I spending time in my short short life on it?
Scott: Get it out of here, right?
Scott: It's like sorry.
Scott: Bye, you know, and I think a lot of people are not doing this but a change of you know The dynamics of the platforms could force people to do that and we bet be better for a lot of people Probably improve the world this way.
Scott: so Yeah, if you're publishing I highly recommend right, you know following the posse model that GeekNights has mostly strictly followed to its benefit because it's not suffering at all and Personally, I did not follow strictly enough.
Scott: But now having learned the lesson of being alive to see so many platforms fail I will now follow.
Scott: I'm gonna work towards following that policy very strictly with myself Personally and with GeekNights for the rest of my life and it won't matter to me when platforms come and go.
Scott: I think both of us syndicating to them or not.
Rym: Twitter was the one we both got the laxest with like.
Rym: that was the one Tumblr.
Rym: a couple dozen posts is all I made there.
Rym: That's no big loss.
Scott: But Yeah, and then if you are a reader right what I would suggest you do is You know, you're gonna have to choose, you know for yourself, right?
Scott: Which platform is the one that has the most like nicest reading experience for you?
Scott: or you know?
Scott: Think about who you're gonna fall.
Scott: Don't worry about what platform they're on.
Scott: think about who and what you really care about.
Scott: That's really important in your life that you need to follow and know about and then you know You're gonna have to find some balance between you know Seeing where those people or organizations or groups are publishing and syndicating to and you know what platforms you're willing to participate in in order to get at what they're publishing and Maybe have to miss some people that you care about.
Scott: maybe you have to add a platform that you read from that you don't really like.
Scott: but the people you care about are on there and You know, hopefully enough people that you follow will follow the posse model, right?
Scott: We'll publish and syndicate to enough platforms to give you know.
Scott: That's like I'm just publishing.
Scott: to all these platforms at least ones.
Scott: I find acceptable.
Scott: it's like I'm gonna give the people who care to hear what I have to say as much choice as I can give them in terms of you know, how they want to follow me and then you know It'll be up to them.
Scott: and I think it's like I don't want.
Scott: you know A lot of people out there are trying to get followers, right?
Scott: It's like I don't think that's not gonna work and that's good.
Scott: I think that that's not gonna work, right?
Scott: it's like I only want someone following me if for some reason I don't can't explain.
Scott: they Really really enjoy whatever hearing what I have to say.
Rym: Yeah, but this will have a lot of consequences that are probably unavoidable.
Rym: for example A lot of indie creators reach their audiences by putting their like links to their store Interleaved with their regular social media content.
Rym: But yeah A lot of people in the post Twitter world might just decide they don't want to see the store links so they just won't see that person's content anymore like I think we're gonna see a lot of.
Rym: This is gonna be a very big impact on how people use the internet over the coming year.
Rym: Yeah, you know, it's like if you're it's the biggest platform to fail in a long time.
Scott: We talked about that, you know with the with you know, I said the visual studio plug-in story.
Scott: It's like yeah, if you were depending on platforms that are failing to make your monies and Those platforms are failing.
Scott: It's like yeah, that's that's what happens You know, it sucks because most of those creators are decent people doing good works, right?
Scott: And you know, they're gonna make less money is just because the place that they were using to.
Scott: you know publish about themselves is failing but But it implies something.
Rym: Patreon goes down if it implies something that we've talked about when we've talked about advertising Many times over the years.
Rym: There are a lot of people who if they are presented with like an ad Even if it's a subtle ad like a friend posting in their stream to a store link or something they can buy They might just buy it Whereas if that had not been pushed in front of them They would not have sought it out and bought it on their own.
Rym: that sale was predicated on putting it in front of them Against their sort of explicit intention to see it Exactly, right.
Scott: if you made for example Let's say indie video games, right?
Scott: So it's like you go to itch IO and I guess itch IO does sort of try to suggest games to you.
Scott: I mean steam tries to suggest games to me Sure, but let's imagine, you know an itch IO equivalent right where you only see games from people you follow and that's it right.
Scott: and So it's like you're only gonna buy a game if you are somebody who cares enough to even go to this website.
Scott: You care enough about playing and buying indie games that you're gonna become a member of this indie game specific site, right?
Scott: You're gonna follow people so that you learned about somehow right that you you like them enough that you've sought them out and click to follow button and You visit the website enough and frequently enough and on top of that The thing they make has to catch your eye in your feed and make you want to buy it enough, right?
Scott: Whereas you know, it's like that's sort of actually the right way that things should be done.
Scott: You shouldn't be buying something unless you really care about it that it's like.
Scott: to that extent, you know.
Scott: Yeah, but the way things are now it's like okay you live your life on Twitter where there are many people that you know You're following for various reasons, right?
Scott: Some of them might retweet shit from someone you don't even follow right and you're following that person.
Scott: Maybe you know, they don't think like that's a person that using my requirements you I wouldn't even follow them.
Scott: And there's they retweet something that gets in the feed and there it is along with everything else and it catches your eye And you end up buying it.
Scott: It's like maybe that was a valuable thing, right?
Scott: Maybe you did discover something you never knew about and that brought You know improved your life or and brought you joy and you wouldn't have had it without this right and that's that's a good thing right, but maybe because of you know, you got you ended up buying something because you know ads work and human psychology and this thing popped up and You know took your money impulse buy and it sat on your shelf and you never cared about it.
Scott: It's just there right?
Scott: It's like you shouldn't have bought that.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: Yeah And that's you know, and then so I think will the world be better, you know with the more stable Only buying things that you it's bad for the economy.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: overall Yeah, I mean capitalism as it is is one of the underlying causes of us even having this entire conversation today.
Scott: Well, it's the entire cause of everything.
Scott: Yeah, at least if the society is capitalist then yes, everything is capitalist.
Rym: You know all this implies to me is you should probably play disco Elysium.
Rym: That's all I'm gonna say about that.
Scott: Yeah, I'm tired of people trying to push on me What content I should be playing?
Scott: Not pushing on you.
Scott: Yeah, you are.
Scott: if I want to play something I'll explicitly go and follow the company that makes them And then I'll decide for myself if I like what I see.
Rym: I bought it cuz it was on my crazy super sale and I'd Been wanting to buy it for a long time.
Scott: Ah So something got popped up in the feed.
Rym: Well, it was.
Rym: I had already wanted to buy it chosen.
Rym: I want to play this game, but It costs more money than I was willing to pay.
Rym: because you know We're both following the rule of never buy again on steam game on steam unless you're gonna play it right the fuck.
Scott: now I'm just trying to tie into the real world.
Rym: example Speaking of tying into the real world right now is where the ad read would happen in a normal podcast.
Rym: But we don't do that shit and I'm hungry.
Rym: So I think we should end the show.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce link Gigi dread lily tenebrae one bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: case care makes music.
Rym: Chris had died.
Rym: Chris Rhymer Clinton Walton deaths Finn Joel Hayes Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin van Holl.
Rym: Stop all the downloading.
Rym: the next station is York University York University Station and a bunch of people who are giving us the bare minimum or just don't want us to say their name.
Rym: Yeah, we're done with Twitter as you might have inferred from this episode.
Rym: So I encourage you to join the GeekNights forum and the GeekNights discord.
Rym: We got good stuff going on in there But for not for tonight since Scott will never take any suggestion to play read or watch anything From any human being that he has ever met in person.
Rym: I simply leave you with The lieutenant nods gravely as you erect tariffs against his apricots and sugar.
Rym: This is going to get ugly With every turn tariffs are raised until neither you nor the lieutenant are producing any income or generating resources for the suzerain Even in the best of cases.
Rym: It's impossible to really win a trade war.
Rym: But this is far from the best case and the lieutenant's apricot powered economic engine crushes yours Soon.
Rym: your covers are empty and the map lies strewn with your worker tokens.
Rym: I hope you learned your lesson.