Rym: It's Wednesday, June 1st, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: It's an anime, manga, comics, cartoons, news, round up!
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: No one's watching any animes or reading any comics these days, so...
Rym: I am watching a lot of cartoons.
Rym: I'm watching The Owl House, Lower Decks.
Rym: Season 2 is going to come out soon again.
Rym: There's Season 3, I guess, at this point.
Rym: I actually, of all things, I've started watching Bob's Burgers and I've watched a bunch of it.
Rym: I've got a lot to say about it now that I've seen more than, like, handfuls and snippets of it.
Rym: But I'll get to that in the news because there's a news related to Bob's Burgers.
Rym: that is timely.
Rym: But I guess before we get into the news round up, you know, we'll still do things of the day and everything else.
Rym: And the only thing I can talk about that's happened to me is the Stanley Cup somehow continuing for us.
Scott: So the listener is going to have to hear from us about ice hockey in June.
Rym: I appreciate the one listener who was like, "You guys really didn't talk a lot about the hockey even when the playoffs were
Rym: happening.".
Rym: And then suddenly you're talked about a lot.
Rym: It's like, yeah, I cannot express how excited I am that the Rangers are this far because no universe did I expect this or even, like, hoped that hard for this.
Rym: I was just happy to make it to the playoffs.
Scott: Right, expectations have already been exceeded, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, I went to Thanksgiving dinner, I'm full, we already even ate pie, like, it's over.
Scott: Someone comes in with, like, a whole other whole ass turkey and it's just like, what the fuuck.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: At this point anything can happen.
Rym: Like, playoffs when you get deep, there's only-- basically, what we're seeing now, like, I watched the other game last night, too, which was ridiculous.
Scott: - I watched part of it, yeah.
Rym: - Yeah, I didn't watch the third period, but I should've, I guess.
Rym: So, we're now watching the four best ice hockey teams on earth playing hockey.
Scott: - That's not necessarily true, right?
Rym: - I think that's pretty necessarily true.
Scott: Who would win, right?
Scott: You know, I guess last year's Tampa Bay Lightning.
Rym: Oh, the teams that are currently active with current rosters.
Rym: We're not talking about the greatest hockey teams of all time.
Scott: - Or, like, Canada national team from last year.
Rym: - I think any of the four teams in the current Stanley Cup playoffs could beat any national team.
Scott: The problem is-- - If you made just a team of the best players from all of Canada, they couldn't beat an NHL team that has a salary cap?
Rym: - I don't think so.
Scott: Primarily-- - That's not even a question.
Scott: The Canadian team would blow them out.
Rym: - I don't think so, actually.
Rym: Because that team does not exist as the same cohesive unit in the same way?
Rym: Long enough that-- I mean, it's moot, because we can't test this, because any NHL team has, like, people from these other teams.
Scott: - Do you think the Colorado Avalanche from this year could beat the Eastern Conference All-Star team from this year?
Rym: - Honestly, Conference All-Star teams I don't think are actually that great.
Rym: But to have that-- this should be a Tuesday show, actually.
Rym: I have a lot to say, and I was about to say way too much and make the show go on way too long about hockey.
Rym: Let's have that conversation not a Tuesday.
Scott: - The point is that there's only four hockey teams left.
Scott: There is exactly one hockey game every night for the next couple, few weeks.
Scott: - But the funny thing-- - 8 p.m.
Scott: Eastern New York time.
Scott: - So, based on, you know, the NHL-- - And half of them involve us.
Rym: - The last thing I'll say, the NHL, for those of you who don't pay attention to ice hockey, what I'll say that's relevant is this.
Rym: It's broken up in divisions, and those divisions are part of conferences.
Rym: There are two conferences.
Rym: Roughly, it's the Eastern United States and the Western United States.
Rym: - Also Canada.
Rym: - Yeah, also Canada, which this year actually matters, unlike previous, relatively recent Stanley Cup playoffs.
Rym: But right now we're in a situation where, generally speaking, one of those conferences has very high-scoring games, and one of those conferences has shockingly low-scoring games.
Rym: So the Stanley Cup final might be a team that can easily score six or seven goals in a game versus a team that has a goalie who could make enough saves to make that game turn into a one or two goal game.
Scott: - Yep, but it means that right now we're not in the finals, we're in the conference finals, the semi-finals, if you will, and right now you have two teams that score a bunch fighting against each other.
Scott: So two unstoppable forces opposing each other, and then on the other side you have two immovable objects opposing each other.
Rym: The Rangers and the Tampa Bay Lightning.
Scott: - You're gonna have the stronger of the two unstoppable forces against the stronger of the two immovable objects in the final battle.
Rym: - This is not just because the Rangers are in the conference finals, which even they didn't think they'd get this far because they had a trade they made where they have to give up a better draft pick if they make it this far.
Scott: - Yeah, but they interviewed Drury, the GM, the World Series champion Chris Drury.
Scott: In the interview they were like, "Oh, you had to give up the draft
Scott: pick.".
Scott: He's like, "Yeah, okay, whatever.
Scott: I'm okay with
Scott: that.".
Rym: - Well, think about it.
Rym: If you make that trade, your thinking is, "There's no way we're making the conference finals.
Rym: And if we do, I don't give a fuck how we got
Rym: here.".
Scott: - That's right.
Scott: You made it so he doesn't give a fuck.
Rym: - But this is one of the better playoffs I've seen in a long, long time.
Rym: Not just because the Rangers are in it because I watch the playoffs every year, but this has been some really fantastic hockey just across the board.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So my thing of the day is a 15-minute video.
Rym: And this channel is actually really fun.
Rym: It doesn't judge the people who come in.
Rym: I want to get back to that.
Rym: It's called Just Rolled In.
Rym: And the conceit is, this is a mechanic and a car just rolled into the shop.
Rym: And they take a look at the car to figure out what's wrong with it.
Rym: It just rolled in.
Rym: And this channel has one, like they have a bunch of different series, but within the channel, the one series that I'm linking to, and this is a best of from 2021 to really seal the deal, is the Customer States series.
Rym: Meaning the car rolled in and the customer says, "This is why I'm
Rym: here.".
Rym: And then it cuts to what is actually wrong with the car.
Rym: Sometimes the customer is right.
Rym: Sometimes the customer is wrong.
Rym: Sometimes the customer says, "I think I have a flat
Rym: tire."
Rym: And the camera zooms back to, "The tire is
Rym: gone.".
Rym: There is clearly a smoldering wreck of what used to be the axle under the car.
Rym: And the person thinks they just need a new tire and they have not gotten out of the car yet.
Rym: It's all sorts of stuff like that.
Rym: But the main reason I'm making this my thing of the day is that, if you were, say, a computer professional, and someone comes to you with an extremely obvious problem, "Hey, my computer stopped
Rym: working.".
Rym: And you turn it on and you're like, "Wow, yeah, your hard drive is completely
Rym: full.".
Rym: And you're like, "Completely full.
Rym: Actually completely
Rym: full.".
Rym: That's obvious to a computer person, but it's clearly not that obvious to people who don't know a lot about computers.
Rym: Similarly, you bring a car in, a mechanic takes one look at it, and they're like, "Just look at
Rym: it.".
Rym: And you're like, "Oh, I know exactly what's wrong, but me, who knows very little about cars, I have no idea.
Rym: I brought my car to the expert because I need
Rym: help.".
Rym: So part of the reason I made this my thing of the day is, if you're a computery person out there, remember that most people, none of this stuff is obvious to them at all.
Rym: And this video is how car people feel when often computer people who know nothing about cars bring their car into the shop with something obviously wrong.
Rym: But I actually want to point out something far deeper in this video, because despite not knowing a lot about cars, if you watch this video, a lot of the problems are extremely obvious, even to someone who has never seen a car in their life, if they just look at their own car and just think, "Should it look like that for maybe 10 or 15
Rym: seconds?".
Rym: And my advice to all of you, if you feel like you struggle with computers, is that computer problems are also that way.
Rym: When your computer is not working 99% of the time, your computer will actually tell you exactly what is wrong, and all you have to do is just click around and look at what the computer's telling you.
Scott: People don't read, stop, think.
Rym: One of these is like, "My car's making a weird
Rym: noise.".
Rym: They open the hood, truck, it's literally full of walnuts that a squirrel must have put in there.
Rym: Like, didn't just open the hood?
Rym: Take a look before you brought it into the mechanic with a tow truck.
Scott: They don't know how to open the hood.
Rym: There's a giant button that has a picture of a hood.
Scott: People are scared to do that, right?
Scott: People are scared to touch their computers.
Rym: I have a friend who, in living memory, like in the last 10 years, I'm being suitably vague about this in case that person listens to the show, they asked for help with their computer and I was willing to check it out.
Rym: And the problem ended up being they had two hard drives and the second hard drive just wasn't plugged into anything.
Rym: It was installed in the case.
Rym: at no point was it plugged into the motherboard or a power supply or anything.
Rym: It was just plugged into the case and they ran out of hard drive space.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So I plugged the computer, I plugged the hard drive in and fixed it.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Anyway, what do you got?
Scott: News wise?
Rym: Thing of the day.
Scott: Oh, you're jumping straight to thing of the day?
Rym: I just, we already did things.
Scott: This was my thing of the day.
Scott: Very related to your thing of the day.
Scott: I also have a fixing things thing of the day.
Scott: I found this YouTube channel.
Scott: This guy's called, I guess his name is Steve, but his YouTube channel is Stiz Stix Fix.
Scott: And I like it cause he's not a YouTube shouty guy.
Scott: He's just a quiet YouTube guy.
Scott: And what's interesting is that usually when you go to YouTube guys, right?
Scott: You know, you're usually finding someone who's like an expert on something, right?
Scott: And you're like, or like a extreme enthusiast about something, you know?
Scott: And it's like, this guy is actually not an extreme expert, right?
Scott: He is here in these, you know, this particular, he does a few different video series, but his best one, which I'm linking to the playlist is can I fix it?
Scott: in which he attempts to fix a purchases, you know, broken and need of repair electronic devices, mostly from eBay and other places, mostly eBay, and then attempts to fix them.
Scott: With soldering iron, you know, whatever.
Scott: And does he know about electronics?
Scott: Like, yes, but does he know as like, he doesn't know that much more than me about electronics and he definitely doesn't know as much about electronics as like big Clive, who really is like expert, right?
Rym: Oh, I just watched a really good big Clive last night.
Rym: So yeah.
Scott: And it's like, how good is he at soldering?
Scott: Better than me, but not great.
Scott: How much does he know about computer stuff and digital logic?
Scott: Less than me, right?
Scott: So this guy doesn't know really, you know, he's not extremely technologically advanced.
Scott: He's not like a doofus, right?
Scott: But it's like, you know, he's not like, you know, one of those S tier people who fucking, you know, blows you away with their knowledge yet.
Scott: Yet he has videos where he goes.
Scott: He buys five broken Game Boy games on eBay, right?
Scott: Like, and he puts them in a Game Boy and sure enough, none of them work.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: With his soldering iron, he fixes original Game Boy cartridges and then they work.
Scott: And it's like, when they actually work, it's sort of like, you know, watching the video, it's like he and you, the viewer, get like this great joy of like, oh my God.
Scott: That was like, it was actually broken, like broken, broken.
Scott: You know, sometimes he gets one that just needs some cleaning and then it works.
Scott: But, you know, a lot of the times when that happens, he won't make a video.
Scott: He'll be like, um, but it's like, he'll be broken Sega Genesis, broken Neo Geo pocket.
Scott: That one, he just kept going at it and like, it fucking worked eventually.
Scott: It's like, holy shit.
Scott: It's like, he didn't know.
Scott: this guy doesn't know anything about the schematic of the Neo Geo pocket, how it works really, you know, anything.
Scott: He just keeps, he opens it up and he repairs it.
Scott: Like, you know, a shoemaker would repair a shoe and it's like, and then it works.
Scott: And it's like, holy crap.
Scott: It's really awesome.
Scott: And a lot of fun.
Scott: It makes you want to go on eBay and buy broken stuff and try to fix it.
Scott: I resisted the urge to do that because what the fuck am I going to do with the shit?
Scott: Even if I fix it, what?
Scott: Sell it for actually, it's funny.
Rym: This is your thing of the day, because, uh, one of the, the Torsier led light that I bought like seven years ago failed in a way where it started flickering.
Rym: And I think I can fix it and I'm actually going to try and fix it.
Scott: You probably could do.
Rym: Yeah, it's not that, it's not that complicated of a device.
Scott: And I looked into, but it's, it's a lot more fun though, to see like, you know, an old iPod come back to Sega Genesis, come back to life, then a lamp come back to life.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But it'll mean that I, I would rather have continued to have this lamp than not have this lamp.
Rym: And I'd rather not buy another a hundred dollars lamp.
Rym: So in the better moment, the geek tonight's book club book, which I expect we'll just do the show on Thursday.
Rym: I don't see any reason why not.
Rym: So next Thursday, nine Fox gambit, we will talk about the books.
Rym: If you didn't start reading it yet, I suggest you read it, learn all about calendars and your tenant, open up your calendar and put it in the entry right for next Thursday.
Scott: Read this book by next Thursday.
Rym: You could easily read this book by the course.
Scott: The listener wanted us to read this book so badly.
Scott: They've definitely read it already, right?
Scott: They read it before I read it.
Scott: You can reread it.
Rym: It's a short read, but, uh, it's not that sure.
Rym: if I, if I have to entice you further, cause you know, I always don't, like, I try not to say, we both try to not say a ton about the book until we actually do the book club show.
Rym: And I know I keep saying that it's about violent calendars or calendar related violence, but I guess I should point out that it also involves you tenant duels.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: There's a couple of, there's a couple of tenant duels and you might be thinking, oh, clearly now they're, they're pretty much just fucking new tenant duels.
Rym: And when you read the book, you'll see.
Rym: And that doesn't even happen that late in the book.
Scott: So there's a, there's a, I mean, I think there's two, right?
Scott: If I remember it, there's like an early one.
Rym: There's a really early one where she duels that, uh, like the one commander, uh, like the commander within the swarm.
Scott: And then there's the, anyway, I think there's a late one.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: There's a, it might be three.
Rym: I think anyway, uh, this book's real good.
Rym: If you like the culture books, you'll probably like this and vice versa is the other thing else.
Scott: Did they both have named spaceships?
Rym: Also little droid guys who are great.
Rym: I love the little servitors.
Rym: Everything about the servitors is great.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So yeah, otherwise, uh, websites coming along, uh, we're not going to be at any cons for awhile.
Rym: Uh, what else can I say?
Rym: So we will eventually, I guess we should tell us what anime that is easily available that we should review and we'll just watch four episodes of it.
Rym: Hard mode.
Scott: I've unsubscribed from, uh, all streaming services.
Scott: So I might have to turn one back on or something.
Rym: I'm, I'm still on Netflix because Netflix actually has the anime I'm watching right now.
Rym: And the cartoons, it basically has everything I'm watching right now.
Scott: I watched, I watched so much Netflix and then I was like, there's nothing.
Scott: I turn on Netflix, scroll through it, watch nothing.
Rym: You could resubscribe to Netflix just to watch orbital children and arcane, and then you can unsubscribe.
Rym: They're both like some of the best cartoons.
Scott: One month of Netflix is what?
Scott: 15 bucks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That'd be worth it.
Rym: That's less than an anime DVD.
Scott: I guess that's true.
Rym: Anyway, but those shows are both up your alley in a huge way.
Scott: You know, it's just not the time like right at this moment for me to, you know, I've been, I've been watching less anime and reading less manga over time.
Rym: I've been watching a lot of cartoons, but not cartoon Scott's watching.
Scott: But I suspect in the near future, right?
Scott: Once the website and the hockey are out of the way in the summertime, right?
Scott: If I go into the beach or whatever, when the weather's fine, it's like, I'm going to have some more free time coming up real soon.
Scott: So I'll have a more, more watching will occur.
Rym: We'll also have to do a final thoughts on Chainsaw Man.
Scott: Oh, that's true.
Scott: We got to wait for the last volume is coming out this month.
Rym: I believe that'll be an easy show that we'll definitely do.
Rym: Cause I got some thoughts already.
Rym: Chainsaw Man is more topical than many of you who don't know anything about it will expect it to be.
Rym: So it's an anime, manga, comics, cartoons, whatever news round up because we didn't have a topic and we haven't done these that often.
Rym: We've done it like once or twice ever.
Rym: So I want to point out just saying the listener said, and I'm quoting directly.
Scott: I think the last volume might've just come out.
Rym: I got to catch up.
Rym: I'm actually not at the second of an ultimate volume yet.
Scott: I think it's 11.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh no.
Scott: June 7th, June 7th.
Rym: So I'm going to quote the listener from the stream right now.
Rym: I hope this unexpected Scott generosity doesn't mean the tech news roundup is delayed longer.
Rym: The tech news roundup listener loves the tech news roundups.
Rym: Just saying.
Scott: Well, listener, I got bad news for you is that the tech news roundup occurred twice last year with the tech news roundup.
Scott: The quota of tech news roundups is once every 12 months.
Scott: Just quit for better.
Scott: Two of them happened three months apart from each other.
Scott: So you have to wait.
Scott: I think I have on the calendar marked somewhere like when the, you know, the sort of, uh, you have a crude enough time for another tech news round.
Rym: I say we should do them quarterly.
Scott: Well, too bad.
Scott: Come up with better.
Rym: Monday show ideas in anime, manga, comics, animation, cartoon news.
Rym: There is a bunch of stuff to talk about.
Rym: I want to start with this drops right after we did our last Wednesday show when we were struggling to find news, which is really funny, but, uh, we knew there was a new or say at coming, you know, the LOM anime, uh, honestly, one of my favorite shows, like of all time in terms of just anime.
Scott: I think we did an episode on the first manga volume, right?
Rym: Pretty sure we did.
Rym: Uh, but we knew a new one was coming right after we recorded GeekNights a couple of weeks ago.
Rym: The trailer for the new LOM anime drops and it appears to be not a Sailor Moon Crystal situation, but a, this is going to be good situation.
Rym: The animation looks fantastic.
Rym: The character designs look fantastic.
Rym: The, the, the sad, the song that they play directly evokes the original shows songs, but also they went nuts on the color and it looks beautiful.
Scott: That's just a trailer.
Scott: It is.
Scott: You can't, you can't believe the whole thing is.
Rym: I want to point out there was not a trailer for Sailor Moon Crystal.
Scott: Well, did tell him when crystal was a, was a hack or hack rush job.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, um, but yeah, I've known this trend is really picking up lately, right?
Scott: It's like you look at say the United States cartoon universe, right?
Scott: And there have always, you know, there were properties that came into existence, right?
Scott: You know, think about really old stuff, say Alvin and the chipmunks.
Scott: That's super old, right?
Scott: You know, sixties like old and that, but when we were kids, it's like, well, there was a different, you know, a remake of Alvin and the chipmunks that was like, you know, the eighties, nineties one, whatever.
Rym: When I was a kid, we had that.
Rym: Like that's what I watched.
Rym: Also that horrible Alvin and the chipmunks movie that you should never watch.
Rym: Not even, there's no reason to watch it.
Rym: It's warning you all right now.
Rym: But we also had a ton of vinyl Alvin and the chipmunk albums from the original Alvin era.
Scott: But the point is, I didn't realize they were different, right?
Scott: It's like they keep animating and coming up with intellectual properties.
Scott: And then when they get a hit intellectual property in the United States, they keep bringing it back.
Scott: Not, you know, not as like sequels and like more seasons, but as like, it goes away and comes back again.
Scott: Transformers goes away, comes back as like, you know, beast transformers goes away.
Scott: It comes back as something else.
Rym: It's like a heartbeat in a protocol, like a communications protocol to keep it alive.
Scott: So when B test finally ran out, they wait a little bit and then Batman beyond comes out.
Rym: Just like, yeah, we can't, we can't let Batman fall out of the popular consciousness.
Rym: Keep it alive.
Rym: Do something.
Scott: Spider-Man and his amazing friends.
Scott: That's gone.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well, now we wait.
Scott: We ate some years.
Scott: Now there's a Spider-Man, you know, cartoon again, you know, just keeps cycling over and over and like even things that were newer more recently, it's like, you know, Oh, there was a powerpuff girls and then it went away and then it came back even though it wasn't sixties old.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, as soon as they find something that's a, that's a hit, it goes and it runs out of steam and then they bring it back.
Scott: So in anime though, that has not happened really as much, right?
Scott: When they have a thing that's a hit, they keep it going nonstop.
Rym: There are exceptions.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: Sometimes there's the, Oh, we had an OAV.
Rym: It was a hit.
Rym: We'll reboot it as a TV show and milk it.
Rym: that happened.
Scott: But it's not, it's not like.
Scott: there's a big gap where it's like, it was a hit thing.
Scott: It goes away and comes back.
Scott: The only thing I can think of that's like goes away and comes back is Lupin, which keeps going away and coming back constantly.
Rym: Evangelion is a weird case cause it ended and then it came back over the course of an extremely long amount of time.
Scott: It's a more recent thing, right?
Scott: You look at say, Pokemon is always successful.
Scott: It's just, yeah, Pokemon just doesn't stop.
Scott: They might completely redo it or, you know, make new seasons, new characters.
Rym: But they don't just remake the original season of Pokemon like one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, they might do a Naruto into a Boruto or whatever they're going to do.
Scott: But it's like, you know, it's like, I think of a popular older thing.
Scott: I guess Gundam keeps going away and coming back.
Scott: Also, that's also a franchise they constantly, right.
Scott: But it's not like there was some gap where they're like, you know what, let's just stop Gundams for a decade and then come back.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, there's always more Gundams coming, right.
Scott: They don't sleep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But these more recently, we are seeing that pattern.
Scott: It's like Ursa Yatsura was a big, long series because it was successful.
Scott: It ended.
Scott: It went to sleep and now it woke up again.
Scott: Sailor Moon was a big, long thing.
Scott: It went to sleep and then it woke up again.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We're seeing a lot more of that happening these days.
Scott: And I thought it was, you know, with the Sailor Moons and things like that.
Scott: I thought it was stuff with international popularity, you know, Dragon Balls.
Rym: Well, Sailor Moon was also.
Rym: there was something with the anniversary and they wanted to capitalize on it, but there was other stuff going on there.
Scott: Ursa Yatsura really does not have the immense international popularity.
Scott: Maybe in some not, you know, there's probably some countries where it's big besides Japan.
Scott: that, you know, but for the most part, I was under the impression that it was mostly big in Japan and not too much in other places.
Scott: So for that to be getting the sleep and wake up treatment.
Rym: Well, so once I learned something about the reason for this is the hundredth anniversary of Shogakukan's founding.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I mean, you know, the anniversary, if you look at the past anniversary things.
Scott: It's like they've always been like anniversary celebration type productions in the past.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: I think it's more true.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: Hey, here we have already committed to at least four whole seasons of this show.
Rym: Like it's not this situation.
Scott: So, you know, you think about some of the anniversary things of the past might have been like, you know, like a one shot deals.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or small OAV type things, not entire TV series remake something.
Scott: You know, it's like, you know, it's like a bigger thing that actually stands alone.
Scott: It isn't just some special.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not like Ursa Yatsura one episode, you know, special comeback for our anniversary.
Scott: It's like, nope, we're redo the whole deal.
Scott: Let's go to full TV season.
Rym: Thing is, what I'm excited about is the original show, the manga, everything about this show, this property, I guess I should say, is fantastic and extremely, deeply funny to me.
Rym: And I hope that this rekindles global interest in this show.
Scott: It could happen.
Rym: Well, we'll see.
Rym: Maybe it'll be bad, but I'm definitely going to watch at least the whole first season of it, unless somehow it's a supreme stinker, uh, it'll get talked about.
Scott: I mean, we'll, we'll watch enough to do a show on it.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: So in some other news, TCAF, uh, the, uh, uh, Toronto comics and arts festival.
Rym: Yeah, it's a, I think so.
Rym: It's a convention that I've been to, uh, what, what?
Rym: Comic arts festivals.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I was correct.
Rym: Emily used to go to whatever year Emily had like tables and reasons to be there, uh, professionally.
Scott: I went once, uh, it's a really fun, you know, it's, I was always, I never went to it, but I was under the impression.
Scott: It was a lot like, you know, the mocha arts festival used to go to right.
Scott: And in the comics show, right.
Scott: Indie creators set up little tables, sell their, their little comics, you know.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: It's a fun time.
Rym: Toronto is a fun city to be in like in pre COVID times, like a lot going on, a lot of good going on with TCAF.
Rym: Uh, I'm not going to cover the entire story of what happened here.
Rym: Cause there's a lot, but what happened was TCAF invited officially, uh, an individual known as pink cat, which is obviously like the name of the studio, Sue, a pseudonym, a property.
Rym: Uh, the artist behind it was a person who was very, very deep into the NFT scam, like big NFT scammer.
Rym: And they made this art.
Rym: that was just NFT bullshit.
Rym: And for some reason, TCAF invited them and featured them and promoted them and made them a big part of TCAF.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It turned, I mean, the it's, there's basically one person on the TCAF board was a fan of the pink cat and champion them.
Rym: That one person appears to also be heavily invested in NFTs.
Scott: Well, is that, is that true?
Scott: Do you have evidence of that?
Rym: The yes, there's a name that was listed.
Rym: I'm avoiding any defamation here right now, but there are numerous sources pointing at a specific individual on the board and showing proof that they own a large number of NFTs.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Add a bunch of NFT conferences.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well, I mean, I don't know if any of that is true or not, cause I haven't seen any of that.
Scott: But the point I was going to say is that like, you know, either that person was an unwitting fan of, you know, this pink cat.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or they were, you know, a knowing fan.
Scott: And you know, it's like if you're on the board, you know, boards of these things are not large.
Scott: If you're on the board of something, you know, championing like a single artist to being like, you know what?
Scott: This one artist should be one of the artists we feature at our show.
Scott: It's like, you got some sway.
Scott: You can probably make that happen.
Scott: And most of the time it's probably just fine.
Rym: But the thing is that artist, if anyone even looked at their Twitter or looked at their art or anything, it was clear that all they do is NFTs.
Scott: I mean, clearly the other people didn't look closely.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: So until they did.
Rym: A bunch of guests of TCAF immediately were like, what's this NFT crap?
Rym: Do you support NFTs?
Rym: Like we're going to, we're not going to come to TCAF.
Rym: If you're doing NFT stuff, what's going on?
Rym: And TCAF didn't really respond, but then it got way worse.
Rym: There is way more bad stuff about this artist.
Rym: There is clear direct evidence.
Rym: They trace tons of their art from other people without crediting them.
Scott: That's what NFTs are.
Scott: You just take JPEGs from the internet and try to sell them.
Rym: Their pink cat character appears to just be traces of other people's art.
Rym: They also made a bunch of black coded art and made a bunch of commentary about it, but they are not black.
Rym: When asked about this, they doubled down on some fairly racist things and it went off the deep end.
Rym: So basically then a bunch of bigger guests, including Ngozi, like a bunch of big TCAF guests were like, yeah, fuck this.
Rym: We're boycotting TCAF unless you guys do something about this.
Rym: It's not just NFTs.
Rym: Way, way beyond NFTs.
Rym: TCAF now rescinded.
Rym: The news is they have rescinded this invitation.
Rym: They have attempted to apologize for this, but their statement does not actually explain why they invited this person.
Rym: And more importantly, doesn't say anything about NFTs.
Rym: So now the entire, like a huge percentage of the community of TCAF is saying, whoa, whoa, whoa, are NFTs allowed or not?
Rym: You got to say you got to say something specific about NFTs or we're still not coming.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you know, I guess this shows you that, you know, if you run a convention, you know, there's a lot of conventions out there, especially smaller ones that will get like any guest they can, especially if it's inexpensive.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And a lot of this is how you get a bunch of derpy cons that invited Vic Mignona because they didn't realize his scandal and had to uninvite him.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Because the people running the con are not super connected to the scene.
Scott: They don't know what's going on.
Scott: Or they are connected to the scene and they're just bad.
Scott: But they're also cons or it's just like, you know, you'll have like, you know, there are agents out there that, you know, for low tier celebrities.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I remember it was a big thing, like a, you know, a decade or two ago.
Scott: There was like, I remember in the nineties when I would watch pro wrestling, there was this guy, Virgil.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And he was a pro wrestler and you would see him on pro, you know, turn on Saturday morning after X-Men pro wrestling starts and he'd be on there.
Scott: But he wasn't, you know, he was like one of the lower, not as famous pro wrestlers.
Scott: He wasn't Hulk Hogan.
Scott: You know, it's like he was some other dude.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then I remember specifically that I saw him at like one of those, you know, sitting at a table doing autographs.
Scott: So like one of those sad, small comic book, you know, trading card, you know, shows at some point in like the two thousands.
Scott: And then I remember seeing jokes of like, you know, specifically targeting him, Virgil, the, the, the, the WWE pro wrestler of, you know, basically of, of, you know, very small amount of fame.
Scott: Like.
Scott: that's what he was doing.
Scott: He was appearing at lots and lots of those shows.
Scott: Like that was his thing.
Scott: And there are lots of people who do exactly that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, and they just know those shows.
Scott: And if you're running a, but if you're running a show, it's like, I need guests.
Scott: It's like, people like that are just going to come to you.
Scott: And it's like, you just be like.
Scott: this person's somewhat famous.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You were actually a pro wrestler.
Scott: You were actually an actor in that TV show.
Scott: You were actually this thing.
Scott: You have some fame.
Scott: You will draw a crowd of some number, right?
Scott: I can use you to promote my con.
Scott: It'll get someone in the door and you are very inexpensive to bring.
Scott: Or in fact, free to bring because you'll just charge money for autographs or something.
Scott: And then you didn't actually look into these people and know about them or how your community or audience cares about, you know, whatever these people are.
Scott: And you can get yourself into trouble.
Scott: You got to really vet every guest very thorough.
Rym: Well, we saw this with the anime cons where there was a brief period where a bunch of cons invited Vic Mcnona because they didn't know about all the bullshit with him.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But now voice actor, he was like, actually he was the English voice actor.
Scott: In a very popular anime at multiple popular animes.
Scott: But then he has fans.
Scott: Look at all the followers he has.
Scott: Why wouldn't I want him at my con?
Rym: But then all the backlash became so obvious that now the only cons that invite him are the cons that basically exclusively invite guests who are banned from other conventions and attract really dire after a certain point.
Scott: It's like, you know, people are loud enough or the audience informs you and you're going to want to point out.
Rym: one of the last cons I saw him announced as a guest at was one of the cons that last year went maskless, no vaccine, no rules.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So anyone can run a con.
Scott: Bad people or good people.
Rym: So TCAF has not yet made a statement on NFTs.
Rym: And this is increasingly worrying because there's a lot of fear that TCAF has some commercial interest or at least someone on the board has continuing commercial interest in that scam.
Scott: It could be if it is really just one person.
Scott: The reason they might not be saying anything is lawyer reasons.
Rym: Yeah, you know, but they could issue a statement denouncing NFTs, which is honestly all all they'd have to do to make this completely go away.
Rym: Yeah, they wouldn't have to do that.
Scott: They will do it very carefully.
Rym: All they'd have to do is say we don't support NFTs.
Rym: They're not welcome at the con.
Rym: They're banned at our tables.
Rym: That would be a even.
Scott: that even while that is very easy to say, you know, if you're an organization, you're going to be very careful, especially when you got some kind of issue like.
Scott: they are even making such a bland statement.
Scott: They're always so legally careful and cowardly, sometimes with good reason, sometimes just for cowardly reasons.
Rym: Yeah, let's see in some other news.
Rym: Oh, Seven Seas.
Rym: There's a lot going on with Seven Seas.
Scott: So if you don't know, there's this company that's been around in the United States for quite a long time called Seven Seas Entertainment.
Scott: And Seven Seas is a manga publisher.
Scott: They publish.
Scott: They do.
Scott: They get manga from Japan.
Scott: They translate it, edit it, et cetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, flip it or not flip it, depending and publish it in print and digital forms in the United States.
Scott: It's all legally licensed.
Scott: They're a real publisher, but the titles that they get are usually not the most popular titles, not the biggest titles.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're usually niche titles or, you know, things that only super nerds know about, you know, things that aren't selling big, but the licenses are cheap.
Scott: So they're still profitable.
Scott: And as you know, the rising manga tide lifts all boats, Seven Seas does okay.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: they're not, you know, going out of business, at least as far as I know.
Scott: In fact, you know, they went from being really small, like 10 or so people.
Scott: I believe that I've seen reports that they now have like 40 employees.
Scott: So it's like that's.
Scott: that's okay.
Scott: Business 40 employees.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's not bad.
Scott: But apparently part of the reason their business maybe works so well is that the employees are underpaid, mistreated, overworked, et cetera.
Rym: No surprises, pretty much all of capitalism.
Rym: The companies where this is not true in any industry are the exception, not the rule.
Rym: But comics and manga in particular are egregious.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So but as it turns out, all those employees being cool manga fan type people were like, fuck this, we're going to union just like all the Starbucks is.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And this is spreading.
Scott: And it's good that it's spreading.
Rym: They have fantastic because they're comic artists.
Rym: They made mascots for the union and they are delightful.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, yeah, they they didn't vote to unionize yet.
Scott: They you know, you do usually do is you just so they don't they wouldn't necessarily you ask the company to just recognize your union voluntarily.
Scott: And then the company, of course, doesn't.
Scott: So they're going to vote.
Rym: But I've seen reports that like 30 plus of the 40 employees are basically in favor, which really put seven seas in a harsh light, because if you say no to the union vote and the union vote is overwhelming.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Anyway, you've already poisoned your relations with that union.
Rym: You could have just said yes and had a much favorable relationship much earlier.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, so they're, you know, the national labor relations boards get, you know, does their usual thing.
Scott: The vote is going to happen at some point in the future that it'll I predict a yes based on the information I have available.
Scott: And that will be very interesting because I wonder, right, you know, a lot of the other unions we've seen happening, right.
Scott: Amazons and Starbucks, those are against mega corporations, right?
Scott: You know, we've seen a few attempts and other things at some smaller places like, you know, some game studios here and there.
Scott: This one could be a really good example to figure out if right.
Scott: Will it what will?
Scott: what kind of deal can the union get against such a small company that doesn't have a lot to give?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And that's that's where I have a worrying opinion.
Scott: But and then B, if they get a deal right, will they end up like hurting?
Scott: You know, obviously I'm in favor of the union and the people shouldn't be mistreated.
Scott: We're super lefty labor people here.
Scott: But is this business of seven C's manga publishing right?
Scott: A viable business that can support right laborers who are fairly compensated.
Rym: So I would back up a little bit because I'm not it is not the it'll just go under, which is probably under the sea.
Rym: It say that happened.
Rym: That is, I think, the best outcome.
Scott: I agree.
Rym: And if I back up because I don't want to imply that I know anything about seven C's financial care, I know nothing about it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But what I'll say is generally I suspect that most for profit companies in America, in every industry, would immediately disappear if they had to treat their workers fairly.
Rym: They would immediately collapse.
Scott: I mean, that's true for like, you know, not just America.
Scott: It's true like worldwide.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What if, you know, the iPhone factory had to treat all the workers like what we consider to be, you know, well, right.
Scott: It's like an iPhone would cost like a hundred thousand dollars.
Rym: or maybe that is the purpose of government.
Rym: And anyway, that's why I'm a communist.
Rym: I'm not even kidding.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So we'll see how this goes.
Rym: This is a very important moment for comics as an industry.
Rym: Just straight up.
Scott: It's going to be very fascinating to see, you know, if the vote succeeds, probably, then what direction does that?
Scott: What deal do they get and what direction does the company go?
Scott: Do they get a crappy deal?
Scott: Do they get a deal?
Scott: But then the company has to lay people off to carry on.
Scott: Does the, you know, how's, you know, is the company actually just evil and is hoarding some money at the top and they'll actually end up being forced to, you know, share the wealth and that will be a good thing.
Scott: So many possible results, but it will be very fascinating to look back on this a year or two from now.
Rym: So if you're not familiar with something, Nino Cooney, you either know about it and care about it, or you have no idea what I'm talking about.
Scott: So Nino Cooney, right, if I remember correctly, was originally billed as like a Ghibli related kind of RPG.
Scott: It is.
Rym: It's long running.
Rym: This is from, like, more than a decade ago, but it's a Bandai Namco game with Joe Hisaishi.
Scott: Like, Joe Hisaishi does the music for it.
Scott: Yeah, it's Ghibli Ghibli.
Rym: Like, it's Ghibli all over.
Rym: So whatever.
Scott: I don't know if they have, like, Nino Cooney stuff at the Ghibli Museum, but, like, you know, let's see, the animated sequences are produced by Ghibli.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: Ghibli is very involved in this RPG video game.
Scott: When it was first announced, it, you know, it was so long ago, it felt like that's a thing that's never going to be translated to English.
Scott: I'm never going to be able to play that.
Rym: We have a Japanese copy of the, like, with the book and everything for the DS in Japanese.
Scott: But yeah, but I'm saying if you go back 10 years ago, I think there was a GeekNights episode that was first announced.
Scott: It was probably the news.
Scott: And I probably said something like, wow, I want to play this, but it'll never be out in English.
Scott: Turns out it was successful and time went on and the world changed.
Scott: And yeah, it's available, obviously.
Scott: And there were many sequels and it's a long running series now, not just a one thing.
Rym: And it's completely destroyed and dead now.
Scott: What's happening is, well, also in all that time, I did never, ever get to play any Nino Coonies.
Scott: So not even once.
Rym: The most recent iteration, because the before, so the last Nino Cooney that came out was in like 2012.
Rym: And then the next one just came out like it.
Rym: It was released, I think, in June in Japan, and it was released worldwide, like in May, like just like last week, Nino Cooney Cross Worlds.
Rym: And I'm not going to say anything else about Nino Cooney Cross Worlds because it is an NFT scam.
Rym: It is 100%.
Rym: The game is farm bullshit in a Ghibli world to get special coins that you can trade for other coins that you can migrate out of the game into a cryptocurrency wallet that you can then trade for like Bitcoin and shit.
Rym: Well, the whole game is a cryptocurrency scam and the roadmap, actually, it doesn't have NFTs yet.
Rym: It only has bullshit, fake, crisp cryptocurrency.
Rym: The entire game is grind cryptocurrency and they're adding NFTs in December of this year.
Rym: Ghibli is all on board with this.
Rym: This latest one is just as official as all the other ones.
Rym: Joe Hishai, she even did the music for this one.
Rym: And it's a shame that it's just a bullshit scam.
Rym: So under no circumstances are you to play Nino Cooney, the Open Worlds Cross Worlds MMO that they just released.
Scott: Free to play, developed by Netmarble.
Scott: Wikipedia says, yeah, OK.
Rym: How did you not see this was all over the news?
Scott: That it's just a paying attention to this.
Rym: You can mine Terai to get Terai tokens that you trade in.
Scott: the crossworlds generated 100 million in revenue in its first two.
Rym: Oh, it is crazy.
Rym: It's actually doing really well in Japan and Korea.
Scott: Free game.
Scott: And actually, it says here on Wikipedia that Japan accounted for only 45 percent of the revenue.
Scott: South Korea and Taiwan accounted for thirty five and fifteen point seven percent of the revenue respectively.
Scott: So it's taken over East Asia money.
Rym: But I cannot stress enough, this game is just a cryptocurrency scam.
Rym: There's like no game in there.
Scott: It's some kind of grindy MMORPG thing, which is a shame because I was under at least 10 plus years ago when the first one came out and I had only seen the trailer.
Scott: And that's all I ever knew about it because I never played it.
Scott: I was under the impression that it was going to be a single player JRPG.
Scott: that was really fancy because of the Ghibli production values.
Rym: You can't make money with that.
Rym: It's the year 2022.
Rym: You're going to cram some crypto NFT bullshit in there.
Rym: Also, probably some gotcha bullshit.
Rym: And you're going to predate on kids until you run out of steam like that's.
Rym: that's how you make money with games.
Rym: Well, that's a shame.
Rym: Uh, in some news, I never thought I would ever, ever say these words.
Rym: I never thought I'd even mention flying ghost ship on the show again.
Scott: We did a whole episode on flying good.
Scott: We reviewed flying phantom ship.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: When we saw it, it was translated as phantom or flying ghost ship.
Rym: But it looks like that the official translation is flying phantom ship.
Rym: Regardless, this movie, which if you haven't seen it, go listen to our review.
Scott: It's a Japanese Russian co-production anime from a long time ago.
Rym: And it involves like, I don't think it was actually, it was a co, it wasn't a co-production, but there was some co-financing.
Rym: It's not as much of a Russian thing as anyway.
Scott: It has notoriety because, uh, you know, Miyazaki animated like a part of it, like the robot part or whatever.
Rym: I think it has notoriety because it is absolutely fucking bonkers.
Rym: And if it is, if you want so many different things crammed together.
Rym: If you watch the first 10 minutes of it, you'll think, oh, it's just gonna be do all right.
Rym: I'm down board with this.
Rym: If you pick any random two minutes of this movie from any part, other than the first 10 minutes, it will be very difficult for you to figure out how the fuck it got there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, it's, oh, it's like, you'll have.
Scott: parts of it are like Astro boy.
Scott: Parts of it are like the Slurm episode of it are like the famous horror movie, the stuff.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Uh, parts of it are like, you know, 10,000 leagues under the sea.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: If you saw project blue cheek, you it, they're very, there are a lot of similarities between these two parts of it or pirates of the Caribbean, obviously with the flying ghost ship.
Scott: It's basically so many different things going on, crammed into one movie.
Rym: Crafty and horror comes in at one point.
Scott: It is absolutely wild.
Rym: It's worth watching.
Scott: I can go listen to our episode on it or watch the movie itself.
Scott: But the news is that disco tech, right?
Scott: Which is, uh, you know, much like in fact, seven seas, uh, there are small anime publisher in the United States as opposed to a small manga publisher.
Scott: Uh, but disco tech is actually kind of, you know, cooler, a lot cooler than seven C has the shit together a lot more, uh, doesn't just get sad licenses, but gets licenses occasionally to really cool stuff.
Scott: Um, and they put out, you know, lots of blue rays that hardcore anime nerds won, right?
Scott: Old school anime nerds, right?
Scott: So you want to, you know what fist of the North star box set.
Scott: That's what disco tech is going to bring you, right?
Scott: So, um, they got all kinds of loupons going on too right now, but anyway, they're going to put out a flying Phantom ship and got a new dub for it on probably the highest quality version of this movie that will ever be available to the public.
Rym: I think I watched a file.
Scott: It's kind of cool that they're doing that.
Rym: I want to see if, cause I was on YouTube.
Rym: I think I've been linked to it at one point.
Rym: The whole movie used to be on YouTube.
Rym: I bet that got taken down now.
Scott: Who knows, but it'll be on Blu-ray now.
Rym: So nope.
Rym: Whole thing's just on YouTube.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: In VHS looking quality.
Rym: So this is, this is important.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I look forward to watching this one more time in my life and high quality, honestly.
Scott: I'll do that when I'm super old.
Rym: It's a, it's a ride that movie.
Scott: That's a retirement home movie.
Rym: So, uh, it's early in news.
Rym: It's just something fun.
Rym: Anime Boston is the last anime con that Scott and I regularly attended and performed at for a lot of reasons.
Scott: We've talked about the last pure anime con.
Scott: There were other cons we went to that had anime at them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But anime Boston was the perfect storm of, it wasn't Otakon.
Rym: It was a big anime con close to New York, get there via train in and out.
Scott: Uh, the staff people there that we knew and could have fun with.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like we'd be there doing a ton of panels, all our other Anna Twitter friends, and also be there doing panels.
Scott: It was usually a really good concert to go to that was worth attending.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: I've, I think it's all the best.
Rym: Other than when Otakon got L'arc en Ciel in the giant arena, all the best anime con concerts I ever saw were at anime Boston.
Scott: They're, you know, pretty good concerts.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Good anime con all around.
Rym: We stopped going for reasons that have nothing to do with the dedication of the staff or the quality of the con itself.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It was mostly just, you know, the hassle of getting there, the hassle of dealing with security, right?
Scott: The fact that, you know, spending a whole weekend there when we only were, you know, doing stuff for some of that.
Rym: Granted, we were doing like six panels at any one of these.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: But even doing six panels, we had a lot of time just doing nothing there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, okay.
Rym: What really hurt was that anime panels, we can't put them on YouTube like all our other panels because of copyright.
Scott: So anyway.
Scott: So still a person who wants to go to anime cons, anime Boston is an anime con you should go to.
Scott: You absolutely should near it.
Rym: But anime Boston has a long running tradition of having a swap meet that I am happy to say went to once or twice.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Not only is it continued, but it appears to have grown.
Scott: So there was a report, I guess, on the swap meet and like.
Scott: it is way bigger now.
Rym: And I wish I'd been able to go because I got a lot of anime crap.
Scott: That's the thing is even when I was going to anime Boston, I wanted to bring crap to the swap meet, but it's like, how am I going to get it there?
Scott: Since I'm not a car person, I was taking a train or bus there.
Rym: I mean, we're on an Amtrak and I'm bringing like equipment with me.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you can't bring a box full of mangas and figurines and other garbage.
Scott: That's a pain in the ass, right?
Rym: So there's an article in Anime News Network by Ruben Baron that just, it talks about like, just direct primary journalism of how the swap meet went down.
Rym: It's got the quote from Christian Daley.
Rym: I'm always happy to see Christian Daley still being mentioned in the anime world.
Scott: Christian Daley, if anyone doesn't know, right, is a person that we barely know.
Scott: Barely know.
Rym: He was like the distant predecessor of what we did with RIT anime.
Scott: When we were at the RIT anime club, he was a freshman.
Scott: He was a person who was mentioned as a previous anime club president, but he had graduated by the time we got there.
Rym: He was legendary enough to where his name was still spoken.
Rym: Kind of like how, at least as of four years ago, our names are still spoken at RIT anime.
Rym: I feel like that finally might have died now.
Scott: He's at least five years older than us, right?
Scott: But there were at least two occasions at Anime Boston where we bumped into him and I guess we knew who each other were at least, even though we didn't really have any kind of relationship other than, "I know you exist, I know who you
Scott: are.".
Scott: But it's like, I remember his name and I know that he has been involved heavily in Anime Boston, like basically forever, effectively.
Rym: He's done a bunch of jobs.
Rym: He's currently the director of exhibits and the dealer's room manager.
Scott: Oh, I think that's what he was also when we met him.
Rym: I know he's done other jobs at some point along the way.
Scott: He's been running that Anime Boston dealer's room for a long time.
Rym: But unlike me and Scott, honestly, GeekNights, we pivoted pretty hard into gaming instead of anime.
Rym: Christian Daley is one of the people who pivoted hard into anime and stayed there.
Scott: He just stuck with that "run the dealer's room" job.
Scott: Good for him.
Scott: So anyway, Christian Daley is responsible for the swap meet, is the point.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And it's just fascinating.
Rym: The comments about this article are even fun.
Rym: The swap meet is a fun thing.
Rym: I feel like it would almost be worth it for me to, if I have some other reason to be in during Anime Boston, to go for one day.
Rym: I am confident there are nerds who will take for, like, I would even trade away for nothing.
Rym: Almost all the anime crap I've accumulated over the years.
Scott: I got a lot of crap I can trade away.
Rym: Anyone want all entire mangas?
Scott: Do you think we can organize like a New York City nerd swap meet?
Scott: Like bring nerdy stuff.
Scott: If it's games, anime, manga, comics, right?
Scott: Technology.
Rym: Yeah, listen, do you want to roll into Anime Boston with the biggest goddamn collection to trade and you're welcome to keep anything you trade for?
Rym: We'll hook you up.
Scott: We could do it.
Scott: It could be a flea market and or swap meet kind of deal, right?
Scott: And we basically have, you know, we could sell, we don't just sell tables.
Scott: We sell tables by time.
Scott: That way it's like, you know, you can sign up for like an hour and see how much of your shit you can get rid of in an hour or two hours or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then, you know, people who really have a lot of stuff, they can buy it, you know, in a more, a bigger table in a, in a more flea market kind of arrangement.
Scott: And it could even be like an outside thing, like in that, you know, parking lot or some shit.
Scott: Right.
Rym: The other way to go is just for one day.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You organize something like that, but make sure it's organized near a convention that will attract nerds that already exists to get out of towners into,
Scott: or we just promote it, you know, in New York City, like in all the nerd communities in New York City, all the nerd, you know, stores, we hang up a sign and, you know,
Rym: one night only, I was about to say one night only the fabulous
Scott: one, one, one morning to afternoon only rhythm
Rym: and blues review, 10
Scott: to six, something like that, you know, 10 to seven.
Rym: We'd have to make a poster that looked like that.
Rym: Anyway, it's not out of the realm.
Rym: I, uh, once we get to a point where either it's safe enough or like, I feel like next year I'm going to try, if no one else does it, I'm going to try to, I'm going to rekindle the board game meetup that started in Long Island City right before COVID and died because of COVID.
Rym: And I actually found the people who founded it and I'm going to, I'm going to actively rekindle it if and when it is safe enough to do so.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, we'll see.
Rym: The problem is the venue they hosted it in also went under because of COVID.
Scott: A really good place to do it would be at the new Pig Beach, which has many tables.
Rym: The previous one was in the giant beer garden that opened in Long Island City.
Rym: that was never crowded on weekends and had a million tables.
Scott: Pig Beach can't, it's not going to be crowded on weekdays.
Scott: But the problem is that it's a barbecue place.
Scott: You can't eat barbecue that often.
Scott: You're going to be in trouble.
Rym: Also barbecue of all the foods.
Rym: I don't want some nerd eating while they're playing a board game with me, especially.
Scott: I'm not a person who cares about preserving the board game.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: But I don't want barbecue is not the, there is, there are no number of napkins there to make your hands safe to touch any board game I own.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Uh, got a couple more little newses.
Rym: So, um, Scott's not watching it.
Rym: You should at some point just pirate it if you have to.
Rym: Uh, the Owl House, which is ending like Disney's basically canceled it after its third season, though it will tell its whole story because they're going to condense everything into like this abbreviated third seasons.
Rym: They can at least get it all out.
Rym: But the Owl House is one of the better shows Disney has put out.
Rym: that is animated.
Rym: It seems like a big part of why it's being canceled is one.
Rym: it's super gay, which means Disney has trouble marketing it in countries like China.
Rym: But two, it's really dark and weird in a way that some executive said out loud doesn't jive with the Disney brand.
Rym: So it, it got killed for a bunch of reasons.
Scott: But I mean, if something is understand, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, it doesn't jive with your brand, right?
Scott: But it's like, if it makes money, if it's popular enough and it's profitable and it's a good, you like it, you know, the something like the alternative is something that would make less money or it's like, be riskier, right?
Scott: It's like, just don't write Disney's Owl House.
Scott: Just call it fucking Owl House.
Rym: And yeah, I mean, there's a reason a lot of comics publishers have an imprint for the stuff that causes trouble for exactly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like DC Comics had, you know, fucking Vertigo.
Scott: They're like, oh, it's Vertigo.
Scott: That way, you know, kids go to the store to buy some DC Comics.
Scott: They don't buy, you know, they don't look at, you know, if it's a DC on it, a kid might buy it thinking it's a superhero thing, you know, but I go on it.
Rym: I think it's one of my favorite cartoons to come out in the last five or six years.
Rym: And I highly encourage you watch it because season two is finishing the second half of season two.
Rym: There's 40 episodes.
Rym: just it's out.
Rym: You can watch a bunch of it.
Rym: I'm almost caught up and it continues to be good.
Scott: Not super news.
Scott: It's actually old news by now because it's already June.
Scott: But Saga, the comic, the best comic published in English.
Rym: Oh, I stopped reading Saga.
Scott: Well, Saga stopped publishing.
Scott: It took a long break after.
Scott: I forget where I left off after a certain volume.
Scott: A very big thing happened at the very end and they stopped publishing it for quite a while as a hiatus.
Scott: That hiatus is over.
Rym: Oh, shit.
Rym: I just remembered what happened right before the hiatus.
Scott: Yeah, the hiatus is over and Saga has been coming out again and it shouldn't be long until, you know, there's enough single issues to make another trade paperback.
Rym: Somehow I lost.
Scott: I had every volume of Saga trade paperbacks.
Scott: Somehow I lost them all.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's like I must have lent them to someone who didn't get them back.
Scott: I don't know what the hell happened.
Scott: Did I lose them when I moved?
Scott: Like, they are not anywhere.
Scott: I'm just going to have to rebuy it maybe in the big fancy editions or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I mean, the first if you'd let's do a review of Saga if you haven't read it or don't know what we're talking about.
Rym: But also I'll just point out the first trade by itself won the Hugo for best graphic story.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Scott: So they actually they have a box set of pretty well.
Rym: So far it's gotten 12 Eisner's and 17 Harvey's.
Scott: Yeah, so, yeah, there's a box set you can get that has everything pre hiatus and you can also get some fancy hard covers if you really want.
Scott: And then, yeah, there have been one, two, three, four, five, six issues, right?
Scott: It started up again in January 2022.
Scott: And I'm sure that there will be a trade paperback coming soon.
Rym: So I guess one last little news.
Rym: This actually just came out like a few days ago.
Rym: But Bob's Burgers has a movie.
Rym: There's actually just a movie and I'm definitely going to.
Scott: I mean, I knew that Bob's Burger was a thing.
Scott: I've heard of it.
Scott: I've seen it.
Scott: I could recognize what it looks like.
Scott: Watched it.
Scott: But I do know that there are a lot of people who actually, you know, like are fans of it and I've been keeping it going.
Scott: And it's you know, it has some popularity, but that's all I know.
Rym: Because what's funny is when it came out.
Rym: Well, you know, like it started in 2010, 2011.
Scott: I get I'm guessing based on the title, it's about someone who owns a burger shop and their name is Bob.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But the main that's all.
Scott: that's it.
Rym: What most people know about it, which what I knew about it was.
Rym: the main guy, Bob, is voiced by John Benjamin.
Rym: One of the best voice actors there is who plays a very particular character.
Rym: Also, Sterling Archer, the guy who plays Archer.
Rym: No, I don't think he voice acts in any shows you watch.
Rym: He's a fantastic voice actor.
Rym: He plays the master in Venture Brothers.
Rym: You hear his voice, you'll know exactly who this guy is.
Rym: He's just really, really funny and good at voice acting.
Rym: But I always just kind of ignored the show because 2010 to like 2020, like that last decade.
Scott: Oh, he's the Dr.
Scott: Cat's voice guy.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Scott: Now I know who that is.
Scott: That's how old I am.
Rym: So this show I kind of slept on like I do.
Rym: It was I'd seen some clips from it.
Rym: It was OK, funny.
Rym: There was a crossover episode with Archer.
Rym: That was actually pretty funny where Archer had a crossover with it, not the other way around.
Rym: But recently, unrelated to the movie coming out, Emily and I started watching a bunch of Bob's Burgers.
Rym: And I will say this, and I know this might sound like I'm overhyping it.
Rym: It is way, way funnier and better than I possibly expected.
Rym: I would say the average quality of an episode of Bob's Burgers is about the level of a season four or a season seven Simpsons episode, not the the purest peak of The Simpsons, not seasons five and six, but four and seven.
Rym: This is this is that level of humor.
Rym: This is absolutely as good as season four of The Simpsons.
Rym: This show is if you ever slept on Bob's Burgers, fucking watch some of it.
Rym: Good Lord.
Rym: It doesn't even matter when.
Rym: Just pick up.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Pick like random episode of season three and just start going.
Scott: Where is it?
Scott: Is it?
Scott: what TV network is it?
Scott: Like what streaming service has it?
Rym: How do you think I know how to watch a show other than how are you watching it?
Rym: Pirate Bay and a free Hulu account.
Scott: OK, so it's on Hulu.
Rym: Yeah, I think it's on Hulu.
Rym: OK, it's probably on some other places, too.
Rym: There's ways to watch it.
Rym: I suspect there is a Bob's Burgers, all seasons dot something file you can download somewhere if you know where those kinds of things are.
Rym: But the show is great and I actually really pumped to see the movie.
Rym: The movie just looks I don't.
Rym: I think the movie, the impression I get from the trailer and from some initial reviews I saw, it's not going to be like The Simpsons movie, which was a little bit of a. we're already past the shark, like the shark is dead.
Rym: We jumped over it and then it died.
Rym: And then they made a Simpsons movie.
Rym: This feels like it's not that kind of situation.
Rym: And I feel like that's enough news because I want to make sure I have time to eat dinner before every hockey game I watch to do Wednesday episodes lately because we're not watching a lot.
Scott: And it's like we already decreased our anime watching so much since the years ago.
Rym: The Rangers game tonight is going to be the most important Rangers game of the season and every Rangers game is going to be the most important hockey game we've seen in a week or two days.
Rym: Every hockey game I watch is going to be one of the most important hockey games of this season.
Scott: It's been like seven years since you've seen Rangers games.
Scott: this significant.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Linky G, Dreadly Tenenbaai, A Bunch of People Who Really Don't Want Me to Say Their Names, Krista Dodd, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finke, Shaya85, Rebecca Dunn, Revue Medical, 34 Cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl, Stop All the Downloading, Taylor Braun, The Next Stationist, Spadina, Spadina Station, and several people whose names I will not say.
Rym: I'm just gonna go watch some hockey and I simply leave you with...
Scott: And the best game you can name is the good ol' hockey game.
Scott: Second period.
Scott: Where players dash with skates of flash, the home team trails behind.
Scott: But they grab the puck and go bursting up and they're down across the line.
Scott: They storm the crease like bumblebees, they travel like a burning flame.
Scott: We see them slide the puck inside, it's a 1-1 hockey game.
Scott: Oh, the good ol' hockey game is the best game you can name.
Scott: And the best game you can name is the good ol' hockey game.