Rym: It's Monday, August 22nd, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are going to advise you on how not to suck at getting a new smartphone.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So the one of those dates with but a lot of twos in it.
Rym: Yeah To 22 22 a lot of twos.
Rym: I do like a lot of twos.
Rym: There aren't that many big palindromic dromic dates that are gonna come up in the rest of our lives, unfortunately.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we already had February 22nd 2022.
Scott: I mean we had.
Scott: we had November 11th 2011 a while ago Yep So I was 2011 not 1000 right?
Scott: I mean what?
Rym: 1011 happened, but nobody quite.
Rym: Anyway,
Scott: so,
Rym: uh Normally, well as you may know the listener that when Scott and I have an opening bit some we might say at the start The show if we don't no matter what happens in our lives no matter how many things happen between When we do one gig nights and when we do the next gig nights We will talk about one thing first Whatever is top of mind and the rest is deleted from our brains forever.
Rym: but I remember what I was going to say from Thursday when we skipped the show because Enough further incident happened today.
Rym: So I have four Biking related open ebits that I don't think we have time for all four it's or they are very short.
Rym: the I'll start with the most egregious one because it is the the funniest one to me, so We biked over the weekend all up to Tarrytown.
Rym: Just now I had some lunch bike back home.
Rym: there's like a nice chill biking day and About 10 miles south of Tarrytown.
Rym: I want you to guess what I saw Parked on the side of the South County Trailway.
Rym: You have one guest.
Rym: Yeah, it's parked.
Scott: it has to be a vehicle.
Scott: it's probably a city bike.
Rym: it was one of the white Super expensive city by.
Scott: someone else posted a photo of it.
Scott: I saw it.
Rym: Yep parked 10 miles.
Rym: so this thing was parked so far outside of New York City and Someone had stripped the entire front wheel off of it.
Scott: Oh The one I saw still had a wheel.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: it was in good shape, but it was like in Tarrytown.
Rym: This is along the trail way like just south of Tarrytown.
Rym: Yeah, I am 100% sure that one was stolen and someone wrote it north until the GPS locked it out.
Scott: I think people either a just don't realize that the bikes have time limits and a certain range or Someone checks it out and somehow they lose it and someone else takes it and they now that person Can just ride it with no cons.
Rym: I have seen a few times someone straight-up steal someone's city bike and just bike off with it.
Scott: Yeah, don't leave the city bike, you know.
Scott: No I'm talking like on someone.
Rym: make sure that someone would say this was a few weeks ago.
Rym: Someone was just like they pulled up near me.
Rym: I was like waiting for a red light on him on a city bike myself and this dude just like pulls up pulls off into the sidewalk gets off the city bike and is standing near it like right there just looking at his cell phone and some kid just Walks by and just grabs it and just bolts.
Scott: Yeah, don't get off of it.
Rym: Yeah So, uh today just now bike in home on the city bike I come around the corner You know that u-turn to get on the Queensborough Bridge from Manhattan.
Rym: There's like a weird Intersection like in the bike lane.
Rym: It's like this really weird u-turn and I'm coming in real slow on a slow City bike far to the right and two road bikers come around the corner at extremely high speed straight for me The first one sees that I'm there because I'm like in the lane And screeches to a stop like the whole rear wheel kicks up and her friend just slams into her from behind and they both eat shit and flip over right in front of Me and they fall to the ground in a heap literally in front of me as I'm just stopped.
Rym: They were kind of okay But they must have been going like 15 or 20 miles an hour coming around that corner.
Rym: for some reason I don't.
Scott: I mean it's a steep downhill so you can you go fast, but at the bottom of it There's a hairpin.
Scott: there's a hairpin turn.
Scott: you got like literally like it's really tight you have to stop.
Rym: This isn't even like Mount Occhia situation.
Rym: It's like that more advanced mountain that starts with an eye from like season four of initial D. Like this is some dangerous shit.
Rym: and So the third incident bike.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: it's not a car situation, right?
Rym: It's like like some bikers make poor decisions to Coming home from work on Friday or on Thursday.
Rym: actually right before that show I'm biking coming home and I see up in the distance on the bike path a ton of cops everywhere and a crowd And I'm thinking I might have to take a weird detour big car accident.
Rym: And as I approach I discover a car has some has crashed in a place that it would take some effort to get a car Into completely blocking the bike lane and is completely just fucked up.
Rym: But the funny part is.
Rym: so I slow down and I'm kind of laughing and taking picture of it.
Rym: There's all these cops and I overhear one cop talking to the other cop.
Rym: I think they arrested the person who caused this accident.
Rym: based on what this collision based on a.
Scott: were they perhaps Intoxicated, uh, I don't know.
Rym: all I heard from the conversation was I still don't know how they got the car in there.
Scott: Well, I mean that's there's a whole division.
Scott: Yeah, that's like, you know that investigates.
Scott: Oh, yeah, how much of a problem right car crashes are.
Scott: they have an entire division of police who are detectives who are experts at?
Scott: Investigating that one exact thing and nothing else.
Scott: They you know, they look like tire tracks and then the damage on the car and they you know every you know.
Scott: So my dad actually I learned and figure out exactly what happened.
Rym: I weirdly learned a lot about that as a kid because my dad was a senior firefighter.
Rym: So a firefighter is usually part of those kinds of investigations Automotive forensics or whatever exactly because it overlaps a little bit with arson investigation type stuff.
Rym: So like the law enforcement forensics often include EMTs and firefighters and other people.
Rym: but also he knew a lot of cops and he had.
Rym: he had the expected low opinion of police officers that you would Expect from someone like my dad, but I remember his little kids.
Rym: one thing he would he taught me and my brother is like What happens when there's a big car accident?
Rym: Like we'd be driving and he'd see something he'd point out.
Rym: Oh, see, there's a guy in a white shirt right there and another guy in a white shirt.
Rym: Someone died.
Rym: Like he would tell.
Rym: like he taught us all these like here's how to know what's going on at a weird scene When there was a car collision of some kind.
Rym: So last the absolute bonkers story.
Rym: So Thursday morning the same day.
Rym: I encountered this accident.
Rym: There's a collision.
Rym: I'm driving biking to work.
Scott: It's not easy is it?
Scott: Website?
Rym: I try really hard to never say car accident because there are.
Scott: there are so few car Accidents that I can probably cover zero car accidents.
Rym: now Imagine imagine someone's driving 20 miles an hour and their car gets struck by lightning Killing them and it then rolls over someone else who was also struck by lightning.
Rym: That is an ad that is our.
Scott: That is an accident, but it's not a car accident.
Rym: That's a Weather accident, so I'm biking to work that same day on a city bike and a car pulls into the bike lane to like make an illegal left turn and clips a Delivery biker with his rearview mirror and the bikers fine.
Rym: the biker like swerves out of the way and flips them off and heads off And there's a bunch of other bikers around and it happens like right in front of me.
Rym: So I just like bike around the situation and keep going and here's some yelling and hawking behind me like whatever.
Rym: Just ignore that kind of situation.
Rym: definitely don't stick around for that kind of situation.
Rym: I keep biking I get to the next intersection and a car Like turns left and cuts across the bike lane and just stops like in front of me and some other bikers.
Rym: So I also ignore this situation.
Rym: I just like bike around it and keep going and I did not realize at that moment It was the same car that hit the delivery guy before Some fancy Benz.
Rym: so then I the third intersection.
Rym: There's a red light.
Rym: So I stopped.
Rym: there's a few other bikers there and suddenly someone comes up from behind me and forcibly pulls me off my stop city bike.
Rym: And this dude just starts screaming at me that I hit his car kick him in the nuts and run away.
Rym: So I did the move that I have done a few times in my life.
Rym: I highly recommend this move.
Rym: This is one of the surest ways to get out of this kind of situation.
Rym: Don't actually call the cops because that's a mixed bag, but pretend you're calling the cops.
Rym: So I back away from this guy a little bit and he's like holding on to the city bike and like you can't leave you Hit my car.
Rym: You can't leave his flipping the fuck out.
Rym: So I'm like, I'm gonna call the cops and I pull my phone out and I just like fake it.
Rym: I hold it up and he got.
Rym: he backs off a little bit and he seems to think that I'm gonna call the cops and The cops are gonna come and sort out his insurance situation with.
Rym: you know This biker that he claims hit him and then I just start saying nonsense.
Rym: I just start lying into the phone.
Rym: I'm like, yeah, this crazy guy is attacking me.
Rym: I'm on I'm on this street at this intersection?
Rym: No, this guy's flipping out.
Rym: I start describing the guy to nobody on my cell phone.
Rym: So the guy actually backs off a little bit more but he won't leave and he's like.
Rym: he seems to hesitate a little bit.
Rym: He looks down for a second and I just hop back into the city bike and fucking book it Behind me.
Rym: I hear him yelling you can't fucking get away from me and I hear a car door slam and tires screeching.
Rym: He screeches forward in the road almost causing a collision.
Rym: I said it right that time and he's clearly gonna try to like head me off the next intersection.
Rym: So I see his car just go past and then I just backtrack like 10 feet and just go down a side street And I'm gone and I have no idea how that situation resolved itself.
Scott: Do not engage the over dangerous person.
Rym: Nope, not at all, but I got to tell you head away.
Rym: Pretending to call the cops on someone loudly and in front of them is a Pretty easy way to get out of a lot of situations because unless someone is actually insane That'll give most agro people a tiny bit of pause.
Rym: Yeah, that was those are my biking stories.
Rym: got any news?
Scott: See what's in the news talk about that.
Rym: open the the program illegally packaged in 14 distributions.
Scott: Oh Okay, so yeah, so if you write a program in the go Programming language we did an episode about this right, you know, it's it's likely that it will be statically linked.
Scott: So any libraries that you included are going to also.
Scott: the code of those libraries will be included in your executable that you have.
Scott: You know you that comes out of the the go compiler, right?
Scott: which means You know that's different than say if you write a C program and you just dynamically link a library That means the person running the software has to go get that library on their own and install it somewhere else, right and that means Let's say you were to include some open source library in your software, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well if it's dynamically linked It doesn't really matter what you know.
Scott: you're.
Scott: the license of your program can be anything because you're only.
Scott: your program only includes code that you wrote.
Scott: So you can give it whatever license you want.
Scott: And even though it may depend upon code that someone else wrote it's not.
Scott: you're not including that you're not giving out copies of that.
Scott: You're just saying yeah If you want to use my program that has this license You're going to need to on your own obtain that other software that has a different license, you know.
Scott: But if it's statically linked well, it's included right.
Scott: you're giving out someone else's code along with your code and so this person, you know was looking into it and They found some software a lot of people are using.
Scott: that includes other software that has like no license.
Scott: What to speak of right and the license of the software that includes the no license software.
Scott: Right does not line up and it's it's like.
Scott: this is an open source, bro You can't be doing this but all kinds of people are doing it because who's paying?
Scott: or nobody is like You know checking these things over outside of large companies.
Rym: Well, never mind that the the status of how much enforcement you could get if any of this stuff is not a hundred percent settled in court.
Scott: Well, there's no info, you know, there's no reason to do any enforcement when none of these people, you know Even though these different open source slash free to various extent software's are You know, I guess.
Scott: well the one with no license isn't free, but it's just sitting there on github.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: You can see all the sir.
Scott: All right, it's like people are just using.
Scott: They just didn't bother to put a license on it.
Scott: So it's like no one's making any money.
Scott: There's nothing to Enforce.
Scott: what are you gonna enforce?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I guess you have to show what damage was caused to you.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there's nothing.
Scott: but you know, that's that's the problem there.
Scott: There was a copyright infringement surely.
Scott: But there's probably all sorts of incidents like this and I think it's a good argument that for open source Distributions you should be sticking to dynamically linked things, right?
Scott: To avoid these kind of situations and then you just need to check the licenses of the programs that you are directly Including because it's basically gonna be next to impossible to actually check all the licenses of statically linked things.
Scott: It's like you get to.
Scott: it's hard.
Scott: Yeah to find out what's in there, you know, it's a lot of effort.
Scott: So.
Rym: but yet this story kind of blew up because people like oh snap Oops, and this is the tip of the iceberg of this kind of thing just in the general open source ecosystem.
Scott: Of course, this happens all the time.
Scott: This the only reason this blew up is someone actually decided to take a few minutes to like look into it.
Rym: Yeah, it's like oh this probably happens every damn day Yep, and it's hard to say how more like how much of a problem it is.
Rym: Should anything be done about it like that's?
Rym: those are questions that very few people care about.
Rym: the answers to.
Scott: to be honest No, but if you're promising, you know open source software to someone else, you know You have to make sure that your your end is is legit.
Rym: Yeah, of course how many people just make stuff and license it Creative Commons But they use material that is not compatible with that license that they just got from somewhere.
Rym: You see that a lot out on the internet especially in creative works especially in GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah There is very little.
Rym: I will say that there's very little in GeekNights.
Scott: That is not duly licensed where we're conscious of it.
Rym: But you know Yeah, the one that's the most dangerous is also the one that only one person has ever recognized and a lot of.
Scott: there's a lot of panel slides that took just images from Google image only old ones actually.
Rym: I have been Extremely studious about getting licenses for every image we use or having a clear fair use defense for at least five years now.
Rym: every slide Yeah, and I don't be stuck.
Scott: Videos right there YouTube videos out there, right?
Scott: Which are you know, maybe?
Scott: and then the Zeke nights episodes of some audio clips here and there.
Rym: The stingers might not be a problem.
Rym: But anyway a little fun thing.
Rym: There's an app.
Rym: I'm not endorsing this app.
Rym: I have not like done a full security analysis of it or anything like.
Rym: do not Think that I am saying anything more than what I'm saying right now.
Rym: But me and Scott and a few of our friends are trying out this be real app, which is one.
Scott: It's the cool new thing.
Scott: The kids are doing and usually when the kids are doing a cool new thing Like the tick-tocks of the snapchats.
Scott: I just ignore that shit.
Scott: Yeah, but the be real is a cool new thing and I was like, alright, you know This seems like a thing that can replace wordle, right?
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna stick with it to replace wordles.
Scott: my thing Yep, I you know, it's basically the way it works is once a day at an unknown time.
Scott: You don't know when but it will be during a typical awake hour.
Rym: I'm curious to see what it's gonna do.
Rym: when I'm in London and you're all at home You can change the time.
Scott: There's four time selections.
Scott: You would change it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but I wonder what it'll do for me in regard to all of you.
Scott: You have to change it - anyway.
Scott: But yeah, see you It picks a time at random but it's the same time for everyone in your zone of the world, right the world?
Scott: I think they split into four or five pieces basically and a notification pops up.
Scott: So you have to give this app notification permission.
Scott: Otherwise, it's kind of useless.
Scott: And when that notification pops up you have two minutes to take a photo So you can't prepare anything like fucking Instagram or you know Photoshop anything?
Scott: But unless you sit there all day waiting for it You take a photo and it will take a photo simultaneously with both the front and rear cameras on your phone and then you can add a caption to it and then it posts it and You're basically You know sharing one photo a day.
Scott: You can't over share or under share, right?
Scott: Well, you could under share you guys not participate.
Scott: You don't see what anyone else shared that day unless you also share that day.
Scott: So there's like an incentive into sharing every day.
Rym: Yeah can post late if you miss it, but it tattles on you and tells all your friends Oh, we're in posted this one two hours late.
Rym: So read into that what you will.
Scott: Yeah, I cheated once right?
Scott: It's like you can cheat and just post late But it tells everyone and I'm sure there's probably some way to hack this thing.
Scott: It's like, you know, this only happens if you use the app in good faith.
Scott: you could Find some way to hack it and send you know interface with their API that I'm sure exists and just post whatever you want.
Rym: I guess here's what I like about it.
Rym: It's simple.
Rym: It just works.
Rym: It doesn't ask me to do a lot.
Rym: Like there's not a bunch of features and nonsense in there.
Rym: It doesn't charge don't scroll.
Rym: It doesn't show me any ads.
Rym: Yeah, I look at it exactly once a day.
Rym: There's nothing to look at in there unless I want to go look at my own history Which is already actually pretty interesting to be honest.
Scott: Yeah So, yeah, it's you know, I think it's really getting back to like what you know.
Scott: The a lot of the apps were like supposed to be in their their early days, right?
Scott: It's like there's this sort of problem where you know people's Instagram feeds or Facebook feeds.
Scott: They're taking pictures like the best exciting parts of their lives and you get sort of this false Impression that everyone's having a great time doing awesome shit all the time Like you think that we have share.
Rym: what if you like if I did my curated my life that way.
Rym: every day I'm either having a fancy cocktail or traveling the world or like on an epic bike ride.
Rym: But with be real I had an epic bike ride on Sunday But you know my be real photo is half awake in the dark in my pajamas watching a rerun of deep space 9 On the TV.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there are some days where it's like I did jack all that day But be real happens to pop up like it's something at least mildly interesting like the grocery store.
Scott: And there are other days where it's like I was at the beach and I was at a party right and when does be real pop up like After I've gotten home and I'm poking the computer and it's like I'm gonna get mostly poking the computer Photos here.
Scott: Why where were the rest of the day?
Scott: It's like, you know, but yeah, it's gonna.
Scott: you know It's a once a day thing.
Scott: It'll be entertaining for a brief period of time until the event as soon as they take advantage of you know privacy violating or Advertisement showing or send me a notification other than the notification that says it's be real time.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna delete it instantly.
Rym: So the listeners already pointed out, you know, I'm sensing a lot of porcelain throne picks.
Rym: that does not happen yet But but we're waiting for it.
Scott: We anticipate it.
Rym: All I'm gonna say is I've decided one I'm only gonna you be friends with people in this app that I am like close personal like in person serious friends with and to.
Rym: I'm gonna go hard.
Rym: I'm gonna do it if I'm pooping Guess what?
Scott: I mean, I wouldn't take a picture down low.
Rym: I'm not taking a picture of my poop and or You'd see my face.
Scott: you would see that I'm clearly in a bathroom and you would see the door to the bathroom or the back Of it.
Rym: You're gonna see what I'm up to.
Scott: some towels, I guess.
Rym: Okay, so in some other news There's a California school in Fresno high school and they have decided to ban cell phones full stop.
Rym: kids Just can't bring cell phones into the school.
Scott: Well in New York City They tried this at one point and what happened was there were these trucks that would set up outside the school and kids would pay the truck Person to take their phone hold on to it sort of like a coat check and then give the phone back when the kid left School,
Rym: yeah
Scott: for like a small, you know deposit fee.
Scott: Are these kids gonna just leave their phones at home or is someone gonna come along with a phone deposit truck?
Rym: I mean, this is all stupid.
Rym: You want to know why?
Rym: Schools suck and kids hate them.
Rym: shit like this.
Rym: the same Happen when we were kids.
Rym: I remember I got a deep shit because I brought.
Rym: I brought my walkman to school.
Rym: Walkman's were banned in my middle school despite the fact that I only used it to listen to music on the bus.
Rym: But the fact that it was in my locker was a big fucking deal to the school.
Rym: But anyway This is stupid.
Rym: That whole concept is stupid, but I want to point something out here.
Rym: The question is more around.
Rym: Why are schools doing this?
Rym: God, why would a school do this?
Rym: What are they?
Scott: Why did first-grade ban Trapper Keepers?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now on one hand some schools make the rationalization that these devices are distracting kids, but kids are.
Rym: Do you forget what it was like being a kid?
Rym: I could be distracted by nothing in middle school.
Rym: A leaf could blow by the window and I'm gone like Kids will distract themselves.
Rym: They'll draw the cool S on their desk if they have to.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I think what it is is that you know you That at least from the perspective of someone who went to American public schools Right is that there were problems with kids that would happen.
Scott: right, you know and various problems, right?
Scott: Like one kid has a Trapper Keeper.
Scott: The other one doesn't so it causes jealousy conflict, etc.
Scott: Right, or you know, it's like some kid has a cool hat and then you know other kid bullies and takes the hat.
Scott: or you Know these objects right become sort of involved in.
Rym: You know misbehavior conflict, but the key is the misbehavior conflict is the problem.
Scott: The bully kid is the problem not the fact Right, so they always so the teachers sort of see these objects magic cards Trapper Keepers phones Right, which are used for you know cyberbullying or whatever.
Scott: right are these tools or?
Scott: Catalysts that are being used and involved in all?
Scott: like every incident The teacher sees this something, you know, a phone is involved somehow or some object.
Scott: Is it so like?
Scott: let's get rid of all these things object?
Scott: because it's a thing they can actually do with their power that they had the limited power they had.
Rym: children have definitely never misbehaved in School until the advent of modern technology.
Rym: We know that Right.
Scott: It's like, you know it's but it's a thing that is within the power of the teachers and the school administration to ban objects of various kinds from the School.
Scott: and so because they can do it and it's like that's what they do, right?
Scott: They have the hammer and there's.
Rym: you know I think a lot of it is around this misplaced idea of this wanting a sense of control over the kids.
Scott: Yeah, but so that they end up doing it and it doesn't actually solve the real problem, which is that if the kids are Shitty or the teachers are shitty or the school system is shitty It's gonna be shitty no matter what they bring it.
Scott: you know what if you had an awesome school all the kids will be able to bring whatever they want and they would be Cool to each other because everyone would be cool.
Rym: You want to fix those problems?
Rym: I don't start my paying teachers more and have more teachers.
Rym: I mean you see like half the teachers in Ohio are gonna go on strike right before school starts because they're not gonna hate shit Good.
Scott: So I was.
Scott: it's like I say this all the time But like, you know give it.
Scott: my ideal life is a life of not working, right?
Scott: But if I have to work my ideal job would be like teach computers to kids.
Scott: that what's better than that.
Scott: Nothing's better than that.
Scott: I'd rather do that than do anything else, right?
Rym: That would make society better.
Rym: that I would gladly spend 40 hours a week doing not just doing but doing with with an actual sense of inspiration and purpose.
Scott: Enthusiastically doing why don't?
Scott: so why don't I do that?
Scott: I could do that.
Scott: Why don't I?
Rym: because you need a master's you'll have to get a master's.
Scott: The barrier the barrier to entry to do it is high.
Scott: It's harder to get that job than it is to get the job.
Scott: I have right.
Scott: number two.
Scott: I know because I understand the world that that job will not Consider can be the part of it that I imagine that I really want to do.
Scott: teach kids computers Will actually be a small percentage of that job mostly glorified babysitter being paid 30k a year.
Scott: Most of that job is going to be comprised of other bullshit.
Scott: that is not what I want to do which is help kids understand the joy of Computers and have a great time and learn and go on to lead wonderful lives and knowing computers better, right and three Right.
Scott: the compensation right.
Scott: considering the barrier to entry is high and the hassle of the job is high The compensation is lower.
Scott: It's worse way.
Scott: Magnitude orders of magnitude worse than the job I have which is easier to get and less hassle Right, so it's like why would anyone teach right?
Scott: But that's what they that's what the system right?
Scott: They well, they don't want good teaching because good teaching would bring about the good democracy.
Scott: right people in charge of our country don't want that because Democratic.
Rym: so not to get too much deeper because we got to move on to some other news and of course the main bit.
Rym: but the reason I bring up this story specifically is because Cellphones are different from a lot of the other things.
Rym: cool those band up to this point.
Rym: I would argue that cell phones are just an integral natural part of the modern world.
Rym: everyone having a smartphone in their pocket is not only a goal but a Positive the negative.
Rym: There are plenty of ways to handle the possible distractions of smartphones in a school.
Rym: and guess what when kids have a job After high school, they're gonna have a cell phone.
Rym: So they better learn.
Scott: I was mad about the same.
Scott: I was mad about calculators in the same way, right?
Scott: I was like, I'm gonna have a calculator my whole life.
Scott: Why would you have a no calculator test?
Rym: My high school never had no calculator tests.
Scott: We they were rare but they had them.
Scott: and even though the few we had I was mad.
Scott: I was like this bullshit.
Scott: and then they'd be like, you can't use a program on your calculator.
Scott: and I'm like, I wrote the program.
Rym: I had a very similar situation.
Rym: I also wrote a program that made it look like you were wiping all the programs off of your calculator.
Rym: We had that.
Rym: So, uh, why are schools mad about cell phones specifically, uh This story actually gives you a very clear window into that.
Rym: This ban comes not too long after this exact school had a problem Where a kid dressed up in a KKK hood in school and some shit went down.
Rym: and the reason this all came out?
Rym: Kids had cell phones.
Rym: They took fucking pictures of it and documented that it happened.
Rym: good Yeah I think schools are banning cell phones solely because They are afraid that the students will use the cell phones to document all the egregious shit that happens in our schools.
Scott: Good.
Rym: I think that is the sole reason schools are getting so aggressive on cell phones.
Rym: Everything else they say is an excuse.
Rym: This is the reason.
Rym: So on some other news, this is a dicey one remember a while back We're talking about Apple and their plan to detect hashes of see Sam which is an acronym for basically Child porn - you know that that whole story.
Rym: Well that type of technology doesn't actually work that well.
Rym: And now we have a specific case where that technology ran afoul of the real world, right?
Scott: So this dude had a kid and his kids junk had a medical issue.
Scott: So I had an infection.
Rym: Oh, you know what fun fact.
Rym: I had some medical issue with my junk when I bruised it in a bike accident not that long ago and guess what I did.
Rym: I Did the exact same thing this father did and a doctor saw looked at a picture of my junk that I sent to them with my smartphone Right.
Scott: So this guy takes a picture of his toddlers junk with his phone.
Scott: Yeah sends it to the doc his doctor his pediatrician Who prescribed antibiotics which cleared up the issue.
Scott: good job doctor, right?
Scott: He could just tell what it was from looking at it.
Scott: a plus, right.
Scott: so What happens is Google comes along and the automatic porn child porn detector detected some child porn and shut him down Right just deleted his account banned him etc.
Scott: And you know He goes.
Scott: and and also the police were notified and the police investigated.
Scott: right.
Scott: somehow miraculously The police Saw the truth.
Scott: They saw that exactly what had happened, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, they investigated there.
Scott: nothing wrong with investigating.
Scott: I don't see any problem with that.
Scott: That's prudent.
Scott: Right and But after they investigated they discovered no crime has been committed here.
Scott: This is not child porn.
Scott: This was perfectly fine.
Scott: We're not gonna do anything about it.
Scott: No charges.
Scott: No nothing Did.
Scott: they did the right thing?
Scott: Google didn't do the right thing.
Scott: Google's like you're banned forever.
Scott: We're not even gonna say anything.
Scott: We're not gonna do anything.
Scott: Right, you're just banned forever.
Scott: deal with it.
Scott: Yeah, all your photos are gone.
Scott: All your emails are gone.
Rym: Now this is where this whole Concept of using hashing algorithms to identify this type of content on platforms I would argue is at least today with present technology Fundamentally flawed in the same way that shot spotter is Fundamentally flawed in the same way that a bunch of news came out today.
Rym: We don't have time to talk about it, but our shot spotter causes more problems than it solves.
Scott: It's true It is, you know, it is a problem.
Scott: But I think that even in this case I don't.
Scott: I don't think this is a great argument for getting rid of the child porn.
Rym: This is a bad at most.
Rym: This is a great argument for companies like Google cannot do this stuff unaccountably and non-transparently Exactly right.
Scott: I wrote a whole thing in our forum, which you could join if you wanted to read it, right?
Scott: I wrote when the story came out.
Scott: I wrote a whole community dot firm crew calm.
Rym: Right.
Scott: is that there needs to be some sort of government consumer protection law?
Scott: Right that if you know we have online accounts some of the online accounts are just bullshit like our forum.
Scott: Okay, you should joy get a bullshit account today.
Scott: It's free but some accounts people their livelihoods depend on those accounts.
Scott: If you have an eBay account, you're running an eBay store.
Scott: That could be your job.
Scott: Are you running a YouTube account?
Scott: because you're a YouTube creator and that's your job.
Rym: Not only am I fucked if I somehow lost access to my Google account, but GeekNights is fucked like right.
Scott: It's like if I lose access to my Google account somehow.
Scott: not only am I fucked many other people are fucked on top of right That are under my digital umbrella, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's not just a hassle It's like a devastating life ruining thing and it should not be permitted to happen.
Scott: I'm not saying it shouldn't be permitted to happen under any circumstance.
Scott: If a Nazis on your platform you absolutely should fuck them over right, but Something like that an important account upon which someone's livelihood is dependent should not be able to be shut down without an open transparent review with some sort of judicial process.
Scott: Right and someone who has the human being with the power to make a decision yes or no Right should examine evidence and here, you know Some sort of it doesn't have to be a full-on fucking trial with a jury of your peers Even though that wouldn't be bad right but something you know.
Scott: an arbitrator I don't know.
Scott: right lawyers figure it out, but there needs to be something.
Scott: there can't just be Automated email that says no with no explanation with no recourse would know.
Rym: This is the logical conclusion of mega corpse like Google and Amazon and Facebook one existing and two Aggressively moving to a model where there is no way to ever talk to a human to get help under any circumstances.
Rym: I dare you to interact with Google in a way where a human will talk to you, right?
Scott: We need a. well I can do it because we have that.
Scott: if you pay for Google workspaces You can do now whatever they change the name of it to now It's it.
Scott: but yeah, if you know is how much?
Rym: how do we actually get in that whole situation?
Scott: now you need to Have.
Scott: we need a consumer protection law that forces their hand, right?
Scott: You must have a human being who can talk and will listen and knows what's up, etc, etc, right?
Scott: Yeah, some sort of remedy must exist and it currently does not and your life can just be fucked over for no reason, right?
Rym: unjustly, but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: so check this out.
Rym: This is a tweet thread with 16 tweets and each of these is an image from an illustrated hand scroll from the 1850s in Japan.
Rym: that was seven meters long and it shows the entire process end-to-end of How sake was made in?
Rym: cowboy times in Japan Mmm, and it is annotated and it is Absolutely.
Rym: Delightful.
Rym: This this is actually a fun journey to follow start to finish.
Scott: This is sake made with great difficulty But also at a scale like it's funny because the the Japanese equivalent of like in America.
Rym: We've got the trope of the jug with three X's on it in Japan.
Rym: I feel like it's that big Like yellowish barrel looking thing that sake comes in with the writing on the side and the ropes around it same thing Yep.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Rym: That's just a jug with three X's on it.
Scott: Pretty much.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So this dude?
Scott: He decided, you know, he likes typewriters and you know, I kind of like the aesthetic of a typewriter.
Scott: The problem is you sit down to use one for a few minutes and it's like, okay The keyboards actually not as nice as my mechanical keyboard Even though it's aesthetically cooler.
Scott: and then as soon as you make a mistake in typing and you press backspace, you're like, oh fuck what you're not one.
Rym: not.
Rym: even when I was like In elementary school our typewriter had a backspace that actually worked and would remove whiteout.
Scott: Yeah Well, it wasn't a white house at the X was the X kind.
Rym: it wasn't white out But it was very similar to white out how it actually worked.
Rym: I don't want to get into it.
Rym: It's odd.
Rym: It's more complicated than you think.
Rym: the way backspace worked on electric typewriters is way different than you think It was.
Rym: that'll be my next thing of the day.
Scott: Anyway proceed sure but anyway, this guy hooks up his typewriter to his computer, right and He basically hooks up the terminal to the typewriter.
Scott: So now when he types on the typewriter, it's typing on the paper but it's also sending those characters to the computer as Terminal input.
Scott: and then when he presses enter and the terminal makes output The typewriter is printing the output as like it's a printer.
Rym: that is.
Rym: that is super cool Because that is kind of how it was to interact with terminals in the early days.
Scott: Yeah, the only difference is that you know, you can if you type something LS it works great, right?
Scott: but it's if you want to open up a terminal app where it's actually redrawing that's just gonna or You know this print a whole page after you hit enter.
Scott: Yeah, you know it could become and it's also really slow and noisy obviously, but it's still pretty cool.
Scott: But you know, I encourage people to.
Scott: it's all video series.
Scott: watch as much of it as you feel But there's a charm to that.
Scott: Yeah, but if you are interested in any of this you should Google.
Scott: There's plenty of resources telling you exactly how terminals TTY works And it's an important thing to know because I feel like even a lot of computer people these days.
Scott: They just click on terminal the application on their computer or whatever whatever they're using.
Scott: putty I term like a gnome terminal Whatever right and they don't know actually what the hell's going on behind that thing.
Scott: And it's kind of important to know and really helpful to know.
Rym: Yep The history of computing is wrapped up in this one of the first things I ever did Connected before I even had access to the internet.
Rym: I was able to basically Mess me and a guy were able to use terminals to mess with each other's computers directly Via a phone line that we just called each other on and we did some fun stuff with that.
Rym: That was like my introduction to networking mm-hmm.
Rym: In the moment the GeekNights book club book is Binti.
Rym: It's a very short read.
Rym: I don't think I we could probably do it on Thursday next week.
Scott: All right, you said that last Thursday We didn't do a Thursday show.
Rym: Have you started yet?
Scott: I didn't I didn't.
Scott: I still haven't even read one page.
Rym: Well, let me double check my travel schedule.
Rym: GeekNights.
Rym: I'll warn you all now in the meta moment GeekNights is gonna get actually moderately disrupted in September because one I'm Emily and I are flying to Seattle to do a panel or two at PAX West And also I do have to do a work trip.
Rym: I got to go to London and Frankfurt, so I'm gonna be gone for a couple weeks and bring back over it again.
Rym: Well, we'll see.
Rym: This is not going to a convention.
Rym: This is just going to my offices there.
Rym: So I should be able to avoid pretty much all people and wear a mask and like it won't be like the conference I went to in London
Scott: Airplanes trouble, uh
Rym: Probably not because I can just wear a mask on the airplane and I'll be in business class pretty isolated from everyone.
Rym: I'm not not actually worried about that.
Rym: I am 100% sure I caught it at the conference when I was in London last time based on the timing Anyway.
Rym: But also Emily and I are doing a long bike trip.
Rym: We're gonna bike from our apartment to Brockport, which is a little bit past Rochester, New York over the course of a week.
Rym: So Might be several weeks of no GeekNights as a result.
Rym: Just gonna give you guys a heads up on that.
Scott: that'll give me some time for things that start with the letter B like biking going to the beach and Building.
Rym: Meanwhile, you're gonna get a lot of side content on that bike trip.
Rym: One thing we do want to do is Record a little like progress thing every day of the journey because we're basically biking 500 miles.
Rym: over the course of a week Rym fell down three times.
Scott: today We got this yet another thing.
Scott: it starts with the bones.
Scott: what bones are remaining?
Rym: yep, how much dysentery did you Ford that River?
Scott: We're On a ferry right now.
Scott: good thing good thing we got money.
Rym: So, yeah, that's all the meta I got.
Rym: I guess we can dive right into it.
Rym: Let's talk about smartphones cuz.
Scott: uh one Apple is coming up right now is like the peak Smartphone season right.
Scott: the pixels 6a just came out which is the like the second tier pixel phone, right?
Scott: I think it.
Scott: I think 6a right?
Scott: I think I'm right.
Scott: And then the iPhone.
Scott: right.
Scott: early September is when they're gonna.
Scott: Apple is gonna have like the biggest Announcements right you've ever seen right?
Scott: It's like we always know.
Scott: early September is the announcement time, but we got new phones.
Scott: There's gonna be new Apple watch for sure.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Those are those are guaranteed, right?
Scott: I'm hoping for new AirPods Pro 2. if they don't make those I won't buy them But I think they hopefully they'll come soon.
Scott: There's gonna be some new iPad action and there might be some other Macs that don't have m2 chips in them yet.
Scott: We'll get upgraded to m2 chips.
Scott: There's gonna be a lot of Apple shit.
Scott: All right Regardless it is new phone season, especially going to the holiday season back-to-school season, right?
Scott: Even if new phones weren't coming out now is the time when people are buying new phones.
Scott: So whether you are buying a brand new phone, you never had one before cuz you're punk kid Or just weren't wealthy before or who knows Or you're replacing a phone, right?
Scott: We're gonna give a bunch of tips on what the hell you should do Yep.
Rym: So number one the most important thing is I mean, I'm not gonna say do you need a smartphone?
Rym: What are you gonna use it for like that high level?
Rym: because I would argue that everyone who can afford a smartphone Should probably have a smartphone.
Scott: Part of the world where there is service for the smartphone Yeah, it it's.
Scott: probably it's beneficial for you to have it.
Rym: So the real question is What other devices do you have or expect to have?
Rym: So that you can think about where and how that smartphone fixed it fits into your life.
Rym: case in point I have a laptop and a workstation.
Rym: So for me a smartphone is Primarily that my access to data when I'm traveling or not near those other devices.
Rym: So as a result, I got that Possible phone.
Rym: Yeah, this is for pooping and biking and like being out in the street.
Rym: I got something that'll fit in my pocket and I really only use it when I'm away from my real devices and that Really colors what I care about in a smartphone.
Rym: compared to someone who say you don't have a home computer You don't have a laptop Do you want a smartphone that is also your primary device for literally everything or do you want a smartphone and separate?
Scott: It's a perfectly legitimate choice given the prices of these smartphones these days.
Rym: It absolutely is.
Rym: or do you want a small fart smartphone?
Rym: I almost said fart phone and And a tablet because a tablet is a very different thing from a smartphone.
Rym: But you have to decide what kind of life do you live?
Rym: Some people are best off with a big smartphone.
Rym: Some people are best off with a tiny smartphone and a big-ass tablet.
Scott: And some people are off with a high-end Smartphone the newest most powerful one.
Scott: some people are better off with like, you know You can get a lower-end model right or a cheaper model right or you know older one.
Scott: They still sell, you know iPhone what you know.
Scott: You can get the like.
Scott: I just said the 6a came out which is not the most powerful Pixel phone, right?
Scott: Yeah, you can get an iPhone 11. still you can get the iPhone SE, right?
Scott: There's a new iPhone SE in fact new ish right you can get one of those.
Scott: It's like that might be good enough for you.
Scott: Yeah, you know, you might not need to get.
Scott: you definitely know iPhone 13.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: yeah, that's probably just fine for just about anyone.
Scott: The iPhone 13 Pro is kind of just a ridiculous thing.
Scott: Even if that's your only computing device It's like.
Scott: it's not that much better than iPhone 13 except for the cameras.
Scott: Like though here's an example somehow are making really high quality photos and videos But you don't have another camera.
Scott: then the iPhone 13 Pro makes sense.
Scott: Otherwise, it doesn't another use case.
Rym: if you're doing photogrammetry and you want to use that lidar and you want to do scan scans Of 3d games that is something that there's really no other cheap device that's gonna do it.
Rym: That is such a win for you to buy that specific file.
Scott: But how many people is that?
Scott: Almost nobody exactly.
Rym: So If you're the kind of person who's got something weird like that going on.
Rym: You don't need our advice.
Rym: I assume you already have a very clear plan of what kind of devices you need But for most people it doesn't really matter that much.
Rym: So it really comes down to do you want a laptop?
Rym: Do you want a phone plus other devices or just a phone?
Rym: because if you want just a phone I actually would say you probably want to get a bigger phone and It's pretty much 50/50 Android or iPhone.
Scott: if you're in there I think you know, the Android or iPhone thing is really going to depend on what else is going on in your life, right?
Rym: So do you already have one of the two and a lot of apps and things you have paid for on that device?
Scott: Yeah, just stick with it.
Scott: You'll stick with what.
Scott: if you're already on one, you know, it's like, you know You could argue all day about which one's better than the other but if you're already in one of them It's like that one's probably better for you Unless you're so barely invested in it.
Scott: that switch at your switching cost is low.
Rym: I made the switch from Android to iPhone.
Rym: if you know what the switching cost kind of high like it's not.
Rym: it kind of sucks To switch from the Google Android ecosystem to the iPhone ecosystem or vice versa Like if you're already in one and you don't have a specific complaint or a specific need Don't switch like only switch if you have a good reason to Yep.
Scott: But yeah, it's like what do you use for?
Scott: do you have email already?
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like if you already got email and it's Gmail you might want to go the Google way, right?
Scott: Yeah, if you're some kid who's never had a phone before right?
Scott: It's like well, you don't have an email either way.
Scott: Well, what do your parents have?
Scott: What do your friends have?
Scott: Right?
Scott: You know if you if your friends are all a messaging get iPhone so you can I message with them in this time with them.
Scott: If your friends, you know if your parents have Google accounts, right?
Scott: It's like, you know Your dad's got an Android phone or your guardian whoever has Android phone get an Android phone.
Scott: It'll be more compatible with what they have.
Scott: if your parents have iPhones, right?
Scott: You can get an iPhone and I watch and now they can do that shit where they you know They can find you.
Scott: if you get lost in the woods because I buy an I have Apple watch or die.
Scott: This is Apple's marketing still.
Scott: Yeah, your children will die.
Rym: So one thing I would say and I actually I have very prescriptive advice.
Rym: I don't think Scott will disagree If now this might change soon because there are new Android watches like Android were things coming and there are apparently some big changes, but if you want a smart watch I Would say go Apple because the Apple watch is perfectly fine And the best Android watch I have ever used is kind of shit.
Scott: Yes, there's if there's.
Scott: if you really need the smartwatch as a part of your life for reasons You really just got to go the Apple way the you know.
Rym: Even back when I was deep in the Android ecosystem, and it was not considering switching I was very vocal about the fact that every app every Android watch is absolute garbage.
Rym: There are no good ones.
Rym: They just there are so many Terrible annoyances with them and the Apple watches.
Rym: by comparison.
Rym: They just.
Rym: they have intelligent defaults and they kind of just work in a way that no Android Accessory is capable of if you don't care about the watches.
Rym: This does not apply to you.
Rym: But if you care about a watch and you want a smartwatch in my opinion There is no answer but an Apple watch.
Rym: and if you want an Apple watch There is no answer but an Apple phone.
Rym: the choice is made for you.
Rym: That is the only factor that matters.
Scott: the benefits of the watch.
Scott: If you're not sure if you want one or not, right is obviously the you know Their major selling point for all the watches not just the Apple ones.
Scott: Is that?
Scott: oh, we'll prevent you from dying.
Scott: We'll detect if your heart is going crazy.
Scott: It's like, you know that you may believe that it's partially true, right?
Rym: The o2 monitors, they're great.
Scott: Yeah, the.
Scott: the real benefits of the watch is that number one.
Scott: if you have the LTE watch Which is gonna cost you a little bit every month You can actually go and leave your phone behind which is great if you're running or swimming or anything of that nature.
Scott: Right, you could just go with the watch only and you won't miss an important emergency phone call Or anything like that and you don't have to carry a phone around no matter how small even without the LTE.
Rym: Sometimes I often run.
Rym: I don't even carry my phone.
Rym: I just have my watch even without the LTE.
Rym: I guess the 5g.
Rym: now it still works because they can still do things like Strava.
Rym: It just doesn't have the communication aspects, right?
Scott: But I mean if someone were to make an emergency phone call you wouldn't yeah, I wouldn't get.
Scott: there was Wi-Fi or something.
Scott: You just happen to be here.
Rym: but like around the apartment I guess where my watch and it'll take I don't actually have to have my phone on me.
Rym: in the apartment.
Rym: my watch Which just has Wi-Fi will buzz.
Rym: I could even take the call on it if I need to.
Scott: yeah, the things I use on my watch the most often are a Notifications show up on the watch so I don't have to get my phone out of my pocket Which my watch is.
Scott: how I don't be real Right, and then that's how I don't have to turn the phone on.
Scott: the phone's battery lasts longer Of the watch right now, they don't have to use the phone as much to Strava.
Rym: I use Strava and the heart rate meter and exercise like that is.
Rym: that is my primary workflow on my watch.
Scott: I did until I got the bike computer and now I use that instead.
Scott: Yeah, I mean most of my sports are if I was running I would use Strava on the watch.
Rym: I mean I do.
Rym: most of what I do is skiing.
Rym: running.
Rym: biking is actually a secondary concern But also at this point I don't even bother with the bike computer.
Rym: my phone and watch handle everything I could ever need me.
Scott: My my computer is also a GPS and whatnot.
Scott: Anyway, so the other thing the watch does is Payments, right?
Scott: So it's like yeah, you can do is Apple pay or Android pay with the phone.
Rym: Good fucking luck.
Rym: Do you know how many times?
Rym: Android at pay on a watch was fucky or didn't work.
Rym: Right?
Rym: Why right?
Rym: or like it?
Scott: yet to reauthenticate the Apple payment on the watch just works Yep, so it's like pay, you know, it's like you think oh I get to take my phone out and use the Apple pay.
Scott: Yeah, that works great.
Scott: But Apple pay on the watch is just like even faster.
Rym: It is literally just you double tap a button and just hold it up to whatever and everything just works.
Scott: It just pays instantly you're done Yeah, so if you're you know, pretty much every almost every business I interact, you know where it doesn't work sit down restaurants.
Rym: They need a credit card.
Rym: You can't even so lately.
Scott: There's a I big.
Scott: in just the past month I've experienced this.
Scott: there are more and more sit-down restaurants using some payment system where they bring you the receipt.
Scott: Oh, yeah He has the receipt has a QR code and you you can't use the watch for this.
Scott: Obviously you photo the QR code with the phone and then you pay with Apple pay or Android pay or whatever.
Scott: The payment thing is on your phone.
Scott: Yeah, and then you just leave You don't have to wait.
Rym: I have seen more and more places doing the European style like just in the last couple months as well where they bring the POS right to the table and you pay right there and I can just scan my watch at the thing that they hold out for it all.
Scott: Just that that happens occasionally outside of the u.s.
Rym: That's the default but the u.s You know, we're archaic in a lot of ways.
Scott: So Alright, so if you get a new phone, you've never had a phone before right?
Scott: What I would recommend you do is get an account right.
Scott: assuming you never had a phone before it means like you don't have an Email you don't have you know anything right.
Scott: get accounts, right?
Scott: That match the phone.
Scott: if you have an iPhone just use the iCloud email the right.
Scott: use all this stuff, right?
Scott: If you have a Google Android phone then get you know Gmail right a new account.
Rym: I would say if you have a very mixed ecosystem that already exists, but somehow are not using a phone.
Rym: Android is probably your best just default bet because Generally all the random stuff that isn't Apple all kind of just works there.
Rym: Well, but Apple does like to guide you toward using the Apple stuff.
Scott: So if you do but the Google Google has apps for a Google and Microsoft both have apps for pretty much everything on iPhone It'll all work just fine.
Rym: Mostly you have to do some extra configuration.
Rym: Like I had to do some fuckery to make sure all my calendar stuff on all my Apple biz Defaults to updating my Google Calendar and not the Apple like built in.
Scott: Oh, oh see I think I just installed the Google Calendar app and I never used the Apple Calendar app.
Rym: But like I use a reminder I was like, hey set a reminder.
Rym: like I every now and then I use some automation or some Non-calendar function and I wanted to make a calendar invite and before I configured it it would default to the Apple calendar.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I just never use any of that.
Rym: I'm saying that's a. if you have a bunch of non Apple stuff You will have to go configure a bunch of things and you're not gonna get all of them right away.
Scott: on your app You tell Siri to like make a calendar event and you only have Google Calendar and it's not set up.
Rym: and like yeah It might be a head but on Android whatever random collection of bullshit you use Android is really good about defaulting to whatever you tell it to and not having edge cases like that.
Scott: Yep, check would you know, if you use any apps clearly use something.
Scott: cuz you listen to a podcast.
Rym: Yeah I want to know who is who will ever hear the words?
Rym: We're saying who does not already have a smartphone or at least an email account.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like if you exist contact us, however, it is you contact people.
Rym: I really want to talk to you like That's a pigeon or Raven's gonna show up at your house.
Scott: Like I don't know But you get the account that goes with the phone.
Scott: you get right and try and what I see a lot of people what they Do is when they get the when they get a phone is like oh what apps should I install?
Rym: Never never never go down that road.
Rym: That is that that path leads you to misery.
Scott: do not ask that question.
Scott: What apps should you install instead?
Scott: Just start using start using the phone and living your life right with the phone without Putting any extra apps on there, right.
Scott: and then whenever you need to do something Right try to do it with the phone as it is, right?
Scott: So it's like oh I need directions.
Scott: Well, I guess that would be the one I was about to say.
Rym: I was gonna do a whole salary.
Scott: the one exception Is he even on the Apple phone?
Rym: You should use Google Maps no matter what device you use anywhere on earth.
Rym: use Google Maps and do not use any other maps.
Scott: Fuck at least as of as of August 2022, actually, you know, yes.
Scott: And for the other the other app the other maps are catching up to Google Maps.
Scott: They're just still not there yet Which they are still significantly behind in key areas as of today.
Scott: They are very behind but they are.
Scott: Google Maps is progressing more slowly and they're progressing more quickly.
Scott: So in a few years time, it could change but as I now doubt it, but we'll see it's possible.
Scott: But as of now use Google Google Maps to be the only thing.
Scott: don't use the Apple Mac.
Rym: It's like you live in San Francisco, then it might be okay Especially if you use Google Maps for things like biking directions like stuff That isn't just looking at what restaurants are nearby or like getting a car direction.
Rym: I also don't super trust the Apple car directions.
Rym: I have compared them before, you know on trips and Apple does not seem to be aware of traffic in a way that Google is.
Rym: but anyway Google bought ways And ways had it shit together.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah for everything besides directions if you need to do something Just you try to use the apps that are already on the phone to do that thing.
Rym: Well, I guess I use Google keep and I continue to use it when I migrated to iPhone.
Scott: However, I also use Google key.
Rym: if I were not already using Google keep when I made the switch I would probably just use like the Apple reminders and that would be it.
Scott: No, the Apple notes also an Apple notice.
Scott: keep is sort of both of those in one exactly.
Rym: But I'm already using keep.
Rym: but guess what keepers is my asks.
Scott: I guess is more like the reminders.
Rym: Yeah Well, my worry is keep and tell.
Rym: again the problem with Google is all their shit overlaps in weird ways.
Rym: So absolutely keep is in a Venn diagram with like two other Google things that themselves are in a Venn diagram With a bunch of stuff on iPhone.
Rym: So Scott's advice is best If you don't already have a way that you do this that you like that works.
Rym: Just do whatever the phone makes easiest and it'll probably be the best option All right.
Scott: And then when you get into a situation where you want to do something with the phone you have a need that is not fulfilled.
Scott: Then go find an app that does that thing.
Rym: and my specific advice there look for an.
Rym: I hate to say this Look for an app that costs money And avoid apps that are free with ads just generally.
Scott: well avoid anyone with ads for sure.
Scott: Sometimes there will be a one that's just free free.
Scott: That's truly free.
Scott: That's good, but you know spend your time investigating them trying them out in seeing you know Which app is gonna be the best one that meets this need that you don't have that is not fulfilled by the default apps on The phone.
Scott: now there's a lot of just about everybody has a phone full of apps that they don't even use Right 99% of the time just taking up space Invading their privacy eating up the battery.
Rym: There's a shit ton of apps full of malware on the Android store that were only recently taken down.
Rym: There's also the thing we're like tick tock just straight up.
Rym: can key log you if you open its in-app browser?
Scott: Yep, it's like you really do not want to use an app.
Scott: if you're not using the app, right?
Scott: Keep it minimal.
Scott: All right as much as you possibly can and if you've got a new phone, it's easiest to do So if you already have an iPhone and you're buying a new iPhone Oh, hey, there's one last thing which I guess also applies if you're switching phones.
Scott: This applies to everybody.
Scott: is that whenever you get a new device, right?
Scott: especially if it's you've never had one before go to the settings menu and Go through.
Scott: just look at every single Setting.
Scott: go to every single settings menu from the top down and look at every setting.
Rym: Don't necessarily change anything just understand.
Scott: Oh, no, not to change anything, but you should read every setting understand what that setting means and If you're not like a hundred percent sure that you want to change the setting like you're absolutely want to change it Don't change it.
Scott: But just go through every setting completely understand all of them and just know and remember which ones Exist.
Scott: and then as you use the phone you might come across a frustrating thing and you'll remember there was a setting for that Yeah, and then you'll change the setting to you know to realize your preference, you know, it doesn't align with it Yeah, but a lot of people just never go into their settings never change them never do anything.
Scott: Anytime I get a new phone anytime there's an OS update anytime that anything, you know, even on computers I go to the settings and I look through every possible setting and I make sure that they are set correctly.
Scott: Usually it's rare that I change something but You know, that's how it's very important to just know what's in there.
Rym: Yep corollary to that Don't hyper customize everything right away until you've used whatever the device is enough to get a sense of how it works and what you like and what you don't like.
Rym: a lot of nerds in particular like to customize everything before they even try to use the thing and That is often a way to Increasingly get yourself into weird situations like oh my shit.
Scott: This is thing is broken.
Scott: It's not working Yes, cuz you messed with it a whole bunch.
Rym: So in terms of the hardware itself, if you've got bad eyesight and like it's a problem get a bigger phone Sure.
Rym: I thought I can increase the font size and you should yep.
Rym: granted I prefer tiny phones any fonts, but I can see really well.
Rym: So that's something I have.
Scott: the I mean I can see really well.
Scott: and I'm turning up the font size.
Scott: Anyway, it's like I can read the small font size, right?
Scott: Just like I can read the bottom of the eye chart.
Scott: right.
Scott: even someone with 20/20 perfect vision They can read the bottom of the eye chart, but you know what?
Scott: It's still easier to read a giant e that it is - at the top.
Rym: I've actually I've turned the font sizes way down on my iPhone just to fit more information on there.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I don't have problems.
Rym: girl I watch has like that's high.
Rym: It's just like a full web browser and tiny text on there and I could read it just fine.
Scott: I mean I can.
Rym: I can read it on the wall Like I prefer it that way.
Rym: I like small fonts and dense text on all my devices That's right.
Scott: Well your rims rims are weird.
Scott: Oh does everything weird, but it's like make the font size Whatever is comfortable for your eyeball, right?
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but If you care about battery life You're gonna have to either get a big phone or an expensive phone.
Rym: Yep, phone small that aren't very expensive will not have long battery life.
Scott: No, the number one thing that kills battery life is you know apps that are running all the time doing bullshit, right and Screens that are big and bright and are on too much right?
Scott: It's like watching videos.
Scott: The screen is on.
Scott: it's bright because you're watching something.
Scott: It's just not.
Scott: the screen is what's eating your battery.
Scott: So that's why the watch saves so much battery.
Scott: because you're turning the screen on less, right?
Scott: The phone is in your pocket.
Scott: The screen is not on.
Scott: the battery is is barely draining, right?
Scott: You know big phones.
Scott: they got a bigger screen, but they also got a bigger battery.
Scott: So that sort of evens out the deal there, but you can also turn the brightness down, right?
Scott: It's like if it's night, you know You don't need that much brightness to be able to see what's on the phone.
Scott: You know, there's some usually an auto brightness setting.
Scott: You should enable that but also occasionally manually adjust it.
Scott: if it's too bright turn it down, right?
Scott: You should only really need to do high brightness like if you're using your phone in the Sun or something like.
Rym: yeah, if you use an Android device get whatever battery.
Rym: if you're using an iPhone honestly get that Apple magnetic battery.
Scott: that is well So the Apple I learned recently.
Scott: I bought the Apple mag safe battery.
Scott: I'm happy with it.
Scott: It's very nice.
Scott: I love that thing but it actually doesn't have that much capacity.
Rym: No, it's like what two-thirds of a charge?
Scott: Yeah, well, it's more than that, but it's the.
Scott: I only bought it because it was like the first one, right?
Scott: It was like there weren't any other competitors.
Scott: Anchor now has a mag safe battery That is vastly higher capacity than the official thing is.
Rym: I don't think I need that because my current phone with no battery will make it all day doing pretty much anything.
Rym: That battery is only for weird situations or something Like.
Rym: I am hiking literally 20 miles over the course of an entire day and I want to stop.
Scott: That's basically what I do too.
Scott: It's like if most days my phone is in my house I can plug it in to charge it whenever I don't need to attach a battery to it.
Scott: Yeah, but if I'm going out somewhere for a long extended period of the day I'm not gonna have an opportunity to charge right?
Scott: am I going to a convention?
Scott: I'm going on a bike ride I'm going to a party right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: then I got I grabbed the battery and I attach it to the phone.
Scott: So I know for sure that I'm not gonna run out of power.
Scott: I probably still won't run out of power without the battery.
Scott: It's just a guarantee like there's no way I'm gonna run out of battery, which is very important.
Rym: Mm-hmm But for anything super serious like trips, I usually just have an external heavy battery that I plug in via cable.
Rym: But that's cuz.
Rym: I'm not using it while I'm like walking around.
Scott: That would be if you're like in a multi-day scenario right where you were not going to have access to power camping.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Scott: Anyway, so the other phone accessory that a lot of people get are cases.
Rym: I was about to say you have to be you have to be introspective You have to look at your own life.
Rym: If you're up if you're replacing an existing phone look at that phone and use it as an example.
Rym: Are you the kind of person who destroys your phones?
Rym: Routinely?
Rym: or are you the kind of person who does not?
Rym: and Honestly, if you can get away with it, I'd advise using no case whatsoever.
Rym: It's really pleasant to use a phone naked.
Rym: They're designed for that.
Rym: However, if you have a history or you believe that you are the kind of person who is gonna drop your phone a bunch And you taste on it because that is a very expensive piece of hardware.
Scott: Well, I'd say before you put the case on the phone.
Scott: I would say you should look at yourself, right?
Scott: It's you can change yourself.
Rym: I Am already getting past the point of I don't think the people who break phones routinely can change that about themselves.
Scott: It may be the case, but if it is possible, right, you know, at least in my life I always seek to change myself before I will change.
Scott: Let's try to change the world.
Rym: I have never put my phones in cases in my entire life and I've never regretted it.
Scott: I did when I you know got like iPhone 3g like way back in the day.
Rym: I think by.
Scott: I think by the time the iPhone before the iPhone 3g was done I had taken the case off and I don't think any other iPhone.
Scott: I had got a case.
Scott: Yeah, and I only broke a phone once when I fought my bike.
Rym: So when I fell off my bike, you know in the injury where I had to take a picture of my fell off on my own Damn self.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: nothing else caused me to follow just my own self.
Rym: No, my my fall over was a pothole that I was too slow to react to.
Scott: but I was just like standing there And I fell over sideways.
Scott: Oh, no Everybody was in my bag And when I got to work, I took the phone out of the bag and it was broken.
Rym: But one thing I will say is that it's about all phones, but especially iPhones.
Rym: But there are like Sony Android phones are similar in this boat.
Rym: They are way more durable in the year 2022 than you probably realize.
Rym: Phone durability has gone way just in the last couple years.
Rym: Like it is skyrocketed Well, I think it's been.
Scott: I think it's been progressing gradually right and and constantly.
Rym: I think it might have hit a tipping point between that like the new sapphire glass and some of the stuff they're doing this iPhone like 13 SE.
Rym: So I flipped over my handlebars and the phone was in my hand at the time like like like held in one of my hands.
Rym: So I flipped over and I landed with my full body weight on my phone on rough concrete.
Rym: The phone was completely fine.
Rym: it has the tiniest scratch.
Rym: Phones are fucking durable as crap nowadays.
Scott: a lot of my previous phones Which I did not put cases on right would often by the time I was done with them have various like You know minor scratches and cosmetic damage, you know rough edges a few maybe like a dent here or there, right?
Scott: Micro scratches things like that.
Scott: right this iPhone 12 is almost two years old, right?
Scott: Cuz iPhone 14s are going to be announced in a month.
Scott: Yeah, right It's almost.
Scott: it's almost two years old.
Scott: if I clean the screen it is 100% smooth right 100%.
Scott: there is not any visible scratch of even a small cosmetic nature Anywhere on that screen.
Scott: I could probably you know I've never put my phone in my pocket with my keys and I still won't but I probably could.
Scott: yeah Right because something that they've done has just made it that much better.
Scott: you may not need it.
Scott: if you're only slightly clumsy right and not, you know, extremely clumsy and Haphazard you may be able to get away without a case Whereas previously you needed one now.
Rym: that said this really only applies to the upper tier Android phones like the.
Scott: the high quality ones from the expensive phones are the more durable phones.
Scott: Cheap ones are made of plastic with less expensive glass and they break eat more a much more easily.
Rym: But the cheapest iPhone is more durable than like the middle-range Android phone on average.
Scott: Yeah, it depends on which one it is.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, if you can get away with it get away with it.
Scott: And the final topic is cables, right?
Scott: Hopefully the iPhone 14 will take you as BC.
Scott: We're hoping for it, right?
Scott: We're gonna find out soon.
Rym: I hate I hate this lightning cable.
Rym: I hate everything about lightning cables.
Scott: I hate the fact the only device you got one device of the lightning cable and everything else in your whole life is like Yes, I had to buy a bunch of lightning cables when I bought this fucking iPhone.
Scott: Right by whatever phone you got by third-party cables that are high quality.
Scott: if you buy cheap cables They're gonna break.
Scott: you can get nice freaking long ones that are durable as hell.
Scott: You can get a third-party charger with like a whole bunch of charging on it right that charges fast, right?
Scott: Don't use the friggin included charger nonsense unless that's all you've got.
Scott: really.
Rym: it's like yeah, you know and I guess last in terms of actually the logistics of you have a new phone And you had an old phone as opposed to nothing.
Rym: if it's an Apple device Just do the Apple thing.
Rym: that like basically just copies everything over to your new phone.
Rym: It just works on Android.
Rym: Honestly, yeah, there there are sort of equivalents.
Rym: I would advise especially with Android Just setting everything up brand new on your new Android phone and only using the Android sync stuff to copy over your data dot and maybe use the App Store to copy over the apps you have installed.
Rym: but Honestly, the Android experience is not nearly as good in that I've never experienced that.
Scott: I guess you've never experienced switching from one iPhone to another iPhone.
Scott: I will at some point the way the way it works.
Rym: you put it next to each other and they say hi Right.
Scott: It used to be it used to be more difficult.
Scott: But the way it works now Is that you have iCloud backup enabled which I strongly recommend.
Scott: having a backup of your phone Right because you're gonna want to set the security setting on your phone to automatically erase your phone If someone tries to log in and fails too many times, right?
Scott: so no one can get into your phone and You won't care if your phone got erased because you have an iCloud backup.
Scott: That's automatic and you could just get a phone and restore it and then your phone will just after you restore it.
Scott: It's it feels like that's your phone like you.
Scott: never nothing got lost at all whatsoever.
Scott: Yeah So turn on iCloud backups pay for Apple storage space if necessary if your phone has too much data that you need to back Up.
Scott: and then with the way it works is when you get a new phone You just hold the phones near each other and it's like, okay.
Scott: I see your old phone I know how to find your iCloud backups I know who you are and it just restores the backup on the new phone as if it's the same process Basically and like in a matter of minutes, you know, once it's done doing all its bullshit.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: It's like your phone is completely transferred over.
Scott: Congrats, right?
Scott: There may be a few things that won't just transfer.
Scott: You know like maybe Google off if you're using that but I recommend Switching to a different solution.
Scott: to avoid that.
Rym: I want to say there was.
Rym: I haven't checked cuz I don't use a Google off anymore But there.
Rym: well, I think there might have been a change where you could Transfer to a new phone in a way that you could add that feature But it's still.
Scott: it's not going to be included automatically with the iCloud.
Rym: I mean I I failed anyway.
Rym: I use YubiKey for everything now.
Rym: Yep, same and last there is one concern that only applies to Android but it is important.
Rym: I would avoid Android phones that have a weird Android version that was made by a carrier or a company.
Rym: Wait the in order Get an Android phone made by Google that just has stock Android like that is your best option.
Rym: second best but actually acceptable is Sony because for whatever reason Sony has the best hardware still of any Android phone.
Rym: It's not as good as an iPhone hardware, but it's still pretty good.
Rym: But Sony does have their Sony Android.
Rym: Not only is it 99% the same as stock Android But it gets updates for a very very long time in a way that very few others weird androids do.
Scott: Pixel phone they're promising five years of updates.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Scott: That's pretty good iPhones But it's better than before where they were only doing like three years.
Rym: I mean, I was getting Sony Android updates on my Xperia That I've used for like four and a half years.
Scott: just fine four and a half.
Scott: Okay, so five but yeah I think it kept going.
Rym: that security updates, but I bailed.
Scott: and while we're talking about updates, right?
Scott: If there are updates to apps and the OS on your phone install them at your earliest convenience.
Scott: Always don't sit around not updating the phone update it.
Scott: You might be like one of those people complaining you don't like the update.
Scott: tough shit Update it immediately because they're usually fixing security vulnerabilities And if your phone is compromised your life is fucked.
Scott: Right, if there is an update for your phone, you should be like, you know, it's not an emergency But you should update it within like a day like that night at the latest.
Rym: my phone being compromised is more dangerous to me than My fucking computer being compromised.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So update the phone And of course, you know the longer the phone when the phone stops getting updates, right?
Scott: You don't throw it out, right?
Scott: But you should sell that phone or recycle it or trade it in I would suggest on a new phone.
Scott: I wish you can afford to do so.
Rym: I have done this for a while and it has saved my butt a couple times.
Rym: if you upgrade to a new phone and the Old phone still works now It's not like the carrier.
Rym: frequencies change and it literally doesn't work anymore.
Rym: Like that happens occasionally If you can afford not trading it in Keeping the old phone as a back up phone is not the worst idea because if something happens to your phone and you're like about to go on a trip or something just Popping your sim back to the old phone and having a smartphone that works and is already set up pretty well for you.
Rym: Not bad that saved my butt once.
Scott: yeah every iPhone I've ever had I have you know Gave into a friend sold trade it in, you know did something to but I still got this Sony Xperia right here.
Rym: I actually had it out recently because I was making sure to had all this updates.
Rym: if something happens to my iPhone I would use this until I got my iPhone replaced, right?
Scott: But my backup phone is an iPhone 7 and the iPhone 7 is going to stop getting updates.
Scott: I think it got its last update already probably.
Scott: Yeah, and so that's a problem now and that it's like.
Scott: well It's my backup phone, but I it still works just fine.
Scott: I could use it in an emergency, but it not being updated is sort of like now.
Rym: we're at it right now.
Rym: A lot of old phones don't support 5g and I got to tell you if you have a phone that doesn't support 5g You're gonna find that a lot of areas don't have 4g that works anymore.
Scott: 4g is still out there.
Rym: So So I have my iPhone and my Sony and I did some tests for a bunch of reasons a while ago.
Rym: 4g does not work in a lot of LIC.
Rym: All right 5g works fine.
Scott: Sure, that's in one place the point.
Scott: if you look at maps 5 4 4g coverage is vast worldwide and 5g coverage is not right.
Scott: the most places don't have 5g.
Scott: but as Time goes on next 5 to 10 years, right?
Scott: You're gonna start seeing that, you know turning off of the right now might have 6g by then.
Scott: who the hell knows, right?
Scott: But yeah, you're gonna.
Scott: a phone will stop working.
Rym: So the listener asked a question.
Rym: Normally we would stop here.
Rym: We've already gone along but we skipped a show and we had a lot to get out.
Rym: You know, we miss when we skip a GeekNights.
Rym: It all just sort of cramps into our brain.
Rym: There's like a backlog in there words to say but especially because with kovat we still don't see each other that often Like I don't he's got in person more often than like once every other week.
Rym: so, uh the listener asks and I actually have some thoughts on this any thoughts on buying used phones refurbished phones previous gen phones.
Rym: I would say one Refurbished phones are often not a great idea because they often do not have a great battery life.
Scott: Yeah, so it depends right?
Scott: So that's true.
Scott: you someone's gonna turn in.
Scott: a lot of people will get a phone with a sad
Rym: battery, however, if you're a poor a Refurbished phone where they have replaced the battery with some third-party battery that phone is gonna be real cheap and it's gonna be pretty good for you, even though
Scott: or a Refurbished phone and you get about you buy a battery and right it's like.
Rym: yep If you're poor a refurbished phone is probably a great idea.
Rym: a refurbished phone That's a good phone that you just have to plug an anchor into all the time because the battery and it sucks.
Rym: That's better than no phone.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: so if a Used phone a cheap phone an old phone are if you don't have a lot of money are indeed a great idea As long as the phone is compatible and still getting software updates like we mentioned right?
Scott: You don't want to get a phone like like.
Scott: I just said.
Scott: my iPhone 7 just went out of style, right?
Scott: So, you know if you buy an iPhone 9, I don't know if that's such a thing.
Scott: Was there a 9?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: 13 se is when I whatever yeah, whichever one they had, you know It's like but the thing is it's like.
Scott: well, you could buy a refurbished right phone.
Scott: But you know, they still sell like iPhone 11's for like 500 bucks, right?
Scott: They sell the iPhone SE.
Scott: how much does that thing cost right?
Scott: For $430, right.
Scott: so it's like.
Scott: Should you be getting a refurbished?
Scott: Phone or an old used phone really gives in the price.
Rym: if you can say you find like a refurbished iPhone 12 for like $150 hell, yeah, well, you're not gonna find one that cheap right my.
Scott: But compare compare.
Scott: they still sell older phones Right, you know, it's like, you know, would you get a refurbished iPhone?
Scott: 11 or You know a. you know, you can get like maybe a pixel seven or not seven That's that would be.
Scott: that's like a new one pixel five right because six six and seven are out.
Scott: now I guess you know, it's like.
Scott: you got to look at the prices There might.
Scott: I was saying is that go there might be a new phone of an old model.
Scott: Might or might not be a better option than a refurbished phone?
Rym: Yeah I would say in a. Generally, of course you have to your research like if you're hunting for deals You got a hunt for deals like look for the parts better for the environment.
Scott: to get the used phone?
Rym: Yeah, but in a pinch I would suggest it's it's eco sensible a new phone from a previous generation or a The best options in that space?
Rym: generally.
Scott: Yeah just as long as the phone is still getting updates and You know, it's in good shape.
Scott: Yeah, and you may or may not need to get the battery replaced.
Scott: Don't be afraid of if you can't do it yourself because you're not a tech wizard Right and you're afraid to open up your phone.
Scott: Don't be afraid of phone repair places, right?
Scott: They're like they actually can repair phones.
Rym: If you're worried about data privacy like especially if it's not an iPhone just have them fix the hardware and then wipe the thing.
Scott: No, wipe it.
Scott: have them figure out.
Scott: you back up your phone right.
Scott: back up your phone wipe it.
Scott: let them repair swap the battery.
Scott: They give it to you right then put your then load your backup, right?
Scott: But yeah, I think iPhone is gonna add it soon like a repair mode where you know people can you know?
Scott: Won't need to unlock your phone in order to fix it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well Apple days coming up Let's say about that, but I think we've gone on plenty long.
Scott: All right good.
Scott: I'm hungry.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights Sorry, I'll enjoy some.
Rym: Gigi dread lily tenebrae on bone She pebble.
Rym: you really don't want me to say the names.
Rym: Chris the dot Chris rhymer Clinton Walton decks Finn Shia 85.
Rym: Rebecca dumb review.
Rym: mad bull 34 cowards.
Rym: Sam Erickson.
Rym: Shervin von Horrell stop all the downloading.
Rym: The next station is Downsview Park.
Rym: Downsview Park station and several people whose names I will not say.
Rym: You really should even though Scott won't watch it because he never will watch anything that anyone he knows recommends to him.
Rym: You should watch the new Beavis and butthead because it is absolutely delightful And thus I simply leave you with a small excerpt from said Beavis and butthead Fire.
Scott: Hello Beavis I have been waiting for you.
Rym: I Am fire Fire.
Rym: yeah, yeah, you like you kick ass.
Scott: Yeah, I Have great power.
Rym: Yes Yeah, yeah, wait a minute, I mean so like so you can talk.
Scott: I Have always been able to talk to you Beavis.
Scott: remember Beavis it is I fire.
Scott: Look upon my fearful glory Fire.