Rym: It's Tuesday, November 1st, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym, and I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are reviewing Marvel Snap.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So, Scott at the Scott household, you guys hosted a minor Friends Halloween gathering, and I gotta say, you're- We decided, well, we did it once before, and we're like, alright, let's just make that our thing, right, you know.
Scott: I like that being your thing, diversify the things, but your costume was an appropriately funny one, and- Well, 'cause, you know, I had, you know, I'm not a person, you know, I appreciate a cosplay, right, but obviously, that's not my hobby, I don't got time for that, right?
Scott: So, if I'm gonna wear a costume, I'm going to purchase it, right?
Rym: Yep, you're not gonna go the level below to what I might have worn at RIT back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, so, I had a Pusheen onesie, and I was like, oh, well, I have this, I might as well- I kept using it as a costume whenever I needed one, but the problem is, it was too small, mostly 'cause my arms are too long, right?
Rym: Well, there's a secondary problem, 'cause I've used my equivalents.
Rym: Yeah, they are way too warm for 90% of circumstances.
Scott: Yeah, so anyway, I was using that, and I'm like, alright, that's enough of the Pusheen onesie, let's get something else, and I said, alright, if I'm gonna get something, it's either gonna be cheap and disposable, or it's gonna be reusable, like the Pusheen was, right?
Scott: So, I was looking around, looking around, and I was like, oh, I could get this, you know, skeleton, basically spandex deal, right?
Scott: It was pretty high quality, it wasn't cheap either, but I could just use that every year, and just get a different kind of skeleton, right?
Scott: I would apply, on top of the expensive reusable skeleton costume, right, some skeleton flavor that is cheap and disposable, right?
Scott: So I started with the very straightforward pirate skeleton, and it looked better than I thought it was gonna look.
Rym: I think the fact that the jaw actually sort of moved separately from the rest of it.
Scott: And it worked, I'm like, alright, got a skeleton, you know, so those two parts I can reuse, and now next year, you know, I'll be a different kind of skeleton, and I'll just keep being a different kind of skeleton forever.
Rym: Yep, Emily and I went relatively low rent, I was gonna get it make a better, like more realistic Star Trek costume, but despite ordering a bunch of parts, like shirt, like things way in advance, none of them arrived by Halloween.
Rym: So, I ended up wearing, basically, a Star Trek costume.
Rym: if you're going low rent is just a cheap shirt, so I had a cheap shirt, and it looked okay in photos, but in person, it was the same material that like, bottom of the barrel sportswear is made out of, like bad knit polyester, that is definitely the kind of fabric that will smell like a gym locker within two seconds of touching flesh.
Rym: But, I will get a better one, I gotta say though, our friend Kat, he really knocked out of the park in terms of Star Trek, because not only was he wearing a real shirt, but he dressed up as Data's painting from the meme.
Scott: Very, oh, one of those, I mean, I don't know what the meme is, but I guess that's one of those, like, one episode- How do you know, we've watched this in your presence, Data's painting is making me dizzy.
Rym: I like being strong, that's where I like being strong comes from.
Scott: I mean, I know the character Data is like the emotionless robot guy.
Rym: Alright, so, all I'll say is there is a short, meme-y internet video where someone took an episode of Star Trek, which is a normal episode where Data starts painting, like he makes paintings.
Rym: And independently, Worf, the Klingon guy, is disturbed by and feels sick because of, among other things, Data's painting.
Rym: And they cut this together, and they replace the paintings with terrifying furry fetish art.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: And it's, like, a minute long, and it's moderately funny, and that is why, in the private Discord, there is an emoji of a horse that is called Strong.
Rym: And I'll leave it at that.
Scott: Alright, but, you know, the point is, I love those, I like the one episode deals, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, who wants to, you could be a Spider-Man costume, right?
Rym: My favorite thing to do if I was going to dress up, like, at anime cons as an adult would be the minorest possible background character from something.
Scott: Yeah, but definitely, but, like, distinctly, that, you know, you could be a Fish-Man from Slayers, right?
Scott: It's like, you know.
Rym: No, you know what it's like?
Rym: It's the difference between being Alan Chazar versus being Cliff Chazar.
Rym: So, in the news, in a recent competitive professional game, you may have heard of this game, it's called NASCAR.
Scott: Well, NASCAR is the league, the sport is stock car racing.
Scott: Even though the cars they use are far from stock.
Rym: So, did you know, total aside, it bothers me now that I realize this.
Rym: A ball bearing refers to, ball bearing refers to the collection of ball bearings in the bearing, and also to the individual balls in the ball bearing.
Rym: They are both called ball bearings.
Rym: Pedants are trying to call the balls inside bearing balls, which would make sense, but literally no one does that.
Rym: It's all ball bearings.
Rym: It's all NASCAR, it's all Legos.
Rym: Anyway, I'm just going to read the headline, then we'll talk about the news, because this headline on Kotaku tells you everything you need to know.
Rym: Quote, "Nascar driver pulls some video game shit, thanks GameCube, an interview
Rym: afterward.".
Scott: Right, so here's the actual story, right?
Scott: So, they're racing, it's the second to last race of NASCAR for this year, right?
Scott: So, the way NASCAR works now, I don't know all the rules of it, because I haven't paid attention to it in decades, since like the last millennia, right?
Rym: High school was the last time I paid attention.
Scott: Yeah, way back in the day, the way it worked is you would just get points, like any other, like F1, right?
Scott: And whoever had the most points at the end of the season was the champion, right?
Scott: Now, there's actually some sort of tournament structures, where like at the final race, there's only four people who actually have like a chance to win, right?
Scott: They're in the showdown.
Scott: So, this guy, who was racing, he was coming, it was one of those tracks that's really short with high banks, almost like a velodrome for cars, right?
Scott: And those are a lot of fun, even though you're basically, like you talk about NASCAR, they're just going around in circles.
Rym: On this track, they're just going around in circles.
Scott: They are really just going around in circles, right?
Scott: Like really, it's so short.
Scott: Anyway, but there's some fun aspects to that, right?
Scott: There's a lot of, the cars are all bunched up all the time, you know, you're not like, if you go to watch one of those races, you can see all the cars at once going around in this, you know, as opposed to like you go to some other big track, and it's like a car will come, and then you sit and wait, and then some cars come, right?
Rym: And also, while the sport zoomed out, looks like just a mess of cars kind of going in a circle, and I'm not a fan of NASCAR, NASCAR Super, really, but zoom in and like watch a dash cam for one car, and there's a lot of micro-aggression nonsense, like fighting and bumping and jockeying for position.
Rym: There's a lot of skill involved in NASCAR.
Scott: There's a lot worse sports, but it's not the best.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So anyway, so this guy's in 10th place on the second to last lap.
Scott: In order for him to qualify to be one of the four people who could win the championship at the next race, he's got to do better than 10th place, right?
Scott: 10th isn't going to be good enough.
Scott: So what reason is there for this guy to not just put it all on the line?
Scott: If worst case, he crashes, as long as he doesn't die, right?
Scott: If he ruins the car, if he comes in last place, what does it matter, right?
Scott: That doesn't matter.
Scott: As long as he doesn't die.
Scott: Right.
Scott: As long as he doesn't die or hurt anyone else, it literally doesn't matter, right?
Scott: So the typical driving pattern on these bold tracks, right, is to take the outside of the track, right, close to the wall when you're on the straightaway, which is very brief on this tiny track, and then dip in, you know, cause it's banked, right?
Scott: So you go down low, right, to the low part of the track to go around the corner and then go back up to the, you know, go back up the wall again and basically bank up and down and up and down and so right.
Scott: And that's basically over the long run.
Scott: That's the fastest way to go around the track because, you know, it's like, yeah, you have to lower your speed to get down into the banks, but you're taking the shortest path, right?
Scott: If you just tried to go around the outside of the track the whole time, you're taking such a long path compared to everyone else.
Rym: Yeah, you're literally driving further in a race, like doing extra laps, like the penalty laps in a biathlon.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It's not a good idea, right?
Scott: But what does this guy do?
Scott: Well, according to him, there's a trick he learned on GameCube NASCAR.
Rym: I'm gonna quote him from the interview.
Rym: "I played a lot of NASCAR 2005 on the GameCube, which I had growing up.
Rym: You could get away with it in the game, and I never knew if it would actually work.
Rym: I mean, I did that when I was eight years
Rym: old.".
Scott: Yep, so when he was eight years old when we were in college, a young dude, right?
Scott: He basically, on the last lap, he floors it, obviously, that's clear strategy.
Rym: Yeah, take the most aggressive, most dangerous line, just go nuts.
Scott: Right, but if you're flooring it on a track like this, right, you can't get down into the bottom of the turn, right?
Scott: You know, because of the, you know, whatever it's called.
Rym: You're gonna be understeering.
Rym: You won't be able to just turn in without spinning out.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So, rather than go down, which he can't do anyway, because this car's there in the way, right?
Scott: When you're going around the turn, there's no cars up at the top, because who's going up there?
Scott: Nobody, right?
Rym: But he guns it on the last lap.
Rym: He kind of bumps out of the way.
Scott: A little bit, yeah.
Scott: But he guns it on the last lap.
Scott: He takes the high road up by the wall around the whole turn.
Scott: So, he's going on a longer course around, right?
Scott: He's covering more total ground, but he's going so much faster by not hitting the brakes to go into the turn, and he's tearing up the side of his car, right, on the wall.
Rym: Yeah, he has rammed the wall, and he's just riding it.
Rym: He said in the interview, he kind of just let go of the wheel, and held the accelerator down.
Scott: Right, it's like he's destroying his car.
Scott: You can't do this every lap, otherwise your car would disappear, right?
Rym: Car looks like it's starting to struggle just as it gets over the finish line, too.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, Porsche, the person who is named Porsche, I don't know his first name, right, who the car is named after, said, like, the ideal race car should cross the finish line and then fall apart, right?
Rym: Blues Brothers car style.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So, this dude, he does exactly that.
Scott: On the last lap, not even on both turns, only on the last turn, the last two turns technically, right?
Scott: But, of the last lap, he guns it, he grinds the car against the wall, he's going, even though he's going further distance-wise, his speed is so much faster than the cars that are braking.
Rym: He passes, like, one, two, three, four, five, six, he passes so many people in that seven seconds.
Scott: He goes from tenth to fifth place on the final lap, which is, by the way, enough to get him in to possibly win the championship next race.
Scott: Also, he eliminated someone, someone who was in, who could have won the championship next race, is now eliminated from championship convention.
Rym: Even better, he had the best lap time for the final lap because of that.
Scott: No, no, no, he had the best lap time ever on this track by a tenth of a second, period.
Scott: Ever.
Rym: Oh, my article didn't say that, it just said he beat the best final lap time by 2.5 seconds.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: By, well, final lap time by 2.5.
Scott: He had the track record for fastest lap in qualifying in a race ever, at least for this kind of car, right?
Scott: By a tenth of a second.
Scott: So, like, someone who was trying to qualify and get pole position and got pole position on an empty track on this, in this, right?
Scott: This guy on the final lap was faster than that by a tenth of a second.
Scott: The fastest ever, right?
Rym: It is amazing that no one tried this before, but maybe it's not that amazing because the dude literally got the idea from the Game of Cube.
Scott: Yeah, but, you know, it's like a player of games, perfect, right?
Scott: But, now that people have seen this, right, is everyone, obviously not on the pre-final lap because you ruined your car, right?
Scott: I mean, you'll be out of the race, but why wouldn't everyone, no, you'd ruin your car, but on the final lap of the race, isn't everyone going to do this?
Rym: So then, it will become, just like when you, me, and our friends pay El Grande, where everyone's trying to position themselves for the exact same endgame, the 2.1.13, but everyone knows everyone's trying to do it, so the arts can be- You won't pass anybody, right?
Scott: And it'll be really interesting.
Scott: So, I also wonder, and also it's track-specific.
Scott: I mean, there are other short tracks, like.
Scott: I think Bristol is another one.
Rym: Well, it's track-specific the same way that in Initial D, Takumi's Hug the Gutter is track-specific.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: There might, though, be other tracks where, you know, even though they're not these sort of, you know, bowl tracks, right?
Rym: But there might be other types of strategies like this that everyone's avoided.
Scott: Have a final, like a turn on the final lap where, like, you know, it's just like, "Fuck
Scott: it.".
Rym: There might be other types of strategies.
Rym: There might be a chicane where you could, like, bounce your rear end off of the second half of it to spin around.
Scott: Like, there's lots of crap people could start trying now that no one's- I mean, in other sports, we've already seen just so many years of, you know, development and destruction of orthodoxy.
Rym: Yeah, nobody's made a new football play in a while.
Scott: Yeah, you know, like, you know, basketball, we've seen people finally just embrace the three-pointer.
Scott: It took them a long time to finally just go for that, right?
Scott: You know, a few decades that they had the three-pointer before they said, "Oh, that's that three points is better than
Scott: two.".
Scott: I mean, baseball- Why didn't you do that in the 80s or 90s when they added the three-pointer?
Rym: Baseball had a million clever trick plays that were all eventually destroyed by the true outcomes.
Rym: Like, every sport, every major sport, and most car racing has hit sort of these terminal strategies for their current rule sets.
Rym: And out of nowhere, this dude is like, "Well, there's a new
Rym: meta.".
Scott: The ABA added the three-pointer in '61.
Scott: Yeah, the NBA added the three-pointer in 1979, and it wasn't until, like, the 2000s that people were doing, you know, like, really focusing on it, right?
Scott: A whole lot.
Rym: So, in some other news, you may remember that Embracer, the company that is embracing basically the entire nerd media world bit by bit, conglomerating all together, that they had bought Square Enix Montreal, which rebranded itself.
Rym: That was the news from October.
Rym: So, not that long ago, the news from October 10th was Square Enix Montreal, having been bought by Embracer, rebranded itself as Onoma to continue making games with a new brand, and they ta-.
Rym: There's this article I'm gonna link to where they talked about, "We're making sequels, remakes, and remasters.
Rym: We're gonna go after Tomb Raider, Deus Ex, Thief, and a few other
Rym: things.".
Rym: It is now November 1st.
Rym: It is a few weeks after that announcement.
Rym: Embracer is shutting down that studio entirely.
Scott: Alright, well, they embraced it.
Rym: I, my cynical guess, I don't have any information, this is a pure opinion-based guess, just to clarify that, is that Embracer really, really convinced the people at this studio to rebrand so that the news wouldn't be Square Enix shuts down in Montreal.
Rym: The news was Onoma, something no one's heard about, shut down, and everyone kind of forgets what happened.
Scott: I don't think it's that, because it's like, you know, if it's no longer owned, if I were to buy Square Enix, I don't know, New York, right?
Scott: And Square Enix officially, the company in Japan, still exists, I'm sort of required to change the name to avoid trademark infringement, right?
Scott: Regardless of whether I'm gonna shut it down or not.
Scott: I can't keep calling it that.
Rym: Depending on the terms of the deal, of course.
Scott: Right, like if you bought Nintendo of America for some reason, you wanted to own a marketing customer service company, right?
Scott: Even though Nintendo of Japan still existed, you couldn't keep calling it Nintendo of America.
Rym: So case in point, a long time ago, I worked for a company called Pipeline Financial, and they, when they were shutting down, renamed themselves for a bunch of reasons to sort of just disappear into obscurity.
Rym: Like, that happens all the time.
Rym: They didn't just rename it, they did a big rebranding, announced projects, and like, made a big deal about like, this is what we're gonna do under this new brand.
Rym: But I'm pretty, my guess would be that that was all just Embracer trying to keep them from imploding until they actually shut them down, and the plan was to shut them down all along.
Rym: You may remember that Embracer, not that long ago, also bought Asmode and Dark Horse, and they are one more of the hyper-capitalist conglomerate threats to all entertainment media.
Rym: I don't know what to do about this.
Rym: It's not like our government's gonna do any antitrust anytime soon.
Scott: Well, it's a Swedish company, but Sweden's going in the wrong direction right now, so...
Rym: Yup, fascism's on the rise all over the world.
Scott: Alright, so, in another news, right, we all know here on GeekNights, we all know about Dwarf Fortress, right, we interviewed, one of the few people who has been interviewed on our podcast is Tarn Adams, the creator of Dwarf Fortress, back in the year 2006.
Scott: That was a long time ago.
Scott: Ancient times, right, and Dwarf Fortress is infamous, but it's managed to keep existing for like, you know, about as long as GeekNights has existed, Dwarf Fortress has also existed, and it's vastly more successful.
Scott: Their Patreon brings in like 10k a month, right, they don't gotta work.
Scott: But anyway, so Dwarf Fortress is out there, and some while ago, right, maybe last year, year before, I forget exactly when, they teamed up with this other game studio, something Fox, something Games, I forget what it's called.
Scott: It's Fox something, right?
Rym: Ah, Kit Fox.
Scott: Kit Fox, that's the one.
Scott: And basically, they're like, alright, we're gonna keep making the Dwarf Fortress, but Kit Fox, you know, we actually want to try to make some money now, not just keep giving Dwarf Fortress away for free.
Scott: You know, I guess they realized they wanted health insurance, right, in the United States, where they live.
Scott: And they're like, okay, we'll make a version of Dwarf Fortress that's sort of like the premium edition, but not ASCII graphics, you know, actual graphics, you know, some other fanciness, and we'll put it out on Steam and itch, and sell it for not free, and we'll keep the original ASCII Dwarf Fortress free, and that's what the state of things will be for as long as they live and keep making this game, right.
Scott: But I'm sure, even if they were to not live, someone else would carry this game, right, forward, somewhere, somehow.
Scott: I may.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: I'm debating making one final attempt at playing Dwarf Fortress.
Scott: So, I'm like, alright, you know, it's like, first of all, it's been so long since I played a Dwarf Fortress, it's still Dwarf Fortress, but there had to have been so many improvements since then, and so many changes, and I've forgotten so much.
Scott: It would be like a whole new thing, and even though the quality of life is gonna be awful, it's gonna still be better than it was.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: 'Cause what it was, I enjoyed talking to all of you when you were trying to play it, but I bounced off hard, despite loving everything that it was, it was just not a game I could play.
Scott: There are a lot of people, there are a lot of people who are like super into Dwarf Fortress, that's their number one thing, and they never play it.
Scott: All they do is watch other people play it, or, you know, hang out in the communities and never actually play it themselves ever again.
Rym: I mean, and our panel at PEX West, me and Emily, we talked about Boat Murdered, like the famous, the first big, widely known Dwarf Fortress playthrough epic story that someone told.
Scott: Anyway, so, this has been, there's been a Steam page for this upgraded Dwarf Fortress, Steam edition, real money edition, it's also an itch.io, for a long time now, it's been on my wishlist.
Scott: They announced today, literally today, right, which I didn't think this would ever happen, they put up a YouTube, like, announced date trailer, yes, it's actually going to be released on December 6th this year, so in a month and five days, it's actually coming out.
Scott: It's not like, I thought it was gonna be years more before it came out, nope, it's December 6th, 2022, it's set in stone, it's coming out.
Rym: Set in stone.
Scott: That's right, that's right.
Scott: So, uh, I'm gonna play it.
Scott: I'm gonna buy it for sure.
Scott: You know what, I will.
Scott: And I'm gonna follow my policy of buy and immediately play, and I'm also gonna buy an itch.io.
Rym: I will do the same, and I will play it until I can't anymore, or do not want to anymore, but I will try.
Scott: Well, get some instructions, if you just try to play it straight up, it's not a good faith effort, you gotta get some instructions.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I know, I wonder if that, I gotta find, do I have a bookmark for that site I used that was like the...
Scott: Well, I actually have a printed, physical, hard, you know, not a hardcover, but a book that was like a Dwarf Fortress book from back in the day.
Scott: that was, I think, O'Reilly published.
Scott: But I doubt it's still correct, because it hasn't been updated in maybe a decade.
Rym: I'll definitely do the thing I did for, like, Hearts of Iron.
Scott: But I'm sure that there's a wiki with a tutorial that has everything.
Rym: Do the thing like Hearts of Iron, where you play, do one playthrough following a very scripted tutorial, that is how I learned to play Offworld Trading Company.
Scott: If, right, if the listener knows the best Dwarf Fortress tutorial, there's probably a YouTube one, too, that you can follow, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: In this day and age, so...
Rym: Oh, we should play Offworld Trading Company again, too, I've forgotten everything about it, so it'd be great to play again.
Scott: I haven't forgotten, except what goes on in the playthrough.
Rym: I don't remember my strats, despite the fact that I seem to have, like, a 90% win rate.
Scott: Your strap was just do what the spreadsheet said.
Scott: The spreadsheet's real good!
Rym: The thing is, every time I tried to do the slightly more advanced variants in the spreadsheet, I would crater.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So one last little news, I don't have a lot to say about this yet, because I am reporting on this, because I did not know this was a thing game companies could do in Steam.
Rym: And when I pointed out to Scott, Scott also was unaware.
Rym: this was a possibility.
Rym: So if you don't know, in Steam, there is a feature that if you're not using it, you really should.
Rym: You can basically share games that you have bought with your household or with your family.
Scott: Without any security issues.
Rym: Yeah, like, you'll have separate cloud saves and everything.
Rym: Like, if I share a game with Emily and it does not, like, break my Slay the Spire save, Emily has her own Slay the Spire save game, they're separate, it just works, it's really good.
Rym: And Call of Duty Modern Warfare 2, just now, on October 31st, at 1621/41 UTC, released a patch.
Rym: And this patch does exactly one thing.
Rym: It removes the ability to do family sharing in Steam for this game.
Scott: It just disables that.
Scott: So on October 30th, if I had this game in my Steam library, because I bought it, and my kid had their own Steam account, and I indicated to Steam that we were in the same family, it would allow my kid to play that game on their account, even though we only bought it once on my account.
Scott: And I don't think it lets both people play at the same time.
Rym: You can't both play at the same time, which is a perfectly reasonable limitation.
Scott: Yes, but you can still, either one of you can play it, because you're literally in the same family, it would be no different than if you bought a Zelda cartridge, and you had an NES, only one person can play it at a time, but you got three save files on there.
Rym: And there are a few minor limitations, like, you can't play it at the same time as the other person.
Rym: You can't play it in offline mode.
Rym: There's minor limitations, but it pretty much does just work.
Scott: Yeah, so, but on October 30th, you could do that with this game, and October 31st, and today, you can't.
Scott: You would have to buy the game twice.
Scott: Now, first of all, you can understand why a game company would think this is a good idea with their backwards capitalist mindset, but the reality is how many extra copies of the game is this going to sell?
Scott: Not many.
Scott: I cannot imagine that many extra copies of this game will sell.
Rym: Meanwhile, how many 14 year olds are going to be so mad?
Scott: Right, it's like, I can't prove that the number is going to be low, but my prediction is that the number of additional copies sold will be very low.
Scott: It won't be zero, it'll be low.
Scott: But the number of angry people, right, for example, the older sibling in a family bought the game and they used the family share, or the parent is a gamer because that's how old people are, right?
Scott: You got millennial parent buys the game and shares it with the kids who are old enough to be allowed to play it, and suddenly those kids are cut off and only the parent has it, but the kid was the one who was playing it the most, and you can't just transfer the game over to the kid's account now, right?
Scott: But the kid has a save game and was playing it online with their friends, and now they can't, and it's like, you're going to really buy another copy, right?
Scott: And there were games.
Scott: Especially if you don't have a lot of money.
Rym: There are games that don't support it out of the box, and Steam actually has a big disclaimer about that in the fact, but that's because those are games that, like, have an external account, and it's a matter of, those games never supported it from day one.
Scott: You knew when you were buying the game that it wasn't supported.
Scott: This is, you bought it, assuming this support was there, and now it's gone.
Scott: They should at least, right, Steam should at least let you refund the game, because then in situations like the one I just described, the parent could refund it and use the money to buy the copy for the kid who plays it the most.
Rym: Now, as of when I got this article together earlier today for the GeekNights episode, the company has made zero statement, and they did this without announcing anything.
Scott: There's no- And this is obviously a popular game.
Rym: I don't play it, but it's called- It is one of the most popular games on Steam right now.
Scott: Indeed.
Rym: Under, like, Counter-Strike.
Scott: Yeah, maybe their data was telling them that, like, there were kids who were, like, buying one copy and then, you know, familying, you know- But they can't play at the same time, so it wouldn't include those numbers.
Scott: Yeah, with all their friends.
Scott: Exactly, exactly.
Scott: Like, I don't understand that- They're just, someone was just like, you know, probably some corporate dude was like, "Eh," and all the developers were like, "Eh," and then they had to do it.
Rym: I mean, case in point, it's like a micro version of what's happening over at Twitter right now.
Scott: Yeah, basically.
Scott: So, even though I don't play Call of Duty and I don't like that game, it's a bullshit.
Scott: It's a bullshit.
Scott: I support you Call of Duty people in calling out this bullshit, especially if you were using it, so.
Rym: Alright.
Scott: I think Steam should be like, "Hey, if you don't support family, you can't be on
Scott: Steam.".
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or you got, we take twice that double cut if you don't support it.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: What did I have as thing of the day?
Rym: The CSS Pokemon thing.
Scott: Oh, right, so.
Rym: It's pretty cool, I ended up on the stream.
Scott: It is really cool, yeah.
Scott: So, if you want to play a card game on the internet with other people, right, you gotta get, you know, there aren't really that many good, you know, implementations of that, except for, I guess, one we'll talk about today, our main bit.
Scott: And, you know, games like Magic, the Magic Online, Hearthstone, obviously, right, a few others, there aren't many.
Scott: It would be really nice if you could do it in the web browser.
Scott: The problem is, is that making a good UI for a card game in the browser is tough.
Scott: You know, even if you could make the UI good, it's not going to look fancy, like, look at the animations in Hearthstone, right?
Scott: It's like, I stopped playing that game years ago, but it's like, you kind of need, it's like, they're not important for someone like me who just cares about the game.
Scott: But it's like, you kind of need that to make a successful multiplayer online card game, right, to have it look good and fancy and all that biz, right, with the animations and the sound effects, because just cards, you know, it's tough, right?
Scott: It's like, maybe you could be successful, but I don't know.
Scott: So, it's like, well, if you're just in the web browser with, you know, where you don't really have much to work with, right, you don't have like a game, you know, fancy game engine going on, how are you going to make the cards look good?
Scott: Well, here we have a obviously copyright infringing tech demo of a web development technique where they used CSS, some 3D transforms, some filters and some other techniques to be, it's not a whole game, but they're just made, you know, interactive in web browser cards that spin, move, light up.
Scott: They're like, it's like, they look fantastic.
Scott: These look better than any cards in any actual game engine card game.
Scott: Like these are the best looking cards like to play with that are digital I have ever seen ever.
Scott: And it's like, just copy this person's code and make an in web browser card game.
Scott: Obviously you can't make the Pokemon one to get in trouble.
Scott: But it's like, this is, you got your, all this work is just already done for you.
Scott: All you got to do is the rest, which is the other 90%.
Rym: This is amazing.
Scott: This is incredible, incredible work here.
Scott: I can't, you know, somebody's going to someday in my life will make a card game where the, you know, digital card game where the cards are like this.
Scott: Maybe it'll be me, but the source code is just fucking right there.
Scott: GitHub, boom, GitHub, Pokemon cards, CSS.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: It's like, holy shit.
Scott: Let's make it happen.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I got a little thing, but you may be familiar with an old game, Zoo Tycoon.
Rym: It was a popular game a long time ago.
Scott: It was in the same series, you know, with the railroad tycoon and the roller coaster tycoon and all those.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: This is a game from 2001.
Rym: Like I was, God, that actually was a long time ago yet.
Rym: We were already in college, so.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: I never played it.
Scott: I played like the first roller coaster tycoon a little bit.
Scott: I guarded the first one, so I never bought or played any of them for an extended period.
Rym: So this video is a short video, but it, it experiments with the game and determines the full details of a very specific behavior in the game when guests fall into or otherwise are in water.
Rym: And what they determined is that you can only drown men in Zoo Tycoon.
Rym: The people in the park are men, women or children.
Rym: They have three like models.
Rym: Let's not get into gender stuff around there.
Rym: This is an old game from 2001, so it is what it is.
Rym: But if you set up implausible scenarios to trap someone in water, men will drown, women and children will be teleported to safety.
Rym: Someone specifically designed this game to ensure that women and children cannot die no matter what you do, but men are fair game.
Rym: It's not clear why.
Rym: There is no game difference between those three kinds of players.
Scott: Okay, so I did some research here.
Scott: This game was made by Blue Fang Games, which was basically owned by Microsoft and then closed down when their Microsoft deal ended.
Scott: They were in Massachusetts, right?
Scott: They were founded in '98.
Scott: They closed in 2011.
Scott: Actually, they're not related to Roller Coaster Tycoon or Railroad Tycoon.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Because they look like identical graphics.
Scott: They're the same genre, yeah, but the games that were made by this studio were Zoo Tycoon, right?
Scott: I think these are expansions for Zoo Tycoon.
Scott: Zoo Tycoon 2, a bunch of expansions.
Scott: Zoo Tycoon DS.
Scott: Zoo Tycoon 2 DS.
Scott: World of Zoo in 2009 for Windows DS and Wii.
Scott: A game in 2009 called Lion Pride for iOS.
Scott: A game in 2010 for iOS called Lion Pride Huge.
Scott: Another 2010 game for Facebook.
Rym: That feels like a downward spiral into shitware.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: A 2010 Facebook game called Zoo Kingdom.
Scott: A 2011 implementation of Carmen Sandiego for Facebook.
Scott: And a 2011 implementation of Oregon Trail for Facebook.
Scott: And then they were done.
Scott: So the only games they really made that were successful or notable, but were indeed popular, successful, notable, and award-winning were Zoo Tycoon, Zoo Tycoon 2, etc.
Rym: Really feels like the kind of game I would get a demo of in PC Gamer.
Rym: But what's fascinating is in exploring this in the video, what we find is that the game has surprisingly complex drowning mechanics.
Rym: Which makes the fact that they decided to prevent women and children from drowning with an additional separate mechanic all the more fascinating.
Rym: A drowning male will only be able to see six tiles in the distance and will swim randomly until they see land or a safe place to get to and then try to get to it.
Rym: And they have a stamina that will run out and eventually they'll just die.
Rym: Women will just teleport somewhere on the map where they'll be safe.
Scott: If you want some more advanced drowning, I would suggest Dwarf Fortress.
Scott: Which is perhaps the most drowning-est game to ever be.
Rym: In the metamoment, the Geegneis Book Club book apparently is still binty 'cause Sonic Segment didn't update the website yet.
Scott: I had a reminder to do it, but then I didn't do it.
Rym: I only make fun of you because I have forgotten to do it every time for at least a couple weeks before I finally do it.
Scott: We're putting it on the list right now.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But the Geegneis Book Club was binty.
Rym: Just read it.
Rym: It's fantastic.
Rym: We did the show on it.
Rym: The new book has been announced.
Rym: It looks really great.
Rym: I already bought it.
Rym: I'm gonna start reading it this weekend.
Scott: Mhm.
Rym: We will be, or either I will be or me and Scott will be at PAX Unplugged on Sunday giving a panel called "Why is this game taking 4
Rym: hours?"
Rym: Which is a somewhat updated version of our "Take your fucking turn" panel.
Rym: But nuance changed a little bit, removing some old examples, adding some new examples, etc.
Rym: But we'll be there.
Rym: We'll only be there on Sunday.
Rym: Don't expect us to be there any other days.
Rym: We'll see what happens in regard to COVID and other PAXes and what the future holds for us doing live performances.
Rym: I pretty much stopped using Twitter, so you're gonna keep seeing updates from me.
Rym: Like, I'm not quitting Twitter in a big huff, but I'm just not going to it anymore, so...
Scott: Yeah, we'll probably talk about this on the next Monday episode, right?
Scott: But, you know, we've always, Geegneis has been following it pretty strictly, but personally I haven't, despite believing in it, I haven't followed it the most strictly throughout my life, but there's a model called the Posse Model, which is where you publish your work on your own site, POS, and then you syndicate it elsewhere.
Scott: So you treat other platforms like Twitter, Facebook, YouTube as just places to basically copy your shit to, to get it out there so people can find it.
Scott: But your official location for any of your own work is your own website.
Scott: You publish everything yourself, and then when you post on other websites, you're either posting copies, and you're hopefully including links back to your own site, and you just do that for everything.
Scott: And then if people only want to use those other sites, okay, they can still see whatever content you choose to send over there.
Scott: And if they don't want to come to your site, okay, they don't have to, but they can, and you'll never lose your shit, right?
Scott: I've seen so many sites, you know, platforms from GeoCities onward disappear over the years.
Scott: If you do, if you do things this way, you can never get burned, because your stuff will always be where it was in its true original location, as long as you can keep it up.
Scott: So I'm going to move to that model more strictly for the remaining years of my life.
Rym: We have both been through this rodeo of a platform becoming the most important platform in the world and then disappearing.
Scott: It's happened so many times.
Scott: Right, it's my last rodeo for this, so I'm just going to transfer to basically having everything on my own shit, and if another site comes up and I happen to syndicate to it, it's like, okay, and if that site dies, okay, it's just a place I'm syndicating to, what do I care, right, you know?
Scott: Whereas now, it's like I unwisely invested in some platforms, you know, and then they die, and it's like, well, I learned my lesson, that's enough of that.
Rym: Downloaded my 6.5 gigabytes of Twitter archive.
Scott: Oh, I mean, I've been downloading it monthly for quite some time.
Rym: I was doing it like biannually, because I wasn't that fussed, because I had most of the archive, but I got one last.
Scott: I mean, yeah, I have like reminders set to back up things to my NAS that I can't do automatically.
Rym: Yup, so I say that because you're going to keep seeing like GeekNights announcements happen for my Twitter, but like don't add me.
Scott: Yeah, we're going to continue, don't, you know, whatever, you know, you have to decide on your own listener, which web platforms, which internet services you're going to use, that's up to you.
Rym: And like to be clear, I'm not making a moral stand, I'm not quitting Twitter in a like, we should all quit it for more reasons.
Rym: I just don't like using Twitter anymore.
Scott: I have opinions on which platforms I like and don't like, but I'm not going to try to, you know, tell other people what they should or should not do.
Scott: I might, you know, air my opinions, but it's like, you know, you do what you got to do, and I'll meet you where you are, right?
Scott: If that's the thing you want to use, I'll post links, you know, so you can get notified the way you want to get notified.
Scott: It doesn't really hurt me, it doesn't help those platforms.
Scott: that much, you know, big deal.
Scott: As long as it's easy enough to do, what do I care?
Scott: I'll meet you where you are at, but I'm not going to participate in the other places, right?
Scott: It's like the time for that is pretty much over.
Rym: I feel like I will still post to Reddit occasionally, but that's sort of a different type of use case.
Rym: I don't generate content to Reddit.
Rym: I just write comments on Reddit.
Scott: Well, we'll talk about it more on the Monday.
Rym: But yeah, don't at me on Twitter, and if Twitter is the only way you know to reach me, DM me.
Rym: I'm keeping my DMs open.
Rym: I do get the DMs.
Scott: You can always email.
Rym: Yeah, email works, guys.
Rym: Email still exists.
Rym: Our email address is real easy to figure out.
Rym: And I am going to make a concerted, because I'm not looking at Twitter anymore, I'm going to replace at least some of that time.
Rym: I would spend wasting my life on Twitter, looking at the GeekNights forum more than I have.
Scott: Wasting your time on your own shit instead of wasting your time on someone else's shit.
Rym: I mean, if you're going to waste time, you're better off smelling your own farts than smelling someone else's farts.
Rym: If farts are what you're after.
Scott: In the attention economy, if you got attention and you're going to burn it, might as well burn it in your own stove, keeping yourself warm.
Rym: So, Marvel Snap is an online digital game.
Rym: It came out this month.
Rym: It's on, I guess, computers.
Rym: Well, not everything.
Rym: It's not on the Switch, even though I think it would be great on the Switch.
Scott: Oh, I thought it was on the Switch.
Rym: No, it's only on Android, iOS, and Windows.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, nothing else.
Rym: That's most things, but I feel like they're leaving money on the table by not having a Switch port.
Scott: So, a lot of the premier developers who worked on Hearthstone at Blizzard, they left long ago.
Scott: I think we must have talked about it when it happened.
Scott: And they went to create a new studio called Second Dinner, which is a joke I presume is related to the second breakfast that hobbits eat.
Scott: And they were working on something, and we assumed it had to be card game-ish because they were all Hearthstone devs.
Scott: And we knew that there was some news that came out that they had a Marvel license.
Scott: But not until, literally, they did the Apple approach, right?
Scott: Basically, they fucking announced the thing and released it pretty much on top of each other.
Scott: Like, here it is, right?
Scott: They weren't like, Marvel Snap coming next year, right?
Scott: They're like, Marvel Snap, fucking here it is, bitches.
Scott: It's out, right?
Rym: I believe there was a brief early access period on Steam in Windows.
Scott: Yeah, there were some beta early access type periods of some kind.
Scott: But it's like, it pretty much, you know, unless you were deep into it with them, it's like, you know, the majority of people didn't know about it until, here it is.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So I think we should, let's talk about the game itself first, because that's a more interesting conversation.
Rym: Before we talk about the monetization and the problems with the ecosystem around it.
Rym: Because I gotta say, like, TL;DL, the game itself is a really solid, well-designed game.
Scott: Well, they stole from the Forgotten Masters, right?
Scott: You might go back into the GeekNights archives and find an episode we did about Rainer Knizia's battle line, right?
Scott: Which is also known as, what, Shot N' Totten?
Rym: Yeah, Shot N' Totten came first, I want to say.
Scott: Yeah, right, but basically, there are several games that are, that I guess originated with Knizia, that are very similar in mechanics, right?
Scott: There's also the Warhammer LCG, which, I forget what that one's called.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The Warhammer LCG, was it the, I think it's the Invasion one, if I'm not mistaken.
Rym: But these games all follow a pattern.
Scott: Yes, Warhammer Invasion is also in the same kind of, you know, realm of game.
Rym: The pattern is basically, there'll be some number of zones of some kind lined up in a row.
Rym: And you take turns playing cards that have various amounts of power in some capacity into those zones.
Rym: And the zones have some sort of limit on how many things can be in the zone, usually.
Rym: And there are some conditions where you win or lose a zone, and whoever controls the most zones, or maybe some variations on that theme, like battle line has some additional ways to win, like controlling three zones that are next to each other, you win the game.
Scott: Yeah, it's a lot like, you know, a Colonel Blotto, right?
Scott: Only, there's no, like, you know, the adjacencies are much simpler because you don't have a map, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And, you know, there'll be like less options, and every single location is worth the same amount, right?
Scott: They're all worth one location, right?
Scott: Whereas like El Grande, the different locations, like when you hold them, how long you hold them, you know, it's like, you go from El Grande, you simplify and make it, you know, linear, and that's battle line.
Scott: And you make it even simpler, and you only have three locations total, and it's just two out of three, that's Marvel Snap.
Scott: Marvel Snap is like the baby's firstest battle line Colonel Blotto, like that you can get.
Scott: It's like as easy and as simple as you can make it while still having it be a game, but even though it's such a, like, it's like they removed so much, but the game is guaranteed to be six turns.
Scott: There's, I think, a rare occasion.
Rym: Well, it can be four turns.
Rym: It can also be four turns.
Scott: It's also rare occasions.
Scott: only four turns, yes, but most of the time it's six turns.
Scott: It takes less than a minute, basically.
Rym: A whole match, even if the other player takes forever to take their turn.
Rym: We're talking 90 seconds, start to finish, game's over.
Rym: So total aside, I pulled up battle line just to like bring up a screen for the listener on the stream.
Rym: Someone made their own version of battle line, and it's all Simpsons characters, and it is like top tier.
Rym: This is way too high quality what this person did.
Scott: Of course, right?
Scott: So Marvel Snap is basically, all right, look, you're not going to get the rich, you know, in-depth complex version that you get with El Grande or battle line where you get, you know, sit there for a little while.
Scott: But you're going to be able to get like that game mechanic.
Scott: Like you're going to exercise, you know, like flex that muscle like three times.
Scott: Like one, two, three.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's not, it's like you'll get some amount of juice for that fruit.
Scott: It's not like you're getting nothing.
Scott: It's like you're getting a little bit of game, game juice.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it takes so little time.
Scott: It's like, you know what?
Scott: Time invested versus game juice received.
Scott: It's like if you sit there and play Marvel Snap for an hour or play El Grande once, you might get more juice out of the Marvel Snap just because there's so many iterations.
Rym: In fact, this ties into that one El Grande.
Rym: Remember our take your fucking turn title where we are.
Rym: Our core argument was that a very short game that's pretty good is probably better by most measures than a very long game.
Rym: That's very good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So in Marvel Snap, you basically construct a small deck of cards, very small.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And there can only be drawn of any card.
Rym: So you can't have like, you can't have ten to Spider-Man and have to Spider-Man.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Each card is unique.
Scott: So it's a completely every one of each.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: And they're all Marvel superheroes.
Scott: And, you know, while there's a collecting aspect to the game, and usually I hate that shit.
Scott: I'm someone who grew up collecting superhero cards mostly.
Rym: So we collected mostly the same cards.
Rym: And these art, the art on these cards evokes the exact art on the fucking cards I collected as a kid.
Scott: They're really nice fucking cards.
Scott: I really like superhero cards.
Rym: I feel like I can smell the cards when I'm playing Marvel Snap.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Part of my brain says you should be able to smell these.
Scott: They're real nice cards.
Scott: So on your turn, you basically take simultaneous turns, which is, we love that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: No waiting.
Scott: And you on your turn, you can play a card to one of the three locations.
Scott: Every superhero has a value of how strong they are.
Rym: You can play any number of cards.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But you have mana.
Scott: basically that scales up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So in turn one, you can play one mana worth of cards.
Scott: And on turn two, you can play two mana worth of cards.
Rym: That has been the pattern for a while now for these kinds of games across the board.
Rym: The just linear mana ramp up.
Scott: And have you seen any mechanics that let anyone cheat that system?
Rym: Not one.
Rym: The only mechanics I've seen that interact with that at all.
Rym: There are some locations that will give both players a bunch of extra mana one round.
Scott: Which sure.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And there is one location.
Scott: As long as it's even, that's fair.
Rym: There's one location.
Rym: If you have no cards in that location, you get one extra mana every turn.
Scott: There's also a location that we'll discuss because it's hilarious.
Scott: Both players at random, right, have one card from their hand.
Scott: Just come and get played at that location for free.
Scott: You have no control over it.
Rym: There's a worse one.
Rym: You both get a card put in your hand without your control.
Rym: And there's another card, Agatha Harkness, which if that card is in your hand, the mechanic is, the AI plays your entire turn.
Rym: You can't play the game.
Rym: The AI plays for you the entire match.
Scott: Does ego the living planet?
Scott: who plays for you, right?
Scott: But yeah, there's all kinds of wacky stuff.
Scott: They obviously borrowed a lot from hearthstone.
Rym: These cards range from Cyclops, he's just a strong guy, to card that makes an AI play for you like we just described.
Rym: They're all over the place.
Scott: But anyway, you play cards at the locations, right?
Scott: And then whoever has more total power at a location is the winner of that location.
Scott: Whoever wins two out of the three locations is the winner of the entire game.
Scott: That's that, right?
Rym: If there is a tie, because ties are pretty common, actually.
Scott: I didn't experience any, but I didn't play that long.
Rym: I played until I got to near gold rank.
Rym: I played it a lot, just to really...
Scott: I played until I lost a game, which was both longer and shorter.
Rym: So if there is a tie, because you could be tied on one or more locations, like that could happen easily.
Rym: Because there are locations where the location power is like, "Cards can't be played here.
Rym: Any card played here is immediately
Rym: destroyed.".
Scott: But there are other guys like Nightcrawler who you can play and then move after you play them.
Scott: So that's how you can get power at a location, even though you can't play anyone directly to the location.
Rym: But if there is a tie, the power differential among the total power on your side versus the total power on their side is the tiebreaker.
Rym: I do not know what the tiebreaker is if that is also tied.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: The fact didn't say it last I checked either.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of unspoken rules, right?
Scott: Because it's such a straightforward game.
Scott: Hearthstone made the same mistake because they didn't provide a complete rulebook, right?
Scott: So the only way to know weird situations is to do science, encounter those situations, and see what the code does.
Rym: What I can say, though, is this game does something that's rare.
Rym: It does the Glory to Rome thing.
Rym: Pretty much every time I've seen an interaction, and I feel like if that plays out the way it logically should, it's going to be really, really ridiculous.
Rym: And the ridiculous thing just happens.
Rym: You got eight hulks out there out of nowhere suddenly.
Rym: The crazy thing seems to happen.
Rym: if the crazy thing seems like it makes sense to happen.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: And the cool part is, in a more serious game that takes longer, that would suck.
Rym: Like, "Oh, the weird thing happened.
Rym: The game just went
Rym: crazy.".
Scott: Yeah, the guy has eight hulks on turn three, and now you have to play the rest of the game for another half hour.
Rym: Yeah, no, this game takes 90 seconds.
Rym: Right, so someone hits a bunch of hulks.
Scott: It's like, "Alright, I lost that one.
Scott: Next.".
Rym: And there's a resign button.
Rym: And this is where the game gets brilliant, because this game did something I never expected, a game that is clearly aimed at children, to do.
Rym: It has a backgammon-esque doubling cube.
Scott: Yup, so the backgammon-esque doubling cube takes a game that would otherwise be a very baby's first child's baby version of a game, and adds a significant strategic element that raises the skill cap somewhat significantly, and makes play actually interesting for advanced players without really hurting it for weaker players.
Scott: It's like, you know, if you're good at the doubling cube, then obviously when you win, you'll win more, and when you lose, you'll lose less.
Scott: But it doesn't matter, because let's say you're low skill, and you don't play the doubling cube properly, okay, and when you win, you'll still win, and when you lose, you still lose, but you'll just win less and lose more.
Scott: But it's like, who wins and loses doesn't change.
Scott: Just how much is won and lost changes.
Scott: So, not a big deal.
Rym: What is this, how much?
Rym: What are we wagering?
Rym: It's basically, there's like a million currencies in this game, we'll get to that part of this in a second, but there is cubes, and the cubes are how you advance through the actual ranks.
Rym: Like, higher cubes mean you're match made with other players who also have higher cubes, and that's kind of the progression system through the game.
Scott: And the snap is an allusion to the Infinity Gauntlet.
Rym: Yup, if you didn't pick up on that.
Scott: The Marvel theme is very strong.
Scott: They just went all in on it.
Rym: Yup, so, oh my god, I just played a game on my phone, and I literally got harkness, and it's playing for me, and now I can't play.
Rym: So, so much for that.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: I uninstalled it.
Scott: I actually never had it on my phone, I only played it on Steam.
Rym: The way the doubling cube works in this game, the snap, is you play the game normally, and at the end of the game, whoever wins gets some cubes, whoever loses loses some cubes.
Rym: At any time, either player can click the snap, and it does a big graphical, like, snap.
Rym: It basically doubles the stakes of how many cubes are going to be won or lost.
Rym: When someone snaps, your options are either continue playing, and the elevated stakes take effect starting the next round, or resign, just quit, just give up, cut your losses, and you only lose that initial cube.
Rym: You don't, like, the doubling doesn't actually happen.
Rym: So, you can snap, and the other person just quits.
Rym: Once you've snapped, you can't snap again, the other player, just like in backgammon, at any time if they want, they can snap, and double the stakes again, and you'll either have to accept that, or quit yourself.
Scott: That's basically identical to what the backgammon doubling cube does, and pretty much, we can have a strategic discussion about how it, you know, adds bluffing mechanics to the game, and how it adds, you know, it rewards people with good positional heuristics, like, if you know you're winning, right, then it's, it rewards, it gives you a reward, because now you know you're, you know, you can, not only can you...
Rym: Doubling cubes are an advanced game mechanic that are, that is, I would say it is one of the most interesting and powerful core game mechanics there is.
Rym: Like, it's up there.
Scott: Yeah, it's really, it's really simple, but it adds a whole lot to a game for players to think about, and they threw it in there, and there you go.
Scott: Good, great, genius, perfect idea, amazing.
Rym: I have won many matches, because I bluffed and snapped in the last round when I had bupkis in my hand.
Scott: Yup, bluffing works.
Rym: And the locations are great too, like, the locations...
Scott: You can't bluff and backgammon though, because it's not like someone, you can't prove that you're gonna get, know that you're gonna get to roll sixes, right?
Rym: Backgammon is just knowing, backgammon the cube really just tests, do you know basic statistics?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Of lots of rolls of 26.
Scott: Or, are you, are you cheating?
Rym: Yeah, are you cheating is a big part too.
Scott: But, uh... Are you, or are you a risk taker, I don't know.
Rym: So here's the problem.
Rym: Everything about the game itself is actually pretty great.
Rym: Like, there is, I have zero complaints about this game.
Rym: In fact...
Scott: Well, okay, the complaint I would have about the game, right, is that, you know, when I, I basically, I played it, and I played it until I lost.
Scott: And the one match I lost, right, we'll tell the funny story, right, a location appeared, well first, a location appeared that said everyone gets rocks in their hand.
Scott: And the rock is basically just a, it's a rock, literally a rock.
Scott: And it's just a card that's basically worthless, that has no power, but to get it out of your hand costs a mana, so, and it takes up a spot on the board.
Scott: So unless you have some other card to synergize with the rock that would make it advantageous, you're not gonna play it, it's just gonna take up space in your hand.
Scott: There's a lot of, it's like a curse in Dominion, right?
Scott: So I got some, we both had rocks in our hand, because everything in the game is even fair like that when it's random, which is nice.
Scott: And then another location appeared.
Scott: that said, both players, at random, to have one card from their hand automatically played at this location for free, right?
Scott: And so the other player had rocks in their hand, and so did I, but a rock came out of my hand for free, which is, you know, it's not that harmful, it eats up a spot, I didn't lose a mana.
Scott: But, you know, it's out of my hand, which is nice, but it's like, it's obviously the worst result, you'd rather get something big for free, right?
Scott: The other player got the hulk for free at that location, right, who is, it's like, some other people have reported this exact scenario happening, so I wonder if it's a scripted thing.
Rym: So, the exact same thing happened to me in one of my early matches, the exact same thing happened to our friend Matt in one of his early matches, the exact same thing happened to some people I saw on Twitter, because I was still looking at Twitter back then.
Rym: We have a lot of evidence that many, possibly most, of your early plays, if you start playing this game from nothing, are scripted entirely, not just to teach you the game, but to expose you to the highs and lows of the game, and make it an engaging and interesting experience.
Scott: Because remember, one of the things that Richard Garfield talked about-- And expose you to the mechanics of the game without the interference of another person.
Rym: But also expose you to, like, the high highs and the low lows, like, the ridiculous once-in-a-lifetime nonsense that happens in a game, the wombo combo that you celebrate.
Rym: You experience that, like, on your fourth game ever.
Scott: Yep, so this, obviously, is, on the one hand, incredible, right?
Scott: That's a hilarious play, it's thematic, it's fun, if it happened at a tournament, people would be going like, "Oh, shit!
Rym: Oh!"
Rym: Right?
Scott: But it's entirely luck-based, right?
Scott: I didn't lose, up until that point, I had not lost a single game, and I only lost that game because of luck.
Rym: But remember, a game takes between 20 and 90 seconds to play.
Scott: Yep, but I told myself when I started, because I could clearly tell what kind of game this was, that I would uninstall as soon as I lost.
Scott: So that was my final game.
Rym: Yeah, I have played several hundred games of this to really, like, interrogate the mechanics, and I am at a point where I only win about half my games.
Rym: The advanced play will get into the whole collectible nonsense and, like, the problems with the monetization in a second, but assuming you have all the cards, and you're not just, like, lacking a card that someone has that's just better, then the game comes down to who made the most clever deck with a little bit of paper-rock-scissors, and after that, who plays perfectly mathematically optimally, which, if you're a reasonably intelligent adult, not hard to do.
Scott: And then number three-- No, but a professional player, even the most professional players will make a mistake sometimes, right?
Scott: And in those games, they're gonna lose because they made a mistake.
Rym: Yep, and then the third thing is it will just be random, but that's where the doubling cube comes in, because this game is more like poker.
Rym: If you're playing this game seriously, forgetting the collectible card shit will get into.
Rym: I keep saying that because it's a deal-breaker, that part.
Rym: The real skill is, if random shit happens, just resign.
Rym: Like, you gotta use that cube, that snap, effectively and elegantly-- As soon as the Hulk came out, I resigned.
Scott: I might have actually played one more card and then resigned.
Rym: Yep, you just resign.
Rym: And if you treat this game like poker, play it well, make good decks, study the meta, and you are very willing to resign and you don't snap stupidly, the game is still on the level, if you play dozens of games, primarily skill-based in the end, because you're gonna advance faster if you are smarter and better.
Scott: If you're smarter and better at this game, even though every individual game will be determined by luck or what cards people drew or my deck happened to be a rock to his deck scissors or vice versa, even though all those things on the level of an individual match, you're not gonna be able to really have much control over the result.
Scott: If your positional heuristics and understanding of the game and just knowing who's going to win earlier, right, are better than the other players, over the course of many, many games, you will win more and lose less and rise in the ranks and be better.
Scott: I would also say-- Even though, once you get to some certain rank, the outcomes of individual matches are primarily luck-based.
Scott: Yep,
Rym: I would also say that even though you will definitely lose games by absolute, uncontrollable, ridiculous randomness, because the games are so short, that ends up being fun, to the point that I'm not even mad about stasis decks, not even mad about, like, literally lose control of the game.
Scott: Yeah, you could just resign immediately, too.
Rym: Or just let it play, and within 40 seconds, you are playing a brand new match, and it really just washes out.
Rym: The skill will come to the top, except this is a free-to-play game, and the way they monetize it is.
Rym: you either have to grind a terrifying amount to get all the cards, and the later cards are just better.
Scott: Like, there are combos-- Not all of them, but most of them.
Rym: But also, without the later cards, you cannot do anything advanced, you cannot make good, clever combos.
Rym: You are just missing out on the fun part of the game.
Scott: Right, so the way the unlocking works is that there's a whole bunch of different, bunch of fucking systems, right, because they can just have one way to do it, right?
Scott: They can have all these different ways, right?
Scott: It's like, you level up your fucking season pass by playing and winning-- It is poisonous, toxic free-to-play, just like every other poisonous, toxic free-to-play.
Scott: Right, it's like when you play cards, those cards that you play get points, and when a card gets enough points, it can upgrade, right, and frame break, and all that, right?
Scott: So basically, the cards upgrade individually, cosmetically, right?
Scott: So you start off with a boring Spider-Man card, just a regular old Spider-Man card, right?
Scott: And you eventually upgrade that Spider-Man card.
Scott: It gets fancier looking, there's holograms and alternate arts, and each card has several different visual, you know, cosmetic options, right?
Scott: Many of which are, they're all fucking awesome, right, all of them.
Scott: The artist team, they're S tier, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, and it's Marvel, so I guess it's even easier, right, to get all that years of IP to work on, but, you know, still amazing art, you know, however easy you want to say it is, I couldn't draw any of that shit.
Scott: But, you upgrade cards cosmetically, and the more you do that, the more you level up on this other meter that unlocks actual cards that you can now have the option to put into your deck, right?
Scott: So, you can spend fucking real money to unlock shit, but it costs a lot, I didn't calculate how much, I'm sure someone on the internet did, but it ain't cheap, it ain't worth it.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: Or, you can grind your way, just keep playing until you unlock all the cards.
Rym: So, as far as I have played, I have played many hundreds of matches, I ranked up to upper silver local, I do not have even, like, half the cards, and 100% of the time I lose a match, the other person has a card I don't have.
Rym: that is a way better combo, and I have no way to counter that.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: So, yeah, I mean, if this game offered some option that was, like, a reasonable price, say, 20 bucks.
Rym: I would pay 40 bucks to just have every card.
Scott: Or, monthly fee, I would pay 5 bucks a month, right?
Scott: Some, yeah, maybe.
Scott: Cos the game is.
Rym: objectively, I thought about how, you could play probably 10 to 15 snaps in the time it takes to play one Nershima Hex, it's a better poopin' game than Nershima Hex.
Scott: Yeah, but I was saying, it's like, you know, because it's a game that's continuously updated, they're always adding more content, right?
Scott: So, it's like, if I pay 30 bucks once for all the cards, it's like, well, now they add new cards.
Rym: But if I had to pay, like, 10 bucks a season to get the next set of cards, I'm not even opposed to that.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not opposed to paying for this game, what I'm opposed to is that even a substantial time or money investment, I don't even care about getting all the cosmetics, even though it's actually kinda awesome in this game, right?
Scott: It's like, I just wanna be on a level playing field with the top, you know, with everybody else, and have every card, and I want my opponents to have every card.
Scott: I don't wanna just win because I got some card the other person doesn't have, that's some bullshit, right?
Scott: I want everyone to have access to all the same cards, and then play that very good, you know, light game in the spare moments of my day, and then I would be into it.
Scott: But because that is not the way it is done, I uninstalled the game.
Rym: The grind is exponential to get all the cards, it is the full-on free-to-play experience, there are at least three currencies in-game, I don't know which one does what because I do not care.
Scott: Yep, so that's a disappointment on what would otherwise be really, really good, like, you know, top tier.
Scott: as far as the toilet multiplayer, like, it's like, has there even been a multiplayer online game, phone or otherwise?
Rym: The only games I can play against another human while I'm pooping on my phone are asynchronous games.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you could play, you know, for a multiplayer toilet game, right, you could play the other card games like a Hearthstone or a Magic Arena, but it's like, those take a while, that's one, maybe you'll get a match in, maybe not, it could be a long one, right?
Scott: It's like, there is no other real multiplayer online competitive actual strategy game that you can play more than once in a poop, right?
Scott: This is it, right?
Scott: And that is very compelling, but not compelling enough for me to grind away my time or money in order to play it properly.
Scott: There's also, as far as I can tell, no competitive organized structure, there's no tournaments, there's no way to say I want to play against my friend Rym and play only against my friend Rym, there's no private lobbies, there's no, you know, way to have a tournament on Twitch, there's nothing, they might add that at some point, but as far as I can tell, none of that exists, you can only just play a game against a rando and then play a game against another rando and that's all you can do.
Rym: I have played four games against randos since the one I lost a little while ago on my phone while we're doing the show.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, if I could have, you know, even Hearthstone lets you play against a specific person in your battle net friends list, right?
Scott: It's like, if that was a thing, then I could have maybe almost gotten into it a little bit more.
Scott: Yeah, because if I would just play against- I could have found a Discord server of serious players and played against them.
Rym: Or we could just play amongst, like, our friends and nobody, no one we know- Yeah, everyone has the same cards, right?
Rym: They'd be close enough, because nobody we know would grind that much, the grind is exponential, and nobody we know would spend that much money.
Scott: To their credit, I will say that even though you have to grind away with money or time to unlock all these cards, they did not do any loot boxes or boosters or random shit.
Scott: You can't sit there, as far as I can see, there might be there that I just didn't see it, I don't think you can buy packs of cards and then, like, disintegrate the doubles to get points and leftover currency.
Scott: Nope, there's none of that randomness, the progression of unlocking cards- That's good, that is good that they don't have that.
Rym: It's the same thing New Overwatch did, where in Switch, funnily enough, nerds are complaining about, because they want the loot boxes, they want that randomness to-.
Scott: Of course, those nerds are there, because they just like gambling and collecting, they're not interested in actually playing a game.
Rym: This is the new design pattern, to get away from the loot boxes, because I think the entire industry sees that that's going to get cracked down on eventually.
Scott: Yeah, I actually don't see a problem, it's like, keep all the grindy bullshit you have, right?
Scott: The kid with no money can grind his time away, right?
Scott: The person who's mega rich can, you know, who wants all the cosmetics, right?
Scott: They can spend, they can be a whale and spend all the money, right?
Scott: Add just the third option, which is, you don't get any cosmetic bonuses, but you do get every card at the non, the weakest cosmetic level to play with, because you care about playing the game, and it costs a flat fee.
Scott: Just add that one payment option, and I'm installing this game again, right away.
Scott: But it's not there, so you're going to have to decide for yourself, you know, how much, if at all, you're going to engage with this game.
Rym: I would say it is worth playing up until you get bored with it, or you hit silver rank and then quit, because, one, I want you to see how this game ramps on board a new player with the scripted events and the bots.
Scott: There's a lot of good design in here.
Rym: That is brilliantly designed, and two, I want you to see how the game functions, because this is a model to steal.
Rym: We are entering the era of a million battle line clones.
Scott: And the user interface is S tier as well, right?
Scott: Except for the menus full of their currency, buying crap, but all the gameplay parts are good interfaces.
Rym: 90% of the menu is just to trick kids into putting real money into the machine.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, I would recommend, if you enjoy this game, when you stop playing it, because it's a grind, going out and playing shot and totten, battle line, warhammer invasion, if you can find someone to play that with you.
Rym: I would even say, even though it's adjacent, it's not the same kind of game, but it shares many characteristics with these games, lost cities.
Scott: Similar-ish.
Rym: I guess that's Jason.
Rym: It shares many characteristics.
Scott: It's also a Rainier Canisia, right?
Rym: That Rainier Canisia.
Scott: If you think about it, all those FPSs where you're trying to control different points are somewhat in the same category.
Scott: And you can also go to the Colonel Blottos, right?
Scott: You can play, we've done GeekNights episodes about El Grande and, what's it called, the Rumble one?
Rym: Oh, Rumble Nation?
Rym: Rumble Kingdom?
Rym: I think it's Rumble Nation.
Rym: I already forgot the name of it.
Rym: I assume it came out and I can buy it by now.
Scott: The Japan one.
Scott: Any Colonel Blotto game is just a non-linear, more complex version of this, right?
Scott: Putting cubes in places and winning the most places.
Scott: What?
Rym: Is it still not released in the US?
Rym: Imports only?
Scott: Oh, good luck.
Rym: It's only like $35 from Hobby Japan.
Scott: Make one.
Scott: It's not a hard game to make.
Scott: You just need some dice.
Rym: I think I might just buy the Japanese one.
Scott: Marvel Snap.
Scott: An impressive, impressive game that does a lot of things right, but does a critical thing wrong to keep me personally from playing it more.
Rym: If you want to blame anyone for that, blame capitalism.
Scott: But still an excellent thing that is quite unique in this world and I applaud it, even though I won't play it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are... ...York University, York University Station, and a bunch of people who are paying a smaller amount because they do not want or need me to say their names.
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty much done with Twitter.
Rym: Scott is mostly done with Twitter too.
Rym: But if you're hearing these words, you already know how to find us.
Rym: And you probably already have a good idea of what our opinions are on anything in particular.
Rym: So I think you can live without us tweeting for a little while while we sort this out.
Rym: But anyway, for tonight, I leave you with...
Scott: So, come up to the lab and see what's on the slab.
Scott: I see you shiver with antici...