Rym: It's Wednesday, August 24th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about the feature films of Hayao Miyazaki.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: I did a whole bunch of stuff over the weekend that would have been Open-E-Bit on Monday, if I had remembered.
Rym: Well, I jumped in with my previous show, Open-E-Bits, that were long.
Scott: Right, so I tried to think, well, what happened over the weekend that could possibly be an Open-E-Bit?
Scott: Because, you know, my current job, I only work the four days a week, which is still incredible, even though I've been doing this for a couple months now.
Rym: So I gotta tell you, as a random aside, today I was-- It's pretty terrific.
Rym: I was coaching a coworker, like, doing some mentoring, and we were talking, and they were like, "Yeah, I just feel like I work too
Rym: much.".
Rym: So I actually told them, like, you know, I got a friend, you know, the guy I do the podcast with.
Rym: He actually works four days a week.
Rym: He totally pulled it off, and there was, like, the look on this person's face.
Rym: It's like they had never considered that this was even a possibility in their lives, and they got really excited about it.
Rym: And I don't think any company in capital markets would ever do something like that, but anyway.
Scott: Someone posted a thread on a website, and they said, "Ask, you know, anyone working a four day a week here as an
Scott: employee?".
Scott: "This is a question mark.
Scott: This is a question for salaried employees,
Scott: etc.".
Scott: And I was like, "Yes!
Scott: That is me!
Scott: Here is how I did
Scott: it.".
Scott: And I got 171 upvotes.
Rym: I think you could just post an AMA and get surprising traction.
Scott: Like, AMA!
Scott: I only work four days a week.
Rym: I only work four days a week, but I have a real job in a real company paying a normal salary.
Scott: Well, it's kind of a startup, but they're paying money, I guess, you know, as long as they don't run out.
Rym: I mean, I have been approached by startups that aren't even at that point.
Rym: They're like, "Yeah, we can't actually pay you in anything but
Rym: equity.".
Scott: Yeah, no, they're paying real money.
Scott: They got from some investors, which usually I'm against, but obviously...
Rym: Even companies like Google and Amazon don't really pay in money.
Rym: They mostly pay in stock.
Scott: But there's customers who are paying and, you know, I'm somewhat believing that the product has uses and has a chance of success, right?
Scott: That's exciting.
Scott: Obviously not a huge chance.
Scott: It's still some startup, but not zero.
Scott: It's not garbage, right?
Scott: Not too shabby.
Scott: But yeah, so the weekend happened and most of the stuff that happened on the weekend is just, you know... I was doing stuff, but it was mostly personal stuff.
Scott: It's not stuff I'm going to talk about in an opening.
Scott: But one of the things I did over the weekend was there was a party and the person running the party hired some people to set up a balloon decoration at the party, right?
Scott: So when I woke up and I went outside, right, there were people blowing up a shit ton of balloons, tying them together, tying them to sticks and creating like an arch kind of deal, right?
Scott: You know, real fancy balloon decoration early in the morning.
Scott: Not that early, like 10 a.m.
Scott: You know, and they set it up and it looks pretty good.
Scott: They did a good job.
Scott: And then they leave and the day goes on.
Scott: A little while later, you know, I hear a pop and I'm like, yeah, balloons are going to pop, right?
Scott: There was no way.
Rym: I got a guess.
Rym: I have no... Scott has not told me the story.
Rym: My guess is the air temperature was high.
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Scott: But, you know, you knew that even if it was cold as crap, there's no way all the balloons are going to survive the whole day.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: But, yeah, they did not under inflate as they should have, knowing the heat wave and the sun coming out.
Rym: I mean, every time I go to my bike, I look at, especially in this climate, I look at what the weather is going to be and I'll take five or 10 psi out of my bike tires, depending on the temperature.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, there was there was popping throughout the day.
Scott: And then once the shade came right later in the day, the popping receded.
Scott: And, you know, also once the under inflated balloons are the only ones that were left.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There was less popping.
Scott: There were some periods where there was a lot of popping.
Scott: But, you know, it's just interesting because the popping is like, well, they messed up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They, you know, they'll learn their lesson the next time those balloon people set up a thing.
Scott: And they won't make the mistake again.
Scott: They'll under inflate if they set up before the sun comes out, et cetera.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like, there's nothing we could do about it now.
Scott: It's unfixable.
Scott: It's like, whatever.
Scott: You know, the popping is not bothering or hurting anybody.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, some people were like, just so fustered by the popping.
Scott: And it's like, I could understand if someone had like a PTSD from loud noises.
Scott: That's perfectly understandable.
Rym: It was outdoors.
Rym: So, balloons popping in an unobstructed outdoor area, unless they're Mylar balloons, not that loud.
Scott: No, they're normal.
Scott: These are like, you know, normal balloons, like rubbery, you know, the standard ones.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, some people are just like, you know, getting upset.
Scott: They're like, oh, we paid for these balloons.
Rym: And I'm like, there's nothing we could do about it.
Rym: Well, that's that specific problem of people care way too much.
Scott: And like, is your anger going to improve this situation?
Scott: Then just ignore it and go on with your life.
Rym: Oh, there's the amusement question.
Scott: You're going to throw these balloons away.
Scott: The party's only three hours long.
Scott: You're going to throw them all away in an hour anyway.
Scott: Why are you so mad?
Rym: I feel like the correct response is to, like, if someone's like that and you want to just like stop it, just start yelling like, whoa, whoa, everybody, everybody, calm down, everyone be quiet.
Rym: We have to end the party right now because the balloons might pop.
Rym: Everybody go home.
Rym: It's all over.
Rym: Talk to Joey Jojo here who's bothered by this.
Scott: The way I see it is like, I see it as a benefit that the balloons pop.
Scott: And the way I see it that way is because, you know, what was that?
Scott: If that, let's say the balloon arch, no balloons popped.
Rym: You would never, you would never, I would never have known there was a balloon arch because you would not have said I was at this party.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And there would have looked nice.
Scott: It would have looked nice and been there and been pleasant in its appearance.
Scott: And then it would have gone in the garbage.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that would have been the end of it.
Rym: I suppose there's a tiny chance.
Scott: Because it popped.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We now got a funny story.
Scott: And, you know, even as soon as next year or even sooner, you'll be like, ah, remember that time all the balloons are popping.
Scott: That is more valuable than the day of balloons.
Scott: Now one could argue.
Scott: Just being nice.
Rym: There is a possibility that the balloon art would have been so impressive.
Rym: Like I was at a wedding once where for weeks.
Scott: It was good, but it was not that impressive.
Rym: There's a possibility a balloon arch could have been constructed in such a way.
Rym: When I was a kid, we went to a wedding once and I remember all the adults for like months would keep bringing up how good the flowers were at this wedding.
Rym: Like it was just a thing among every adult we knew.
Rym: But this actually gets us some extra benefit.
Rym: And this is relevant to my thing of the day because I was involved in a balloon related incident when I was a kid.
Rym: And I know my mom is watching the live stream, so she's probably already laughing because she knows what happened.
Rym: We were in...
Scott: You grabbed too many helium balloons and flew away?
Rym: It's actually relevant to your thing of the day as well.
Rym: So we were in the fancy mall, not the one in Detroit that we would go to like for normal stuff, but like the fancy mall the family would go to for like, we're going to go shopping on a Sunday, like drive out to the suburbs and go to the big fancy new mall.
Rym: And I had this Mylar balloon and I'm walking around with it like a little kid, you know, really, really happy about it.
Rym: And I turned to my parents and I'm just like, can I pop it?
Rym: And they're not paying super attention to me.
Rym: So they're just like, yeah, yeah, whatever.
Rym: So I just, as a kid, I put this balloon on the ground and I stomp on it.
Rym: It is so loud.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: It sounds like a for real gun went off.
Rym: Everybody goes silent.
Rym: People in the distance start yelling.
Rym: A stampede starts.
Rym: It is just like chaos everywhere.
Rym: And my parents very intelligently are just like, keep walking, get up, keep walking, don't acknowledge it.
Rym: And we're trying to just not be involved in any of this chaos that we have caused.
Rym: and it's trying to get out of the mall.
Scott: Correct move.
Rym: Long story short, we did meet some police.
Rym: They determined that no foul happened.
Rym: Everybody calmed down.
Rym: No one was injured.
Rym: And my advice to you is to not randomly pop a Mylar balloon in a giant echoey eighties mall.
Rym: Unless you desire this outcome, in which case
Scott: my advice to you would be if you're going to inflate balloons outside in warm weather and it's not at the peak warmth of the day or and or the balloons are going to be in direct sunlight, you should under inflate them.
Rym: I would say if you are a person who has access to public schooling in America, pay a little bit of attention in like middle school pre physics, but in your life, you might know the physics, but you just might not think of that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not about not knowing hot air expands.
Scott: It's about having that come to your mind and like thinking about that moment when you're inflating balloons.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not about.
Scott: it's like, yeah, you know, hot air expands.
Scott: And it's like.
Scott: but it's like, what?
Scott: Why would you think of that at this moment?
Scott: There's nothing you know.
Rym: So in the news, there's actually we had a ton of news, which I won't try to dwell on all of it, but I want to start it.
Scott: We can do pretty quick.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I will start with one non animation anime manga comics news because it's actually a huge deal.
Rym: The United States, our president, Joe Biden, basically just signed an order that cancels arguably the majority of people's student loans in America.
Rym: A lot of it, a significant the far majority of all student loans are ten thousand dollars or less right now.
Scott: Meanwhile, all the countries with just free secondary education are like, oh, yeah, believe me, college should be free.
Rym: It should continue from high school for anyone who wants it.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: But at least the public ones, I guess this is a huge deal.
Rym: And if you have student loans, pay attention to this, because the reason I'm making my news is I have a couple of reasons.
Rym: One, a lot of people who maybe don't understand much about American politics but are mad about it.
Rym: It's fine to be mad about it.
Rym: It's even fine to not understand it.
Rym: But don't be publicly mad about things you don't understand if you're going to be wrong.
Rym: He said he was going to do it.
Rym: People were swearing up and down he would never do it.
Rym: And he did it.
Rym: So that's one.
Scott: He did it kind of.
Rym: Yeah, well, I mean, he did it.
Rym: This is this is obviously only the first step.
Scott: You didn't cancel all student loans, period.
Rym: Yeah, that's common.
Rym: I would say we give that time.
Rym: But two, much more important, the ten thousand dollar limit and the Pell Grant limit that everyone's talking about, that is only the tip of the iceberg.
Rym: That is actually not the most important part of this.
Scott: The other parts are extra parts in the fine print that were not publicized enough.
Scott: Well, I think they were.
Scott: they were publicized.
Rym: fine.
Rym: The problem is the media didn't talk about them because they're kind of complicated and the people who are affected by them don't understand them.
Rym: But basically, it is so much more than just canceling ten grand of student debt that it's going to cap interest.
Rym: It raises by a huge, huge margin, like what income they are allowed to just talk to you and give you a discretionary exemption.
Rym: It forgives loans less than 12K remaining.
Rym: If after 10 years you still haven't paid off that last bit, excess interest.
Rym: There is so much going on in this bill.
Rym: I would say go to the government website.
Rym: Well, yeah, it's an order, which is because that's actually kind of relevant.
Rym: We can't pass bills like this.
Rym: There's literally no way to pass a bill like this.
Rym: So the only way we can do this is an executive order, which means there are limits to exactly how far it can go.
Rym: But this is a huge goddamn deal.
Rym: I would say go to the government website to check out exactly how it affects you.
Scott: If you're a United States person who has student loans left.
Scott: However, I hope you didn't refinance them with some non-government place.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: However, one, that government website is down the fuck down right now.
Rym: So give it a few days.
Rym: And two, if there is, I doubt there's anyone listening to this podcast who believes this, but if you're the kind of person who somehow thinks this is unfair, especially because you paid off your student loans and you're mad that other people...
Scott: I paid off my student loans.
Rym: I paid off mine.
Scott: But I wouldn't even be able to get this because I make too much money.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I would say if you're mad about this, you're a prick.
Rym: If I'm not going to make an economic argument or a political argument, you are just a bad person who wants people to suffer for no reason.
Scott: You just believe that because, right, it's like you had to suffer and therefore you believe other people should also suffer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you're just a piece of shit.
Scott: People who really suffer.
Rym: If we diverted the trolley to the track with no one on it, it wouldn't be fair to all the people the trolley already killed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like most people who really suffer.
Scott: They, you know, it's like they say no one else should ever have to suffer like I suffered.
Scott: That's what a good person says.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: If you say, right, I suffered so you should also have to suffer, you're a bad person who's not good for society.
Scott: We should either fix you or get rid of you or something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You got problems.
Scott: You're the problem with the world.
Scott: Get the hell out of here.
Scott: There are some people who are concerned about inflation, which I guess is not entirely wrong.
Scott: There is some amount of truth there.
Scott: But what I would say to them is that, okay, let's, you know, y'all just give them, I'll just give it to them.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Let's say that, what, $300 billion, whatever, you know.
Rym: Oh, you're using one of my favorite rhetorical constructs.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I'll agree to 90% of what you said.
Rym: just to get to the part that's the stupidest thing you said.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So we're just going to let you pretend that, that the thing that's not true, that you're arguing for is true.
Scott: Cause that's how wrong you are is that we can pretend that your assertion is true when it's not.
Scott: And you'll still be wrong.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Let's say that this, this is the equivalent of just printing $300 billion, which would cause some amount of inflation.
Rym: I mean, one that rounds down to zero in terms of like how money works.
Scott: If you're really concerned about that, right, that amount of inflation and in that printing of that money, this is a much better way to spend $300 billion than a lot of things in the U S budget.
Scott: You should instead argue for cutting the defense budget by $300 billion for one year or $30 billion a year for 10 years or something like that.
Scott: And so if you are saying that this is the inflation problem, you're basically saying that helping people whose lives are incredibly burdened and uplifting all of society is a worse way to spend money than bombs or subsidies to big companies or any of the other awful things.
Rym: I won't even grant people the, well, we could cut defense spending because the reality is we could not only keep defense spending at the level it is, but radically increase it and, and homelessness and, and hunger and of universal healthcare in America.
Rym: And all we'd have to do is raise taxes on the very rich by not even that much.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you're worried about inflation, then you should just say, okay, canceling student loans is good.
Scott: And then we should raise some taxes to make up for it, which would cancel out.
Scott: Why don't we just delete, delete favor of raising the taxes on the rich and that why are you against the student loan thing?
Scott: Why don't you just argue for, if the inflation is your concern, just argue for something else, right?
Scott: Like cutting spending or raising taxes to balance it out.
Scott: Don't argue against the student loan spending.
Rym: Pay off the student loans and delete an equivalent amount of money from the hundred, from the thousand highest balance saving accounts in America.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The point is if someone is arguing, you know, for the, with the inflation argument, trying to hide the fact that they're a prick, the fact that their solution is to get rid of the student loan spending and not some other solution to cancel it out.
Scott: Inflation wise shows they're just hiding.
Scott: the truth is that they believe that I suffered, therefore you should suffer.
Rym: Well, similarly.
Rym: So people who are mad about this, who are saying, well, I shouldn't have to pay for someone else's student loan.
Rym: Let's skip the.
Rym: you're a bad person.
Scott: You pay for everyone else's social security.
Scott: You pay for everyone else.
Rym: Because how this is actually being paid for, uh, effectively there are people who will pay for these loans through taxes and people who won't.
Rym: Anyone who is, who says they have to pay for these is already a multimillionaire or billionaire.
Rym: And most of the people who are mad about this will pay zero more dollars in taxes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, uh, yeah.
Rym: Getting into some, uh, anime news.
Rym: Uh, you just watched the documentary.
Rym: We've talked about this before.
Rym: I don't need to say much about it, but if you are unaware of the live action animated crossover sailor moon that was, that they tried to produce for American TV and then scrapped, but they filmed a whole pilot, uh, Mike tool, you'd like to show the clips that you've all seen from this thing.
Rym: Well, uh, someone found the entire pilots, the entire library of Congress.
Scott: I think they found it.
Rym: They found it in the library of Congress, the entire episode, all the footage, and they not only published it, but they put, they made a documentary about it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: If you don't know about it, basically there was, you know, a children's animation company back in the day that, you know, tried to make a U S version of sailor moon, get rid of all the Japanese stuff and make it palatable to a multicultural American audience.
Rym: That was the target demographic of kids TV.
Scott: Uh, well, they weren't doing that, you know, cause the original sailor moon was palatable.
Scott: They were just making it palatable to their own adult senses.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Of what's American advertisers are.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Palatable to what?
Rym: producers of entertainment, racist people.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: It's bad.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They, you know, and it, it never started, but they, they met, they produced the one, the one thing, and now we can watch that one thing.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And, uh, we'll see, we'll see if any, if we ever talk about this again, but you can watch it.
Scott: It's a fascinating history.
Rym: It is.
Rym: It absolutely is.
Rym: Uh, real quick, I got a mini geek bite here.
Rym: As you all know, I was a big fan of Beavis and Butthead when I was young, uh, much like that for a hundred D. The reason I got into Beavis and Butthead is because my mom actually got me and my little brother to watch it.
Rym: Like when it first aired.
Scott: I watched it a bit, but I wasn't that into it.
Rym: The family would sit around and watch it.
Rym: This was, this was as important as the Simpsons to us as a family.
Rym: So, but I'll say is Beavis and Butthead was rebooted once, but it was rebooted again recently.
Rym: The first season of the new Beavis and Butthead is airing right now.
Rym: You can watch it on Paramount Plus.
Rym: Uh, I think there's like four episodes that are out so far total.
Rym: And as a brief geek bite, I will say one, it is hilarious.
Rym: Two, it is worth watching.
Rym: Three, it is deeply a spiritual successor.
Rym: Like it is true to what made Beavis and Butthead funny in the old days, but it has advanced the writing.
Rym: Like the writing's a little better.
Rym: It has more modern sensibilities.
Rym: Uh, they've excised some of the grosser and less entertaining or more dated parts of Beavis and Butthead.
Rym: Uh, and it almost has a Looney Tunes style of humor in terms of how situations escalate.
Rym: It is dense with comedy.
Rym: Uh, I'm going to watch every goddamn episode of this.
Rym: And the most important thing, they have continued, they brought back the part of Beavis and Butthead that was actually the most important part, which was not the cartoon itself, but the meta show where it's just them on the couch watching music videos and making fun of them.
Rym: They still have that.
Rym: Sometimes they watch music videos.
Rym: Sometimes they're watching whatever YouTube videos or TikToks are viral at any given time.
Rym: And if you see nothing else from the show.
Scott: Are they paying to license those TikToks?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: If you watch nothing else, find the clip.
Scott: I guess if you make a TikTok and then Beavis and Butthead tries to include it in their episode, they only have to pay TikTok and not you because TikTok turns to service.
Scott: They own that shit, right?
Scott: So that sucks.
Scott: But I guess you get some fame, maybe?
Rym: I think you'd get some fame.
Rym: So the one clip you should watch, if you're not sure if you'd like this or not, Beavis and Butthead, watch one of those ASMR videos.
Rym: And it is a peak moment of comedy, this segment.
Rym: You got any news?
Scott: We got some more news.
Scott: So Paprika, right?
Scott: The last Satoshi Kon movie was based on a book, right?
Scott: The book was by, what was that guy's name?
Scott: Tsutsui, I think?
Rym: Uh, do you think so?
Scott: Yeah, I never remember his first name, right?
Scott: But basically he's this really famous Japanese, like, contemporary sci-fi author.
Scott: And he also, I believe, wrote Girl Who Leapt Through Time, the book, whatever it was based on, I believe, same author.
Scott: Anyway, so somebody is going to make a Hollywood live action series based on the book that Paprika was based on by the novelist Tsutsui.
Scott: And obviously, even though that technically means that there's no connection to Paprika the movie, right, they obviously are going to use the fact that Paprika is a great movie based on the same work as part of the hype for their series that they're making.
Rym: Total aside, I'm just going to read what the listener just typed, because in this case the listener is my mom.
Rym: Late to the stream, oh my god, the balloon story.
Rym: I will never forget the whole mall panic it caused.
Scott: Alright, so that's the thing that's happening.
Rym: There are, I would say, charitably, there is a wide range of how this is going to go, this show.
Rym: This could be terrible, this could be amazing.
Rym: We'll just have to see.
Scott: I would like to see, because I've heard about this author quite a few times and never actually read any of their books.
Scott: I don't know how many, if any, are available in English.
Scott: But I would like to see this author, maybe if they get elevated to the Murakami level, or at least the level where their books all come out in English and I can read them.
Scott: Because it seems like a lot of people have taken a lot of interest in this author's works.
Scott: And I remember when I was watching the Satoshi Kon documentary, there was a lot of mention of this author.
Scott: And like Satoshi Kon, often blurs the line between fiction and reality.
Rym: Plus, randomly, Harley Quinn, the show, just had a weirdly long reference to 1Q84 because all the characters are into it and reading it, just in an episode for some reason.
Rym: What the hell?
Rym: That show's actually pretty good and you would probably enjoy it.
Scott: Anyway, in other news, in the United States, we have these mega movie theaters all everywhere, owned by a few chains.
Scott: And AMC, I think, is the biggest one.
Rym: Also the bankruptest one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So AMC was sort of in on the GameStop stock shenanigans, and what they're doing is they're going harder on those shenanigans.
Scott: They're creating some security of some kind called ape, right?
Rym: Now obviously they are referencing bored ape NFT bullshit without saying it out loud.
Scott: I think it's that the people who were all in on AMC stock around the GameStop time also coincidentally called themselves ape, apes, right?
Scott: Which might have stood for something, like AMC proppers, I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, but there's definitely a cultural commonality between that group and the NFT groups of people, right?
Scott: There's clearly the same crowd, right?
Scott: It's the same humans.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah, they're going to sell some kind of security called ape as the symbol.
Rym: I didn't read all the details.
Rym: I'm pretty sure it's a preferred stock of some kind.
Scott: I don't know what the deal is.
Rym: Here's the best way I'm going to try to explain this in like...
Scott: As far as I can tell, it's a scam to just get money from fools.
Rym: In my personal opinion, but not the opinion of any employer I may work for or have worked for in the past, this is probably a scam.
Rym: But the way the rules work is, I would say, in my opinion, companies like AMC, you can tell when I'm thinking about what the lawyer would say if he was standing over my back.
Rym: They have to do this by the book and be very transparent about what they're doing and why.
Rym: And all the dipshit investors who are buying these meme stocks, who have no idea how the stock market works, are basically giving them cover to fleece people because they can point to their stock price and point to this interest and say, "Because of that, we are doing
Rym: this.".
Rym: And the SEC has to look at it and say, "Yeah, I guess technically that is true because we can't actually take action against you just because a whole bunch of people are extremely
Rym: stupid.".
Scott: So that's happening, but at the same time, Regal Cinema, another major big time theater chain, might be going bankrupt.
Rym: Theaters across the country are going bankrupt.
Rym: We've talked about this on GeekNights.
Rym: for as long as GeekNights has been going.
Rym: I remember, even when we were living in Beacon, every movie theater anywhere near us, if we ever went to the movies, there'd be like two people in the theater with us, even back then, at any time.
Rym: Weekends, weekdays, any time, no one was at the theater.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: So yeah, that's, you know, theaters, you know, we thought theaters were in trouble during the pandemic times, but now those, you know, are the pandemic times over?
Scott: No, they're not, not even close.
Scott: But, you know, people have largely come outside, right?
Scott: People are going to the movies and I guess they don't miss going, most people don't seem to miss going to the theater that much.
Scott: I think going to the theater will mostly be a thing for people who really care about that sort of thing.
Rym: I like to go to the theater for big movies I care about.
Rym: Like I'll go see Dune in the theater at some point.
Rym: I'm sure it'll be in the theater again.
Scott: I think, you know, the point is there's going to still be a theater going crowd.
Scott: It will reduce over time and it'll, you know, there'll be the, you know, certain special places that have a theater for, you know, special runs of things and then other things, just most people might not ever go to one, right?
Rym: In some tragic news, a gentleman who most of you would probably know as the voice actor of Fuyutsuki in Evangelion, Motomu Kiyokawa has passed away at the age of 87.
Rym: Once again, Godspeed.
Scott: I'll take 87.
Rym: Every time I see someone who was famous and popular and seemed like a good person and seemed to be in good health and made it like past 80 something, I would take that.
Rym: Absolutely.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But yeah, if you look at the photos of the dude, I've never seen the guy before in my life or even a photo of him until now.
Rym: He kind of looks like my grandma.
Rym: Like I'm not even joking.
Scott: But he's definitely got that, you know, cool old Japanese guy style, right?
Rym: I think it's because he's wearing the same glasses my grandma always wore.
Scott: The gradient, right?
Scott: You know, the cool suit and whatever.
Scott: But it's like you look at this guy, you could probably guess he's the voice actor of Fuyutsuki.
Scott: just looking at this photo, right?
Scott: And it's like, you know, just looking at that photo gives me the feeling like that was one badass dude.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I said this was also relevant to my opening bit.
Rym: So for those of you who are somehow unaware, I grew up in Detroit.
Rym: Detroit was an interesting place when I was a kid in the 80s.
Rym: But there's a place in Detroit.
Rym: It is.
Rym: Detroit's a fascinating place.
Rym: I think Detroit will be a very important city in the years to come because Detroit might be, and Chicago together, are the biggest real cities in the world that are in some of the places that are geographically the safest from climate change the longest.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So if you haven't lived in Detroit, you've probably never heard of Belle Isle, which is basically this island that's like in the Detroit River between Detroit and Canada.
Rym: It's like a giant park.
Rym: It's like this giant park island.
Scott: We looked it up.
Scott: It's five square miles.
Scott: So it's kind of big, actually.
Rym: It is kind of big.
Rym: When I was a kid, it had a reputation for a few things.
Rym: One, a lot of violence happened there, like a lot of gang shootings, a lot of fights, a lot of trouble.
Rym: There were fallow deer that used to live on the island.
Rym: I'm pretty sure they're all gone now.
Rym: There were a lot of nature parks, like there'd be field trips there that we'd go to as kids.
Rym: But there was this thing.
Rym: It was built in like 1966 or 1967 that we just used to call the Belle Isle Slide.
Rym: It is just this gigantic, dangerous-as-shit metal slide that you would just get in a burlap sack and ride.
Scott: Now, there's plenty of big slides that you ride in a burlap sack.
Rym: I've done that tons of times.
Rym: This is the kind of thing, if you saw a video of this, even without seeing the danger of it, the first thing you would think is, "Oh, is that an action
Rym: park?".
Rym: I would be hard-pressed to argue against that if I didn't know the Belle Isle existed.
Scott: Action Park had an alpine slide, even more dangerous.
Rym: Fun fact, more people are injured at ski resorts on the alpine slides than are ever injured at ski resorts actually skiing.
Scott: And that's a large amount because a lot of people are injured skiing.
Rym: Do not ever get on an alpine slide.
Rym: But anyway, do not ride the giant slide at Belle Isle either.
Rym: So I guess it closed.
Rym: I rode this as a kid.
Rym: Stories of its danger and its jankiness are not unfounded, nor are they exaggerated.
Rym: But this thing was closed in like 1994.
Rym: I think it was closed until 2014.
Rym: They opened it again, they closed it again.
Rym: Long story short, it is now a meme, and the whole world knows about it.
Scott: A pile of rubble is what it should be.
Rym: So Detroit rapper GM Cash wrote a song about the slide, and what I'm going to link to is a tweet where someone has taken this song and juxtaposed it with images of this slide when it just reopened.
Rym: I think Jimmy Kimmel even talked about it, so this is looming large in pop culture out of nowhere.
Rym: Basically, they reopened it, they polished it too much when they cleaned it, and it was already dangerous before.
Rym: Like you have to ride it with a special technique that I learned as a kid, or you will very likely lose a tooth.
Rym: And people did not know this technique, and it was way slicker than it should have been.
Rym: And I guess I would say it is like jumping off a roof riding the giant slide.
Rym: Just watch this video.
Rym: This is kind of amazing.
Rym: This brought back so many memories of my childhood.
Rym: Do not go to Belle Isle and ride this slide.
Rym: I cannot stress that enough.
Scott: Hopefully they don't let anyone do that.
Rym: They reopened it after degreasing it and spraying it with water.
Scott: But it's still open?
Rym: Yeah, but it is back to the level of danger I remember from the late 80s in Detroit, and not the level of danger from like a week ago.
Scott: The danger is too damn high.
Rym: The lyrics to this song are something else.
Rym: What was it?
Rym: If your kids are annoying you, put them on the giant slide.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Alright, so when I was a kid, we did safe things like go to the fancy mall.
Rym: Hopefully someone doesn't pop a balloon and cause a stampede.
Scott: Yeah, and in the 90s, the economy was fucked the fuck up in a different way than it is now.
Scott: And that meant that shopping malls were like amusement parks basically.
Rym: Well, the nice shopping malls were.
Rym: When we were a kid, we would go to Eastside Mall like in Detroit.
Rym: No store like this was in that mall.
Scott: There were regular malls and then there were fancy malls that had, like I said, carousels and you know, all kinds of, you know, it's like go to amusement park.
Rym: We would like get in the car as a family on a Saturday and go to Lakeside Mall out in the suburbs.
Scott: There would be an arcade there, there would be a food court.
Rym: Lakeside Mall had two indoor water slides and a pool.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It was, you know, get Nathan's, right?
Scott: It was like an event to go to the, anyway.
Scott: So, one of the things, one of the key features of any 90s US fancy mall was a Warner Brothers Studio store.
Scott: And the thing about a Warner Brothers Studio store is that, you know, it had, the store itself was just fun to be in because there was all sorts of animatronics and things on display.
Rym: I would say it was Warner Brothers stuff.
Rym: The average Warner Brothers store like this was higher quality than the Disney equivalent stores that were contemporary to them.
Scott: The Disney stores were pretty equally fancy in terms of the arrangement of the store.
Rym: True, but the Warner Brothers store had way higher quality merchandise.
Scott: The Warner Brothers Disney store mostly just sold Disney merch, like shit with Mickey's face on it, right?
Scott: It wasn't like you went to the Disney store, it's like there wasn't anything special on sale there typically, right?
Scott: It's like I think my cousin collected this one kind of statue they had there, but it's like that was about it.
Rym: Oh my god, the statues I had, anyway.
Scott: The Warner Brothers Studio store had like rare, unique merch, like collectibles and shit.
Scott: Like at all these stores they were selling animation cells and like, you know, film pieces and like, like if you were a film nerd, they actually had.
Scott: like all these rare, or like, you know, in a day when there wasn't so much internet or no internet, it's like this kind of stuff was not accessible to the average person anywhere, you know?
Scott: Videotapes of things that you couldn't get anywhere else.
Rym: If they still had t-shirts with Batman on them, right?
Rym: Think about how you felt when you went to an anime con before.
Rym: you could buy stuff online and there was a dealer's room.
Rym: That was what it felt like to go to one of these stores in a mall in the 80s and early 90s.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they just had like this unbelievable stuff there, like you couldn't believe that like, it's the kind of stuff you might expect to see at like an amusement park gift shop right in the fancy section, but it's like they were able to gather so much stuff and produce so much stuff and have it in malls everywhere.
Scott: It was like, that was, it was pretty awesome.
Scott: Even though we really didn't buy any of it, it was still really great to go to the store, maybe that's why it went out of business.
Scott: Because people going in a store and not buying anything isn't a great way to profit.
Scott: Anyway, so someone made a video about the rise and fall of the Warner Brothers store.
Scott: Honestly, the video is not the best video.
Scott: It's not like defunct land where they super researched and give you all this interesting info and you know, whatever.
Scott: But, the video does comprise of, is comprised of, a lot of old footage.
Scott: So you can see shit going down at Warner Brothers stores back in the day and that is worth watching this video.
Scott: You can see like, you know, grand openings of big stores and the interiors of normal ones and interviews with customers and some of the merch and all this stuff.
Scott: And if you didn't experience these stores yourself, it's a thing to see.
Scott: And if you have experienced the stores yourself, it's a nostalgia to see.
Scott: So, why not?
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book is binti.
Rym: We'll see when we do the show because we're going to miss a ton of GeekNights.
Rym: I think I'm even going to pause the Patreon for September because I'm going to be with Emily, doing a panel at PAX West, losing on Sunday.
Rym: I will also be doing a bunch of work travel and- No, that's this Sunday.
Scott: Yeah, well, it is- No, it's two Sundays from now.
Rym: It is next Sunday, not this Sunday.
Rym: I am very happy that you have agreed with me on this versus next Sunday.
Rym: Otherwise, you know, work travel, that bike trip- I said two Sundays from now.
Rym: Two Sundays from now.
Rym: But website's coming along.
Rym: I don't really think we have any other big updates to share just yet.
Rym: Maybe Scott can finish some of the website stuff while we're not doing GeekNights while I'm doing all this travel.
Scott: It depends on the weather.
Scott: This weekend is looking a lot more letter B.
Rym: Bike and beach than it is looking- Yeah, no, this weekend is 100% a B weekend.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, let's go.
Scott: So, yeah, what happened was is last week we went to go and see a Radio City Music Hall where I haven't been inside since last millennia.
Scott: Just because there never was a show that I went to see there, just coincidentally.
Scott: And we went to see Joe Hisaishi and a large orchestra with choirs and opera singer and his daughter singing and pianists and a guy playing an instrument I don't know the name of that looked like a ukulele and a banjo got together and had a baby.
Scott: And they played the works of Hayao Miyazaki while on a giant screen they played clips from movies to accompany the music and the whole place was 100% sold out.
Scott: And it was actually way- I thought it was going to be pretty good.
Scott: It was I'd say better than I thought.
Scott: It was pretty fantastic.
Scott: If you have a chance to ever go to that, I recommend it.
Scott: But yeah, he had to cancel his London shows because he got COVID and the US shows got delayed.
Scott: but somehow we still went and it happened and he was alright and it was real good.
Scott: So, but that made me think, hey, we need a Wednesday idea.
Scott: We haven't watched the anime.
Scott: But how many episodes have we really done about Miyazaki, right?
Scott: The legendary anime director, right?
Rym: Maybe the most legendary anime director in ancient times in like 2006 or something.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: I looked it up and even though we talk about him all the goddamn time in the news and other things, we did an episode on Laputa, a whole episode.
Scott: It was the main bit.
Scott: There were some opening bits or geek bites about other works that we saw but we didn't both see them at the same time or whatever.
Scott: And it's like we really haven't done a whole lot of full episodes about him.
Scott: We're like, well, you know what?
Scott: We're not going to like, I don't see us rewatching all of these soon to do full episodes on all of them.
Scott: That would be like a year long project for us because it was like, how many just feature films he made that he directed?
Scott: One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, twelve.
Scott: Well, the twelfth one is being worked on.
Scott: Only two of them were released.
Scott: Twelve Wednesdays?
Scott: That's like half a year of GeekNights.
Rym: Only two of them were released while GeekNights was in production.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I think we had to review The Wind Rises.
Rym: We saw it in the theater and we had a lot to say about it.
Scott: I didn't see it.
Scott: You saw it.
Scott: I saw Princess Kaguya and you didn't.
Scott: You didn't direct but it was still Studio Ghibli.
Rym: You should watch The Wind Rises.
Rym: I could do a review on it right now without even needing to see it again.
Scott: I heard some music from the soundtrack live.
Scott: I performed live.
Rym: It's the one where a lot of the background sound is human beings doing foley with their bodies.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so I'm like, hey, let's just, you know, get an easy Wednesday idea.
Scott: Let's go and talk about these movies and Miyazaki and Studio Ghibli briefly as a whole.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I think we can focus.
Scott: How can you not have an episode on that?
Scott: That seems like a necessary episode to have.
Rym: If there is one thing I associate, if you just say the words Miyazaki movie, the things that I think of just off the top of my head immediately are environmental messages and lush backgrounds, lush landscapes, scenes with lots of little shit moving around everywhere.
Scott: You love to do that animation, that particular kind of animation that you see, the boar in Manonoke and Panyo, all the water, right?
Scott: It's like the motion of like just lots of snakes or like a blob or, you know, even Spirited Away also, right?
Rym: Or people, whenever there is one character, they're animated in a certain way.
Rym: Whenever there's a bunch of characters, like in In La Pita, there's the blob of pirates that just appears over and over again doing pirate stuff together.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like this certain, I don't know how they did, just like this is his look of, you know, animating a mass in a certain way that he like keeps going back to and reusing that sort of aesthetic over and over.
Scott: And it's just, it's like an eye candy kind of thing.
Rym: I think of with few exceptions, a certain amount of childhood whimsy, strong female protagonists who often look very similar to one another.
Scott: You know, that feeling of being in a warm, cozy cottage in the woods alone, but the cottage is full of interesting shit, like, you know, sort of in a maybe like a Roald Dahl kind of way a little bit.
Scott: A little bit of that feeling.
Rym: And also just...
Scott: A little bit of Dr.
Scott: Seuss feeling.
Rym: I can say there's definitely a little bit of that in there.
Rym: An absolutely like mind, not mind bending, but just an absolutely fantastic score that gets stuck in your head.
Rym: You even think about one of these movies.
Scott: Like we just discussed, that's Joe Hisaki's fault.
Scott: Someone chose to hire him, I guess.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So, yeah, let's, uh, let's go through.
Scott: So we're gonna talk about the full length animated features that Miyazaki directed, right?
Scott: So Studio Ghibli is his studio.
Scott: You got to remember a lot of things made by that studio.
Scott: He did not direct, you know, someone else directed it.
Scott: He had a different level of involvement in those things, right?
Scott: Or, and some of them that they produced were shorter, right?
Scott: So, for example, like Pompoco, it was a Studio Ghibli movie.
Scott: He was the executive producer.
Scott: He was not the director.
Scott: He didn't, you know, who knows, did he draw anything for it?
Scott: Maybe, right?
Scott: But it's like, doesn't count, right?
Scott: You know, Arrietty, right?
Scott: It's like he was just a co-screenwriter and planner, right?
Scott: So it's like, okay, he had some involvement there, but you can't really call that a Miyazaki movie.
Scott: It is clearly a Studio Ghibli movie, right?
Scott: There were other ones where, like, he was the director, but they were short, right?
Scott: They weren't full-length animated features.
Scott: So usually, these are like those ones that they show at the Ghibli Museum only, and you can't see them anywhere else easily.
Scott: I have seen exactly one of those.
Scott: Yeah, On Your Mark, the music video, right, for example.
Scott: But yeah, so the movie is in chronological order.
Scott: The only one from before we were born was, you know, Castle of Cagliostro, which I think we might have done a full episode on that.
Rym: If we did, that's an easy show.
Scott: I don't think that was Studio Ghibli, though, right?
Scott: That was just a thing he directed.
Rym: He just directed it and he wrote it.
Rym: And what I love is that Lupin has this already, like, this history that we know today as different people do their take on Lupin.
Rym: Just like Bon, we've talked about that before.
Rym: And this Lupin was a mold breaker in that there aren't really other Lupins quite like the Miyazaki Lupin.
Rym: And this is my favorite.
Rym: I don't even count it my favorite Lupin because I consider it separate.
Rym: It is one of my favorite Miyazaki movies, but it is so different from a lot of the Lupin canon that I wouldn't say it's my favorite Lupin movie.
Rym: But it's also my favorite Lupin movie if I combined all the Lupin canons together.
Scott: Before this, he had worked on a bunch of these other movies where you can sort of see the one we always go to as a Horus Prince of Sun.
Scott: Sort of like the pre-Miyazaki Miyazaki.
Scott: You can watch Horus Prince of Sun that he contributed significantly to and you can see a lot of Studio Ghibli Miyazaki stuff in there even though Studio Ghibli didn't exist yet.
Scott: And then in Castle of Cagliostro where he's actually directing, you can see it even more even though this is an existing property.
Scott: He didn't write it.
Scott: I think he made the screenplay, but he didn't create Lupin, right?
Rym: Yeah, he just took Lupin.
Rym: He took these characters and somehow was able to seamlessly have all of them fit into a Miyazaki kind of story that's lighthearted and earnest and fun and whimsical but also a little dark.
Rym: And yet be somehow pretty true to those Lupin characters.
Rym: It's kind of amazing considering what those Lupin characters are like in the vast majority of Lupin that came up to the year 1979.
Scott: It also helped that he sort of minimized their involvement in the story, right?
Scott: There is not like a shit ton of Jigen in that movie as compared to other Lupin.
Rym: But where he appears with your sword and my anti-tank rifle.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Alright, so then the real Studio Ghibli begins and Naoshika comes out right after we're born.
Scott: And now the real deal has begun, right?
Scott: He made the manga Naoshika.
Scott: That was his manga.
Scott: He made it all, you know, at least his name is the only name on it.
Scott: He had assistants clearly, right?
Scott: Like all manga authors do.
Scott: And the manga, if you haven't read it, it's available in English.
Scott: You can buy this big ol' box with it in there.
Scott: I've read it all.
Scott: Yeah, and that manga is a hell of a thing.
Scott: And it tells this huge story.
Scott: And much like Akira, where the movie is, you know, clearly related to the original manga.
Scott: But, you know, sort of does not tell the whole vast sprawling story that the manga tells.
Scott: It tells a much more condensed, focused, brief story in the same characters, in the same universe with some similarities, right?
Scott: But, you know, it's sort of like, we didn't just adapt it straight over, you know?
Scott: But yeah, Naoshika is a hell of a thing.
Rym: Yep, it's definitely, even despite only covering such a tiny part of the manga and being pretty constrained in that way, it still tells a very sweeping, epic story.
Rym: And it does a pretty good payoff.
Rym: Like, there's a lot going on in that movie that I very much enjoyed.
Rym: I quote it pretty often that "if not now, then when" from the very end of the movie with the weapon.
Rym: I guess, no spoilers for people who somehow have not seen every Miyazaki movie.
Scott: You probably should.
Scott: Any movie we mention here, you should probably watch.
Rym: Yeah, if there's any movie we mention that you have not heard of or seen, just go watch it, like, tonight.
Rym: You will not be disappointed.
Scott: They're all on HBO Max.
Scott: Well, we'll see how long that lasts.
Scott: If you're in the US, they're legally available on HBO Max.
Scott: And if you're elsewhere in the world, figure it out.
Scott: And no matter where you are in the world, yarrrr.
Rym: So, Laputa Castle in the Sky, it might be my favorite Miyazaki movie.
Rym: Partly because I am big into precursor technology and stories around that kind of story.
Scott: Well, Naoshika has some of that.
Rym: Oh, it does.
Rym: I'm not saying it doesn't.
Rym: Actually, a few of these have that.
Scott: Even Cagliostro has, sort of.
Rym: I guess what I liked about Castle in the Sky, specifically, is that it is a movie, a little bit apart from the rest of his movies, where the environmental storytelling tells this extremely sweeping, epic tale of the rise and fall of civilizations.
Rym: Like, the background of this movie tells a bigger story than a lot of movies tell in their foreground.
Rym: But the foreground movie, somehow, is just this very narrow story about some people who are just existing in this tiny fraction of the time that the background is telling this story about.
Rym: Like, the opening credits tell you this entire rise and fall story of civilizations, and there's no words.
Rym: You just see it in these very simple imagery.
Rym: I think Laputa, more so than any other movie he made, other than Maybe the Wind Rises, trusts the audience to get it, and trusts the audience to understand what it's trying to say without saying any of that out loud.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, we did the whole episode on it.
Scott: You can listen to that, but I will say that when I think about Laputa, I also think about Zelda games.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: In a Zelda game, there's not a lot of talking too much, right?
Scott: And it's like, you know, Link walks around a dungeon, and there's an environmental storytelling to it, right?
Scott: It's like just experiencing this place, right?
Scott: You now understand, like, what happened here, right?
Scott: And Laputa is the same thing.
Scott: All the dialogue in Laputa is about, you know, the people and their, like, current conflict that they're dealing with.
Scott: Pretty much most of the dialogue anyway, right?
Scott: But it ends up, you know, they're traveling in the world that they're in, usually in airplanes and other things, and they end up in places that are, you know, amazing, and it's like when you just see the places, you now understand what happened, right?
Scott: And that's, you know, you get this really sort of, you know, sense of awe of, like, as if you were yourself standing in some sort of amazing place like that.
Rym: That is one thing that most Miyazaki movies do very well, is there will be scenes that inspire a sense of awe, very specifically in a particular way.
Scott: Yeah, even though Laputa carries over a lot of the, you know, the tropes that Naoshika started that you see in all the Ghibli movies, right?
Scott: Like the magical girl heroine character, and all these things we already discussed, right?
Scott: You know, it's one of the only ones that has that sort of, like, you know, going to the secret place deal, right?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, all right.
Scott: Totoro is next one, right?
Scott: That's probably the most famous one.
Scott: It's the one that they use for their logo.
Rym: Totoro and Kiki's are the ones I've seen the least recently again.
Scott: Totoro is maybe the one I've seen most least recently, but I've seen Kiki's somewhat recently.
Scott: But yeah, Totoro is like, it's just, you know, the story it tells isn't honestly that much of a story.
Rym: Well, because the story it's really telling is that, like, why is this family here?
Rym: Like, the story it doesn't tell is sort of the context for the story of Totoro.
Scott: You know, it's sort of an imaginary friend kind of deal.
Rym: How do kids cope with, like, what the adults are talking about and what's actually happening and why we've gone to live in the summer house?
Scott: Right, and I think you do see, there's again a commonality with Zelda, right?
Scott: Miyamoto always talks about how he made Zelda 1 by, you know, going into the woods and whatever behind his house, right?
Scott: And that sort of feeling, and this is basically that feeling, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, the kid goes outside into the woods behind their house and has, you know, their imagination and their adventures even though it's just a small woods behind a house.
Scott: Which actually, that's a theme that brings out the cat boss and it brings out everything.
Rym: You want to talk about a very specific theme that is common to almost all Miyazaki movies.
Rym: There will be a child who has real agency over their own world and the world around them.
Scott: Usually.
Rym: Almost all of them.
Rym: The ones that don't, like, The Wind Rises does not have that.
Rym: The Wind Rises is a very different movie.
Scott: Parkaroso, not so much.
Rym: Parkaroso is very much like The Wind Rises.
Scott: The airplane ones, right?
Rym: Yeah, the airplane ones are about a very different thing.
Scott: Well, Lapita is also an airplane one.
Scott: Nachika is also an airplane one.
Scott: That's another thing.
Scott: Miyazaki fucking loves airplanes, right?
Rym: I would argue that Lapita, I refuse to explain this in detail because we don't have that much time left on the show.
Rym: Lapita is the intersection of the rest of what Miyazaki likes to do and specifically the themes of The Wind Rises and Parkaroso.
Rym: But I refuse to explain that further.
Rym: I will not elaborate.
Rym: But Pokemon does that too.
Rym: And you see this very specifically in Kiki's Delivery Service.
Scott: You've got a young girl in Kiki's Delivery Service who comes to a town and creates a business and starts paying rent.
Scott: And it's like becoming an instant adult basically.
Rym: Kiki's is just such a delightful, charming movie that everyone should watch.
Scott: The story of it is not a particularly amazing story, but it's just that you don't see that kind of story become a mass media item.
Scott: No one sells a book with that kind of story.
Scott: No one sells a movie with that kind of story.
Scott: Except this one, right?
Rym: So when we get past that, these movies all are very similar to one another in a lot of ways.
Rym: They have these very clear thematic connections.
Rym: And then Parkaroso I think hits a lot of people who are watching a Miyazaki canon like a curveball.
Rym: Because it is about fascism, it is about chauvinism, it is an adult movie, but it's animated the same way as all the rest of them.
Rym: It's got the blobs of people and that amazing fist fight scene.
Rym: It's got all the Miyazaki scenes.
Rym: That fist fight scene is like, that goes on a top ten list of animated scenes in all movies ever for me.
Rym: Maybe top twenty.
Scott: It's definitely more, most of Miyazaki movies, all of them, are clearly movies for children first.
Scott: Like George Lucas likes to pretend.
Scott: He's like Star Wars is for the children.
Scott: Miyazaki's movies are for the children.
Scott: Except, Parkaroso, even if he wants to say it was for the children, I don't think a lot of children would enjoy or understand it.
Scott: I can't imagine how they would.
Scott: I don't think I would have enjoyed, I might have slightly enjoyed it, but not understood it when I was a child until maybe at least I had two digits or plus in my age.
Rym: I expect as a child I would have loved Parkaroso and not realized what it was about and be like, "Yeah, the cool pig.
Rym: He's got an airplane.
Rym: Yeah!".
Rym: But, Parkaroso, much like The Wind Rises, is very much like this deep interrogation of what it is to be a man or what are the consequences of the decisions we make.
Rym: It'd be hard to get into it much deeper without getting into Parkaroso, which I feel like we can do a show on at some point, but Parkaroso is a standout movie for me specifically.
Rym: It's got this sort of mid-century, it reminds me of a lot of plays and musicals that are sort of set in this Americana mid-century, just in terms of the style of the way people interact and how the towns on these islands act.
Rym: Even though it's not set in that setting, it has a similar aesthetic or a similar sort of feel to me.
Scott: Those first four, Naoshika, Laputa, Totoro, Kiki's, those are huge deals, but they were huge deals on the other side of the world.
Scott: People still didn't know about any of that stuff outside of that geography in and around Japan.
Scott: Princess Mononoke was sort of the breaking point, where I remember in the year 2000, in between high school and college, I went to Israel and one of the kids I was on the trip with was talking about this movie, Princess Mononoke.
Scott: I didn't know who Miyazaki was, I didn't know anything.
Scott: But he's like, "Oh, you gotta see this movie, it's the
Scott: best.".
Scott: And I'm like,
Scott: "Alright.".
Scott: And then I remember we walked past a movie theater and the poster for the movie was there.
Scott: and I'm like, "Oh, this dude was talking about a movie that's out
Scott: now.".
Scott: I didn't realize that, I thought it was some older movie I had missed or something.
Rym: I had pirated Mononoke Hime with subtitles to watch before it even made it to the US.
Rym: I already had the soundtrack that I pirated, because by then I was already like eight years into being a weeb.
Rym: But it was the first anime movie in my entire life where non-weebs knew about it without me being the one to tell them about it.
Scott: Right, well Akira I think was the first one of those.
Rym: Non-weebs in my area did not know about Akira, weirdly.
Scott: It was in a local newspaper and shit.
Rym: All the people I knew who were into weird sci-fi stuff when I was a kid, they were also already into anime, mostly because I got them into anime.
Scott: Anyway, so it was in the theaters around the world to some extent where the other ones weren't.
Scott: It got the big time Hollywood dub in the US.
Scott: Disney got the famous people to dub it, which was a big deal that hadn't been done, I don't think it had been done before at all for any anime that I'm aware of.
Rym: For its minor fault, pretty fantastic.
Scott: Not that no anime had been dubbed before, but none had been famous Hollywood big time dubs.
Rym: Kiki's actually had a pretty for real dub, but not on the level of Mononoke Hime.
Scott: Wasn't that dub made after?
Scott: I'm not sure, I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I forget what year that dub was made, I'm not gonna dig through all the Wikipedia's right now.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know when they did that.
Scott: Regardless, was Kiki in the theaters in the US?
Rym: But that was Mononoke and then Spirited Away, like one after another a few years apart.
Rym: Those were mainstream movies in America, a lot of people saw them, a lot of people found out who Miyazaki was because of them.
Scott: Right, well Mononoke was like, you know, here I am, rest of the world, and it's like, now we know who you are, and then Spirited Away, it's like that guy's back.
Rym: From the person who brought you Princess Mononoke.
Scott: Exactly, and that sort of, it was sort of like a combo, right?
Scott: Mononoke was the jab, and Spirited Away was the big hook that knocked out the rest of the world.
Rym: I think Spirited Away is the best put together movie.
Scott: But certainly the most popular, best selling, most grossing number one of all.
Rym: I think it's the best put together movie he's ever made.
Rym: I think it's the most technically well made, it's got the tightest script, the tightest story.
Rym: Spirited Away is nearly, it might just be a perfect movie.
Scott: I think it's clearly the peak Miyazaki, right?
Scott: Not to say that everything, the things that came after Spirited Away were still excellent in their own right.
Rym: Well I would argue that Wind Rises is more poignant than Spirited Away, but I think Spirited Away is a better movie.
Scott: Right, but if you just take in all, if you consider all factors, I feel like Spirited Away was the peak of the Miyazaki mountain, and since then, I'm not saying it's been downhill into the dumps, right?
Scott: But it has not been as high as it was at that point, right?
Scott: It is lower than it was then.
Rym: Because after that, four years later, we get Ponyo, which was beautiful, and I loved it, but it does not tell much of a story compared to pretty much any Miyazaki movie.
Scott: It's kind of a mess a little bit, it's the cohesion of what's going on here, why, why do we care, right?
Scott: You know, it has a little bit of that Totoro thing going on where it's like, okay, the kid is Ponyo, right?
Scott: Or the kid has the imagination.
Rym: I appreciate that it doesn't explain anything and just lets, like, you're just supposed to just roll with it.
Scott: It explains a little bit, right?
Scott: There's that weird underwater mad science hatter kind of guy going on, you know.
Scott: I'm sure someone out there is mad, like, they know the plot of Ponyo completely.
Scott: I saw it once in the theater and that's it.
Rym: I mean, I'd say I know.
Rym: The movie does the thing that Lapita does where it just shows you some stuff that's in the background, that's the world, and it trusts that you're just gonna understand it enough to engage with the movie.
Rym: What's really familiar is, in Lapita, that was done extremely well.
Rym: In Ponyo, I thought it was done well enough, but a lot of people who saw the movie just did not pick up on those things and were just confused.
Rym: Which is sad, but that's just how movie-watching audiences are.
Scott: Oh, we skipped over Howl's moving cast.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Well, Howl's was all fun, but there was, like, no substance there.
Rym: It didn't really line up with the book.
Scott: For some reason, like, there's a lot of people I know, like, that's their favorite one.
Scott: Like, they love the shit out of it.
Rym: If you didn't read the books this is based on, what the hell?
Rym: What story did it tell?
Scott: Well, it's like, yeah, there's not a lot of context for, like, what's going on, you know, and it's like, I just couldn't, like, bring myself to care about what was happening in Howl's Moving Castle.
Scott: Even though the environment and the characters and everything about it were, you know, basically amazing, I couldn't care because I didn't understand without the context.
Rym: Much like Howl himself, both in the movie and the books, Howl's Moving Castle, the Miyazaki movie, is just a hot mess.
Scott: I wouldn't say a hot mess.
Scott: I've seen much bigger messes, but...
Rym: Well, as in, it is beautiful.
Scott: It's clearly not as...
Rym: It is beautiful, it is fun, it is worth watching, but it's just a goddamn mess of a movie.
Scott: Also, Cowsl for the Talking Fire is, like, my favorite game.
Rym: Yeah, like, I would watch Howl's Moving Castle again, but it doesn't really fully explore any of the themes it raises.
Rym: Like, it raises a lot of interesting ideas and then just drops them.
Rym: And it kind of just peters out toward the end.
Rym: Like, the movie just gets less and less...
Scott: It's a kind of magnifiable, like, you know, flow with a big climax and a, you know, resolution.
Rym: And while Ponyo has similar problems, at least Ponyo sort of gets more and more dreamlike.
Rym: and then there's this moment where you feel like you woke up from a dream.
Rym: Howl's doesn't really have a moment like that.
Rym: Howl's just meanders off into nowhere and then the credits roll.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: And then there's Wind Rises.
Scott: that was Miyazaki going off on his own... Yeah, the Wind Rises... Airplane fanboyism again.
Rym: And I would argue it is Miy- because you know what it's about, right?
Rym: Do you know what this movie is about?
Scott: It's about the dude...
Rym: It is about the dude who basically designed the Zero, like, the fighter that Japanese forces used in World War II.
Rym: And the story is basically this guy made these death machines because he loved the beauty of their mechanism and their design.
Rym: And he willfully turned a blind eye to what they were going to be used for.
Rym: That is what this movie is about.
Rym: He was in love with aviation.
Rym: The only way to express that was by making war machines that killed countless people in one of the worst conflicts in human history.
Rym: And the movie is about the disconnect between the craft and the progress of humanity and the reality of those weapons being used by fascists to murder people.
Rym: And the movie does this in many layers, and I will elaborate in a show at some point.
Rym: And he's got a new one coming!
Rym: How do you live?
Scott: The one that he's trying, you know, he refuses to retire.
Rym: I feel like he's asking this question of himself at this point.
Scott: Well that's the title of the book it's based on.
Scott: So the author, Genzaburo is the author, right?
Rym: Yeah, Yoshino Genzaburo.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Right?
Scott: But yeah, the book is called How Do You Live?
Scott: It's like a famous book that I haven't read.
Scott: But the book is, I think we did a news or a thing of the day or something, when the book became available in English.
Scott: And I put it on my list to read it at some point.
Scott: Maybe it could be a book club book.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Maybe when the movie comes out we'll read it.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I think this is very important.
Scott: Will the movie come out?
Rym: It's the movie about the coming of age of a teenager, but more importantly it was published in 1937.
Rym: And knowing that, and knowing what Miyazaki's previous movie was about, it is easy to see that he's exploring these themes of fascism and its intersection with art and its intersection with life.
Rym: And we'll see what this movie is, but I feel like this is going to be a lot more like The Wind Rises and a lot less like Kiki's Delivery Service.
Scott: Yeah, well we'll see if it comes out.
Scott: And if it does come out and he's still alive, is he going to keep going?
Scott: You know, it's like you feel like he's, you know.
Scott: Right?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I have the book about Miyazaki, the starting point book that I haven't read at all.
Scott: And it's like, it's like he's a cranky old man who smokes a lot.
Scott: You know, it's like wow, but he's still at it somehow.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: And he works too much.
Scott: All he does is draw.
Rym: Well I guess the important takeaway is that regardless of which of his movies you like or don't like or your opinions on any of them in particular, Miyazaki and his works are absolutely unignorable.
Rym: They are deeply important to the history of animation and the history of cinema.
Rym: And I think every one of them is worth watching.
Rym: Without exception.
Scott: Who else, right?
Scott: We've seen like, you could say Disney as a whole, but it's like, alright.
Rym: There are some Disney animated features that are not actually required viewing in the year 2022.
Scott: Oh, there's plenty.
Scott: What I'm saying is like, what individual animation...
Rym: ...animated feature?
Rym: Yeah, there's some sinkers in there.
Scott: If you have taken any person in throughout his history, right, who has directed animated movies, right, and you compare their entire bodies of work up against each other, right?
Scott: It's like Miyazaki's just gonna win by a lot, right?
Scott: It's just an avalanche.
Scott: Like who's even in second place?
Rym: Like Tezuka.
Rym: You're already talking about Tezuka in terms of volume of output.
Scott: What movies, what animated movies did Tezuka direct?
Scott: And how many of them?
Scott: He drew a lot of manga, right?
Scott: Tons of it.
Scott: But it's like, you know, that's quantity, right?
Scott: Not all of them are quality, even though many are the highest quality.
Scott: It's like, just look at directed animated movies.
Scott: It's like there's no one even close.
Rym: Miyazaki's like, it's almost like a Babe Ruth situation, but imagine if there was a Babe Ruth type baseball player who, every three or four years, just suddenly is on the bench on the team, out of nowhere.
Rym: You're like, "Oh, I guess he's
Rym: back."
Rym: And he comes out, and his at-bat is a spectacle, and then he disappears for a few years.
Scott: I think it's like Wayne Gretzky, like he's got numbers that no one else is gonna, no one's breaking, they're just not, it's not happening.
Scott: It's like no one's gonna break the records that they have.
Scott: He's too strong.
Scott: But I think he'll be a legendary artist, right?
Scott: I think if you wait like a century or so, right?
Scott: It's like, I think it's pretty clear that Miyazaki's gonna be like a Van Gogh level of famous, you know, Michelangelo level of, you know, art history, like he'll be in the art history book, right?
Scott: Next to all those people.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Linki G, Dread Lily, Tenebrae, a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names, Kristen Dodd, Chris Farmer, Clinton, Walden, Dex, Finn, Kishaya85, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMedable34, Coward, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horo.
Rym: Stop all the downloading.
Rym: The next station is Downsview Park, Downsview Park Station, and a bunch of people whose names I'm not gonna say.
Rym: Like I said, I am probably going to pause the Patreon during September, just because we'll be skipping so many shows due to all that travel.
Rym: So that'll save those of you whose names I have said at least five bucks.
Rym: And yeah, just enjoying summer.
Rym: Stay safe out there, and I will simply leave you right now with something you should have expected.
Media: Hey, you can break your back.
Media: On the giant slide.
Media: You can even break your neck.
Media: You can even bump your head.
Media: On the giant slide.
Rym: Man, watch your hands and your legs.
Media: It's like jumping off a roof.
Media: On the giant slide.
Media: Man, you can lose a tooth.
Media: It ain't much you can do.
Media: On the giant slide.
Media: What's going on with this new fucking giant slide?
Media: Kids were getting on my nerves, so I sent them to the giant slide.
Media: I told them, "Hold on, baby, it's about to be a giant
Media: slide.".
Media: So when you go down, baby, it's about to be a lot of fun.
Media: Man, I don't know what happened.
Media: All I heard was a lot of crying.
Media: They sent the same giant slide we got on as children.
Media: This new slide looking like they jumping off of a building.
Media: This new slide, you got to take a Tylenol to get on.
Media: If your kids getting on your nerves, make them get on.
Media: They're still getting on your nerves, so you make them get back on.
Media: This new giant slide break necks and back bones.
Media: Then you just lay the kids down soon as you get back on.
Media: Let my kids get on once, and they ain't want to get back on.
Media: Hey, you can break your back.
Media: On the giant slide.
Media: You can even break your neck.
Scott: You can even bump your head.
Media: On the giant slide.
Media: Then watch your hands and your legs.
Media: It's like jumping off a roof.
Media: On the giant slide.
Media: Man, you can lose a tooth.
Media: It ain't much you can do.
Media: On the giant slide.
Media: What's going on with this new fucking giant slide?