Scott:
Rym: It's Thursday, February 17th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about, for the second time, The Tale of Genji.
Rym: I'm sure we might reference it off and on in the future.
Rym: It's part of the lexicon of things I've read that I have thoughts on.
Rym: But if you missed it, you know, The Tale of Genji was the GeekNights book club.
Rym: We talked at length about why it took so long to read it.
Rym: It wasn't just because we were slow.
Rym: There was a lot of other things going on.
Scott: We spent on this one book.
Scott: Now, in the past two months, I've read 1.9 books that aren't The Tale of Genji.
Rym: But we already did an episode talking about the plot, the story, Genji himself, like our reactions to it just as a novel.
Rym: And because that took over an hour and we spent two years in this liminal space of not reading The Tale of Genji, and many of you have read it, at least I hope you have, there are only two people watching this live stream so I can see the relative interest in the second Genji episode compared to other topics.
Scott: But that's fine.
Scott: Yeah, that's fine.
Scott: I'm going to spend two and a half years reading a book.
Rym: You're going to spend two and a half years hearing about it.
Scott: I'm going to spend two podcasts talking about it at least.
Rym: But this episode is a combination of all the things we wanted to say that we couldn't get out because, you know, we talked for over an hour in episode one.
Rym: We were tired and hungry.
Rym: But two, the meta, like the things around the book that aren't just the story itself because we had an hour of just...
Scott: Because if this hadn't been the first novel written a long ass time ago in Japan, and if this, you know, if a book like this was written just a couple hundred years ago, right?
Rym: Kind of trashy romance story.
Scott: And there was some other novel that was the first novel.
Scott: This book would be, you know, not studied by scholars, not remembered, not, you know, significant really.
Rym: Well, the end of the book even mentions other works that are referenced or mentioned in The Tale of Genji that are real close to being novels but don't quite make it.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not sure.
Scott: I tried to research what counts as a novel and basically it just...
Rym: Oh, you want to find a community of people who have different opinions on what that means?
Scott: Sure.
Scott: It's like there isn't actually a complete agreement that this is the first novel, but, you know, I didn't really see any... It's like there was an agreement that I couldn't find people saying that this is definitely the first novel 100%, but I didn't see anyone referring to anything else as a potential first novel, right?
Scott: It's like the only nominee.
Scott: It doesn't get a unanimous vote, but there aren't any other nominees, so that's why it's the first novel.
Rym: Novel.
Rym: A fictitious prose narrative of book length typically...
Scott: Is that what Wikipedia says?
Rym: That's just the dictionary definition from Oxford Languages, it looks like.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: A fictitious prose narrative of book length typically representing character and action with some degree of realism.
Scott: Some degree of...okay.
Rym: Comes from Italian, French, Latin, Latin, Latin, Novus.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But yeah, you know, it's like anything older than this...
Rym: Which means new, a sense of novelty.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So anything older than this is going to be like, you know, not in, you know, a long prose form, like a poem is not a long prose form, right?
Rym: Or it's a long form that involves prose, but comes from a non-written literary tradition.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It could be a spoken tradition or a musical tradition or something, you know, some other sort of, you know, it's like, you know, a movie is not a novel, even though it's a long story about people.
Scott: It's fictional, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Because it's not text, so it's like, you know, a short story is not a novel.
Scott: Why it's too short?
Scott: I don't know what the line is between...because there's some short novels out there, but especially...lines get really blurry because, like, you can have an adult short story, right?
Scott: It's going to be longer than a kid's novel.
Scott: But, you know, whatever.
Scott: So yeah, we're going to talk about meta stuff, right?
Scott: I think we should start, which is when I chose this book, you know, like I knew the book existed, but I didn't really know what it was about.
Scott: I knew it was, like, a big historical deal, and I figured, you know, ah, this is one of those things that's referenced very often.
Rym: Well, like, when we read The Odyssey, or, like, we both read a lot of old works.
Rym: They're very fascinating to read.
Scott: Right, but it's, you know, I'm like, this is an old, significant, often referenced work, so therefore I should become knowledgeable about it so that when it's referenced, I get the reference.
Scott: You know, I have a greater context and understanding of other works, right, even if I don't, you know, whether or not I enjoy this work or not, which I didn't know at the time.
Scott: I keep hearing it come up.
Scott: If I hear anything, basically if I hear anything come up too often, well, there must be something to it, right?
Scott: And then, you know, I think I said this before, there was an exhibit about the book at The Met, right, which I can just take the subway to in a few minutes, and I saw, I woke up one morning on a weekend, and I saw on Twitter, they're like, yeah, last weekend for the exhibit, and I was like, I'm not fucking doing anything.
Scott: Just walk my ass over there, right?
Scott: And at that exhibit, I learned many fascinating things that I will now discuss, right?
Scott: So the first thing is that this book, when it was originally released, was released in separate books.
Scott: It wasn't one giant book like we read.
Scott: It was all.
Scott: these chapters were coming out, you know, chapter by, you know, in smaller sections, which really reminded me of when you go to a Japanese bookstore like Kinokuniya, and you see that the novels come out in, you know, chapter by chapter.
Scott: I think one of our earlier Book Club books was Qteen Eighty-Four, right?
Scott: And, you know, we read Qteen Eighty-Four, you know, by Murakami, author Murakami, not artist Murakami, as one giant book, right?
Scott: But I think if you read Qteen Eighty-Four in Japan, I don't remember exactly how many, was it two or four?
Scott: It was some, you know, number of smaller books that came out one at a time.
Rym: And that's not unique to Japanese literature, like The Count of Monte Cristo was just a serial with like a little chapter revealed like every time.
Scott: Well, that was like in, that was in a larger publication though, right?
Scott: Like you would get like a magazine or something.
Rym: It was basically the Shonen Jump of its time, like hey, here's a bunch of short stories.
Scott: Of its time, I think.
Rym: But, as a result, in its time, very few people read that as one big work.
Rym: They would just read it like, oh yeah, The New Count of Monte Cristo was out in the thing, and I read it.
Rym: But then when we read it as adults, we read it as this giant book that's like a thousand pages long.
Rym: that took me a month to read.
Scott: It was real good.
Scott: So that goes back to what makes a novel.
Scott: See, I had erroneously thought that something that makes a novel a novel is that it's a chapter book, right?
Scott: That there are, you know, because a short story is not going to be, if you have two chapters, you can't be a short story, right?
Scott: That just makes sense.
Scott: So, you know, but if something's got chapters.
Rym: I've read short stories that included a like chapter two.
Scott: Maybe, but I, you know.
Scott: But they were still short, like under 50 pages.
Scott: My erroneous previous conception was that a novel is a novel, you know, one of the characteristics of a novel is chapters, right?
Scott: Well, I guess that doesn't seem to be the case.
Rym: Because the way I've thought about it, and this is not based on any academia, like this is just how I personally interact with novels.
Rym: I think of novels as when you've got a relatively consistent story that progresses over the course of the work, of sufficient length, with an intentional ending of some kind.
Rym: Like that's kind of the broad area of how I've looked at novels in that I've read works older than the Tale of Genji.
Rym: And other than the Odyssey, very few of them had a lot of that intention of like this story starts here and ends here with a consistent cast-ish of characters at a relative progression of the plot.
Rym: And while many epic poems have that and do have an intentional ending, like we know how the Odyssey ends, it has a very, like it wraps everything up very neatly, but because it's an epic poem, I always did treat it differently.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, so, you know, the fact that it came out as these separate books, and actually at the exhibit we saw, like, you know, not the earliest.
Rym: Oh, none of those exist.
Rym: All the originals are lost to time, with no exception.
Scott: Right.
Scott: These weren't originals, like, touched by the author, right?
Scott: But these were, you know, extremely old published editions that, you know, noble people had back hundreds of years ago.
Scott: And it was several, it was like, they had, like, it was like all these books lined up, right?
Scott: Volume one, two, three, four.
Scott: And I could imagine that, like, you know, at the time it was probably like this, you know, this woman would write a volume, right?
Scott: And then I don't know how they would, you know, print it.
Scott: Was it like woodblock or whatever?
Rym: Oh, so it was, it's a specific style that was popular at the time, the Oriholm style, which is a little mini book, but it doesn't open like a normal book.
Rym: It's basically, imagine one long piece of paper that's alternatingly folded like an accordion.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: But yeah, it's like they would produce enough of those, right?
Scott: And then they would get disseminated, probably, you know, by horse, I guess, is the fastest way, right?
Scott: It's like amongst all the other nobles, right?
Scott: And they'd be waiting for the next one the way that people today are waiting for, like, Netflix seasons to drop, right?
Rym: So get this, I'm looking at the Wikipedia about Oriholm because I don't know a lot about this.
Rym: Obviously, if you want to know about the real history of The Tale of Genji, go read an expert's website.
Scott: I'm not going to, you know, I'm trying to avoid doing the thing where we, like, read Wikipedia and then just reiterate it because you can do that yourself, right?
Scott: I'm only going to talk about things that I'm aware of, you know, in my own brain.
Rym: But I was skimming it just to see if there's anything interesting and it points out that this style basically became extremely popular in Japan largely because of The Tale of Genji.
Rym: Like, it is noted as one of the earliest popular uses of it and one of the most popular books to appear in the history of the style was in the 12th century.
Rym: The Tale of Genji got more and more popular.
Scott: So yeah, so something else, right, so basically when I was at this exhibit, that was like one of the first things I noticed, right, was that sort of commonality that we had with these Japanese nobles from centuries ago, right?
Scott: It's like there was a serial work that they were, you know, it's like how much leisure did they have?
Scott: Well, in fact, The Tale of Genji gives us a lot of insight into their leisure.
Rym: Yeah, case in point, ask an average person, what the fuck is Genji's job?
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's like they didn't have any movies or video games.
Scott: It's like they enjoyed life, you know, watching archery competitions, performing theater for each other, playing music with each other.
Scott: They didn't have concerts to go to.
Scott: There wasn't like rock stars.
Scott: They played music, you know, for each other, right?
Scott: You know, because it's not like they trained the peasants how to play music, you know, they played Go and other board games, you know, and they wrote poetry and had poetry competitions and art competitions.
Scott: And, you know, these were the sorts of things they did for leisure, including reading The Tale of Genji and then talking about it.
Scott: And it was interesting to see at the exhibit because I not only did I see that, but so many of the things were other examples of things that we had in common with, you know, us of today.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Who?
Scott: we don't consider ourselves to be nobles, but I guess relatively we are.
Rym: Oh, absolutely.
Rym: As we on our own dime, for the most part, are making a podcast for whoever happens to listen to it because we think it's fun.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it's like how much we had in common with them, not only following serial artworks.
Scott: But I also saw there is like the poetry competitions.
Scott: It's like all throughout Genji.
Scott: People are communicating to each other with poetry in the poetry.
Scott: They're dropping references to things.
Scott: How often do we just like insert Simpsons references into whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if someone if I wrote some book with a Simpsons reference, like two knives.
Scott: And someone republishes that in five, six hundred years.
Rym: They'll be a footnote.
Scott: This is they got to put a footnote on that.
Scott: Two knives.
Rym: This is a reference to most his lack from a lost animated series we believe was called The Simpsons.
Scott: Hopefully they have a cyberspace.
Scott: They could just insert the clip of Mo going two knives.
Scott: But you know, you get the idea.
Scott: The same thing.
Scott: They're constantly dropping references to Chinese poetry and shit in The Tale of Genji.
Rym: Well, to the point, there's one chapter that I even it's one chapter I actually kind of glossed over because the chapter was like dense and I didn't really understand what was going on.
Rym: We got to the end of it.
Rym: I went back and looked at the footnotes.
Rym: It was very clear that chapter was like unique among all the chapters of The Tale of Genji and that it was almost nothing but references to popular Chinese literature that readers of The Tale of Genji in its context and time would have recognized.
Rym: So that is like us stumbling into like a bunch of people are really into, I don't know, Twilight fandom.
Rym: And we have no idea what the fuck they're talking about.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the other.
Scott: so it goes even further.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So this poetry nonsense, I got the feeling that it was a lot like today where you see like a sports anime come out and that sport gets popular.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Scott: Chicken and egg.
Scott: What came first?
Scott: But there were a lot of things that that exhibit about poetry competitions and people flinging poetry at each other.
Scott: And it was clear that like that's something that they were doing.
Scott: And I don't know if it was, you know, The Tale of Genji like got people interested in flinging poetry at each other or they already were.
Scott: And it sort of made it more popular or, you know, right.
Rym: Well, there's contemporary like current things that have like we've seen this happen where something is depicted in media.
Rym: People get interested in it.
Rym: Even though it was a thing, it becomes more popularized and more people make it a thing or start doing it.
Rym: And it's like hackers did some of that with like hacking culture.
Rym: But War Game really did that because that movie war dialing was extremely unknown and not common.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I want to even say that war dialing was not a agreed upon term before that movie.
Rym: But after that movie, a million kids, including me, like got really into hacking and learned about it because of the movie.
Rym: But then that fed into this mythos around hacking to where people didn't realize how popular that movie made it specifically.
Rym: yet watched that movie and thought, oh, yeah, this is describing the hobby that I'm into.
Rym: Like it's a it's definitely a feedback loop.
Rym: And we've seen this time and time again.
Scott: Now, this sort of becomes obvious once I mention it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And this is this is the real.
Scott: this is the bomb.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's sort of common sense.
Scott: But you go I was at the Met.
Scott: It's an.
Scott: it's an art museum.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But they had an exhibit about a book.
Scott: So what are they going to show there?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's not paintings.
Scott: It's not sculptures.
Scott: It's not right.
Scott: It's just a book.
Scott: So this is like what was in the exhibit volumes of books and then like text on the walls explaining it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, no, the exhibit, the vast majority of it was fucking fan art.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It was ancient people hundreds of years ago doing Genji fan art.
Scott: They had screens that had Genji scenes painted on them.
Scott: They had like these people read this fucking thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they had all their artists make them Genji musical instruments, Genji, all Genji, any Genji fans, like anything that you could put art on.
Scott: Genji scrolls, you know, Genji inkstone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like these.
Scott: get, you know, Genji is basically Genji merch.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It was like, you know, like the artist's alley of Genji merch, like, hey, check out this painting I made about Genji.
Scott: When Genji painted on the bamboo screen, like they had Genji T-shirts, there were Genji kimonos with like scenes of Genji in the in the fabric.
Rym: It was all, you know, the pick up artists of the late Heian era were like trying to be Genji and were like writing poems and like writing them on a little fan and like trying to emulate what they read in that work.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The kids today with and there was also fanfics too.
Scott: There was Genji fanfics too.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like there's even debate about some of the later chapters might have been collaborations or written by someone else.
Scott: Like there was every all this shit that people are doing today.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That different.
Rym: Look at Roman graffiti or look at OK.
Rym: Like, OK, the word OK.
Rym: Do you know the origin of that word?
Rym: It's a meme from hundreds from a couple hundred years ago where people would make acronyms that were incorrect and spelled wrong because they thought it was funny.
Rym: OK stands for all correct, spelled wrong with a K. And it was a meme from like the eighteen hundreds.
Scott: I don't know if that's right or wrong, but OK.
Rym: There was.
Rym: I watched a documentary on this not that long ago, so it was fresh in my mind.
Rym: But is it OK?
Rym: Memes like memes and pop culture references and like the idle leisure's of people who have the privilege to take idle leisure's.
Rym: Not much has changed.
Rym: And these old works only feel inaccessible because of the distance from that culture in the same way that even contemporary cultures are very inaccessible to people who don't know about the shibboleths and the details in the context of those cultures.
Rym: And that stood out very profoundly in the tale of Genji, because it's the first work I've read in a long time that is from a culture I know very little about.
Scott: I don't know much.
Scott: I didn't know basically anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, my knowledge of, you know, what Japan was like, you know, hundreds of years ago is basically limited.
Scott: You know, a very self-aware of this is basically viewed through the lens of fictional works like samurai movies, which obviously are no less than 100 years old.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And like those movies are set in different eras of Japan from the Heian era that this is set in.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And that was even if there's any accuracy to them, you know, because it's sort of like.
Scott: if someone wanted to get, you know, the history of like, you know, 20th century, you know, the US and was watching The Godfather.
Scott: It's like, you know, how accurate is this?
Scott: It's like that's what watching, you know, let me watch Seven Samurai.
Scott: It's like, OK, well, yeah.
Scott: But it was also Father was sort of somewhat at least closer to the time it was made closer to the time in which the events it portrays would have taken place.
Scott: Whereas samurai movies were made hundreds of years after.
Scott: Well, maybe not necessarily hundreds, depending on which era of Japan they were making the movie about.
Scott: But quite many more decades between the movie and the of the events, the fictional events would have taken place.
Rym: But what is interesting is that it feels like the tale of Genji feels very true to many of the broad cultural strokes of that era, even though the specific events in this book are clearly fictionalized and exaggerated.
Scott: Because this book, unlike Godfather, right?
Scott: Seven Samurai, this book was made at the in the era of which it is portraying.
Scott: Like if I wrote a book today about the 21st century.
Rym: What if I wrote a book about like being a podcaster during this era?
Rym: Like I work in a tech company.
Rym: I got some money.
Rym: This is how I spend my day.
Rym: There's a bunch of chapters about Overwatch because I play it all the time.
Scott: Also, right, is that we know we don't know their real name, but we know that the author was the daughter of like some regional governor.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, not like a not like, you know, hanging out with the emperor, but like, you know, a noble person, not a, you know, a peasant, right?
Scott: Someone who obviously was literate, had access to paper and ink and, you know, all kinds of things.
Scott: And this not only tells you about the time, but also about the perspective of a person in that position at that time.
Scott: You know, you're seeing, you know, the world through that person's eyes.
Scott: They can only write what they know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I talked about how, you know, that's I think my guess as to the reason why you don't see a lot of things written about, like what was going on with, you know, wars or politics or peasants or commerce.
Scott: Because this person who wrote that wasn't engaging in those things and they didn't know about them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They were hanging out, playing music, writing poetry, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: So, you know, having a romance.
Scott: So that's what they wrote about.
Rym: But also they wrote in a way which may be a reflection of the reality of the time, maybe a romanization of the reality of the time, or may have been a pointed avoidance of difficult topics.
Rym: But this was published contemporarily.
Rym: Like it wasn't like this was an insider account.
Scott: Yeah, they wrote it and then nobles read it.
Scott: So they couldn't upset...
Rym: See also, like Shakespeare.
Rym: Shakespeare couldn't just be like, "Yes, this king in particular, fuck
Rym: him.".
Scott: Yeah, Shakespeare didn't go to the Globe Theater and be like, "Fuck the current king who's paying for
Scott: this.".
Rym: So he wrote a lot of stories like, "Oh yeah, that past king was no good because he's not in favor with the current
Rym: royalty.".
Rym: So it's hard for me, as someone who doesn't know much about Hay and Erra, to know how much of this might have been her avoiding these topics.
Rym: But it seems like a lot of this writing was during a relatively stable and peaceful era of the Hay court.
Scott: Except as the story goes on, it seems like, you know, and I noticed this pattern in lots and lots of fictional works of the greatest, you know, most prosperous, wonderful times.
Scott: I guess there's people who feel this way too, right?
Scott: Are always the oldest times.
Scott: And in this book, it's actually interesting in that the prosperous times are actually the beginning of the book.
Rym: It's the current times right up until Genji gets a little older and then it's the evil times where the government is getting more austere and there's political troubles that are never described specifically at any point.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But something like Lord of the Rings, it's like things used to be fucking crazy good and then you're reading, but the story takes place in the third era or whatever, right?
Scott: Or things are not as awesome.
Scott: It's like, you know, King Arthur, it's like, okay, I guess King Arthur does get to the good times, but then the not so good, right?
Scott: There's always, it's always a downslope.
Scott: I very rarely read, I'm sure they exist.
Rym: Culture.
Rym: Every day forward in the future.
Rym: Star Wars.
Rym: Old Republic.
Scott: Whoa, it's awesome.
Scott: And then Star Wars, you know, down.
Scott: It's just a downward slope.
Scott: There's no, it doesn't go, it doesn't get great.
Rym: Of course, arguably the later movies point out that the Old Republic sucked and had deep problems.
Scott: Well, in some ways it sucked, but in some ways not.
Rym: Well, look at the culture books.
Rym: Literally every year that goes by, everything is better.
Scott: Well, culture, I guess would be the exception.
Rym: And the old times are terrible.
Scott: I guess, yeah, culture is the backwards one.
Rym: A lot of optimistic sci-fi is like that.
Rym: It's always like we've come out of a dark age and we're entering an enlightened age.
Rym: But it's very telling that the Tale of Genji, and that's where I don't know how much of that was a reaction to maybe shifts in the author's life or things the author noticed.
Rym: How much of it might have been just them just getting, them just getting old.
Scott: because as people get old, right, you know, we see people just in our lives, you know, which are half over, right?
Scott: Like conservative people are always like, ah, the old days, right?
Scott: You know, the old days.
Rym: I look at Counter-Strike 1.6 and I think, thank Satan, there is Counter-Strike Go.
Scott: But I think there is a general, you know, wrong feeling of, ah, the great old, the good old days, right, amongst people, you know, all over the place.
Scott: It's not, you know, some one culture that feels that way.
Rym: But another way to look at this, because I don't want to remove literary agency from the author because the story, everything feels great when Genji's young and doesn't have any responsibilities or problems or consequences, but then the story gets more melancholy and complex as Genji is an adult and has to deal with complications.
Rym: So that also, it fits the story of Genji growing up and seeing the world from increasingly broader perspectives.
Scott: So even if the world stays the same, right, getting older kind of sucks in so many ways.
Rym: I just turned 40 and I got to tell you, 40 ain't 30 and 30 ain't 20 in terms of certain physical parts of my body.
Rym: Look at you, left knee.
Rym: You betrayed me for the last time.
Scott: Especially people didn't live that long in this era.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I mean, look at these emperors like, oh, no, he's 40.
Rym: Yeah, he's going to die any day.
Rym: Good Lord.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, they didn't have medical science that we had, you know.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But in terms of that meta too, it's interesting to see how radically differently, at least the translation we read, the book is structured differently as it goes on.
Rym: Chapters are written differently and that's something we pointedly avoided talking about in the first half of the show.
Rym: Pick any random chapter from After Genji Dies and it is just absolutely, I skimmed through one again before the show just to make sure I wasn't just, you know, those are the ones I read most recently.
Rym: No, it's like night and day.
Rym: The later chapters to a modern audience are just easier to read.
Rym: Full stop.
Scott: They have structure.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: They tell you more about what's happening.
Rym: A section will end and the next section just like either picks up where the last one left off or explains the setting change.
Rym: Like now we're in this other place and here's what this person's up to.
Rym: The first chapters were just like you'd have two characters talking and then suddenly two different characters are talking and you're not sure if they're in the same place or not and sometimes they aren't.
Scott: I highlighted a part.
Scott: I looked through my Kindle for just the few parts that I highlighted when I was reading and there's literally a sentence in one of the middle chapters that's like, "Ah, yeah, you know, and the years went on such and
Scott: such.".
Scott: And it was just one sentence at the beginning of a paragraph and there's a footnote attached to that sentence and the footnote says, "This sentence covers a period of four
Scott: years.".
Scott: And also I think I did mention there's like a paragraph where it's like, "Oh, yeah, an emperor died.
Scott: Another emperor took over and someone else
Scott: died.".
Scott: And it was like that was in the middle of a paragraph.
Rym: Yeah, I'm back in like, "Wait, which emperor?
Rym: The current emperor?
Rym: Who's that emperor
Rym: now?".
Scott: Right.
Scott: But meanwhile, when Murasaki, the author's character dies, that's a whole fucking chapter.
Scott: It's all these different, you know, the time scales just keep getting out of whack.
Scott: But after Genji dies, the rest of the book has sort of a steady pace of things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like this happened and this happened and this happened.
Scott: It's not just an artifact of the translator doing something different for those chapters.
Scott: It's like this.
Scott: They really are.
Rym: There is just there is more context as to where and there's fewer.
Scott: there's fewer characters.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's less moving all over the place.
Scott: Things are happening always in chronological order.
Scott: You don't have the overlapping stuff going on anymore.
Rym: The characters are a little simpler to like the characters.
Scott: The characters aren't changing their roles too much.
Scott: You always know who's who.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: They're acting in character.
Scott: They have these, you know, it's only dealing with one plot.
Scott: So it's like you can follow, you know, the characters pretty much have the same motivations and goals throughout the rest of the book.
Rym: But like it really feels like the early chapters are very disconnected from each other in that they're almost like, let's have a story where Genji has this kind of affair.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Let's have this kind of affair.
Rym: And consequences are not like tied together or like they don't progress anything other than Genji's development.
Rym: And they're very standalone.
Rym: But also it almost reads like a, well, that's just what would have happened, which is a thing that a lot of in modern sensibilities like contemporary today, that's often the sign of a less apt writer like a George R.R.
Rym: Martin.
Rym: Like, I'm just going to.
Rym: Well, yeah, that wasn't a good story.
Rym: What just happened there?
Rym: But that's logically what would happen.
Rym: That's what that character would have done.
Scott: I don't see the author as a not good author.
Scott: I see the author as it's like if you just watch old Olympics and it's like you watch the high jump gold medalist.
Scott: And it's like that was the highest jumper in the world at the time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's they couldn't jump very high compared to how we jump today.
Scott: That's because it was 100 years ago.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They couldn't jump that high.
Scott: Then they didn't know how.
Rym: Watch a sitcom.
Scott: Athletic training and all the things that we have.
Rym: Watch a sitcom like one episode.
Scott: This person didn't have Shakespeare to read.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Shakespeare had other things to learn from, you know, and then other people had Shakespeare to learn from.
Scott: But, you know, Murasaki, Shakiba, what did they have?
Scott: Right.
Scott: They had Chinese literature, the poems that.
Scott: It's like there wasn't like a whole bookstore full of novels that this this woman could read to learn to be a better writer from.
Rym: But look at the craft.
Rym: Like the craft of media has changed so much because right now I'm watching a bunch of Star Trek.
Rym: So I'm watching old Star Trek and new Star Trek.
Rym: And it's very stark to look at TV shows from the 70s, 80s, 90s and like how they were constructed.
Rym: They feel very poorly put together.
Rym: The scripts don't feel that good.
Rym: There's a lot of downtime and sort of dead ends and just the craft wasn't there yet.
Rym: And the craft has evolved.
Rym: Modern entertainment a couple decades later is denser.
Rym: The stories are tighter.
Rym: They're more focused.
Rym: Like audiences change.
Rym: But also the craft advances.
Scott: So not but not only does it advance over a long period of multiple people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you could see even with if you just forget the the later the post Genji's death chapters.
Scott: You can see it advance within those.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The same way when you look at something like a webcomic and you see the oldest strips are like are way better to say.
Rym: I just looked at a penny arcade from twenty two years ago when Gabe proposed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you can see the artist improving their art just because they're doing it right.
Scott: The author of The Tale of Genji gets better at writing as the book.
Scott: the chapters go.
Rym: Absolutely not.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: I thought, you know, it was hard to tell because I was like, am I just getting better at reading this book?
Rym: Right.
Rym: Early chapter.
Rym: I still don't know what happened sometimes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like that is a part of it.
Scott: You do get better at reading it, you know, as you go on and push through.
Scott: But no, the early chapters are written way worse, way harder to follow.
Scott: You know that, you know, it can't just be the translator getting better at translating because they clearly edited and went through how many times.
Scott: They spent their whole life studying the book.
Scott: I don't feel like they put more effort into translating the later chapters than the earlier ones.
Rym: But like around when Genji gets exiled and then comes back and like that second the second phase, I guess, of the very hard to follow what's going on around there.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But right after that, it just gets easier and easier to follow.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But those ones, the third set of chapters, what struck me the most about the third part, like after Genji's death, is that the characters felt faker, but were easier to understand.
Rym: And their relationships felt very planned in advance in a way that it didn't feel to the reader, to me at least, in the early chapters that there was a plan for exactly how this was going to go down.
Rym: Like she was writing this almost chapter by chapter, but the later chapters feel like this was designed to wrap itself up in a particular way.
Rym: This character is going to be here to serve this purpose in the plot as opposed to this is a character that would make sense to be there based on what I'm writing about.
Rym: I don't know if that was her motivation, but that stood out to me as a reader.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, I mean, there's a lot of debates about, you know, who wrote what and, you know, because we don't know for sure any of these sorts of things.
Rym: This is from the like the twelve hundreds.
Rym: Like this is a long time ago.
Scott: But my personal head, head cannon.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is that, you know, she started writing this thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, just like for fun, like here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, wrote like a chapter or two about this awesome dude, Genji.
Rym: Hey, you want to read about the hottest goddamn person to ever be born?
Rym: Well, I got a story for you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So wrote like a chapter or two and then people were into it.
Scott: And it's like, oh, I got nothing else to do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I love doing this.
Scott: I'll keep doing it.
Scott: You know, and then there was demand for it now.
Scott: So there's like pressure to like deliver on this.
Rym: Imagine even if it was just the court at first, like, like we start way back there doing gig nights.
Rym: Then some people like, hey, I actually like gig nights.
Rym: Someone who isn't our friend contacted us once like, oh, someone's listening.
Rym: And so imagine now the author is like, well, I'm going to start like planning a little more or writing more or thinking about what would my audience want to see?
Rym: I know I'll have him sleep with the wrong person.
Rym: That'll be great.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, you know, you know, and then as over time they got better at writing, you know, maybe, you know, perhaps there were some parts where like they were reluctant to go on, but they went on instead.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Who knows what was going on in their lives.
Scott: You know, a lot of the things I could, you know, I could imagine a lot of the things I see in the book happening to the author, you know, illnesses or having to move or, you know, who knows what, right.
Scott: All kinds of dramas, you know, incorporating those.
Scott: probably.
Scott: maybe, you know, there could be things in here that we don't even know.
Scott: Like, you know, maybe some of the, you know, uh, there could be some like, uh, you know, like chapters that are basically distracts against real people that they knew.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like the same way that like art musicians will sing songs about their ex.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There could be some of that shit in here and you just don't even realize it that it's going on.
Rym: Um, you know, there were a bunch of moments where I would feel like that was true, but I did couldn't articulate it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, you know, like the right, you know, they have a character who's like, you know, portrayed negatively.
Scott: and it's like, is that character someone they knew and they're portraying them in here.
Rym: Like especially Genji's wife in particular, it felt like, did you know someone who you really didn't like in the card?
Scott: Like, yep.
Scott: Or you, you, you saw a story happen.
Scott: So you write the story, you know, you, you know, you take a rumor you heard and write it down with other characters.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: Um, but that, you know, so as for the chapters that come after Genji's death, right.
Scott: You know, it's not like the previous chapters, you see a gradual improvement.
Scott: It's this sudden jump into a different mode of writing.
Scott: So obviously other, you know, people have all kinds of explanations.
Scott: It could be a different author, uh, in which case it's like a fan fiction addendum.
Scott: Uh, it could be, you know, you know, Oh, she stopped writing Genji, but we must, we must have more Genji and the emperor told someone to write more.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, you know, it could, you could imagine so many possible explanations.
Scott: Maybe there was a, they got tired of Genji and they said, that's enough of that.
Scott: And then, you know, they were still alive and they were pressured to write more, but they were so much better at writing by that time that they were able to, but they didn't have enough new ideas.
Scott: And then therefore they produced, uh, you know, those, those ending chapters and then they passed away.
Scott: And that's why it ends sort of.
Rym: I did skim her biography.
Rym: Uh, I'm not going to like relate everything because, you know, go read it yourself or read the Wikipedia page.
Rym: But one thing that was very clear is it's it, most people agree that she published it herself with her own ladies in waiting to a small audience, almost like a zine at first.
Rym: And it got popular and eventually patrons started to like fund it and it grew from there.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Which that's how, that's, that's how webcomics happened today.
Rym: Like almost directly, like someone makes a webcomic, cost of money, 1200 something.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But, uh, let's see what other meta can I think of around the tale of Genji that we didn't talk about in the first episode to avoid talking about Genji and the characters again.
Rym: But the thing that was just thrown out the most was how much easier those later chapters were to read and how tighter they felt.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I guess we got, you know, I guess we can talk about, you know, I don't know too much about right.
Scott: What, what it was like, you know, the history of what was going on in that era.
Rym: That my knowledge of Heian era is that it was a deeply dysfunctional and extremely divided Japanese society where the nobles really didn't interact with normal people at all.
Scott: And I, I mean, that's what it seems like in the book.
Scott: and the other, I think the number one thing that just like stood out the most in the book was, you know, how, uh, women were so like cloistered and secluded.
Scott: And like, you know, we talk about objectification of women in today's society, right?
Scott: It's like, it's like literally.
Scott: it's like you own some women, right?
Scott: It's like there wasn't any woman that didn't belong to somebody.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Well, when there's a woman living on her own, it was always, it happens a few times in the tale of Genji.
Rym: It's always a like, yeah, who's paying her bills?
Rym: Like what's going on?
Rym: They're living in this decrepit house somewhere cause there's no man around.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Who's, who's take, you know, I need to make sure all my daughters are taking, you know, belong to someone.
Scott: I'm going to die.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Someone's I had to make sure that each one has some man to take care of them.
Scott: Uh, and like, you know, you can't let anyone, like you talk about modesty, like, you know, Victorian or whatever, right?
Scott: Like can't show any ankles and whatnot.
Scott: This is like, you cannot let anyone see you unless like they're your like father, uh, maybe not even your brother, you know, unless you're a child.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, once you're, you know, I guess the donning of the train maybe is that comes up a few times in the book.
Scott: I assume that some sort of adult coming ceremony.
Scott: I didn't research it.
Scott: Uh, but it's like, yeah, it's like, once you're an adult woman, it's like, nobody sees you except your staff.
Scott: You know, you're like your parents, right?
Scott: Uh, your children, uh, you know, your spouse.
Scott: It's like you are, you are hidden behind walls.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, and that really struck me because even if you watch, you know, all sorts of, you know, samurai movies and stuff, right.
Scott: It's like, yeah, the women aren't, you know, they're hidden and protected, but not that level of right.
Scott: You know, it's like, you'll still see scenes or like someone's bowing before, you know, the empress who's sitting there getting mad or something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, whereas here it's like in this time, clearly the empress would be behind some wall and you wouldn't even know.
Rym: It's like, you only know that they're there because you know, but what I do find interesting is these, this book portrays the rich inner lives of what is happening behind those walls.
Rym: And it shows like the interactions that actually happen.
Rym: Like there's a, you know, the men have, they're, they're all hanging out together in the early part of the tale again, but you always see the echoes of the women behind that screen are all hanging out together and doing their own thing.
Rym: And it's interesting to see that portrayed so directly.
Rym: So the other thing is I know about the Han era just personally, and again, I'm probably radically overgeneralizing is that that government was extremely incompetent and got more and more incompetent and incapable of running the country as time went on.
Rym: That's, that's a common trope.
Rym: I've seen like currency started to fall apart, like banking institutions collapsed.
Rym: Rice became the primary unit of exchange.
Rym: Uh, I pulled up the Wikipedia.
Rym: Oh God.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Right here.
Rym: The money circulation fell apart.
Rym: Rice became literally the primary unit of exchange.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Get the reason they were giving gifts to each other so much, largely because there wasn't any other way to transfer value and transfer wealth.
Scott: So in the book, yeah, throughout the book, they were constantly gifting things to each other.
Rym: When Genji goes into exile, like he's wealthy and he stops at a bunch of his storehouses, his wealth is big warehouses he owns filled with his shit.
Rym: And he goes and like gets stuff from those warehouses to bring with him, to give to people as gifts, to pay them basically.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Every, everywhere they go, they're constantly gifting, right?
Scott: You know, here have some, you know, there's a ceremony.
Scott: Ah, they gave everyone gifts and whoever danced the best got the best gift.
Scott: You know, it's like, yeah.
Rym: But that was partly because there really wasn't a currency to trade.
Rym: You couldn't give someone a tip.
Scott: I guess, uh, there's also, the book also talks a lot about th you know, these really small details, you know, you know, I guess in, in modern times you talk about it, like appreciating this, the little things in life.
Scott: Um, but there's a lot of text in this book dedicated to going through extreme detail about the little things in life, right?
Scott: Like they're constantly perfuming things themselves, papers, right?
Scott: Cause it's just like, there isn't that much sensory entertainment.
Scott: There's no VR, right?
Scott: So it's like perfuming things, you know, looking at flowers.
Rym: They talk a lot about, oh shit, that's the good colored paper.
Rym: Oh, God damn.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they go to look at flowers the way that you would go to Disney world.
Scott: You know, it's like all this kind of stuff, right?
Scott: These things that we would consider like simple pleasures are like big pleasures.
Rym: So I found a historical statistic that really puts this into light.
Rym: The aristocracy, the people portrayed in the tale of Genji are referred to contemporarily by a Japanese word that basically means the good people.
Rym: And there were about 5,000 of them total in a nation of around five to 6 million.
Rym: And so 5,000 extremely wealthy people playing games and singing and living in this closed existence and five or 6 million people living in desperate poverty around them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The book pretty much never talks about the people living in the poverty.
Rym: Remember way back I kept talking about that one scene with normal dialogue?
Rym: That never happens again in the book.
Rym: You never have a normal person say words other than that one scene in like chapter five.
Scott: And it even seems like, you know, it's like, okay, you've got like, you know, the empress.
Scott: and the empress has, you know, women around her, but those women don't seem like they're peasants, right?
Scott: Those women are like, ah, yes, some merchant's daughter was sent to the palace to, you know, to, right.
Scott: It's like, you know, they're, and they're like sent, you know, they're sending each other's.
Scott: like, you know, some of their children who end up not being, you know, so high ranking are sent to work for someone.
Scott: It's like, you know, those are still like noble people.
Scott: They're just lower ranked noble people.
Scott: Like the actual peasant people, like planting rice, you know, doing actual hard labor.
Scott: People are like not even present.
Rym: All I can think of is there's a song in Centra World.
Rym: Please, sir, tell me where food comes from.
Rym: Like that song.
Rym: But the other thing that I see just skimming this around that era that was, that came up a lot in the Tale of Genji, they talk a lot about how difficult and dangerous travel is.
Rym: Like, your fence being broken is a big deal.
Rym: Like if your fence is not able to be sealed, they basically let the police forces completely collapse.
Rym: And there were just robbers and brigands anywhere outside of the walled cities and outside of the walled estates.
Scott: And they're always traveling like in a, in like a wagon, like basically a thing with two wheels that someone's pulling.
Rym: Usually with a big entourage and armed guards and like heralds.
Scott: It's basically, it's similar to Oregon Trail.
Scott: only humans are pulling instead of oxen.
Scott: Or, you know, like a, you know, a, you know, what's the call where you just people just pick you pick you right the fuck up, right?
Scott: But I forget what those are called, Polonkin, whatever.
Rym: Or Palquins?
Scott: Yeah, it's something like that, right?
Scott: People just pick you up and carry you through the street.
Scott: But yeah, they always travel, right?
Scott: Like with people, right?
Scott: No one's just going and walking around.
Rym: Well, the book, it's very clear because a few times Genji goes off by himself or mostly by himself in disguise.
Scott: When he goes mostly by himself, he's like only with his trusted like five dudes.
Rym: Yeah, that's what I was about to get at.
Rym: Genji going off like surreptitiously is still this giant like entourage.
Rym: They're just wearing what I imagine are flimsy disguises and nobody's fooled.
Scott: Well, I think it's more like if he's only traveling with five or ten dudes, he must be a lower ranked.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, you're trying, you're like almost the emperor, right?
Scott: You're pretty close, right?
Scott: The emperor would come out with like a fucking army, right?
Rym: It's like a Monty Python.
Rym: How do you know he's a king?
Rym: He hasn't got shit all over him.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: But, you know, so it's like, okay, well, normally when you come out, you come out with a hundred dudes.
Scott: So you come out with five dudes and that's your disguise as a lower ranked person who's, you know, so that maybe people, you know, you still got guards, but you wouldn't go out by yourself because people would be like, hey, there's someone who hasn't got shit all over him all by themselves.
Scott: Let's fucking rob him.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And it's telling because, you know, there's like, then she sneaks away with that girl early on and they just go to an event.
Rym: There's a lot of abandoned structures and abandoned estates all over the place.
Rym: Like you feel that in the books.
Scott: And well, some of them is like become abandoned.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you can see that like in the story, it's like, ah, a family was here and then a dude died or a dude moved or someone got married.
Scott: And just the way that the families and the hierarchy is structured and shifts, it's like, you know, the, the great, you know, even, you know, the, the Roku Joe, right.
Scott: Genji's house on the sixth street, right.
Scott: The Roku, um, you know, which is like the, the big, like central location of the majority of the book where most of the action is.
Scott: It's like, it had its Heyday when Genji was there with all his wives and then, you know, people are still there, but after Genji dies, you know, you can, you can tell, even though it doesn't come up in the story very much at that place, like declines, you know, cause there's not really, you know, there's no Genji, no great person living there anymore.
Scott: There's like the remnants of Genji's family living there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And as they move out or marry other people or die, it's like that place goes downhill.
Scott: And if it's not up kept, then, you know, and there's not a lot of staff working there that who the hell wants to live there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You would, you would need to wait for it to be like completely empty and then for someone to need a new house to go in there and take it and refreshing it is someone with a lot of power and money and whatnot.
Rym: Um, and that's kind of how the hand era eventually ended is that the nobility was so rich and so disconnected that basically the, what little military they're maintained, like people like Genji who ostensibly was a captain to the guard or whatever at one point.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: A lot of the people have military titles, you know, the, the, the, the, you know, the whatever of war, right?
Scott: All these people, but it was an era of mostly, you never see any, the only military stuff you see will be like for entertainment, like boat archery competitions or horse riding.
Rym: So basically later on, like post when the tale of Genji was set, the people who were actually doing the military work kind of just took over because no one could stop them.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: But it's interesting to read this from the perspective of we're seeing like this narrow glimpse into and some by some arguments, the height of hand culture, like the most peaceful era right before it collapsed.
Rym: Like it didn't last that much longer after the era that was portrayed, but at the same time, we're seeing the height only from the perspective of the people who were living the, the best wealthiest lives within what was otherwise an extremely broken society.
Rym: Very similar to many times throughout history, including our own time right now.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you know, it's like, even though these people were like, you know, the extremely wealthy 1%, you know, there's at least in the book, there's no depiction of them doing like incredibly cruel things.
Rym: No, they're just doing nothing.
Rym: Like the outside world just doesn't exist.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they're living a life of leisure.
Scott: And, you know, enjoying wondrous arts.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, some of them are very religious.
Scott: You know, and they actually give up worldly things.
Rym: You know, and that was the theme in hand era too, especially as Buddhism started to become popular among the nobles, then you'd see a lot of that.
Rym: There were a bunch of emperors who were like, fuck it.
Rym: I'm a monk now.
Rym: You're on your own.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: Have fun.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: A lot of women want to become, you know, nuns.
Rym: Well, you saw that in Europe.
Rym: A lot of women, if you look at like different parts of European society and different eras in the medieval times.
Rym: I can live this horrible life and marry that shit bag.
Rym: Or I can go join a nunnery and escape all that.
Rym: A lot of people would choose the nunnery.
Rym: I mean, even Genji's grooms of life.
Scott: If it wasn't for the religion part, you know, being like even a Christian monk, right?
Scott: It's like, that's kind of, you know, it's kind of cool except for the Christian part.
Rym: Well, it's also a way to escape the like the actual violent reality of the society outside of that institution.
Scott: I think that's what's appealing.
Scott: If I think about becoming, you know, some sort of religious monk.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like the religious part isn't the appealing part.
Scott: The escape capitalism is the appealing part.
Scott: It's like it's like a. it's like the one way to escape capitalism is to win at it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You have so much money.
Scott: You don't have to do anything anymore.
Scott: But another way is like, yeah, there's some organization like a church or whatever, you know, or even though you're living an ascetic life of some kind, you know, it's still a life.
Scott: It's not, you know, it's not the worst.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not like homeless, you know, absolute destitution.
Scott: And, you know, you're if you can enjoy the smaller things in life, you know, like, you know, nice smells and tasty foods and whatnot, you know, like Belgian monks making delicious beers, which I don't even like.
Scott: Stuff like that.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: that can be a fulfilling life, you know, and if you have the opportunity to do it, then it could be a good choice, even if you're an extremely wealthy emperor.
Scott: That could be an appealing choice.
Scott: Get away from all this fucking drama in this palace.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like or avoid getting married off to some just random rags at some dude you hate is going to treat you like property.
Scott: You know, but if you're I guess if you're a peasant, you probably don't even have the opportunity to go become a monk.
Scott: You know.
Rym: Well, even though when he's living in exile, there's that family and they're like, oh, we got a bandit.
Rym: We got to hook our daughter up with Genji because this is like the richest person who's ever going to come to this town again.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Is there anything else to say about this book?
Scott: I guess we're never going to have to talk about it again on this show.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: I I'm glad we read it.
Rym: Like, I enjoyed reading it.
Scott: I did.
Scott: You know, it's not like my favorite book.
Scott: But and I, I guess I was disappointed in that there's not actually I don't have an encounter as many references to it as I expected in other words.
Rym: It's good to know about it, though, like not not every nice book club book is going to be like a bad a thousand hit with us.
Scott: This was I did learn a lot.
Scott: I did learn a lot of things.
Rym: You know, I got interested.
Rym: I got more to actually got interested enough in hay in history to start reading like high level like this.
Rym: It's an era I'd like to know more about, but I'm not going to become an expert on it.
Rym: But I want to.
Rym: I would have a working knowledge of that era, which I did not have in any capacity before I read this book.
Rym: And I'm close to having like a very broad strokes like I would have about Europe during that time knowledge.
Scott: But, you know, my secondary reason, right, my primary reason of trying to, you know, get more literary references between things.
Scott: I didn't really pan out so much.
Scott: But my secondary reason of drawing parallels between, you know, the people of today and the people of then in terms of media culture and also, you know, the form of the novel parallels between current novels and the original novel.
Scott: Right.
Scott: As I think that I batted a thousand on.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: Just so right.
Scott: It's like you can see exactly where it's like, oh, I have an example.
Rym: I got.
Rym: well, I mentioned that star years ago.
Scott: The reason I think this is what counts as a novel today.
Scott: And you can see exactly how they line up.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I mentioned the Star Trek stuff because I'm watching a lot of older media lately.
Rym: And I've really like it really stands out the differences in like the craft over time.
Rym: But it also stands out that older media has the same fundamental truths because humans have the same fundamental interests when not subverted by situation, circumstance, capitalism, et cetera.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Even in this completely different culture, completely different language, completely different circumstances, you know, they're passing memes around and enjoying music and trying to escape capitalism.
Scott: The humans are still human.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They didn't have.
Scott: capitalism wasn't invented yet.
Scott: But it's like they still have all these things that are just innately human that we can you know, we can see the same motivations.
Scott: You know, we see jealousy.
Scott: You know, all these same same things that we see today.
Scott: You know, fan art.
Rym: Well, thus so the the the act of making an increasingly distant from current culture.
Rym: Simpsons reference is, in fact, echoing the tale of Genji.
Rym: And therefore, I will continue to do this.
Rym: And when I'm 90 and I write, I reference the I reference The Simpsons and the kids have no idea what I'm talking about.
Scott: That's no different than someone in the tale than this author referencing some Chinese poem that everyone at that time who is noble would know about in the tale of Genji.
Rym: I can't say how many times in the tale of Genji I would read like a short section, like one quote paragraph, and it would get this feeling of.
Rym: this is a joke I don't get.
Rym: This is referencing something I don't get.
Rym: This is clearly intended.
Scott: The footnote would tell you.
Scott: the footnote tells you, ah, yes, this this is a reference to, you know, because they would make an analogy like, yeah, you smell like this something and it's like, what's the something?
Scott: Oh, it's it.
Scott: You know, it's a reference to this other poem.
Scott: But not every something was X.
Rym: Not every passage that gave me that feeling had a footnote.
Rym: because I wonder, you know, this has been a long time since this was written.
Rym: How many references might be embedded in the text that aren't recognizable?
Scott: That's true.
Scott: Or how many.
Scott: I literally became references themselves.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: But at work a few weeks ago, I made a different Simpsons reference, like kind of casually as part of a conversation.
Scott: Which one?
Rym: Oh, it was actually it wasn't the same.
Rym: It wasn't two knives, but it was the most is like it was I was just going to cut you a little.
Scott: I was going to catch you.
Rym: Yeah, like I was going to cut you because I was like, just cut you a little bit.
Rym: And like the guy laughed.
Rym: But later we were talking and he was like and it was very clear that he thought I had made a joke on my own from nothing.
Rym: Like, I was like, no, that was just a reference to The Simpsons.
Rym: Like, I'm not that funny.
Rym: And it sparked.
Rym: it sparked an interesting conversation with someone who is 20 years younger than me.
Rym: That just made me feel terrifyingly old.
Scott: It's like you have not watched every Simpsons and Seinfeld episode ever.
Scott: No, it's like some.
Scott: Was there some noble?
Scott: a hundred years?
Scott: You know, I guess not even a hundred.
Scott: A few decades after the tale of Genji was no longer a big hit.
Scott: I hadn't read all of the tale of Genji and then was missing references from grandpa dropping poems.
Rym: But does the tale of Genji itself have references that were just missed by translators and lost to time?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Someday will people not remember?
Scott: I mean, the treasure could definitely be some.
Scott: But the fact that these translators have like they basically these are people who spent their whole lives studying this one fucking book.
Rym: I feel like there aren't many.
Rym: But I feel like it's still possible just due to the distance of time.
Scott: Anyway, that's that's the end of Genji's tale, at least as far as our lives are concerned.
Scott: So I'm going to make the post.
Rym: It is official now.
Rym: The book club book, which we will do soon.
Rym: We're just going to give you some time to read.
Scott: I already finished reading this book weeks ago.
Rym: The City We Became by N.K.
Rym: Jemisin.
Rym: It's a it's a gig night.
Rym: See book.
Rym: And I think you're going to like it.
Rym: And we're going to do a show on it.
Scott: It's got a. it's got a real big, big drop, right?
Scott: The beat the beat drops close to the end.
Rym: We'll do it in about.
Rym: we'll do it in about a month in the best way, because it will not take you long to read this.
Scott: I didn't take long at all.
Scott: But yeah, we have for once.
Scott: You had to wait for us to read.
Scott: Now we're going to wait for you to read.
Scott: We'll give you a month or two.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I feel like I'm going to have this book done before the end of February.
Rym: But we'll still wait like a couple of weeks after that.
Rym: Then we'll do the show or we'll record it in advance.
Rym: But we're going to publish it after a month.
Scott: So that's not a bad idea.
Rym: It's not a bad idea at all.
Rym: Get ahead on the book club.
Scott: Maybe we could put something like, you know, on the Internet and have like.
Scott: people can come and check the box like when they finish reading it and then we can sort of track when it hits a certain amount.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I want to.
Rym: I think now that we're rekindling the book club with a new book, we know that people will start reading the book around this time so we can talk about the book in the forum and the discord while we're all reading it together.
Rym: That used to happen with all the other book club books and only didn't happen with the Elegangy because because, you know, you know exactly why.
Scott: Let us let us know if you plan on reading the city we became and, you know, let us know when you finish reading it.
Rym: So this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for the second and final episode of the GeekNights book club on the Tale of Genji.
Rym: We will probably not talk about this book much again in the foreseeable future.
Rym: R. Heidi McNicholallen, Joyce Linkagey, Dred Lillie, Tenebrae and a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Chris Sadad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Kshaya85, Rebecca Dunn, Reviewmedbull34, Coward, Sam Erickson, Shervin Van Horl.
Rym: Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is Summerhill, Summerhill Station.
Rym: And several people whose Patreon names I will not say.
Rym: So yeah, next book, N.K.
Rym: Jemisin.
Rym: We're going to read it.
Rym: Scott already read it.
Rym: I'll have it done pretty soon.
Rym: We'll give you a month.
Rym: But yeah, come into the Discord, come into the forum, chat with us about the book.
Rym: And for now, I simply leave you with...
Scott: Ryuu ga waga teki wo kurau!
Scott: Ryuuji no kei wo kurau!